<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Harriet Tubman</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lithograph of Harriet Tubman from the book, "Scenes of the Life in Harriet Tubman" (1869) by Sarah H. Bradford. The wood-carved likeness for the printing is attributed to J.C. Darby. She is wearing a long dress, coat and kerchief, and is holding a rifle with both hands. The author refers to this as her "costume as scout."</dc:description>
<dc:description>Harriet Tubman is well known for her work with the Underground Railroad. Born a slave around 1820 in Dorchester County, Maryland, she escaped to Philadelphia in 1849. A prominent abolitionist, she returned to the South 19 times and escorted over 300 slaves to freedom from 1849-1860. During the Civil War, she worked as a nurse, cook, and spy for the Union. After the Civil War, she became actively involved in the women's suffrage movement. Her life stands as a monument to courage and determination.</dc:description>
<dc:date>approximately 1869</dc:date>
<dc:creator>J.C. Darby</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>W.J. Moses</dc:publisher>
<dc:coverage>Auburn (N.Y.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>Library Photograph Collection</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Tubman, Harriet, 1820?-1913; Slavery; Fugitive slaves; Antislavery movements -- United States; Women abolitionists; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Women; Espionage</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Women; Spies; Spying; Slaves; Fugitive slaves; Slavery; Suffragists; Activists; Women's suffrage; Civil rights; Abolition movement; Abolitionists; Underground railroad system</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>33951</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>Still Image</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jp2</dc:format>
<dc:rights>	While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees, that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll18/id/22</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>