<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of a World War II salvage drive for rubber</dc:title>
<dc:description>This photograph depicts a salvage drive taking place on a street in Knoxville, Tenn. Featured in the photo is a downtown Knoxville street with large tires lined up down the length of the street. There are three men and one police officer standing beside the tires holding a sign that reads ""State of Tennessee enters 'Treausure Hunt' for Salvage Rubber"".</dc:description>
<dc:description>During World War II, Americans were frequently called upon to salvage raw materials for the war effort. Frequently, Tennesseans participated in salvage drives to collect materials such as rubber, paper, silk, cooking fat, iron, steel, aluminum, and more. Salvage drives represented a way that Tennesseans could participate in the war effort at home and also built a sense of patriotism among the home front.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1942</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>Knoxville (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>Governor Prentice Cooper Papers 1939-1945</dc:source>
<dc:subject>World War, 1939-1945; Rationing-- United States</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>41876</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>Still Image</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jp2</dc:format>
<dc:rights>	While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees, that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll18/id/252</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>