<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Plan and profiles of Fort Loudoun on Tanasee River projected and constructed by William Gerard de Brahm</dc:title>
<dc:description>A black-and-white photographic plate that presents de Brahm's plan for the fort, along with a profile (the elevation or ground-level view) of the completed structure as he envisioned it.  </dc:description>
<dc:description>The plate on which the plan is represented appears to have been prepared for Samuel C. Williams's book, Early Travels in the Tennessee Country.  It was inserted as a figure at the beginning of a chapter titled "DeBrahm's Account" (p.186), which reprinted DeBrahm's own version of his work on Fort Loudon .  DeBrahm was a respected mapmaker and military engineer who was born in Holland and trained in the Bavarian army.  He came to Georgia with a group of German colonists in 1751.  DeBrahm arrived at the site of Fort Loudon with the Brisitsh colonial garrison in 1756 and designed his plan based on the geography of a site which the Cherokee had specified.  He quarrelled with both the Cherokee and the first commander of the British garrison, and secretly left the site on Christmas night, 1756, well before the fort was completed.  His plan suggests a far more impressive structure than Fort Loudon, with its log walls, would appear when it was completed.  But it was still too strong for the Cherokee to capture by a direct attack.  The fort, however, was separated from the European colonies by the Appalachian mountains and by four groups of Cherokee settlements lying between it and the nearest other colonial forces. Its isolated location left it vulnerable to the Cherokee siege, and the Cherokee turned back the advance of a large British and colonial force which attempted to relieve the garrison in the summer of 1761.  Faced with starvation, the second British commander, who was the brother of the commander with whom DeBrahm had quarreled, surrendered to the Cherokee on August 9,1761.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1756</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>Tennessee</dc:coverage>
<dc:creator>William Gerard de Brahm</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>The Watauga Press</dc:publisher>
<dc:coverage>Johnson City (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>Samuel Cole Williams Papers 1765-1947</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Fort Loudoun (Tenn. : Fort); Cherokee Indians--History; French and Indian War (United States : 1754-1763) </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Bookplates; Site Plans; Forts &amp; fortifications; Log buildings; Palisades</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>42220</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>Still Image</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jp2</dc:format>
<dc:rights>	While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees, that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>ie17teb</dc:contributor>
<dc:coverage>10.5 cm x 17.75 cm</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll18/id/1010</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>