<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Letter from Adam Fergusson to wife, Hester Ann Fergusson, regarding the status of their farm</dc:title>
<dc:description>Adam Fergusson writes this 4-page letter to his wife, Hester Ann, to update her on the status of their farm. He begins by saying he arrived and everything is safe, but the harsh frost makes growing cotton difficult. He describes the local economy and growth. Of particular interest is a description of an encampment of Creek Indians from Alabama waiting to cross the river at Memphis, Tennessee, on their journey of removal to the Indian Territory.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Throughout the 18th and 19th centuries, the American government continually pressed the various tribes of Native Americans to cede their ancestral lands and remove to lands west of the Mississippi River. In 1825, the United States Government signed the Treaty of Indian Springs with William McIntosh, ceding all Creek lands east of the Mississippi. After investigation, it was discovered that McIntosh did not have the authority of the Creek National Council and the treaty was nullified in 1826, making it the only treaty between the United States and an Indian tribe to be overturned. However, in 1836, conflict between the Creeks and white settlers resulted in a series of battles known as the Second Creek War. In response to this war, the United States forced all Creeks to remove to territory west of the Mississippi River.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1836 October 14</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>Holley Springs (Miss.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:creator>Fergusson, Adam</dc:creator>
<dc:source>Fergusson Family Papers, 1784-1927</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Indian Removal, 1813-1903; Indians of North America</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Indigenous peoples</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>42440</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>Still image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:rights>	While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees, that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll18/id/2040</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>