<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>"Stax Backers' Talk..."</dc:title>
<dc:description>"Stax Backers Talk Sounds Like Broken Record," The Commercial Appeal, Memphis, TN. Third in a series of three articles. This third article discusses how Stax was closed for business in 1976 as mandated by federal court. It briefly discusses the possible future of Stax and the Memphis Sound.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Stax Records was a major catalyst in the creation of Southern and Memphis soul music. Founded in 1957 by two white siblings and business partners, Jim Stewart and Estelle Axton (STewart/AXton = Stax), the label was renowned for its output of African-American music and integrated bands. It had a racially integrated team of staff and artists, at that time unprecedented both in Memphis and the South.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1976 February 10</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>Memphis (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:publisher>The Commercial Appeal</dc:publisher>
<dc:coverage>Memphis (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>Newspapers on Microfilm</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Stax Records; Soul music--United States; Music and race</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jp2</dc:format>
<dc:rights>	While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees, that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>ie17hma</dc:contributor>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll18/id/900</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>