<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Constitution and by-laws of the state &amp; subordinate agricultural wheel, of the state of Tennessee, together with the constitution and by-laws of the National Agricultural Wheel, of the United States of America</dc:title>
<dc:description>Pamphlet containing the printed constitutions of the national and state agricultural wheels</dc:description>
<dc:description>Building on the grievances and methods of the Grangers, the Agricultural Wheel established primacy as a farmers  organization in Tennessee in the mid-1880s, before joining forces with the Alliance in 1889. In line with the belief that agriculture was the fundamental wheel of forward economic progress, the national organization s spokes extended to state and local levels. J.R. Miles was the first and only president of the Tennessee Wheel, presiding over some sixteen hundred local chapters. Encouraging efficient farming practices and establishing cooperative efforts to buy and sell equipment and goods, the Wheel provided an organized front against the persistent post-war economic hardships that laid the groundwork for the farmers  movement.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1887</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>Toiler Print</dc:publisher>
<dc:coverage>Fulton (Ky.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>Library Collection</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Agriculture; Constitutions; Pamphlets</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>42145</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jp2</dc:format>
<dc:rights>	While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees, that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>ie17jgb</dc:contributor>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll18/id/775</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>