<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Siege of Fort Watauga, July 20, 1776</dc:title>
<dc:description>A black-and-white drawing showing Catherine Sevier scaling the log palisade of Fort Watauga to escape attacking Cherokee warriors</dc:description>
<dc:description>The drawing is an illustration from a 1970 book entitled The Overmountain Men, by Pat Alderman. It depicts one of the most dramatic incidents in early Tennessee history. According to contemporary accounts, a number of women had left Fort Watauga (in the Sycamore Shoals area of Northeast Tennessee) in the early morning of July 21, 1776, to milk the settlement's cows. The women discovered a force of Cherokee warriors approaching the fort in a surprise attack. Their cries awakened the men inside the fort in time for them to bar the fort's gates, man the palisade, and repulse the attack. Cut off from the entrance to the fort by advancing warriors, young Catherine "Bonnie Kate" Sherrill -- who was described as tall and athletic -- ran to another side of the fort and attempted to climb the wall. The settler atop the palisade was John Sevier, who reached down to grasp Catherine's hand and pull her to safety. The two were married four years later. Sevier went on to serve six terms as Governor of Tennessee and two terms in the United States House of Representatives. He is generally acknowledged as one of the "fathers" of Tennessee. The illustration itself reveals a good deal about the way white Tennesseans of the mid-20th century perceived the history of early white settlement. It depicts the attacking Cherokee, armed primarily with lances and bows, as throwing themselves against the well-engineered walls of the settler fortress. This imagery draws heavily on the western movies and television programs of the period. In reality the Cherokee warriors would have been armed primarily with flintlock guns supplied by the British and similar to those wielded by the white defenders. After the failure of the initial attack, the Cherokee settled into a two-week siege intended to force the surrender of the white garrison, a strategy that had succeeded against a much larger white garrison at Fort Loudon some fifteen years before. The defeat and retreat of another Cherokee force at the Battle of Island Flats on July 20 probably influenced the Cherokee to break off the siege and retreat before additional white militia forces arrived.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1970</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>Carter County (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:creator>Andrews, Bernie</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>The Overmountain Press</dc:publisher>
<dc:coverage>Johnson City (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>Library Photograph Collection</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Forts &amp; fortifications; Women; Watauga Association; Sevier, Catharine, - d.1836; Sevier, John 1745-1815; Cherokee Indians -- History -- 18th century; Tennessee -- History -- 18th century</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Book illustrations; Forts &amp; Fortifications; Rescues</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>1507</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>Still Image</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:rights>	While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees, that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll18/id/2167</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>