<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Trade agreement between United States and Chickasaw and Choctaw</dc:title>
<dc:description>Trade agreement between the United States government and the Chickasaw and Choctaw tribes sanctioned by Southwest Territory governor William Blount. The agreement states that boat captain David Moore will transport goods given to these tribes by the United States in Philadelphia. The goods willl be transported from the Holston River to the mouth of Bear Creek on a flat bottomed boat powered by six oarsmen. Opoca Mingo, a Chickasaw leader, and several others of his tribe will be on the boat to help to direct it. David Moore is given special instruction to protect the Chickasaws on board as well as their goods, especially from parties of hostile Cherokees and Creeks. The agreement does not provide specifics on what types of goods are being transported.</dc:description>
<dc:description>William Blount was the territorial governor of the Territory South of the River Ohio (Southwest Territory) and was instrumental in achieving Tennessee statehood. He was also a signer of the United States Constitution and one of Tennessee's first state senators. He negotiated the Treaty of Holston and gained land west of the Appalachian Mountains from the Indians for the United States In the late 1700s, territorial clashes between white settlers and American Indians including the Cherokees and Chickasaws led to hostile and often violent environments between the two groups. Several series of treaties between the United States government and tribal governments were signed in an attempt to establish boundary lines and prevent further violence.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1794 October 12</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>Tennessee</dc:coverage>
<dc:creator>Blount, William</dc:creator>
<dc:source>Territorial Governor William Blount Papers, 1790-1796</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Chickasaw Indians; Blount, William; Choctaw Indians</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>42871</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:rights>	While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees, that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll18/id/1938</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>