<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Beale Street</dc:title>
<dc:description>Beale Street in Memphis, Tenn.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Beale Street in Memphis, Tennessee is significant to both the history of the city and of blues music. Created in 1841, the west end primarily housed merchant shops that traded with ships along the Mississippi River, and the eastern part developed as an affluent suburb. In the 1860s, many black traveling musicians began performing on Beale. In the 1870s, the land around Beale Street was purchased by Robert Church, eventually making him the first black millionaire from the South. During the 1890s, Beale Street underwent renovations, adding the Orpheum Theater and Church Park with its auditorium. In the early 1900s, the street filled with clubs, restaurants, and shops - many of which were owned by African Americans. From the 1910s through the 1940s, Beale Street became an epicenter for blues and jazz and the development of the Memphis Blues style. The stretch from Main to 4th was declared a National Historic Landmark in 1966, and on December 15, 1977, Beale Street was officially declared the "Home of the Blues" by an act of Congress.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1953 September 9</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>Memphis (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Memphis (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>Tennessee Department of Conservation Photograph Collection, 1937-1976</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Beale Street (Memphis, Tenn.); Memphis (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>15946</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>Still Image</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jp2</dc:format>
<dc:rights>	While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees, that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>ie17hma</dc:contributor>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll18/id/899</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>