<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Letter from John Sevier to Governor Patrick Henry announcing the formation of the State of Franklin</dc:title>
<dc:description>Negative photostat (possibly from the Virginia state papers) of a two-page handwritten letter John Sevier wrote to the governor of Virginia, Patrick Henry, announcing the formation of the State of Franklin and Sevier's appointment as governor.</dc:description>
<dc:description>This notification followed the first official meeting of the Franklin Assembly in March of 1785 and the subsequent election of John Sevier by delegates as governor of the State of Franklin. The letter represents Sevier filling his role as head of this newly formed state, communicating with another state leader, and informing Henry of trade negotiations with the Chickasaw undertaken by the State of Franklin. At the same time, Sevier, recognizing the volatile climate in the area, reassured Governor Henry that Franklin intended to incite no unrest in Virginia, nor encourage encroachment on Native American lands. Notably, Sevier mentions that he expects no official correspondence with Governor Henry until the State of Franklin is recognized by Congress, an acknowledgement that never materialized.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1785 July 19</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>Franklin (State)</dc:coverage>
<dc:creator>Sevier, John, 1745-1815</dc:creator>
<dc:source>Penelope Johnson Allen Cherokee Collection, 1775-1878</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Sevier, John, 1745-1815; Henry, Patrick, 1736-1799; Franklin (State); Tennessee -- History; Virginia -- History; Virginia. Governor</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>42078</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jp2</dc:format>
<dc:rights>	While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees, that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>ie27dkb</dc:contributor>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll18/id/617</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>