<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Wanted! for murder: her careless talk cost lives</dc:title>
<dc:description>This World War II era poster features a woman posed in a traditional Wanted! advertisement meant to help the public search for a criminal. It is meant to illustrate a point that American citizens should be careful about sharing information about the location of soldiers and more during the war. This copy of the poster was distributed by the Office of War Information to the "Tennessee Library Division" in Nashville. A note on the reverse of this poster identifies the creator, Victor Kepper, and concludes with a statement "The prominent display of this poster will be appreciated."</dc:description>
<dc:date>1944</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>Washington (D.C.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:creator>Keppler, Victor</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Office of War Information</dc:publisher>
<dc:coverage>Washington (D.C.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>World War I and World War II Poster Collection</dc:source>
<dc:subject>World War, 1939-1945; Posters</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>42040</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>Text; Still Image</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jp2</dc:format>
<dc:rights>	While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees, that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>ie28kdw</dc:contributor>
<dc:coverage>71 x 51 cm.</dc:coverage>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll18/id/688</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>