<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Essay submitted by Katherine R. Barnes (Mrs. Melville) regarding her experiences on the homefront in Tennessee during World War II</dc:title>
<dc:description>As part of a Tennessee Historical Society project documenting and interpreting "Home Front Tennessee: The World War II Experience", Mrs. Katherine R. Barnes of Nashville submitted this seven page personal essay in response to a series of questions intended to explore an individual's experience here in Tennessee during World War II. Mrs. Barnes writes about what was expected of Americans, the role of women during the war, the availability of consumer goods, the rationing of food and gas, planting Victory Gardens, and the likelihood of Nashville being in danger during the war. She relates a story about college-educated men being able to get commisisons in their desired service and how many of her friends took this option rather than taking a chance on the draft. Mrs. Barnes husband was called by the lottery in the winter of 1944. He reported to Camp Forrest in Tullahoma and then was turned down because he "weighed too little". She concludes by writing about President Franklin D. Roosevelt and their opposition to him holding a third term and the surrender of Japan.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1991-1993</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>Nashville (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:creator>Barnes, Katherine R.</dc:creator>
<dc:source>"Home Front", World War II Oral History Project, 1991-1993</dc:source>
<dc:subject>World War, 1939-1945; Rationing-- United States</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>41946</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jp2</dc:format>
<dc:rights>	While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees, that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>ie28kdw</dc:contributor>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll18/id/672</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>