<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Letter from William H. Polk to Gideon Pillow</dc:title>
<dc:description>Letter from William Polk to Gideon Pillow. William Polk, President James K. Polk's brother, writes from Mexico City during the height of the Mexican- American War to his friend, General Gideon Pillow. The letter is about a recent scandal between General Pillow and the Commander of Forces in Mexico, General Winfield Scott. Scott had Pillow court martialed for exaggerating his role in several battles. In this letter, Polk reassures Pillow that his friends in the military in Mexico are sure that his innocence will soon be proven.  </dc:description>
<dc:description>The conflict between an arrogant young General Gideon Pillow and famous War of 1812 veteran General Winfield Scott started when Pillow exaggerated his role in a battle in Mexico on one of his military reports. Scott asked him to change it, which Pillow did. However, Pillow also wrote to a New Orleans newspaper under the guise 'Leonidas' claiming that it was Pillow who won several battles in Mexico (which were actually won by Scott and several other generals). Scott court martialed Pillow over this letter and other infractions. Before the trial could happen, President James K. Polk (who was a friend of General Pillow's and politically opposed to General Scott) fired Scott as the Commander of the Army and reduced Pillow's court martialling to a simple investigation. The court found Pillow not guilty and he resumed his position in Mexico. After a few weeks, President Polk also reinstated Scott as the commander in Mexico. </dc:description>
<dc:date>1848 May 6th</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>City of Mexico</dc:coverage>
<dc:creator>Polk, William H.</dc:creator>
<dc:source>Polk, James Knox (1795-1949) Collection, 1815-1949</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Polk, James K (James Knox), 1795-1849; Mexican War, 1846-1848</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>42161</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jp2</dc:format>
<dc:rights>	While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees, that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>ie28cal</dc:contributor>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll18/id/1092</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>