<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Our Masked Foe: Typical Speech # 5</dc:title>
<dc:description>Form speech written for use by the Four Minute Men Association. This speech seeks to warn Four Minute Men speakers of those who spread anti-war or pacifist propaganda for "un-American motives." It presents the Four Minute Men Association as advocates for war combat enemy propaganda by disseminating truthful information rather than hate against Germany. It describes the Four Minute Men speaker's intended audience as American people who are apathetic or skeptical about the United State's participation in the war.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The Four Minute Men Association developed during World War I to provide a means for dissemination of information on Liberty Bond drives. The organization was directed by the Committee of Public Information and acquired its name because speakers at meetings were urged to speak for only four minutes.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1917</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Four Minute Men (Society); United States. Committee on Public Information</dc:creator>
<dc:coverage>Washington (D.C.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>Four Minute Men Association, 1917-1919</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Four Minute Men (society); Patriotism--United States; World War, 1914-1918; World War, 1914-1918, Germany; United States. Committee on Public Information; World War, 1914-1918--Social aspects--United States; World War, 1914-1918--Propaganda</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Propaganda</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>42694</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:rights>	While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees, that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll18/id/1983</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>