<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Letter from the Secretary of Labor to Gov. Browning about continuing the CCC in Tennessee</dc:title>
<dc:description>This letter from the Secretary of Labor W. Frank Persons to Governor Gordon Browning discusses the benefits of continuing the CCC in Tennessee after the 1937 Congressional act expanding the Corps. It also provides specific numbers of Tennesseans involved in the CCC up to that point.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The CCC was created in 1933 to provide jobs and training for umemployed young men around the country.The Corps employed young men to perform structural improvements to bridges and roads; erosion and flood control; and various conservation workprojects. The Corps was instrumental in the infrastructure of the Tennessee State Parks System and National Parks in Tennessee. According to this letter, by the time that the CCC was expanded in 1937, 38,136 young men from Tennessee had been enrolled and employed by the CCC.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1937 August 12</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>Washington (D.C.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:creator>Persons, W. Frank</dc:creator>
<dc:source>Governor Gordon Browning Papers, 1937-1939</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Persons, W. Frank, 1876-1955; Civilian Conservation Corps (U.S.); New Deal, 1933-1939; New Deal, 1933-1939--Tennessee</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>42769</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:rights>	While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees, that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll18/id/1670</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>