<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Tennessee Valley Authority fish census taken at Cherokee Lake</dc:title>
<dc:description>This photograph depicts a man and his son weighing fish at the Cherokee Lake Boat Dock in Hamblen County.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The Cherokee Dam is located on the Holston River in East Tennessee. It was named for the tribe of Native Americans who once inhabited the area. The Cherokee Reservoir is a popular recreation destination. There are many commercial boat docks, a state park and a state wildlife management area for visitors. One popular recreational activity at Cherokee is fishing. At the reservoir, visitors can find a wide variety of fish such as black bass, sauger, walleye, crappie, sunfish, and rough-fish species. </dc:description>
<dc:date>1946 May 16</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>Hamblen County (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>Tennessee Department of Conservation Photograph Collection, 1937-1976</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Photographs</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Fishing</dc:source>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>16686</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>Still Image</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:rights>	While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees, that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll18/id/2198</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>