<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Letter from Ed Porter Thompson to Henry Benton Henegar requesting information about Indian removal</dc:title>
<dc:description>In this letter, Thompson writes to Henegar stating he had read an article that listed Henegar among the people who traveled west with the Indian tribes during Removal. Thompson requests details about the route they followed to the Indian Territory and the length of time it took to make the journey. He continues by saying the accepted historical accounts implied the tribes traveled due west through the lower Southern states of Alabama and Mississippi, but he had heard a recent account claiming the routes went through other Southern states and any information Henegar could provide would be helpful to his writings on the topic.</dc:description>
<dc:description>H. B. Henegar was employed by Cherokee Chief John Ross as wagonmaster and secretary during the Indian Removal of 1838-1839. He traveled with a detachment of Cherokees to their new country in Arkansas, west of the Mississippi River.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1897 October 22</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>Frankfort (Ky.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:creator>Thompson, Ed Porter</dc:creator>
<dc:source>Henegar Family Papers, 1845-1924</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Indians of North America-- Relocation; Cherokee Indians-- Relocation; Trail of Tears, 1838-1839; Indian Removal, 1813-1903;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Indigenous peoples</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>42136</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:rights>	While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees, that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll18/id/2118</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>