<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Interivew with Jean Prueher about her motivation to join the Red Cross</dc:title>
<dc:description>Video interview of Jean Prueher by Susan Gordon of the Tennessee Historical Society. In this clip, Gordon asks Prueher to describe her motivation for joining the Red Cross. Prueher's response is that when she moved to Nashville, she wanted to be a part of the war effort and the Red Cross needed people to give out doughnuts on the train. She says that the trains would come through town carrying soldiers that seemed to be so young to her at the time and she would push doughnuts and candy bars though the windows and the boys would lean out of the windows and talk with them. She also states that, though she does not know if this was organized by the Red Cross, her church in downtown Nashville used its fellowship hall as a place where soldiers from the Classification Center, Camp Forrest and Fort Campbell could sleep and eat breakfast on Sunday mornings.</dc:description>
<dc:description>In the 1990s, the Tennessee Historical Society recorded oral histories of Tennesseans who had served in the armed forces, volunteered in civilian services, or worked in war industries during World War II. Jean Prueher worked with the Red Cross during World War II. She and her fellow Red Cross workers would take carts of desserts to Union Station in Nashville to serve soldiers passing through the train station. </dc:description>
<dc:date>1993 May 12</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>Nashville (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:creator>Tennessee Historical Society </dc:creator>
<dc:source>"Home Front" World War II Oral History, 1991-1993</dc:source>
<dc:subject>World War 1939-1945; World War 1939-1945-- Participation, Female-- Tennessee; World War 1939-1945-- War Work-- Tennessee</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Women; War relief; Military personnel</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>42880</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>Moving Image</dc:type>
<dc:format>Video/mp3</dc:format>
<dc:rights>	While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees, that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>IE17EMR</dc:contributor>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll18/id/1172</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>