<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Regulations concerning the removal of the Indians</dc:title>
<dc:description>This booklet was a publication printed by the United States War Department and outlines the regulations for conducting the business of removing the Indians from the Southeast to the territory west of the Mississippi River. It outlines the Directing Department, special agents, disbursements, transportation, supplies, provisions, appraisement and payment of property, miscellaneous and compensation relating to the removal. The opening paragraph states that the observations of the past year ""have led to the convictions, that a more systemic plan of operations is essential to the economy and to the satisfactory progress of these movements."" It states what the emigrants can and cannot carry with them, how much each person is to receive in rations, what items are to be provided to them, how much they will be paid for their property and compensation to those hired to help remove them. The forms at the back of the book are an example of how these things are to be recorded and submitted to the Office of Commisary General of Subsistence.</dc:description>
<dc:description>After President Andrew Jackson signed the Indian Removal Bill of 1830, the United States began negotiating the removal of all of the Native American tribes residing east of the Mississippi River to lands in the west. This publication is an attempt to better organize and document the removal of the tribes.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1832 May 15</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>Washington (D.C.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:creator>Cass, Lewis</dc:creator>
<dc:source>Library Collection</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Indian Removal, 1813-1903; Cherokee Indians--Treaties; Cherokee Indians--Relocation; Indians of North America</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Indigenous peoples; Indian agents</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>RegulationsConcerningIndianRemoval</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:rights>	While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees, that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll18/id/2117</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>