<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>AVCO workers at end of World War II on property of Vultee</dc:title>
<dc:description>This photograph shows a group of AVCO employees, many of them female, posing on a train on the property of Vultee Aircraft, Inc. There are three men in the photograph, two of which are wearing dress clothes with ties and the third is dressed in engineer's overalls. There is one woman dressed in overalls. The rest of the women are wearing casual dress attire.</dc:description>
<dc:description>World War II was the catalyst that brought change in the gender roles held for women. Because of the labor shortage produced by men joining the armed forces during World War II, women were encouraged to take jobs in nearly every industry. Traditional gender roles had limited the job descriptions of women, but the need for manpower during the war allowed women to extend the boundaries of the work they could perform outside the home. Aviation Corporation (AVCO), with its subsidiaries, was among the top employers of women in Tennessee during the war.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1945</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>Tennessee</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>Dudney Family Papers 1862-1991</dc:source>
<dc:subject>World War, 1939-1945; World War, 1939-1945--War work--Tennessee; Vultee airplanes; Women employees</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Women; Employees; War work; Aircraft industry; Railroad trains</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>42915</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>Still Image</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:rights>While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll18/id/2327</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>