<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Church of the Lord Jesus service, 1996 August 31</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Video recording opening with an outside view of the church and surrounding landscape, which cuts to Bob Elkins who speaks about the church&#8217;s policy on handing serpents for new members and visitors. He ends his speech and asks for the congregation to join him in prayer. &#160;The prayer ends and the music begins as congregants take to the floor to dance. The crowd is large and the pews are filled, even with many members standing and dancing. As the music plays, members of the congregation dance in the twirling style of the Jolo church and many handle serpents. Barb Elkins sings, but the recording cuts off and when it begins again a man comes up from the pews to testify on the pulpit, giving his respect to the Elkins. Carl Porter testifies and the music begins again. Thereafter he begins again, giving way to the testimony of another preacher in from South Carolina. He continues, giving a sermon to the assembly. Following his sermon the collection plate is passed around, followed by another preacher who begins a sermon to the congregation with considerable zeal. His sermon ended, the congregation once again opens to song, dance and handling of serpents. As the music continues, seven members of the congregation drink strychnine. One member of the congregation is overcome with religious fervor and he handles a serpent. Members of the congregation lay hands upon a member of the congregation.</dc:description>
<dcterms:created>1996-08-31</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Appalachian Region, Southern--Religious life and customs; Dance--Religious aspects; Expository preaching; Extemporaneous preaching; Pentecostal preaching; Homecoming; Imposition of hands; Lay preaching; Singing--Religious aspects; Slain in the Spirit; Snake cults (Holiness churches)--Appalachian Region, Southern</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Anderson, Brice; Chafin, Dewey; Christian, Roy; Church, Charles; Elkins, Barbara; Elkins, Bob; Evans, Richard; Evans, Spencer; Hagerman, Jeffreyrey; Hollins, Kirby; Hollins, Lydia; Kimbrough, David L., 1951-; McCoy, Tim; Porter, Carl</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Church of the Lord Jesus (Jolo, W. Va.)</dc:subject>
<dcterms:spatial>Jolo (W. Va.)</dcterms:spatial>
<dc:type>Moving Image</dc:type>
<dc:type>field recordings</dc:type>
<dc:format>video/mp4</dc:format>
<dcterms:extent>02:02:46</dcterms:extent>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:identifier>MS-074-03-07</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>J-7</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Church of the Lord Jesus recordings and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson field recordings, interviews, and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Special Collections</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</dc:publisher>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson Holiness Churches of Appalachia recordings and interviews</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16877coll2/id/60</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>