<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Church of the Lord Jesus Christ service, 1995 February 18</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Video recording of a service that begins with footage captured outside of the church. The recording resumes within the church where the congregation is led in song by Jamie Coots. Members clap along to the beat or play tambourine and the camera pans around the assembly before members begin to handle serpents. Several serpents are laid on the floor and alternatively picked up and handled by members. Music ends and, still handling serpents, Carl Porter preaches to the congregation. When he concludes his sermon, music and dance begin again. Members still handle serpents. A member of the congregation testifies as he handles and his testimony gives way to more singing.  Carl Porter speaks as he handles and congregants sing and gather at the front of the church to be blessed. The video cuts and reopens on a man who is overcome and being surrounded by other congregants who lay hands on him as he sits on the floor shaking. Two men take him to his feet and dance around with him between them as he continues to be overcome in spirit. He stumbles around as other members dance with and support him physically. Eventually he is laid back on the floor and other members of the congregation pray over him. He is joined by a woman on the floor and she, also overcome, speaks in tongues. She stands briefly and collapses to the floor as others raise the other member to his feet. As this continues, the preacher praises them. The video cuts to a visitor who testifies before the congregation.</dc:description>
<dcterms:created>1995-02-18</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Appalachian Region, Southern -- Religious life and customs; Dance -- Religious aspects; Expository preaching; Gifts, Spiritual; Glossolalia; Imposition of hands; Slain in the Spirit; Singing -- Religious aspects; Snake cults (Holiness churches) -- Appalachian Region, Southern; Witness bearing (Christianity)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Brown, John Wayne, Jr., 1964-1998; Coots, Jamie, (Gregory James), 1971-2014; Frazier, Diane; Lemming, Billy; McCormick, Junior; Miller, Shade; Pelfrey, Bill; Porter, Carl</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Church of the Lord Jesus Christ (Kingston, Ga.)</dc:subject>
<dcterms:spatial>Kingston (Ga.)</dcterms:spatial>
<dc:type>Moving Image</dc:type>
<dc:type>field recordings</dc:type>
<dc:format>video/mp4</dc:format>
<dcterms:extent>00:41:41</dcterms:extent>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:identifier>MS-074-04-04</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>K-4</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Church of the Lord Jesus Christ recordings and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson field recordings, interviews, and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Special Collections</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</dc:publisher>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson Holiness Churches of Appalachia recordings and interviews</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16877coll2/id/83</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>