<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Barb Elkins funeral service, 1999 February 9</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Video recording opening with shot of the inside the Church of the Lord Jesus Jolo, West Virginia as members gather for the funeral of Barb Elkins. Flowers adorn the floor and walls of the altar and the casket is centered there and open for viewing. As members of the church speak quietly to one another, the camera pans across the room and pauses on the deceased. Bob Elkins speaks with members of the church as more members gather for the funeral. Tim McCoy comes forward to M.C. the service and lets the assembly know that the service will begin with a few songs. As the music plays, people come forward to speak to members of the family. Lydia Hollins sings with another female member of the church and her voice breaks several times as she sings. When the songs end, Carl Porter speaks and eulogizes Barb Elkins and calls for a prayer. Member bow their heads in prayer, and as Carl Porter leads prayer, others speak prayers of their own. Tim McCoy asks Brother Harris and his choir from Alabama to come forward and pay respects. He takes the microphone and introduces the song they will sing. The choir then sings &#8220;Fill Me&#8221; in her memory. When they finish Tim McCoy reads out Barb Elkin&#8217;s obituary for those assembled. He follows with a eulogy and extorts her virtue before singing. Roy &#8220;Booty&#8221; Christian sings and plays guitar with Tim McCoy after the first song is finished. When their song ends, Carl Porter comes forward once again to say some words. He gives testimony and preaches to the congregation. When his speech and sermon end, music once again fills the church and members, friends and acquaintances come forward to pay respects to the deceased and to give condolence to the family. The recording continues as members walk to the grave site. Pall bearers take the casket from the Herse and deliver it to the grave as the assembly moves under a tent. Carl Porter asks for a prayer and follows with a verse from Psalms before speaking to the congregation and asking for another prayer. People pay their final respects before pall bearers are called forth to lower the casket. The recording ends when her coffin is in place and the mechanism for lowering her smoothly is removed. </dc:description>
<dcterms:created>1999-02-09</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Appalachian Region, Southern -- Religious life and customs; Snake cults (Holiness churches) -- Appalachian Region, Southern</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Christian, Roy; Church, Lucille; Elkins, Barbara; Elkins, Bob; Evans, Melissa; Hollins, Kirby; Hollins, Lydia; Porter, Carl; McCoy, Tim</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Church of the Lord Jesus (Jolo, W. Va.)</dc:subject>
<dcterms:spatial>Jolo (W. Va.)</dcterms:spatial>
<dc:type>Moving Image</dc:type>
<dc:type>field recordings</dc:type>
<dc:format>video/mp4</dc:format>
<dcterms:extent>01:53:39</dcterms:extent>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:identifier>MS-074-08-04</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>F-4</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Fatal bites, funerals, and wakes field records, 1985-1998</dc:source>
<dc:source>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson field recordings, interviews, and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Special Collections</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</dc:publisher>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson Holiness Churches of Appalachia recordings and interviews</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16877coll2/id/164</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>