<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Full Gospel Tabernacle in Jesus' Name service, 1996 August 3</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Video recording of a service opening with music. Jamie Coots plays guitar and Greg Coots plays guitar and sings. The music pauses while one guitarist repairs a string. As the musical cacophony continues, others come forward to sing including: Mark Brown, Sherman Ward, John Wayne "Punkin" Brown Jr., Rochelle Brown, and Jamie and Linda Coots. As the songs continue, the camera pans to the crowded pews and shows several women dancing and one receiving an imposition of hands from a fellow parishioner. A lull in the music reveals a woman speaking in tongues as a member of the church named Bruce Helton preaches. As he does, members including John Wayne "Punkin" Brown Jr., Carl Porter, Sherman Ward, John Brown, and Carl Turner, handle serpents. Following Helton's sermon, members speak and testify. A sermon by Jamie Coots concludes the video. </dc:description>
<dcterms:created>1996-08-03</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Appalachian Region, Southern -- Religious life and customs; Dance -- Religious aspects; Singing -- Religious aspects; Expository preaching; Extemporaneous preaching; Glossolalia; Homecoming; Imposition of hands; Lay preaching; Snake cults (Holiness churches) -- Appalachian Region, Southern; Witness bearing (Christianity)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Brown, John; Brown, John Wayne, Jr., 1964-1998; Brown, Mark; Brown, Rochelle; Coots, Greg; Coots, Jamie, (Gregory James), 1971-2014; Coots, Linda; Helton, Bruce; Porter, Carl; Porter, Sherman; Turner, Carl; Ward, Sherman</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Full Gospel Tabernacle in Jesus' Name (Middlesboro, Ky.)</dc:subject>
<dcterms:spatial>Middlesboro (Ky.)</dcterms:spatial>
<dc:type>Moving Image</dc:type>
<dc:type>field recordings</dc:type>
<dc:format>video/mp4</dc:format>
<dcterms:extent>01:43:19</dcterms:extent>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:identifier>MS-074-05-02</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>M-2</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Full Gospel Tabernacle in Jesus' Name recordings and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson field recordings, interviews, and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Special Collections</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</dc:publisher>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson Holiness Churches of Appalachia recordings and interviews</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16877coll2/id/126</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>