<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Church of God in Jesus Christ Name service, 2003 July 12</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Video recording of a service lead by Jimmy Morrow. The service opens with Brother Russell preaching to the congregation and Jimmy Morrow leading them in prayer. There follows singing by the congregation, this time unaccompanied by guitars. Following the initial songs, a member of the congregation plays banjo as the congregants sing. Following this a member takes up the organ in accompaniment. Following the song, Jimmy Morrow preaches to those assembled and briefly handles a serpent. He continues his sermon and lays hands on a member of the congregation. The service closes with testimony from congregants and a brief prayer from Brother Russell.</dc:description>
<dcterms:created>2003-07-12</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Appalachian Region, Southern -- Religious life and customs; Expository preaching; Imposition of hands; Lay preaching; Pentecostal preaching; Prayer; Singing -- Religious aspects; Snake cults (Holiness churches) -- Appalachian Region, Southern;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Morrow, Jimmy</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Edwina Church of God in Jesus Christ's Name (Del Rio, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dcterms:spatial>Del Rio (Tenn.)</dcterms:spatial>
<dc:type>Moving Image</dc:type>
<dc:type>field recordings</dc:type>
<dc:format>video/mp4</dc:format>
<dcterms:extent>00:54:38</dcterms:extent>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:identifier>MS-074-02-09</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>D-9</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Church of God in Jesus Christ Name field recordings, 2002-2004</dc:source>
<dc:source>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson field recordings, interviews, and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Special Collections</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</dc:publisher>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson Holiness Churches of Appalachia recordings and interviews</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16877coll2/id/53</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>