<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Full Gospel Tabernacle in Jesus' Name service, 1996 August 4</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Video recording of a service opening with indistinct chatter as the camera focuses on a hand-written list and a printed document on the church wall. It cuts to a shot of the serpent boxes and then cuts again to reveal the outside of the church as members gather and mill about. A final cut returns the view to the church interior where pastor Jamie Coots calls for a prayer. The prayer comes to an end and music promptly takes the place of the cacophony of prayers. Singers rotate and between songs, members testify. When the music starts again members of the church including John Wayne "Punkin" Brown Jr., Gene Sherbert, Carl Porter, Joel Sherbert, Bill Pelfrey, Carl Turner, Verlin Short, Lydia Hollins, Jamie Coots, John Brown, John Fish, David Kimbrough, Diane Tucker, Sherman Ward, Greg Coots, Sister Pelfrey, Mark Brown, Kirby Hollins and several others handle. Sister Pelfrey takes a moment before she sings to praise the Lord. After her song, more song by female members of the church follows and members dance. The music stops and testimonies from members of the church begin. Their testimony gives way to a sermon by another member who extemporizes while in the background, Carl Porter organizes serpent boxes. The sermon ends and other members testify including Bill Pelfrey. The testimony ends the recording. </dc:description>
<dcterms:created>1996-08-04</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Appalachian Region, Southern -- Religious life and customs; Dance -- Religious aspects; Singing -- Religious aspects; Expository preaching; Extemporaneous preaching; Homecoming; Lay preaching; Prayer; Snake cults (Holiness churches) -- Appalachian Region, Southern; Witness bearing (Christianity)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Brown, John Wayne, Jr., 1964-1998; Burton, Thomas; Coots, Jamie, (Gregory James), 1971-2014; Kimbrough, David L., 1951-; Hollins, Kirby; Hollins, Lydia; Pelfrey, Bill; Sherbert, Gene; Sherbert, Joel; Short, Verlin; Tucker, Diane; Turner, Carl; Ward, Sherman</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Full Gospel Tabernacle in Jesus' Name (Middlesboro, Ky.)</dc:subject>
<dcterms:spatial>Middlesboro (Ky.)</dcterms:spatial>
<dc:type>Moving Image</dc:type>
<dc:type>field recordings</dc:type>
<dc:format>video/mp4</dc:format>
<dcterms:extent>02:03:08</dcterms:extent>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:identifier>MS-074-05-03</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>M-3</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Full Gospel Tabernacle in Jesus' Name recordings and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson field recordings, interviews, and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Special Collections</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</dc:publisher>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson Holiness Churches of Appalachia recordings and interviews</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16877coll2/id/127</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>