<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Church of God in Jesus Christ Name service, 2004 June 13</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Video recording of a service, opening with singing lead by a member of the chruch who also plays guitar. Rayford Dunn takes prayer requests and begins a prayer. Music follows, and a female member of the congregation sings at the pulpit. Rayford Dunn then sings at the pulpit. When the singing comes to an end, Jimmy Morrow begins a sermon to the congregation. At the conslusion of Morrow's sermon, there is more singing and testimony from the congregation. Jimmy Morrow closes the service by welcoming a visitor to the congregation and closes with a prayer.</dc:description>
<dcterms:created>2004-06-13</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Appalachian Region, Southern--Religious life and customs; Homecoming; Imposition of hands; Pentecostal preaching; Singing--Religious aspects; Witness bearing (Christianity)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Dunn, Rayford; Morrow, Jimmy</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Edwina Church of God in Jesus Christ's Name (Del Rio, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dcterms:spatial>Del Rio (Tenn.)</dcterms:spatial>
<dc:type>Moving Image</dc:type>
<dc:type>field recordings</dc:type>
<dc:format>video/mp4</dc:format>
<dcterms:extent>01:56:01</dcterms:extent>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:identifier>MS-074-02-08</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>D-8</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Church of God in Jesus Christ Name field recordings, 2002-2004</dc:source>
<dc:source>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson field recordings, interviews, and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Special Collections</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</dc:publisher>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson Holiness Churches of Appalachia recordings and interviews</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16877coll2/id/52</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>