<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Brice Anderson's congregation service, 2002 July 17</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Video recording opening with a member of the congregation leading the congregation in song. When he is done, Brice Anderson calls Brother Phil forward to testify while members go to get some water. Brother Phil testifies and calls members to come forward and worship. When he is finished, Brice Anderson begins his sermon. As part of his sermon he removes his shoe and sock to reveal a yellow jacket sting. He uses it as an example. His sermon concludes with a call to prayer. Members of the congregation leave their pews and come to kneel before the altar as three others sing and play guitar. When members finish their prayer, several come forward to sing along. One child in the congregation joins in on the microphone and is eventually joined by other children. A woman in the congregation receives an imposition of hands at the altar while they sing. She is overcome in spirit and when the video pans back from the children to her she lies upon the floor. Next to her another member receives blessings and an imposition of hands from members of the church. Brice Anderson calls others forward to pray and lays hands on a member of the congregation who comes forward. The woman who was slain in spirit recovers and can be seen kneeling before the video cuts to another segment of the service. Brice Anderson introduces Ralph Hood and the recording crew, and calls members to worship. He explains the format for prayer requests and asks that members keep the requests short and concise requests for prayer. He also makes a prayer request. He goes on to talk about his yellow jacket sting again and shows people the sting. Members come forward to see it and asks for members to pray for healing. A female member of the church is called to the altar and many members of the church pray over her and lay hands upon her. Members are then called to pray and some move forward to the altar and others bow their heads and pray in their pews. When the prayers end, music begins and members dance and sing for a bit before one member testifies. There follows more song and imposition of hands on more members of the congregation. The music ends the service. </dc:description>
<dcterms:created>2002-07-17</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Appalachian Region, Southern -- Religious life and customs; Dance -- Religious aspects; Extemporaneous preaching; Imposition of hands; Pentecostal preaching; Prayer; Singing -- Religious aspects; Snake cults (Holiness churches) -- Appalachian Region, Southern</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Anderson, Brice</dc:subject>
<dcterms:spatial>Georgia</dcterms:spatial>
<dc:type>Moving Image</dc:type>
<dc:type>field recordings</dc:type>
<dc:format>video/mp4</dc:format>
<dcterms:extent>01:58:20</dcterms:extent>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:identifier>MS-074-09-02</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>A-2</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Services and interviews field recordings, 1985-2002</dc:source>
<dc:source>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson field recordings, interviews, and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Special Collections</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</dc:publisher>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson Holiness Churches of Appalachia recordings and interviews</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16877coll2/id/167</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>