<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Church of God in Jesus Christ Name service, 2002 June 9</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Video recording of a Saturday evening service during which Jimmy Morrow and Silas Crawford handle a serpent and congregants sing. The service opens with Bobby Smart preaching, receiving prayer requests, and leading members in prayer. SInging follows Jimmy Morrow sermonizes to the congregation while a National Geographic film crew and still photographer are present. Jimmy Morrow preaches and leads the congregation in the laying on of hands. Silas Crawford plays guitar and sings, and afterwords he handles serpents and testifies. The service ends with singing and donations to the church followed by a brief prayer from Bobby Smart. A sepecial segment of the recording shows Silas Crawford and Jason Barnes handling a large serpents at the graves of John Wayne &#8220;Punkin&#8221; Brown Jr. and Melinda Brown. There follows another clip in which Silas Crawford handles a scorpion.</dc:description>
<dcterms:created>2002-06-09</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Appalachian Region, Southern -- Religious life and customs; Glossolalia; Homecoming; Imposition of hands; Lay preaching; Pentecostal preaching; Prayer; Singing -- Religious aspects; Snake cults (Holiness churches)-- Appalachian Region, Southern</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Barnes, Jason; Brown, John Wayne, Jr., 1964-1998; Brown, Melinda, 1967-1995; Crawford, Silas; Morrow, Jimmy; Smart, Bobby</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Edwina Church of God in Jesus Christ's Name (Del Rio, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dcterms:spatial>Del Rio (Tenn.)</dcterms:spatial>
<dc:type>Moving Image</dc:type>
<dc:type>field recordings</dc:type>
<dc:format>video/mp4</dc:format>
<dcterms:extent>00:51:51</dcterms:extent>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:identifier>MS-074-02-02</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>D-2</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Church of God in Jesus Christ Name field recordings, 2002-2004</dc:source>
<dc:source>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson field recordings, interviews, and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Special Collections</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</dc:publisher>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson Holiness Churches of Appalachia recordings and interviews</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16877coll2/id/46</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>