<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Church of God in Jesus Christ Name service, 2002 April 20 </dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Video recording of a service officiated by Jimmy Morrow with a small number of attendees. Jason Barnes and his sister lead the congregation in song. Glenn Dukes, who is visiting the congregation, handles first one and then two serpents at a time. Jimmy Morrow preaches in melodic tones, expounding on scripture. During the sermon he begins handling a serpent for a short time. The sermon is following by more hymns and the testimony of Rayford Dunn.</dc:description>
<dcterms:created>2002-04-20</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Appalachian Region, Southern--Religious life and customs; Lay preaching; Pentecostal preaching; Prayer; Singing--Religious aspects; Snake cults (Holiness churches)--Appalachian Region, Southern; Witness bearing (Christianity)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Barnes, Jason; Dukes, Glenn; Dunn, Rayford; Morrow, Jimmy</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Edwina Church of God in Jesus Christ's Name (Del Rio, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dcterms:spatial>Del Rio (Tenn.)</dcterms:spatial>
<dc:type>Moving Image</dc:type>
<dc:type>field recordings</dc:type>
<dc:format>video/mp4</dc:format>
<dcterms:extent>01:00:04</dcterms:extent>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:identifier>MS-074-02-01</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>D-1</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Church of God in Jesus Christ Name field recordings, 2002-2004</dc:source>
<dc:source>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson field recordings, interviews, and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Special Collections</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</dc:publisher>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson Holiness Churches of Appalachia recordings and interviews</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16877coll2/id/45</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>