<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Church of the Lord Jesus Christ service, 1996 April 4</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Video recording of a service opening with music. Singing is led by Bill Pelfrey. There are few in attendance. It is not long before the singing comes to an end and Carl Porter speaks. As he does, he places prayer cloths on the pulpit and asks if anyone has any prayer requests. Bill Pelfrey preaches a short sermon thereafter and leads the congregation in song. He follows his song with more preaching. A man is helped to the pulpit where Carl Porter and Bill Pelfrey anoint him with oil and many members come forward to pray over him. Carl Porter follows this with a sermon after which, Bobbie Sue Lynn sings. Porter follows the song with one of his own and as he sings, Billy Summerford takes up a serpent. Others quickly follow. Carl Porter follows this singing and handling with testimony after which he yields the microphone to Spencer Evans who preaches and later in his sermon handles serpents.</dc:description>
<dcterms:created>1996-04-06</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Appalachian Region, Southern -- Religious life and customs; Dance -- Religious aspects; Extemporaneous preaching; Imposition of hands; Lay preaching; Pentecostal preaching; Prayer; Singing -- Religious aspects; Snake cults (Holiness churches) -- Appalachian Region, Southern; Witness bearing (Christianity)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Evans, Spencer; Lynn, Bobbie Sue; Miller, Shade; Pelfrey, Bill; Porter, Carl; Summerford, Billy </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Church of the Lord Jesus Christ (Kingston, Ga.)</dc:subject>
<dcterms:spatial>Kingston (Ga.)</dcterms:spatial>
<dc:type>Moving Image</dc:type>
<dc:type>field recordings</dc:type>
<dc:format>video/mp4</dc:format>
<dcterms:extent>01:15:16</dcterms:extent>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:identifier>MS-074-04-19</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>K-19</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Church of the Lord Jesus Christ recordings and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson field recordings, interviews, and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Special Collections</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</dc:publisher>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson Holiness Churches of Appalachia recordings and interviews</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16877coll2/id/95</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>