<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Ray McCallister wake, 2000 November 14</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Video recording opening on the wake of Ray McAllister at the Church of the Lord Jesus Jolo, West Virginia. Music opens the recording and the open casket reveals both McAllister&#8217;s body and a folded American flag. Members dance and sing while Melissa Evans plays organ. Dewey Chafin handles serpents as the music continues and others join him periodically. As music and songs continue, the camera zooms in on a card within the coffin. The text reveals it to be a Christmas card from Ray McAllister&#8217;s wife. Lydia Hollins handles serpents and sings while members dance and Roy &#8220;Bootie&#8221; Christian plays guitar. Dewey Chafin holds the largest bundle of serpents that any recording has revealed heretofore. The recording cuts to a view of Dewey Chafin testifying as he holds the massive amalgam of serpents. He tells the congregation that Ray McAllister just &#8220;went home&#8221;. More music follows and members dance in front of the casket. The music pauses and Bob Elkins preaches to the congregation. His sermon is interspersed with more music and he speaks during lulls and dances with the other members of the congregation while the music speeds up. When he is done speaking, Melissa Evans takes up the microphone and sings with Lydia Hollins. Dewey Chafin and Bob Elkins both handle serpents as the music plays. An abrupt cut in the film changes to slower music and reveals more members handling. The music continues and the recording zooms in on the body of Ray McAllister again. As the music plays, children run around the pews and Lydia Hollins continues to sing. </dc:description>
<dcterms:created>2000-11-14</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Appalachian Region, Southern -- Religious life and customs; Snake cults (Holiness churches) -- Appalachian Region, Southern</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Chafin,Chafin, Dewey; Christian, Roy; Elkins, Bob; Evans, Melissa; Hollins, Kirby; Hollins, Lydia; McAllister, Ray; McCoy, Tim</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Church of the Lord Jesus (Jolo, W. Va.)</dc:subject>
<dcterms:spatial>Jolo (W. Va.)</dcterms:spatial>
<dc:type>Moving Image</dc:type>
<dc:type>field recordings</dc:type>
<dc:format>video/mp4</dc:format>
<dcterms:extent>00:50:09</dcterms:extent>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:identifier>MS-074-08-05</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>F-5</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Fatal bites, funerals, and wakes field records, 1985-1998</dc:source>
<dc:source>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson field recordings, interviews, and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Special Collections</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</dc:publisher>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson Holiness Churches of Appalachia recordings and interviews</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16877coll2/id/165</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>