<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Church of the Lord Jesus service, 1998 September 5</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Video recording of a service opening with singing lead by Dewey Chafin and Lydia Hollins. Members handle serpents and dance in the twirling style of Jolo.  Many members take to the floor and take up serpents as the music continues to play. One member is bitten as he removes serpents from the box. Members gather around him and he continues to dance and handle. Barb Elkins is present, but confined to a wheelchair. After the music ends, Bob Elkins begins to preach and addresses the issue of snakebites while he preaches. He punctuates his sermon by drinking strychnine and handling two serpents. During his sermon, members approach the pew and begin to pray while the organ plays, and the music begins again. One member of the congregation who was bitten receives prayers.  Another member of the congregation preaches to the congregation with considerable fervor. A slow melody follows him from the pulpit and a member of the congregation sings. The recording ends with song.</dc:description>
<dcterms:created>1998-09-05</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Appalachian Region, Southern -- Religious life and customs; Dance -- Religious aspects; Expository preaching; Extemporaneous preaching; Imposition of hands; Lay preaching; Pentecostal preaching; Prayer; Singing -- Religious aspects; Snakebites; Snake cults (Holiness churches) -- Appalachian Region, Southern; Witness bearing (Christianity)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Chafin, Dewey; Christian, Roy; Elkins, Barbara; Elkins, Bob; Hollins, Lydia; McCoy,Tim</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Church of the Lord Jesus (Jolo, W. Va.)</dc:subject>
<dcterms:spatial>Jolo (W. Va.)</dcterms:spatial>
<dc:type>Moving Image</dc:type>
<dc:type>field recordings</dc:type>
<dc:format>video/mp4</dc:format>
<dcterms:extent>01:23:32</dcterms:extent>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:identifier>MS-074-03-12</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>J-12</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Church of the Lord Jesus recordings and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson field recordings, interviews, and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Special Collections</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</dc:publisher>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson Holiness Churches of Appalachia recordings and interviews</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16877coll2/id/65</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>