<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Church of the Lord Jesus service, 1997 August 30</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Video recording opens outside the Jolo church, which quickly cuts to a recording within the church as members of the congregation chat and await the beginning of the service. The video cuts to music played on an organ by Lydia Hollins and Bob Elkins welcoming members to the service. Barb Elkins greets a member of the congregation. The music continues and members of the congregation begin to handle serpents including Lydia Hollins. The music ends and Bob Elkins welcomes members, calling them to raise their hands in prayer. Members interpose hands on others as the music begins again and members begin to dance. Melissa Evans handles a serpent and is bitten. Members of the congregation gather around her as she continues to dance. Members usher her to a seat and she receives prayers and leaves the service. Congregants continue to handle serpents and dance as music plays. When the music concludes, Dewey Chafin testifies about his belief in the serpent handling tradition. After this, music and handling by members of the congregation begins once again. When it comes to an end, Bob Elkins begins his sermon. When he concludes, the music begins again and another member of the congregation begins to preach. After the second sermon, another member of the congregation bears witness. Following this, members of the congregation approach the pulpit in praise. Music begins again and Melissa Evans returns to the congregation in new clothes. Members begin to handle again and throughout the service, a total of three people are bitten.</dc:description>
<dcterms:created>1997-08-30</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Appalachian Region, Southern--Religious life and customs; Dance--Religious aspects; Expository preaching; Extemporaneous preaching; Homecoming; Imposition of hands; Lay preaching; Pentecostal preaching; Prayer; Singing--Religious aspects; Snakebites; Snake cults (Holiness churches)--Appalachian Region, Southern; Witness bearing (Christianity)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Brown, John Wayne, Jr., 1964-1998; Chafin, Dewey; Christian, Roy; Dukes, Glenn; Elkins, Barbara; Elkins, Bob; McCoy, Tim; Hollins, Lydia; Kimbrough, David L., 1951-; Porter, Carl </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Church of the Lord Jesus (Jolo, W. Va.)</dc:subject>
<dcterms:spatial>Jolo (W. Va.)</dcterms:spatial>
<dc:type>Moving Image</dc:type>
<dc:type>field recordings</dc:type>
<dc:format>video/mp4</dc:format>
<dcterms:extent>02:02:23</dcterms:extent>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:identifier>MS-074-03-09</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>J-9</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Church of the Lord Jesus recordings and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson field recordings, interviews, and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Special Collections</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</dc:publisher>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson Holiness Churches of Appalachia recordings and interviews</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16877coll2/id/62</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>