<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Church of the Lord Jesus service, 2004 August 5</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Video recording of a service opening with song. Bill Pelfrey is visiting the congregation. After the music, Bob Elkins stands with assistance and addresses the congregation and gives a short sermon before drinking strychnine. After Bob Elkins finishes he relinquishes the pulpit to Bill Pelfrey who warns visitors about approaching serpents. He asks if anyone has prayers they wish to speak aloud, and members respond before he leads them in prayer. Music follows the prayer, and members sing and dance. Congregants handle serpents after a few minutes of music and many church members handle. Bill Pelfrey handles a serpent and testifies with one in his hand. After this testimony members once again take to dancing. Bill Pelfrey, who spoke earlier, speaks again as members of the church lay hands on and pray for Bob Elkins. After this, Eileen plays piano and leads the congregation in song. Bill Pelfrey takes to the pulpit after the music again subsides, and he gives a sermon which concludes the video.</dc:description>
<dcterms:created>2004-08-05</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Appalachian Region, Southern -- Religious life and customs; Dance -- Religious aspects; Expository preaching; Extemporaneous preaching; Imposition of hands; Lay preaching; Prayer; Singing -- Religious aspects; Snake cults (Holiness churches) -- Appalachian Region, Southern; Witness bearing (Christianity)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Chafin, Dewey; Elkins, Bob; Evans, Melissa; McCoy, Tim; Pelfrey, Bill</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Church of the Lord Jesus (Jolo, W. Va.)</dc:subject>
<dcterms:spatial>Jolo (W. Va.)</dcterms:spatial>
<dc:type>Moving Image</dc:type>
<dc:type>field recordings</dc:type>
<dc:format>video/mp4</dc:format>
<dcterms:extent>01:59:28</dcterms:extent>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:identifier>MS-074-03-24</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>J-24</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Church of the Lord Jesus recordings and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson field recordings, interviews, and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Special Collections</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</dc:publisher>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson Holiness Churches of Appalachia recordings and interviews</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16877coll2/id/76</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>