<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Church of the Lord Jesus Christ service, 1999 January 30</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Video recording of a service opening with Junior McCormick singing and testifying. Following Junior McCormick, Fanny Bell Baker speaks and when she is done, the congregation comes forward to bless her as Junior McCormick anoints her head with oil and prays over her. Carl Porter sings after she is anointed. His testimony follows his song. He continues with a sermon about prohibitions in the Bible. Kneeling before the pulpit, he thanks God for his blessings. His sermon continues and is interspersed with personal testimony, and afterwards he sings as Steve Porter removes two serpents from the box and begins to handle. A woman in the background can be heard shouting in tongues. As Steve Porter handles, he wraps a serpent around his neck so that he can light a bottle of kerosene ablaze and handle fire and a serpent. Carl Porter removes the serpent from his neck before he begins to handle fire. After he handles, he gives the serpent to Junior McCormick, and places the bottle of flaming kerosene on the pulpit to burn out. Before it does, Junior McCormick returns the snake to Steve Porter and handles the bottle of flame until it expires. Larry Pelfrey sings to a bass heavy song as Steve Porter continues to handle. Junior McCormick testifies thereafter and his testimony continues until the end of the recording. </dc:description>
<dcterms:created>1999-01-30</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Appalachian Region, Southern -- Religious life and customs; Expository preaching; Glossolalia; Imposition of hands; Lay preaching; Prayer; Singing -- Religious aspects; Snake cults (Holiness churches) -- Appalachian Region, Southern; Witness bearing (Christianity)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Baker, Fanny Bell; McCormick, Junior; Pelfrey, Larry; Porter, Carl; Porter, Steve; </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Church of the Lord Jesus Christ (Kingston, Ga.)</dc:subject>
<dcterms:spatial>Kingston (Ga.)</dcterms:spatial>
<dc:type>Moving Image</dc:type>
<dc:type>field recordings</dc:type>
<dc:format>video/mp4</dc:format>
<dcterms:extent>02:00:04</dcterms:extent>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:identifier>MS-074-04-39</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>K-39</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Church of the Lord Jesus Christ recordings and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson field recordings, interviews, and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Special Collections</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</dc:publisher>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson Holiness Churches of Appalachia recordings and interviews</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16877coll2/id/113</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>