<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Church of the Lord Jesus service, 2001 September 1</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Video recording of a Sunday service opening with piano and singing. After members file into the church, Bob Elkins begins a sermon and asks people to pay attention and to pray. Following the prayer, members unlock the serpent cages and music begins with many member of the church singing and dancing. Jeff Hagerman removes the first serpents from their box and others follow. Ray McCalister, Dewey Chafin, Buddy Jewel, Larry Muncie, Carl Porter, Rayford Dunn, Cynthia Porter, Ruby Jewel, Roy &#8220;Bootie&#8221; Christian, Glenn Dukes and others handle after Hagerman. During the music the camera pans between members of the church, both young and old, and focuses on a visiting preacher as he sings. He is also a point of focus as he lays hands on members of the congregation. Bob Elkins testifies and preaches to the congregation as they lay on hands on a man. There follows more dancing some in the twirling style of Jolo.  Kirby Hollins is bitten by a serpent, and discusses with others who have been bitten while his hand is elevated by another member of the congregation. Other members reminisce about previous bites. </dc:description>
<dcterms:created>2001-09-01</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Appalachian Region, Southern -- Religious life and customs; Dance -- Religious aspects; Homecoming; Imposition of hands; Lay preaching; Prayer; Singing -- Religious aspects; Snakebites; Snake cults (Holiness churches) -- Appalachian Region, Southern; Witness bearing (Christianity)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Chafin, Dewey; Christian, Roy; Dukes, Glenn; Dunn, Rayford; Elkins, Bob; Hagerman, Jeffrey; Hollins, Kirby; Hollins, Lydia; Jewel, Buddy; Jewel, Ruby; McAllister, Ray; McCoy, Tim; Muncie, Larry; Porter, Carl; Porter, Cynthia</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Church of the Lord Jesus (Jolo, W. Va.)</dc:subject>
<dcterms:spatial>Jolo (W. Va.)</dcterms:spatial>
<dc:type>Moving Image</dc:type>
<dc:type>field recordings</dc:type>
<dc:format>video/mp4</dc:format>
<dcterms:extent>00:47:25</dcterms:extent>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:identifier>MS-074-03-17</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>J-17</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Church of the Lord Jesus recordings and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson field recordings, interviews, and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Special Collections</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</dc:publisher>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson Holiness Churches of Appalachia recordings and interviews</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16877coll2/id/70</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>