<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Church of the Lord Jesus service, 1999 September 5</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Video recording of a service opening with Bob Elkins leading the church in prayer. Lydia Hollins plays organ and sings. She is accompanied by Bob Elkins on guitar and Eileen on piano. Members of the church dance and sing. As the singing continues, members of the church begin to handle serpents. Among the handlers are Ruby Jewel, Ray McCalister, Dewey Chafin, Larry Muncie, Roy &#8220;Bootie&#8221; Christian, Melissa Evans, Cynthia Porter, Verlin Short, and Richard Evans. Dewey Chafin talks about belief as he handles a rattlesnake. After he speaks another member gives testimony and take to the floor and dance as the music begins again. As music plays, three members of the congregation drink from a jar of strychnine. The music ceases and a visiting preacher gives a sermon. This is followed by a sermon by Bob Elkins during which he calls for the visiting preacher to give the final sermon of the service.</dc:description>
<dcterms:created>1999-09-05</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Appalachian Region, Southern -- Religious life and customs; Dance -- Religious aspects; Expository preaching; Homecoming; Lay preaching; Pentecostal preaching; Prayer; Singing -- Religious aspects; Snake cults (Holiness churches) -- Appalachian Region, Southern; Witness bearing (Christianity)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Chafin, Dewey; Christian, Roy; Elkins, Bob; Evans, Melissa; Evans, Richard; Hollins, Lydia; Jewel, Ruby; McAllister, Ray; McCoy, Tim; Porter, Cynthia; Short, Verlin</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Church of the Lord Jesus (Jolo, W. Va.)</dc:subject>
<dcterms:spatial>Jolo (W. Va.)</dcterms:spatial>
<dc:type>Moving Image</dc:type>
<dc:type>field recordings</dc:type>
<dc:format>video/mp4</dc:format>
<dcterms:extent>02:00:27</dcterms:extent>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:identifier>MS-074-03-15</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>J-15</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Church of the Lord Jesus recordings and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson field recordings, interviews, and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Special Collections</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</dc:publisher>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson Holiness Churches of Appalachia recordings and interviews</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16877coll2/id/68</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>