<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Full Gospel Tabernacle in Jesus' Name service, 1997 August 2</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Video recording of a service opening with a view from outside the church as people gather for the service. The video is not stabilized and the image is disturbed. A cut in the film reopens inside the church as Jamie Coots calls members stand to pray. Shortly thereafter, music begins and thought the camera is still poorly stabilized, several members from other churches can be seen in attendance including Bob Elkins, Barb Elkins, who sits at the front with her great, great grandchild Lydia Hollins and others from the Jolo church. Bob Elkins comes forward to sing, as does Lydia Hollins. Members of the church gather at the front to dance as members begin to handle serpents. Spencer Evans testifies during a lull in the music. The music begins again and when another lull presents itself, Bruce Helton preaches with zeal. He is followed by several members of the congregation who testify before the congregation. Music plays thereafter and members of the church come forward to receive an imposition of hands. More testimony, handling and song follows and the testimony from Diane Tucker ends the recording. </dc:description>
<dcterms:created>1997-08-02</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Appalachian Region, Southern -- Religious life and customs; Dance -- Religious aspects; Singing -- Religious aspects; Homecoming; Imposition of hands; Lay preaching; Prayer; Snake cults (Holiness churches) -- Appalachian Region, Southern; Witness bearing (Christianity)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Brown, John Wayne, Jr., 1964-1998; Chafin, Dewey; Chruch, Charles; Coots, Jamie, (Gregory James), 1971-2014; Dukes, Glenn; Elkins, Barb; Elkins, Bob; Evans, Spencer; Helton, Bruce; Lydia Hollins; Kimbrough, David L., 1951-; Muncie, Larry; Porter, Carl; Short, Verlin; Summerford, Billy; Taylor, Bill; Tucker, Diane; Turner, Carl;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Full Gospel Tabernacle in Jesus' Name (Middlesboro, Ky.)</dc:subject>
<dcterms:spatial>Middlesboro (Ky.)</dcterms:spatial>
<dc:type>Moving Image</dc:type>
<dc:type>field recordings</dc:type>
<dc:format>video/mp4</dc:format>
<dcterms:extent>02:02:50</dcterms:extent>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:identifier>MS-074-05-05</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>M-5</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Full Gospel Tabernacle in Jesus' Name recordings and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson field recordings, interviews, and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Special Collections</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</dc:publisher>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson Holiness Churches of Appalachia recordings and interviews</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16877coll2/id/129</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>