<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Church of the Lord Jesus service, 2002</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Video recording of a service opening with the new pastor of Jolo, Kirby Hollins, asking members to pray. When the prayer ends, music and dancing begin, Lydia Hollins sings and the blind pianist who is again visiting, and Roy &#8220;Bootie&#8221; Christian play. During the dancing, members of the congregation begin to handle serpents.  Kirby Hollins handles serpents and speaks in tongues before he passes serpents to members of the church and venerates God, and Lydia Hollins introduces a visiting preacher who is visiting from Alabama. As he begins to speak, the film cuts off and reopens in a different location outside a men&#8217;s restroom. Two men are conversing but there is no audio. The film cuts and reopens with an extremely dark nighttime scene outside the church as member of the congregation gather outside. The preacher can be heard in the background, as the men talk about their personal experiences with snakebites and the Kentucky laws that prohibit snake handling churches. They continue discussing the laws in several states which regulate the snake handling tradition.  One man tells the interviewer that he had been bitten 19 times. The video cuts once again and reopens with the visiting preacher preaching to the congregation. His sermon is well received by the congregation and they applaud him several times throughout. The video then looses audio but the camera reveals a scene of a member of the church handling several rattlesnakes simultaneously. Audio returns and music fills the film. Members including Kirby Hollins handle the multitude of serpents, which are being passed around by members. </dc:description>
<dcterms:created>2002</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Appalachian Region, Southern -- Religious life and customs; Dance -- Religious aspects; Glossolalia; Homecoming; Imposition of hands; Lay preaching; Pentecostal preaching; Prayer; Singing -- Religious aspects; Snake cults (Holiness churches) -- Appalachian Region, Southern; Witness bearing (Christianity)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Christian, Roy; Elkins, Bob; Hollins, Kirby; Hollins, Lydia; McCoy, Tim;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Church of the Lord Jesus (Jolo, W. Va.)</dc:subject>
<dcterms:spatial>Jolo (W. Va.)</dcterms:spatial>
<dc:type>Moving Image</dc:type>
<dc:type>field recordings</dc:type>
<dc:format>video/mp4</dc:format>
<dcterms:extent>01:24:50</dcterms:extent>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:identifier>MS-074-03-20</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>J-20</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Church of the Lord Jesus recordings and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson field recordings, interviews, and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Special Collections</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</dc:publisher>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson Holiness Churches of Appalachia recordings and interviews</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16877coll2/id/73</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>