<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Bruce Helton's congregation service, 1987</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Video recording opening with music. After the music slows for a moment, the camera pans around the church and focuses briefly on the writing on a wall poster. It is incomprehensible. The video and audio quality falters for a bit as two female members of the congregation sing. While music continues, one congregant holds a serpent. When the music ends, members can be heard preaching and speaking in tongues. Two members become the focus of the camera and they speak briefly before going forward to the altar to pray. Others can be seen with their arms upraised in prayer or with heads bowed as the congregation prays. The people who went to the altar receive an imposition of hands from members of the congregation as they kneel. More music follows the prayers, and several congregants remain at the altar in prayer as the music plays. One man removes a serpent from its box and handles as he walks around the front of the church. He lays it briefly upon the floor before picking it back up and walking back up to the altar. A woman in the congregation dances towards the back of the church and as the camera pans back and forth across the congregation it returns to her sitting in a pew receiving an imposition of hands from another woman in the congregation. A pause in the music gives Bruce Helton the opportunity to ask for prayer requests. He prays over a woman from the church and others join him and place hands upon her. Pastor Helton delivers short testimony and another call to prayer. After the prayer, Helton asks if anyone else has any songs they wish to sing. Nobody comes forward and Helton takes up the microphone and preaches a sermon beginning with Luke 9:56. </dc:description>
<dcterms:created>1987</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Appalachian Region, Southern -- Religious life and customs; Dance -- Religious aspects; Extemporaneous preaching; Imposition of hands; Pentecostal preaching; Prayer; Singing -- Religious aspects; Snake cults (Holiness churches) -- Appalachian Region, Southern; Witness bearing (Christianity)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Helton, Bruce</dc:subject>
<dcterms:spatial>Harlan (Ky.)</dcterms:spatial>
<dc:type>Moving Image</dc:type>
<dc:type>field recordings</dc:type>
<dc:format>video/mp4</dc:format>
<dcterms:extent>01:30:56</dcterms:extent>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:identifier>MS-074-09-04</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>A-4</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Services and interviews field recordings, 1985-2002</dc:source>
<dc:source>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson field recordings, interviews, and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Special Collections</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</dc:publisher>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson Holiness Churches of Appalachia recordings and interviews</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16877coll2/id/168</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>