<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Full Gospel Tabernacle in Jesus' Name service, 1997 August 2</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Video recording of a service opening with a disturbed recording of the gathered congregation. Billy Taylor opens the service with prayer requests. The film is poorly calibrated throughout and there is a considerable amount of feedback as members pray at the altar and in their pews. When they finish, a member of the church tells the congregation to ignore the cameras and focus on Jesus before launching into a song. Between musical numbers, John Wayne "Punkin" Brown Jr. testifies and sermonizes the congregation. Several members, including John Wayne "Punkin" Brown Jr., Bruce Helton, Sherman Ward, Carl Turner, Gracie McCalister, Jamie Coots, handle serpents. They handle as music once again fills the church. Gracie McCalister follows her serpent handling with the handling of fire. The video remains distorted in both audio and video.  When she finishes handling the flame, she sits upon the pulpit with raised hands, as the music continues. Before long, she and other members can be seen dancing to the music. The music once again gives way to the testimony of church members. The testimony and music alternate until Bruce Helton comes forward to preach. Following his sermon, other members of the congregation testify including: Glenn Dukes, Dewey Chafin, Larry Muncie, Rayford Dunn, Sherman Ward, Billy Taylor, Jamie Coots, Sister Coots, and Gracie McCalister. Their testimony ends the recording. </dc:description>
<dcterms:created>1997-08-01</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Appalachian Region, Southern -- Religious life and customs; Dance -- Religious aspects; Singing -- Religious aspects; Homecoming; Lay preaching; Prayer; Snake cults (Holiness churches) -- Appalachian Region, Southern; Witness bearing (Christianity)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Brown, John Wayne, Jr., 1964-1998; Chafin, Dewey; Coots, Jamie, (Gregory James), 1971-2014; Dukes, Glenn; Dunn, Rayford; Helton, Bruce; Muncie, Larry;Taylor, Billy; Turner, Carl; Ward, Sherman;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Full Gospel Tabernacle in Jesus' Name (Middlesboro, Ky.)</dc:subject>
<dcterms:spatial>Middlesboro (Ky.)</dcterms:spatial>
<dc:type>Moving Image</dc:type>
<dc:type>field recordings</dc:type>
<dc:format>video/mp4</dc:format>
<dcterms:extent>02:02:44</dcterms:extent>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:identifier>MS-074-05-04</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>M-4</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Full Gospel Tabernacle in Jesus' Name recordings and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson field recordings, interviews, and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Special Collections</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</dc:publisher>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson Holiness Churches of Appalachia recordings and interviews</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16877coll2/id/128</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>