<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Church of the True Believers in Jesus' Name service, 1997 December 20</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Video recording of a service opening with music and dancing as members keep rhythm with music performed Billy Lemming. As the camera pans around the room it is easy to see the range of ages represented in the congregation. Many children are present and they sit as older members of the congregation stand and dance. When the music comes to an end, Rayford Dunn who says that he is 61 years old today, takes up the microphone and preaches before singing. When he does, many members including several children stand to dance and keep rhythm as Lemming plays guitar and Dunn sings. While the music continues led by Billy Lemming, Rayford Dunn lays hands on members of the congregation and prays. Shade Miller likewise lays hands on members as they come forward to the altar to receive the imposition. Shade Miller and Rayford Dunn then anoint members with oil as they lay hands upon them. Rayford Dunn then preaches again between walking among the congregation and laying hands upon members. The music picks up again as two female members of the congregation sing. The duet is followed by another female member of the church who sings alone save for the musical accompaniment of Billy Lemming&#8217;s guitar. Shade Miller takes the pulpit and makes a few announcements before a woman in the congregation testifies to the applause of many congregants. Shade Miller then prays for the congregation and blesses the food. More music follows led by a female member of the congregation before Billy Lemming again takes charge of the song and musical accompaniment as members receive an imposition of hands form Shade Miller and Rayford Dunn. Dunn preaches to the congregation after they have returned to their seats. His sermon is punctuated with a song and more imposition of hands. As Lemming sings, Shade Miller handles a serpent in the background. When Dunn begins to preach again a woman comes forward and lays hands upon Dunn. Shade Miller follows Dunn and closes the service with a prayer. </dc:description>
<dcterms:created>1997-12-20</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Appalachian Region, Southern -- Religious life and customs; Dance -- Religious aspects; Imposition of hands; Lay preaching; Pentecostal preaching; Prayer; Singing -- Religious aspects; Snake cults (Holiness churches) -- Appalachian Region, Southern; Witness bearing (Christianity)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Dunn, Rayford; Hood, Ralph W.; Lemming, Billy; Miller, Ethel; Miller, Gail; Miller, Shade; Nietzel, Delphia</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Church of the True Believers in Jesus' Name (Calhoun, Ga.)</dc:subject>
<dcterms:spatial>Calhoun (Ga.)</dcterms:spatial>
<dc:type>Moving Image</dc:type>
<dc:type>field recordings</dc:type>
<dc:format>video/mp4</dc:format>
<dcterms:extent>01:54:11</dcterms:extent>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:identifier>MS-074-06-03</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>C-3</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Church of the True Believers in Jesus' Name recordings and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson field recordings, interviews, and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Special Collections</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</dc:publisher>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson Holiness Churches of Appalachia recordings and interviews</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16877coll2/id/137</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>