<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Church of God in Jesus Christ Name service, 2003 June 8</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Video recording of a homecoming service featuring testimony, prayer, singing, and preaching by Jimmy Morrow. The recording opens with testimony by Bobby Smart. Smart's testimony is followed by a prayer and music with Jason Barnes and Silas Crawford playing guitar. Jimmy Morrow then begins his sermon to the congregation while handling a serpent. Other members of the congregation including Jason Barnes and Silas Crawford handle serpents as well. Silas Crawford preforms Glossolalia and testifies. The congregation signs and dances while some members handling serpents. The recording culminates with Jimmy Morrow and Silas Crawford alternatively holding their hands to a flame.</dc:description>
<dcterms:created>2003-06-08</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Appalachian Region, Southern--Religious life and customs; Dance -- Religious aspects; Glossolalia; Homecoming; Lay preaching; Pentecostal preaching; Prayer; Singing--Religious aspects; Snake cults (Holiness churches)--Appalachian Region, Southern; Witness bearing (Christianity)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Barnes, Jason; Crawford, Silas; Morrow, Jimmy; Smart, Bobby</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Edwina Church of God in Jesus Christ's Name (Del Rio, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dcterms:spatial>Del Rio (Tenn.)</dcterms:spatial>
<dc:type>Moving Image</dc:type>
<dc:type>field recordings</dc:type>
<dc:format>video/mp4</dc:format>
<dcterms:extent>00:59:10</dcterms:extent>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:identifier>MS-074-02-05</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>D-5</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Church of God in Jesus Christ Name field recordings, 2002-2004</dc:source>
<dc:source>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson field recordings, interviews, and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Special Collections</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</dc:publisher>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson Holiness Churches of Appalachia recordings and interviews</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16877coll2/id/49</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>