<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title> Full Gospel Tabernacle in Jesus' Name service, 1998 August 1</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Video recording of a service opening with a prayer. Billy Taylor addresses the congregation briefly before they all bow in prayer. Shortly thereafter, Mark Brown plays and sings. A member of the congregation speaks briefly during a lull in the music before it begins again. Several members can be seen dancing as the camera pans across the room. Several members testify before Bruce Helton preaches during another pause in the music. Music begins again as members come forward to the altar. Some come forward to bless or be blessed and receive an anointing in oil and an imposition of hands. Helton takes up preaching again as Billy Lemming handles a serpent. His sermon ends the video. </dc:description>
<dcterms:created>1998-08-01</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Appalachian Region, Southern -- Religious life and customs; Dance -- Religious aspects; Singing -- Religious aspects; Expository preaching; Homecoming; Imposition of hands; Lay preaching; Pentecostal preaching; Prayer; Snake cults (Holiness churches) -- Appalachian Region, Southern; Witness bearing (Christianity)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Brown, Mark; Coots, Jamie, (Gregory James), 1971-2014; Helton, Bruce; Lemming, Billy; Summerford, Billy; Taylor, Billy</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Full Gospel Tabernacle in Jesus' Name (Middlesboro, Ky.)</dc:subject>
<dcterms:spatial>Middlesboro (Ky.)</dcterms:spatial>
<dc:type>Moving Image</dc:type>
<dc:type>field recordings</dc:type>
<dc:format>video/mp4</dc:format>
<dcterms:extent>02:03:21</dcterms:extent>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:identifier>MS-074-05-08</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>M-8</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Full Gospel Tabernacle in Jesus' Name recordings and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson field recordings, interviews, and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Special Collections</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</dc:publisher>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson Holiness Churches of Appalachia recordings and interviews</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16877coll2/id/132</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>