<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Church of the Lord Jesus service, 1998 September 4</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Video recording of a service opening with music, dancing and handling of serpents by the congregation. Tim McCoy sings, and Dewey Chafin handles serpents. A member of the congregation drinks strychnine. Barb Elkins is present and handles a serpent from her wheelchair. Bob Elkins gives an impassioned sermon, and there follows more music and dancing. A female member of the congregation handles a serpent and dances while members of the congregation look on, some joining the dance for brief periods, she is followed by other members of the congregation. Many attendees have cameras and are photographing the event. The music concludes again and Bob Elkins brings a microphone to Barb Elkins who addresses the congregation and gives an admonition to the assembled. She laments the reluctance of visitors and congregants to join in the worship. Music once again follows her and Lydia Hollins plays organ while congregants sing. The music picks up tempo and members begin to dance and handle serpents again. A member handles and as the music ends, he begins to speak in tongues, before bearing witness and discussing popular misconceptions about the serpent handing tradition. Other members give testimony. Bob Elkins delivers a sermon which ends the service.</dc:description>
<dcterms:created>1998-09-04</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Appalachian Region, Southern--Religious life and customs; Dance--Religious aspects; Glossolalia; Homecoming; Lay preaching; Pentecostal preaching; Prayer; Singing--Religious aspects; Snake cults (Holiness churches)--Appalachian Region, Southern;Witness bearing (Christianity)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Brown, John Wayne, Jr., 1964-1998; Chafin, Dewey; Christian, Roy; Dukes, Glenn; Elkins, Barbara; Elkins, Bob; Evans, Melissa; Hagerman, Jeffrey; Hollins, Kirby; Hollins, Lydia; Kimbrough, David L., 1951-; McCoy, Tim; David;  Porter, Carl; Roberts, Nola Faye; Roberts, Paul; Short, Verlin; Summerford, Billy</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Church of the Lord Jesus (Jolo, W. Va.)</dc:subject>
<dcterms:spatial>Jolo (W. Va.)</dcterms:spatial>
<dc:type>Moving Image</dc:type>
<dc:type>field recordings</dc:type>
<dc:format>video/mp4</dc:format>
<dcterms:extent>01:52:58</dcterms:extent>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:identifier>MS-074-03-11</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>J-11</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Church of the Lord Jesus recordings and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson field recordings, interviews, and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Special Collections</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</dc:publisher>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson Holiness Churches of Appalachia recordings and interviews</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16877coll2/id/64</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>