<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Ulysses Prince funeral service, 1995 August</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Video recording opening with church members handling serpents and dancing. Recording quality is low and the film and audio cut repeatedly throughout the recording. After roughly eight minutes, the recording cuts and reopens on a view of a stricken man in his home as members of the congregation watch over him and pray. The stricken man&#8217;s left arm and hand are swollen and he sits with it propped up on a pillow as he sits upon a chair. The film loses quality again and a blue and black screen alternate, followed by lines of poorly stabilized images which obfuscate the recording. Audio cuts in and out as well. When the recording becomes intelligible again, members of the church sit around the stricken man again and, as he sits, the camera zooms in on his hand, revealing the puncture wounds of the snake bite. A close shot of the man&#8217;s swelling neck and chest reveal that he is in poor condition. Members stand as the casket is brought in and the funerary service begins. The logistics of the funeral go on and the immediate family is called to the front of the church. The events are laid out and the pastor calls a member of the congregation forward to sing a song. As he sets up, the pastor continues to speak to the congregation, apologizing for the close quarters and lack of convenience. He follows this with a request that members pray with him. He is followed by the young man who begins to sing. When he is done, another preacher takes the pulpit and preaches a sermon to the assembled congregants. The pastor who opened the funeral then asks members to join him in a prayer again and as he speaks, other members follow him in prayer. He ends the prayer by introducing another singer who eulogizes the deceased (who is identified as Charles) before launching into song. The preacher delivers a sermon in the wake of the song, and when he is done, a man with an accordion plays and sings. Another eulogy from the sister of the deceased follows, and she sings a song beloved by her brother in his memory. She takes up a guitar when she begins to sing, and many in the congregation sing with her. Other members of the church follow with testimony and words about Charles.</dc:description>
<dcterms:created>1995-08</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Appalachian Region, Southern -- Religious life and customs; Snake cults (Holiness churches) -- Appalachian Region, Southern</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Prince, Ulysses Grant</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Apostolic Church of God (Greeneville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dcterms:spatial>Greeneville (Tenn.)</dcterms:spatial>
<dc:type>Moving Image</dc:type>
<dc:type>field recordings</dc:type>
<dc:format>video/mp4</dc:format>
<dcterms:extent>01:54:29</dcterms:extent>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:identifier>MS-074-08-02</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>F-2</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Fatal bites, funerals, and wakes field records, 1985-1998</dc:source>
<dc:source>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson field recordings, interviews, and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Special Collections</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</dc:publisher>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson Holiness Churches of Appalachia recordings and interviews</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16877coll2/id/163</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>