<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Church of the Lord Jesus Christ service, 1997 November 22</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Video recording of a service opening with a call for prayer requests. Junior McCormick asks members to pray and several go forward to the pulpit to do so. Junior McCormick speaks briefly before singing. As he sings, the camera pans to the assembly and reveals only a small crowd. Junior McCormick preaches as Virgil Porter plays harmonica, and after a brief musical number, McCormick testifies before singing again. Virgil and Carl Porter alternatively join him in song. After their singing, Carl Porter preaches at length to the congregation. His sermon ends with a song  and is followed by testimony from members of the church. Junior McCormick testifies and as he does he takes a large serpent from its box and handles. Following his testimony, music begins again and Carl Porter lays hands on a congrigant and the two march together with raised hands to the beat. The man who received an imposition of hands speaks in tongues and dances to the music. </dc:description>
<dcterms:created>1997-11-22</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Appalachian Region, Southern -- Religious life and customs; Dance -- Religious aspects; Gifts, Spiritual; Glossolalia; Imposition of hands; Lay preaching; Pentecostal preaching; Prayer; Singing -- Religious aspects; Snake cults (Holiness churches) -- Appalachian Region, Southern; Witness bearing (Christianity)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>McCormick, Junior; Porter, Carl; Porter, Virgil</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Church of the Lord Jesus Christ (Kingston, Ga.)</dc:subject>
<dcterms:spatial>Kingston (Ga.)</dcterms:spatial>
<dc:type>Moving Image</dc:type>
<dc:type>field recordings</dc:type>
<dc:format>video/mp4</dc:format>
<dcterms:extent>01:27:12</dcterms:extent>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:identifier>MS-074-04-34</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>K-34</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Church of the Lord Jesus Christ recordings and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson field recordings, interviews, and photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>Special Collections</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</dc:publisher>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson Holiness Churches of Appalachia recordings and interviews</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>Hood, Ralph W.; Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16877coll2/id/108</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>