<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Letter from Andrew Jackson to John Overton, June 8, 1829</dc:title>
<dc:description>Six-page letter in which Jackson discussed with his good friend Overton several state, national, and personal issues: westward expansion, importance of Texas, Cherokee Removal, and the Bank of the United States. He commented on political luminaries of the day such as William Carroll, Felix Grundy, and John C. Calhoun. Of the Adams-Onis Treaty, he wrote that it  .must have been with the view to keep the political ascendancy in the North, and east, &amp; cripple the rising greatness of the west. The letter sheds much light on Jackson's position on the need, as he believed, for Indian removal from their native lands. Jackson appointed William Carroll as representative to the Cherokee and Creek Indians and counseled him to "give them my talk on the subject of their removal to the west of the Mississippi." He was "to use his influence in conjunction with the agent to enforce upon their minds the neccessity [sic] of their adopting this course, as the only means we have in preserving them as nations and of protecting them." The State of Georgia had extended their civil Jurisdiction over them, making it "desirable that the Indians should remove to a Territory over which no state has any right to the soil  The course pursued by Georgia is well calculated to involve her &amp; the United States in great dificulty [sic], unless the Indians can be got to move west of the M.  Jackson suggested a change in the incorporated Bank to that of a national bank, believing this to be the only way to prevent the U.S. Bank from rechartering. He continued with, "I believe this is the only thing that can prevent our liberties to be crushed by the Bank." Jackson briefly discussed Major John Eaton, telling Overton, "I can say with truth there never was a man more cruelly treated than Major Eaton, and by some of my friends." He expressed his unhappiness as president, disclosing that the only reason to continue is that "my country has required it and it is a duty I have to that country." He concluded by reaffirming two policies he wished to pursue: have the constitution amended to create a national bank and extend the western boundary. The President ended on a cheerless note about the next term's effects on his already fragile health. The thought gave him "serious forebodings that I shall not spend much of my time in this world on the silent walks of the Hermitage."</dc:description>
<dc:description>John Overton was Jackson's closest advisor and confidante. He often wrote to Overton, discussing Washington politics, local and national affairs, land speculation and gossip. As president, Jackson eyed the rich Indian lands in Georgia and North Carolina, and ordered tribal evacuation beyond the Mississippi River. The Indian Removal, which uprooted the Cherokee and Creek, remains a sensitive and controversial topic. Jackson was an early proponent of expanding western lands, and this letter illustrates his contempt for the "late Treaty with Spain," a reference to the Adams-Onis boundaries with Mexico.  Although the Adams-Onis Treaty (1819) secured U.S. acquisition of Florida and protected New Orleans, it limited American expansion into Texas and beyond. Jackson believed the treaty favored Northern interests and suffocated the South's hope to extend its western boundaries. </dc:description>
<dc:date>1829 June 8</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845</dc:creator>
<dc:coverage>Washington (D.C.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>Jacob McGavock Dickinson Papers, 1812-1946</dc:source>
<dcterms:references>http://sos.tn.gov/products/tsla/dickinson-jacob-mcgavock-papers-1812-1946</dcterms:references>
<dc:subject>Nullifcation (states' rights); Indian removal; Spain. Treaties, etc. United States, 1819 February 22</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>43090</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Andrew Jackson Collection;</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dcterms:medium>Correspondence</dcterms:medium>
<dc:rights>No copyright - United States: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll33/id/144</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>