<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Letter from Daniel S. Donelson to Andrew Jackson Donelson, October 31, 1831</dc:title>
<dc:description>Brigadier General Daniel S. Donelson wrote to his brother, Andrew Jackson Donelson, regarding the Eaton Affair. Donelson reported that "Eaton and his wife arrived at this place on Monday last.  He stated that "the wives of the office holders and members have and are giving in their adherence." He knew "of but one exception to their rule of action that of McLane." He informed his brother that a dinner was held for the "redoubtable Major," the previous Saturday. He claimed that "the president was so completely identified with Eaton that a refusal to pay him attention would be assuming a hostile attitude to the president himself." Daniel Donelson believed that the American people misunderstood the "unpleasant affair." He concluded that the letter had been written in "great haste. </dc:description>
<dc:description>The Eaton Affair, also known as the Petticoat Affair, was a political scandal involving Jackson's cabinet Jackson's Secretary of War, John Eaton, and his new wife. The cabinet members and their wives, led by the Vice-President's wife Floride Calhoun, spurned Eaton and his wife, Peggy, over the morality of their marriage. This led to the resignation of nearly all of Jackson's cabinet and the rise of Martin Van Buren, who defended the Eatons. </dc:description>
<dc:date>1831 October 31</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Donelson, Daniel S.</dc:creator>
<dc:coverage>Nashville (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>Dyas Collection of John Coffee Papers</dc:source>
<dcterms:references>http://sos.tn.gov/products/tsla/dyas-collection-john-coffee-papers-1770-1917</dcterms:references>
<dc:subject>Eaton, John Henry, 1790-1856</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Correspondence</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>43051</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>THS II-A-3. Box 15, Folder 11</dc:source>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Andrew Jackson Collection;</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dcterms:medium>Correspondence</dcterms:medium>
<dc:rights>No copyright - United States: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll33/id/154</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>