<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>General Edward Pakenham's order for the Battle of New Orleans</dc:title>
<dc:description>Though not signed, presumed to be British General Edward Pakenham's orders for the Battle of New Orleans, "captured from him." These instructions appear to relate to the left side of the British assault ("Maj. Genl. Keane's left"  Pakenham explained that "This flank battn[battalion] will carry the action on the batary[sic] on the right of the enemy's line. " He continued, "When the position is correct the flank battn. to press the enemy's rear 1/2 a mile." Verso reads "British plans of carrying the American breastwork near New Orleans. Jan 8th, 1815." This document was found among the Tennessee General Assembly's legislative records and hence may have been given by a Tennessee officer to the legislature as a trophy from the battle. Not likely to have been taken from the mortally wounded Packenham, who was carried off the field to a place behind British lines, it may have taken off the body of one of his officers or simply picked up from the battlefield.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The primary Battle of New Orleans took place on January 8, 1815, the culmination of 17 days of engagement between American and British troops south of New Orleans. Under cover of artillery fire, the British launched a two-pronged attack on the American breastworks at the Rodriquez Canal on the morning of January 8. One, led by Colonel William Thornton on the west bank of the Mississippi River, attempted to distract from the main assault, but a collapsed dam and heavy mud, held it up. The main force, led by Major General Samuel Gibbs, marched toward the center of the fortifications, held by Major General William Carroll, hidden by a dense fog. As they neared the defenses, the fog lifted exposing them to heavy artillery fire, which, along with forgetting to bring the ladders and fascines to cross the canal, decimated the British advance. Major General John Keane led a small detachment to assist the assault but was wounded while crossing the battlefield. Colonel Rennie and most other senior officers, as well as a large number of their troops, were killed in the initial attack. Major General Edward Pakenham, the commander of the entire British force, led a second wave, which collapsed when both Pakenham and Gibbs received fatal wounds by grapeshot. Major Wilkinson led a third and final assault on the breastworks, but was wounded when he made it to the American line. The remainder of the British force, primarily reserves commanded by Major General John Lambert, retreated toward camp. Thornton's delayed attack on the west bank was initially successful, but the lack of support left these achievements unrealized. Adjutant General Robert Butler reported to Jackson that the British sustained 700 killed, 1400 wounded, and 500 taken prisoner; however, the United States Army Center for Military History today states 285 killed, 1,265 wounded, and 484 captured or missing. The American suffered only 13 dead, 30 wounded, and 19 captured or missing. This one-sided victory cemented Andrew Jackson's reputation as a war hero and thrust him into the national spotlight.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1815 January</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>New Orleans (La.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>RG 60: Legislative Records</dc:source>
<dcterms:instructionalMethod>2.36; 4.49; 8.43; War of 1812; Growth of the Republic</dcterms:instructionalMethod>
<dc:subject>Pakenham, Edward Michael, 1778-1815; New Orleans, Battle of, New Orleans, La., 1815</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Campaigns &amp; Battles </dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>43088</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>RG 60, Miscellaneous Reports, Oversize Box</dc:source>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Andrew Jackson Collection;</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dcterms:medium>Military records</dcterms:medium>
<dc:rights>No copyright - United States: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll33/id/334</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>