<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Letter from Andrew Jackson to Robert I. Chester, November 7, 1830</dc:title>
<dc:description>Jackson responded to Chester's letter of October 25. He stated that "no complaints here of General Purdy" and that he had not heard if Purdy planned to resign. Jackson promised Chester that his "enemy" would not be appointed. He mentioned that one of his slaves, Charlotte, requested that Chester purchase her. Jackson explained that he first purchased Charlotte at the request of her husband Charles, but now "he appears desirous that she with her children be sold." He discussed a "great reduction of hands on [his] plantation" due to deaths in 1829. The remainder of the letter discussed the payment for Charlotte and her three children. He concluded with a mention of appointed S. D. Hays as surveyor, but that it might be opposed in the Senate, even with [David] Crockett and [Robert] Desha representing him. </dc:description>
<dc:description>Robert I. Chester was born in Pennsylvania, but grew up in Jonesboro, Tennessee. He served as quartermaster of the 3rd Tennessee regiment during the War of 1812. After the war, he became a merchant and surveyor in Carthage, until he moved to Jackson where he became postmaster. Sam Houston appointed him colonel in the Texas Revolutionary Army, but returned to Jackson by 1836. President Martin Van Buren appointed Chester U. S. Marshal for the western district, and served until the Civil War. After the war, Chester was elected to the Tennessee House of Representatives from 1869 to 1873.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1830 November 7</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845</dc:creator>
<dc:coverage>Washington (D.C.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>THS T-100</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Slavery--United States</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Correspondence</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>43046</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>IX-A-3v Box J-1, 44J</dc:source>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Andrew Jackson Collection;</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dcterms:medium>Correspondence</dcterms:medium>
<dc:rights>No copyright - United States: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll33/id/178</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>