<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>A sketch of the Battle of Talladega</dc:title>
<dc:description>Map of the Battle of Talladega from John Eaton's The Life of Andrew Jackson, Major-General in the Service of the United States. It shows the hilltop fort of the "friendly Creeks" who were besieged by "hostile Creeks" or Red Sticks during the Creek War. Jackson's army is shown surrounding the hostile Creeks and divided into units of infantry, cavalry, and mounted gunmen.</dc:description>
<dc:description>General John Coffee's victory at the Battle of Tallushatchee left 154 friendly Creek surrounded at Fort Leslie near Talladega, Alabama. One Creek warrior draped himself in a hog skin and sneaked by the besieging Red Sticks to warn Jackson of their dire situation. Major General Andrew Jackson marched 2000 Tennessee militia from Fort Strother to lift the siege. On November 9, 1813, Jackson's militia surrounded the attackers, killing 300 enemy warriors while sustaining only 15 dead. They successfully broke the siege, but their encirclement failed and the bulk of the Red Sticks escaped.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1817</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>Talladega (Ala.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>Grille Books</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845; Coffee, John, 1772-1833; Creek War, 1813-1814;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Maps; Campaigns &amp; battles</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>43111</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>E 382 .E11</dc:source>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Andrew Jackson Collection; Maps at the Tennessee State Library and Archives;</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:type>Still Image</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dcterms:medium>Drawings; Maps</dcterms:medium>
<dc:rights>No copyright - United States: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll33/id/281</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>