<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Letter from James Buchanan to W. Hugh Hamilton, December 14, 1823</dc:title>
<dc:description>Letter from Pennsylvania congressman James Buchanan to his friend and newspaper editor Hugh Hamilton regarding the 1824 presidential election. Buchanan revealed that William Crawford's supporters wanted to hold a Congressional caucus, and that "all other candidates are opposed to the measure." Buchanan gave his opinion on Jackson as a "mild, frank, and polished" individual. He called him "a real and not a nominal candidate," going so far as to call him the "candidate of Pennsylvania." Buchanan implored his friend not to disrespect Jackson in his publication, and urged him to back Jackson's candidacy. A "strictly confidential" postscript mentioned that a Tennessee legislator planned to oppose the Congressional caucus. </dc:description>
<dc:description>The 1824 presidential election was a fierce contest. Four frontrunners, Henry Clay, William Crawford, John Quincy Adams, and Andrew Jackson, were identified as early as a year before the election. The results were highly regional; each candidate won his home state. Jackson received the most popular votes but failed to win a majority of electoral votes so the choice fell to the House of Representatives. Clay threw his support behind Adams, who ultimately won. Adams then appointed Clay as Secretary of State which infuriated Jackson and his supports who deemed it the "corrupt bargain." James Buchanan served as a member of the United States House of Representatives from Pennsylvania at the time of this letter and Hugh Hamilton was editor of the Harrisburg Chronicle. Jackson as president later appointed Buchanan as Minister to Russia.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1823 December 14</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Buchanan, James, 1791-1868</dc:creator>
<dc:coverage>Washington (D.C.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>Sir Emil Hurja Collection</dc:source>
<dcterms:references>http://sos.tn.gov/products/tsla/hurja-sir-emil-collection-1793-1953</dcterms:references>
<dc:source>THS 9</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Presidential elections--1820-1830; Election campaigns</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>42966</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>THS I-C-2, Box 6 Folder 10</dc:source>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Andrew Jackson Collection;</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dcterms:medium>Correspondence</dcterms:medium>
<dc:rights>No copyright - United States: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll33/id/68</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>