<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Letter from Santa Anna to Andrew Jackson, April 19, 1843 </dc:title>
<dc:description>Letter (and translation) from Mexican Presidente Santa Anna to American President Andrew Jackson, written just weeks after the Black Bean Episode, in which Santa Anna had ordered the execution of 17 captured Texans. The letter began discussing prisoner exchange, specifically George Crittenden. Santa Anna rebuked Texan forays into Mexican territory. He then discussed the prisoner escape that occurred on February 11, 1843, and denounced the actions of the escapees. He went on to justify the execution of the prisoners and stated that it "avoided butchery [evitardo asi los horrores de una carniceria]" and that "nobody [could] dispute to Mexico the legality of the acts [nadie podr&#225; disputar &#225; la megicana la legalidad de ecta providencia.]." On the final page, Jackson asked for a translation. The original letter is written on elaborate letterhead of the Presidente de la Republica.</dc:description>
<dc:description>After the Treaties of Velasco and the cession of the Texas territory, Mexicans continued to raid the border in an attempt to regain control. In 1842, Alexander Somervell led an expedition of 700 men to recapture these border towns. The Mier Expedition, a small operation within the greater Somervell Expedition, involved 308 Texan militia who ignored orders to return home. They successfully captured Ciudad Mier, but encountered a Mexican detachment, 3,000 strong, five days later. Outnumbered tenfold, the Texans left 650 dead and 200 wounded but were ultimately overwhelmed and the remaining 243 Texans were taken prisoner. On February 11, 181 prisoners escaped as they marched toward Mexico City, but due to the inhospitable surroundings, most were recaptured. A furious Santa Anna ordered the execution of all escapees. This led to the Black Bean Episode, where the Mexican captors placed 176 white beans and seventeen black beans into a pot and ordered the Texans to draw beans. All seventeen who drew black beans were executed by firing squad.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1843</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Santa Anna, Antonio L&#243;pez de, 1794?-1876</dc:creator>
<dc:source>Andrew Jackson Collection, 1788-1942</dc:source>
<dcterms:references>http://sos.tn.gov/products/tsla/andrew-jackson-collection-1788-1942</dcterms:references>
<dc:source>3, 79-048</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Jackson, Andrew, 1776-1845; Texan Mier Expedition (1842-1844)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Correspondence</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>43022</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>VI-A-5, Box 3, Folder 3</dc:source>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Andrew Jackson Collection;</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dcterms:medium>Correspondence</dcterms:medium>
<dc:rights>No copyright - United States: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll33/id/131</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>