<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Letter from Andrew Jackson to John Coffee, June 21, 1817, concerning treaty-making with the Cherokee</dc:title>
<dc:description>Jackson reported that he reached "Highwassee" on the 11th when he heard the Col. [Return J.] Meiggs [Meigs] had changed the meeting place to the Cherokee Agency. He met with the Cherokee delegation the prior day, and they had "expressed great anxiety for an exchange of territory." Jackson was respected by native Americans in such treaty negotiations, and he considered himself a man of liberal sentiments concerning their situation. He expressed sympathy for how the Cherokee were being exploited, saying that "a few white men and half breeds...have and are still fattening on the annuities of the nation and the labour of the poor Indians." Jackson stated that General David Meriwether accompanied him and he had "no doubt" that they would "obtain half if not all the territory here for lands on the Arkansaw." Jackson concluded with business and land dealings between the two men, specifically the sale of land in Alabama. </dc:description>
<dc:description>Andrew Jackson, Joseph McMinn, and David Meriwether served as commissioners for the Cherokee Treaty of 1817. This document was written in the negotiation phase of the treaty, just 6 months before ratification. The treaty recognized the division between Upper and Lower Cherokee as well as arranged an exchange of lands in East Tennessee for land in Arkansas Territory. It also began the process of voluntary emigration to the Arkansas Territory, the first phase of large scale Indian removal, which was overseen by Joseph McMinn. It provided 640 acre reservations for those heads of family that wished to remain east of the Mississippi and become U.S. citizens. This treaty was signed, but disputed by the Cherokee until the Cherokee Treaty of 1819.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1817 June 21</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845</dc:creator>
<dc:coverage>Tennessee</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>Dyas Collection of John Coffee Papers</dc:source>
<dcterms:references>http://sos.tn.gov/products/tsla/dyas-collection-john-coffee-papers-1770-1917</dcterms:references>
<dc:subject>Coffee, John, 1772-1833; Meriwether, David, 1755-1822; Cherokee Indians--Treaties</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Correspondence</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>43047</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>THS II-A-2. Box 8, Folder 33</dc:source>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Andrew Jackson Collection;</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dcterms:medium>Correspondence</dcterms:medium>
<dc:rights>No copyright - United States: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll33/id/135</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>