<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Letter from Felix Grundy to Andrew Jackson, May 6, 1833</dc:title>
<dc:description>Senator Felix Grundy wrote President Andrew Jackson regarding Grundy's opposition to nullification and South Carolina's threat to secede. The letter includes a copy of Jackson's response of May 13. Jackson congratulated Grundy that his conduct "in opposition to the absurd and wicked doctrine of nullification" had been "highly useful and energetic."</dc:description>
<dc:description>The Nullification Crisis was a confrontation between the federal government and South Carolina over tariffs, South Carolina's perceived rights, and the threat of secession. It began with the passage of the Tariff of 1828, referred to by the South Carolinians as the "Tariff of Abominations." They argued that the tariff protected manufacturing rather than agriculture. Jackson's election as president was expected to ease the tensions, but Jackson refused to lower the tariff until national debts were repaid. After the passage of the Tariff of 1832,  Jackson issued the Proclamation to the People of South Carolina denouncing the nullification doctrine. In the following session, the Force Bill was introduced to Congress, which authorized the use of force to ensure that South Carolina would comply with federal tariffs. This led to the introduction of the Compromise Tariff of 1833. The passage of these two bills eased the rising tensions and ultimately ended the crisis.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1833 May 6</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Grundy, Felix, 1777-1840 ; Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845</dc:creator>
<dc:coverage>Nashville (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>THS T-100</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Nullification (States' rights); Tariff</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>43198</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>IX-A-2v Box G-1, 86 G</dc:source>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Andrew Jackson Collection;</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dcterms:medium>Correspondence</dcterms:medium>
<dc:rights>No copyright - United States: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll33/id/307</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>