<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>An account of some of the bloody deeds of General Andrew Jackson</dc:title>
<dc:description>One of the published 'coffin broadsides' used to attack Jackson during the electoral campaign of 1828. This particular broadside is unique in that it depicts the executions rather than just the coffins. An engraving of the executions of six Tennessee militiamen accused of mutiny during the Creek War is located at the center top. The execution of John Woods by firing squad is depicted to the left. An attack on Jackson's conduct during the Battle of Horseshoe Bend is located in the very center. Jackson's deadly duel with Charles Dickinson is recounted in the bottom right, and his fracas with Thomas Hart Benton and his brother, Jesse, in the bottom left. As the title implies, the overall message of this political campaign document was that Jackson is a violent, intemperate man prone to "bloody deeds. </dc:description>
<dc:description>The election of 1828 was one of the most contentious and unscrupulous of the 19th century. Many published attacks on Jackson's character and supposed misdeeds circulated the country. Jackson's supporters denounced John Quincy Adams for promising the Secretary of State position to Henry Clay in return for his support in the 1824 election. Jackson prevailed four years later, winning 56% of the popular vote.</dc:description>
<dc:date>approximately 1828</dc:date>
<dc:source>Sir Emil Hurja Collection</dc:source>
<dcterms:references>http://sos.tn.gov/products/tsla/hurja-sir-emil-collection-1793-1953</dcterms:references>
<dc:source>THS 9</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Broadsides; Presidential elections </dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>42922</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>THS I-C-2, Box 10 Folder 1, #6</dc:source>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Andrew Jackson Collection;</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:type>Still Image</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dcterms:medium>Broadsides</dcterms:medium>
<dc:rights>No copyright - United States: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll33/id/257</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>