<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>King Andrew the First</dc:title>
<dc:description>Political cartoon depicting Andrew Jackson as a despotic monarch. He tramples on the Constitution and the coat of arms of Pennsylvania, the location of the United States Bank. A book titled the Judiciary of the United States appears to be thrown aside. In his hand Jackson holds a veto, referring to Jackson's veto of the Bank's rechartering. The text links him with William IV, the reigning monarch of the United Kingdom. A classic of Jacksonian era political propaganda, this broadside illustrates the popular sentiments ("Shall he reign over us, or shall the PEOPLE RULE?") that led to the formation of the anti-Jackson Whig Party in Jackson's own backyard.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Jackson's veto of the re-charter of the Bank of the United States was perhaps his most controversial. The bank's recharter passed Congress on July 3, 1832 , which Jackson vetoed on July 10. With his veto, Jackson delivered an address to Congress, that outlined his views on the bank as part of the executive branch, and therefore subject to his orders. On July 13, the veto was sustained as the senate was unable to produce enough votes to override. The bank became an important topic in the 1832 campaign, but Jackson's supporters were able to successfully steer the debate to a decision between Jackson and "the people" against Nicholas Biddle, the bank, and "the aristocracy." After the removal of federal deposits from the Bank, Congress censured Jackson for violating the Constitution. The bank's charter officially expired in 1836.</dc:description>
<dc:date>approximately 1832</dc:date>
<dc:source>Sir Emil Hurja Collection</dc:source>
<dcterms:references>http://sos.tn.gov/products/tsla/hurja-sir-emil-collection-1793-1953</dcterms:references>
<dc:source>THS 9</dc:source>
<dcterms:instructionalMethod>4.55; 8.55; Andrew Jackson; Growth of the Republic</dcterms:instructionalMethod>
<dc:subject>Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845; Bank of the United States--1830-1840; Economic policy--1830-1840; United States--Constitution--1830-1840</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Political cartoons; Broadsides; Constitutions; Books; Vetoes; Propaganda</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>43194</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>THS I-C-2, Box 10</dc:source>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Andrew Jackson Collection;</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:type>Still Image</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dcterms:medium>Cartoons; Political cartoons</dcterms:medium>
<dc:rights>No copyright - United States: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll33/id/289</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>