<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Notes on the New Building</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <identifier>CS3126.2</identifier>
  <location>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://cdm15916.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15916coll1/id/154</url>
    <url access="preview">http://cdm15916.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p15916coll1/id/154</url>
  </location>
  <abstract>When planning the new Christian Brothers College Building for East Parkway, it was noted that: a three story building was all right if there would be an elevator (Unfortunately, there were three floors but no elevator when the building was completed); two bathtubs with flanged edges were needed; there should be independent single light switches in addition to the main corridor lights; toilet and bathroom doors should come within two inches of the floor; the cook stove should be in the center of the kitchen, facing the water supply; provision should be made for roller paper in the restrooms, not box paper; and a cellar under the storeroom would be nice to have as a cool place to store vegetables.</abstract>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated>ca. 1939</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <subject>
    <geographic>East Parkway, Memphis, TN</geographic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Buildings</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Educational Facilities</topic>
  </subject>
  <physicalDescription>
    <form>typewritten memorandum</form>
  </physicalDescription>
  <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Christian Brothers University</recordContentSource>
  </recordInfo>
  <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/">Copyright Not Evaluated</accessCondition>
  <accessCondition type="local rights statement">While CBU may house an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use. Any image from the library's collection must cite as the source: Brother I. Leo O'Donnell Archives, Plough Library, Christian Brothers University. For all requests, please contact the Archives at archives@cbu.edu.</accessCondition>
</mods>
