<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Photograph of Bishop Keith in front of Chattanooga Home, 1950s</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <identifier>Chnash_032</identifier>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated>195-</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <physicalDescription>
    <internetMediaType>image/jpeg</internetMediaType>
    <form>still image</form>
    <form>photographs</form>
  </physicalDescription>
  <location>
    <physicalLocation>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</physicalLocation>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll23/id/431</url>
    <url access="preview">http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p15769coll23/id/431</url>
  </location>
  <abstract>A black and white photograph of Bishop Keith standing in front of a brick house with two young girls seated beside her. The three are in the far right corner of the photograph and wear dark colored clothing. This is likely the House of God Children's Home founded and operated by Bishop Keith outside Chattanooga. Children lived here in the dorms and attended school, based on grade, at either the Keith Bible Institute in Summit or Booker T. Washington High School. It later became an all girls' dorm with two girls to a room or as many as four per room. Time was very structured: students went to school during the day time, bible school four nights a week, Friday night church service, and Sunday school service. Parents were allowed to visit. Dr. Mary F. L. Keith (unknown -1962) succeeded Mother Mary Magdalena Lewis Tate as the second Chief Overseer of the House of God Church in 1931. She was an educator and philanthropist and under her administration the House of God Church greatly enhanced its social services and programs; expanded its real estate holdings; and increased membership. Under her direction, the church printed the First Universal Sunday School Lessons, and founded the Keith Bible Institute; the House of God Home for Children in East Chattanooga, Tennessee; and the House of God Home. She died on July 14, 1962 in Chattanooga, Tennessee. The House of God, Which is the Church of the Living God, the Pillar and Ground of the Truth Without Controversy, Inc. was founded by Mother Mary Magdalena Lewis Tate with the help of Bishop Keith, her secretary who would go on to be the second leader of the church after Mother Tate died. Mother Tate incorporated the church in 1908. After her death in 1930, the church split into three dominions, Jewell, Keith, and Lewis Dominions. The church took on the name House of God Church Keith Dominion at this point, named after Bishop Keith. It is headquartered in Nashville, Tennessee.</abstract>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Collection">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Generations - African American Women's Early Activism in Tennessee</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <accessCondition type="local rights statement">U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782</accessCondition>
  <subject>
    <topic>Keith, Mary F. L., Bishop, -1962</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Church of the Living God, the Pillar and Ground of the Truth</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Women in church work--Tennessee--Chattanooga</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Women and religion--Tennessee--Chattanooga</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>African Americans--Women--Tennessee--Chattanooga</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Evangelists--Tennessee--Chattanooga</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>African Americans--Education--Tennessee-Chattanooga</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Church and education--Tennessee--Chattanooga</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Buildings--Tennessee--Chattanooga</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Schools--Tennessee--Chattanooga</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Silverdale (Tenn.)</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <temporal encoding="edtf">1950/1959</temporal>
  </subject>
  <genre authority="aat" valueURI="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300264387">images (object genre)</genre>
  <genre authority="aat" valueURI="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300046300">photographs</genre>
  <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Project">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Nashville Public Library Digital Collection</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <location>
      <url>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/landingpage/collection/nr</url>
    </location>
  </relatedItem>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Nashville Public Library</recordContentSource>
    <recordChangeDate>2023-05-09-04:00</recordChangeDate>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
    <recordOrigin>Record has been transformed into MODS 3.5 from a qualified Dublin Core record by the Digital Library of Tennessee, a service hub of the Digital Public Library of America, using a stylesheet available at https://github.com/utkdigitalinitiatives/DLTN. Metadata originally created in a locally modified version of qualified Dublin Core using ContentDM (data dictionary available: https://wiki.lib.utk.edu/display/DPLA.)</recordOrigin>
  </recordInfo>
</mods>
