<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>"At 67, The King Of Clarinet Is Still Swinging"</dc:title>
<dc:subject>Goodman, Benny; jazz; music; 1970s;</dc:subject>
<dc:description>&#8220;With a clarinet at his side, the musical score on his lap and his fans peeping through the dressing room door, Benny Goodman prepares for his concert &#8211; one of &#8216;thousands and thousands&#8217; he has given during his life. -- But the &#8216;King of Swing,&#8217; famed for his bands and his jazz and the sounds that have come from his clarinet for the past 40 years, said that each audience is a new challenge. -- &#8217;I&#8217;m still breaking my leg,&#8217; each time on stage, he said.  &#8216;It&#8217;s still show business.&#8217; -- And since Goodman is a living legend of sorts, known to music lovers as the subject of 1955&#8217;s &#8216;The Benny Goodman Story,&#8217; he also has to put up with the little interferences that come with being a star. -- As he enters the concert hall, he is stopped for his autograph.  As he studies and sings the music for the performance, admirers poke their heads into his dressing room.  Before he has a chance to warm up his clarinet, his lips and his stomach, he finds himself in another interview &#8211; also one of thousands and thousands he has given during his life&#8230;.&#8221;</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Barrett, Katherine</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Commercial Appeal</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Frierson, S.</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1976-09-18</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>newspaper clipping, mounted, 7 x 5 in.</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Memphis - Visitors - Goodman, Benny, 1976</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>Jazz023.jpg</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>The M Files</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>Jazz</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>Memphis Information File</dc:source>
<dc:source>Memphis &amp; Shelby County Room, MPLIC</dc:source>
<dc:rights>Digital Image &#169;2010, Memphis Public Library &amp; Information Center.  All rights reserved. While the Memphis Public Library &amp; Information Center may house an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use. Any image from the library's collection published in any form must cite as the source: Memphis and Shelby County Room, Memphis Public Library &amp; Information Center.  For all requests, please contact the History Department at 901.415.2742 or hisref@memphistn.gov.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16108.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p13039coll5/id/246</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>