<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>"Nursing Profession Short Of Facilities, Funds"</dc:title>
<dc:subject>medicine; nursing; women; 1960s;</dc:subject>
<dc:description>"...Despite the many attractions, not enough young girls are entering the profession.  Shortage of hospital nurses with an R.N. (licensed as a registered nurse) has been a chronic ailment here and throughout the country a long time.  Now the problem is fast becoming acute.  It is most felt at the actual bedside of the patient. -- Last month, the Nurses' Official Registry received 1,406 calls from Memphis hospitals for registered nurses.  The registry was able to fill only 970.  Throughout the year, and average of 308 calls went unfilled each month..."</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Clemens, Ida</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Commercial Appeal</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Frierson, S.</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1960-01-25</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>newspaper clipping, mounted, 7 x 9.75 in.</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Memphis - Nurses and nursing</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>CTFM030.jpg</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>The M Files</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>Women in Medicine</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>Memphis Information File</dc:source>
<dc:source>Memphis &amp; Shelby County Room, MPLIC</dc:source>
<dc:rights>Digital Image &#169;2010, Memphis Public Library &amp; Information Center.  All rights reserved.  While the Memphis Public Library &amp; Information Center may house an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use. Any image from the library's collection published in any form must cite as the source: Memphis and Shelby County Room, Memphis Public Library &amp; Information Center.  For all requests, please contact the History Department at 901.415.2742 or hisref@memphistn.gov.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16108.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p13039coll5/id/203</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>