<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Memoirs of John William McAfee, Sr. 1915-2001</dc:title>
<dc:subject>civil rights; film; media; news;</dc:subject>
<dc:description>John William &#8216;Bill&#8217; McAfee, Sr. began his career in film as an assistant projectionist during the silent movie era and remained active through the medium&#8217;s various transformations.  He played an interesting part in socio-history by screening films for Boss Crump&#8217;s chief censor, Lloyd T. Binford, and Elvis Presley.  As a Navy serviceman, he secretly filmed Japanese beachheads for Marine Invasions.  As a news cameraman, he worked with correspondents such as Dan Rather, Tom Jerrard, Don Farmer and Peter Jennings and interviewed and documented everything from W.C. Handy to the Civil Rights Movement.  He also worked on motion pictures, most notably MGM&#8217;s Intruder in the Dust, where he enjoyed hanging out with William Faulkner.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>McAfee, John William</dc:creator>
<dc:contributor>Jasmine Holland</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>2003</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>manuscript, 8.5 x 11 in., 97 pages</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>070.195092 M113x</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>LFA001</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>The M Files</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Memphis &amp; Shelby County Room, MPLIC</dc:source>
<dc:rights>Digital Image &#169;2013, Memphis Public Library &amp; Information Center.  All rights reserved.  While the Memphis Public Library &amp; Information Center may house an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use. Any image from the library's collection published in any form must cite as the source: Memphis and Shelby County Room, Memphis Public Library &amp; Information Center.  For all requests, please contact the History Department at 901.415.2742 or hisref@memphistn.gov.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16108.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p13039coll5/id/1885</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>