<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>"Hirt may horn in on new home"</dc:title>
<dc:subject>Beale Street; Hirt, Al; jazz; Morris, William "Bill"; music; 1980s;</dc:subject>
<dc:description>"Al Hirt, famed jazz trumpeter, will be in Memphis next week as a guest of Shelby County Mayor Bill Morris to investigate a possible permanent move here, Morris said. -- Hirt, who lived in Memphis in the 1940s, will visit the city Thursday through Saturday with an eye toward possibly using Memphis as a base for his performances. -- Morris said he was courting 'some degree of permanency' for Hirt in Memphis.  Hirt recently shut down his famous nightclub in New Orleans' French Quarter, complaining of crime and other problems in the area. -- 'Al likes Memphis real well,' Morris said. 'He's going to take a look at some of the things that are happening here.  We're going to show him the flavor, the example of great Memphis hospitality.' -- Some of that hospitality probably will include a visit to the Beale Street redevelopment project, which already has received commitments from entertainers Lou Rawls and Charlie Rich to open clubs there.  Morris said Hirt and his party may visit The Peabody and a private home during their stay. -- Morris said hirt would be a 'great addition' to the Peabody's Skyway Room as a performer a few nights a week.  Eventually, Morris said, he would like to see a national radio broadcast coming from the Skyway, similar to the one done during the big-band era. -- 'Al Hirt's name is known throughout the country,' Morris said. 'It could become a catalyst.'..."</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Bloom, David</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Memphis Press-Scimitar</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Frierson, S.</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1983-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>newspaper clipping, mounted, 10.25 x 4.75 in.</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Memphis - Visitors - Hirt, Al, 1983</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>Jazz038.jpg</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>The M Files</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>Jazz</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>Memphis Information File</dc:source>
<dc:source>Memphis &amp; Shelby County Room, MPLIC</dc:source>
<dc:rights>Digital Image &#169;2010, Memphis Public Library &amp; Information Center.  All rights reserved.  While the Memphis Public Library &amp; Information Center may house an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use. Any image from the library's collection published in any form must cite as the source: Memphis and Shelby County Room, Memphis Public Library &amp; Information Center.  For all requests, please contact the History Department at 901.415.2742 or hisref@memphistn.gov.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16108.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p13039coll5/id/265</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>