<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Count Magri, Lavinia Warren and Baron Magri</dc:title>
<dc:subject>Warren, Lavinia; Magri, Primo; portraits;</dc:subject>
<dc:description>A portrait of three little people in formal dress. Based on the time period it seems likely that the photo&#8217;s subjects are Lavinia Warren, Count Primo Magri, and Baron Magri. Lavinia Warren was a famous circus performer who became one of the most well-known figures of the period when she married Charles Sherwood Stratton, also known as General Tom Thumb. Count Primo Magri was her second husband.</dc:description>
<dc:publisher>Eisenmann</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Collection donated by June Beasley Mann; Collection processed by Laura Fogarty</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Laura Fogarty</dc:contributor>
<dc:type>Image</dc:type>
<dc:format>sepia-toned photo, 4.5 x 6.5 in.</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Box 2, Folder 2</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>Laura004</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>The M Files</dc:relation>
<dc:source>The J. B. Mann Suffrage Collection</dc:source>
<dc:source>Memphis &amp; Shelby County Room, MPLIC</dc:source>
<dc:rights>Digital Image &#169;2012, Memphis Public Library &amp; Information Center. All rights reserved.  e Memphis Public Library &amp; Information Center may house an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use. Any image from the library's collection, published in any form, must cite as the source: Memphis and Shelby County Room, Memphis Public Library &amp; Information Center. For all requests, please contact the History Department at 901.415.2742 or hisref@memphistn.gov.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16108.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p13039coll5/id/1006</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>