<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>"Jazz Festival Lists Stellar Lineup"</dc:title>
<dc:subject>Cole, Natalie; Gladys Knight and the Pips; Green, Al; jazz; Kool Jazz Festival; Mighty Clouds of Joy; music; Roy Ayers Ubiquity; Sylvers, the; Temptations, the; 1970s;</dc:subject>
<dc:description>&#8220;Al Green, Natalie Cole, the Sylvers, the Mighty Clouds of Joy, Gladys Knight and the Pips, the Temptations and Roy Ayers Ubiquity were announced yesterday as the lineup for the Kool Jazz Festival July 8-9 in the Mid-South Coliseum. -- The announcement was made at a press conference by Dino Santangelo of Festival Productions, Inc., the company set up by internationally known promoter George Wein, whose many other festivals include the Newport Jazz Festival.  The Memphis event is one of 13 Kool Jazz Festivals being put on this year, up from the nine shows that attracted 650,000 people last year, Santangelo said. -- Green, Ms. Cole, the Sylvers and the Mighty Clouds of Joy will hold the stage for the first night of the event, with Ms. Knight and the Pips, the Temptations and Roy Ayers Ubiquity closing it out the next evening. -- The two concerts mark the first time Wein has brought a festival event into Memphis since 1969.  Santangelo said Wein decided to bring the Kool festival to Memphis this year because the records showed that about 5,000 Memphians attended last year&#8217;s Atlanta festival, &#8216;which made us think that there was a bigger market in Memphis for what we&#8217;re doing than we had thought.&#8217; -- Also, he hinted that a 1978 festival is in the works for Liberty Bowl Memorial Stadium. &#8216;Next year we may surprise you by going to larger facilities here in Memphis, because, as you know, most of our festivals are held in stadiums.&#8217; -- The Kool Jazz Festivals are subsidized by manufacturers of Kool cigarets in return for the use of the product&#8217;s name, and the cigarette company and Festival Productions also make cash grants to community organizations in each city in which the festival plays. -- Tickets to the Memphis concerts are available by mail order from the coliseum.  Over-the-counter sales will begin June 1.  A free brochure describing festival details is available by writing Memphis Kool Jazz Festival, P.O. Box 911, Memphis 38101.&#8221;</dc:description>
<dc:publisher>Commercial Appeal</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Frierson, S.</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1977-03-03</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>newspaper clipping, mounted, 6.5 x 3.5 in.</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Memphis - Kool Jazz Festival, 1977</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>Jazz025.jpg</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>The M Files</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>Jazz</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>Memphis Information File</dc:source>
<dc:source>Memphis &amp; Shelby County Room, MPLIC</dc:source>
<dc:rights>Digital Image &#169;2010, Memphis Public Library &amp; Information Center.  All rights reserved.  While the Memphis Public Library &amp; Information Center may house an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use. Any image from the library's collection published in any form must cite as the source: Memphis and Shelby County Room, Memphis Public Library &amp; Information Center.  For all requests, please contact the History Department at 901.415.2742 or hisref@memphistn.gov.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16108.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p13039coll5/id/248</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>