<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Woman with child</dc:title>
<dc:description>African American woman gently places her hand on a child's head. Both are cleanly dressed but barefoot. The woman wears a long dress with vertical stripes, and the little girl wears a smock-like dress. The child is smiling broadly and is standing behind her toy high chair. The woman's expression seems to reflect a hard life of poverty. Rocks and pebbles are strewn on the ground.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The South was the poorest part of the nation in the decades following the Civil War. Blacks and poor whites struggled with debt, low cotton prices, and laws favorable to employers and creditors. In rural areas sharecropping became the dominant labor system for African Americans and many destitute whites.In this system, planters made contracts (favorable to themselves) with families so they could farm small plots of land. At season's end, sharecroppers gave a portion of their harvest to the planters. After poor harvests, sharecroppers needed borrow money from the planters to buy seed. This kept them in eternal debt. (From the "Encyclopedia of the United States in the Nineteenth Century" 2011)</dc:description>
<dc:date>approximately 1900-1912</dc:date>
<dc:source>Earl S. Miers River Photograph Collection</dc:source>
<dc:subject>African Americans; Toys; Women; Children</dc:subject>
<dc:source>908</dc:source>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>32992</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>Still Image</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photographs</dc:format>
<dc:rights>No copyright - United States: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/miersphotos/id/30</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>