<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Rev. Billy Kyles, 2006</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <accessCondition type="local rights statement">All rights reserved. The accompanying
                        digital object and its associated documentation are provided for online research and
                        access purposes. Permission to use, copy, modify, distribute and present this
                        digital object and the accompanying documentation, without fee, and without written
                        agreement, is hereby granted for educational, non-commercial purposes only. The
                        Rhodes College Archives reserves the right to decide what constitutes educational
                        and commercial use; commercial users may be charged a nominal fee to be determined
                        by current, commercial rates for use of special materials. In all instances of use,
                        acknowledgement must begiven to Rhodes College Archives and Special Collection,
                        Memphis, TN. For information regarding permission to use this image, please email
                        the Archives at archives@rhodes.edu or call 901-843-3334.</accessCondition>
  <location>
    <url access="object in context" usage="primary display">http://hdl.handle.net/10267/33553</url>
    <url access="preview">http://dlynx.rhodes.edu:8080/jspui/bitstream/10267/33553/3/20061107_Billy_Kyles.jpg.jpg</url>
  </location>
  <name>
    <namePart>Kyles, Samuel Billy</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm>Contributor</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <name>
    <namePart>Windless, Crystal</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm>Contributor</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated>2006-11-07</dateCreated>
    <dateOther>2018-05-21T15:16:04Z</dateOther>
  </originInfo>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n88258779">Rhodes College</recordContentSource>
    <recordChangeDate>2023-05-09-04:00</recordChangeDate>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
    <recordOrigin>Record has been transformed into MODS 3.5 from a Qualified Dublin Core record by the Digital Library of Tennessee, a service hub of the Digital Public Library of America, using a stylesheet available at https://github.com/digitallibraryoftennessee/DLTN_XSLT. Metadata originally created in a locally modified version of Qualified Dublin Core using ContentDM (data dictionary available: https://wiki.lib.utk.edu/display/DPLA).</recordOrigin>
  </recordInfo>
  <identifier type="local">20061107_Billy_Kyles</identifier>
  <subject>
    <topic>Interviews</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Oral history</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Memphis (Tenn.)</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Civil rights</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Religion</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>King, Martin Luther, Jr., 1929-1968</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Sanitation Workers Strike, Memphis, Tenn., 1968</topic>
  </subject>
  <relatedItem displayLabel="Project">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Crossroads to Freedom</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <abstract>Rev. Kyles was and continues to be one of society's most active members in the push for Civil Rights. Reverend Kyles is the last living individual to have shared Dr. Martin Luther King Jr.'s last living hour with him. He was also an eyewitness of Dr. King's assassination. Reverend Kyles has traveled the country sharing his story of activism and giving a witness to the legacy of Dr. King.In addition to his participation during the Civil Rights Movement, characterized by his participation in marches, integration of segregated businesses and schools, and much more, he has served as the pastor of Monumental Baptist Church for over four decades. Among his many accolades, Reverend Kyles has also served as a panelist at the White House Conference on Hate Crimes.</abstract>
  <relatedItem displayLabel="streaming resource">
    <location>
      <url>https://vimeo.com/278540513</url>
    </location>
  </relatedItem>
</mods>
