<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Carey Jones, 2015</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <accessCondition type="local rights statement">All rights reserved. The accompanying
                        digital object and its associated documentation are provided for online research and
                        access purposes. Permission to use, copy, modify, distribute and present this
                        digital object and the accompanying documentation, without fee, and without written
                        agreement, is hereby granted for educational, non-commercial purposes only. The
                        Rhodes College Archives reserves the right to decide what constitutes educational
                        and commercial use; commercial users may be charged a nominal fee to be determined
                        by current, commercial rates for use of special materials. In all instances of use,
                        acknowledgement must begiven to Rhodes College Archives and Special Collection,
                        Memphis, TN. For information regarding permission to use this image, please email
                        the Archives at archives@rhodes.edu or call 901-843-3334.</accessCondition>
  <location>
    <url access="object in context" usage="primary display">http://hdl.handle.net/10267/33348</url>
    <url access="preview">http://dlynx.rhodes.edu:8080/jspui/bitstream/10267/33348/3/Capture.PNG.jpg</url>
  </location>
  <name>
    <namePart>Jones, Carey</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm>Contributor</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <name>
    <namePart>Williams, Prince</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm>Contributor</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <name>
    <namePart>Walker, Allison</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm>Contributor</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated>2015-06-23</dateCreated>
    <dateOther>2018-04-30T20:02:29Z</dateOther>
  </originInfo>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n88258779">Rhodes College</recordContentSource>
    <recordChangeDate>2023-05-09-04:00</recordChangeDate>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
    <recordOrigin>Record has been transformed into MODS 3.5 from a Qualified Dublin Core record by the Digital Library of Tennessee, a service hub of the Digital Public Library of America, using a stylesheet available at https://github.com/digitallibraryoftennessee/DLTN_XSLT. Metadata originally created in a locally modified version of Qualified Dublin Core using ContentDM (data dictionary available: https://wiki.lib.utk.edu/display/DPLA).</recordOrigin>
  </recordInfo>
  <identifier type="local">20150623_Carey_Jones</identifier>
  <subject>
    <topic>Interviews</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Oral history</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Memphis (Tenn.)</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Civil rights</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Highland Heights (Memphis, Tenn.)</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Neighborhood Histories</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Crossroads to Freedom</topic>
  </subject>
  <relatedItem displayLabel="Project">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Crossroads to Freedom</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <abstract>Hugh Carey Jones was born in Memphis, TN in 1946 to parents Glen and Evelyn Jones. He attended Treadwell High School where he met his wife, Rita, with whom he had 3 kids; Becky, Chrissy, and Steven. Later, he attended the University of Memphis, formerly known as Memphis State University where he earned his Engineering degree. He did all of this after joining the Tennessee Air Guard in order to help his country in its time of need, even though it meant that he had to sacrifice some time in college. After college and the Air Guard, Jones went on to pursue a career with Memphis Light Gas and Water, working as an electrical engineer.</abstract>
  <relatedItem displayLabel="streaming resource">
    <location>
      <url>https://vimeo.com/280578798</url>
    </location>
  </relatedItem>
</mods>
