<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Eagleville High School Students, 1963, Washington, DC</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Crick, Shirley Porrell</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1963</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Eagleville High School</dc:description>
<dc:description>Front row (L to R): Betty Lou Dyer Ettinger, Cindy McClaran Vaughn, Kathy Riggs Trout (Deceased), Marion Ann Maupin Haynes, Esther Crosslin Victory; Shirley Perrell Crick, and Patsy Rowland Reeves. Standing: Charles Blackwell, Buddy Pate, Tom Reed, Jon McCord, Kenny Snell, Don McCord, Mr. J. D. Todd, Mrs. Todd, Mrs. Elmore, Mr. U. R. Elmore, Harold Vincion, Eddie Wayne Haley, Bus Driver (name unknown)</dc:description>
<dc:title>Rutherford County Schools Collection</dc:title>
<dc:description>EHS 1963 Senior Class, By Shirley Perrell Crick
Our class, like those classes who had gone before
us, sold magazines our Junior and Senior
years. Our Senior year we worked the concession
stands during the basketball games which
added to our "Washington Senior Trip."
In our particular class we had $7.00 per day
on which to eat. Enough to pay for everyone's
week stay from and back to Eagleville. Our transportation was a chartered a Greyhound
Bus. We squeezed Lincoln's head off each
pennY, making the money stretch for the "Senior
Trip."
Our chaperons had made the trip so many
times that they knew exactly where to go and
what would be the best time to arrive at each
destination.
We had a curfew of midnight. The girl(s)
could not go out unless we had one ofthe boys
with us.

One from our Class of 1963 came back and
became principal of Eagleville School. Buddy
Pate served as Principal from 1995 - 2004.
On a personal note, I had never been any
further than Nashville. It was so exciting to
save and work hard to make the money for
our "Senior Trip". It is something I will never
forget. Since 1963 I have visited Washington and seen most ofthe places that we saw in 1963. But for a farm girl it was a really big deal to make that first trip. Our class was small and we were like family. I am truly grateful for the experience.
We went in separate directions after returning from our trip. We use to get together every five years for a class reunion. We have missed a few but those special classmates will always have a special place in my heart.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Portraits, Group; Students;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Capitols</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Washington, D.C.</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Still image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Newspaper</dc:format>
<dc:format>10 x 6 in.</dc:format>
<dc:source>E_00014</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/schools/id/21</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>