<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Correspondence from Sarah Hamilton to John B. Hamilton, November 8</dc:title>
<dc:relation>&#8220;Nov. 8
Columbia
Tenn

Dear Husband
	I have just received a letter from you stating that you had never received more than three letters from home since you left. I cannot give any account for you not getting mine when I write every three or four days. I was very glad to hear from you and [illeg] but sorry to learn you would not be at home soon. It was quite a disappointment for I was looking for you very soon. But I had just as well quit looking. For you don&#8217;t intend coming home no more it seems. As for the news I can give you a little. All of the Colored Troops have left. Here and there is but very few that are sorry. I think we will get along very well without them. I received a paper last Saturday directed to you with a receipt in it. On opening it I found it was my favorit [sic] paper it was the Metropolitan. I was somewhat lifted up thinking you was not far off and would be at home soon. I have cribed [sic] all of my corn which is about 80 bl: Corn is selling for $8.00 per bl in the field. Polk will be from 15 to 20 cts some are asking 20 cts. Flour is selling for $6.00. You did not speak of Bro Milner&#8217;s health. His wife is very uneasy about him and wants him to come home.
	Cousin Amstead Poke&#8217;s gin house was burned and his dwelling was robed the same night. He lost a great deal of cotton and money. Mr. Maxey left last Wednesday. He took both of the girls and Charlie. Although he promised me to bring Charlie back but I don&#8217;t know whether he will or not. Jimmie is very anxious to go off and learn a traid [sic]. He is waiting for you to return so he can decide. Mr. Maxey toled [sic] him if he would come down there his board should not cost him anything. We received a letter from Lollie White that use to be and she is now in Lexington, Ky and will be out to see us as soon as she can get rested. John Tyler&#8217;s wife is dead. She has been dead 2 years but we never heard it until lately. You must in your next letter write me word what I must do. Whether I must rent out my place or whether I must keep house. I would like very much to know before it gets to [sic] late. The negroes have but all seased [sic] to do any thing for me. Osker and Mariah are still with me yet&#8230;
	You must write soon
		Your devoted wife
			S. A. Hamilton

P.S. The People here are all dreading an insurrection with the negro
			S. Ann Hamilton

P.S. Tell Tommie I have just received his letter and was very glad to hear from him. Tell him his Ma&#8217; is no better and nor Lou Wilson is no better. I will answer his letter soon.&#8221;</dc:relation>
<dc:description>Letter from Sarah Hamilton to her husband, John B. Hamilton.  She discusses problems with the slaves and the crops.</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Columbia (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:date>1863 or 1864 November 8</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Hamilton, Sarah</dc:creator>
<dc:source>Hamilton-Williams Family Papers, 1850-1971</dc:source>
<dc:description>Sarah Ann Hamilton and her husband, the Rev. John Bell Hamilton, lived in the Williamsport area of Maury County, Tennessee. In 1861, Hamilton and his adopted son, Thomas Hamilton Willams, entered into the Confederate army. Captain Hamilton raised a company of cavalry which became part of the Second Tennessee Battalion, later part of the First Tennessee Regiment. Williams and Hamilton were stationed in Mississippi, and were in the retreat from Atlanta.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Civil War in the West; Civil War society; United States - History - 1783-1865; United States - History - 1849-1877; United States History - Civil War, 1861-1865; Maury County (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Social values; Domestic life; Soldiers; Military life; Military personnel; Military organizations; Armies; War; Cities &amp; towns</dc:subject>
<dc:relation>90-342</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>34082</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>TEXT</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:relation>1303</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law.  Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll1/id/72</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>