<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Correspondence from Robert Rutledge to G. R. Rutledge, April 8, 1864</dc:title>
<dc:relation>[Page 1]

&#8220;Uncle Sams. Apr 8th 1864
Dear Father
	I redc a letter from Minerva yesterday telling me that all the family were well with the exception of yourself. And as my letters will be of more interest to you than any one else upon account of locality I have concluded to answer Minervas letter by writing to you I wrote to Minerva a few days ago from Aunt Elziras. in that for you I gave the encampment of the different Brigades. for fear that the letter may not reach you I will tell you in this how we are encamped. Gen Buckner has resumed Command of his Division and has his Hed Quarters upon the hill we used to call the old Orchard. it is on the hill that is directly opposite the front end of Aunt Elziras house All around him are scattered Provost Guards and waggon trains &amp;c. Johnsons Brigade is encamped in the woods between the Old Buher field and the road. You remember that square of eight or ten acres it is now pretty much cut down. Graceys Brigade is encamped back of the plantation next to where Sam Millard and Aunt Elziras mother used to live. Laws Brigade is encamped about opposite the old clover field on Uncle Sams and the Old Edwards farm A Battallion of Artiliry is encamped in the woods directly back of the old White top place. Waggon Trains and Quarter Master and Company quarters are scattered all about on Uncle Sams and Aunt Elziras, and the Buher farm. The fences are all torn down in every direction, and Aunt Elzira and Uncle Sam I fear will be prevented from making any crop this year. Aunt Elziras Negroes are doing no good. They steal from her about as fast as they make. They have even been stealing and selling hay I do not know what the Citizens here are to do if we remain much longer where we are. Aunt Elzira sold her best horse to a gap soldier for $800.00 on a short credit and has never herd anything from the man since. I consider his note as worth nothing Felix Earnist is going to Richmond on some business and I gave him the note to try the young mans&#8221;

[Page 2]

&#8220;Father and see if he will pay the det, but I understand that he has been disenhereted by his Father for bad conduct and I fear Mr Earnest will not get the money for Aunt Elzira Aunt Elzira is in a great deal of trouble and I do not know how she will make out for the next year.
Went down and saw Uncle George Anderson and Aunt Elza a few days ago. They are all well, and are still living with John Anderson. The Country that we have evacuated is swept of every thing families almost everywhere have been robbed by the soldiers. They are robbing the Citizens around here of every thing they have to eat. The Country we have passed over is said not to have a Hog goose duck turkey or chicken or sheep left. Starvation is now staring many a poor defenseless Southern woman and many many poor helpless little children in the face Our Army is getting to be as much dreaded as the low down thieving Yankees. Some of the Alabamiens went a few days ago to a mill near here and found some ground Plaster in an old bolting chist and thinking it was Shirts they stold several Haversacks full of it, and after they had got it baked they said they had never seen such bread as that before. (this is a matter of fact) Tim Millers Brother of Capt Sam is dead. The funeral procession has just passed here a few minutes ago. Said to have died from excitement and trouble. I went up to Bristol a few days ago and got the promise of a shoe pattern. From Alf Carmack. For $16.00, his common price is $24.00. I staid all night with him They send their respects to the family Uncle George Andersons Aunt Elziras and Uncle Sams families, are all well with the exception of Catherine who is only slightly sick. They all send respects to the family. Hope Gamble will soon be exchanged and get a furlough to come home and stay with you for a while. I have not felt right well for several days but am knocking about, and drilling. Think we will leave here before long. Think at best the principal portion of the Army will shortly go to Va probably all but Buckners Division. Lt Brittian has returned.
You and Minerva must write soon
		As ever your Son RARutledge&#8221;</dc:relation>
<dc:description>Letter from Robert Rutledge to G. R. Rutledge describing the state of his current encampment near his Uncle Sam and Aunt Elzira's property.  He explains that due to pillaging by the army the local population now despises the Confederate army almost as much as they do the Union army; tells of the death of Tim Miller, brother to Captain Sam; and comments on the condition of Uncle Sam's and Aunt Elzira's families and his own health.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1864 April 8</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Rutledge, Robert A.</dc:creator>
<dc:source>Rutledge Family Letters, 1858-1865</dc:source>
<dc:description>Robert A. Rutledge was the son of G. R. Rutledge, the brother of Gamble Rutledge, and the husband of Mary Minerva Montgomery Rutledge.  Both Robert and Gamble served in the Confederate Army during the U.S. Civil War. Robert was killed at Drury's Bluff, Virginia, in 1864.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Civil War in the West; Civil War society; United States - History - 1783-1865; United States - History - 1849-1877; United States History - Civil War, 1861-1865</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Civil Wars; War; Correspondence</dc:subject>
<dc:relation>1990-340</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>34180</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>TEXT</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:relation>1263</dc:relation>
<dc:relation>http://www.tennessee.gov/tsla/history/manuscripts/findingaids/90-340.pdf</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law.  Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll1/id/322</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>