<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Correspondence from John G. Latta to John Latta, June 7, 1861</dc:title>
<dc:description>Correspondence from John G. Latta of Boston to his father, John Latta, of Dyersburg, Tennessee. In this four-page letter, he states that if Tennessee secedes, "the only channel of communication now left will be closed, and we cannot commicate with each other."  He assures his father that they are safe in Boston, and that there are many Southern sympathizers in Boston.</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Boston (Mass.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:date>1861 June 7</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Latta, John G.</dc:creator>
<dc:source>Samuel Rankin Latta Papers, 1848-1862</dc:source>
<dc:description>John Latta (father, 1796-1872) was born in Lancaster Co., Penn., to John and Mary Rankin Latta. Moved from Pennsylvania to Dyersburg, Tenn., in 1855. John Gilchrist Latta (son, 1824-1901)was a sadler by trade.  He was born in New Alexandria, Penn., and died in Atlanta, Georgia. In 1862, he moved from Dyersburg to Newton Corner, Massachusetts, where he served as postmaster. He returned to Dyersburg before his death.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Civil War in the West; Civil War society; United States - History - 1783-1865; United States - History - 1849-1877; United States History - Civil War, 1861-1865</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Correspondence; Fathers; Children; Abolitionists; Civil Wars; War</dc:subject>
<dc:relation>1990-198</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>34130</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>TEXT</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:relation>84</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law.  Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll1/id/174</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>