<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Correspondence from Mary Guthrie Latta to Samuel R. Latta, January 25, 1862</dc:title>
<dc:relation>[Page 1]

&#8220;Dyersburg Tenn Jan 25 &#8216;62
My dear husband.
	I have looked in vain for a letter since you left home. &amp; have thought so much about you that last night I dreamed I had received one &amp; as I can&#8217;t have a real letter to answer I will answer the one I dreamed of. I am glad it was only a dream though &#8211; for it contained this piece of bad news &#8211; &#8220;My term of enlistment will be out the first of June, &amp; you need not look for me home until that time. As it will be impossible to obtain a furlough under any pretence.&#8221; Now as your coming home is the only pleasure I look forward to. Such news if true, would throw a considerable&#8221;

[Page 2]

&#8220;damper over my feelings. But why have you not written? Did you get disgusted with me when you were at home &amp; concluded I wasn&#8217;t worth writing to? If you did I am very sorry, but will have to acknowledge it as a good excuse for not writing. But if the Lincolnites get you, please let us know. There have no events transpired at home or in town since you left that will be likely to interest you. I have not been outside the yard but once since the evening we went to John&#8217;s. Our lives glide on from day to day in the same even channel. Everything is so peaceful &amp; quiet. That were it not for the absence of so many familiar faces it would be hard to realize that war, &amp; all its attendant horrors, are&#8221;

[Page 3]

&#8220;pressing so heavily throughout the whole country.
	Mrs. Webb &amp; Mrs. Jakes called &amp; interrupted me this evening while writing, &amp; as they usually make very long visits, this was not an exception. &amp; I have missed my chance of sending my letter by tomorrow&#8217;s mail. But in the meantime I rec&#8217;d yours by Mr. Ledsinger, for which I am very much obliged, as I know my sleep will be much sounder  &amp; my dreams not disturbed in trying to decipher half erased pencil marks. I am sorry I caused you any uneasiness in my note about Kate. As it was altogether slight &amp; will not have a scar. But at the time I wrote I did not know the extent of her injury. &amp; in my alarm magnified a thousand fold.&#8221;

[Page 4]

&#8220;But you need not expect anything else that that her face will be terribly disfigured, for besides all the burns &amp; bruises she gets, she has got to bumping her head through the window panes. &amp; of course at such tricks the little imp will get her face cut all to pieces. She asked me this evening if I was writing to Pa. I told her I was, &#8220;told tell Pa I tiss him.&#8221; Was her message. Johnny&#8217;s is &#8220;tell him when I get up I am going to say my lesson.&#8221; He has dropped off to sleep after talking me out of patience. For I can&#8217;t very well talk &amp; write at the same time. I don&#8217;t think I ever saw a child so devotedly fond of a father as he is of you. He seems to think his Pa is all &amp; everything that any body ought to be, &amp; I can govern him almost entirely by telling him of what you would like him to do.&#8221;</dc:relation>
<dc:description>Four-page letter from Mary Guthrie Latta to husband Samuel expresses anxiety over not receiving a letter from him and the fact that this worry has infiltrated her dreams. She writes of receiving visitors, of the children's exploits, and of managing the children on her own.  She notes how the peacefulness of her passing days contrasts with the horrors of the war.</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Dyersburg (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:date>1862 January 25</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Latta, Mary Guthrie (1833-1920)</dc:creator>
<dc:source>Samuel Rankin Latta Papers, 1848-1862</dc:source>
<dc:description>Samuel Rankin Latta (1827-1910) was a lawyer and a teacher from Pennsylvania.  He adopted the South and married Mary Guthrie (1833-1920) of Greene County, Tennessee on December 9, 1852.  He served as a captain in Company K (The Dyer Grays) of the 13th Tennessee Infantry, CSA, a company comprised of men from Dyer County.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Civil War in the West; Civil War society; United States - History - 1783-1865; United States - History - 1849-1877; United States History - Civil War, 1861-1865</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Civil Wars; War</dc:subject>
<dc:relation>1990-198</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>34134</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>TEXT</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:relation>84</dc:relation>
<dc:relation>http://state.tn.us/tsla/history/manuscripts/findingaids/90-198.pdf</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law.  Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll1/id/209</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>