<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Excerpts from the Narrative of Jesse Cox</dc:title>
<dc:relation>[Page 472 (511)]

&#8220;June 19, 1861. Today started on a tour of preaching. Drove and staid at Bro. Owens. Very much fatigued. 
20th Today drove 30 miles and staid at Washburn in Smith County. Bro. Owen with me. The [weather?] clear and warm.
21st . Today 2 miles to Brush Creek the Cong. unusually large anxiously waiting to hear me on the prophesies. I preached two hours. Some well pleased, and others displeased, a large portion here still contend for the Union. Owen, Evans, and Lancaster with me. Rode 5 miles and preached at Dead mans at night congn. Small.
22nd . Today 15 miles to Mount Pleasant congn. Small Owen and Petty with me. 3 miles to Drapers congn. Small. I had liberty, warm.
23rd. Today 3 miles to Mount Pleasant the congn. very large. Owen preached, and then I preached upon the prophesies, the congn. well pleased. Evans and me administered the sacrament, dined at Nights then drove 12 miles and preached at Nearbals the congn. large. Owens, Evans, and Lankaster with me, the weather very warm.
24th. Today 10 miles (over a desperate road) to Healton&#8217;s Creek the congn. very large not half in the house. I stood in the door preached 2 hours on the prophesies great attention, and well pleased. Owens, Evans, and Lancaster with me. The weather very warm cloudy today, dined at Yergans. Then we rode 4 miles and preached at night in Alexandria in Decalb Co. The congn. large 2 Methodist preachers present. Staid at Lawrences, and Boys very kindly treated, rained some.
25th. Today rode 10 miles and preached at E. Ages his funeral. The congn. very large and attentive. I was hoarse. Owens and Evans with me. Then rode 2 miles and preached at Hickman&#8217;s Creek. At 5 the congn. large. Went 1 mile and staid at Nobels.
26th. Today 1 mile and preached at Hickman&#8217;s Creek the congn very large and attentive. I preached upon the subject of the Priesthood of Melcesidec. I had liberty but hoarse. Owen and Evans with me. The 2 miles and dined at Evanes. Then 2 miles to Hickman at 5. The congn. large I am still hoarse, 3 miles and staid at Pigs. Very much fatigued.&#8221;

[Page 473 (512)]

&#8220;June 27th, 1861. Today 3 miles to Hickman&#8217;s Creek to congn. very large and attentive. I preached the funerals of 3 of Esq. McGee&#8217;s children. I am still hoarse some, and although I have preached here twiste a day for 3 days the people seem as anxious as ever, a good deal of feeling today I bid them farewell today. Then rode 7 miles and preached at McGee&#8217;s the congn. large although it rained, the weather warm.
28th. Today 16 miles and preached at Bro. C. West&#8217;s the funeral of his daughter. The congn. unusually large. I had liberty nearly clear of hoarseness. Many a Missionary Baptist preacher with me, in the evening I preached at the same place on the prophesies tonight and last night I suffered all that a man could to live with the Asone rained at night.
29th. Today 18 miles to Testament in Macon Co. the congn. not large. Owen, Petty, and West with me. 1 miles and dined at Margus. Then rode 3 miles and preached in Layfayett the congn. large and attentive. I had liberty, very warm, 1 mile and staid at Holins. Greatly fatiaged on account of labour, and lack of sleep.
30th. Today 3 miles to Testament. The congn. large. I preached on the prophets, with the kingdom of Christ. The congn. very attentive. Some displeased because I preached against the North and their fanaticism, but a large number well pleased. 3 miles and dined at Brattons, then 7 miles and preached at Harmony a Missionary house. The congn. not large but well pleased, Owen with me. The Night dark and rained. Staid at B. Greggs. They are very kind to us. The weather cool.
July 1st. Today started home, drove 42 miles. Some of the road very bad. I am very much fateagud. Staid at Bro. Owens.
2nd. Today drove 36 miles. I am alone. Half of the road bad. I reached home after an absence of 14 days greatly fateagued but wish to be thankful to God for his protection to me and my family during my absence, and the many tokens of friendship , and approbation. I never saw more ansciety to hear, but not much feeling. I preached 20 times in ten days. Besid hearing Bro. Owing. With the Lord bless the labours of this twoo.&#8221;

[Page 474 (513)]

&#8220;July 3rd, 1861. Today so worn down that I scarcely set up. 
4th. Today more wrested wrode  3 miles to see the sick.
5th. Today rained slowly. A large commet has appeared for 5 nights.
6th. Today 18 miles to Providence the congn. small. 3 miles and dined at Col. Greers. At 4 preached at Ednaies, a good congn.
7th. Today 3 miles and preached at Providence. A good congn. I had liberty preached upon the kingdom of Christ. Returned 
8th. Today remained at home. Rained very hard a little while.
9th. Today to Franklin and back.
10th. Today at home the weather cool.
11th. Today at home, windy and cool.
12th. Today to Franklin and back.
13th. Today to Cool Spring. The congn. small. One mile and to Seagall.
14th. Today 1 mile to Cool Spring. A good congn. I had liberty.
15th. Today to Franklin. The weather still cool at night.
16th. Today at home, rained a shower at night.
17th. Today art home. Still cloudy.
18th. Today at home warmer.
19th. Today My birthday. I am 68 years old.
20th. Today to Franklin. The congn. small. I preached.
21st. Today to Franklin. The congn. large and very attentive. I preached upon the prophesies with great eas. Then rode 2 miles and dined at Jordans. Then 4 miles to Meaies and preached at 4. The congn. large and attentive. I had liberty. Then returned home, rained before I reached. Today while preaching I said perhaps while I am explaining the prophesies our sons are ingaged in mortal combat, which proved to be true. At that moment the fearces battle was in the midst of it that has ever been in the United States, and the most signal victory ever achieved was gained by the South over the fenatics of the North. It rained all night without intermission and continued for 17 hours.&#8221;

[Page 484 (521)]

&#8220;November 3rd 1861. Today rode 18 miles to Providence. The congn. small. I preached 1 hour then rode 6 miles and dined at P. Smith&#8217;s. Then 1 mile and preached 1 &#189;  hours. The congn. large and attentive. The weather still cloudy rained some. 1 mile and staid at the Barrie&#8217;s. I am very much fatigued and cough wors.
4th. Today returned home 10 miles, a very heavy frost. 
5th. Today at home. The weather windy, I am sowing wheat.
6th. Today to Franklin. Voted for Davis, for President, Stevens for Vice-President of the Southern States. The weather windy.
7th. Today at home, my health improving, the weather fine.
8th. Today at home, the weather clear, and warm.
9th. Today rained so I did not go to Cool Spring.
10th. Today 8 miles to Cool Spring. The congn. small. Then returned.
11th. Today 43 miles to Cornersville Giles Co. Furgehson with me.
12th. Today preached a funeral in the Methodist Church. A good congn. I had liberty. 3 Methodist, and one Missionary preacher present and well pleased. The congn. highly delited. It was the first of a Baptist sermon ever preached in the place. 3 miles to Furgehson.
13th. Today 3 miles to Cornersville. Preached 2 hours upon the Prophesies in connection with our difficulties. The congn. increased, and excited almost to extacy. I had liberty, dined at Mrs. Slaughters. The above preachers all present, received visits from them and others. I Preached again 2 hours at night the congn. largely increased, and unusually attentive. I never received more tokens of approbations. They presented me with 10 dolors. Staid Mrs. Slaughters
14th. Today made 12 miles and preached at Lynar Creek. The congn. not large. I had liberty. Bro. Holt eschorted, dined at Buggs at night. 1 mile and preached in Lynnville on the prophesies in the Presbyterian church, a good congn. I have liberty. 1 mile to Buggs.
15th. Today start home, rained some in the night, rode 38 miles to Fergasons. The weather has been very fine all the trip. Returned 4 miles.
16th. Today 7 miles and preached in Franklin. The congn. small then.
17th. Today 4 to Franklin. A good congn. I had liberty. The [missing] cough increased.&#8221;

[Page 486 (523)]

&#8220;December 19th 1861.Today at home.
20th. Today at home, the weather cooler, and windy.
21st. Today at home. We have had frost every morning for 2 weeks.
22nd. Today at home, rained slowly all day.
23rd. Today turned very cold. The ground frozen snowed some.
24th. Today still cold. Untill evening I am quite unwell.
25th. Today at home allone part of the day. The weather warm.
26th. Today at home. Have a bad cough. The weather warm and raining.
27th. Today at home. Some cooler.
28th. Today to Furgersons. The weather fine but cool.
29th. Today 1 mile to the Brick church. Nance &amp; me preached. A good congn. The weather fine. Dined at  S. Grays. Staid at Furg.
30th. Today returned. The weather cooler. I am very feeble.
31st. Today at home. I am much harassed with my cough. This brings me to the close of the year 1861. Having rode
This year. Miles 	2460	| Heard Sermons	45
Preached Sermons	138	| Escharted		14
Baptised		none	| Ordained		none
Communed		3	| Washed feet		1
Preached funerals	12	| 
This year I have traveled two thousand four hundred and sixty miles. Although I was sick in the forefront of the season, and quite well for three months in the fall, have preached as much as usual. And although my enemies whose  conduct I could not felloship, have tryed to break me down, and verily thought they had. For they said I had no friends, and that no one wood hear me preach. Yet I have had more, and larger congn. than I ever have had since I have been preaching. In Franklin the congn. have never been so large of the best citizens before, and in various other places throut soms 20. Co. and part of two states in places where I never preached before. The congn. not only large but the most intence anxciety to hear me upon the prophesies I ever saw. Though thair  is but little of the spirit of religion, yet I have received more [missing] than I ever did. Will the Lord bless it&#8221;

[Page 487 (524)]
 
&#8220;January 1st 1862. Today to Franklin. The weather like Spring.
2nd. Today at home. The weather very fine and warm.
3rd. Today warm and cloudy rained at night.
4th. Today cloudy and cool. My health not much improved. As I am just entering upon the year 1862, will the Lord sustain me by his grace in the decline of life and make me more useful. Although the prospects looks very gloomy for I am quite old and inferm. Our country is actually at war all the last year. The North against the South, and more troops than ever was under arms in this country. And then a portion of the Baptist in this section are biterly opposed to me because I cannot fellowship thair illegal conduct. The lord has hitherto sustained me.
5th. Today at home, cloudy and cool.
6th. Today to Franklin. The weather freesing and windy.
7th. Today killed hogs. I am not able to be out much.
8th. Today warm, and cloudy.
9th. Today warm rained and thunder.
10th. Today very warm and cloudy.
11th. Today did not go to Cool Spring. So like for rain very warm.
12th. Today very cold, snowed some, Such a sudon change.
13th. Today very cold. Snowed round snow, and froze.
14th. Today still cold. My health very bad barly able to be up.
15th. Today some warmer rained all night slowly. The snow not melted.
16th. Today turned colder, cloudy all the time.
17th. Today warmer again. The snow nearly gone.
18th. Today did not go to Franklin to meeting it is so like for rain, and my health bad.
19th. Today the same. The weather warm.
20th. Today thundered and rained all day.
21st. Today cold and cloudy, it has been cloudy every day this month. Some days very dark, as for 2 days.
22nd. Today cloudy and warm.
23, 24th. Today clear and cool.
25th. Today windy and cool.&#8221;

Page 488. (525)

&#8220;January 26th 1862. Today a heavy frost, clear and fine.
27th. Today cloudy rained last night, warm at night.
28th. Today cloudy. My health worse, confined to the house.
29th. Today to Franklin. Warm and cloudy rained in the evening.
30, 31st. Today cloudy and rained some.
February 1st 1862. Still cloudy.
2nd. Commence to rain and continued 30 hours.
3rd. Today rained all day.
4th. Today cleared off in the evening.
5th. Today a heavy frost. Turned warm, and clouded before night.
6th. Today thundered and rained very hard.
7th. Today still cloudy and dark, but cooler.
8th. Today rained so I did not go to Cool Spring, not well yet.
9th. Today cloudy and cold, so I did not go to Cool Spring.
10th. Today some warmer but cloudy and rained.
11th. Today cleared off. The weather fine.
12th. Today very Spring like.
13th. Today warm, but clouded up in the evening, rained and snowed before morn.
14th. Today quite cold windy, and frozzen. Snowed at night.
15th. Today very cold, so I did not go to Franklin to meeting.
16th. Today still cold, clouded, and rained at night. Great excitement ammong the people for fear that the Yankees will get in Tenn.
17th. Today rained hard in the morning, cloudy and warm.
18th. Today cleared away at 10 and clouds in the evening.
19th. Today comenced raining at night, continued all day. The darkest and gloomiest I nearly ever saw. The country in a flood. The excitement still continues.The northern army have taken Fort Henry on the Tenn. river nothing now to obstruct them. They then came up the Cumberland to Fort Dolison, and the South whiped them on the 15 killing some 4 thousand, and loosing some 15 hund. Then the North reinforced and on the next day fought again, and took the fort. So there is nothing to keep them from Nashville. The citizens are leaving, or the women and children. It is most [missing] wicked war ever was waged.&#8221;

[Page 489 (526)]

&#8220;February 20th 1862. Today clear and cool.
21st. Today warm, and clear, I rode to town. See a number of soldiers returning from the Battle at Dolisone. The South fought part of three days nearly ten to one, killing some 7000, and loosing some 18 hundred. They then being worn out surrendered on Sunday morning some 8000 thousand. Generals Pillow, and Floid came off. Floid brought off his Briggade [sic]. Our troops have left Nashville, and falling back to Murphresborough  through his influence of the citizens and the governor for fear they would destroy Nashville.
22nd. Today it rained from 1 in the night to next night some time in torrents.
23rd. Today nearly clear but cold.
24th. Today clear, cold and windy.
25th. Today I rode to town. Clear and warmer. Ten boats came to Nashville this morning with the enemy. Some cavalry has been in sight several days. Will the Lord save us from such an unreasonable foe.
26th. Today rained before day. Then clear at twelve.
27th. Today cloudy. I am very sick confined to the bed.
28th. Today clear and cool. Comenced plowing today.
March 1st. Today warmer rained some, more at night.
2nd. Today very changeable, powerfull rain and hail in the evening.
3rd. Today very cold, cloudy, and snowing.
4th. Today everything frozzen. My health better.
5th. Today rained, and snowed at night two inches.
6th. Today cloudy cold, and snowing at times very cold.
7th. Today clear, and cold.
8th. Today two unlikely to go to Cool Spring. Clear in the evening.
9th. Today rode to Cool Spring the congn. small. I was not at liberty. The weather veary  windy. I returned very much fatigued.
10th. Today rained. Rained last night and then [illeg.]
11th. Today still cloudy and warm.
12th. Today clear and warm.&#8221;

[Page 490 (527)]

&#8220;March 13th. 1862. Today very fine and warm.
14th. Today cloudy and dark, rained from one untill eight as hard as ever I saw it, and then slow all night. Washed the fences.
15th. Today still raining, so that I could not go to Franklin.
16th. Today cold so I did not go to Franklin. The Northern army commences coming through today and continued all week. Our troops are south at Decature. We may expect an awfull battle soon. So strange are the ways of providence, that Tenn&#8217;s compose part of boath armies, and also of they. For two brothers are generals one North, and the other South.
17th. Today warm and windy, clear most of the day.
18th. Today rained verry hard.
19th. Today still cloudy but warm and windy.
20th. Today turned cool in the evening, my health no better.
21st. Today cold snowed last night enough to cover the ground.
22nd. Today cold snowed some all day.
23rd. Today a heavy frost. Snowed very hard in the morning.
24th. Today snow showers. I am confined to the house.
25th. Today begin to moderate, and has generally been warm and windy tro 26, 27, 28, 29, 30, and 31. Today commenced to sow oats.
April 1st. Today warm and windy. I am very much fatigued sowing Oats as I am very feeble.
2nd. Today verry windy, and getting dry. Then rained a shower.
3rd. Today still warm. My health improving.
4th. Today rained very fine still warm.
5th. Today rained so I did not go to Providence.
6th. Today clear and cool. I am still at home. The prospect for preaching is very gloomy. With an enimy in our midst seeking to kill our sons, and soldiers every thing looks gloomy.
7th. Today clear and fine.
8th. Today rained nearly all night and half the day slow.
9th. Today clear and warm until evening, then rained at night.
10th. Today cold and cloudy, wind from the north.
11th. Today [missing] rained some verry dark.&#8221;

[Page 491 (528)]

&#8220;April 12th 1862. Today cloudy verry windy and rained some, so that I did not go to Cool Spring, my health improved some though I have taken cold. The weather this week has been very gloomy, indeed every thing looks gloomy; for the north, and south has been fighting two or three days this week south of this on Sunday 6th the South gained the victory after fighting 13 hours and on Monday the North being reinforced with 40 thousand gained the advantage. A large number killed perhaps 20 thousand, on Sunday. The South took 6 thousand prisoners and 50 canon. On Monday the North took some prisoners. It was on Ten. River. It is expected that the will fight again in a few days.
13th. Today the morning very dark, and my cold and hoarseness kept me from going to Cool Spring.
14th. Today the weather good but windy.
15th. Today the weather good. do 
16th. Today fine and warm. do
17th. Today fine commenced to plant corn. My boy Sam 15 years old having been doing bad for some time refuse to be corrected by me, Jerked me down. I being very weak, and then took the ax and started off. I sent the older one after him, he presently returned with the ax and said the Yankey cavalry had taken Sam behind one of them and said they would send him to Ohio, that thair ware no slaves in thair country, and thair should be none here. That they had nearly whiped thfsis. Another nasty hog hole, and that they were coming at night to take me, for my preachen. Sam returned in 3 hours to the field and went to work. Two Yankees presently came in looked bad talked insulting, and said they had come by the feald talked with the negroes. When I told them how Sam had done and that I did not care wheather he left or not. They said that I was old and the boys ought not to leave me. That they did not want them as they had enough to cook for them. They then went by the [field?] again and talked with them, making them disobident [illeg.]
18th. Today fine, cloudy in the evening rained some. Sam still at work I have not spoken to him [missing]&#8221;

[Page 492 (529)]

&#8220;April 19th 1862. Today rained so that I did not go to Franklin to meeting. Rained all night, stoped an hour or two, then rained all day and all night.
20th. Today rained all day slowly, so I did not go to town, verry dark.
21st. Today still raining, and cold windy.
22nd. Today still cloudy, blew off in the evening.
23rd. Today cool in the morning, then very fine.
24-25th. Today fine weather. My health about the same.
26th. Today wet rained last night.
27th. Today clear and cool.
28th. Today clear, and cool. I had the Asma very bad last night.
29th. Today clear and windy.
30th. Today cloudy rained last night, and some today.
May 1st 1862. Today clear, and fine not very warm. My health better. For three days it has been clear.
4-5th. Today rained and quite cool.
6th, 7, 8, 9. The weather quite cool. I have not improved.
10th. Today to Cool Spring, and back the congn. small. The weather warm. I am fatigued.
11th. Today to Cool Spring. A good congn. returned in the evening. The weather warm. I am very much fatigued.
12th. Today my boy Dave ran off to and his Mother.
13th. Today the old woman came back, and said she had been to the Yankies, to get them to come after me. I gave three of them a whipping. The weather warm.
14th, 15, 16. The weather warm and dry.
17th. Today my friends persuaded me not to go to Franklin as the Yankees has threatned  me.
18th. Today still at home quite unwell, the weather cool.
19th, 20, 21, 22, 23. The weather fine. The last night rained.
24th. Today rained untill 12. I rode to Bro. Owens. 17 miles.
25th. Today Stevens and me preached the funerals of  [missing] Ouda, and her son, at Flat Creek the congn. large and very feeling. Dined at J. Owens and then returned.
26th, 27. [missing] The weather cool at night.&#8221;

[Page 493 (530)]

&#8220;June 1st 1862. Today to Buchanons schoolhouse. A good congn. the weather fine, dined at Jordans, and then returned home. The weather this week very fine.
7th. Today to Cool Spring the congn. small, returned home.
8th. Today to Cool Spring the congn. very large and attentive. It was reported that the Yankies would take me today but they did not. Preached upon the death of witneses, then returned.
This weeke the weather very cold at night.
15th. Today to Perkins Brick Church the congn. very large. I had liberty, dined at Furgersons, and then returned much fatigued.
The weather this weeak is warm and very dry.
21st. today 16 miles to Colage Grove. The congn. very large and attentive, went 3 miles and dined a Pettuces  verry tired.
22nd. Today to Eaglesville, the congn. the largest I ever saw for one days meeting, and verry attentive. A third of them standing while I preached 2 &#189; hours, on the despursion  and return of the Jews. I had more than usual liberty. Dined at Williams, returned.
23rd. Today returned home 15 miles the weather dry.
This weeak it has been warm and wet every day.
29th. Today to Perkins brick church. The congn. very large and attentive. I dined at Furgersons, then returned home. It was understot that the Yankeys would arrest me at Eaglevill but they did not. So it was said they would today, but I passed through Franklin, and back, saw them but they never interrupted me, though. I am expecting them every hour. If they do arrest me for no other offence but preaching it is a positive violation of the constitution, and is anti Christ. The Beast that opened from the botomless pit, to make war with the witneses, as they are to die this month according to all my calkulations, everything go to prove it.
July 1st. This weeak the weather fine.
8th. Today did not go to Providence, Eliza being very sick with Typhoid fever, for six weeks.
10th. This week the weather fine. Rode 16 miles to Collage grove preached the funeral of  D. Wood [missing]  I returned&#8221;

[Page 494 (531)]

&#8220;July 12th 1862. Today to Cool Spring the congn. small.
13th. Today 1 mile to Cool Spring a good congn. returned home the weather fine rained Wednesday night.
22th. Today to Buchanons Schoolhouse, a good congn. 
23rd. Today rode 16 miles to Pettuce&#8217;s.
24th. Today 6 miles to Locks the congn. very large and attentive. I preached K. McCray&#8217;s funeral, then returned.
26th. Today rode 16 miles to Bro. Owens.
27th. Today 8 miles to Chappel hill. The congn. unusually large and attentive, at least one thousand present. Two Methodis preachers. I had great liberty, dined at Brittons, Fulton rode 16 miles and staid at Stegalls.
28th. Today rode 9 miles home verry much fatigued.
30th. today rained verry much needed.
31st. Today still raining some.
August 2nd. Today 16 miles to J. Grays had to go round to keep out of the way of the Yankies.
3rd. Today 5 miles to Providence, the congn. small. I preached with ease, dined at Grays, and returned home.
The weather this week dry and warm.
9th. Today 8 miles to Cool Spring staid at Jordans.
10th. Today to Cool Spring, a good congn. I preached upon the prophesies , Mr. Fleming said he did not see how I kept the Yankies off of me, and preach that way. Returned.
 11th. This week very warm and dry.
17th. Today 6 miles to McCays the congn. verry large and attentive. Some of them very much allarmed when we met. As report said we would all be arrested. I told them that I would preach if the would stay and hear it which quieted them. I preached upon the prophesies, and the war [illeg.] at Dr. Crooks. Then rode 2 miles and preached [missing] Buchanons Schoolhouse. The congn. large and attentive then returned 4 miles home. The weather still dry [missing] that I have not been arrested today.&#8221;

[Page 495 (532)]

&#8220;August 23rd. 1862. Today 15 miles to Bro. Grahams, preached a funeral at 3. The congn. very large, report said we would be arrested, but I preached and we were not interrupted. I had the asma six hours at night very bad.
24th. Today we went to Flat Creek the congn. unusually large but the report that the Yankeys would be thair Stevens told the congn. it would be better to leave, and they left 15 minutes before ten just as I got in sight. They came in crouds but we kept on, and as they had left. (some of them very much allarmed, and some mad) I went to Farrors and staid all night. Disappointed.
25th. Today 7 miles to Grahams to dinner very hot and dry then home 15 miles. The Yankeys was here after me today.
26th. Today I left and went to Jordans to keep out of the way then went to Steagnall and staid all night. Three Yankeys came today and as they did not find me they drove off all my sheep. Worth two hundred dollars, came home at night.
27th. Today I rode 16 miles to Pettuces hid my horses and waggon.
28th. Today returned home passed in sight of 3 Yankies.
29th. Today hid my horses in the thickets, and staid out in the day.
30th, 31. The same as yesterday. The weather exceeding dry.
September 1st. Today still hid out. The weather very dry.
2nd -3. Still the same, not making more than half a crop.
4th. Today the Yankies all left the county, today. The people are much rejoiced, and greatly relieved.
6th. Today rode 15 miles and staid at J. Grays.
7th. Today 4 miles to Providence the congn. verry large and attentive. I preached with great care, though thair was three thousand Yankies in three miles. Then returned.
13th. Today 8 miles to Cool Spring the congn. small. I had liberty, staid at Steagalls. The weather warm and dry.
14th. Today to Cool Spring the Congn. large and attentive. I preached two funerals, and then returned home.
16th. Today rode 16 miles and staid at Pettuces.
17th. Today 8 miles to Overalls a good congn. I had liberty. Staid at Colonel Kings, rained this [missing]&#8221;

[Page 496 (533)]

&#8220;September 18th 1862. Today 6 miles to Locks the congn. very large and interested. I rode 4 miles and staid at Pardans.
19th. Today 1 mile to Tryune the congn. large and respectible. I had liberty. I then rode 4 miles and staid at Pettues.
20th. Today 4 miles to Colage grove the congn. very large. I dined at Caryes. Then returned home 15 miles.
21st. Today 4 miles to Buchanons Schoolhouse a good congn. The congn&#8217;s this week have been unusuall larg and greatly interested as I preached upon the Prophesies. I thank God for the liberty, and strength of bodie, and mind, and for the devine presence that I injoyed  during this trip, pray God to bless.
22nd. Today to Franklin for the first time since crismus.
23rd. Today rained some. 24th. Cloudy all day.
25th. Today to Belview, quite unwell, a very large congn. I had liberty, then returned.
26th. Today to Franklin, Still unwell.
27th. Today 12miles and dined at Bro. Grahams then 4 miles and preached at Flat Creek to a large and attentive congn. one hundred Southern Soldiers present. They were highly pleased with the explanation of the prophesies, Staid with Bro. Owen.
28th. Today 7 miles to Chapple Hill the congn. unusually large and attentive. I preached 2 &#189; hours on the Kingdom of Christ, and the opposition of anti-Christ. Dined at the Millers. Then rode 8 miles and staid at Sister Woods, very tired.
29th. Today rode 16 miles home greatly fatigued . It has been cloudy and rained some for 3 days.
30th. Today not yet rested. Clear.
October 1st 1862. Today, and the 2, &amp; 3, the weather good.
4th. Today 12 miles and preached at McWills a good congn.
[missing]th . Today was to preach at Mills campground but just before time to meet 2 messengers arrived and informed me that there [missing] and Yankies [sic] in 2 miles. I retruned home.&#8221;

[Page 497 (534)]

&#8220;October 6th 1862. Today rode to Franklin and back.
7th, &amp; 8. Clear and warm. I visited two sick persons.
9th. Today to Franklin still warm and dry. 
10th, &amp; 11. Today rained some so I did not go to Cool Spring.
12th. Today to Cool Spring the congn. small, the weather cool and windy. I taken a violent cold returned very unwell.
13th. Today rode 13 miles at Arents Creek the congn good. 1 mile and dined at Warteres, then 7 miles to Pettuses.
14th. Today 3 miles to Williamsons a good congn. my health better.
15th. Today 6 miles to Locks the congn. large and attentive. I did not have much liberty, 1 mile and staid at C. Houses.
16th. Today 4 miles and preached at the Davis Seminary the congn. large and well pleased, dined at Roses, 10 miles to Nances.
17th. Today 3 miles to Concord a good congn. I had liberty then returned 14 miles much fateagued after an absence nearly a week.
18th. To Franklin the congn. small, the first time that I preached thair the Northern armey  came thair, the weather cool.
19th. Today to Franklin the congn. verry large and attentive. I then went 2 miles and dined at Jordans, then 1 mile and preached a funeral at Bohanons Schoolhouse at 3 o&#8217;clock, a large congn. I then returned 4 miles verry much fateagued being quite sick last night and this morning, I thank God that I have been able to preach every day for 8 days, and the last day twiste. Although in feable health all the time and 7[5?]years old nearly pray God to bless my feble efforts, although down in weekness he can rais it in power.
20th, 21. Today cool, and the first frost, my health improved.
23rd. Today to Franklin, and the tanyard, and back.
24th. Today 12 miles to Bethsada a good congn. I was not at liberty. Went 1 mile and dined at Grahams, then 6 miles to Leens, windy &amp; warm.
25th. Today 6 miles to Alens Chappel the congn. large and attentive. I had liberty, the weather very windy. I then returned to Leens through the rain and sleet, preached at night to a small congn. [missing].
26th. Today 4 miles to Flat Creek a good congn. preached 5 funerals and then rode 7 miles to Stiagualls [missing] cold.&#8221;

[Page  498 (535)]

&#8220;The snow two inches deep, and very windy for three days, the most sudden change I ever saw, and snowed with the ground dusty, and the leaves green on the trees, ice this morning 2 inches thick.
27th. Today 10 miles from home a verry heavy frost the branches frozzen over. Strange are the ways of Providence to us ignorant creatures.
28th. Today clear but a heavy frost.
November 2nd. Today to Hebron the congn. large and attentive. I had liberty. Dined at J. Wilsons, and then returned.
3rd. Today to Franklin. The weather fine.
8th. Today to Cool Spring. The congn. very small. The weather cold.
9th. Today to Cool Spring the congn. small, returned in the eve.
15th. Today to Franklin the congn. small, they expect the Yankies 
16th. Today to Franklin the congn. very large and attentive many persons thair that never were thare before. I preached two hours upon the Kingdom of Christ. Pray God to bless it.
17th. This week the weather has been fine.
22nd. Today to J. R. Furgersons the weather cold.
23rd. Today 1 mile to the Brick church a good congn. I went to Furgersons and dined , and then returned home.
27th &amp; 28. Verry cold and windy.
29th. Today to Franklin, and back.
30th. Today to Buchanons Schoolhouse, a good congn. I dined at B. Carithers, rained some, I returned home.
December 1st. Cold and clear.
4th. Today to Franklin, and back. The Yankies was in 2 mls.
5th. Today snowed 4 inches deep. At night very cold.
6th. Today very cold and clear.
7th. Today so cold I did not go to Tompsons Station to my appointment.
8th, 9 &amp; 10. Clear and warmer, but the snow not all gone. 
I have not kept a regular journal for two months the weather had been very cold and, then wet all the time.
[missing] Today 8 miles to Tompsons Station, a good congn. I am hoars [missing] excitement as the Yankies were in Franklin last evening [missing] and then returned.&#8221;

[Page 499 (536)]

&#8220;December 29th 1862. Today I am quite unwell, have a very bad cold &amp; cough. God has wonderfully blessed our soldiers of late, in self defence having gained great victories in 4 days fighting in Virginia, and about the same time one at Vicksburg, in which our boys was only 13 killed. While the enimy lost in killed, wounded, and missing 35, thousand.
30th, and 31. Was a great battle at Murphresborough. Our boys was 5 or 6 thousand killed, wounded, and missing. Thairs was 30 thousand, 43 field peaces, so 20 thousand small armes, Eight hundred waggons tranes and baggage. The wonderful goodness and power of God is so clearly manifest in the behalf of those that are endevouring to maintain thair indipendence; against an enemy that are endeavourin to subjegate us. That I cannot help feeling devout grattitude to God for his protection Pray God that he would spedily deliver us from such an enimy. This brings me to the close of the year 1862. having.
Preached Sermons		63| Heard Sermons		2
Preached Funerals		14| Ordained			none
Baptised 		       none  | Washed feet		none
Communed		       none  | 
Traveled, miles	       1071  | 
Although I have traveled less, and Preached less on account of my health in the Spring, and the Northern armey being all over the country taking horses and other property, and aresting persons, and especially the minestry so that I had to hide out sometime, yet I preached more than any one else in this secion, and with better success, larger congn. and more anxiety than ever in my life. In week days, as well as Sundays, by all denominations, although the spirit of religion is less universal and no additions, on accoun of the death of the two witness which took place in July last according to my calculation, and observation. Yet I cannot help beliving that it was productive of good to the people, and will be for the Glory of God. As I preached upon the subject of the Prophesies as connected with the kingdom of the world, and thair oposition to the kingdom of Christ, She [missing] that the present ware is of the Beast from the Botomless p[missing] against the Lamb, but he will [missing]&#8221;

[Page 500 (537)]

&#8220;January 1st 1863. Today I am entering upon another year will the Lord sustain an old, and very infirm survant, and help him to be faithfull, and obedient, though I am verry unwell have a distressing cough yet he has sustained me hither to. During this month Forest, Harnes and others went all over west Tennessee took many towns, and prisenors, and vast quantity of Armey stores. The weather has been very cold at times Snow and then rain so thair has been but 3 sunshining days in this month, so that I havent preached only once a funeral.
February 1863. Today I did not go any whare to preach .
2nd. Today still at home my health better.
3rd. Today the Yankeys came to Franklin in great force doing great damage on the road, our cavelry left on Saturday.
I havent preached any this month for the Yankies an weather this 19th day is still dark and cloudy for a week. I have been hiding my horses, and waggon meat and so on for two weeks they have not taken any thing from me this time, though they have been in sight.
During February we have not had only about 3 clear days.
March the 1. Today partly clear, the Yankeys are nearly in sight with 25 waggons foraging, two came to my house for meat.
3rd. Today they are in the neighbourhood taking everything. I am still afraid.
4th. Today snowing, and very windy. Our troops attacted the Yankey picqits south of Franklin at eleven and fought an hour and a quarter but I do not know what was done, they were reinforced, and ours fell back.
5th. Today snowing some, the Yankies folowed our men to Thompsons Station and are fighting now while I am writing at eleven. Pray God that we may be victorious over every enimy. (later) They fought 4 or 5 hours the South took prisenors and killed near 4 thousand and took 4 bateries 125 waggons, only 2 thousand returned, in haste.
8th. Today they had a skirmish at Colage Grove the Yankies fell back.
9th. Tody the weather good. 10th. The Ynakies followed our men to Rutherford Creek. The South with massed batteries at one fire killed 30 and then the Yankies returned, they were 1400 strong.&#8221;

[Page 501 (538)]

&#8220;March 12th 1863. Today the weather getting fine. The took my saddle horse today.
15th. Today fine. 50 waggons came today to get forrage, and every thing else in the neighborhood, and such a scene I never witnessed and I pray God I never may. I talked very plain to the officers. I told them they were all rogues, and that God would punish them.
15th. Today 40 thousand Yankies started to Columbia.
Two or 3 days this week I have heard firing south.
20th. Today, and all the fore part of the week the weather fine.
21st. Today cloud and like raining, my health pretty good.
22nd. Today weather good but rained some. 23rd. rained today.
24th. Today 50 waggons came and loaded mostly with corn. They were Kentuckeyns, and did not do as bad as before. One boy came to the crib and was caring off my half bushel, when I asked him not to do it. He galloped up to me presented his gun, and swore if I did not go in the house he would shoot me. I looked him in the face untill he put down his gun. He then called me a damed old sun of a bich and said he would blow my brains out. I stood thair until he rode off. I talked very plain to some of the officers.
25th. Today cold We gave breakfast to 15 of them, and to 7 the day before, Jesse came at 3 to see his sister that is sick, and at half past eight they came and took me, and Jesse , and the boy Sam and Jesse horse made us walk to the Gard fire, then took Jesse to her quarter, and I have not heard from him since, I sat up all night in the most wicked company I ever was in very cold, Starns and Forrest went round half way to Nashville and took 800 prisenors, a good many waggons, and never lost a man.
26th. Today they let me come home to breakfast, and after talking some time they released me, and Sam, for which I thank God. Thought they never would tell me what they arrested me for.
27th. Today quite unwell, had the Asma all night.
28th. Today very unwell, rained in the evening this area all night.
29th. Today raining some the Yankies hear for something to eat every day 2 or 3 times in the day and never pay anything.
30th. Today fine but still cold.
31st. Today cold the Yankies come ever[missing] d[missing]&#8221;

[Page 502 (539)]

&#8220;April 1st 1863. Today fine though cool, planting corn. This first week very windy, and cool, the Yankeys here every day.
6th. Today still cold and windy. It seems that the Yankies will take everything that I have got. The puiquts are all the time in sight.
8th. Today a reinforcement camped close by. Doing great mischief in the neighborhood.
10th. Today the rebels attacted them and drove them out of town, but not out of thair fort. They fought nearly all day, but I have not heard the perticulars. They were here in the morning persuading my boy to take a horse and go with them. One came in the evening and called me out some hundred yards from the house, has his gun cocked to shoot me because I had went to the fence to put it up, where they were down.
11th. Today dooing a great deal of mischief. The fellow that was going to shoot me yesterday, took the Mule from the waggon today. They got whiped yesterday, and are very mad today.
12th. Today the weather fine. The Yankeis took my buggy hors today. I have only two left 20 years old and one of them won&#8217;t work.
13th. Today the East Tennesseans returned to Murphres.- and burned a number of houses on the way. Say 27. Threatned to burn mine and drive me off. We are packed up as well as we can not knowing what will be the result. Will the lord help us to bare it with patience, no tunge can describe the intence anxiety.
14th to 19. Nothing uncommon only taking my corn and fodder every day, and getting other provisions.
20th. Today rained. Thair was firing toward Thompsons in the evening.
21st, 22. Today they have broken a lock stold chickens, and eggs and caried off 11 loads of corn and fodder.
23rd. 24. They have nearly caried off the last ear of corn, and what I am to do the Lord only knows. I pray God to give Grace and fortitude to bear it with sufficient fortitued and resignation.
25th &#8211; 26. The continued every day until they got all the corn and fodder I had, and all the hams and shoulders they could get.&#8221;

[Page 503 (540)]

&#8220;May 1st 1863. Today very fine. This month has continued mostly dry, cool and windy, verry dry for three weeks untill the last days of the month we had a fine season. Corn looks very bad on account of the drouth, wheat is fine. But the Yankes are cutting any wheat, and grasing on my meadow. They got very badly whiped on the Rappahanoc the first of this month by Lee, and Jackson fought a whole week having 15 thousand killed. They have been fighting for ten days in Miss. And at Vicksburge, I do not know the perticulars, but it is said they have lost 30 thousand. Will the lord help. My wife, and Sarah are verry sick. I have tried to get my son from Franklin as a Doctor but the Yankies wont let him. We are without medicine.
June 1. Today verry fine after the rain if the Yankies was away. My Wife, and daughter verry sick.
2nd. Today the piqites left here and went to Tryune The weather dry. Jess was released last evening, and staid here last night having been a prisoner two months, and released without a trial. They had taken his horse, and when he left here two of them fowloed him and took his watch and $70 dollars.
3rd. Today Forrest drove them out of Franklin and took the Sutlers Stores. In the evening the cavalry came by here from Tryune, three Regiments, and met our men in a half of a mile from her, and fought an hour. Two more Yankey regiments flanked our men on both flanks, so they had to fall back. We lost six killed and 4 wounded. They lost forty killed, and eighty wounded.
16th. Today rode .5 miles to visit yong Vaughr who is verry low with consumption the first time I have been outside of my farm in three months. My wife and daughter still verry sick. The weather verry dry Wheat crop very fine.&#8221;

[Page 504 (541)]

&#8220;June 23rd. Today it rained very fine, and has continued all the week the 29 as hard as ever I saw washing down fences. The fight is still going on at Vicksburgh, they have lost 75 thousand, and we less than one thousand. At port Hudson they have been repulsed 27 times. And Lee has whiped Hooker again, and drove him back nearly to Alexandria. They have taken 10 thousand Yankey prisenors, and Stewart is over in Chambersburgh Pensylvany. All this is so clearly the work of God that even an infidel cannot help seeing it. It is the Lamb that is destroying the Beast from the botomless pit. The Lord grant to hasten our deliverance.
July 1st. Today verry fine, the ground verry wet. Thair has not been a Yankey hear for a month. Oh how relieved from such rougerry, and tiring. Thank the Lord for his goodness.
2nd &amp; 3. The weather warm and showery, Our men have fallen back since the fight at Hoovers gap. One Briggade fought five killing 5 thousand, and loosing three hundred.
4th. Today, Alas have changed the times. Martha came today, has not been here for 7 months.
5th. Today very fine untill evening rained verry hard.
6th. Today verry warm. my family verry sick.
7th. Today rained hard in the evening.
8th. Today verry cloudy, and raining some.
9. Today nearly clear.
10th. Today very dark and smokey. Quite warm.
11th. Today still dark and foggy, verry strange weather.
12th. Today rode 8  miles and preached to a large and attentive congn. visited a sick lady and returned home verry much fatigued. The weather the most dark and foggy I ever saw rained some at 12 oclock. Rained nearly all night.
13th Today dark and still raining.
14th. Today dark as ever untill 12 rained some. The weather is the strangest I ever saw.&#8221;

[Page 505 (542)]

&#8220;Today rode 9 miles and found my Buggy horse that the Yankeys stole from me 3 months ago. Then returned.
July 19th 1863. today is my birthday being seventy years old today. I thank the thoug most holly and divine creator of the universe for the many token of Divine favor and protection amidd so many dangers, and difficulties. Help me to be more faithfull, and obedient, and grant me thy spirit and Grace for the remainder of the Journey. Rained this evening.
20th. Today fine. Comenced to cut hay, rained at night.
21st. Today cloudy and dark still foggy.
22nd. Today fine thair has been no Yankeys here since the little close by. And we feel so much relieved, that we thank God and take courage, will the Lord still keep us from such enemy.
23rd. Today fine only it is still smokey.
24th. Today still the same my Daughter still verry sick.
25th. Today verry cloudy, and rained some. The weather continued seasonable to the end of the month.
August 1, 1863. My family has been so sick that I have not kept up my daly record. The weather good.
7th. Today rode 8 miles and preached at Cool Spring a good congn. I then returned. The weather geting dry.
21st. Today my daughter Sarah was taken verry bad so that we thought she could not live. She continued very bad untill Sunday 23rd. At day light I went to her. I thought she was past speaking when to my surprise se said Father am I going. Yes I said it cant be long. She said thank the Lord for that. I said is your faith still strong, are you satisfied. Yes she said what he does will be right. I said you are not suffering much. Yes she said. After some minuts she said wake up Jesse, and when he came to her (young as he is) he saw she was dying and was greatly destressed. Said Lord have mercy on my soul and boddy, for I will have no papa nor mama neither . he said mama cant you stay with me. She said no and held up her hand (though it was cold as it could be) and said good by. She then kissed Pa, and after resting some time he still greatly distressed, she said you mind what your&#8221;

[Page 506 (543)]

&#8220;Grand pah says to you. After some time breathing verry hard and her eyes closed, and I thought insensible to every thing. She said Father why can&#8217;t I go (speaking so as to be heard all over the room) I said you must fill up the measure of the suffering of the boddy of Christ, and in five minut she breatheed her last. One minute before she closed her mouth smiled and raised her hand. And entered into that rest that remains to the people of God. At fifteen minutes before seven of the clock on the 23 of August 1863. Being 38 years six months and 16 days old. She was intered at home (agreable to her own request) on Monday 24th. A large company of nabours being present, they have ben verry kind to us during her 14 months of sickness and great suffering. Which she bore with more patience than any person I ever saw, for which I desire to thank God, and them for their kindness. She remaind concious to the last moment, and intirely calm and serene without the least being excited.
I have not kept up my naritive daly, but nothin verry particular has transpired. The weather has been verry dry through August, and most of September. On the second Sunday in September I rode to Cool Spring and preached to a very large congn. I preached upon the seting up of the kingdom of Christ. I had liberty, and good attention, returned.
On Monday I rode to Wilsons, and Payners, and returned.
On the third Sunday I was taken sick and was quite sick all the week, but on Sunday morning I was better and drove 12 miles to Colege Grove and preached to an unusual large, and attentive congn. I preached upon the subject of measuring the Temple and the death of the two witnesses then drove 4 miles to Mr. Pettuce very much fateagued having been 8 hours ingaged  without rest. I had such a fever that I slept none all night.
Monday drove to Clem Jordans to dinner, and then home allmost exhausted.&#8221;

[Page 507 (544)]

&#8220;I continued to get wors all the week untill I was verry bad with pain in my head and eyes als a bad cough. The next week I mended October 1st gradually untill Sunday, and though I had scarcely been out of the house for two weeks. I rode to Cool Spring and preached to large and attentive congn. I finished on the subject of the Kingdom of Christ and then returned very tired in deed.
On Monday I expected to be wors, but thanks to the Lord I am not.
The Yankies has not been here since June, But about the third Sunday September Rosecrans and Bragg fought some four days and Bragg whiped him verry badly drove him back 15 miles. Rosecrans lost 35 or 40 thousand, Bragg 5 thousand, and the cavelry have taken nearly all the towns in his rear, and has destroyed a vast ammount of waggons and stores.
On the fourth Sunday in October. I rode 6 miles to bellview and preached to a good congn. Dined at J. Tulloes, and then returned.
November 1863. On the second Sunday I rode 8 miles to Cool Spring to a large and attentive congn. Dined at Jordans and returned.
On the 20 I rode 5 miles and visited a verry sick young man, sung and prayed with him. And then returned 5 miles.
December 1863. I have been confined to home sowing wheet and for the want of something to write, it has been verry wet.
12th. Today rode 5 miles to L Poyners met with J. W. Wilson and Sister Vaughn had a long conversation upon the scriptures and the present war. Then returned 5 miles.
The first of this month Bragg and Grant fought two days at Lookout Mountain Grant lost ten thousand (10000) killed and twenty thousand wounded. Bragg lost one thousand killed and two thousand wounded with four thousand prisoners. What a dark and gloomy time, and the loss of life and treasure, but we must receive it as a chastisement from God.
24th. Today two Yankey soldiers came here for the first since June thank the Lord for guardin us thus far, and our fervant prayer is that he will continue his protection.&#8221;

[Page 508 (545)]

&#8220;This bring me to the close of the year 1863. Having rode187 miles, and preached.
Sermons		14 | Heard sermons		one
Funerals		 1  | Exhortations		none
Sacraments	        none | Ordained			none
Baptised	        none | 
I have rode less and preached less than any year since I have been preaching having been confined nearly all the year by the Yankies, who forbid me going from home, and by sickness myself and family. But my health is better now than it has been for three winters. But what preaching I done was better received, and larger congn than usual. I desire to thank the Lord for such tokens of divine favour for while many may all my breathern in the ministry that live near have been banished from thair homes and propert, and the citizens have all taken the oath, I have still escaped and permited to remain at home untill now. My dependence is entirely upon the Lord to direct me right through this year, and in this dark and trying hour.
January 1st 1864. Today verry cold turned cold last evening and hailed, and then snowed and remained very cold for two weeks. Then we had a week of pleasent weather. Then again a weeak of very cold.
February 2nd. My servants all left today 3 young men and two women and child, and went to the Yankies.
On the 7th some person broke down my stable door and took two horses and rode them off.
16th. Tonight a party of Fed Soldiers came and searched the hosue over twice, stoled a good many things and left.
20th. Today I was compelled to tak the oath of allegence or be driven off and loose my home. Being the only man in the county but what had taken an oath. If I have done wrong I pray God to forgive me. The weather has been very cold for a week.&#8221;

[Page 508 (546)]

&#8220;February 24th 1864. We had some good weather for some days.
29th. Today rained and hailed, and then snowed so as to brake down abundance of timber.
March 5th. Tonight came a gang of Yankey soldiers and threatened to shoot us. Broke down the meet house door and took 22 hams and shoulders. How long O Lord will though suffer me to be thus tried, and tempted by such out laws, pray the to give grace to bair it with patience. 
About the first of the month they fought in East Tenn, Florida, at Dothan Georgia, and Missis in which the rebels reputed them at each place. 7th we had rain and thunder.
9th. Tonight came and took all our fouls but three.
13th To Cool Spring the congn. large and attentive. I have a very bad cough. Returned home, very much fatigued the weather cold cloudy and dissagreeable.
April 10th. Today to Cool Spring a good congn. though the weather is cold and windy, I returned in the evening.
11th. today 5 miles to visit sick man.
13th. Today I am giving one dolar per bus for corn.
18th. The weather has been cold and cloudy all this month the most bacward Spring I ever saw. The trees hardly shows any buds yet. I still have a destressing cough.
I continued to preach regulary during the balance of this year to verry large and attentive congregations more so than usual. But I became so nervas, and having to labour for support that I have not kept up my regular record, wich I very much regret. I am compelled to labour as I lost about eight thousand dolars worth of property by the Yankeys, for wich I have never received any compensation. But I try to submit to it cheerfully seeing that it is the will of God that it should be so.
I preached five times in the Presbyterian Church in Franklin by their request, and they wished me to continue regular which I could not do on account of other engagements.&#8221;

[Page 509 (547)]

January 1st 1865. The war being over this year the South being overturned have to submit to every thing. They lost thair caus by being divided among themselves and many going over to the North, and the Yankies geting Troops from all other nations. Lee surendred to Grant on the 9th of April 65 which they never would have done if they had been united. And of had none but the North to fight. By such men we have lost our property and our liberty.
I am undetaking to make a crop by myself this year so I canot travel far during crop time having only one blind mair to do it with. I am preachin round by invitation in the houses of all denominations at Duglasses, Tompsons Station, in Spring hill, at the Brick Church, at the Presbyterian Church and west Harpeth at Mcays several times, at Buchannons Schoolhouse, at Stockets, at Johnstans, at Bell view, at Colage Grove and at Eagleville, also Chappel Hill. To large and respectable and interested congn. beside preachin regular for Cool Spring and Providence.
In September Bro Hix sent a buggy to Mr. Pettis and carried me to his house on Thursday night, on Friday at Flat Creek and at night in Lynchburg.
Saturday morning to the Elk river Association at Mount Mariah. Bro Wagner preached the introductory, then Bro West , and Bro Millhouse, I preached at night at Bro Holemans. On Sunday the congn. the largest I ever saw at an Association an twenty five preachers, Bro West preached then Bunyan Stevans. I preached last the congn. very attentive and feeling, Stevens preached at Holemans at night, on Monday Emmons, and then Been preached, Then I preached the last sermon by request from the congn. through the Association, at the close thair was great feeling from which a revival took place which has aded forty to the church. We ten went to Bro Greens, and on Tuesday Bro Forest and myself preached two funerals at county line and although it rained the congn. was very large. We then went to Bro Hicks, and next day he sent me to Bro. Pettises, and next morning I returned home.
I preached round during the fall, having traveled and preached more than I did last year, for this is the first Association that I have been to since the war commenced. And feel greatly revived in being presented to meet the Breathren again. And receive so many tokens of approbation and fellowship both from God and the Breathern.&#8221;</dc:relation>
<dc:description>Excerpts from a diary, 1834-1865, and memoir of early life, written by Jesse Cox (1793-1879), a Primitive Baptist minister and resident of Williamson County, Tennessee. He describes the hardships of life as an itinerant preacher,  some religious controversies with other denominations, and his experiences during the Civil War years as an ardent supporter of the Confederacy.</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Williamson County (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:date>1861-1865</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Cox, Jesse 1793-1879</dc:creator>
<dc:source>Jesse Cox Diary, 1834-1865</dc:source>
<dc:description>For Jesse Cox the war came, quite literally, to his front lawn.  He had several suspenseful confrontations with Yankee troops, and saw much of his crops and property stolen by both sides.  Cox also recorded that at some of his congregations, there were substantial numbers of Unionists or anti-Confederates, who in some cases left because of Cox's pro-Confederate stance.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Civil War in the West; Civil War society; United States - History - 1783-1865; United States - History - 1849-1877; United States History - Civil War, 1861-1865</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Civil Wars; War</dc:subject>
<dc:relation>789</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>34084</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>TEXT</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:relation>86</dc:relation>
<dc:relation>http://tennessee.gov/tsla/history/manuscripts/findingaids/789.pdf</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law.  Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll1/id/49</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>