<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Correspondence from Mary Guthrie Latta to Samuel R. Latta III, August 26, 1861</dc:title>
<dc:relation>[Page 1]

&#8220;Dyersburg Tenn.
Aug 26 1861.
My dear husband -.
	I wrote you by Mr. Nash, but as he did not go as far as New Madrid, I do not know whether you received my letter or not &#8211; if you did not, you missed a rich treat. There was one from myself, &amp; enclosed was one from John to Mother. Cousin Beck also wrote the same time. I have not received your last, by Mr. Chitwood. &amp; of course I am in a perfect fever about it. Mr. C. gave it to Mr. Nash to bring home. &amp; report says he got tight &amp; left his saddle-bag on the road.
	It has been a long dull Sunday, &amp; have thought so much of you today, that I concluded to try &amp; relieve my thoughts by writing to you. I wonder where you are &amp; what you are doing this evening. I would&#8221;

[Page 2]

&#8220;give much to know. We are beginning to feel the terrible realities of war in earnest now. Those that are dearest to us on earth are gone we know not where, &amp; no probability of hearing from them soon- I suppose this will be my last opportunity of writing, &amp; though I have nothing at all to write, I could not let it pass without letting you know that your darling little Johnnie has gotten almost well, &amp; Kate as well &amp; bad as usual. The rest of us are all well, except Vickie &#8211; she does not improve any - &amp; I very much fear never will. She will be a great charge on my hands, for she is not as capable of taking care of herself as Johnny is. But she is my sister, &amp; I will try to do my best by her. Though it is a sad charge. Mother is away today &#8211; spending the day with Mrs. Jakes -  other [?] has another daughter - &amp; Mother&#8217;s services as usual were called into requisition. She calls it Lucy Ellen. Through compliment to Mother.&#8221;

[Page 3]

&#8220;Cousin Beck seems to be enjoying herself finely. Dr. Hibbitt called this evening &amp; from the way their tongues are running they have plenty to talk about. I am glad he called. With the exception of Mr. Hanks she has had no other visitor since she came. &amp; I am afraid her visit this summer has not been pleasant enough to induce her to come back.
	Sunday night &#8211; steals on me almost unawares &amp; cast a shadow on my heart as well as on the earth. The heavy pattering of the rain, causes me to think of you poor soldiers, who are probably exposed to it tonight, with no dry place to lay your heads. &amp; I feel as if I would so willingly exchange places with you if I only could. But alas, &amp; alas, I am only a woman, &amp; must enjoy the comforts, with which your hand has so fairly provided, and cannot share with you the privations &amp; hardships you endure.
	Mrs. Pierce called as she promised you yesterday evening. She gave a full&#8221;

[Page 4]

&#8220;description of her visit. She seemed to enjoy it very much although she did have a sick husband to nurse. I was gratified to hear her report of you all being in good spirits it was one of my greatest troubles when I was there. I fancied you all looked very gloomy. Perhaps it was only because I felt so myself. How do you like your experience in marching so far? Didn&#8217;t you get terribly tired. I feel so spoiled when I see this great fat horse of yours standing around doing nothing &amp; you tramping on foot through mud &amp; water with those dear old long legs aching in every bone. I have been thinking seriously about sending him to you, but the uncertainty of you getting him &amp; not knowing whether you would like it. I will wait for orders from head quarters before I venture. Cousin Beck sends his love, &amp; says she will not bore you with a letter this time. I suppose she thinks mine will be as much as you can get through with. But I guess she is mistaken for I know my letters are interesting. 
If there is not much sense in them, because they are from home. I will still hope to hear from you frequently though from all accounts, it seems I have but a slender foundation to build a hope upon. With many wishes for your safety, &amp; your early return home, I must bid you good night. &amp; may God forever bless you my dear husband,
					Ever yours,
					Mary&#8221;</dc:relation>
<dc:description>Correspondence from Mary Guthrie Latta to her husband, Samiel R. Latta. In this four-page letter, she expresses concern for the safety of her husband. She states that she is "beginning to feel the terrible realities of war in earnest now."</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Dyersburg  (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:date>1861 August 26</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Latta, Mary Guthrie</dc:creator>
<dc:source>Samuel Rankin Latta Papers, 1848-1862</dc:source>
<dc:description>Samuel R. Latta (1827-1910), of Irish descent, was reared in Pennsylvania and moved to Dyersburg, Tennessee, where he was a lawyer, teacher, Mason, Captain in the 13th Tennessee Volunteer Infantry C.S.A., elder of the Presbyterian church, and Sunday school superintendent. Mary Guthrie Latta (1833-1920) was the daughter of John Guthrie. She was born in Greene County, Tennessee. She married Samuel R. Latta on December 9, 1852.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Civil War in the West; Civil War society; United States - History - 1783-1865; United States - History - 1849-1877; United States History - Civil War, 1861-1865</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Correspondence; Fathers; Children; Families; Mothers; Civil Wars; War</dc:subject>
<dc:relation>1990-198</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>34127</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>TEXT</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:relation>84</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law.  Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll1/id/199</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>