<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Correspondence from Mary Guthrie Latta to Samuel R. Latta, June 28, 1861</dc:title>
<dc:relation>[Page 1]

&#8220;Dyersburg Tenn June 28th &#8216;61
My dear, dear husband,
	I received your letter by Mr. Watkins &#8211; I was just at my breakfast this morning when your last by Maj. Fowlkes came &#8211; you may be sure. I made a hasty meal of it - . Your letters are all I look for with any eagerness &#8211; not having you to look for. They come nearer supplying your place than any thing else. &amp; you cannot write too often. You must not be disappointed if you do not get one from me by every one passing, for I do not know if their going to Randolph. You know we live so far in the country, we do not hear much that is going on in town. I do not know how I will send [missing] but I must write at [missing] to chance, for an opportunity [missing]&#8221;

[Page 2]

&#8220;We are getting along as well &amp; comfortably as usual, and only need your dear presence, to make us happy. But oh! We miss you so much, &amp; my anxiety is so great for you, that you are never one moment from my mind. And though I know God is able to protect you, where ever you are, still I cannot feel that &#8220;you will be as safe in the battlefield as in your peaceful home.&#8221; My only hope now is, that something will be done in Congress to still the tempest that is now threatening us, before it burst upon us with all its fury, and leaves thousands of hearts and homes desolate. I am rejoiced to hear that you are getting along so pleasantly &#8211; for it would be an additional trouble to me to know you were not comfortably situated &#8211; I understand that several of your company returned. How were they received:
	I had just put up my letter to go to the kitchen, &amp; mix&#8221;

[Page 3]

&#8220;some light bread to send you, when Mr. Ledsinger drove up to the gate, &amp; I must finish my letter in a hurry to send by him, I leave read to Mary &#8211; if it is not so good as I would have made, you will have to excuse it. The uniform will be sent to the river in the morning. &amp; I am sending you a box of edibles &#8211; I don&#8217;t know that it will be any better than you get. But will show that you are still thought of at home.
	Father and Mother are still very feeble, but are better than when you left. Johnnies old cough has returned on him. I am very uneasy about it &#8211; He is very well with that exception &#8211; Katie face appears to be entirely well, but it may break out again at any time. 
	Dr. McGauby requests me to tell you that M. R. Hill is candidate for Congress. Mrs. Barton has got home &amp; brought her eldest sister with her &#8211; She is&#8221;

[Page 4]

&#8220;such a fine, lively girl, that she will be good company for Cousin Beck &#8211; for she can talk equally as fast &#8211; I will have to answer all your questions about home in one &#8211; every thing is getting along tolerably well. &#8211; The weather is so dry that our vegetables are suffering very much. You inquired about your bus. Mr. Howe had just finished taking a box to send you when your letter came. This is the second box that we have taken, it is not so nice as the first. I had intended writing you a good long letter in return for yours on Sunday &#8211; but Mr. Ledsinger has spoiled it all - &amp; I am so hurried I hardly know what I am writing. Johnnie send you a kiss &#8211; all send their love but accept the warmest, truest love from,
				Your affectionate wife,
				Mary G. Latta.&#8221;</dc:relation>
<dc:description>Correspondence from Mary Guthrie Latta to her husband, Samuel R. Latta. This four-page letter provides information about the homelife of Mary Guthrie Latta since her husband's departure.  She states that the family "is getting along as well and comfortable as usual, but oh!! We miss you so much."</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Dyersburg (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:date>1861 June 28</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Latta, Mary Guthrie</dc:creator>
<dc:source>Samuel Rankin Latta Papers, 1848-1862</dc:source>
<dc:description>Samuel R. Latta (1827-1910), of Irish descent, was reared in Pennsylvania and moved to Dyersburg, Tennessee, where he was a lawyer, teacher, Mason, Captain in the 13th Tennessee Volunteer Infantry C.S.A., elder of the Presbyterian church, and Sunday school superintendent. Mary Guthrie Latta (1833-1920) was the daughter of John Guthrie. She was born in Greene County, Tennessee. She married Samuel R. Latta on December 9, 1852.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Civil War in the West; Civil War society; United States - History - 1783-1865; United States - History - 1849-1877; United States History - Civil War, 1861-1865</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Correspondence; Children; Families; Mothers; Spouses; Civil Wars; War</dc:subject>
<dc:relation>1990-198</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>34128</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>TEXT</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:relation>84</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law.  Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll1/id/189</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>