<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Correspondence from Sarah Hamilton to Thomas "Tommie" H. Williams, January 25, 1863</dc:title>
<dc:relation>&#8220;January 25th, 1863

Dear Tommie

	Having an opportunity of sending you a letter I write you [a few?] lines knowing that you are always anxious to hear from home.
	I have just returned from the hospital in Columbia. I have a room there and went in to see about my patients. There is a great many sick soldiers there. Some that have their hands frost biten. [sic] They are mostly Forest&#8217;s men. I heard in town today that they were expecting the Yankees in Franklin. Whether it be true or not I can&#8217;t tell but hope it is not true for if they get here again they will ruin us. When I see so many soldiers coming home on furlough I think it is right hard that you and Jimmie can&#8217;t get home.
	Mr. Hamilton left last week. He stayed at home longer than he would have done on account of Peter. He was not willing to go south and leave his wife. Your Pa sold him to Mr. Crosby. We have bought Cary Purpose to wait on you. We heard you had three servants in your mess and did not need him but I don&#8217;t think it is true. Keep Cary to wait on you if you get sick he can wait on you.
	Your Ma W. has been very sick with a sore throat. I was in to see her yesterday. She is better. Hew Bradshaw is married. He married the widow Ford.
	Mr. Woodside was arrested the other day and sent up to Bragg. He has been in Nashville ever since the Yankees left Columbia. He came back the other day and was [paper missing] up as a spy. Report says his sentence is death.
	Billie is in the drugstore clerking for Bryen.
	I received your last letter and the papers you sent me. I read them and handed them to Alice as you requested. I would brake up housekeeping if it was not for your uncle Sam and that I expect you boys home some day. Mariah has a fine daughter. She has named it Ella Ford after Dr. Ford of Mt. Pleasant. He and his lady have been up and spent the day. He is an excellent physician. The Legislature of Indiana have met and they won&#8217;t vote another dollar nor another man to carry on this war. Report says they have troubles among themselves. Kentucky has sent a petition to Lincoln if he does not repeal his emancipation bill she will secede.
	There were [paper missing] of Forest&#8217;s men froze to death the last cold spell we had. I suppose they were neglected while standing picket. 
	I hope the Lord will protect you and spare you to return home again. Give my love to Jimmie. Tell him to write me. Jennie White sends her love to you and Jimmie. She has come up to stay awhile with me. Write every opportunity you have. Nothing more.
		Your mother
			S. A. Hamilton&#8221;</dc:relation>
<dc:description>Letter from Sarah Hamilton to Thomas Williams.  She discusses patients at the war hospital in Columbia, rumors of the Yankees at Franklin and concern for her son, "Tommie."</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Columbia (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:date>1863 January 25</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Hamilton, Sarah</dc:creator>
<dc:source>Hamilton-Williams Family Papers, 1850-1971</dc:source>
<dc:description>Sarah Ann Hamilton and her husband, the Rev. John Bell Hamilton, lived in the Williamsport area of Maury County, Tennessee. In 1861, Hamilton and his adopted son, Thomas Hamilton Willams, entered into the Confederate army. Captain Hamilton raised a company of cavalry which became part of the Second Tennessee Battalion, later part of the First Tennessee Regiment. Williams and Hamilton were stationed in Mississippi, and were in the retreat from Atlanta.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Civil War in the West; Civil War society; United States - History - 1783-1865; United States - History - 1849-1877; United States History - Civil War, 1861-1865; Maury County (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Social values; Domestic life; Soldiers; Military life; Military personnel; Military organizations; Armies; War; Cities &amp; towns</dc:subject>
<dc:relation>90-342</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>34080</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>TEXT</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:relation>1303</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law.  Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll1/id/89</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>