<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Correspondence from Robert Rutledge to Mary Minerva Rutledge, April 5, 1863</dc:title>
<dc:relation>[Page 1]

	May need a hat with my fine suit if I get it
Cumberland Gap Apr 5th 1863
Dear Wife
	I recd yours of March 31st 1863 on yesterday was truly glad to learn you were all well and it was with great pleasure I prerused your letter. My letters come so irregular that I hardly know when to look for letters from you. Last night was a very cold one and I froze out about an hour before day it is a cold bleak place out here, and does not suit me as far as climate and water is concerned but the way things now stand in the Army I believe I would prefer staying here to any where else until fall except it were on the Rail Road. You say that Pa talks somthing like coming to see me this Summer. I would love very much to see him but he cannot come without a great deal of trouble and probably would make himself sick he could not enjoy himself here because it is up hill both ways as it is downhill both ways in Ala. I want to see Pa but do not want him to undertake a trip to this place. Since the Alabamains, Gen Grays pets and the old rip himself have left we have been getting more to eat, also get a better quality have for the past week had splendid Flour &amp; Bacon and get Sugar at five cents pr pound and dried fruit at three cents pr pound, but fruit is not good, wish I could secure some Sugar to send home but there is no chance I have not been on duty for two weeks. Our left wing is under command of Maj Akin. That will account sufficently for my long release from duty. You say that I have a $500 bond and three $100&#8221;

[Page 2]

&#8220;interest bearing notes suppose that will include the $100 I sent by Mr. Edmundson. I want to try to have $1000 at interest or due me against the 16th day of May, at which time I will have served as a Lieut one year, and I want a little surplus to start on for my next year . If I were in Texas that much would buy me a right snug little home You and Pa seem to think that I am most wretchidy despondant because I cannot get home. I am tired of this war and tired of being seperated from the loved ones at home, but if God gives me health and I am not captured by the foe I will be at the side of the last man that will stand and contend at the point of the bayonett for our  homes and all that is near and dear to one in this life. I would be very happy to kiss the little baby Boy of mine that says his ugly Pappy has gone to Cum. Gap to shoot Yank. Also would be happy to see little Eva, hope she may have good health and be a good child to raise. In fact would be happy to see each any and all of you. We have drilled none since we came over here. Think Maj Akin will not drill us here if atall. Went out today and got a mess of wild greenes for dinner. They were superb to the palate of a soldier. I feel very well today but as for my health in general I fear it is on the decline. I would not weigh near so much as when I left home. Dr Atchly my special friend has left us. he applied for a furlough and it would not be granted and he resigned and went home. Write soon
Yours as ever RARutledge&#8221;</dc:relation>
<dc:description>Letter from Robert A. Rutledge to Mary Minerva Rutledge concerning the climate and his living conditions, provisions, and financial situation. He attempts to dissuade his father from visiting him at the camp but expresses his weariness of the war and being away from family.  He sends a special message to his son George and to "little Eva."</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Cumberland Gap (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:date>1863 April 5</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Rutledge, Robert A.</dc:creator>
<dc:source>Rutledge Family Letters, 1858-1861</dc:source>
<dc:description>Robert A. Rutledge was the son of G.R. Rutledge, the brother of Gamble Rutledge, and the husband of Mary Minerva Montgomery Rutledge.  Both Robert and Gamble served in the Confederate Army during the U.S. Civil War.  Robert was killed at Drury's Bluff, Virginia, in 1864.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Civil War in the West; Civil War society; United States - History - 1783-1865; United States - History - 1849-1877; United States History - Civil War, 1861-1865</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Civil Wars; War; Correspondence</dc:subject>
<dc:relation>1990-340</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>34175</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>TEXT</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:relation>1263</dc:relation>
<dc:relation>http://www.tennessee.gov/tsla/history/manuscripts/findingaids/90-340.pdf</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law.  Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll1/id/287</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>