<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Correspondence from Beck Wallace to Samuel R. Latta, June 7, 1861</dc:title>
<dc:relation>[Page 1]

&#8220;Macon June 7th
Dear Cousin Sam,
	I received a letter yesterday from Dr. Nheu of the New Con Grays informing me that you were Captain of a company in their regiment. I had a letter from Cousin Mary not long since, but &#8211; she said nothing about your leaving home. So that you may be sure I was surprised. You have the knowledge that you are doing right to cheer you, but it is terrible that you were obliged to leave home. I cannot tell you cousin mine how distressed I have been ever since I received the news. I have been thinking of Cousin Mary and the children so much&#8221;

[Page 2]

&#8220;I know she is a brave true woman but it must have been a heavy trial to give you up. When will these sad days be over? I try to hope for the best but it is hard to see any &#8220;light behind the cloud.&#8221; I had a letter from Mother last week Lucy has lost the Office. I think the man if man he can be called that was mean enough to take it from her must have buried everything in the way of generous and noble emotions. This letter will be given you by Dr. Nheu. I trust you will form his acquaintance. A better nobler man I never knew. He has been very kind to me, indeed he is one of the best friends I had in Macon. He is also an excellent&#8221;

[Page 3]

&#8220;physician,  but I hope and pray that you may never need his nor any one&#8217;s service in that line, while you are gone. I have another very good friend in the Macon Grays. Mr. Dougan, 1st Lieutenant I think you have heard me speak of him, both the gentleman mentioned have been very kind to me ever since I have been in Macon. Cousin Sam if you should get sick or wounded and want a nurse you have but to let me know, and I will go to you at once. You have always served just as near and dear to me as a brother. Never shall I forget your kindness to me when I came a stranger to a strange land. Which is now our home by adoption. I think I should&#8221;

[Page 4]

&#8220;go to Dyersburg soon after school closes. I shall write to Cousin Mary to morrow. If you have time let me hear from you if not I will hear through Cousin M. It is school time and I must close. Hoping and praying that you may be preserved from all danger, and soon be restored to your home. I am as ever your affectionate cousin.
						B. H. Wallace&#8221;</dc:relation>
<dc:description>Four-page letter from Beck Wallace to her cousin, Samuel R. Latta, of the 13th Tennessee Infantry, conveys her sorrow at his leaving home to fight for the Confederacy. She is deeply concerned for his wife and children. Beck, a teacher in Fayette County, writes of her plans to visit the family in Dyersburg and of her offer to nurse Samuel if he becomes sick or wounded.  Several mentions are made of "The Macon Grays" as being a part of Samuel's regiment.</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Macon (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:date>1861 June 7</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Wallace, R.H. (Beck)</dc:creator>
<dc:source>Samuel Rankin Latta Papers, 1848-1862</dc:source>
<dc:description>The 13th Tennessee Infantry was organized on June 4, 1861, and went into Confederate service on August 14, 1861.  Company B was designated "The Macon Grays." The company was made up of men from Fayette County.  Joe L. Cranberry, Ben F. Lightle, and William G. Mehane served as captains of this company.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Civil War in the West; Civil War society; United States - History - 1783-1865; United States - History - 1849-1877; United States History - Civil War, 1861-1865</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Civil Wars; War</dc:subject>
<dc:relation>1990-198</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>34136</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>TEXT</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:relation>84</dc:relation>
<dc:relation>http://state.tn.us/tsla/history/manuscripts/findingaids/90-198.pdf</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law.  Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll1/id/219</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>