<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Correspondence from John S. Brien to John C. Crittenden, February 28, 1862</dc:title>
<dc:relation>[Page 1]

&#8220;Nashville Tennessee
Feby 28th 1862
Honl John J. Crittenton
	Washington
		City
			Dear Sir:
					Genl Buels Division of the Army has been in and round this city for several days. My heart is sincerely rejoiced that it reached and occupied the city and county without the necessity of sheding one drop of the blood of one of our citizens. The approach of his army was greatly feared by many of our citizens, some of the prominent ones fled the state. Then however wise comparatively small, the great body of the people remained, and in afords me unspeakable pleasure to say, that the conduct of the army has been such as to raise the admiration of both the friends and former enemys of the Union. I can say in all candor, that I have never in all my life, seen such a revolution in public sentiment, in so short a time. The high toned conduct of the officers &#8211; the just appreciation of and observance of the private rights and property of the people upon the part of the whole army, is the theme of all conversations. And must if continued (of which I have not doubt) win the state back to its allegence to the Union.
	Now Govn. what I want to say to you &amp; which which the object of this communication. If the government, should feel it to be its duty (as it may ultimately be) to make us a provisional&#8221;

[Page 2]

&#8220;government, ask them to give us time for this revolution to become full throughout and complete before that be done. It is now working gloriously and a little more time to enable Genl Buel to disabuse the public mind as to the objects and purposes of his government, will in my opinion do more to win the state back than any battle he has or may win and I am not sure that if Tennessee takes the cause now indicating and to the extent I supose it will that there will not be many more battles, and the slaughter of our citizens and friends will thereby be stayed, a consumation devoutly to be desired by every Christian.
	I will not attempt to infer[?] these suggestions by argument. The reasons will present themself to your mind at once. And better ones than I could give.
	I parted with your son Gen. Thomas Crittenden minutes since he has been in good health and is general very well, but desired me to say that he had a slight derangement of the bowels and was on that account relieved from duty today, but would be all right by tomorrow.
	I need not undertake to give you the history of the army and the battles recently[?] in this state as you will have heard it from headquarters before this reaches you.
	Gen will you give me from time time to time the news of the government as to these states. You see I regard the whole as virtually evident for which I do sincerely thank God.&#8221;

[Page 3]

&#8220;Allow me to thank you personally for what you have done towards the solution of this country.
I am not sure that this solution will in after years, be rejected by the lovers of good government. For the reason that it will have established an important fact. That the Government of the limited states had and has an inherant power to sustain itself.
Excuse this disconnected note. With high regard and Esteem am ever your
					Sincere friend &amp; obt sevt 
					John S Brien&#8221;</dc:relation>
<dc:description>A three-page letter dated February 28, 1862, from John S. Brien to John C. Crittenden. Brien rejoices that Buell's troops "occupied the city and country without the necessity of shedding one drop of blood." He argues that property rights must be protected to "win the state back to its allegiance to the Union."</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Nashville (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:date>1862 February 28</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Brien, John Smith</dc:creator>
<dc:source>Buell-Brien Papers, 1805-1943</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Civil War in the West; Civil War society; United States - History - 1783-1865; United States - History - 1849-1877; United States History - Civil War, 1861-1865</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Correspondence; Cities &amp; towns; Campaigns &amp; battles; Troop movements; Surrenders; Military retreats; Generals; Civil Wars; War</dc:subject>
<dc:relation>267</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>34119</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>TEXT</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:relation>829</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law.  Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll1/id/132</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>