<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Corner of First Avenue North and Church Street architectural survey, 1980</dc:title>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Business; Capitol City; Downtown Nashville; Architectural surveys--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Details; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture, Victorian--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Commercial buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic preservation--Tennessee--Nashville; History--Societies, etc.--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; First Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Church Street (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:description>Detailed architectural and historical survey of the building located on the southwest corner of First Avenue North and Church Street,consisting of photographs and documents created in 1980. Black and white photographs show the Church Street side of the building, in almost its full entirety.  Documents contain architectural descriptions. This building was built around 1910. It is made of brick and is four stories tall. Forms part of Historic Nashville Inc. Downtown Survey, Series I. Downtown Survey.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church St., Nashville, Tennessee 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1980</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still image; Text; Photographs; Manuscripts</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>HNIDTS-Prop175</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. Downtown Survey, Series I. Downtown Survey</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1980-1989</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content.  This content is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without written permission.  Please contact the repository for permission to use this content.  </dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll22/id/156</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>