<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Combat engineers engage in horseplay as break from work</dc:title>
<dc:description>One of Brock's fellow soldiers resting with his helmet to his side. He is probably taking a break from doing engineer work. Another soldier at the left is shaking a shovel at him in jest.</dc:description>
<dc:description>As a soldier in the 2nd Infantry Division's 2nd Engineer Combat Battalion, Company D attached to the 72nd Tank Battalion, David Franklin Brock built roads, bridges, and bunkers for the front while often under enemy fire. Brock, a Demolitions Specialist, detonated explosives and laid and cleared land mines. As with all Combat Engineers, he was trained in combat infantry, and, when needed, functioned as an infantry soldier. The summer of 1952 found Dog Company on the line west of Chorwon repairing heavy monsoon damage to roads and bridges, mass producing prefabricated log bunkers for the 2nd Division through Operation Abe Lincoln, and designing a new mobile attack bunker for the infantry that could be quickly assembled for overhead cover and protection. The 2nd Engineers also laid minefields, tactical wire, napalm and booby traps, often under mortar and artillery fire, to strengthen the hill outposts of Old Baldy, T-Bone, and Arrowhead Ridge. Attention was then turned to improving supply routes and shelter and installation construction for the winter. After coming out of reserve in late January of 1953, the 2nd Engineers supported infantry regiments in battle positions in the British Commonwealth section. Company D maintained the main supply routes to the front, in general support of the division, and continued to build bunkers for the 2nd Infantry Division. Another stint in reserve was followed by more support of the 2nd Division by the battalion beginning in July of 1953 in the Chorwon-Kumhwa sector. Here engineers often confronted enemy patrols and heavy mortar, artillery, and sniper fire. Toward the close of the war, Company D worked as engineers during the day and served as blocking infantry at night at the position known as The Hook.  During the American Revolution, George Washington appointed the first engineer officers, and engineers have served in combat in all the wars to follow. The 2nd Engineer Combat Battalion identifies as its parent unit the Battalion of Engineers, initially organized on August 3, 1861. Prior to the Korean War, the 2nd Engineers and its lineage had been awarded campaign streamers from the Civil War, the Spanish American War, the Philippine Insurrection, World War I, and World War II. In the Korean War, the 2nd Engineer Combat Battalion protected the retreating Eighth Army and 2nd Infantry Division at Kunu-ri when U.S. and U.N. troops were surprised and overrun by the Chinese in late fall of 1950. As a result of a missed communication, the 2nd Engineer Combat Battalion was left as the last unit in opposition to the Chinese onslaught and was decimated on November 30, 1950. </dc:description>
<dc:date>1953</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Brock, David Franklin, 1931 -</dc:creator>
<dc:coverage>Korea</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>David Franklin Brock Korean War Photograph Collection</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Korean War, 1950 - 1953; Korean War, 1950 - 1953 -- United States; Korean War, 1950 - 1953 -- Military personnel; Korean War, 1950 - 1953 -- Engineering and construction; Military engineers; United States. Army. Infantry Division, 2nd. Engineer Combat Battalion, 2nd</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Photographs; Soldiers; Military personnel; Engineers; Helmets; Shovels</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>brock0024</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>Still Image</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dcterms:medium>Photographs</dcterms:medium>
<dc:rights>While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees, that may be necessary for the intended use. </dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll32/id/49</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>