<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>C-124 Globemaster pictured at military airstrip</dc:title>
<dc:description>Pictured is a C-124 Globemaster four-engine plane at a military airstrip in Korea. Tanks could be driven into the open front of the plane; it was three-decks high inside the cargo hold. This plane is surrounded by hospital ambulances. Possibly the wounded are being picked up from this location. Brock flew in the same type of plane to Tokyo and back. The plane was 40,000 lbs. overweight and had mechanical trouble with an engine when taking off from Korea; the exact same plane carried Brock back to Korea from Japan following his R&amp;R.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Globemasters joined the other types of propeller-driven transport aircraft toward the end of the Korean War. Compared to the more common C-54 Skymasters and C-119 Flying Boxcars, the C-124 Globemasters were giants. The Globemasters were utilized in both of the two categories of Korean War transport aircraft, the tactical (intratheater) airlift of the Far East Air Force (FEAF) Combat Cargo Command and the strategic (intercontinental) airlift of the Military Air Transport Service (MATS). The United Nations Far East Air Force used fifteen air bases in Japan for combat support over the course of the war, and built or improved fifty-five airfields in Korea.</dc:description>
<dc:date>Spring 1953</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Brock, David Franklin, 1931 -</dc:creator>
<dc:coverage>Korea</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>David Franklin Brock Korean War Photograph Collection</dc:source>
<dcterms:instructionalMethod>5.63; US.77; Korean War; Modern United States</dcterms:instructionalMethod>
<dc:subject>Korean War, 1950 - 1953; Korean War, 1950 - 1953 -- United States; C-124 (Transport plane); Transport planes; Korean War, 1950 - 1953 -- Transportation; Military installations; Airstrips; Airfields; Ambulances; Korean War, 1950 - 1953 --Medical care</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Photographs; Air bases; Military facilties; Transport planes; Ambulances</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>brock0076</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>Still Image</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dcterms:medium>Photographs</dcterms:medium>
<dc:rights>While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees, that may be necessary for the intended use. </dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll32/id/100</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>