<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Korean War veteran David Franklin Brock oral history interview</dc:title>
<dc:description>Transcript of a five-hour telephone interview conducted over the course of two days with Korean War veteran David Franklin Brock, Corporal of the 2nd Infantry Division, 2nd Engineer Combat Battalion, Company D by Darla Brock, Tennessee State Library and Archives Manuscripts Archivist and Brock's daughter. Numbering of the questions correspond to the U.S. Army Military History Institute's Korean War Era Service Survey Questionnaire. Brock's answers appear in bold. Interjections by the interviewer appear inside parentheses.
Note: The opinions, views, and language expressed herein are solely those of the interviewee. They do not reflect or represent the opinions or views of the Tennessee State Library and Archives.</dc:description>
<dc:description>At the age of twenty, David Franklin Brock, a farm boy from Van Buren County, had only been out of the state of Tennessee once in his life before his country called him a world away. Brock served from January of 1952 to October of 1953 in the Korean War. He trained at Fort Leonard Wood, Missouri. He attained the rank of corporal as a combat engineer with the Second Infantry Division, the famed Indianhead Division "Second to None".  His unit built roads, bridges, and bunkers for the front while often under enemy fire. As a demolitions specialist, he detonated explosives and laid and cleared mines. As with all combat engineers, he was trained in combat infantry, and, when needed, functioned as an infantry soldier. During his tour of duty, he was stationed in Korea's Chorwon Valley, Kumhwa region, and at the Hook, a bend on the Samichon River near the border between North and South Korea. Brock came home on active reserve to his sweetheart, Laura Mae Phillips. They married in 1954 and made their home in Sparta, Tennessee. Besides recording the Korean War experiences of Corporal David Franklin Brock, this transcript figures in the initial efforts in 2011 of the Tennessee State Library and Archives to record the contributions of Tennessee's veterans of both the Korean War and the Vietnam War through an ongoing project entitled Tennessee Remembers. Tennessee Remembers seeks to honor the men and women who served in Korea and Vietnam by preserving as only an archives can the history of their wartime experiences. The goal of this project is to collect original documents, photographs, and memorabilia related to the in-country experiences of these veterans to be preserved for future generations and made accessible for research and educational purposes. As a part of Tennessee Remembers, the Tennessee State Library and Archives has developed a Korean War veterans and a Vietnam War veterans questionnaire that will give individuals an opportunity to document and preserve their war experiences for future generations.  In 2011, with the support of Secretary of State Tre Hargett and State Librarian and Archivist Chuck Sherrill, Dr. Wayne Moore headed a Veterans Committee made up of State Library and Archives staff members charged with designing questionnaires relevant to both groups of veterans. At the committee's request, Manuscripts Archivist Darla Brock posed selected questions from the U.S. Army Military History Institute's Korea War Era Service Survey Questionnaire to her father, Korean War veteran David Franklin Brock. His responses and reactions to these questions assisted the committee in designing the Korean War questionnaire. Similar connections were made with Christopher Ammons, a Vietnam War veteran, who donated a collection of materials to the Tennessee State Library and Archives. Beginning in the spring of 2011, staff videographer Todd Spainhour conducted filming for the project's promotion with these two veterans and Vietnam veterans Bud Alley and Tennessee State Representative David A. Shepard. The institution's Exhibits Committee, chaired by James Castro, also began planning for a veterans exhibit revolving around the donated materials of soldiers Brock and Ammons; Todd Spainhour headed up the Korean War exhibit (Forgotten War, Unforgettable Memories: The Korean War Experiences of Cpl. David Brock), and James Castro organized the Vietnam War exhibit (Counting the Days and Getting Short: The Vietnam War Experience of Christopher Ammons). By 2012, the questionnaires were available in print and on the State Library and Archives web site, and donations of materials were being received. A reception on November 9, 2012, in the Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives Memorial Hall marked the opening of the dual exhibits honoring Korean War and Vietnam War veterans through the service of Brock and Ammons and promoting the Tennessee Remembers project. Secretary of State Tre Hargett presided over the ceremony, with David Franklin Brock and Christopher Ammons present. Commissioner of Veterans Affairs Many-Bears Grinder addressed the crowd that attended the opening as well. The Tennessee State Library and Archives continues to solicit donations to enrich its holdings and accept completed questionnaires from Korean War and Vietnam War veterans who were living in Tennessee at the time of the war or veterans who currently reside in Tennessee.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2011 January</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Brock, David Franklin, 1931 -</dc:creator>
<dc:coverage>Sparta (Tenn.); Nashville (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>David Franklin Brock Korean War Photograph Collection</dc:source>
<dcterms:instructionalMethod>5.63; US.77; Korean War; Modern United States</dcterms:instructionalMethod>
<dc:subject>Korean War, 1950 - 1953 -- Personal narratives; Korean War, 1950 - 1953; Korean War, 1950 - 1953 -- United States; Korean War, 1950 - 1953 -- Veterans; Veterans; Veterans -- United States; Veterans -- Tennessee; Sparta (Tenn.) </dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>DavidBrockInterview</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dcterms:medium>Interviews</dcterms:medium>
<dc:rights>While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees, that may be necessary for the intended use. </dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll32/id/172</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>