<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Brock sitting in front of 2nd Division Friendship Home for Korean orphans</dc:title>
<dc:description>Brock in front of the 2nd Division Orphanage--referred to as the 2nd Infantry Division Friendship Home. It was built in June of 1952 at Chong P'yong-Ni by Korean carpenters. Brock is pictured with the 2nd Division emblem. The Division sponsored and supported it. Brock's squad was transported by truck to work at the home. They insulated the overhead where the ceiling had been sweating. </dc:description>
<dc:description>Over the course of its history, the Second Indianhead Infantry Division has fought in four wars, obtained over twenty campaign participation credits, and has yielded forty Medal of Honor recipients. The Division organized on October 26, 1917 at Bourmont, Haute Marne, France, and first saw combat in the Battle of Belleau Wood. The Second engaged in six Western Front campaigns during World War I, stood the most decorated American Division of the American Expeditionary Forces (AEF) at the end of the fighting, and sported what was termed the most coveted shoulder flash of the AEF. Based out of Fort Sam Houston at San Antonio at the time, the Indianhead Division was one of only three divisions remaining intact and on active duty throughout the interwar period. World War II found the Tomahawk Warriors going ashore at Normandy and fighting in six European campaigns. The Second Division proved the first unit sailing from the United States to reach Korea following the outbreak of hostilities in the summer of 1950. The Warrior Division was the first to break out of the Pusan Perimeter; led the Eighth Army drive to the Manchurian Border; at a terrible cost, protected the Eighth Army in its withdrawal upon Chinese intervention in November of 1950; and triumphed in the February 1951 Battle of Chipyong-ni, considered by many the turning point of the war. The unit helped defeat the enemy's spring offensive of 1951 and continued to fight outpost and hilltop battles until the conclusion of the conflict. In July of 1965, the Division returned to be stationed in South Korea as the Second Infantry Division/ROK-U.S. Combined Division with a mission of guard the Demilitarized Zone (DMZ) and help maintain peace in the region. The distinctive nickname and shoulder sleeve insignia of the Second Division grew out of a contest initiated by 2nd Supply Trains Commander Colonel William F. Herringshaw to produce a design to emblazon the Division's trucks. A combination of the winning designs (1st place an Indian Head and 2nd place a star) yielded the accepted vehicle insignia. Toward the end of the year, the design was chosen for the Division's shoulder patch, incorporating specifically the sculpted Indian Head appearing on the American five dollar gold piece. A total of forty-four variations of the insignia sprang up to denote different components of the Division, until a June 1920 directive deemed the design for all Indianhead Division personnel to be a black shield with a white star and Indian Head.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1952</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Brock, David Franklin, 1931 -</dc:creator>
<dc:coverage>Korea</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>David Franklin Brock Korean War Photograph Collection</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Korean War, 1950 - 1953; Korean War, 1950 - 1953 -- United States; Korean War, 1950 - 1953 -- Military personnel; Korean War, 1950 - 1953 -- Engineering and construction; Military engineers; United. States. Army. 2nd Infantry Division; United States. Army. Infantry Division, 2nd. Engineer Combat Battalion, 2nd; Korean War, 1950 - 1953 -- Children -- Korea (South); Korean War, 1950 - 1953 -- Refugees; Korean War, 1950 - 1953 -- Charities; Orphanages -- Korea (South); Military insignia</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Photographs; Engineers; Soldiers; Military personnel; Orphanages; Emblems; Insignia</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>brock0051</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>Still Image</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dcterms:medium>Photographs</dcterms:medium>
<dc:rights>While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees, that may be necessary for the intended use. </dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll32/id/76</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>