<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>N. Hirsch &amp; Co. and Trade Palace</dc:title>
<dc:description>Exterior view of N. Hirsch &amp; Co. and Trade Palace on Market Street, with people standing in front of the building and in the windows. Signs on the building advertise dry goods, clothing, boots, shoes, hats, carpets, and oilcloths. The building has the words "wholesale and retail dry goods &amp; clothing" painted on the brick. The merchandise on the sidewalk includes trunks, shoes, and suits. The two-story brick buildings for the businesses have crow-stepped gables. N. Hirsch &amp; Co.'s second-floor windows have rectangular lintels, while the Trade Palace windows have decorative lintels. </dc:description>
<dc:description>In 1870, Nathan Hirsch opened the N. Hirsch Store on Union Street in downtown Nashville. At the time, it was one of the earliest Jewish-owned businesses in Nashville.  The store's location changed multiple times in the downtown area, having addresses on Cherry Street, College Street, and the Public Square. N. Hirsch and Company would later merge with a store owned by his son, Samuel Hirsch, and son-in-law Sam Lowenstein. </dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Nashville (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>Library Photograph Collection</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Storefronts; Stores, Retail; Jewish merchants; Commercial buildings; Architecture and history; Facades; Historic districts; Historic buildings; Tennessee--History; Streets--Tennessee; Historic districts--Tennessee; Historic districts; Historic buildings</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Business districts; Commercial streets; Storefronts; Facades; Stores &amp; shops; Dry goods stores; Clothing stores; Chests; Boots; Clothing &amp; dress; Merchandise displays; Suits (Clothing); Textiles; Painted wall signs; Signs (Notices); Architectural decorations &amp; ornament; Lintels; Windows</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>3240</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isFormatOf>809</dcterms:isFormatOf>
<dc:source>Drawer 16, Folder 164</dc:source>
<dcterms:medium>Photographs</dcterms:medium>
<dc:rights>No copyright - United States: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll25/id/1427</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>