<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Market Street</dc:title>
<dc:description>Illustration of Market Street (Second Avenue) looking south showing the buildings and businesses. The street scene includes people on the sidewalks and horse-and-buggies on the street. An advertisement for a business is painted on the side of the building. The street has electric lines and utility poles. The sign for McKeon Saddles &amp; Harnesses hangs from outside of the business, and their display includes a saddle. Clothing is hanging in front of a storefront. An advertisement for Hillman, Buford &amp; Just and the Tennessee Iron Store, accompanied by an automobile illustration, hangs from an electric line. An inset view shows the Nicholson House located on Church Street.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Nashville&#8217;s early trading and manufacturing ventures are associated with Second Avenue (originally Market Street before a name change in 1904).  Access to the Cumberland River and railroads made the location ideal for a business district. Many merchants and manufacturers used First and Second Avenue for their storehouses and warehouses. Occupants of the street came from all industries. The buildings on Second Avenue are representative of the transition in the late 19the century to brick buildings with significant architectural ornamentation.   M. McKeon, operated by Michael McKeon,  was a wholesale saddle and harness manufacture whose advertisements of goods included: handmade carriage harnesses, barouche harnesses, buggy harnesses, English coupe harnesses, horse blankets, gents oil, coats, hats, rain covers, and lap robes.  Addresses for the business over the years included: 55 South College Street, 67 South College Street, 118 Broad Street, and 119 North Market Street.  Hillman, Buford &amp; Justi, formerly Hillman Bro. &amp; Sons, owned the Tennessee Iron Store, which was the sole manufacturer of Tennessee Charcoal Bloom and Kentucky Charcoal. The company operated a rolling mill, allowing them to offer various iron products such as merchant bar, round square, sheet, heads, fire-box, and boilerplate Iron. The company's advertisements marketed their product to manufacturers of wheelbarrows, buggy materials, hardware, railroad supplies, mining supplies, blacksmith tools, stovepipes, and scalding troughs. Over the years, locations of the Tennessee Iron Store included 18-20 South Market Street and 52-54 North Market Street.  The Nicholson House, located at Church and Spruce Street, was a hotel operated between the 1870s and 1880s by proprietor Isaac C. Nicholson. The hotel started as a boarding house, but its popularity required the property to create several additions. The results of the additions made the hotel resemble a series of connected houses formed in a  square. The hotel was later replaced by the Tulane Hotel. </dc:description>
<dc:date>1887</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>Nashville (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:publisher>Ward Brothers (Columbus, Ohio)</dc:publisher>
<dc:coverage>Columbus (Ohio)</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>Library Photograph Collection</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Tennessee--History; Streets--Tennessee; Historic districts--Tennessee; Historic districts; Historic buildings</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Business districts; Commercial streets; Structural elements; Architectural elements; Storefronts; Facades; Stores &amp; shops; Saddlery; Carts &amp; wagons; Sidewalks; Brickwork; Doors &amp; doorways; Awnings; Windows; Painted wall signs; Signs (Notices); Advertisements; Storefronts; Drugstores; Window displays; Pedestrians; City &amp; town life; Electric lines; Utility poles; Horses</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>27858</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Drawer 13, Folder 170</dc:source>
<dcterms:medium>Illustrations</dcterms:medium>
<dc:rights>Copyright not evaluated: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll25/id/1425</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>