<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Dudley Brothers and Berry's Wholesale Drug Company</dc:title>
<dc:description>Exterior view showing Dudley Bros., Berry's Wholesale Drug Co., and neighboring buildings on Second Avenue. The text on the inset stone panel at the top of the Berry Wholesale Drug Co. reads "Hooper 1924".  A sign hangs from the building with the name of the company. A van for Berry Wholesale Drug Co. is in front of the entrance. The painted sign for Dudley Bros. is faintly visible above the second-floor windows. A sign on the exterior of 134-136 Second Avenue advertises H. G. Lipscomb &amp; Co. Wholesale Hardware located at 138-142 Second Avenue.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The Charles Nelson &amp; Co. building, located at 134-136 Second Avenue, is an Italianate style three-story brick building constructed sometime after 1890. Brackets support the overhanging cornice. The fa&#231;ade includes Doric pilasters, modillions, and decorative egg-and-tongue motif molding. Prominent distiller Charles Nelson purchased the property in 1888, and he designed the building to meet his needs as a liquor distributor. The building housed Chas. Nelson &amp; Co.  Greenbrier Distillery, Wholesale Whiskies &amp; Fruit Brandies until 1909. Other occupants of the 134-136 Second Avenue building include Southern Woodenware &amp; Hardware Co. and H.G. Lipscomb.   The Dudley Bros. &amp; Lipscomb Hardware Co. building, located at 132 Second Avenue, is an Italianate style three-story brick building constructed around 1890. The building has a dentilled cornice, corner pilasters, and a limestone stringcourse. The window fenestration includes segmented brick arches. According to earlier images of the building, the structure next door was identical to the building at 132 and belonged to the company at the time. Dudley Brothers &amp; Lipscomb Hardware Co. was the successor to Dodd, Dudley &amp; Lipscomb Co., which had been founded in 1883 and located on Broad Street. The new company moved from that location to 132 Second Avenue in 1888. The firm became Dudley Bros. after Horace Lipscomb left in 1890 to start his own business. Previous occupants of the 132 Second Avenue building include Parlin &amp; Orendorff Co., Nashville Produce Co., Nashville Spring &amp; Mattress Co., and W. T. Jordan &amp; Sons.  The Hooper Building, located at 128-130 Second Avenue, was a three-story, commercial-style brick building constructed in 1924 by John M. Hooper. The building has an inset stone panel with the name of the building and the date of construction. The upper floors have large, linear groupings of windows.  Starting in 1908, the Hooper Grocery Company began leasing the buildings at 129, 130, and 131 Second Avenue as their headquarters. The business was formerly located at 135 Second Avenue and moved due to the need to expand. A fire in October of 1923 amounted to $325,000 of damage to the business and other buildings surrounding it. The company was able to move back to the building in 1924. Significant alterations were made to the building over the years, with much of it demolished in 1994.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1970</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Boucher, Jack E.; Historic American Buildings Survey</dc:creator>
<dc:coverage>Nashville (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>Library Photograph Collection</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Tennessee--History; Streets--Tennessee; Historic districts--Tennessee; Historic districts; Historic buildings; Architecture--Details; Whiskey industry; Alcoholic beverage industry; Selling--Whiskey</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Commercial facilities; Business districts; Commercial streets; Structural elements; Architectural elements; Storefronts; Facades; Stores &amp; shops; Pilasters; Stringcourses; Moldings; Paneling; Egg &amp; dart moldings; Doric order; Distilling industry; Liquor stores; Drugstores; Hardware stores; Grocery stores</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>27832</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Drawer 18, Folder 197</dc:source>
<dcterms:medium>Photographs</dcterms:medium>
<dc:rights>Copyright not evaluated: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll25/id/1440</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>