<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Watkins Block</dc:title>
<dc:description>View of Watkins Block Building on Second Avenue showing Mid-South Shoe Co., Standard Sales Co., and Philips &amp; Quarles Hardware Co. Signs on the businesses advertise health aids, cosmetics, drugs, hosiery, gloves, paper goods, housewares, brooms, mops, light bulbs, radios, chinaware, glassware, sunglasses, Timex watches, jewelry, and Benjamin Moore paints. The entrance to Standard Sales Co. has a sign with an arrow to the entrance. </dc:description>
<dc:description>The Watkins Block, located at 108-114 Second Avenue, was built in 1875 by brickmaker Samuel Watkins, a prominent builder in Nashville. The building is a three-story, brick Italianate style building. Paired brackets support the large overhanging cornice. Brick dentil ornamentation runs above the third-story windows. Shouldered metal moldings with keystones accentuate the round windows on the upper floors. The center structure of the block has a dated parapet. Four years after the construction of the building, Samuel Watkins started on plans for the Watkins Institute. Historically, the building had an assortment of different occupiers, such as Herman Bros., Lindauer &amp; Co., the largest wholesale house in 1889, and the laboratories, offices, and warehouses Spurlock Neal Co. Wholesale druggists since the 1890&#8217;s. </dc:description>
<dc:date>1952</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>Nashville (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>Library Photograph Collection</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Tennessee--History; Streets--Tennessee; Historic districts--Tennessee; Historic districts; Historic buildings; Architecture--Details</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Business districts; Commercial streets; Structural elements; Architectural elements; Storefronts; Facades; Stores &amp; shops; Cornices; Architectural decorations &amp; ornaments; Brickwork; Parapets; Windows; Keystones; Hardware stores; Shoe stores; Signs (Notices); Advertisements</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>3557</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Drawer 18, Folder 183</dc:source>
<dcterms:medium>Photographs</dcterms:medium>
<dc:rights>Copyright not evaluated: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll25/id/1445</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>