<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Apartment and storefront on Second Avenue</dc:title>
<dc:description>View of the apartment and storefront with awning on Second Avenue. No parking signs and a for lease sign are visible from the street. The area in front of the building is blocked off. One car is parked on the street and the back of a moving truck is open. The building at 174 Second Avenue has a fire escape. The word &#8220;fire&#8221; is visible in three of the windows of the building at 176 Second Avenue. </dc:description>
<dc:description>The Berry &amp; Demoville building, located at 174 Second Avenue, is a four-story, Italianate style brick building constructed around 1875. The building has an arched parapet, corbeled brick, and cornice supported by brackets around the roof area. The top of each window has detailed stone hood molding. The metal cornice above the storefront has elaborate end caps and decorative medallions. The property was owned by Charles Nelson, who also owned 134, 136, and 172 Second Avenue. In 1908, the drug firm Berry and Demoville occupied the building.  The building located at 176 Second Avenue is a four-story, Italianate-style brick building constructed around 1875. Properties 174 and 176 are nearly identical in construction, with one of the main differences being the arched windows at 176 Second Avenue. Both buildings have similar arched parapets, corbeled brick, window molding, pilasters, stringcourses, and large cornices.  The Orr Bros. owned the building from 1876 through 1880, with Robert Orr and family associated with it from 1881 through 1951. In 1890, the building was occupied by Orr,  Jackson and Co., a wholesale grocery firm. The company occupied the entire building, utilizing the third-story operating as a factory in 1908 to produce extracts such as O.J. No. 11. Previous addresses for the building include 42, 58, and 60 South Market Street.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1970</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Boucher, Jack E.; Historic American Buildings Survey</dc:creator>
<dc:coverage>Nashville (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>Library Photograph Collection</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Tennessee--History; Streets--Tennessee; Historic districts--Tennessee; Historic districts; Historic buildings; Architecture--Details</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Business districts; Commercial streets; Structural elements; Architectural elements; Storefronts; Facades; Stores &amp; shops; Parapets; Brickwork; Cornices; Pilasters; Stringcourses; Windows; Apartments; Trucks; Automobiles; Signs (Notices); Awnings</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>27829</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Drawer 18, Folder 197</dc:source>
<dcterms:medium>Photographs</dcterms:medium>
<dc:rights>Copyright not evaluated: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll25/id/1424</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>