<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Pulaski City School</dc:title>
<dc:description>Pulaski City School Drum and Bugle Corps, a group of young African-American students.</dc:description>
<dc:description>In 1889, the City of Pulaski erected a two-story building for African American students. This building, no longer standing, was located near Fort Hill at the corner of what is now North 3rd Street and McLean Street. The Pulaski City School, under the operation of the City Board of Education, originally served grades one through ten, later adding an eleventh grade, and required a tuition fee of $0.50 to $1.00 from students living outside of the city. This school served as the only African American school in Pulaski until around 1900 when J.T. Bridgeforth, who later became the first principal of Bridgeforth High School, established the first black public school operated by the county in Pulaski. By the 1930s, African-American schools were located in almost every community in Giles County. Almost all of these were elementary schools as few students continued their education to the high school level. Most went to work to provide additional income for their family rather than continue on for additional schooling.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1946</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>Pulaski (Tenn.); Giles County (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>Looking Back at Tennessee Photograph Collection, 1890-1981</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Students; Children; Marching bands; Marching percussion; Bands; Drums (Musical instruments); Band uniforms</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>8128</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>Still Image</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dcterms:medium>Photographs</dcterms:medium>
<dc:rights>Copyright not evaluated: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll50/id/395</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>