<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Bledsoe County "Colored Citizens' Petition" Against the Repeal of the Free School System</dc:title>
<dc:description>A "Colored Citizens' Petition" to the General Assembly protesting the repeal of the Free School System. The text of the petition is the same as the Free School petition from Hamilton Co. Like the Hamilton Co. petition above, none of the signers of the petition is individually identified as "colored." All of the names appear to be signed by the same hand. 60 total signatures.</dc:description>
<dc:description>After the Civil War, Radical Republican governments helped to establish free public schools across the south to educate both black and white children. The Free Schools received immense support from African Americans in particular, and the schools educated freed adults in addition to children. Not merely an educational tool, the schools represented a way out of poverty for newly freed people struggling to build their lives. The Free School system was a political flashpoint for white conservative backlash as the frustration of disenfranchised former rebels clashed with African Americans who rallied around the cause of protecting the schools and petitioned the legislature for such protections.  </dc:description>
<dc:date>1867-1869</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>Bledsoe County (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>RG 60: General Assembly Bills, Petitions, Reports, Etc., 1790-present</dc:source>
<dc:source>RG 60</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Reconstruction (U.S. history, 1865-1877)--Tennessee</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>45078</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Box 354, Folder 6</dc:source>
<dc:relation>Reconstruction in Tennessee</dc:relation>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:format>Legislative Records</dc:format>
<dc:rights>No copyright - United States: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/;</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/reconaa/id/398</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>