<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Chieu Hoi leaflet with weeping mother imagining son killed in fighting</dc:title>
<dc:rights>While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law.  Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>Black and white two-sided propaganda leaflet conveys the anguish of a mother as she cries over the image she envisions of her son, killed in fighting.  The leaflet number is on the front (SP.2141).  The reverse contains a list of eleven advantages/rewards;  received from the government by surrendering.  Fifteen million copies of this leaflet were printed in December of 1967.  Portions of the front image and theme would be incorporated into another leaflet that would feature a lengthy, sentimental poem.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Mothers; Families; Dead persons; Dreaming</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Vietnam War, 1961-1975; Chieu Hoi Program; Counterinsurgency -- Vietnam; Political refugees -- Vietnam; Vietnam -- Politics and government -- 1945-1975; Propaganda; Leaflets dropped from aircraft; Intelligence service</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Vietnam (Republic)</dc:coverage>
<dc:date>1967</dc:date>
<dc:description>The Chieu Hoi (Open Arms) program represents a 10-year psychological operation launched by the South Vietnamese government in April 1963 to encourage the "return" or "rally" of Viet-Cong, North Vietnamese Army soldiers,; and Communist sympathizers. An estimated 160,000 defections occurred, but the program did not tend to sway hardcore Viet-Cong , North Vietnamese officers, or the more educated of enemy forces.</dc:description>
<dc:relation>I mourn for those who are dead and gone,&lt;br&gt;
Your shattered family caused by those enslaved to Communism.&lt;br&gt;
Your aged mother and tiny child: exhausted and bitter, but waiting still.&lt;br&gt;
When will the day come, that day of togetherness? (Translations provided by the Tennessee Foreign Language Institute)</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Christopher D. Ammons Papers, 1967-1970</dc:source>
<dc:relation>2010-086</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>35964</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>IMAGE</dc:type>
<dc:format>JPEG</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll13/id/350</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>