<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Wade, Edie Berry</dc:title>
<dc:description>United States. Army; 3rd Army; Engineers Corps</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Johnson City (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Washington County (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>36.31344</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>-82.35347</dc:coverage>
<dc:date>1882 September 9</dc:date>
<dc:date>1919 February 4</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>Koblenz (Germany)</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>White</dc:description>
<dc:source>Tennessee World War I Gold Star Records, 1918-1924 (RG 53)</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Condolence notes; Military correspondence; United States. Army--Records and correspondence; World War, 1914-1918--Correspondence; World War, 1914-1918--Poetry</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Air raid shelters--France--Paris; Air raid warning systems--France--Paris; Airplanes--Piloting; American Committee for Devastated France; Armies--Medical and sanitary affairs; Automobiles--England; Automobiles--France; Aviation; Bairnsfather, Bruce, 1887-1959; Bicycles--France; Cathedrals--France; Catholic Church--France; Cemeteries--France; Cemeteries--Germany; Cercle de l'union interalliee; Champs-Elysees (Paris, France); Chaplin, Charlie, 1889-1977; Chateau-Thierry, Battle of, Chateau-Thierry, France, 1918; Chateau de Fontainebleau (Fontainebleau, France); Chateau de Versailles (Versailles, France); Christianity; Church of the Holy Trinity (Stratford-upon-Avon, England); Corelli, Marie, 1855-1924; Clothing and dress--France; Daylight saving--France; Distinguished Service Cross (U.S.); Dwellings--France; Eglise de la Madeleine (Paris, France); France; French Revolution; Foch, Ferdinand, 1851-1929; Germans--Racial discrimination; Great Britain. Army. Women's Army Auxiliary Corps; Great Britain. Royal Navy; Hearst, William Randolph, 1863-1951; Howitzers--Germany; Influenza Epidemic, 1918-1919; Jardin des Tuileries (Paris, France); Jazz; Knights of the Round Table (San Francisco, Calif.); Lafayette, Marie Joseph Paul Yves Roch Gilbert Du Motier, marquis de, 1757-1834; Louis XVI, King of France, 1754-1793; London (England); Marie Antoinette, Queen, consort of Louis XVI, King of France, 1755-1793; Marlowe, Julia, 1865-1950; Military aircraft; Military hospitals; Military uniforms; Musee du Louvre; Napoleon I, Emperor of the French, 1769-1821; Paris (France); Paris Peace Conference (1919-1920); Patriotism; Pershing, John J. (John Joseph), 1860-1948; President Grant (Transport ship); Railroads--France; Rationing; Roads--France; Salvation Army; Soldiers; Sothern, E. H. (Edward Hugh), 1859-1933; St. Gervais (Church : Paris, France); Stars and Stripes (Newspaper); Stratford-upon-Avon (England); Subways--France--Paris; Subways--New York (State)--New York; Theater--England--London; Tour Eiffel (Paris, France); Transportation--France--Paris; Transportation--Great Britain--London; Typhoid fever--Vaccination; United States. Army--Pay, allowances, etc.; United States. Army--Signal Corps--Female Telephone Operators Unit; United States. Army. American Graves Registration Service; United States. Navy; Vaccination; War bonds; Wilson, Woodrow, 1856-1924; Women's Land Army of America; World War, 1914-1918; World War, 1914-1918--Aerial operations, French; World War, 1914-1918--Aerial operations, German; World War, 1914-1918--Armistices; World War, 1914-1918--Artillery operations, German; World War, 1914-1918--Casualties; World War, 1914-1918--Censorship--United States; World War, 1914-1918--Economic &amp; industrial aspects; World War 1914-1918--France; World War, 1914-1918--France--Social aspects; World War, 1914-1918--Great Britain--Social aspects; World War, 1914-1918--Health aspects; World War, 1914-1918--Naval operations--Submarine; World War, 1914-1918--Prisoners and prisons, German; World War, 1914-1918--Participation, Female; World War, 1914-1918--Songs and music; World War, 1914-1918--Transportation; World War, 1914-1918--War work--France; World War, 1914-1918--War work--Red Cross; World War, 1914-1918--Repatriation of war dead; World War, 1914-1918--War work--Women; World War, 1914-1918--War work--Young Men's Christian associations</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:type>Still Image</dc:type>
<dc:format>Application/pdf</dc:format>
<dcterms:medium>Correspondence; Manuscripts</dcterms:medium>
<dcterms:isFormatOf>RG 53</dcterms:isFormatOf>
<dcterms:references>http://sos.tn.gov/products/tsla/world-war-i-gold-star-records-1918-1924</dcterms:references>
<dc:rights>No copyright - United States: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll26/id/11738</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>