<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook,  p. 11 c</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 11 c. Newspaper clipping: 'Congressman Austin's Reply.' Knoxville Journal.  April 6, 1917.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's suffrage;</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Knoxville Journal</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>April 6, 1917</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 11</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>CONGRESSMAN
AUSTIN'S REPLY
To Resolution Regarding Passage of Susan B. Anthony
Federal Amendment.
On March 28 a Knox county committee
was formed to work with the Woman's
party for the passage of the Susan B. Anthony federal  amendment.
A resolution was passed and copies ordered sent to President Wilson and the
Tennessee congressmen.  A reply has been
received from Representative Austin, which
is here published with the resolution.
RESAOLUTION (sic.)
Whereas, the international situation is
in such a disturbed condition that none can
predict what a day may bring forth, and
it is not improbable that war may shortly
be declared between the United States and
Germany;
Therefore, be it resolved, that it is the
sense of this meeting that because in the
event of war the women of this country
equally with the men will be called upon
to carry their share of the burdens thereof,
that now is the time for congress to take
the first step toward the recognition by
the government of this republic of the citizenship of women by the passage of the
federal amendment looking to the removal
of the political disabilities of the women
of the whole Union.
The patriotism of the women of the
United States is assured, but the pleasure
of their patriotic acts will be greatly enhanced by the knowledge that the government recognizes their right to full citizenship.
We most earnestly petition the President
and congress to do all in their power to obtain justice for women before calling upon
them to perform extra duties.
Be it further resolved that a copy of
these resolutions be sent to the President
and each member of congress from Tennessee.
Mr.   Austin's reply is as follows:
Washington, D. C, April 3, 1917.
Mrs.   L.   Crozier  French,
Knoxville,   Tenn.
Dear Mrs. French: I beg to acknowledge
receipt of the copy of the resolutions
passed at a meeting of a Knox county committee of the Tennessee branch of the National Women's party, on March 28, for
which   please   accept   my   thanks.
I trust that those who control the organization of the house will give us an
opportunity to vote on the amendment to
the constitution. I am transmitting your
letter to Mr. Kitchin, leader of the majority, with the suggestion that the committee
having this legislation in charge report out
the amendment for the consideration of the
house,  etc.
With great respect, I am
Sincerely,
R.   W.   AUSTIN.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/317</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>