<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 09 a</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 09 e. Newspaper clipping: 'Rival Suffrage Conventions. Both Factions Elect Officers and Delegations to Nashville Meeting.  Honor for Mrs. French. '  By Libbie L. Morrow, Nashville Banner.  October 31, 1914.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Suffrage; Meetings;</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Libbie L. Morrow.</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Nashville Banner</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>October 31, 1914</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 09</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>RIVAL SUFFRAGE
Both  Factions  Elect  Officers
and Delegations to Nashville Meeting.
HONOR   FOR  MRS.  FRENCH
Named As Parliamentarian For
the   National   Gathering   to
Be   Held  In   This City.
ADDRESS BY MRS.  DUDLEY
By   LIBBIE   L.   MORROW.
(Staff Correspondent.)
Knoxville, Tenn., October 31.&#8212;Both
factions of Tennessee suffragest elected officers Friday, both adjourned at
noon, the "regulars" to hold an afternoon session, and the bolters finally
adjourning. The meeting of "regulars"
was presided over by Mrs. L. Crozier
French. While the Credentials Committee was in session, prior to election
of officers, Mrs. Dudley made an
eloquent address on suffrage and was
greeted  with  much applause.
Mrs. Perkins Baxter gave a report of
the Credentials Committee which was
adopted. Miss Marie Thompson Daviess,
Vice-President for Middle Tennessee
 At the meeting presided over by
Mrs. McCormack, Miss Margaret Ervin
took the chair and Mrs. McCormack,
Memphis, was unanimously elected
President. Other officers unanimously
elected were: Vice-President-at-Large,
Mrs. Frances Fort Brown, Chattanooga; Vice-President for East Tennessee, Mrs. Julia S. Lucky, Knoxville;
Vice-President for Middle Tennessee,
Mrs. John E. Turney, Nashville; Vice-
President for West Tennessee, Mrs. A.
S. Buchanan, Memphis; Corresponding
Secretary, Mrs. A. Y. Scott, Memphis;
Recording Secretary, Mrs. David Meriwether, Knoxville; Honorary President, Mrs. J. D. Allen, Memphis;
Treasurer, Miss Catherine J. Wester,
Chattanooga; State Organizer, Miss
Hannah J. Price, Morristown; Chairman of Legislative Committee, Miss
Margaret Ervin, Chattanooga; Superintendent of Press Work, Miss Ernestine   Noa,   Chattanooga.
All the officers were elected unanimously, and Miss Wester, re-elected,
was given a vote of thanks and confidence.
When Mrs. Turney was notified that
she had been elected a Vice-President
at the meeting presided over by Mrs.
McCormack, she stated she came to
the convention as supervisor of legislation of the state suffrage work and
did not come as a candidate for any
office, but was for harmony. She was
not present at the meeting which
elected her, and has not announced
her acceptance or declination of the
office.
RIVAL   DELEGATIONS.
Delegates elected to national convention in Nashville, November 12-17,
were: Mrs. Lena Earner, Mrs. A. S.
Buchanan, Mrs. Robert Beatty. Mrs. J.
D. Allen, Memphis; Mrs. H. J. Kelso,
Mrs. David Meriwether, Mrs. E. M. Gil-
len water, Knoxville; Miss Margaret
Ervin, Chattanooga, and Miss Hannah
Price, Morristown. Alternates elected
were: Mrs. Frances Fort Brown, Miss
C. J. Wester, Miss Noa, Chattanooga;
Mrs. Sarah Hood, Miss Mary Trigg,
Jackson, Mrs. C. S. Simms, Knoxville;
Mrs. T. A. Hesey, Morristown; Miss
Frances Church, Mrs. A. Y. Scott, Mem-
phis.
The delegates were entertained at
luncheon at Seilaz by Knoxville suffragists.
AFTERNOON    SESSION.
At the final session Friday afternoon
the President, Mrs. L. Crozier French,
presided.
A feature of Friday's sessions was a
rising vote of thanks given Miss Sue
White for her services as Recording-
Secretary. The action of the President
was unanimously sustained in suspending the Treasurer, Miss Wester,
for alleged violation of the constitution and insubordination to the President.
The sum of $200 was voted the
Nashville league toward paying the expenses of the National Convention in
Nashville, November 12-17.
Miss Maria Thompson Daviess read
the report of the Resolutions Committee, extending thanks to all who helped
make the Knoxville convention a success. Included in the resolutions was
the  following:
"Resolved, That the Tennessee Equal
Suffrage Association extend a message of all good will, hopes for successful work and harmonious relations to all organizations endorsing the
cause of equal suffrage in the State of
Tennessee."
Miss Mary Boyce Temple made a
strong plea for legislation in the state,
making women eligible to serve on
school boards."
A rising vote of thanks was given
the Knoxville ladies for their beautiful
hospitality.
The convention aroused much interest in Knoxville and made many converts to  the cause.
Mrs. French read, an official communication from the Knoxville branch
of the Southern Association of College (missing)
reporting its official endorse- (missing)
qual suffrage, and numerous
(missing)</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/304</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>