<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 15 a.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 15 a. Newspaper clipping: Easter In Knoxville Four Score Years Ago.  (Re:Crozier family). Knoxville Journal &amp; Tribune.  April 6, 1922.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Clippings; Scrapbooks; Group portraits; Families; Holidays;</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Knoxville Journal &amp; Tribune</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>April 6, 1922</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 15</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>EASTER IN KNOXVILLE FOUR SCORE YEARS AGO
EASTER IN KNOXVILLE FOUR SCORE YEARS AGO.
A social center in Knoxville 80 years ago was the Crozier residence which occupied the entire square on Gay street, The old residence is
now a part of the Farragut and Starling hotels and in the picture are shown the sons and daughters of the household. Note the Easter styles
of that day.
Lower row. left to right: Mary Ann (Mrs. Frank Keller)  Hannah Wells (Mrs. William Swan)  Elizabeth (Mrs. David Deadrick) and Margaret (Mrs.  Ramsey,  wife of Dr.  J.   G.   M.  Ramsey,   historian  of  Tennessee and author of Ramsey's Annals.
Top row, left to right: Ex-Congressman John H. Crozier, Mr. Arthur  Crozier    Mr.  Hugh   Crozier and   Dr. Carrick White Crozier.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/334</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>