<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 16 e.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 16 e. Newspaper clipping: Funeral of Miss Cornelia Crozier (fragment). By Annie Booth M[cKinney]. [December 1911].</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Funeral rites &amp; ceremonies;</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Annie Booth M[cKinney].</dc:creator>
<dc:date>[December 1911]</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 16</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>FUNERAL 0F
MISS CORNELIA CROZIER
Tribute Paid to the Memory of
a Well Known Woman.
The   funeral   of   [Miss]   Cornelia   Croz[ier]
was   conducted  from  St.   John's  Episco[pal]
church   Sunday   afternoon,   December (missing)
at   two   o'clock   bb   the   rector,     Rev.  (missing)
Walter   C.   Whitaker.     The   pall     bea[rers] _
were:    Dr.  A. P   White, Mr.  H.  T.  (missing)
Mr.  James   Scott,  Mr   John  M.   Allen,
Henry  Lenoir  and Mr.   Robert  Kella (missing)
As   the     flower-covered     casket     moved
slowly down the aisle to the organ's deep-  
toned accompaniment   under    the    sympa-
thetlc touch of Mr. Frank Nelson, and the
well  trained  choir  added to the solemnity  
of  the   occasion,   memory   swept  one   back 
 to the long ago when, upon so many similar  occasions,  had  been  heard Miss  Cro-
zier's  splendid  voice.
Her intimate connection with St. John's
Episcopal church dates far back. Bishop
Otey was Tennessee's first Episcopal
bishop, and when Bishop Otey made his
initial visit to Knoxville, there were just
two avowed Episcopalians: William Ethel-
red Williams, Miss Cornelia Crozier's
grandfather, and Thomas McMullen, grandfather of Mrs. Edward Oates, Messrs.
James Wallace and Hugh Rodgers and
 Mrs.   Frank  Clark.
At ten years of age. Miss Crozier was
bridesmaid, while her brother, Ethel Crozier, scholar, musician and courty (sic.)  gen-
tleman, aged fourteen, was groomsman in
old St. John's, at the wedding of a cous-
in, one of the most beautiful belles of
 Tennessee's early  days,  Miss Mary  Hume.
St. John's is, today,
a  new face  (missing)
, but despite the added archi-
tectural   grandeur,   the
beautiful  structure  dear to the hearts of
many   among   Knoxville's pioneer citizens.
None was more interested in the advancement of her church, nor more generous in her efforts and labors than Miss
Cornelia Crozier. A devout Episcopalian,
she gave of her time and talents free  (missing)
for  the upbuilding of St.  John's.
Miss   Crozier   was   a   woman   of   grea[t]
force,   despite   the    frailty     of   the   she (missing)
which   encased   the   indomitable   woman-
soul.    Practical,   energetic,   yet   shrinking
from   notoriety,   cultured,   refined,  artistic
in  taste and  instinct, loyal in the highest
degree  to   friend   and  principle&#8212;in  short,
selfless&#8212;hers was a  rare personality  and
 her going will leave a void in the hearts
of  those  who  dwelt  within   the  circle  of
 her  regard.
 Miss Crozier comes from a family which
has been prominent in the intellectual life
 of  Knoxville.     Her  father,   Hon.   John   V
Crozier,   was    acknowledged   one   of   the
 brainiest   men  ever  sent  by  Tennessee   to
 congress.    She is survived by four sisters
Mrs.   L.   Crozier   French,   Miss   Lucy   Crozier-
and  Misses  Mary   and  Anna  Crozier, "
 ail women of dominance and Individuality 
At   the  conclusion   of   the  church   serv-
ices,   Miss   Crozier's   remains   were   borne 
 to Old Gray cemetery, and laid to rest in
 the family lot.    As the sun burst through
sullen   clouds   that   darkened   the   sky,   to
 illumine  the   flower-banked     mound,     be- 
neath which lay this noble Christian wo- 
man,  who was  so  truly  of  the  "pure  in 
heart," those who turned from her resting
place thought how fitting it was that the
cold, hard clods should be hidden beneath 
gracious  bloom.    Possibly  next  to   a  passionate love of music. Miss  Crozier  loved
flowers.    Some  who watched the exquisite
'floral   offerings  transform  crude  (missing)
a  mound   of  bloom,   were  minde (missing)
deft fingers whose magic touch h (missing)
ten in the years  gone by, when
had neither florist nor  greenhou (missing)
wreaths and posies for the brid (missing)
burial.     It   seemed   fitting   that  (missing)
generous soul should rest bene (missing)
rant   blanket   despite  December  (missing)
sky. ANNIE   BOOTH M[cKinney]</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/342</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>