<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 41 c</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 41 c. Newspaper clipping: Miss Paul's Address.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's rights; Women's suffrage;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>Unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook p. 41</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>Miss Paul's Address.
The chief talk was made by Miss 
Paul, who for practically an hour told
the story of the rise of the Congressional
union, of its work and hopes. If there
was anyone present at the close of Miss
Paul's talk who did not understand the
union, how and why it came into being,
what it has accomplished in the three
years of its existence, and what it confidently expects to achieve before the
present session of congress comes to a
close, it was not the speaker's fault,
for she certainly made it all as plain
as "the nose on your face.''
Miss Paul, has, to a remarkable degree, the power of clear, logical speech.
She has trained herself to think on her
feet, and in her impassioned plea for
solidarity among women, for the dropping of petty differences, and for the concentration of the suffrage forces upon the
passage of the desired federal amendment, she stirred and aroused a desire
for action in every woman within the
sound of her voice.
The effect of Miss Paul's address upon
the audience was manifest in a practical
and substantial manner at its close by
the raising, within a very few minutes,
$350 for the work of the union.
The Knoxville Political Equality
league promised $50, the Johnson City
suffrage league $50, the Knoxville Equal
Suffrage leage $25, and the remainder
of the money subscribed was individual
contributions.
About sixty persons present allowed
their names to be placed on record as
members of the Tennessee branch of the
Congressional union.
The Time to Strike.
In her address, Miss Paul said that
the federal amendment has a better
chance of being passed during this congress than it will have again for four
years. This is due to the fact that
this is Presidential election year, and
one-fifth of the electoral votes, about
one hundred in number, are already controlled by women voters in twelve equal
suffrage  states.
This is why the speaker pled with the
women to unite; it is why she is asking
the suffragists in all the states in the
union to unite at this time and get the
amendment through congress.
"The negro was enfranchised by the
passage of a federal amendment," said
Mis Paul, "why should not the women
of the" nation be enfranchised the same
way?"</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/501</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>