<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Votes for Women a Success (p. 2 of 4)</dc:title>
<dc:description>Votes for Women a Success (p. 2 of 4).  Southern States Woman Suffrage Conference. No Date.  Lizzie Crozier French Papers.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Women's suffrage; Voting; Ephemera;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>ephemera</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizze Crozier French Papers</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>A Call to Southern
Governers
One of the most significant indications of progress of 
the movement in the South was the tenor of the call sent you last   November   to   the   Governors   of  the   Southern 
States, written by Miss Kate Gordon and signed by the 
Presidents and leading members of the Southern Suffrage 
organizations.    It read as follows: 

"The undersigned women of the Southern States, on the 
part of the Suffragists of their respective States, earnestly 
request the Governors of the Southern States or their rep- 
resentatives to meet them in conference in New Orleans, 
November 10-11, to discuss and adopt a uniform plan of 
action for the adoption of Woman suffrage in the South. 
"We are united in the belief that Suffrage is a State 
right,  and that the power to define a  State's electorate 
should remain    the    exclusive   right   of the   State. How- 
ever, we recognize that Woman Suffrage is no longer a 
theory to be debated, but a condition to be met.    The in- 
evitable 'votes for women' is a world movement, and un-
less   the   South squarely faces the issue and   takes   steps 
to preserve the State right, the force of public opinion will 
make   it   mandatory   through   a   National   Constitutional 
   Amendment. 
     "In fact, the National Council of Voters, consisting of 
enfranchised women, has for its object the influencing of 
national legislation to  secure  the ballot for the women 
who have not yet received it.   While as Southerners we wish   to see the power of the State retained, yet as women we 
are  equally  determined  to  secure,  as  of paramount im- 
portance, the right which is the birthright of an American 
 citizen. 

"We, therefore, appeal to you gentlemen vested with 
it  the power to so largely shape conditions, to confer with                                                                                                              us and influence public opinion to adopt Woman Suffrage 
through State action.    Failing to accomplish this, the onus 
of responsibility will rest upon the men of the South if 
Southern women are forced to support a national amend- 
 ment, weighted with the same objections as the Fifteenth 
Amendment. 
          "Hoping for an early and favorable response,</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/278</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>