<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 27 b.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 27 b. Newspaper clipping: Selected Motion Pictures Will Be Topic of Mrs. Speed. Officials of Ossoli Circle Announce Appearance of Virginia University Educator Here Next Sunday Afternoon &#8212; Censorship Idea Not Involved But Selection.  News Sentinel.  February 20, 1922.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Motion pictures;</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>News Sentinel</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>February 20, 1922</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 27</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>SELECTED MOTION PICTURES
WILL BE TOPIC OF MRS. SPEED

Officials of Ossoli Circle Announce Appearance of Virginia Uni-
versity Educator Here Next Sunday Afternoon &#8212; Censor-
ship Idea Not Involved But Selection. 
"Selected Motion Pictures" will be
the subject of an address to be given
by Mrs. Philip Speed of the University of Virginia when she appears on
Sunday afternoon at 3 o'clock at the
Bijou Theater. Mrs. Speed is brought
to Knoxville under the auspices of
Ossoli Circle which is vitally interested in securing the highest type of
amusements for the people of the city.
Mr. Dunbar has given the use of the
theater and Frank Nelson will render
a special musical program.
"The purpose of the meeting is to
arouse public sentiment for a better
type of motion pictures for Knox-
ville," Ossoli Officers said. "The
people generally get what they want,
and pictures of a baser sort are only
screened because there are certain
people who enjoy looking at them.
The popularity of well known actors
attests to the wholesomeness of the
general taste, inasmuch as these best
sellers only appear in clean and entirely inoffensive pictures."
Selection Big Idea
Not censorship but selection is the
idea to be put forth in the mass meeting Sunday. Leading club women
and men of the city, as well as the
motion picture exhibitors will be invited to join in a frank and open
discussion of how to secure the best
always for Knoxville. The ministers
from  the  different  churches  will  be
urged to co-operate in the movement,
to announce the meeting in their pulpits Sunday morning, and to set an
example to their church members by
attending the gathering themselves.
Mrs. Speed, who will be the chief
speaker, is well known throughout
 the country as a leader in recreational work. She comes from a famous
old family, her grandfather having
been an ambassador to England for
the Southern Confederacy. Mrs.
Speed was educated in Virginia and
Washington, and became the vice-
principal of Gunston Hall in that
city. Both as a teacher and mother,
she has been concerned with the
"leisure time problem" of young people and has given freely of her energy
to the student life of the university."
Pioneer Worker
In 1915-16, she did pioneer work, in
New York City, in building up Saturday morning entertainment for the
young people. This brought her into
close association with the Board of
Education, city officials and of parents. Later, because of her ability,
she was called upon to assist in selecting
 pictures for the Training
Camps for the Army and Navy, and
for the men on the battlefields of
Europe.
Mrs. Speed has a practical message
of decided import for the club women,
teachers, ministers and parents of the
city, and will be heard with the deepest interest by those who are concerned in solving the motion picture
problem to the best advantage of (missing)</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/434</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>