<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 42 f</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 42 f. Newspaper clipping: Questions That Interest Women Voters.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Voting;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>Unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook p. 42</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>QUESTIONS   THAT   INTEREST   WOMEN  VOTERS.
"Sister Is Primping for the Ballot-
Box Party."
This title, in big letters, runs across
a whole page of the Boston Sunday
Globe, devoted to a symposium of the
question whether women will make good
as voters.
Helen MeDaniel of the National Civic
Federation urges women to be open
minded, and predicts that in matters of
social welfare they will renounce par-
tisanship. A leading anti declares that
women as voters have dolefully failed to
make good.
President Woolley of Mt. Holyoke Col-
lege says: "The majority of women will
doubtless enroll in the established par-
ties. The party which shows the most
progressive attitude with regard to in-
ternational policy, and questions of
social and political welfare at home, will
attract the woman who has a social
conscience and thinks for herself.
"If the old established parties become reactionary this type of woman
will ally herself with the new party
certain to arise under these circum-
stances, a party composed of men and
women. There is little likelihood of a
'Woman's Party,' the cleavage will be
not along sex lines, but between the men
and women who look forward and the
men and women who look backward in
their thinking and  acting."
Mrs. Elizabeth Tilton, state chairman
of the National Physical Education Ser-
vice, urges women to make good by
working for better health conditions, es-
pecially among children, to counteract
the decline of national health due to
modern industrialism. She says, in
part:
"The International Red Cross has
called for a great child conservation
movement through the world.
"In Milwaukee the Red Cross has
placed scales in every school, that all
children may be weighed and measured, and those discovered to .lbe under
par weeded out and given, under the
supervision of the school doctor and
nurse, the corrective treatment necessary. Knowing that so much works
back to under-nourisbment and to the
popular fallacy that milk is a drink,
not a food, the Red Cross is running
milk wagons to the schools at recess
and to the playgrounds. In the meantime there has been formed at Washington a National Physical Education
committee authorized hy the Government to put forward legislation that 
shall tend to reduce to a minimum the
defects revealed by the draft. This
legislation, manifold in its variety, can
never be got through without the women. </dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/509</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>