<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 14 f.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 14 f. Newspaper clipping: Funeral For Mrs. L. French. Service For Nationally Known Woman, Native of Knoxville, to Be Held Monday.  Knoxville Sentinel.  May 16, 1926.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women;</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Knoxville Sentinel</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>May 16, 1926</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 14</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>FUNERAL FOR
MRS. L FRENCH
Service for Nationally Known
Woman, Native of Knoxville, 
to Be Held Monday.

Funeral  services   over   the   remains 
of  Mrs.   L.   C.   French,   who   died  in 
Washington Friday  after a brief  ill-
ness.   will  be  held Monday   afternoon
at ::30 (sic.) o'clock in the Woman's building.  Rev. D. M. Welch,  pastor of the
Unitarian  church,  will    conduct    the
services,  assisted by Rev. Walter  C.
Whltaker,  D. D.  rector  of St.  Johns'
Episcopal church.  Internment, will  be
held  privately in  Old Gray cemetery.
Remains of Mrs. French arrived in
Knoxville aboard the Memphis
Special  Saturday night, accompanied
by her son W. W. French, of Birmingham. The body was taken to the
undertaking establishment of Hall &amp;
Donahue. She was to be removed
early Sunday morning to the latter
residence. 620 West Cumberland
avenue. The remains will be removed
to the Woman's building Monday
morning at 9 o'clock.   
Active pall bearers will be Geo. P.
Gaut, Malcolm McDermott, Judge
John R. Neal, John Rogers, Leo
Meehan   and David  Scott.
Honorary pall bearers will he Dr.
Andrew White, Capt. William Rule,
Judge Hu L. McClung, Rev. Alva Roy
Scott, H. B. Branner, M.B. Arn-
stein, Jack Williams, Robert Keller,
Insley Deadrick.
Surviving Mrs. French are her son,
W. W. French; three sisters, Miss
Lucy Graham Crozier, Miss Mary
Crozier and Miss Kate Anna Crozier;
two grand children, William and
James V. French, and three nieces. 
Fought for Prohibition
Mrs. Dozier (sic.) French was a potent
force in the successful fight for the
emancipation of women and the
enthronement of prohibition. She
was not only a conspicuous worker
for these causes in Tennessee, but
enjoyed a national reputation as an
energetic, tireless and able advocate of woman's suffrage and prohibition. The incidents surrounding
the death of Mrs. French are of peculiar interest, as they relate to her
public record and the honor that
was being bestowed upon her by
those women with whom she had
been associated in their struggles
for legislative relief.
Mrs. French was one of the foremost women leaders of the coun-
try, and especially in Tennessee. In
the matter of promoting woman
suffrage and prohibition, she had
given her life's efforts in behalf of
these causes. She had gone to
Washington to be present at the
national conference in behalf of
equal rights, the national women's
party and other activities of women.
In consideration of her great service to woman suffrage and the
emancipation of women, the national woman's party had set aside
a room in honor of Mrs. French in
their headquarters building at
Washington, which is an old historic building situated near the
capitol and which was given to the
National Woman's party by Mrs. O
H. P. Belmont, president of that
organization. The building presented
by Mrs. Belmont is valued at $350,
000 and is one of the most interesting buildings in the capitol city,
having at one time been used as the
temporary capitol. This Tennessee
memorial room was to be dedicated
in honor of Mrs. French, and for
the dedication of which she was to
be present during her stay in the
capitol city.
Mrs. French was stopping at the
Capitol Woman's party headquarters, and at her request was assigned to the Tennessee room, during a call by Mrs. L.D. Tyson, upon
Mrs. French's, the purpose of which
call was to discuss the fittings and
furnishing of this Tennessee room,
Mrs. French was suddenly taken
very ill. The Tennessee room is situated on the third floor of the National Woman's party headquarters,
and it is necessary to climb two
flights of stairs to enter the room.
Mrs. Tyson was met in the lobby of
the building by Mrs. French, and 
in Mrs. French's active, vigorous
and energetic way she preceded
Mrs. Tyson up the stairs and into
her room, or the Tennessee room,
the very room which was to be
named for her, and she with great
pride called Mrs. Tyson's attention
to the bronzed name-plate upon the
door which bore the inscription
"Tennessee room,  in honor of Mrs.
L.   Crozier  French,   In  appreciation
of her life work for women."
Suddenly Stricken
Upon entering the room Mrs.
French remarked to Mrs. Tyson
that she felt badly, in fact was-quite
sick, and the assistance of a physician was immediately called for.
First aid was administered by Mrs. 
Tyson and Miss Ainge, national 
treasurer   of  the   Woman's     party.
Upon advice of physicians she was
removed to the Providence hospital, where she passed away about
4:30 Friday afternoon. Her sudden
death was not expected, in fact, it
was thought by the physicians that
she might live for several days, and
that there was an even chance for her recovery. Her son, W. W.
French, of Birmingham, Ala., was
communicated with almost immediately after her first attack and
left Birmingham Thursday morning. Arriving in Washington at noon
Friday, a few hours before the end.
She was conscious to the end and
her son and those who were with
her Friday afternoon felt encouraged over her condition. She conversed with her son and he left her
a few minutes after 4 o'clock to
send telegrams to relatives, fully
confident that she had a chance for
recovery and that there was no immediate  danger.
The women of Tennessee are un-
dertaking the pleasant duty of furnishing the Tennessee, room, in
memory of Mrs. French and the
room already contains several excellent
historical pieces of furniture, one of which had just arrived
and was given by Mrs. French herself in the name of Miss Sue White,
secretary to Senator K. D. McKel-
lar, and of whose work in behalf of
women, Mrs. French expressed deep
appreciation. The table thus given
originally belonged to the Honorable Hugh Lawson White, of Tennessee.
Senator and Mrs. I.. D, Tyson,
Miss Sue White, Miss Fannie
Cooper and other Tennessee friends,
were untiring  in their efforts to
alleviate the suffering of Mrs.
French, in fact the entire organization of the National Woman's party
were solicitous of her every comfort and today the purple, white and
gold banner of the organization
representing the cause for which
Mrs. French spent her entire life
flies at half mast in front of the
national headquarters of the Woman's  party.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/329</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>