<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 32 e</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 32 e.  Newspaper clipping: "Suffrage Would Mean Clean and Unpurchashable Votes."</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's suffrage;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>Unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook p. 32</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>"Suffrage Would Mean Clean and Unpurchashable Votes."                                                                                                                              The Memphis News-Scimitar prints the
following letter received by the editor
of the woman's page from Mrs. George
Randolph in regard to woman's suffrage.
 "A republican form of government is
lasting and stable only so long as the
majority of votes cast are honest votes.
The many political scandals unearthed
in recent years prove that the number of
bought or controlled votes has steadily
increased since the early days of the republic.
"The votes of women are opposed
among others by the liquor interests, by
the 'big business' manufacturers who
now weave the souls of women and chil-
dren into costly fabrics, and by all who
exploit women and babies. The reason
for their opposition is that they fear the
stand women will take when they or-
ganize, and vote, and that only by their
united action can the opinions of women
 crystalize  into  power.
"Few women who have the mother in-
stinct would cast a vote other than for
what they believe to be for the best in-
terest of their children and fireside. Suf-
frage would mean clean and unpurchas-
able votes and our government needs a[ll]
such.
"The woman movement at work as
over the world today stands for honesty,
humanity, progress,  good government."</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/462</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>