<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. How Can Women Aid In Obtaining A Uniform Marriage and Divorce Law? (2 of 2)</dc:title>
<dc:description>French. How Can Women Aid In Obtaining A Uniform Marriage and Divorce Law? Page 2 of 2.  Lizzie Crozier French Papers.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Legislation; Women's rights;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>manuscript</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Papers</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>
THE FIRST  THING NECESSARY TO  BRING  ABOUT  UNIFORMITY OF MARRIAGE
AND DIVORCE LAWS   IS  TO  HAVE THOSE LAWS MADE AT  THE NATIONAL   INSTEAD  OP  AT  48   STATE CAPITALS.   WE MUST  WIPE OUT   STATE LINES   IF
WE WOULD   INAUGURATE MANY DESIRED   REFORMS.      MR WILSON BEGAN     THIS
WHEN HE  APPLIED  THE  ARTISTS  GUM  IN HIS  SUSCESSFUL  EFFORT   IN  PASSING THE  INTERSTATE CHILD LABOR LAW.     CONGRESS  WILL MAKE THE
LINE FAINTER WHEN   IT   PASSES  THE PROHIBITION LAW.     AND  THIS NEXT
CONGRESS WILL NO DOUBT MAKE IT  ENTIRELY DISAPPEAR WHEN   IT   PASSES
THE FEDERAL  AMENDMENT  FOR WOMAN   SUFFRAGE.   WHEN THE WOMEN  ARE
ENFRANCHISED  THEY MAY GO  TO  WORK IN  EARNEST  TO  PROTECT  THE HOME
AND  AMONG  THEIR FIRST  ACTS  WILL  BE THE MARRIAGE LAWS     WHICH  CON-
STITUTE THE FOUNDATION  OF  THE HOME.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/287</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>