<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 15 c.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 15 c. Newspaper clipping: 'Points in parliamentary law...' Mentions Lucy Graham Crozier, representative from Mars, Ossoli Circle, and Miss Ethel Arnold. (clipping fragment)</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Clubs;</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>unknown</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>unknown</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 15</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>Points in parliamentary law, not suspected by many and little practiced in
many clubs, were made in rapid succession at the session, and a large number of the ladies quite distinguished
themselves for their aptness and ability.
A great deal of fun was created in
the beginning when "fraternal delegates'' were received. Miss Lucy Graham Crozier brought credentials form (sic.)
a representative of Mars, "the land
where the beehive hat is unknown", she
said, and "where the women vote." This
brought on a furious argument, many
being unwilling to rick the uncertainty
in their midst of a representative of a
planet that had already caused so much
trouble.
The Question was asked of Miss Crozier if her delegate would expect her
expenses to be paid, and was assured
that the same was to be voted on without respect to "age, sex or previous conclusion," and begged that her coming
into Tennessee be not a question of expense. The opposition was so strenuous
and the argument so irregular, the Mars
delegate being voted in, and then out
again, several times, that Miss Crozier
finally withdrew her motion, saying that
"through the medium of thought transmission, she has been advised to do so,
Mars not wishing to participate in a
congress where women do not know
their own minds." This was a fair example of a bit of the fun that prevailed
but considerable serious work was done
before adjourning. The event proved a
brilliant success from  every  standpoint.
The final business session of the
year of Ossoli Circle will be held this
moring (sic.) at 10:30 at the Lyceum building. To this session it is urged that
both boards be present and all members if possible. Important business will
come up for transaction.
Among questions to be determined is
the possibility of bringing to Knoxville
for a lecture on Woman in Economics.
Miss Ethel Arnold, one of the most
brilliant women of the day, and a ardent advocate of woman's rights. She is
a sister of Mrs. Humphrey Ward who,
in strange contradiction has been fighting the cause as earnestly as her sister
had espoused it. Miss Arnold is a
granddaughter of Mathew Arnold and
has other distinguished connections aside
from which she would easily stand alone
as her own intellect, culture and learning entitle her to a place among brainy
men and women of the day.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/336</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>