<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 19 c.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 19 c. Newspaper clipping: An Open Letter to Rev. Len. G. Broughton. Knoxville Journal &amp; Tribune.  December 12, 1912. (1913?)</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Clergy; Women's suffrage;</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Knoxville Journal &amp; Tribune</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>December 12, 1912 or 1913</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 19</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>AN OPEN LETTER TO THE
REV. LEN G. BROUGHTON
In The Journal and Tribune of Saturday, 
Dec. 2nd,  was reported a lecture delivered
by you to a Bible class, on the preceding
Friday evening.    For several reasons I am 
asking the indulgence of The Journal and 
Tribune for space to make a reply to your 
adverse criticism regarding equal suffrage.
The form of speech of which you make
use would seem to imply that you believe
yourself   to   be   an   authority   as   regard's
God's whole  scheme  in general,   and  His
intentions  concerning woman's  position   in
the human  family  in particular.    I  quote
from your  remarks as reported:&#8212;
"Suffrage," said Dr. Broughton, "for 
women is contrary to the whole scheme of
God, He intended that man should stand 
for woman. He intended that woman 
should not stand by his side in his responsibility for anything, but that she 
should be by his side for protection."
It  would  Seem  hardly necessary  to  re-
mind a Protestant clergyman of the twentieth    century that    as far    back  as  the
sixteenth century, Martin Luther led a cru-
sade against tyranny over the human mind. 
The triumph of protestantism assures the 
right of private judgment in religious mat- 
ters, to  every individual  where  its teach- 
ings are held in respect; though Roger Williams and the good Baptists of early America knew what it was to suffer under the
narrow bigotry of their religious neighbor.
But the framers of the constitution of the 
United States knew the impossibility of the 
finite comprehending the infinite and hav-
ing had experience as to the fallibility of
man's Judgment in earthly things,   wisely I
concluded  that  it was  hardly  likely   mere 
man   could  decide    positively    concerning 
God's schemes and intentions,    Our constitution therefore, virtually insures to every
individual freedom from religious dictation
and prosecution.
While our bodies may not be made to
suffer pain by decree of religious fanatics
it is still possible for weak minds to be
held in thraldom by the utterances of any
egotist who thinks his imaginings are at
one with God's Intentions. You may not
be conscious of any intention to tyrannize
over weak minds, so I take the precaution
of warning you of the danger of it.
You are reported to have said: "God 
shows clearly that man should work for, 
plan for, think for, woman."
Unfortunately in times' long past many
men held this opinion and so interpreted
God's intention when it suited their 
convenience and gratified their vanity and con-
ceit. Especially do we find in comparing
the social conditions of men and women
that much objection was made to women
thinking and planning, but no obstacles
were put in the way of her working, if the
work were of an humble kind, and it could
be shown that it was principally intended
to be of benefit to some man or men.
Drudgery and all tasks that carried with
them no pleasure,  riches, power, honor or
glory,   have   always   been   freely   allowed 
to woman as carrying out God's intention 
as to the work proper to her sex.
Probably   the  best     examples    of  your
theory   that  God     does not    intend     that
woman should work, plan or think are to be
found In the harems of the Mohammedans.
The conclusion of the Moslem that women
have no souls is quite consistent with yours
that they were not designed by the Creator to
 think.    Every Individual  soul must 
think,  if a member of the human family. ,
To place woman in the non-thinking class 
is  to consign her to  the  animal kingdom. 
Primitive  man,     not having    developed !
great   intelligence,   naturally   placed   brute
force as the greatest human attribute.    He
despised the physically weak and made all
such his slaves.    Those men found it easy
 to make women subservient to them.    Not 
 even  clubs   were     necessary;   their   naked 
hands were sufficient    weapons to subdue
the females of the species- especially when 
they  were   with  child.
You,  who know so much of God's intentions,   probably  agree  with   me  that  God
intended motherhood to be woman's crown
of glory.    You  know enough  of the  social 
history of the human family,  and  I  hope
you are candid enough to confess that man
has  too  often  made  it  the   cause  of  her
degradation and misery.    Is this what you
would term man's protection of woman?
As  man  evolved in  the  course of time,
and   intellect   and   character   became   successful
 rivals  of physical  force,   woman's
condition was ameliorated, yet within the
recollection of many of us not yet a hundred years old, fiats have been put forth by
certain   male  egotists,   that  woman   could
not acquire  learning  equal  to  man,   or,   if
she   did,   it   would   be   at   the   expense   of
her health.    The regime which women have
passed through at the dictation of ignorant
men would seem to have been sufficient to
make idiots of them all.    The  only reason
why they have escaped this fate must be
because the all wise Creator has protected them until the man has sufficiently developed to recognize that he is not the special
favorite   of   Deity,   but   that   the   love   of
God is no less for His daughters than His
sons.
The God that I adore is the acme of jus-
tice, wisdom and love who endowed
with equal capacity man and woman.   As
the animals seem to have developed first 
so as to prepare the way for the human 
family, so the earlier development of man
to power and position would seem to be 
for the purpose of pointing the way to the 
mother of the race.
 Many women have been so dominated and 
suppressed by man's presumptuous egotism 
that their intellectual  development has been 
much retarded. It is this class that I fear 
may be influenced by your teaching and 
thus get erroneous view of God and His 
scheme and Intentions.
One other quotation I would consider
in    explaining    his      position,    Dr.
Broughton   said:    "I  am  enough  of  a
pacifist to believe that the ballot must
be supported, if need be, by the bullet,
   in order to enforce its meaning.    Outside of any Biblican convictions, I believe that no one should vote, who cannot back  their  vote  with  arms."
Here speaks the primitive man.    Is brute
force the only power by which mankind is
to be controlled?    It is truly surprising the
little  real   influence  the   teaching  of  Jesus
has had on the so-called Christian world.
I ask you to consider that when the world
was governed by brute force the ballot was
unknown. The common people who did the
fighting did not cast a vote. Bullets and
ballots are not companions, but ballots in
the hands of the people are supposed to be
a substitute for bullets in the hands of
hired  agents,   too  often of  tyranny.
Thanks be to God that in giving woman
the crown of motherhood He made her the 
giver,  not the taker,   of life.    Woman  has
no greater claim to the right to the ballot
than that she is a producer and not a 
destroyer of life.    Much as I believe justice
demands   the  ballot   for   woman,   I   would
shopper to buy more than ever before, goes
a  long way  to  indicate  the  financial  success of the season, there being more money
in circulation this year than for many years
past.
Prices.
Despite
the much talked question of the
high cost of living and the appalling in-
crease in price of the actual necessities of
life, the wares appropriate to the holiday
season are to be had at approximately the
same prices that were quoted last season.
 "Made in America."</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/391</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>