<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 33 b</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 33 b Newspaper clipping: Woman's Suffrage in United States.  Question Attracting Wide Attention and is Being Universally Discussed.  Where Women Can Vote.  Opinion of Eminent Men on the Subject Proves Interesting. (By Laura M. Thornburgh). 1914.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's suffrage;</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Laura M. Thornburgh</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1914</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook p. 33</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>WOMAN'S SUFFRAGE
IN UNITED STATES
Question Attracting Wide Attention and is Being Universally Discussed.
WHERE WOMEN CAN VOTE
Opinion of Eminent Men on
the Subject Proves
Interesting.
(By Laura M. Thornburgh.)
There is probably no question receiving more universal attention at the
present moment than the question of
woman suffrage and what that implies.
______ is like the Pinchot-Ballinge
affair or city elections may assume more
importance for a short space of time
but the suffrage question with arguments pro and con is one that is likely
to continue indefinitely or until it is
satisfactorily settled to those most concerned.
One can hardly pick up a newspaper
or a current magazine without finding
some article bearing on the question.
Leading and representative statesmen,
public officials, literati and professional men have been interviewed and
their opinions printed. It is an interesting fact that most of the opinions
publicly expressed are decidedly in favor of the movement. Those who have
given the matter thought seem to realize that equal suffrage not only will
come to those who want it, but is already here, and it is only a question ot
time when it will be universal in this
country.
The question has come to be, "Will
it be best for all concerned that women
be given the ballot?" for the question,
"Is it right that women have the power
of the ballot?" has been answered in
the affirmative. There are no sane arguments that intelligent women should be
discriminated against when the illiterate
negro has a right to say what shall be
done in municipal affairs. It also seems
absurd to think that a young boy just
twenty-one years of age can go out
and vote on matters of public welfare
when the school teacher who has taught
him all he knows about political economy
shall be denied a voice in the matter.
It is interesting to read the sentiments of public men from the states
where women's suffrage is now allowed.
The general feeling is decidedly favorable. Those who object are almost entirely the party bosses and  professional
politicians whom the women have defeated.
Women Vote In  Municipal Affairs.
The   city   government   is   now   elected
by   men   and   women   together   in   every
city  of England,   Scotland,   Ireland,   Aus-
tralia,    New    Zealand,    Norway,    Sweden
and   Denmark.     In   this   country   women
have    the   rights    of   equal    suffrage    in
Idaho,   Wyoming,   Utah  and  Colorado.
Opinions  of   Public   Men.
 In    speaking   on      woman's      suffrage,
United States   Senator   Borah,   of  Idaho,
savs:      "I would be entirely unwilling to see woman's suffrage abolished."  United States Senator Heyburn, of Idaho, says: The   general  tone
of   political
affairs in  the   stale   have   
improved   and
greater   care   in   the   selection
of  candi-
dates   has   resulted.     Between
 sixty   and
seventy   per   cent   of   the   
women   vote."
On   the   same   subject   present
 Governor
Brady   says:     ''Woman's   
suffrage   is   an
unqualified   success   not   only
  in   Idaho
but  in  all  of   the   western
states   adopt-
ing    the   principle.      I    am
heartily    in
favor   of   its   wide   expansion."
Former
Governor   Steunenberg   says
"In   Idaho
women are  today the same
loving wives,
kind   mothers- and   capable
home   man-
agers   they   have   always   been,    nor   has
there   been    the   least   belittling   of   the
sex  in  the  eyes  of the  men."
 The    same    sentiments   are   voiced    by
 the men of Utah and Wyoming and Colorado.     Former    United   States    Senator
 Sutherland,   of   Utah,    says:      "Woman's
 suffrage   has   raided   the   whole   tone  of
politics."      Governor    Brooks,    of   Wyoming,   says:     "I   consider   woman's   suffrage   of   great  benefit   to  any   commonwealth.      There   is   no   argument   which
can be made against it."    Judge Lindsey,
of  Colorado,   says  that   he  owes  his  last
election   largely   to   the   influence   of   the
women and to their votes.
Many of these testimonials come un-
solicited. It has been said that the
men desiring the women's votes speak
favorably of woman's suffrage for political reasons, but in that case the endorsement need not be so unqualified
and   universal.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/465</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>