<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 16 d.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 16 d. Newspaper clipping: Col. Arthur R. Crozier.  + handwritten note re: Arthur R. Crozier (December 1, 1809-June 15, 1899), Blanket, Texas. [Morristown Gazette] [1898].</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Clippings; Scrapbooks;</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>[Morristown Gazette]</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>[1898]</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 16</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>
Col. Arthur R. Crozier asks us to
change the direction of his copy of
The Gazette-from Graham, Texas, to
Blanket, Texas, a station on the Fort
Worth and Rio Grande railroad, located in Brown county, where, in the family of his son, Dunlap Crozier, he expects to spend his last days. Col. C. will
be pleasantly remembered by many of
our older readers. For many years&#8212;
more than a third of a century ago&#8212;
he was an important factor in the
Democratic party of the State, especially in East Tennessee. He was elected State Comptroller three successive
terms, and no more competent or hon-
ester officer ever filled that responsible position. His former friends and
associates will be gratified to hear
that he is enjoying excellent health.
His chirography&#8212;if he would only
apply a soft pencil to soft paper, rather
than a hard pencil to hard paper&#8212;has
all the feminine neatness and steadiness of nerve that used to mark his 
editorial manuscripts while conducting
the old Knoxville Standard. Col. Crozier began the 89th year of a good and
useful pilgrimage on earth December
1, 1898. May he live to enjoy many
returns of that anniversary.                                                                                                                                                                                                                            (Handwritten note: Born Dec. 1, 1809. Died June 15, 1899    Arthur R. Crozier.  Blanket, Texas.  Dec. 1, 1898 was his 89th birthday.  See strip from Morristown Gazette of Feb. 1, 1899.)
</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/341</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>