<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 39 b</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 39 b . Newspaper clipping: WOMEN IN PROFESSIONS.  News Sentinel.  March 30, 1913.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's rights;</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>News Sentinel</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>March 30, 1913</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook p. 39</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>WOMEN IN PROFESSIONS.
"Mrs. Winifred Harper Cooley of
New York is president of the Allied
Clubs of Domestic Science; a member and officer of the Domestic
Science club, of the Society for the
Promotion of Pure Foods and many
other women's organizations and a
recognized leader in all women's
movements in the east.
Mrs. Cooley was born in Indiana,
and   is   the   daughter   of   Mrs.   Ida
Husted  Harper,  one of the leading
woman   suffragists     in     United States.
She is the author of  "The
New Womanhood"    and    numerous
magazine   articles  on  food preparation   and   the   servant   problem.
By Mrs. Winifred Harper Cooley
Are  women   taking  men's  jobs  away
from  them?    Well,  who said they  were
 mens,   anyway?     Men   say   so,   to   be
tsure,   but   one   never   wants   to   give   up
 what  he  has.     There   are   several   laws
 recognized   throughout   the   world.     One
 of   them   is  the  law   of  supply   and   demand.    Another is that there is always
plenty of room at the top.
Girls are athletic nowadays,  and can
climb trees pretty well; so we find them
holding   big   salaried   positions   "at   the
top"  (for no earthly  reason except  that
they  are so absolutely capable of filling
them).
Folks say that it is eccentric for a
woman to be a hodcarrier or a dentist
or a photographer. Of course I must seem eccentric to the
pride of the harem when she looks out over her barred windows
 and sees a woman civil engineer
measuring  space or a woman architect planning to erect a library building. 
But   why  take   the  viewpoint of the harem?
Living  by  sex   is  an ancient occupation, sometimes remunerative, sometimes not.  But it is scarcely a very respectable one, and a good many women prefer living by their brain or their handiwork.
In   1807   there   were only   seven professions open to American women.
Today there are 371 trades
and professions.  Teaching is almost monopolized by them, although in the early days paid 
four dollars  a  week.     There
are some   6,000 women physicians, some of them house surgeons, heads of insane asylums and medical examiners for public school children.  There are several hundred women dentists, the first dentist to enter the Philippines having been Dr. Anna Sawyer.  There are 400 women pharmacists in the United States.  In New York city twenty women own and manage drug stores. 

... United States of America, who may raise no voice for or against any measure of government are children,
aliens, idiots, lunatics, criminals and women.  We, the last named item, desire to be removed from this catalogue, where we should never have been placed.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/496</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>