<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 30 c.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 30 c. Newspaper clipping: The Price of Virtue. Morality at Eight Dollars a Week--The Minimum.  Lalla Block Arnstein.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women;</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Lalla Block Arnstein</dc:creator>
<dc:date>Unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 30</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>THE PRICE OF VIRTUE
Morality   at   Eight   Dollars   a
Week&#8212;The Minimum.
If the price of girls is dependent on
eight dollars per week (the minimum
wage) over which Chicago is at
present so loudly clamoring, then indeed has our standard of morality fallen very low. The investigating committee has proven nothing beyond the
fact that girls paid less than eight
dollars per week, cannot maintain
their respectability, but must resort to
immoral living in order to keep up appearances. This seems a strange
reason for transgression, a devious
winding from the path of virtue.
Is Virtue to be  maintained by dollars     and   cents?       Are     department
stores, houses of refuge for the weak
fibred,   weak-kneed   girls   and   young
women who have no morals excepting
those that are  bought and paid for?
The stores would  do well to establish
 houses of rectitude for such young women,
instead  of thrusting them  upon
department stores to keep straight at
 eight dollars per week.
Virtue that can be bought at this
 minimum wage will not be virtue of
long standing; for eight dollars brings
more demand than four or five dollars
and the accessories that complete the
living wage of eight dollars is liable
and propable to lead to grosser wrong
and greater immoral practice, than
that at a lower wage.
The legislature is imposing a very
different taste upon the employee.
Many girls entering stores have no
standard of right conduct and right
living. The fault is in their home environment where virtue should be
inculcated and implanted so deeply 
that the vanities of life will not lead to
ruin, for after all. it is not the low living wage that leads to girls going astray. It is the glamor of life, the love
of grandeur and luxury, the longing
for the delicate accessories and comforts. The wage of eight dollars per
week will not naturally benefit the
girls in this way. The heart longing
will be just as keen at eight as at five
dollars a week, the means of securing
them will also be just the same.
The investigators, seem to take no 
consideration of the fact that there are 
hundreds of thousands of pure, honest
upright girls working for their daily
sustenance to whom this investigation
is an insult and a slur. By what right
do they cast aspersions upon the 
characters of so many honest bread 
winners?
It is libel that should be punishable,
for such reflections upon ones character and  reputation  demands explanations and calls loudly for redress. Let
the honest girls of toil rise up in denunciation of the ignominy at present
being assailed  and  branded.     Human
nature is human nature, and we cannot
legislate  against it.     There  are     men
and women, boys and girls, whose instincts and ruling passion are for the
immoral life, cannot be gainsaid.    The
minimum wage will never affect these
They  must  be  placed  at  a     different
angle with regard to  human life,  before their moral status can be chang-
ed.    Neither eight dollars, ten dollars,
nor  fifteen   dollars  will     ever     cause
them to change their physical     emotions.    Virtue  that  can be gauged by
the minimum  or the  maximum wage
is not water tight virtue.    Department
stores should not be made to stand the
brunt   of   this   investigation   of     wage 
and morality, nor should suspicion be 
cast upon  the innocent.  The least ef- 
ficient  should  not  be  forced  into the 
place of the most efficient.    It    is    a 
line   artificially  drawn  to  repress  the 
best activities of the more capable.
Chicago is digging a pit for its wage 
earning girls, into which many will
heedlessly fall. She is showing them 
how immorality is more lucrative 
than honest labor, discouraging their 
efforts at bread winning, and her loud
clamorous cry of virtue at eight dollars per week, will make more converts
to a life of shame and ease, than to a 
living wage life of toil and struggle.
LALLA   BLOCK   ARNSTEIN</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/449</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>