<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 52 d</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 52 d. Newspaper clipping: fragments. Mentions William Gibbs McAdoo for President. [1920].</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Poll taxes; Political elections;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>[1920]</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF; 400 dpi</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook p. 52</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>(missing) the
 (missing)God,
the Red cross, (missing)an
Who was it suffered the most in the
war   between   the  states  and  in   the
late  world-wide  war?    It    was    the
motherhood of this country. Ladies to
me  mother is  the sweetest name  in
all  the  world.  It  is  she     who    goes
down    into   the   valley   of   death   to
give him birth. It is she who nestled
him   in   her  arms   and   coos   him   to
sleep  and   later  it   is  she  who  leads
him  into   Sunday school  and  church
and it was she who. during the last
two years followed him to the depot
and   bid   him   a   fond   farewell   with
a  smile  on  her face  and  a bleeding
heart,  giving  her boy  as   a  sacrifice
that we  migrht live  in   peace  and in
happiness.   It   mattered   not   whether (missing)
bec(missing)  twenty-(missing)
the tenth of Janu[ary]
liable for poll tax and would be allow[ed]
to vote without poll tax. Since thinking,
the statement I made in regard to the
poll tax feature applying to women vot- 
ers might excuse them. But for their 
safety if they do not care to make a 
test suit they should at least have Gen. 
Frank M. Thompson, of Chattanooga, 
give the state election commission an
opinion if the women are liable for poll
tax for 1918 and 1919 before they can 
vote as the law enfranchising them was
passed after the tenth day of Janu- 
ary, 1919. If this is true you would not 
have to pay your poll tax to vote for 
the president who I hope will be Wil-
liam Gibbs McAdoo, whose dear sweet
mother was president of Ossili 1890-91,
and 1900-1901.
"I now have some ballots, and if you 
so desire, we will hold our first election
for   mayor   and Commissioners,   so   you
can see the practical side."
</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/593</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>