<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 23 a.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 23 a. Newspaper clipping: Busy Week In Club Circles.  State Suffrage Convention is of Most Interest.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's suffrage; Clubs;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 23</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>Busy Week In Club Circles.   State Suffrage Convention is of
Most Interest.
It Will Be Convened Here Wednesday&#8212;Other  Events   on
the Club Calendar.
The club calendar for the new week
is of unusual interest, and club women
of the city will be kept very busy this
week keeping up with the various
events.
The unusual club activity of the week
is occasioned by the fact that the state
suffrage convention will be in session in
this city Wednesday, Thursday and
Friday. The day sessions of the convention will be held at the Imeprial (sic., Imperial)
hotel, and at Market hall in the evenings. The public is invited to attend,
the afternoon and evening sessions.
This afternoon, Ossoli circle will study
George Bernard Shaw, the greatest living English playwright. This study
comes in the department of modern
English drama, of which Mrs. Harry C.
Martin, is chairman. There will be no
papers, and the entire meeting will be
devoted to a general discussion of
Shaw, his work, and his genius.
Tuesday morning, at ten o'clock at
the home of Mrs. H. J. Kelso, a meeting of the Political Equality League of
Knoxville will be held. This is the new
suffrage league, formed last week, of
which Mrs. C. E. Lucky is president.
At the meeting Tuesday, officers will be
elected, also delegates to the state convention, to be held in this city this week.
Dr. Lillian Johnston and Miss Ernestine Noa will be present at this meeting, and will make talks. All persons
interested in "the cause" are cordially
invited.
Wednesday afternoon, the mothers' association of the Highland avenue school
will meet at the school building to observe vice-president's day. Dean J. D.
Hoskins will make a talk, and there will
be special music.
The parent-teacher association of the
Bell House school will hold a meeting
at the school building Wednesday afternoon.
Friday   afternoon,   at   the      board   of
commerce   rooms,   the   regular   meeting
of  Nicholson   Art  league   will  be  held.
The league  will  study     early     Flemish 
painters of genre.    Miss    Marion    Van
Campen is chairman for the  afternoon.
The Writers' club will meet with Mrs.
Samuel McKinney    Friday     afternoon.
The   meeting  will  be  a social one,  and
an informal program will be given.
 	</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/406</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>