<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 36 d</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 36 d. Newspaper clipping: Tennessee Delegations.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's suffrage; Meetings;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>Unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook p. 36</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>Tennessee Delegations.       
Following discussion   of   the   legislative
measure the convention   adopted   recom- 
mendation of a special committee that all 
the twenty-two memebrsof the two Tennessee
delegations, one headed by   Mrs.   L. 
Crozier-French of  Knoxville, and the other
by Mrs. James  McCormick of Memphis, be
given seats in  the  convention.
Delegates    from southern states at a con-
ference tonight decided to concentrate
their efforts toward the winning of a
southern state for woman sufrage within
the next two years. It was stated that
Alabama probably will be selected for the
campaign as it is proposed to introduce a
suffrage initiative petition in the next
Alabama  legislature.
Shaw Opposition Fades.
That the opposition to Dr. Anna Howard Shaw for re-election as president of
the national association has been dropped
was revealed tonight when nominations
for officers were submitted to the elections
committee. The time for presenting nominations expired at eight o'clock tonight.
Dr. Shaw's is the only name on the list
as candidate for head of the suffrage
body.
The list, of candidates in addition to Dr.
Shaw  follows:
First     Vice-President--Miss    Jean    Gor-
don, New Orleans; Mrs. Katherine Dexter   McCormick,  New  York.
Second Vice-President- Mrs.       Desha
Breckinridge,   Kentucky.
Third Vice-President- Miss Katherlne
B. Davis. New York, Mrs. Medill McCormick,   Chicago.
Corresponding Secretary -Mrs. Orton H.
Clark.   Michigan;   Mrs.    Jeanette   Rankin, Montana.
Recording Secretary--Mrs. Susan W.
Fitzgerald, New York: Mrs. Anne H. Martin,   Nevada.
Treasurer- Mrs. Henry     Wade    Rogers,
Massachusetts.
First Auditor-Mrs. Helen G. Miller,
Missouri.
Second Auditor&#8212;Mrs. Nellie N. Somer-
vllle,   Mississippi;   Miss Zona   Gale,   Wisconsin.
Election of ofifcers will be held next
Monday.
Senator Lea Speaks.
Senator Lea in his address at tonight's
mass meeting mentioned that he had voted
for a federal amendment to give women
the ballot because he believed suffrage
would increase the number of good voters.
"In states where women vote," he said,
"woman suffrage has opened more schools
and closed more saloons than all other
political movements combined." Senator
Lea urged suffragists to fight primarily
for state constitutional amendments and
also to support the national amendment.
A Speaker's Bureau.
The recommendation of the committee
for the establishment of a speakers bureau in connection with the work was
adopted    Then  began   the  debate  on  the
recommendation providing for further organization of congressional districts. The
committee advised that each state suffrage
board appoint a congressional chairman
who would appoint chairmen in each district to work under control of the state
organization.
Immediately upon the reading of this
recommendation, half a dozen suffragists
were on their feet calling for recognition
from the chair.
Miss   Kate  M.   Gordon   of New Orleans, 
Mrs.   Desha       Breckinridge   of     Kentucky, 
and   Mrs.   Harriet   Stanton   Blatch   of New
York   asserted   they   wanted   a  definite declaration   that the   national
congressional committee  should  not  interfere  with   work
of the  state  organizations.
Miss Mary Winsor of Pennsylvania said
that the Pennsylvania suffragists would
support    whatever    policy    the    committee laid down.
"Whenever the committee says 'black list' a congressman, we will 'black lsit' him," she declared.  Miss Burnham, also from Pennsylvania, however, declined to subscribe to what she called Miss Winsor's "sweeping approval of the congressional committee's actions."  Mrs. Grace Wilbur Trout and other memebrs of the Illinois delegation. empathically declared their desire for a policy which would prevent the publication by the the national committee of information relating to congressmen without the consent of the state associations.
Mrs. Medill McCormick, and Dr. Shaw both asserted that the congressional committee was designated to serve the state organizations and had no intention of attempting to orverride the state assocations' wishes with its work.  The motion as amended then was adopted by more then two-thirds majority vote.
Much interest was displayed by delegates today in the slate of officers of the nationaly(sic.) association adopted by the leaders of the administration element in a secret caucus which continued until after midnight this morning.  This ticket was headed by Dr. Anna Howard Shaw for re-election as president.  It was stated today by those in charge  of the conference that the selection of  Mrs. Katherine Dexter McCormick of New York for first vice-president,  was finally ratified by the caucus and that Miss Hannah Patterson of Pennsylvania, was chosen for the "administration" candidate for the office of second vice-president in place of Mrs. Desha Breckinridge of Kentucky, who was first selected for the place.  Confirmation was given today of the other selections on the ticket as announced last night.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/479</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>