<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 24 c.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 24 c. Newspaper clipping: Citizenship In National Government. The Vote and the Voter.  By Mary Sumner Boyd.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's suffrage;</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Mary Sumner Boyd</dc:creator>
<dc:date>Unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 24</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>CITIZENSHIP   IN   NATIONAL   GOVERNMENT.
THE VOTE AND THE VOTER,
(By Mary Sumner Boyd)
What is Citizenship? For the time being, in order to have a working definition, we will say that citizens are of
two kinds; full or "active" citizens who
have both political and civil rights, and
partial or "passive" citizens&#8212;these will
give us some trouble later&#8212;who have
civil rights alone. Only as citizen of a
state can an American have full citizenship for only in this way can he have
voting rights. But only as a citizen of
the United States does he gain the fun-
damentals of civil rights.
With certain important limitations,
the federal constitution leaves to the
states the decision as to who shall be
full voting citizens and who shall not.
On their part, the states with the exception of eight, in conferring voting
citizenship lay down as one requirement
that a voter must have first of all that
degree of citizenship which the United
 States government alone can give. The eight exceptional states (Arkansas, Delaware,
 Indiana, Kansas, Missouri, Ne-
braska, South Dakota and Texas) give
voting rights to aliens who have taken out their first papers, "declared their
intention" to become citizens of the
United States. Among jurists there is
doubt as to whether these states have
not assumed a power to which they have
no right in allowing persons not yet
naturalized to vote for members of congress. A case has never come to federal
courts however, and the federal constitution, in the first of its four important
references to voting qualifications, specifically provides that electoral qualifications in respect to congress shall be
left to the states. Article I, Section 2,
of the Constitution of the United States
says: "The house of representatives
shall be composed of members chosen
... by the people of the several states
and the electors in each state shall
have the qualifications for electors of
the most numerous branch of the state
legislature."
In only two respects, one minor and
one major, does the federal constitution control voting citizenship. Of presidential elections, Article II, Section &amp;,
says: "Each state shall appoint in such
manner as the legislature thereof shall
decree, a number of electors." The
United States decrees that not the electors enumerated by state constitutions
but those decided on by the state legis-
latures shall elect the president of the
United States.
The  major limitation  on the  states'
power  to  determine  voting  citizenship
is  the XV Amendment  of the  United
States Constitution. "The right of citi-
zens of the United States to vote shall
not be denied or abridged by the United
[States or] by any state  on account of
(missing) previous condition of ser- (missing)</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/416</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>