<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 23 d.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 23 d. Newspaper clipping: Chattanooga suffragists have not appointed delegates...</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's suffrage;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 23</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>CHATTANOOGA suffragists have not
appointed delegates to the state convention at Knoxville, Oct. 28-30, but it
was said yesterday that this matter
would likely come up at the next meeting of the local league. This year Nashville will send twenty delegates to the
state meeting and the trip will be made
in a special coach decorated with the
suffrage colors. At each station "votes
for women" literature will be distributed. Memphis will also send a big
delegation. Last year Nashville, Memphis and Chattanooga each had ten representatives at the meeting and the increased number of delegates from the
capital city is evidence of the rapid
growth of that body. Mrs. L. Crozier
French has announced that a number of
prominent suffragists will appear on the
program, among them being Miss Alice
Paul. Mrs. Medill McCormick. Miss
Kate Gordon and others of equal note.
The social features of the state convention are numerous and the plans include several big affairs including a public reception at the Hotel Imperial,
where the delegates will be entertained
by the Knoxville league. The league
at Franklin will be the baby association
of the state at the convention. This
league was organized last week by Mrs.
Guilford Dudley, president of the Nashville forces.
</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/409</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>