<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 42 b</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 42 b. Newspaper clipping: In The Interest of Votes For Women.  The Knoxville Equal Suffrage League,  Edited by Emma Farrand Tyler.  Knoxville Journal. 1919.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's suffrage;</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Edited by Emma Farrand Tyler</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Knoxville Journal</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1919</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook p. 42</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>In The Interest of Votes For Women.  The Knoxville Equal Suffrage League,  Edited by Emma Farrand Tyler.
"A good number of representative men
and women, responded to the call issued
by Mrs. H. C. Milnor, president of the
Equal Suffrage league last Friday for a
meeting to consider present work in suffrage  lines.
Knoxville women, as full fledged citizens now have responsibilities that they do not wish to assume ignorantly
and they are
therefore taking steps to gain thorough information regarding questions of civic interest which will hereafter be incumbent
upon them to help their brother-citizen
in deciding, here in our own beautiful
Knoxville. We were never more proud of
its beautv and its promising future than
today, and we desire with all the things
we have in trust to serve our city well.
Therefore,    the    Equal    Suffrage    league
realizing that its initial work was done, called this meeting where was formed an orgainization with larger aims, the non-
partisan political league, with which the
old Equal Suffrage league has become
merged.
This league which has thus been dis-
solved, is the parent suffrage league of the
city, having been formed in 1910, at the
home of Mrs. L. Crozier French. There
were 36 charter members. Its first officers
 were: president, Mrs. French; vice-
president: Mrs. N. K. Cooper, secretary:
Mrs. H. W. Curtis and treasurer Mrs. Fred-
erick N. Jones. Its object has been "to ad-
vance the educational, industrial, legal and
political rights of women, and to secure
suffrage to them by appropriate state and
national legislation."
From  this  league has  been   formed   two
other   suffrage   organizations   in   the   city,
"the Political Equality league and the Mar-
garent   Brent  club,   whose   presidents are
respectivelv,   Mrs.   C.   H.   Lucky   and Miss
Ada  Fanz.    Much interest in the new or-
ganization is expressed by  both  men and
women   and   it  promises  to   become a liv-
ing  center  of  great   benefit   to   the city.
LETTER PROM  BULLS  GAP    Some weeks ago a letter came into my hands, addressed to the "Equal Suffrage League, Knoxville."'  It was from Mr. J.C. Self, principal of the high school at Bulls Gap, Tenn., stating that some of the high school girls were preparing to enter a contest on essay writing on some phase of the woman suffrage question, and asking for suggestions and literature.  Complying with these requests and expressing a keen interest in the undertaking, I asked that the 'prize essay' should be sent to me.
Feeling sure that our readers will be interested in this effort I am presenting the 
following essay, which was received this 
week. It is the essay which won the
prize at the high school meet held at
Rogersville. recently. The author is Miss
Velma Hale Addington. E. F. T.
WOMAN'S   PARTICIPATION    IN   CIVICS
To know the new, search the old.    War
has   shown   how   valuable   women   can   be
 in   civic   work.     It   has  proved   that   they 
are not  only  willing to  serve their country   but   that   they   are   abundantly   able. They are revolting against the ill health of
body   and   mind   incident   to   their   condition.   They are becoming ashamed of their 
own  faults  and   vices,   the  sense  of  help-
lesness  and   of irresponsibility   which   belittles   them.     They    know    things,    they
 are   learning   more   every   day,   and   they
 want  to   work   off this  energy  and   know- 
ledge.      This   nation   must    awaken   to   a
realization of the fact that the most dangerous thing on earth is a highly trained intelligent woman who has nothing to do.
Thw war is  finished  now  with its  great
emergencies   which   offered   them  so  many opportunities
 for service.    Something must be done
and   done  quickly   to   keep   them
honorably employed.
No man   is   a   good   father   who is   not
also   a good   citizen.       He   may     provide
everything  for   his   family   and   still   vote
against his wife   and   children.     No  woman
can be a  good  mother  who is not also a
good citizen.     She   may   train   her  chil-
dren in the way they should go while  they
are in the home and accomplish every sacrifice, and
 still be unable to protect her children 
against  conditions     outside    the home. 
We may   abuse   the force   of nature  but we cannot
obstruct    any   force   in   nature
without suffering disastrous consequences.
The woman  has   seen   the   great   need   of
her service and since she has so readily responded to the
call the  stupid effort to close her up will 
prove   ineffective and  even more disastrous in the future than it has been in the past because there is a
rapidly developing intelligence and a good growing desperation to try Eve's fate with Adam in the open, where the curse imposed was the blessing of being obliged to earn their bread by the sweat of their brow.  Women have taken and are taking today great interest in the civic reform educationally.  The women of today are see- (missing)</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/504</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>