<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 45 g</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 45 g. Newspaper clipping: (fragment) 'If the predictions in this ward are true...'</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Voting; Voter registration;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>Unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook p. 45</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>If the predictions in this ward are true
then there will have to be on an average
of 100 votes polled every minute, or
one every thirty-six seconds, and accord-
ing to these figures the booths will be
crowded every minute of the day.
In the fourteenth ward, Park City,
more than 1,000 persons have registered
and the same thing will be true as to
the voting on election day as in the eleventh ward.
Roy H. Beeler, chairman of the commissioners of election, says that he has
already urged several of the leaders in
the women's non-partisan league to
bring this matter before the members,
in order to assure everybody a vote.
Additional booths will be placed in
the larger wards of the city by the commissioners of election and all preparations will be made to accommodate the
vast crowd on the day of the contest.
In making out the list of election officers, the commissioners took into consideration the fact that the vote will
be exceedingly heavy, and men were
appointed as clerks who could quickly
enter the names of those voting and
who could count the ballots at a rapid
rate.
Mr. Beeler says he hopes the public
in general will bear in mind these facts
and assist the commission and those
who have been appointed to hold the
election as far as possible.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/519</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>