<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 23 h.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 23 h. Newspaper clipping:  no heading (Instances were related of a married woman...)</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>Unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 24</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>Instances were related of a married
woman working to support herself and
family and worthless husband. She
had saved $500 which she placed in
the bank and just before election her 
husband drew it out and went on a 
spree, using his wife's hard earned
money for a jollification. Another instance was told of a woman who owned
the homestead. Her husband urged
her to sell it and buy a larger one.
She was satisfied and refused, but
finally his persuasion and persistence
ruled and she sold it. He secured the
money and left the city and has not
been heard of since. The law protected her real property but not her personal property, and her ignorance left
her at the mercy of her unscrupulous
husband.
The first thing necessary is "education and a knowledge of the laws and
the league intends to begin at the be-
ginning, first studying the laws and
then devote their efforts towards having the most unjust ones changed or
repealed.
Women now have complete suffrage
in four states, Wyoming, Utah, Colorado, and Idaho. They have municipal suffrage in Kansas; school suffrage
in twenty-six states and territories-
taxpayer's suffrage in four states, but
Tennessee is not included in any of
these.
In New Zealand, Australia and Finland all women have same voting
privileges as men. In Norway they
have complete suffrage with slight
property qualifications. In Great Britain, Sweden, Iceland, they vote for
all officials except members of parliament. In Canada they have school and
municipal  suffrage.
An effort will be made to first secure a school and taxpayers suffrage
and municipal suffrage. Petitions on
these points will be framed and read
at the next meeting and generally discussed.
These are points that should interest all men and women who are interested in good government. It is
hoped that a large attendance will be
present at the next regular meeting
when these practical points of general
interest, will be discussed.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/413</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>