<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook,  p. 11 g</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 11 g. Newspaper clipping: Meeting Of Club Women Is Called.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's suffrage;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 11</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>MEETING OF CLUB
WOMEN IS CALLED
Plans Will Be Made to Entertain State Convention.
Mrs. L. Crozier French, president of
the Tennessee Equal Suffrage league,
has called a meeting of all representative women of this city to be held this
morning in the board of commerce parlors,   at   ten   o'clock.
This meeting is for the purpose of
discussing ways and means for Knox-
ville's entertainment of the Tennessee
Suffrage association, which convenes in
this   city   October  27,   28   and   29.
Attending this convention will be a
number of the most prominent and influential women of the state, socially
and in club work, and the gathering will
also be attended by notable suffrage
workers from eact (sic.) and west. The personnel of the convention will be quite
distinguished, and Knoxville women
must, if they are to make this gathering what it has been in other cities,
be  up  and doing,  say local leaders.
Not  only   will  members   of   the   local 
suffrage   league   be   interested   in   these
visitors,   but  every   club  woman  of  the 
city,   every  woman   prominent  in  social
circles, will find that the guestlist of this 
convention includes     names  of    women 
whom she would gladly entertain in one
way   or   another.
Mrs. French, a representative of one 
of the oldest and best families of this 
city, feels that Knoxville women will 
be glad to uphold the city's reputation
for hospitality in connection with this 
convention.
Mrs.   French   will  be   pleased   to   see 
this morning all Knoxville women who 
are  interested.    The     meeting     will  be
held  promptly  at  ten   o'clock"  and  will 
be  brief.
</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/321</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>