<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 32 c</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 32 c. Newspaper clipping: Select Leaders of Conferences. State-Wide Citizenship Efficiency Officials Are Announced.  May 28, 1913.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Meetings;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>May 28, 1913</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook p.</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>SELECT LEADERS OF CONFERENCES
State-Wide   Citizenship   Efficiency Officials Are
Announced
Presiding officers and leaders of
the discussion for the ten groups who
will figure in the conference on efficient citizenship to be held at the
University of Tennessee, June 6 and 
7 in connection with the commence- 
ment and dedicatory exercises for the
 two new buildings, have been
an nounced.
The conference will be divided into
ten general groups, composed of
closely allied agencies. Scores of
letters have been sent to prominent
men and women all over the state
requesting their presence at this conference. Letters have also been sent
 to all organizations with the request that they be represented by
 delegates. The response has been
most gratifying and the success of
 the conference is already assured.
 Gov. A. A. Taylor will preside over
the group on civil administration. In
addition to presiding over this group
conference, Governor Taylor has been
asked to preside at the dedication
of the new agricultural building on
the university farm on the Kingston
pike on Monday morning, June 6, and
at the dedication of Ayres hall, the
new liberal arts building on the crest
of the University hill on Tuesday afternoon,  June  7.
Leaders of Discussion
In addition to the presiding officer
of each group there have been named
two or more leaders of discussion for
the group.     In the group of civil administration,   over   which     Governor
Taylor   will    preside,   the   discussion
 will be led by Hon. W. W. Bond, of
Brownsville,  speaker    of    the    Tennessee  senate;   by  Hon.  A.  L.   Todd,
of Murfreesboro, speaker of the Tennessee  house  of  representatives;   by
Rowlett   Paine,   mayor  of  Memphis;
 and   by   Judge   Lytton   Hickman,   of
Nashville.
Capt. T. P. Peck, state commissioner of agriculture, will preside over
 the group conference on agriculture.
 A, D. Smith, of Knoxville, and E. C.
Cunningham, of Clarksville, will lead
the  discussion.
Z. W. Whelan, of the Whelan Machine works, of Chattanooga, will preside over the group on commerce and
industry. George R. James, of Memphis, and John Houser, of Ducktown
Copper company, have been chosen
leaders of the  discussion.
Malcolm McDermott, president of the state bar association, and dean of
University of Tennessee law school,
will preside over the group on law.
Dr. Wm. B. Burns, of Memphis,
is to preside over the group on medicine and dentistry. The group leaders are Dr. James W. Winn, past
president of the State Dental association; and Dr. R. E. Dee Smith, superintendent of the Eastern Hospital
for the Insane at Knoxville.
C.  P.  J.  Mooney,  of  Memphis,  ed-
itor of the Memphis Commercial Ap-
peal, has been asked to preside over
the   press   group.      J.   D.   Holbrook,
editor, of      the   Dresden   Enterprise,
and J. I. Finney, editor of the Columbia Herald, will lead the discussion.
Mrs. Eakin a Group Leader
Mrs. John Hill Eakin, of Nashville, 
president of the state board of charities and corrections, will preside over
Ithe  group  on  home  and  social wel-
fare.      Miss   Margaret   Ambrose,   di-
rector   of   home   demonstration   work
in the division of extension, will lead
the   discussion.
Prof. J. B. Brown, state superin-
tendent of public instruction, is to
preside over the group on education.
Prof. R. L. Jones, superintendent of
the Chattanooga public schools, will
lead the discussion.
Rev. James I. Vance, D. D., pastor
of the First Presbyterian church of
Nashville, will be chairman of the
group on religious education. With
him as leader of the discussion will
be Dr. Carey E. Morgan, also of
Nashville, pastor of the Vine Avenue
Christian church, and Dr. Oscar E.
Sams, of Jefferson City, president of
Carson-Newman college.
All group conferences will be held
on Monday afternoon, June 6, in the
new agricultural building on the university  farm.
On Tuesday, June 7, there will be
 a general conference in the morn-
ing preceding the dedication of Ayres
hall in the afternoon. At this time 
a committee chosen by the groups 
will present their conclusions and any recommendations that may have
been decided upon.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/460</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>