<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 04 b</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 04 b. Newspaper clipping: 'Mrs. L. Crozier French Woman's Candidate for Councilman from City-At-Large'. Continued from Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 04 a. 1923.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women;Political elections;</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Lizzie Crozier French</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1923</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 04</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>As soon as the legislature gave the women municipal suffrage I organized the
Non-Partisan Municipal League. Mrs. T. P. Miller served as chairman during its active
existence and proved a most efficient one. Because of this league's splendid work,
twice as many women were registered to vote in Knoxville in our first election after
enfranchisement as registered in any other southern city.
Several years ago I was elected president of the board of directors of the woman's building, succeeding several presidents who had made a great business success of this
woman's enterprise,
Mrs. Geo. F. Mellen only resigned the presidency after all debts had been paid
and the building was self-supporting. This enterprise bears witness that women are successful in business when given the opportunity to exercise their business ability freely.
I have given this hasty sketch of my civic work in the past so that citizens may
draw their own conclusions as to whether I would be an efficient and faithful servant
should voters place me in the position of a councilman from the city-at-large.
It is possible for me to give my whole time to the duties of a councilman, as I
have no family to look after, nor any regular business to claim my attention.
I am for every progressive improvement that will tend to make our city a desirable place in which to live and a great business center, but I shall watch carefully that
the means used to this end are practical and not wasfully extravagant.
The public may rest assured that everything that will safeguard the home and give
adequate protection to women and children, the weak and unfortunate will receive my
hearty support. 
One of the most positive traits of my character is that I will not allow myself to be
used by any ring or clique for personal ends. The righteousness of any proposed measure and the benefit that will accrue to the public through its enactment must be shown
me.
Voters of Knoxville, I ask for your support and promise in return efficient and
faithful service.
L. CROZIER FRENCH
(Adv.)
</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/185</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>