<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 31f</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 31 f. Newspaper clipping: "Women in general have a deeper and more abiding interest in children than men have. ..."  Emma Lee Rice.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women;</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Emma Lee Rice</dc:creator>
<dc:date>Unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook p. 31</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>Women in general have a deeper
and more abiding interest in children
than men have. This is necessarily
true because mothers are more closely
associated with their children than
fathers are. In fact, in many homes
the training of the children is left
practically in the hands of the moth-
er. It follows that women know more
of the disposition of children, their
wishes and their needs than men can
possibly know.
At present in the state of Tennessee
women not being qualified voters are
debarred from positions on the boards
of education. Had women positions on
these boards, the children of Tennessee would fare better than they now
do in many places
Professional politicians are said to
have declared that a school board
composed of men is much more easily
managed than one consisting of both
men and women. In the latter case,
each acts as a check upon the other.
If women were qualified voters
they could serve on boards of education and vote on all school questions.
Then the great-army of women teachers who outnumber the men many
times would be placed on an equal
footing with the men in their profession ,and merit alone would determine position and salary.
Surely a condition in which both
the pupils and teachers of the schools
will be benefited is a desirable one,
nay a necessary one for highest development of the schools.
 EMMA LEE  RICE.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/457</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>