<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 01</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 01.  Mrs. L. Crozier French, Woman's Candidate For Councilman From The City-At-Large.  1923.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Political campaigns;  Political elections; Women; Ephemera;</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Lizzie Crozier French</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1923</dc:date>
<dc:type>ephemera</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 01</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>MRS. L. CROZIER FRENCH

WOMAN'S CANDIDATE FOR
COUNCILMAN FROM THE CITY-AT-LARGE
To The Voters of Knoxville &#8212;
Because of the failure of the committee of 18 to nominate a woman on the "People's Ticket," a number of warm advocates of the city manager charter have requested me to allow them to put forward my
name as a candidate for nomination for councilman-at-large at the primary election, September 15th, 1923.
My consent has been given because I believe in a "square deal for all"&#8212;young and old, rich and poor,
white and black and men and women. Those who bear the burdens of family and municipal life should be
regarded as equal factors in home and city and no ban should be put on mothers and business women, because of sex.
My record as a public spirited citizen is known to all of those who have given attention to the educational and welfare activities of Knoxville during the last half century.
In 1885, with my sister, I took charge of the Female Institute which my grandfather, John Crozier,
(first postmaster) helped to found. About that time I bought a home and have been a tax payer ever
since.
In that same year I organized the
Ossoli Circle, a literary society for
women which has the distinction of
being the oldest club for women in
the south. At the end of five years,
being disappointed that I could not
prevail upon Ossoli Circle to take up
work for civic betterment, I organized the Woman's Educational and
Industrial Union.
Having educated my son and
started him in a successful business
career, I gave up my school and devoted my whole time to educational
and uplift work for city and state.
As soon as the trustees voted to admit girls to our university, the then
president, Dr. Charles Dabney, wrote
to me: "The thing you have so long
worked for has come to pass&#8212;the
University of Tennessee is no[w] coeducational."
About 1890 I induced the city
council to establish the office of police matron, Knoxville thus became
the first city in the south to put a
woman in charge of women offenders. About this time I began soliciting the county court to establish an
industrial school for girls and boys.
Seven years from that time I was
successful and saw the present institution established.
I persuaded the King's Daughters
to establish the first kindergarten in
this city. &#8212;	
The first woman's exchange I also put in operation. A lady is now doing a splendid trade in beaten
biscuit who began as a child to make biscuit for that exchange.
All the time I was working to establish these permanent institutions I was helping the police matron
in rescue work.    Many girls who had taken the first downward step we returned to respectable society.
It is impossible for me to enumerate here all the civic activities that I have helped forward. Some
are: The first hospital for Knoxville, parks and play grounds, juvenile court and first refuge for unfortunates. 
I was chairman of the committee that established the Associated Charities, and was one of the founders of the Writers' Club.
In 1910 I organized the first local suffrage association. We had a state suffrage association for many
years, of which I was a member from its inception. I have been state president of the suffrage association,
also of the Federation of Women's Clubs and the first vice-president of the State Parent-Teachers Association.
As soon the legislature gave the women municipal suffrage I organized the Non-Partisan Municipal
League. Mrs. T. P. Miller served as chairman during its active existence and proved a most efficient one.
Because of this league's splendid work, twice as many women were registered to vote in Knoxville in our
first election after enfranchisement as registered in any other southern city.
Several years ago I was elected president of the board of directors of the woman's building, succeeding several presidents who had made a great business success of this woman's enterprise.
Mrs. Geo. F. Mellen only resigned the presidency after all debts had been paid and the building was
self-supporting. This enterprise bears witness that women are successful in business when given the
opportunity to exercise their business ability freely. 
I have given this hasty sketch of my civic work in the past so that citizens may draw their own
conclusions as to whether I would be an efficient and faithful servant should voters place me in the position
of a councilman from the city-at-large.
It is possible for me to give my whole time to the duties of a councilman, as I have no family to look
after, nor any regular business to claim my attention.
I am for every progressive improvement that will tend to make our city a desirable place in which
to live and a great business center, but I shall watch carefully that the means used to this end are practical and not wastefully extravagant.
The public may rest assured that everything that will safeguard the home and give adequate protection to women and children, the weak and unfortunate will receive my hearty  support.
One of the most positive traits of my character is that I will not allow myself to be used by any
ring or clique for personal ends. The righteousness of any proposed measure and the benefit that will
accrue to the public through its enactment must be shown me.
Voters of Knoxville, I ask for your support and promise in return efficient and faithful service.
MRS. L. CROZIER FRENCH
 W-  L-  WARTERS    CO..     KNOXVILLE
</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/166</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>