<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 31 a.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 31 a. Newspaper clipping: The Ballot and The Schools.  By Mrs. Helen L  Grenfell.  Knoxville Journal &amp; Tribune.  March 16, 1913.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Education; Women's suffrage;</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Mrs. Helen L  Grenfell</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Knoxville Journal &amp; Tribune</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>March 16, 1913</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 31</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>
The Ballot and The Schools
By MRS. HELEN   L. GRENFELL,
Former State Superintendent of Public Instruction for Colorado.
Women  have  always     had     school
suffrage   in   Colorado.   The   fact   has
acted as a preventive of the nomination   of     obnoxious     persons.     Judge
Louis   W.   Cunningham    of    Colorado
City,  writes:
"In Colorado City, from 1883 to
1893, there were six mayors who were
saloonkeepers. During two or three
years there were three saloonkeepers
in the council; and for one year we
had a mayor, and three councilmen
who lived on the woes of others. Since
1894, when women came to their own
there has never been a saloonkeeper
elected to any office in Colorado City.
Women have always had a vote at
school elections in this state, and, as
a consequence, while saloon men were
on the city council, not one ever served on a school board in our town."
What is true in Colorado City is
true, with hardly an exception,
throughout the state. It is alleged that
the voting woman forgets the welfare
of her children. Statistics are not
thrilling, but they are convincing.
Nothing tells the location of our
hearts more surely than the figures
of the tax list.  According to age and
long establishment, the thirteen original colonies should lead the United
States in the educational procession.
Let us consider the per capita expenditure of the  total population, for the
education of their young folks in
these  states.
Massachusetts, $4.96; New Hampshire,
 $2,79; 
Rhode      Island, $3.79; 
Connecticut, $ 3 .72;   New  York, $5.00; 
New Jersey, $3.51; Maryland, $2.12; Pennsylvania, $3.52;  Virginia, $1.07; 
Delaware, $2.46;   North   Carolina,   66 cents;
 Georgia,   97 cents.,
Over against these let us set the
$5.08 spent by Colorado, the highest
amount spent for educational purposes by any state in the Union. These
figures are from the report of the
commissioner of education, William T. Harris, for 1901-02.
But   it   may   be   urged   that   school
suffrage  is sufficient,   and     that    full-
suffrage has not assisted the Colorado
woman in  extending the scope of her
educational  work.  No one who is acquainted with  the facts will  say this.
With the school franchise only, women   found  it -up-hill   work   to   inaugurate  reforms along  educational   lines..
They  formed association and founded
"free   kindergartens,"     kept     up     by
philanthropic    people,    fairs, bazaars and the various means used by women everywhere.
    In   the   spring   of 1893, the year 
when the vote was to be taken on the
suffrage question  in November, for
the first time, the annual school election
 held in May became a burning
 question  throughout the state.
Thousands   of   votes   were polled where
there had been  tens and fifties.
The women proved past a per-adventure
they   would   vote.   In Denver they, for the first time, elected a woman (Mrs. Ione T. Hanna) to the school board.  
The issue was to make the
kindergarten a part of the public school system.
 The powers that were bowed to the inevitable.  Today the kindergarten is firmly established in many districts throughout the state, and many are being started as rapidly as finances permit.
The next progressive step
 was   the erection of a 
manual  training high school in Denver, and manual training departments have
been  added  to a number of schools throughout the state.
Instead of thinking loss of their
homes,   women     began     to     consider 
them   more   carefully   and   sought   to 
bring into  these     close     corporations 
something of the   scientific   spirit of
the age.   Chairs of domestic economy 
were established  in the state agricul-   
tural   college   and   the   state   normal 
school, and the professor of domestic
economy in the former has been twice 
president of the Colorado Suffrage association.  The   interest   in   the   old- 
fashioned womanly arts has increased
instead of diminishing. There is hardly a  state  where   the  school  population   is   increasing  so   rapidly.   It   has
gained 25 per cent in five years.  Colorado's  compulsory     education    laws
are  said   to   be   the  best  in   existence
anywhere.     There     is     no   difference
made in teachers' salaries on account
of  sex.
After   twenty  years'   experience   in
school work, I can say that our school
boards are    absolutely    non-political,
and party affiliation is never  considered in the appointment  of teachers.
Whilst our teachers are citizens, taking part in  public affairs, voting and
often   attending   primaries   and   conventions,  I  have  never    heard    of a
teacher being dismissed or appointed
because she was a republican or democrat,   nor   of a  member  of a  school
board   being   elected   because   he   belonged to this or that party. Generally,   both   parties   are   represented   on
the  same   board.  Sometimes  a   board
principally democratic is found in republican communities, and vice versa.
Our teachers are free to vote according to  their  own  consciences.  I  have
seen  or  heard  more  party politics  in
school matters in one block in Albany,
Buffalo   or   Philadelphia  than   in   the
103,92 5 square miles of Colorado soil.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/451</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>