<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 28 c.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 28 c. Newspaper clipping: Enfranchisement Of The American Woman. Arguments Against Woman's Suffrage Answered By Principles Of Good Government.  By L. CROZIER FRENCH, President, Equal   Suffrage   Club.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's suffrage; Women's rights;</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>L. Crozier French</dc:creator>
<dc:date>Unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 28</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>ENFRANCHISEMENT OF
THE AMERICAN WOMAN
Arguments Against Woman's
Suffrage Answered by Principles of Good Government.
"The Principles of Government Applied to Women's Enfranchisement" is
the subject of a paper by Mrs. L.
Crozier French, president of the Knox-
ville Equal Suffrage League. Mrs.
French has read widely on the subject
which she treats logically in this paper,
answering the common arguments
against suffrage with arguments that
noted statesmen and orators have used
in pleading for national independence.
The subject is one that is attracting
widespread attention and the following
paper is one that should prove of general interest.
The paper is as follows:
Says   Benjamin   Franklin:     "Liberty
or freedom   consists in having an  actual   share    in     the    appointment     of
those  who  frame  the  laws,   and   who
are to be the guardians of every man's
life,    property   and   peace,   for   the   all 
of one  man  is  as  dear to him  as the 
all   of another."    Is  not  this   true  of 
every woman as well as of every man ? i
Franklin   continues:
  "The poor man has  an  equal  right, 
but more need to have representatives
in the   legislature than the rich  one."
How great a truth is here set forth.
Those who are powerless through poverty need the protection  afforded    by
the  ballot.      Custom   has  decreed   for
centuries that man must  have charge
of the finances; hence, women may be
considered poor as a class.
  Nature,  aided  and   abetted  by  custom,
has made woman weak physical -
ly, and for this   cause another  reason
arises why she  should   have the  pro-
 tection   of  the  vote.     But  some     say
 women are represented  by men,     not
making  note   of  the   fact   that     many
 women  have  neither   father,   husband,
 brothers or cousins.    But let   us   hear
Franklin   on   this   sort   of   representa-
tion:      "They  who  have  no  voice  nor
vote in the electing  of  representatives
do   not   enjoy   liberty,   but   are   absolutely   enslaved   to   those     who    have
votes and to their representatives,   for
to   be  enslaved   is  to  have   governors
whom other men have set over us, and 
be  subject, to   laws  made by  the  rep- 
resentatives of   others,  without   having
had representatives of our own to give
consent in our behalf." i
Distasteful   as   the  statement   is    to
men that women are politically slaves,
the  fact  must    be  acknowledged    by
reasonable people.   Here is what James
Otis says of the sort of representation
 women  have   had:     "No  such  phrase
 as  virtual    representation     was    ever
 known   in   law   or   constitution.  It   is
altogether    a     subtlety     and    illusion,
wholly   unfounded   and   absurd.       We
 must  not  be  cheated   by     any    such
 phantom or other trick of law or poli-
tics."     If no   man  can represent    any
other   man,   how   much    less   can   any
man   represent   a   woman?     Can   any
man represent the feelings of a mother?     The    most     frequent objection
one    hears    urged    against    the    enfranchisement  of   women  is   that   politics   is   too   corrupt   for   good   women
to take part in.    Could any reason   be
more absurd?    Women   must live  under the government conducted by these
bad   politicians.     If   women    are      the
better, why not  let them try  to  make
some   improvement?     Why   tie     their
hands and   make  them stand idly    by 
while  unworthy men are  put  in  high
places to rule over  them?
A violation of the constitution of the
United  States   that is practiced  in all
except four of the states today is the
taxation   of   the   property   of   women.
Read what James Otis said about taxation,    without    representation:      "The
very act of taxing exercised over those
who   are   not   represented.   appears   to
me to be depriving them of   their most
essential    right    as   freemen,   and     if
continued,   seems   to  be,   in  effect,   an
entire  disfranchisement  of  every  civil
right.    For  what  civil   right is  worth
a rush, after a man's property is subject to be taken from him at pleasure
without his consent?    If a man is not
his own assessor in person or by deputy, his  liberty  is  gone, and he is entirely   at   the  mercy  of  others."     And
this is true,   even   in a greater degree
of women, because of their impecunious condition and their physical weakness?.
No greater example could be given
Of the necessity of every class and
every individual being represented at
the polls than is here shown of these
great statesmen, Otis and Franklin,
who could point out so clearly these
human rights and yet who did not demand them for women, so far as I
know. When individuals or classes
are fighting for their own rights they
are apt to neglect those of others. So
the laws concerning women have been
always the last to be changed as civilization advanced, because
have not looked after the
themselves. Some have been too poor,
weak and ignorant to do so and
others have been basking in the lap
of luxury, protected and cared for by
male relatives, and have been heedless
and indifferent to the needs of others
except in the way of giving pity and
charity.
Before   the   close   of  this  twentieth
century   I   dare   to   predict   that   class
slavery  will  be     banished     from     the
Anglo-Saxon world  and women,  being
free,   there   will   be seen   a   new era
about  to  dawn     on     earth,    and
prophecy  contained   in   the   song     the
angels   sang will begin  to  be realized
'Peace on earth, good will to men.'
L. CROZIER FRENCH,
President, Equal   Suffrage   Club.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/440</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>