<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 07 b</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 07 b. Newspaper clipping: 'An Open Letter To The Knox County Election Commission.'</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Voter registration; Voting;</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Mrs. L.C. French</dc:creator>
<dc:date>unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 07</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>An Open Letter To The Knox
County Election Commission.
Gentlemen:
It has been announced that your
commission has instructed registrars
to compel women to give their exact
age when applying for a registration  certificate.
It is the purpose of this communication to ask you to give your
reason to the public for giving such
instruction.
It is most probable that many
are as much puzzled as I am, as to
the necessity or advisability of such
an interpretation of the election law.
I hope that it is not due to mental
weakness that I cannot think of one
single reason why registrars should
know the exact age of any one who
applies for a certificate to vote. The
registrar must have reason to believe that the applicant has arrived
at the legal age, twenty-one, which
is required by our state law of every voter. Why should the registrar
know anything more as regards the
age of applicants?
One of the commission is reported
as saying, "The women now have
got into politics and they must be
reconciled to complying with all requirements." If the requirement is
one which in no way promotes the
interest of the public but is most
displeasing to many electors, why
should they obey it? I have not the
election law to which to refer, but
I venture to say it is not the intent of that law to pry into the
private personal affairs of electors.
Every elector should resist, by endeavoring to have changed, any law
which approaches tyranny even
though it involves so small a matter as  the exact age of the voter.
You are not compelled to put a
tyrannical construction on this law,
why do so?
MRS.   L.   C.   FRENCH.
</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/200</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>