<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 34 b</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 34 b. Newspaper clipping: Equal Suffrage Department.  Editors: Mrs. Julia Lucky, President of Equal Suffrage League, and Mrs. Sara H. Hood.  March 30, 1914.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's suffrage;</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Mrs. Julia Lucky and Mrs. Sara H. Hood</dc:creator>
<dc:date>March 30, 1914</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook p. 34</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>Equal Suffrage Department.  Editors: Mrs. Julia Lucky, President of Equal Suffrage League, and Mrs. Sara H. Hood.

STATUS OF SUFFRAGE  IN THE STATES.
Free  States.
Wyoming, Colorado, Utah, Idaho,   Washington,   California.   Oregon,   Kansas, Arizona
Campaign   States.
                                                    House                   Senate                  Goes to Voters
Michigan                                        74-21                     26-6                      1913
Montana, two dissenting votes in each   house,                                           1914
Nevada                                          49-03                    19-3                       1913 or 14
South Dakota                                  70-30                    41-2                      1914
States Where Amendment Has   Passed   One Legislature and Must Pass Another
New Jersey                                     46-5                      14-5                       1914
 New York                                     125-5                      40-2                       1915

Favorable But Not Final   Action
Iowa                                             81-26                                                   1916
1910
Missouri, both houses have passed bill to engrossment                                 1914
North Dakota,  passed in senate                                                                 1914
Pennsylvania, passed in house         131-70                                                 1915

A bill granting full suffrage to wo- 
men has just passed both houses of 
the  Alaska     Legislature,     without     a   
single dissenting vote.    As Alaska is a   
territory the ballot can be granted by   
an Act  of Legislation and  it will  not  
have to be referred to the voters. 

Representatives   from   19   states   of 
the South and West will attend    the        
Mississippi   Valley   Suffrage     Confer-   
ence  which   meets  in  St.   Louis  April 2,3, and 4.  Among the many notable women who are to appear on various programmes arranged for this occasion is the President of the Tennessee Equal Sufrrage Assocaition - Miss Sarah Barnwell Elliott.  Superintendent of instructin of North Carolina.  Mr. Joyner has lately placed himself on the right side of the fence by urging that women be made eligible to school boards "in order that the schools may have the benefit of their peculiar fitness."  Hurrah for Mr. Joyner. 
...of happiness is curtailed by the lack of the ballet.  Much of the happiness of life comes from the ability to do or help to do large things that are worthwhile, and that are a blessing to other family circles as well as my own.    "No man liveth unto himself," and no family can live unto itself.  The interest of all are so inseparably united  that  no woman can do her full duty inside the four walls of her own home.  She sums up her argument by giving the following concise reasons  for the ballot:  I want to vote because (a) Intelligence is a prime qualification for voting, and it is conceded that the general average of intelligence is as good among women as among men.
(b)     1  have to  obey  the  laws,  and
therefore want to help make them.
	
(c)     I pay taxes.

(d)     I am as much  interested and
concerned  in   the  things  voted   on  as
men  are.
(e)     Disenfranchisement is a    badge
of  inferiority   and   contempt.
"in     order
(f)     I am more capable of casting
an intelligent ballot than thousands of
men are.
Hurrah   for
Finally&#8212;I   want   to   vote   because   I
Want to  Vote.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/470</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>