<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 18 c.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 18 c. Newspaper clipping: Educational Myopia. Lalla Block Arnstein.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Education;</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Lalla Block Arnstein</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>unknown</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 18</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>Educational Myopia.
The shortsightedness of our state legislature has brought about a condition
which is working against the object of
our educational system&#8212;the development
of an intelligent citizenship. Our self-
satisfied citizen sits complacently by,
while our legislators make laws, such
as county school boards. Why should
men exclusively govern our schools'?
What have a man's party affiliations to
do with his ability to educate the young?
Yet it is an accepted fact that the
schools, like other offices of the state
government, are controlled for political
patronage. With all the money expended by the state for schools and
school purposes, the state of Tennessee
remains one of the most illiterate in the
Union.
Twenty-five years ago there was absolutely no qualification necessary to be a
member of the school board. Men were
not questioned whether they could even
read or write. This was in time changed
and to "read and write" was made the
first qualification. Then a little higher
education was asked and so have the
board been struggling on for this last
quarter of a century. With what result?
That today Tennessee is still steeped in
illiteracy, notwithstanding the fact that
twenty-five per cent of the state's taxes
are devoted to educational work. If
men have fallen so short in their efforts,
why will they persist in making laws
that bar all but "qualified voters" from
school   boards ?
And   why   was   this   law   made?     To
shut out the women.    And why shut out
women?    Because the politicians control
and wish  to control the school funds. A
man in East Tennessee said under oath
that   a   county   superintendent   declared
that the  board of education is the very 
finest   political   asset   a   man   can   have.
Are we to sit calmly by, purblind to all 
this?    About twenty-seven states in the 
Union give to women a vote for school 
officers.   There are any number of
women on county and city school boards
and  acting as county  and  city  superin-
tendents.    The eastern and the western
states   have     recognized     woman's   efficiency   and   such   short   sightedness   on
the part of Tennessee legislators, should
be   overcome.     It  is  only   in   the   south
that educational myopia  remains a  per-
vasive  disease.
LALLA BLOCK ARNSTEIN.
</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/348</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>