<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 35 b</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 35 b.  Newspaper clipping: Suffragists' Convention.  Will Be Occasion of Much Activity by Women.  1914.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's suffrage; Meetings;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>1914</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook p. 35</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>SUFFRAGISTS'
CONVENTION
Will Be Occasion of Much Activity by Women.
Social Events For Visitors Are
to Be Made Important Feature of the Gathering.

As the time for the annual meeting of the Tennessee Equal Suffrage convention draws near, interest in the event increases.
It is thought, by all in touch with the suffrage movement in this state
that the 1914 convention, to be held in this City October 28, 29 and 30, will be the most successful ever conducted in Tennessee, and a large attendance from all sections of the state is expected.
The Nashville delegation will be the largest.  It will consist of about twenty women, who will come to this city in a special Pullman.
Mrs. Guilford Dud-
ley, president of the. Nashville league
and a social leader at the Tennessee cap-
ital, will lead the delegation. Maria
Thompson Daviess, the well-known author, will also be in the party from
Nashville.
A large delegation is also expected
from Chattanooga, several will come
from Jackson, and a number from Mor-
ristown and other East Tennessee cities.
The Hotel Imperial is to be convention headquarters, and the day sessions
will be held in the convention room at
that hotel. The evening sessions will
be in  Market hall.
It was first announced that the sessions of the convention would he held
In the Lyceum building, but it has been
decided that the assembly room of the
Woman's building is too small.
The morning sessions will be devoted
to business, and although the public will
be admitted, these sessions will not be
of general interest. The afternoon sessions will be interesting, but the night
sessions have been planned with the idea
of making the suffrage movement of
more interest to the general public. At
these evening sessions addresses will be
made by national speakers and prominent suffrage speakers of Tennessee.
Gentlemen are especially invited to attend the evening sessions.
All sessions of the convention will be 
presided over by Mrs. L. Crozier-French, 
of Knoxville, president of the Tennessee 
association.
Besides  the prominent Tennessee suf- 
fragists who will be in attendance, sev- 
eral   national   workers   will   be   present. 
The national board sends representatives
to   each   state   convention,   and   several
women   with   national     reputations     as
speakers   will  be  heard   here.
Chief among these are Miss Alice
Paul, of Washington, D. C, president
of the Congressional Union for Woman
Suffrage; Mrs. Medill McCormick, of
Chicago, chairman of the congressional
committee of the National Woman's Suffrage association, and Mrs. Ernest Seaton-Thompson, wife of the author-naturalist, who is chairman of the program
committee of the National Suffrage as-
sociation.
Besides the sessions of the convention, a number of social events have been
planned.
On the evening of Wednesday, October 28. following the opening session,
a reception will be held in the parlors
of the Imperial. On the afternoon of
Thursday, October 29, Ossoli circle will
entertain at the Lyceum building for
the   delegates  to   the   convention.   "This affair is to be given in special compliment
 to Mrs. French, who is the founder
of Ossoli and is president of the Tennessee  Suffrage association.
Each afternoon of the convention some
social courtesy will be tendered the visitors, and the convention will be the
occasion of   unusual  club  and social activity
 in   Knoxville.
The first session of the convention will
be  held   on   the   evening   of   Wednesday,
October  28,   at  eight   o'clock,   when   ad-
dresses of  welcome,   with responses, will
be  made.    An   address   will   then   follow
by Mrs.  Mediil   McCormick,  of Chicago.
Thursday   afternoon,   addresses   will   be
made   by   Miss   Alice   Paul     and   Miss
Maria   Thompson   Daviess.
Following are the officers of the state
aissociation:                                                       
President&#8212;Mrs.     L.     Crozier-French.
Vice   President&#8212;Mrs.   James  M.   Mc-
Cormack.   Memphis.
Vice   President Middle Tennessee
Miss  Maria   T.   Daviess.   Jackson.
Vice President West Tennessee&#8212;Mrs.
G.  H.  Robertson,  Nashville.
Vice     President     East     Tennessee &#8212;
(Withdrawn).
Corresponding    Secretary&#8212;Mrs.    Perkins  Baxter,   Nashville.
Recording Secretary&#8212;Miss Sue White,
Jackson.
Treasurer&#8212;Miss C.  J.   Wester.  Chattanooga.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/474</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>