<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 03 b</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 03 b. Newspaper clipping: 'Anti-Vice Leaguers Against Segregation.' Knoxville Journal Tribune.  May 6, 1914. Continuation of clipping p. 03 a.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Scrapbooks; Clippings; Politics &amp; government; Prostitution;</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Knoxville Journal Tribune</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Knoxville Journal Tribune</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>May 6, 1914</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 03</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>Mr.   Flenniken   discussed   the   light- 
ing question and  said  that he would 
recommend   that  a  sub-committee  be 
appointed  to    investigate  the    advisability of erecting a municipal lighting   plant     that   citizens   might     get
cheaper light   and power than at present. .
Forty-inine arrests were made by 
the police last week, fines assessed to 
the amount of $510, and $255 collect- 
ed, according to the report of Chief of
Police  Ed. D. Connors.
Chief Sam B. Boyd, of the fire department, reported that three runs
had been made by the fire department.
Commissioner James A. Hensley
submitted the monthly report of the
police department which showed that
356 arrests were made, $2,166.50 in
fines assessed, and $799.15  collected.
The city electrician reported that he
had made thirty-five inspections, and
had issued 18 permits during the
month past.
By motion of Mayor Heiskell the
bill of Pickle, Turner and Kennerly
for service in connection with the
suit brought to retain $24,000 contingent fund set aside at the time of
the purchase of the city waterworks
plant was order paid. The amount
was $568.
It was decided to let out a part of
the work of constructing sewer laterals in the ninth ward connecting
with the Third creek sewer to contractors and Recorder D. G. Leahy
was instructed to advertise for bids.
The cost of the work is estimated at
$1,700.
Repaving of Gay Street
Commissioner John W. Flenniken
stated that as the conduit work on
Gay street would be complete in a
month, and everything in readiness for
the re-Paving of Gay street, the commission should advertise for bids for
work and material, so that the cost
and merits of all could be determined
before action is taken. He made this
as a  motion   which   was   duly   carried.
Mayor Heiskell voting the negative
Recorder Leahy was then instructed
to advertise for bids on all standard
material, to be received until noon
Monday, April 27, when the bids will
be opened.
The budget and tax rate ordinances
which have been held up for, consid-
eration of the commission as a whole
were advanced one reading when they
were brought up by Sam E. Hill
commissioner of finance and accounts
for the second time. Mr. Hill explained that the ordinances will really have to receive four readings, as
they will lie over a week upon the
third reading before passage.
An ordinance granting the Southern
Railway company permission to build
a side track on Campbell street was
passed on second reading. The ordinance providing the kind of paving
to be used on Gay street between car
tracks was passed on its third and
final reading. It provides creosoted
wood  block  paving.
Attention to the proposition made
to the commisison some time ago by
the trustees of the Lawson McGhee
library was renewed by a letter from
the trustees. The proposition was to
erect a $50,000 library building to be
used as a public library  in the same
name as at present, and lease to the
city for a period of ninety-nine years
all the expenses of the operation,
maintenance, etc., to be borne by city
was rejected upon moton of Mayor
Helskell. A motion was carried to invite a committee of the trustees of
the library to meet the commission in
council to discuss further a library
for the city. Mayor Heiskell appoint-
ed a committee composed of Commissioner Hill and McTeer to investigate
the cost of a lot, the cost of erecting a
suitable library building, and all in
connection  with  the matter.
</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/168</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>