<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 23 e.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 23 e. Newspaper clipping: Equal Suffragists Have Ended Their Convention.  Resolutions Adopted by Faction of Which Mrs. French is President.  [1914]</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's suffrage;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>[1914]</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 23</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>EQUAL SUFFRAGISTS HAVE
ENDED THEIR CONVENTION
Resolutions Adopted by Faction of Which Mrs, French
is Presdent (sic.),
The annual convention of the Tennessee Equal Suffrage association was
brought to a close Friday afternoon 
when the faction of which Mrs. L. Crozier French is president, adjourned sine
die. The faction of which Mrs. James 
McCormack is president, adjourned Fri
day morning.
It  was voted by Mrs.  French's faction
to donate the sum of $200 to the national 
suffrage   convention,     which     meets     in
Nashville  Nov.   12 to  17.
The city of Knoxville was thanked   by 
rising vote for  its  hospitality  and   kindness,   and  resolutions   of  good  will   were
adopted   as  follows:
"Resolved, first, that a hearty vote of
thanks be given the Knoxville Equal 
Suffrage league and its friends for their
delightful entertainment of the convention of the Tennessee Equal Suffrage
association of 1914, among which we
mention especially Mr. William M. Epps,.
Mr. Joseph S. Monday, Mr. Wm. Eugene Monday, who with their handsome
cars met belated trains with good humor,
handled weighty suit cases with chiv-
alric courtesy, and with celerity conducted the delegates to various points of
local and historic interest; also a number of the members of the Board of
Commerce who were so generous with
their cars; also the ladies of the Ossoli
circle for their most enjoyable entertainment  of the delegates.
"Resolved, second, that the Tennessee
Equal Suffrage association extend a message of all good will, hopes for successful work, and harmonious relations to all
organizations endorsing the cause of
equal suffrage in  the state of Tennessee.
"Resolved, third, that the press of
Knoxville be thanked for its interest in
the  convention.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/410</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>