<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 51</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 51. Newspaper clipping: Mrs. L.C. French To Be Highly Honored.  Knoxville Sentinel.  October 4, 1925.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women;</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Knoxville Sentinel</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>October 4, 1925</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook p. 51</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>Mrs. LC. French To
Be Highly Honored
The French Memorial Room, in
the headquarters of the Women's
Party in Washington, willbe dedicated to Mrs. L. Crozier French, a
pioneer worker for women's rights
in the South and the founder of
Ossoli Circle in Knoxville. This honor is being paid to Mrs. French
while she is still living to show her
the great love that her native state
holds  for   her.
The Woman's Party for Tennessee has charge of the decorating
and furnishing of the room, and
Mrs. S. L. Branch of Knoxville is
the general chairman of the work.
Mrs. Branch has sub-committees
in West, Middle and East Tennessee. Mrs. S. G. Heiskell of Knoxville is chairman of the East Tennessee committee.
There was a meeting of this division at the home of Mrs. French
on Wednesday morning to complete
plans for the work. All the decorating in the room has been finished,
and it is now ready for the furnishings.
Each women's club in the state
is asked to give one article toward   the   furnishing of   the  room.
Only old pieces of strictly Tennessee colonial style will be used in
furnishing the room. Some of the
furniture of President and Mrs.
Polk will be used. A lady in Middle Tennessee has donated a sugar
chest over one hundred years old.
Other pieces that have been con-
tributed are a fireside chair, given
by Mrs. Wm. C. Ross, and some of
the furniture of President Johnson.
Anyone who has old furniture that 
she would like to give, or anyone
who would like to give money should 
communicate with Mrs. S. L. 
Branch, Box 647, or, Mrs. S. G.
Heiskell, 710 Henley street. Mrs.
Heiskell is chairman of the Ossoil
committee   and   state   treasurer.
The Women's Party headquar- 
ters in Washington is an old build- 
ing on Capitol Hill. Mrs. Belmont
gave it to the Women's Party to 
be used for political headquarters.
The house was at one time the cap-
itol of the United States for seven
years. It is made up of three old
homes, and at present it has forty
rooms in it.
Several of the states have completed the decorating and furnishing of their rooms: Virginia, Dela-
were, Colorado, Massachusetts,
Connecticut, Others are working oi
their rooms.
The L. Crozier French Room will
be dedicated early in December at
the   time   when   congress   convenes.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/541</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>