<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Votes for Women a Success (p. 3 of 4)</dc:title>
<dc:description>Votes for Women a Success (p. 3 of 4).  Southern States Woman Suffrage Conference. No Date.  Lizzie Crozier French Papers.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Women's suffrage; Voting; Ephemera;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>ephemera</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizze Crozier French Papers</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>"Signed:
 "MRS. SOLON H. JACOBS, Birmingham, Ala., President
 of the Alabama Equal Suffrage Asoociation.
 "MRS. ALICE ELLINGTON, Little Rock, Ark., President
 of the Little Rock Political Equality League.
"MRS. CHESTER JENNNGS, Little Rock, Ark., President
 of the Little Rock Political Equality League.
 "MRS. HELEN RAND TINDALL, Washington, D. C.
 "MRS. MARY F. McLENDON, Atlanta, Ga., President of
 the Georgia Equal Suffrage Association.
 "MRS. DESHA BRECKENRIDGE, Lexington, Ky., Presi-
, dent of the Kentucky Equal Rights Association.
 "MISS LAURA CLAY.. Lexington, Ky., Secretry of the Ken-
tucky Equal Rights Association.
"MRS.  SARAH CLAY BENNETT, Richmond, Ky.f "MRS. MARY B. CLAY, Richmond, Ky.
 "MISS KATE M. GORDON, New Orleans, La., President
 of the Louisiana State Suffrage Association.
 "MISS FLORENCE LOEBER, New Orleans, La., Presi-
dent of the Era Club of New Orleans.
MRS. EMMA MADDOX FUNCK, Baltimore, Md., Presi-
 dent of the Maryland Woman Suffrage Association.
 "MRS. DONALD R. HOOKER, Baltimore, Md., President
 of the Just Government League.
 "MRS.   ANNIE   KINKEAD   DENT,   Yazoo   City,   Miss.,
 President of the Mississippi Woman  Suffrage Asso-
 ciation.
 "MRS. ROBERT  SOMERVILLE, Greenville,' Miss.
 "MRS. EUGENE REILLY, Charleston, S. C.
 "MRS.  ADELIA  C.   STEPHENS,  Oklahoma  City,  Okla.,
 President  of the   Oklahoma  Woman  Suffrage  Asso-
 ciation.
 "MRS. MARY WINTHROP GIBBON, Charleston, S. C.
 "MISS SARAH BARNWELL ELLIOTT, Sewanee, President of the Tennessee Suffrage Association.
 "MISS  M.  ELEANOR  BRACKENRIDGE,   San  Antonio,
 President of the Texas Equal Franchise Society.
 "MRS. B. B. VALENTINE, Richmond, Va., President of
 the Equal Suffrage League of Virginia.
 "MRS. HELEN GARDINER, Washington, D. 


 It was hardly to be expected that the Governors would
 attend  this   conference,  but  it was  thrilling warning to
 backward legislatures that the hour has come when the
 women must come into their own.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/279</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>