<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 02 f</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 02 f. Newspaper clipping: 'Women Study How To Vote. Ossoli Circle Hears Address This Afternoon by Judge R.P. Williams.'  Knoxville Journal &amp; Tribune.  April 21, 1919.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Scrapbooks; Clippings; Voting; Women's suffrage; Organizations;</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Knoxville Journal &amp; Tribune</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Knoxville Journal &amp; Tribune</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>April 21, 1919</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 02</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>WOMEN STUDY HOW TO VOTE                                                                                                                                                Ossoli  Circle Hears Address
This Afternoon by Judge
R. P. Williams
PROPHETIC TOPIC
Municipal and State Government and Suggested Improvements Discussed
Ossoli Circle devoted its session
Monday afternoon to the timely con-
ideration of "Our Local Government"" Mrs, L. Crozier French, chairman of the political science department which arranged the program,
termed the selection of this subject,
"almost prophetic" since the topic
was chosen several months ago and
is now so appropriate in view of the
recent enfranchisement of women
of Tennessee in municipal and presidential elections.
"The County System of Tennessee," was discussed by Mrs. Lewis
Tillman with special reference to
the administration of the county government.
Miss Leah Fletcher led the general discussion on "Suggested Improvements." Needed  changes in county
 government   were   subjects   of   brief
 talks by various members of the circle.
Recorder Williams'  Address
Recorder  Williams   in   his  address
on   "Machinery  of Voting" ' said    in
 part:
"Madame   chairman   and   ladies:   I
 know of no higher honor that could
I be conferred upon a man than to ad-
dress this organization.  It being the
oldest  in   the   city  and   composed   of
 women who believe in   doing things.
 I  am not a  new  convert  to  woman
suffrage. I have believed in it many
 years and declared for it in a school
address     at     Fountain      City     High
school.   Why?   Because   I   believe in
women. If you will pardon me I will
 prove to you that the women of this
country  and the   world  have  always
been faithful  to  every  trust.  Let us
go  back  to  when   our     Savior     was i
crucified. What does the Bible teach 
us. That all of the men deserted and a woman  followed him to the cross.
Who was it first met Him when He 
arose from the grave? It was a woman.
Who  was   it  that  has   been  the 
stand  by  of the  church  and  schools
of   this   country   and   watched   after
the interest of the children while the
men   were   chasing   the   rainbow   of
fame or the almighty dollar? It was
the women.  Who was  the  (missing)
of   the   greatest  organization (missing)
world outside of the  Church.  (missing).
duties. The last legislature made it
a misdeameanor or fine for a person appointed to hold an election
not to serve without good cause.
"They  appoint  an   officer  of election,   three   judges,   two   clerks,   two
registrars and one marker. The polls
in  the  cities  open  at  9  o'clock  and
close  at  7  p. m., in  the county district at 9 o'clock and close at 4 p. m.
How To Vote
"Ladies, you no doubt would be surprised   when   I   tell  you   that   in   every
ward  in  the  city of  Knoxville at  each
election   there   are   ballots   not   counted
 simply  because  the man   who cast the
I ballot   did   not  know  how  to  mark  his
ticket.    The law requires he shall place
an X or cross mark opposite the name he
desires to vote for and instead of doing
that he scratched out the name of the
man he did not want to vote for.    The
law further requires you must pay your
poll tax thirty days before, the election. This tax for elections held in 1919 would 
 be the poll tax for the year 1918. There
ihas been a question raised that the la-
dies will not have to pay poll taxes to
 vote in 1919 as they were not assessed.
 This is a question of law that should De
looked  into,   in  fact  it  is  such  an im-
portant  question   in  my  opinion  a  test
case   should   be   brought   and   tested   in
supreme   court before our next  city elec- 
tion.   I know able attorneys have stated
you  are not liable for the poll tax  because you were not assessed.    There are
hundreds of voters in the city of Knoxville  who  are not assesed  by  the  tax
assessor on January 10, as the law requires,  their names are not on the  tax
books, but they desire to vote and they
go to  the trustee's office more than a
year after the assessment is made and
pay their two dollars.    This is placed on
the   pick-up   list   as   the   name   of   Mrs.
George   Templeton   was   placed   a   few
days ago.    On election day you will get
registration   certificates   and   your   poll
tax  receipt  and  go   to   the  polls.     You
will first go to  one  of the registrars  and
present  your  credentials.    He will give
you   your   ballot.   Then   you   will   hand
your   registration   certificate   and   your
ballot to what is known as the marker.
He  will  take both  and  place  the same
number, say 22, on both certificate and,
ballot.    This is done to keep any ballots
being voted from the outside or marked
by some one else than the voter. After
I this you will then go in the booth and
make a cross mark after the names of
each person you desire to vote for. Then
you will go to the officer of election, give
him your ballot, registration certificate
and  poll  tax receipt.    He  will call  out
your name and it will be checked on the
registration book by the registrars and
officer   will   say  voted  and  place  your
ballot in the box.
"At 7 o'clock the officer of election
will announce the polls are closed and
no one is allowed to vote after that
hour. The officer then opens the ballot
box and from the ballots he calls each
name that has a cross mark opposite
the name. The two clerks on the talley
sheet record the votes, making a
straight mark for each vote including
No. 4 and the fifth vote received by a
candidate the clerk makes a slanting
mark across the four and says talley:
each clerk must have the same record
and this is kept up until all of the votes
are counted and the officer, judges and 
clerks sign the returns from their respective precincts and took by them to the
county election commission who meet at
the courthouse in each county and can-
vass the returns and make their reports on the results. If city officers are
to be elected, they report to tne city
commission, state officers to the state
election commission and secretary of
state. The judge's duty is to watch the
ballots and to pass upon all disputes, If
a man has made false statement or has
moved and his vote has been challenged
by some voter or citizen, then it is the
duty of the judge to pass upon the question if he is a legal voter.
Must  Pay   Poll  Tax
"All persons twenty-one years of age
on   January  10,  the year  preceding  tne
e.iection, up to fifty [years] of age, must
pay poll  tax.    To (missing)
tion in September (missing)</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/163</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>