<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 46 f</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 46 f. Newspaper clipping: "We have heard all the candidates..." (fragment).</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Political elections;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>Unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF; 400 dpi</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook p. 46</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>"We have heard all the candidates-
and next Wednesday Senator E. E. Pat-
ton will discuss the school situation from
every angle and each candidate is asked
to come to hear Senator Patton. Possibly no one in Knox county knows really
more about the city and county schools
than he. The Non-Partisan league has
concentrated on the school as the largest
issue in the coming election. Certainly
nothing could he more important, and
we really desire the candidates to familiarize themselves on the school subject.    It will be worth much to them.
"We have discussed equalization of
taxes. We need more money for our
schools. We ought to pay our teachers more and only through an equalization of taxes could this millenium
exist. We need police protection&#8212;if the
force isn't large enough to cover and
protect Knoxville&#8212;then let's stretch a
point and enlarge it.
"We want our city to be an all-around
beautiful one&#8212;materially and spiritually.
Constructive work has been done&#8212;we
have splendid streets and school buildings. The Non-Partisan league has studied in a general and comparative way
the principles of municipal frovernment
in other cities&#8212;giving special consideration to certain principles that may be
advantageously applied to our own city
affairs.
"The sentiment of this organization is
in no sense partisan, and will take no
part in the nomination of candidates. It
is the aim of the league to give such information as will enable individual mem-
bers to thoroughly understand the necessary qualifications for a candidate for
any municipal office.
"The Non-Partisan Political league intends neither to recommend nor condemn any man or woman who may be
seeking an office; but, we expect the
members of the league to be able to
make decisions more intelligently be-
cause of the study inaugurated by the
policy of the league.'</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/591</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>