<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 49 b</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 49 b. Newspaper clipping: Last Rush Of Voters/</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Voter registration; Voting;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>Unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook p. 49</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>LAST RUSH
OF VOTERS
Four Thousand Five Hundred
Make Ready for Primary.
TOTAL OF 2,595 WOMEN
SECURE CERTIFICATES
New   Record   Set   During  Three-Day
Supplemental   Registration &#8212; Colored   Women   Registered   Number   644&#8212;1,951   White
Women.
At the close of the three day's supplemental registration on account of the city primary election of June 10, it was 
found that all records of a supplemental
had been smashed. The rush of voters,
both men and women, continued until the
limitation of the law closed the books.
The total registration reported to The
Times by the officials of the registration
was 4,318. The Tenth ward registrars
were too tired or something. They failed
to make a report again, as they did on
Tuesday night. From an outside authority it was learned that the total registration in that ward was 225, which runs
the aggregate in all wards and precincts
and of all races and sexes to  4,543.
It is impossible to separate the Tenth
ward registration into sexes or races, but
the remainder of the city was very obligingly turned in by the registrars in detail, notwithstanding they all had a
strenuous day, with the heaviest work
during  the closing  hours.
Excluding the Tenth ward, the figures
of  the  registration   may   be analyzed:
The final day's registration brought in
1.042 white women and 457 negro
women. White men registered numbered
589 and negro men 300. The final day's
registration   is   shown   in   the   following table:
Last   Day. (Lists White &amp; Colored Males &amp; Females by Wards).
Totals     589      1,042       300      457
In the total registration for the three
days it develops that 1,240 white women
qualified as legal voters under the new
suffrage law and 644 negro women. The
total female vote, therefore, that has
qualified   by   registration   is   2.595.
Following table sets out the registration by precints in detail.
(Lists White &amp; Colored Males &amp; Females by Wards).  Total 1240  1951  483  655    Totals Three Days (by wards and precincts)...Total  4, 318</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/534</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>