<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 09 d</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 09 d. Newspaper clipping: 'MRS. FRENCH SPEAKS TO NATIONAL SUFFRAGISTS--Knoxville Woman to be Leading Parliamentarian of Coming Convention.'</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Suffrage; Meetings;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 09</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>MRS. FRENCH SPEAKS TO
NATIONAL SUFFRAGISTS
Knoxville Woman to be Leading   Parliamentarian    of
Coming Convention.
HONOR    STATE   RESIDENT
Recognized by Board, Which
Also Approves Nashville as
Meeting Place.
Mrs. L. Crozier French is assigned a
place as leading parliamentarian on the
program of the National Suffrage association convention. Mrs. French is
recognized as a leading parliamentarian
in this state and has a wide knowledge
of parliamentary law.
As president of the State Suffrage
association Mrs. French is on the program for the national convention, to be
held in Nashville in November. She
will deliver a welcome address.
Mrs. French, it will be remembered,
elected president of the state association at a called meeting of the executive board held a few months ago. Up-
was elected president of state association
Miss Sarah Barnwell Elliott, the vice-
president, Mrs. McCormack, of Memphis, called a meeting of the executive
board for the purpose of deciding the
city in Tennessee in which to hold the
national convention, and also for the
purpose of electing a new state president. Mrs. French was chosen president, and Nashville was selected as the
place of meeting. This action has
unanimously acknowledged and confirmed by the executive board of the
National Suffrage association, according to recent announcement. National
leaders have been consulting with Mrs.
French in regard to the coming national convention, which promises to
be a noteworthy event. Such women
as Dr. Anna Shaw and Miss Jane Ad-
dams are in the national board.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/307</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>