<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook,p. 31c</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 31 . Newspaper clipping: An Open Letter To Dr. Ayres, President of the University of Tennessee. By L. Crozier French.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's suffrage; Women's rights;</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>L. Crozier French</dc:creator>
<dc:date>Unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>AM OPEN LETTER
To Dr. Ayres, President of the
University of Tennessee.
Dear  Sir:&#8212;The   press reports you   as
having delivered an address at Memphis
to the graduates of the public schools
and quotes the two sentences which follow:&#8212;
"Woman's suffrage tends to destroy
the home and with it the sweetness of
human life."
"All this business of women pushing
themselves into the sual avocations
followed by men is destructive to the
homes "
A formal public utterance by one occupying a high position naturally attracts
attention and is calculated to have much
influence.
No greater problems for solution have
ever come to any nation than the two
subjects touched upon by you in the
sentences quoted above: those of the
suffrage, and industrialism.
Every human being, man, woman and
child, is vitally interested and should be
impartially considered in the study of
the problem.&#8212;
1.&#8212;How are the people to sustain
life?
2.&#8212;How   are   the   people   to   be   gov- 
erned ?
In   the   eyes  of  many   there  are   few 
higher positions than that of  the  presi- 
dent  of a   university;   than  that  of   the
man who stands at the head of the edu-
cational system, of a common wealth.
To reach such a position a man is supposed   to  be  versed  in   the  fundamental
principles which underlie ail great ques-
tions of general interest and to have such
depth and breadth of mind as to be able
to  interpret   them  without   prejudice  or
partiality.     Such   a   man   will   make   a
statement of facts only when he has the
 fullest knowledge  of the  truth of  them.
   The   first   day  of   January   there   was
 organized   in   Knoxville   an   Equal   Suff-
rage League the object of which is: "to
 advance the educational, industrial, legal
 and   political   rights   of   women   and   to
 secure  suffrage  to  them  by  appropriate
 state and national legislation.
     The  membership is composed  of men
and women, about forty in number.    The
object is not selfish nor is there any desire to assert one sex against the other.
Our belief is that the infranchisement of
women   will  contribute  as  much   to   the
betterment  of   men   and   children   as   to
the  women   and  that the  home  will  be
made a better,  purer,  happier place for
the family and that the influence of this
 better family  life will  radiate and  help
 to clear that "dirty pool of politics" one
hears  spoken of so often.     Do you  ask
upon what  the  opinion   is   based?     The
reply is upon principles and upon facts.
As to the principle I refer you  to Benjamin   Franklin:&#8212;"They   who   have   no
voice nor vote in the  electing  of representatives do  not enjoy liberty,  but are
absolutely   enslaved   to   those   who have
votes and to their representatives for to
be enslaved is  to have governors  whom
other met)  have set over us and  to   be
subject to laws made by the representatives of others without having had representatives of our own to give consent
in our behalf."
Those who are slaves can never develop into as great characters as those
who are free, hence all children, both
girls and boys, would be benefited if
their mothers were free and independent
both financially and politically.
The fact plain to all who read history
and study human conditions that laws
and customs favorable to women are
the last to be changed as civilization advances because women do not look after
these matters themselves. Some have
been too poor, weak and ignorant to demand improved conditions, while others
have been basking in the lap of luxury
protected and cared for by male relatives
and have been heedless and indifferent to
any higher life.
In conclusion, will you consent to give
a public address in Knoxville setting
forth more fully your views concerning
the advisability of demanding the financial dependence of women upon men and
the continuance of woman's political
slavery.
Waiting your  reply,   I   remain.
Your humble servant,
L.  CROZIER  FRENCH.
President Equal Suffrage League.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/453</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>