<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 50 a</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 50 a. Newspaper clipping: WOMEN MUST STAND TOGETHER TO BRING ABOUT IDEAL GOVERNMENT, MRS. KENNY DECLARES.  Knoxville Journal.  May 18, 1923.  Includes photographs of Mrs. Jno.M. Kenny, Mrs. W.L. Morris, and Mrs. Leslie M. Kennedy.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women;</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Knoxville Journal</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>May 18, 1923</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook p. 50</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>WOMEN MUST STAND TOGETHER TO BRING ABOUT
IDEAL GOVERNMENT, MRS. KENNY DECLARES
President Of State League
Gives Principles For Which
Group Should Work.
The things that women will be
able to accomplish through organization, and the need for their par-
ticipation in politics were presented
to Knoxville women yesterday in
two stirring addresses by Mrs. John
M. Kenny, president of the Tennessee League of Women Voters.
Mrs. Kenny has been an ardent
worker for equal suffrage for sev-
eral years and based her message
on her own personal experiences
through this period and her careful
study of present political situations
in the nation, in the state and in the
municipalities.
Mrs. Kenny's first address was
made at the luncheon tendered In
her honor at noon at the Y. W. C.-
A. by the League of Women Voters
and which was attended by both
men and women. Later she addressed a large number of women
at the Lyceum building.
In her talk at the luncheon Mrs
Kenny confined herself to a discussion of the aims of the League of
Women Voters and the reason for
the existence of such an organization. This, Mrs. Kenny explained.
was primarily in order that women
might through standing shoulder to
shoulder, regardless of party organization, be able to procure recognition and bring about through their
exercise of suffrage the many things
that as women they saw and felt
the need of.
"We believe in party organization," said Mrs. Kenny, "and sometime we shall return to our respective parties; but at the present we
must stand together as women for
women, and for the bringing about
of our ideals of clean government.
"I believe in the League of Women Voters as a safe and sane organization," said Mrs. Kenny. "Because men, both democrats and republicans, could not get together in
one organization like this, they have
been prone to think that we could
not, but we can.
The necessity, of a definite program was strongly stressed by Mrs.
Kenny as a condition precedent to
success of the League and to gain-
ing the privilege of being admitted
later to the councils of the principal
parties. This cannot be expected in
a decade after 300 years of political
slavery, and patience will be necessary, she said.
Mrs. Kenny outlined the four prin- 
cipal things for which the League
of Women Voters stands as being 
(1) Efficiency in government, and in
this connection she urged upon all
women the necessity of a careful
study of political questions and an
intelligent use of the "ballot.
The second thing for which the
League stands is legislation for women and children. Mrs. Kenny
referred to the recent fight for the
passage of the Sheppard-Towner bill
and declared that there would always be difficulty in the passing of
such bills until women were given
representation in the legislative
bodies of the state and nation.
Third, the League stands for representation on election boards. Mrs.
Kenny warmly commended Senator
Hill of Knox county for his support
of women for this position in event
the bill enlarging the number on
the election boards had passed the
last legislature.
The final principle of the League
as presented by Mrs. Kenny is "cooperation to prevent war." "Let us
start now," said Mrs. Kenny to interest women in the issues of coming national election. They must
be able to vote intelligently on the
international court of justice question which is going to be one of the
principal Issues."
Mrs. Kenny paused here to say
that the League of Women Voters
had endorsed the international court
of justice.
In closing Mrs. Kenny stated that
the ballot must become a part of
the daily life of every woman&#8212;bound
up with the care of the home, the
care of the children and all her other interests, for all of these things
were  directly  or indirectly affected by it.
IDA B. CHEATAM    When asked regarding the telegrams that had been released Mrs. Morrissaid that she had understood Mrs. Kenney to say that Mrs. Cheatam had wired her (Mrs. Morris) to the effect that she had nothing to do with the situation here, and that no such telegram had ever been received by her.  She said she had received the telegram regarding Miss Woolley, but that Mrs. Cheatam was laboring under a misapprehension in the matter, that never had the question of Miss Woolley's direction been brought up.
OFFICERS IN STATE
AND  LOCAL LEAGUE
OF WOMEN'S VOTERS
MRS. JNO. M. KENNY,
State President.
MRS. W. L. MORRIS,
Knox League. 
Preceding    Mrs.  Kenney (missing)
luncheon program were L.M.G.
Baker and Miss Mary B. Temple. 
Mr. Baker discussed briefly the 
great need f6r honest elections and 
the methods that were used to pre-
vent their being held. "The square 
deal should apply in politics as well
as in everything else," said the 
speaker, "and if women will join 
with the men who desire clean poli- 
tics, the time is not far distant
when such a condition as we hope
for will obtain." Mr. Baker decried 
the control of election machinery 
which is so often sought as a means
of election by candidates and stated 
that regardless of party every good 
citizen should stand for honesty in
elections. 
Miss Temple, in a brief talk expressed the thought that women are
giving too much time to clubs, and
have too great a variety of interests. She should combine these ac-
tivities and unite only on those
things looking to the betterment of
humanity. The two best ways in
which she can do this, said Miss
Temple, are first, the bettering in
practical ways of health conditions,
educational conditions and improvement of the ballot; and second, in
being loyal in all relations of life
and in fair dealing with one's fel-
lowman.
In closing her talk Miss Temple
ipreesnted Mrs. Kenny with a corsage
of roses, and paid a tribute to her
for her splendid work in behalf of
women.
Mrs. R. L. Cunningham who acted as toastmistress called for a talk
from Mrs. L. Crozler French, pioneer woman suffragist, but the latter declined to make a speech, taking time only to thank Mrs. Kenny and Mrs. Cunningham for the praise
which she had been accorded for her
long service in behalf of woman suffrage.
Women Of City Hear Campaign Methods Used In
Nashville's Election.
The importance of woman's part
in matter of government, with particular reference to municipal affairs
was discussed by Mrs. John M. Kenny, president of Tennessee League
of Women Voters, in her address at
the Lyceum, building yesterday af- 
ternoon.
Mrs. Kenny urged especially the
organization of the women of Knoxville and Knox county as the first
step in bringing about the things
for which as individuals they stand.
MRS. LESLIE M. KENNEDY,
Knox League
There can be no strength without
organization and program, said the
speaker.
Much of Mrs. Kenny's talk had to
do with the work of the Nashville
League in the recent city election
and contained many suggestions for
the benefit of local women in view
of the approaching municipal elec-
tion in this city.
"Women must be made to see their
opportunity for service in situations
like this, and that they can make
their city just what they want it
to be. If you have high ideals and
work for them, you will certainly
realize them. But, let me tell you,
said Mrs. Kenny, "that eternal vigilance will be the price you will have
to pay. You must be always and
eternally  on  the  job!"
"The recent election in Nashville
did not go to suit the League of
Women Voters, but we made our influence felt as it had been felt before, and clearly outlined our stand
for   clean   government."
House to house canvasses were
made in organizing the women of
that city, and at every voting place
on election day women worked at
the polls, having at hand a card index showing the registration and poll
tax lists of all wards, and seeing
that everything was done in accordance with the law. "Some of our
most prominent women worked from
early morning until after the polls
had closed and the returns had been
made in certain wards, and the re-
sults when compared with those of
former elections showed that their
labors had been most worthwhile."
"You know women work for ideals, 
and men work for jobs," said  Mrs.
Kenny smiling,   "and with this  un-
selfishness in our labor we are sure
to accomplish good."'
Mas. Kenny feels that women
should have representation on all
boards or commissions of the city
which involve dealing with women
and children. She told of the splendid work that has been accomplished
in Nashville by the municipal hospital commission since the placing
of women thereon, and of the work-
ings of the Women's Protective Bureau of that city which was established a few years ago.
Mrs. Kenny also made the point
that only the most qualified women
should be backed for positions of
any kind, but that women should
take advantage of every opportunity to have representation where it
could be given.
Another thing Mrs. Kenny urged
was the strict observance of laws.
"The so-called foolish acts of the
flapper do not concern me half so
much as the careless observance of
certain of  the laws  that are  upon
our statute books. Whether we approve a law or not we sould
respect it as long as it remains a law."
</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/539</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>