<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 02 b</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 02 b. Newspaper clipping: 'Co-Operate Instead of Criticizing Commission'.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 02</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>CO-OPERATE, INSTEAD OF
CRITICIZING COMMISSION

"I have met many women who
criticise the city and the commissioners, but I have met few people who
are willing to spend the time bettering these conditions," stated Mrs. L.
Crozier French, at the weekly meeting of the good citizenship class,
which is held at the Lawson-McGhee
library every   Thursday  afternoon.
Mrs.   French   stated   that    women
had sufficient time to study the gov-
ernment, constitution and laws, and:
should put some thought on them es-
pecially since they have been granted
the franchise.
Mrs. French is opposed to the recall movement, because the citizens
were the ones who put the present
commission in office.
She advocates the mayor being
made the financial agent of the city.
She does not believe the present commissioner of finance is incapable,
but the office should be occupied by
the mayor.
She states the present commission
came into office when the city government was nearly bankrupt, and
could not be expected to immediately
put it on a sound basis.
This organization meets every
Thursday afternoon. The first meeting day of the month it discusses the
United States constitution,, the second Thursday of the month it studies
the laws of Tennessee, and the third
and fourth Thursdays are used in
studying the city government. It is
hoped that many women will take
the  opportunity  of    learning    some
helpful facts concerning the government, by attending the meetings.
</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/159</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>