<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 30 a.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 30 a. Newspaper clipping: Legal Status of Women in Tennessee and The Present Legislature.  L. Crozier French. Knoxville Journal &amp; Tribune.  January 12, 1913.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Women's rights;</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>L. Crozier French</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Knoxville Journal &amp; Tribune</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>January 12, 1913</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 30</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>
Legal Status of Women in Tennessee  and The Present Legislature
   Since Ossoli circle in 1909 passed a
resolution asking the Tennessee Federation of Women's club to make a thorough investigation of the legal status of
Tennessee women, an agitation has been
almost continually going on, until now
the meekest women in the state no
longer say they have all the rights they
want, but acknowledge they would like
to control their own property and have
some share in the guardianship of their
children.
The present legislature in one respect
will be unique, for if all plans are carried out, for the first time in the history
of the state members of the legislature
will realize that the people of the state
are interested in having laws made for 
the bettering of the condition of mothers
and wives.
The  statutes  of  Tennessee  on  record
at present appear to be primarily to protect men, especially husbands.   The man
who marries a rich woman is perfectly
secured in his rights to her wealth, and
there is no adequate punishment for him
if he fails to provide for wife and children.    He can squander all on dissolute
companions   and go entirely unpunished
as far as  Tennessee law  is concerned.
Some Bills to be Presented.
The Federation of Women's clubs and the bar
association will  see that a  bill
is  presented  asking for the  removal   of
the   coverture   of   the   old   English   common
 law   from   married   women.     This
would  allow  the married  woman   to  re-
tain full control of her property.     It is
 possible a  bill may be presented  asking 
 that   mothers  be  made   joint   guardians
 with fathers of their children.
Pensions for Mothers.
G.   H.   Robertson,   president   of
the Tennessee   branch  of   the   Mothers' congress, 
will have presented a bill asking
for a small pension for mothers who
have   small   children   and   no   means  of
support. Several states have passed such 
bills believing it will cost much  less  to 
enable the mother to stay at home and 
take  care  of  the  children   than  for  her
to work out of her home while the chil- 
dren   run   on   the   street   and   get   their
training for the penitentiary.
Kindergarten Bill.
The   Mothers'   congress   also   have   a
bill to be presented asking that the kindergarten be made a part of the schools
of the stare.
Women on School Boards.
Another   bill   this   legislature   will   be
asked   to   pass   is   one   making   women 
eligible to school boards.
Not until 1907 was the law passed
that members of county boards of education,  "'must be qualified  voters."
I have made diligent inquiry as to
why such a stricture was put upon the
women of Tennessee, when other states
were giving their daughters such positions and even more important ones.
I was told this was done to please the
professional politicians, because they regard
boards of education as among their
best political assets and they would not
find it quite so easy to manipulate
women members of the boards. So our
schools must suffer to please the politician who has been preying upon poor
Tennessee- so successfully for so long a
time. We should have a law making it
obligatory to have two members of every
board of education in  the state  women.
Votes for Women.
The   best   lawyers   in   the   state   have
been   consulted   and   they    express   the
opinion that no constitutional amendment
is   necessary   to   give   the   vote   to   the
women of Tennessee, but that the legislature   has   full   power     to   extend   the
right of suffrage  as there  is nothing in the
constitution    forbidding   it.      It    is
likely,   therefore,   that  such   a   bill   will
be brought before the present legislature.
Many of the leading men of Tennessee
are  for   the   enfranchisement  of  women
and   it would  not  surprise some  people
if this legislature were to pass a bill to
that   effect.     All   intelligent     men   and
women   concede   that     the     victory   for
equal suffrage has been won and it only
remains for the remaining states to make
formal  surrender.     Why should Tennessee
 wait  to come in to line at the end,
 when it will no longer be respectable to
carry arms against the cause of women.
L.  CROZIER FRENCH.
	</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/447</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>