<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 23 f.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 23 f. Newspaper clipping: The Future of Woman Suffrage.  Mentions re-election of President Wilson (1916).</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's suffrage;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>[1916]</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 23</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>The Future of Woman
Suffrage
The result of the recent election will
be taken as positively settling for the
time being at least one of the questions
relating to woman suffrage. The platforms adopted by the two parties at the
opening of the campaign were similar in
sentiment if not in language. But the
republican nominee went much further
than his democratic competitor.
Judge Hughes came out in his campaign for an amendment to the national
constitution. President Wilson when the
question of woman suffrage was up before the voters of his state went from
Washington to his home and voted for
woman suffrage; but he is known to have
opposed an amendment to the national
constitution in favor of woman suffrage preferring that the matter be left
to settlement by the states.
The   re-election   of   President   Wilson
'"will be taken as an endorsement of his
position   and   whatever  effort   is  to   be
made in the next four years will have to 
be  made  in  the  states  themselves  and 
not   in   the   general   government.     This
would seem to render useless one of the
well known  organizations of  women to
advance  the  cause of  woman  suffrage,
that known as the Congressional Union.
The purpose of the Congressional Union
is that of bringing to bear influence on
members of the national congress looking
to the adoption of an amendment to the
national constitution.
As already suggested the election of
Wilson committed to the doctrine of
states rights in the matter as he is, and
the defeat of Hughes who was avowedly
in favor of amending the national constitution settles the question for four
years leaving it to the states as it has
been here before.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/411</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>