<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 37e</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 37 e. Newspaper clipping: Universal Suffrage. (Mortimer Thompson).</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women;</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>(Mortimer Thompson)</dc:creator>
<dc:date>Unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook p. 37</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>UNIVERSAL SUFFRAGE
(Mortimer  Thompson.)
I  believe  in  democracy,  in  its  generic
sense,  democracy in  politics,  in religion,
in  economics  and in the family.
I believe democracy is no experiment to be tried but an evolution to be fulfilled.
I have   no   confidence in any institution among human beings that is not cornerstoned in the consent of those human beings.
Universal suffrage is necessary to that consent.   
Sooner or later women's suffrage must be established.  It is one of the stages in the evolution of democracy
and when one considers the great economic revolution of the last fifty years it seems strange that it is not already established.
Decent men no longer regard women as either serfs or idiots. Then why should they longer
permit their statute books to insult their
mothers, wives and daughters with the
implication? That honorable self-re-
specting women are indignant and sometimes break windows is
not surprising.
Heads have   been   browen(sic.)  with   far  less provocation.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/488</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>