<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 52 a</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 52 a. Newspaper clipping: "Woman's Rights" In Texas.  F.M. Brantley, Fort Worth, Texas. New York Times.  February 10, 1924.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's rights;</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>F.M. Brantley</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>New York Times</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>February 10, 1924</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook p. 52</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>"WOMAN'S RIGHTS" IN TEXAS
New York Times:
To the Editor of The New York Times:      	
It appears that in a communication in
the Sunday issue of The New York
Times of some days back, Ethel M.
Smith, in writing of the proposed equal
rights amendment to the Federal Constitution, mentions that the State of
Texas denies to a married woman the
control of her own earnings; while in
a subsequent issue of The Times of
Jan. 22, it appears that Paul Caruthers Morris  of  your  city,   in  a   communica-
tion, says Miss Smith is in error in the above statement as to the laws of the State of Texas, and kindly takes her to task with the suggestion that her sisters should look up her charges before taking them seriously.  And in that connection he essays to set her aright with the further statement, as the truth of the matter, that Texas, along with certain other States named by him, is a community property State, and that under the laws of that State the wife's earnings belong in half to her husband, and cites in support of his statement a Law Directory published in your city.
As an old practioner down in this far-off State, I beg to submit to Mr. Morris that he in turn is in error, due possibly to his like failure to "look up the law" further on the point--though he seems to be only half right as to the same.  Yes, Texas is, and from the beginning may be classed as a community property State, but of late years it has become something more is response to the demands of modern woman for her "rights," and though somewhat cumbrous in dimensions has "got a move" on her in response to such demands; as under recent enactments of it Legistatures,
which have "finally
"seen the light," all of the earnings of
the wife belong to her, is subject to her
exclusive control, and to do with as she
pleases. She is also given like control
of all her other separate property and 
to dispose of as may suit her whim and 
without any interference on the part of
her husband; save that the joinder of
her husband is necessary in a convey-
ance or encumbrance by her of her real estate; and in the latter instance if her spouse balks she may go to court and procure such conveyance without his joinder therein, (See Acts of Texas Legislature of 1917, p. 436, and of 1921, p. 251).
Moreover, while the wife by these en-
actments has absolute control over her
earnings,  to  cast them  at the birds, or
to  the  milliners,  as  suits  her whim,  a subservient Legislature, by further enactment, has provided that in the event of the failure or refusal of the husband
to  provide  for  the  proper support  and
maintenance of the wife, or if he "runs
away"   to   avoid   the   discharge   of   the duty, he
may  be brought  back and be put in jail or be put to penal servitude until he signifies a willingness to discharge his marital duty.
Hence,   it  may  be  a little  difficult to
conceive   what   further   rights   the   for-
ward looking women of the Lone Star
State may crave, unless possibly the prerogative of possessing more than one
husband at one and the same time, and
with   the   privilege   of   driving   them   in
tandem   or   in   pairs   as   may suit their pleasure.
F.M. BRANTLEY     Fort Worth, Texas, Jan. 29, 1924.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/542</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>