<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 38 b</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 38 b. Newspaper clipping:  In The Interest Of Votes For Women. S.H.H.  Knoxville Journal Tribune.  February 11, 1915.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's suffrage;</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>S.H.H.</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Knoxville Journal Tribune</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>February 11, 1915</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook p. 38</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>IN THE INTEREST OF VOTES FOR WOMEN
KNOXVILLE POLITICAL EQUALITY  LEAGUE.
Committee&#8212;Mrs. Edw. Gillenwaters, Mrs. Henry Kelso, Mrs. David Meriwether, Jr.
Mrs.  Sarah Hood.

Rooks Suffrage Bill. 
For the last three weeks the attention 
of the Tennessee suffragists of all creeds
and classes has been focussed upon the
state capitol where, amid dramatic 
scenes and accessories, the so-called 
Rooks' Suffrage Bill has played a con- 
spicuous part.
This bill&#8212;which by the way, is "mo-
thered" by the Tennessee Suffrage asso-
ciation. Inc., whose president is Mrs.
Gilfred Dudley, of Nashville, was passed
without much protest or palaver in the
house of representatives by vote of
fifty-nine to twenty-five.  Hopes were
high that the senate would take the same favorable action. But alas, no! It seems that some of the senators were false to their party platforms and promises and fomented a conspiracy which 
resulted in the defeat of the measure  in spite of the eloquent advocacy of 
Senators Houk,  Ogle and others. 

However, the bill is "not dead yet"
 by any means, for at the last moment it was snatched from total defeat by a motion to reconsider, and, in consequence, 
 it will be called up for a second
hearing as soon  as the   legislature convenes again after the recess.
This  delay will not only give    the
suffragists time to strengthen their 
forces, but will afford the opponents the 
chance in remember their forgotten 
pledges and to retrieve their error by
joining in the movement to place the old
Volunteer State in the front ranks of
progress.
While it is generally conceded that the most logical and expedient way to secure the enfranchisement of women is by federal amendment, yet nothing would give the women of Tennessee such genuine gratification as to receive the ballot from the hands of their own men.  
Therefore, it is hoped that not a single
senator will   fail
in   his   duty   to   his
family,   his   state, his party, 
and    his
country when the day comes to vote on
the Rooks' Suffrage Bill.   S.H.H.
</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/492</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>