<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 37a</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 37 a. Newspaper clipping: Mock Session Of The Legislature Is Very Amusing.  News Sentinel.  March 27, 1914.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's suffrage;</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Knoxville News Sentinel</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>March 27, 1914</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook p. 37</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>Mock Session Of The Legislature Is Very Amusing. 
Equal Suffragists and Parliamentary Law Class
Participate
MESSAGE IS READ
FROM "GOVERNOR"'
Many Bills Introduced Relative to the
Status of   Women   and    Several
Freak Measures-Mrs. French
Acts as Speaker                               

Both instructive and amusing was the
mock extra session of the Alabama legislature held yesterday afternoon at the
Cable hall with Mrs. L. Crozier French's
class in parliamentary law as the principals and the members of the Birming-
ham Equal   Suffrage   association   as   the
members.  A number of bills   were introduced that will 
be presented at the next
session   of   the   legislature  such   as  bills
relating to child labor, compulsory education, women on school boards, equal pay
for  equal  work,   co-guardianship of  children   and   others  of   like  nature,   all   of
which were ably presented and discussed
pro and con.   To "spice up" the meeting
several freak bills  were presented,  such
as   "a   bill   to   regulate    the    length, of 
trousers,"   "taxation   of   bachelors"   and 
"bill   to   regulate  the   dress   of  women." 
all  of which were very amusing.
Mrs. French acted as speaker and show-
ed much ability as a presiding officer,
both as to the general routine of legisla-
tive business and rulings on questions
of parliamentary law. The members di-
vided into two factions, the liberals with
 Mrs. Bossie O'Brien Hundley as leader
and the conservatives, led by Mrs. Myr-
telle W. Snell.  Miss Amelia Worthington was clerk, Mrs. Louise Owings Charl-
ton, page, and Mrs. Mae Kendel Hannum
as   messenger.
In  opening the session Mrs. French
 made an address on the status of women
 in the body politic of all states. She then
announced the several committees with
 the following chairmen: Judiciary, Mrs.
Laura Sharpe; education, Miss Florence
McCrossin; house, Mrs. Marilou Armstrong Cory; health, Miss Kate Eubank
Blackburn; industrial work, Mrs. Octavia
F. Frazier.  Among the first "business"
transacted was a motion to limit the
speeches to five minutes and to adjourn
at 5 o'clock; both of which carried. The
messenger introduced the governor's message as follows:
"Governor's" Message
"State of Alabama, Office of Governor.
"To the General Assembly: You have
assembled, in obedience to your conscience, to exercise your legislative power
for the honor and welfare of the people
of Alabama, including women and children.
"Keenly alive as you are to the far-
reaching importance of your great trust,
I now give you information of the state,
of the government, and acknowledge that
through your lofty purposes, we are about
to enter upon a better era of happiness.
"I regret that I cannot go into detail
as to the needs of our state in this mesasge, for the reason that I am very
busy at present, preparing my next speech in favor of the election of my worthy successor A.B. Homes.
"With this masterful effort completed,
I have to fulfil an important engagement
with Horace Wood, of the People's Journal, from whom I expect to gain many
points upon the question of better  state service.
"The Condition of the Treasury&#8212;From
a recent detailed financial statement, I
would recommend that the appropriations
committee make no appropriation for
school purposes, since there is only about
30 cents left in the treasury.
"Because of my unquestioned loyalty
to the cause of woman suffrage, I confidently hope that all other shortcomings
of his administration be overlooked.
"In closing, I would ask that of all the
legislation which has been urged from
this executive department, I wish to
stress most the stringent prohibition
laws, for which I have always so firmly
stood.
"R.   R.   REPEAL.  Governor."
    Freak Bills Introduced
Mrs. Nellie Kimbell Murdock introduced 
the child labor bill and made a vigorous
appeal for its passage.   Mrs. Pattie Ruff-
ner Jacobs offered a bill to regulate the
wearing of trousers,  among the requirements  pf   the   bill  were    that    trousers 
should be not less than six inches from 
the  floor or less than  six inches below
the   knee   with   pockets  on   the   outside.
The  discussion   that   followed  was   very
amusing and the bill was finally shelved.
Miss   Helen   Benners   presented   a   bill 
looking to the taxation of bachelors over
30 years  of  age,  providing  for   the levying  of   a  tax  of  50  per   cent  of   the   incomes of all bachelors, the funds derived
from this source to be applied to the sup- 
port of widows with dependent children. 
A substitute to include spinsters as bene- 
ficiaries  of the system  caused a heated
discussion   and  the  bill   was   lost
Other bills were offered by Mrs. Cory,
Mrs. W. L. Beasley, Mrs. Morris, Mrs. 
Dora Fell, Mrs. Lillian Roden Bowron,
Mrs. Octavia F. Frazieir, Mrs. Retta L.
Ullman, Mrs. Prentice Read and Judge
Hundley, who offered a "message from
Mars."</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/484</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>