<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 14 c.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 14 c. Newspaper clipping: Tribute Is Paid Ossoli's Leader.  Surprise Meeting Was Birthday Party for Mrs. Lucy Crozier French.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Birthdays; Organizations;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 14</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>TRIBUTE  IS PAID
OSSOLI'S LEADER
Surprise Meeting Was Birthday
Party For Mrs. Lucy
Crozier French
Ossoli circle's surprise program for
its regular meeting Monday afternoon,
was one of the most delightful of the
year. It was converted into a birthday
party in honor of the distinguished president, Mrs. L. Crozier French and as
such was enjoyed by nearly two hundred
prominent women of the city who had
been bidden to attend. 
The idea of this celebration originated
with Mrs;. Walter S. Nash, "who with
Mesdames W. C. Baker and William G.
Smythe were hostesses. Receiving with
them were Mrs. French and the officers
of Ossoli.  About two hundred guests
were present including only the mem-
-bers of the circle. The occasion proved
to be a veritable love feast, all were
seated in two large circles, the president
in the seat of honor.
Mrs. Smythe most graciously welcomed the guests with a short talk.
Birthday greetings and felicitations
were extended to Mrs. French by Mrs.
Nash. Mrs. French responded with a
few delightful remarks, expressing her
appreciation of the honor shown her.
After this the circle expressed their
greetings and congratulations and a social hour followed.
A birthday cake with lighted candles
was presented to the honor guest, the
number of lighted candles were the feature of a guessing contest, four ladies
guessing the correct number, and in
the cut for the prize, Mrs. Albert Sydney Birdsong won the prize, a blue-
back spelling book, was presented by
Mrs.   W.   C.   Baker.
Mrs. R. J. Yearwood was in charge
of the decorations, which were beautiful
and carried out the colors of Ossoli, lavender and white. The floral centerpiece
of the picture table was lavender iris
and white roses, and the silver candelabra burned lavender tapers.
Mrs. George F. Mellen and Mrs.
Charles T. Cates presided at the table
and served the ice and coffee,. Also assisting were Mesdames Inge Murphy,
Frank Fowler, Logan Reid, Archer
Bishop. Churchwell Mabry, and other
members   of   the   social   committee.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/327</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>