<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 17 d.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 17 d. Newspaper clipping: Off to Washington to See Suffrage Parade. [March 1913?]</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's suffrage; Parades &amp; processions;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>[March 1913?]</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 17</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>OFF TO WASHINGTON TO
SEE SUFFRAGE PARADE

And Incidentally to Witness the
Inaugural  Ceremonies.
After weeks of strenuous planning
and preparation the suffrage crusaders
are now encamped in Washington,
awaiting marching orders. Monday at 3
p.m.  sharp, rain or shine, a grand army
of women will, for the first time, pass
down the historic highway, hereto held
sacred to masculine demonstrations.
Everything that feminine ingenuity,
patience and skill can devise has been
done to render this pageant-procession
the medium of a powerful appeal to the
intelligence, and sympathy of the thousands of spectators who will witness it.
Each feature has been designed with an
eye single to the advancement of the
great cause it represents. From the
classic pantomime and tableaus to be
enacted on the spacious plaza of the
treasury by society favorites and famous artists, to strains of interpretative
music&#8212;to the last remnant of oppressed
working women, the pageant will portray, in a series of vivid, living pictures,
the long dramatic story of woman's
struggle for freedom and justice, and
foreshadow the ultimate victory that is
destined  to crown her heroic efforts.
The installation of a new president into the highest office of the land will,
of course, be one of the drawing cards
of inaugural week, but this quadrennial
ceremony, it is. generally conceded, will
be a mere matter of moonshine compared
to the rival attraction presented by this
first national suffrage parade. For the
last week the clans have been gathering
from all quarters of the country&#8212;car
loads of women of every rank and condition and many nationalities, and fresh
relays are rolling in with every incom-
ing  train.
Tennessee has caught the contagious
of nation-wide enthusiasm and is to be
well represented by delegations from
each division of the state, not the least
among them being the party of women
from Fast Tennessee, many of whom
will take active part, in this epoch-making event.
The following telegram has been received by Mrs. French from the grand
marshal of the suffrage parade to be held
in Washington March 3:
The Tennessee delegation in Washing-
ton parade, March 3rd, will form at
2 o'clock, p.m., on South Capitol street,
between C and D streets under the
Tennessee banner, between South and
Texas.
Parade headquarters 236 Delaware
avenue. Northeast.
MRS.  KYARD C. BURLESON,
Grand Marshal.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/387</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>