<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 02 h</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 02 h. Newspaper clipping: 'Machinery of Voting.' (fragment) Ca. 1919.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Scrapbooks; Clippings; Voting;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>ca. 1919</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 02</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>(missing)
he came from a mansion or a hovel.
He  was  her  boy.  It  is  she  and   she
alone that, stays with  him always.
"It, matters not whether her hopes
proved to be gold or alloy.
She  is  his  mother,   and  he  mother's boy."
Machinery of Voting
"But my subject is the  Machinery
of Voting:   Years ago the sheriff of
the   various   counties   held   the   elections. But  the law has  changed and
now in Tennesseee we have  what is
known as the state board of election
commissioners. These men are elect-
ed   by   the   members   of  the   legislature,   two from   the   majority   party
and one by the minority party. This
board   meets   in   Nashville   and   they
appoint   three   men   in   each   county
who are known as the county board
of elections. 
"Two are named from the majority
party and one from the minority
party. Elections are held in Tennessee every two years. In August the
year preceeding the election to be held the various county boards ap- 
point two men at each voting precinct to open the regislation books
for all qualified voters to register.
"These books remain open for ten
days. To be a qualified voter in Tennessee you must be twenty-one years
of age before the day of election. It
is the duty of every qualified voter
when the biennial registration is held
to go to his voting precinct and register. You give the registrars your
name and address, your age, how
long you have lived in Tennessee and
how long you have lived in the county and district, also what state you
were born.
To be a voted and entitled to a registration   certificate  you   must   be  a
resident   of  the   state  one  year  and
the   county   six  months   and  district
twenty days.  If you  fail   to  register
during the general registration of ten
days  there  is  a  second  chance.   The
law  provides   that  twenty  days  before   each   election   that   the   county
election commission    shall      appoint
registrars   to   keep   the   books   open
three days, and this is known as the
 supplementary registration.       If you
 move   from   one   house     to    another
on   the  street    you     must    register.
The   registrars   are   two   in   number,
one a democrat and the other republican.   They  issue   you   a   certificate
good   for  two  years     from     August,
1919,   providing  you  do    not    move.
They  also   place your  name   on   the |
registration   book    numerically    and
then they copy it on  the other book
in   aphabetical   form.     Should     you
lose   or   mislay  your   certificate   you
can   go   to   the   polls,   call   upon   the
register to give you your number and
your   name   being  on   the   book,   you
are entitled to vote.
"The next step is voting. The
county election commissioners' next
duty, ten davs before the election is
to appoint nine persons in each voting precinct to hold the election as
is named by law. All must take oath
of office  before  entering   upon   their (missing)
</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/165</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>