<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook,  p. 11 d</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 11 d. Newspaper clipping: Want Representation on School Boards.  Chattanooga Times.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; School board members;</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Chattanooga Times</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 11</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>WANT REPRESENTATION
ON SCHOOL BOARDS
Knoxville   Suffragists   Have   Started
the Movement In State.
Mrs. Margaret Carson, of Knoxville, is
at present in Chattanooga in the interest
of the series of lectures to be given by
Mrs. L. Crozier French, president of the
Tennessee Equal Suffrage association, on
parliamentary law and laws governing
women and children in this state. Mrs.
French will address the various clubs in
this city during the latter part of October or first of November.
According to Mrs. Carson, the people
of Knoxville are very much interested in
the convention of state suffragists which
will be held in that city late in October.
The suffragists of that city are planning
to entertain the delegates during the two
days session and a number of social features are included.
The suffragists of Knoxville have started a movement to allow a due proportion
of the women in this state to be made
a constituent part of all school boards,
both county and city. Resolutions have
been adopted to this effect and a committee appointed to push the matter.
When asked about the unpleasantness
said to exist in the ranks of the Chattanooga suffragists over the election of Mrs.
L. Crozier French to the office of state
president on the resignation of Miss
Sarah Barnwell Elliott, Mrs. Carson
called attention to a section of the bylaws which states that the executive committee may fill any vacancies occurring
in the interim of the annual meeting.
Mrs. French was elected at a meeting
of the committee when Mrs. McCormick.
of Memphis, who is vice-president of the
state association,  was presiding.
Chattanooga suffragists claimed that
Mis French's election was not in accord-
ance with parliamentary ruling and was
therefore illegal. The local members of
the cause have so far refused to recognize
Mrs. French as the state leader.
Mrs. Carson will leave Chattanooga
tonight for Athens, where she will confer
with a number of clubwomen regarding
the organization of a suffrage league.
Mrs. French will lecture on "Suffrage"
before the Browning circle at Athens at
an early date.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/318</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>