<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 05 h</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 05 h. Newspaper clipping: 'To Abate Smoke If Fuel Saved.'</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Smoke; Pollution;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 05</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>TO ABATE SMOKE
IF FUEL SAVED
Dads Favor It If Coal  Is
Saved.
Mrs. French's   Request For
Action Taken Under
Advisement.
Whether or not the city commission will pass an ordinance requiring factories in the city to equip
their standpipes with smoke consumers or their furnaces with smoke
abaters, in compliance with the request of Mrs. L. C. French, representing an Ossoli circle committee,
will depend on whether or not the
smoke eliminators will save fuel for
the companies.
  N.  B.  Kuhlman.   commissioner  of
public  safety,  announced  he  would
not vote on such an ordinance unless a saving was instituted by the
consumers. It is understood tha[t]
the other members of the commission agree with Commissioner Kuhlman on this point.
Mrs. French, in addressing her request to the commission, stated the
abaters would save fuel. The commission will send to other cities
where smoke ordinances are in effect
to secure copies of the measures and
information regarding the efficiency
of such a law.
If the plan is found feasible, it is
expected  the  commission  will   pass
such an ordinance.   A mass meeting
of women will be held today in the
Woman's building, under the auspices of the Constituional league, to
discuss the smoke question from all
angles and a further appeal may be
made to the commission. It will
probably be several weeks before
the commission acts on the project.
</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/190</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>