<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook,  p. 13 c</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 13 c. Newspaper clipping: Chattanooga's "Hot Dog" Quartette That Took First Prize At Toronto Convention And Entertained Banqueters Last Night.  Also, Mrs. French Tells Lady Kiwanians of New Field. [Knoxville] Sentinel.  August 25, 1922.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Organizations; Clubs;</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>[Knoxville] Sentinel</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>August 25, 1922</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 13</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>
CHATTANOOGA'S "HOT DOG" QUARTETTE
TOOK FIRST PRIZE AT TORONTO CONVENTION
AND ENTERTAINED
 BANQUETERS LAST NIGHT

MRS. FRENCH TELLS LADY
KWANIANS OF NEW FIELD
Addressing Luncheon to Visiting   "Squaws"    Tells    Them
Right to Vote Has Given  Them    More    Strength    and
Power&#8212;Mrs. C. C. Rutherford Presides.
Telling the women present, that the
right to vote has given them more
strength and power than has ever
before been woman's possession, but
advising them to use this power for
the protection of their homes, and to
avoid partisan politics, Mrs. L. C.
French in an address at the luncheon
tendered by the wives of local Ki-
wanians to the visiting ladies, Thursday afternoon, at 2 o'clock, pointed
out how a wonderful work may be
done by women in this age of advancement of and opportunity for
women.
Mrs. French's speech was the principal address of the luncheon, and as
this was exclusively a woman's meeting, she confined her remarks to topics of particular interest, to the women of today. Mrs. French stated that
the age in which we now live is a
wonderful one. In "the past two hundred  years,   she   said,   more   discov-
eries and inventions of importance to
man have been made than in all the
preceding  history  of  the  world.  But
not only in  material  ways is this  a
wonderful  age.   The   ideals   that  are
predominant     have     changed.   Mrs
French    said that she can   remember
when  men's    clubs  at    their    social
meetings did not employ themselves
in the interest of wholesome amusement  and   humanitarian   enterprises.
She declared that a new spiritual  dis-
covery  has  been   made   in  this   era,
that of the value of work for humanity,
interest    themselves    also    in    such
questions.
Kiwanis   Auxiliary
Mrs. Myer, of Chattanooga, spoke
on the ladies' auxiliary of the Kiwanis club that has been formed in Chattanooga and the work it is doing. The
club has forty-five members said Mrs.
Myer, and is at present supplying
eighty-seven children with milk. A
trained nurse is maintained by the
organization to visit homes needing
medical inspection and treatment.
Food, clothing and coal are furnished to needy families, and instead of
giving aid promiscuously last Christmas., the la[d]ies visited needy homes,
ascertained their greatest wants and
supplied them.
Mrs. Myer stated that the auxiliary
was first formed as a social adjunct
to the Chattanooga Kiwanis club, but
it was soon felt if the organization
was to be maintained, there must be
some definite objective other than, a
social one. As a woman's natural instincts lead her to think of the welfare of the child, hence the child welfare work was adopted as the main
objective of the auxiliary. A large
delegation from the organization was
present at the luncheon, and was
presented by Mrs.  Myer.
Mrs.   Rutherford   Presides
Mrs.  C.  C.  Rutherford  presided at
the meeting, introducing all speakers,
and the various numbers on the pro-
gram. In delivering her address of
welcome to the visitors in the city,
she said:
The ladies of the Knoxville Kiwanis Club wish to convey through
me, as their chairman, to the visiting ladies of the Convention, their
very great pleasure in being your
hostess on this occasion; also their
personal appreciation for such a large
attendance. It shows that we are interested in common with our husbands.
I have never seen a body of men so
deeply wedded to a club as are the
Kiwanians. I believe there is a great-
er per centage of real, live, active
members in the Kiwanis Club than
any other organization, and of course
we, as the wives, are very proud of
this fact.
Convention    Means    Much
I doubt if we fully appreciate and
realize what Kiwanis means to our
men, and I am sure that such conventions as this, where we can work
and learn more about Kiwanis, will
be a great inspiration to us. As I
study Kiwanis I am more and more
impressed with the fact that they
should have something like a Ladies'
Auxiliary, for I see many avenues in
which we could do good.
I am greeting you all today on behalf of The Knoxville Club. I sincerely hope that you will go away, from
the convention just as happy as we
are that you came.
Mrs. Hal Mould, of Pineville, Ky.,
responded to the greeting, expressing
her appreciation of the courtesies that
the Knoxville women have extended
the visitors and stating that she and
the other guests await an opportunity
for returning the hospitality that has
been so generously offered them in
this city.
Organization  Needed
Another   point  which  Mrs.  French 
stressed is the need of effective or- 
ganization for producing the best results   "It is utter foolishness to  say
that "you can work better alone," she
remarked. It is through organization
she reminded  her  audience  that the
great   things   of   the   world   are   accomplished.   As   an   example   of   an
what  may  be  accomplished  through
organization she mentioned the Parent-Teachers' Association. This body,
she stated, has a more clearly defined
work  than the  majority  of women's
clubs, and through its work for the
child, which is in line with woman's
natural  inclinations,   much  good  has
been accomplished.
Although some man may tell you
that women had more influence before they secured the ballot," said
Mrs French, "don't believe him. It
isn't true. Women have more power
and strength right now through their
vote than they have ever had at any
other period in the world's history.
They can now safeguard their homes
from evil, she said, instead of having
to sit by passively and watch the
calamity befall."
This does not mean, she declared
that women must go outside of their
homes to find their work now; on
the contrary, woman's work lies as it
always has in the home, but it is her
duty to study civic questions with
her husband, and go to the polls and
do her duty by voting. Mrs. French
___mened the study of civic ques-
tions for the betterment of local con-
ditions in the towns in which the women present at the luncheon might
live for as wives of men interested
in a club standing for civic improvement it behooves them, she said, to (missing)</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/333</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>