<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 39 d</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 39 d . Newspaper clipping: In The Interest Of Votes For Women.  Edited by Emma Farrand Tyler.  July 27, 1916.  Knoxville Journal.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's suffrage;</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Edited by Emma Farrand Tyler</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Knoxville Journal</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>July 27, 1916</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook p. 39</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>In The Interest Of Votes For Women
Edited by Emma  Farrand Tyler.
(Those starred have ratified)
Legislatures Now in Session or to Meet 
in 1919 
Massachusetts*
Michigan*
Illinois*
Pennsylvania*
Wisconsin*
Georgia&#8212;June  25,  1919.
Alabama&#8212;July  8,   1919.
Ohio*&#8212;June.  16.   1919.
Texas*&#8212;June  23,   1919.
Special   Sessions   Called   to   Ratify
New York* &#8212; Called by Governor 
Smith for June 16.
Kansas*&#8212;Called by Governor Allen 
for June 16.
Wyoming&#8212;Called by Governor Carey. Date not set.
Missouri*&#8212; Called by Governor Gardner for July 2,
Indiana&#8212;Called by Governor Goodrich  for  first. week  in  Sept.
Colorado&#8212;Called by Governor Shoup.
Date not set.
Iowa*&#8212;Called by Governor Harding
for July 2.
South Dakota,&#8212;Called by ' Governor
Norbeck.    Date not set.
Utah&#8212;Called by Governor Bamberger for first week in October.
Nebraska&#8212;Called by Governor Mc-
Kelvie for July 18,
Arizona&#8212;Date not set
Arkansas &#8212; Called by Governor
Brough for July  28.
California&#8212;Date not set.
Regular Legislatures&#8212;1920
Kentucky&#8212;(Biennial)&#8212;January   6.
Louisiana&#8212;(Biennial)&#8212;May  11.
Maryland&#8212;(Biennial)&#8212;January  1.
Mississippi&#8212;(Biennial)&#8212;(Every other
session is special)&#8212;January 1.
Virginia&#8212;{Biennial)&#8212;January 14.
New York&#8212;(Annual)&#8212;Janunary 8.
Massachusetts&#8212;(Annual)&#8212;January 1.
Rhode  Island&#8212;(Annual)&#8212;January  2.
South Carolina&#8212;(Annual)&#8212;January 3.
New Jersey&#8212;(Annual)&#8212;January 8
Georgia&#8212;-(Annual)&#8212;-In June.
Texas is the eleventh state to ratify
the first of the southern states. Which
next?
TENNESSEE ACTIVITIES
The executive board of the Tennessee
Woman Suffrage Asociation met in
session recently at Lookout Mountain.
A budget of $10,000 was voted ito be
raised by the year's work, each district to be assigned its quota.
Mrs. George Fort Milton, the new-
ly elected state president, presided at
the session and also at the luncheon
at the Hotel Patten, which was the
social  feature  of the gathering.
Mayor-elect  A.   W.   Chambliss     was 
present to make the welcome address;
Mrs. John M. Kenity of Nashville gave
the response. Other speakers were
Mrs. Guilford Dudley, a vice present of
the National American Woman Suffrage Association, Senator P. T. Carter, and representative L. D. Miller, all
of whom were honored guests at the
luncheon.
Mrs. R. B. Cooke of Johnson City
spoke as representing East Tennessee;
Mrs. John M. Ransom of Tullahoma
for Middle Tennessee, and Mrs. Isaac
Reese of Memphis for West Tennessee.
In introducing Mayor-elect Cham-
bliss, Mrs. Milton referred to him as
Chattanooga's best mayor, because the
first one ever elected by women. Representative Miller was introduced as
the legislator who secured the vote for
the women of Tennessee. He disclaimed the honor accorded him, saying that
the bill and everything else was in fine
shape when presented to him. Senator
Carter said he never dreamed he had
pleased so many people in helping push
the suffrage bill, which showed the popularity of suffrage in Tennessee. He declared that the women by their entrance into politics had made it impossible for any more "crooked old
politicians"  to fall  in line.
The Tennessee suffragists are planning a strenuous year devoting much
time to intensive organization work.
A state organizer will be engaged to do
educational work in the rural districts.
Mrs. Milton, the new president of
Tennessee, comes to her duties well
qualified to give Tennessee a banner
year. As she is a woman of rare tact,
judicial temperament, and endowed
with zeal and enthusiasm, as well as
a charming personality, she has the
qualities that make for good leadership. Mrs. Milton is prominent in social, club and church circles, and is
widely known through her clever pen,
which he (sic.) has used most generously on
behalf of the suffrage cause.
Her husband, as editor of the Chattanooga News, has been a staunch ally.
The new officers of the Tennessee
Woman Suffrage Association include:
Mrs. George P. Milton, Chattanooga,
president; Mrs. John M. Ransom, Tullahoma, vice president; Miss Carolina
Williams, Columbia, recording secretary; Mrs. L. T. Hill, Chattanooga, corresponding secretary; Mrs. D. T. Kim-
brough, Nashville, treasurer; Mrs. Reuben Mills, Nashville, auditor.
The Congressional district chairmen
include: First, Mrs. H. White and Mrs.
R.   B.   Cooke  of Johnson  City;  second,
Mrs. H. C. Milnor of Knoxville and
Mrs. Howard Howe of Rochwood (sic.); ithird,
Mrs. John L. Meek, Chattanooga and
Mrs. Annie A. Son of Pittsburgh;
fourth, Mrs. P. S. Dresser of Gallatin,
and Mrs. Sam Young of Dixon Springs;
fifth, Mrs. Lee Fox, of Murfellsford and
Mrs. G. S. Lamon of Tullahoma; sixth,
Mrs. John M. Kenny of Nashville and 
Mrs. J. T. Lupton of Clarksville; sev- 
enth, Mrs. George Sheldon of Columbia and Mrs. E. Eslick of Pulaski;
eighth, Mrs. A. Coylar of Dresden and
Mrs. Budes Owen of Jackson; ninth,
Miss Mary Skeffington, Dyersburg and
Mrs. Marc Anthony of Trenton; tenth,
Mrs. Isaac Reese of Memphis and Mrs.
Cummings of Germantown.
The standing committee chairmen:
are: Mrs. Jas. B. Ezzell of Newsum
Station, legislative; Mrs. Jas. A. Beas-
ley of Nashville, literature, and Mrs.
John Flantt of Memphis, finance.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/498</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>