<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 06 c</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 06 c. Newspaper clipping: "Mrs. French asks The Journal and Tribune to publish..."  By L. Crozier French.  July 29, 1916.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Universities &amp; colleges; Teachers;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>July 29, 1916</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 06</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>Mrs. French asks The Journal and Tri
bune to publish her letter to the executive
committee of the University of Tennessee,
because the verdict of the special committee reflecting upon her veracity and
consistency of conduct has not only been
published in the public press, but is a part
of the record of the state university that
must go down to posterity. Mrs. French
asks the public to give her their help in
her efforts to have this unjust verdict ex
punged from the record.
To   the   Executive   Committee   of   the  University   of  Tennessee.
Gentlemen:&#8212;In the published report of
the meeting of the trustees of the university, I call your attention to the resolution
of a special committee under the heading
"The  Stough   Case."
In the summing up of this case in the
last paragraph but one, my name is conspicuously used as one of several ladies
who it is implied are in some way re
sponsible for Dr. Stough's attack upon the
teaching of a professor of the university.
I wish to brand this finding of your special committee as a gross slaader of these
ladies and myself, hence I write to demand|
a re-hearing&#8212;not of the "Stough Case,'
his case being no concern of mine, but of
the verdict against the ladies and myself
that we are guilty of making charges
against said professor that cannot be sub 
stantiated when we have not been given
the opportunity of defense before the body
that tried  and  convicted  us.
An early reply is solicited as to when I
may be allowed the privilege which is al
ways given the lowest criminal, of defending myself against a verdict which brands
me as guilty of conduct unbecoming any
self-respecting woman.
Yours for justice,
L.   CROZIER   FRENCH.
Knoxville,  Tenn., July 29, 1916.
</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/197</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>