<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 40 d</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 40 d. Newspaper clipping: 'CHAIN' BY SUFFRAGISTS.  1,000 Are to Circle White House and End Picketing Today.  March 4, 1917.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's suffrage; Pickets;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>March 4, 1917</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook p. 40</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>'CHAIN' BY SUFFRAGISTS.
1,000 Are to Circle White House
and End Picketing Today.
DROP  THE   JERICHO   FEATURE
Ram's Horns Will Not Be Blown During Big Demonstration, Leaders Believing Tactics Out of Place in the
 Present Crisis&#8212;Union and Wom-
an's Party Combine.
 Encircling the  White House with a
chain of purple, white and gold, women suffragists will bring to a climax at
 3   p.   m.   today   in   a   two-hour   silent
demonstration  their siege  of  President
Wilson on behalf of a Federal suffrage
amendment.    About a thousand women,
members   of   the   Congressional   Union
for  Woman  Suffrage and  the National
Women's Party, have   enlisted to lengthen for the final watch the line of pickets on guard at the White House gates
for   the   last   six   weeks,   encompassing
the  President's comings and goings to
impress   him   in   the   last   days   of   his
first  term   with  their determination  to
have the ballot.
Not Exactly Like Jericho.
Only in a modified form, however,
will the demonstration follow plans
that had been laid to reproduce the
march of the Israelites around Jericho.
At first it was proposed to circle the
White House seven times, with seven
priests carrying the suffrage ark, and
accompanied by "a long blast of the
ram's horn," the citadel signifying to
suffragists the stronghold of opposition
to the cause of suffrage by Federal
amendment.
Why   that   method    of   attack    was
abandoned has not been made entirely
clear by the women's leaders, some of
them explaining that the  critical international situation  would  make  such a
demonstration   appear   as   bad   tactics,
and others hinting that some  of those
in the suffrage ranks thought it might
 seem to border on the sacriligious.
Outwardly, at least, the President has shown no sign of wavering in his oppo-
sition to a Federal amendment and his
jpreference for suffrage by State enact-
ment.
Won Only Wilson's Smiles.
Daily  he  has   smiled   and   saluted   at
the pickets always encountered, rain or
shine,   when   the   presidential   car   has
left    or    entered    the    White    House grounds.
 During the first days of the siege,
 when bitter January winds tried the
 courage of the guards, he sent them an
 invitation to come inside. But it was
 not accepted, and since then, except for
jthe daily smile and salute, he has not
jshown that he was aware of his state of siege.
Today's demonstration, the most re-
markable perhaps of all those that have
 characterized the fight for equal suf-
frage, will be timed to begin three
 hours after the official beginning of the
new presidential term.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/526</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>