<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 41 d</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 41 d . Newspaper clipping: Brilliant Event.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's rights; Women's suffrage;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>Unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook p. 41</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>Brilliant Event.
  The formation of the Tennessee branch 
of the union occurred amid the most
favorable circumstances. When it be-
came known that Miss Alice Paul, the
official head of the Congression unon,
was to come to Tennessee to form an
organization, and when it became fur-
ther known that this organization would
be effected in Knoxville, the Political Equality league, one of the three local
suffrage organizations, made arrangements for a banquet to be given in honor 
of Miss Paul, and it was at this that
the Tennessee branch was inaugurated.
Following the discussion of the menu, 
Mrs. G. W. Denney, who presided 
gracefully and charmingly as toastmis-
tress, introduced the speakers.
In the absence of the mayor, John E. McMillan,   who  was  to   have  made  the 
 first talk, Mrs. L. C. French, the veteran 
suffragist of East Tennessee, the woman 
who has fought many verbal battles for
the cause, was called upon, and as usual, 
rose   splendidly   to   the   occasion.    Mrs.
French said she had long secretly wished 
to.occupy  the  mayor's  chair,   and   that 
this was, at last, the realization of her
hopes.    Mrs. French  said she had been
in sympathy with the policy of the union
 since   its   organization,   for   the   federal 
amendment route is the most direct and 
 the least expensive way to the suffrage. 
  Capt.   William  Rule,     editor    of  The 
Journal   and   Tribune,   was   the   second 
speaker.    He   wished  the   union   speedy
and complete  success,  and  said  that  he 
was   willing   to   go   on   record   as  being 
one   man   in   Knoxville   who   was   not 
    afraid   the  affairs  of  the  nation   would 
go to destruction if the women are given 
 the right of franchise.
Mrs. W. F. Searle, vice-president of
Ossoli circle, who is a recent convert to
the suffrage cause, told how she "saw (missing)e light," and became converted.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/502</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>