<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Votes for Women a Success (p. 4 of 4)</dc:title>
<dc:description>Votes for Women a Success (p. 4 of 4).  Southern States Woman Suffrage Conference. No Date.  Lizzie Crozier French Papers.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Women's suffrage; Voting; Ephemera;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>ephemera</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizze Crozier French Papers</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>SOUTHERN STATES WOMAN SUFFRAGE fCONFERENCE. 
Declaration of Principles. 

The following resolutions were unanimous-
ly adopted on Suffrage Day by the Southern 
States Woman Suffrage Conference: 
"Whereas,   woman   suffrage   is   a   world 
movement now conceded as inevitable; and, 
"Whereas, 9,000,000 women in the indus- 
tries of this so-called republic need the ballot 
for protection as much as the workingmen 
need it, demonstrating thereby that woman 
suffrage is no longer a theory to be debated, 
but a condition to be met; and, 
"Whereas, there are but two ways of se- 
curing this extension of suffrage to women, 
through a national amendment to the Consti- 
tution or through the State submitting to the 
voters the question; and,
"Whereas, we believe suffrage is a State 
right, and not a Federal right, and that the 
best interests of the nation will be conserved 
by preserving to the State the right to de- 
fine its electorate; be it 
"Resolved, That we women of the South, 
guided by the lessons of the past, do affirm |
our faith in self-government, not alone for in- 
dividuals,   but   in   self-government   for  the 
State, as the greatest constitutional heritage 
 which, in the wisdom of the framers of our 
 government, was chosen to insure a free man 
and a free State as the central ideals of de-
mocracy; be it further
  "Resolved, That the time has come for the 
 Democratic Party, the State rights party, to 
 record itself in favor of 'Votes for Women,' 
 and to this end we, the men and women of 
 the South, consecrate our best efforts to make 
 the party so record itself." 
SOUTHERN STATES WOMAN SUFFRAGE CONFERENCE                                                                                                       Headquarters: 
301 CARONDELET ST.        NEW ORLEANS, LA.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/280</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>