<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 07 a</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 07 a. Newspaper clipping: 'Women and City Politics Topic. Mrs. L. Crozier French Will Address morristown Club Feb. 22 On Important Subject.'</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 07</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>WOMEN AND CITY
POLITICS TOPIC
Mrs. L. Crozier French Will Address Morristown Club Feb.
22 On Important Subject
"Activities of Women in the Problems of a City Government," will be
the subject of an address to be delivered by Mrs. L. Crozier French, president of Ossoli circle at the citizenship
day program of Somo Sala circle, February 22, at Morristown. This will be
the leading address of the day; other
five minute talks being given by different members as follows:
"Types of City Government."
"Mayor and Council Type"&#8212;Mrs.
Harris.
"Commission Forb"&#8212;Mrs. Witt.
"City Manager Plan"&#8212;Mrs. Phillips.
The theme for the subjects under
discussion is suggested by the quotation from Lowell which heads the
program:
"New occasions teach new duties;
Time makes ancient good uncouth."
The Morristown club is greatly interested in a practical solution of some
of the problems which face every community, and hopes to follow up the
discussions by some action that shall
result in permanent good to all concerned. It is particularly fortunate in
securing as a speaker Mrs. L. Crozier
French who is one of Knoxville's most
active and brilliant club women, and
who has been for some time at the head
of Ossoli circle.
</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/199</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>