<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 14 d.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 14 d. Newspaper clipping: Mrs. L.C. French Dies In Washington, D.C.  Prominent Club Woman And Civic Worker Succumbs Following Heart Attack.  By Russell Kent, Journal Washington Bureau.  May 14, [1926].</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Death;</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Russell Kent</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Journal Washington Bureau</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>May 14, [1926]</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 14</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>Mrs. L. C. French Dies
In Washington D. C.
Prominent Club Woman And Civic Worker
Succumbs Following Heart Attack,
BY RUSSELL KENT
Journal   Washington  Bureau
WASHINGTON,   May   14  &#8212; Mrs
L.  Crozier  French,  for  many  years  
prominent in social and civic activi- 
ties in Knoxville and a pioneer work-   
er   in   Tennessee   for   women's   suf- 
frage, died here at 4 o'clock this  af-
ternoon. She was 75 years old.
The body will be sent to Knoxville
on the Memphis Special early in the
morning, arriving at Knoxville tomorrow night. Funeral services will
be held  Monday  morning.
Mrs. French reached Washington
Monday morning, intending to remain several days. She was walking
with Mrs. L. D. Tyson, wife of the
senator, in a room in the National
Women's Party building here which
has been furnished by the Tennessee Women's Party and is to be dedicated in honor of Mrs. French when
she became suddenly ill Wednesday
afternoon. She was removed to Providence hospital.
A son, William W. French arrived
this morning from Birmingham, Ala.
Mrs. French rallied and it was believed she had started toward recovery when in mid-afternoon she
suffered a relapse which brought the
end quickly.
The cause of death was  ascribed
to   heart   trouble,   complicated by  a congestion  of both  lungs  approaching pneumonia and by other physical ailments.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/328</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>