<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. A list of some of Tennessee's discriminations against women.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Papers.  'The Legal Research Department of the Woman's Party...list of some of Tennessee's discriminations against women:'  1 page, typescript.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Women's rights;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>manuscript</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Papers</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>
The legal Research Department of the Wman's Party has not
entirely completed its survey of the Tennessee laws relating to
women.  Only major subjects have been covered.  The following is
a list  of some   of  Tennessee's discriminations  against women:
1  (stricken through) The father alone is the natural guardian of his children. Ross v. Cobbm 9 Yer. 463: Miles v. Kaigler, 10 Yer. 10.  The mother is not a natural guardian of her own child unless the father is dead
or a deserter.
2.  When a married woman dies without a will, her husband gets
her entire personal estate.   On the other hand, when a married man
dies without a will, his wife gets only a child's share in his personal estate.
Only if there are no children does she get his
entire personal estate.
3.  The husbandis entitled to use for his life all the
real estate of his deceased wife, provided a child
was born
alive during the marriage.  
The wife, on the other hand, is entitled to use for her
life of only one-third of her deceased husband's lands.
4.  Women are excluded from jury service.
5.  The father inherits all the personal estate of a child
who dies without a will and without descendants.  The mother inherits
the personal estate of her deceased child only if the father is dead,
and even then she must share the inheritance with the brothers and
sisters of the decedent.
6.  A mother is not entitled to sue for damages for an injury
to her minor child unless the father is dead or has deserted.  The
right to sue belongs exclusively to the father except in the in-
stances named.
7. A husband is entitled to his wife's services and he may
recover for the loss of such services by reason of personal in-
juries sustained by her. In such a case the wife collects damages
only for her pain and suffering. When a married man is injured,
he recovers all damages.



</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/281</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>