<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 46 b</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 46 b. Newspaper clipping:  Pleased With Registration.  1919.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Voter registration;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>1919</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF; 400 dpi</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook p. 46</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>PLEASED WITH
REGISTRATION
Mrs. T. P. Miller Says Women
Are Encouraged.
Goal of Organization Is to Have
50 Per Cent of Sex Qualify
to Vote.
"We are very encouraged over tbe
registration of women this past week
and feel certain that fifty per cent of
all eligible women voters will registe-
before the 21st," declared Mrs. T. P.
Miller, chairman of the Non-Partisan
Political League, last night.
"Amusing incidents are told by ward
and block chairmen. One chairman
was sitting on the porch of a woman in
her ward and the woman was telling her
how bitterly her husband opposed the
idea of suffrage, when said husband appeared. He ordered the chairman off
the porch and premises. She was a
tactful woman and instead of flaring up
she admired the children and the pretty
lawn, etc., and when he regained his
composure she insidiously presented per-
tinent reasons why his wife should
shoulder her responsibility and vote, as 
hundreds of other Knoxville women
would do. He saw the light and invited her to stay for supper, and also
said he wanted his wife to get out and help.
"Another chairman tells of visiting a
timid little woman who said: It was not
in the jurisdiction of women to vote,
they ought not to pray in public, etc.
Her husband was reading on the other
side of the porch and overhearing the
block chairman's persuasive voice&#8212;with
paper in hand came round to where the
two women were talking and said: "Do
you want to be the only woman in this
block who has not registered ? If you
really do&#8212;I don't wan't you to&#8212;I'd feel
mortified if my wife couldn't do as well
as the rest of them.' The wife consented.
"Daily reports from     the wards   are
awaited with   interest,     each   chairman
hoping to have the banner ward.
Urges  Earnestness.
"Knoxville is naturally a beautiful city
and now that the women have a voice 
in the election of the people who oversee 
it, we must think earnestly and inielli-
gently, weighing each man mentally 
and morally, giving full credit where it
is due and conscientiously cast our bal- 
lot for the man whom we find fit, abso- 
lutely regardless of party. It has been
said that men who know no such thing
as 'non-partisan,' that they will run true
to form, once a democrat, always a dem- 
ocrat, once a republican always a re-
publican. I feel sure the women will 
look for the man, not the partv.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/600</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>