<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 25 c.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 25 c. Newspaper clipping: How Will Women Vote?</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's suffrage;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>Unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 25</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>How Will Women Vote?
THE movement that is now under way in Knoxville owes much to the women. Two capable
and public-spirited women helped frame the new charter&#8212;-Mrs. W. L. Morris and Mrs.
E. L. Thomas. There were many women on the general and district committees which nominated the 'People's Ticket.
Many women &#8212; and men, too for that mater&#8212;believe it would have been a good thing if
a woman had been put on the People's Ticket for council.
But we believe there are few women who agree with Mrs. L. C. French that the People's
Ticket should be discarded because it does not contain a woman candidate.
Most women are primarily interested in the welfare of the city and their homes. To them
the "woman's movement" is less important.  Most women's interests in politics is in claning (sic.)
 up government, and especially city government, so that their homes will benefit therefrom.
 So rapid is the advance of women in industry and in public affairs that most women are not
 indignant because it is not faster. To most women, the participation of women in the People's
movement marks distinct progress.    Office holding will come  soon enough to please    most women.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/423</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>