<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 07 h</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 07 h. Newspaper clipping: 'Mrs. L. Crozier French Edits Paper.'   Mrs. French has
begun the publication of a monthly journal, "The People," a journal of inquiry, protest and an exponent of the people.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Journalism;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 07</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>MRS.   L.  CROZIER
FRENCH  EDITS PAPER.
It is doubtful if there is any woman
prominent in the club and literary life of
the South who would as instantly command the attention of the public in her
own enterprise than Mrs. L. Crozier
French, the brilliant club leader whose
influence is still felt in Birmingham's
club life. Mrs. French, who is now living
in her old home in Knoxville, Tenn., has
begun the publication of a monthly journal, "The People," a journal of inquiry,
protest and an exponent of the people.
Contrary to the usual object of a woman's paper, the club organs and those
that discuss the fashions and other time-
ly subjects which regale the readers of
the woman's page in the daily papers.
Mrs. French will make no effort to interest readers of this class. In emphasizing her position, the editor savs:
"This publication claims not to be a
guide to society ladies. It resigned all
such ambitions to the Ladies' Home Journal and similar sheets. You will not learn
from these columns how to butter your
bread, or hold your fork. The best manner of folding your napkin will be left
to your imagination. It will not undertake to instruct you in the number of the
hairs of your head, nor the proper number of kisses you should give to your
sweetheart. The editor of this journal
takes it for granted that its readers are
not inmates of institutions for the feeble
minded." 
In a somewhat lengthy editorial, Mrs.
French leaves no doubt, however, as to
the policy of "The People." With her
usual comprehensiveness and frankness
she outlines the policy of her journal.
Education will occupy much space in
"The People," education is the highest
and broadest sense of the word, including schools, the theatre, pleasures, ethical questions,  health.
Mrs. French is particularly interested
in municipal affairs of her own city. In
an open letter, she has already challenged the "ring leaders," and she calls
attention to certain municipal problems
that will be discussed from time to time
in her journal. Briefly the policy of "The
People" is:
The People is not the propagander of
any set of tenets, be they religious, political, philosophical or scientific. The
People will investigate, as opportunity
offers, any subject that is of vital interest to humanity, but will dogmatize,
about none. Great principles will be
studied, and the endeavor will be to
show how they may be made to govern
the practical affairs of life. The policy
will be to treat every subject with candor, but it is hoped with perfect good
nature. The private character of no man
or woman, nor their private affairs will
be considered legitimate subjects for discussion in these columns. Public officials,
together with all those, be they men or
women, who are in professions that bring
them before the public, will be dealt with
as may seem fit from time to time, but
neither flattery, nor spite will be permitted to dictate the spirit of any criticism. Institutions and people will stand
on their own merit. The policy of The
People will be controlled neither by fear,
nor  favor."
Among the contributors to Mrs.
French's journal is her sister, Miss L.
Graham Crozier, a woman of national
prominence as a lecturer, teacher, essayist. With two such gifted women, "The
People" will be conducted on the broadest
lines, and will interest a large class of
readers.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/272</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>