<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 26 d.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 26 d. Newspaper clipping: Not Discouraged.  Knoxville Journal.  August 1919.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's suffrage;</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Knoxville Journal</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>August 1919</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 26</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>NOT DISCOURAGED
Mrs. L. Crozier French has received
the following letter:
Birmingham, Ala., Aug. 3.
My dear Mrs. French:
Please allow me to thank you for
sending the paper containing the decision of the Tennessee court regarding
suffrage.    I have enjoyed reading it.
I am in Birmingham only over Sunday, returning to Montgomery tomorrow, for although we had an unfavorable vote on ratification several days
ago in the senate, we are fighting to
secure a reversal, which we think we
shall get a little later. At any rate
we are not yet "defeated."
Thanking you  for  remembering me
I am, cordially,
PATTIE  R. JACOBS,
President Alabama    Suffrage    Association.
In Alabama, where the resolution was
voted down, it can be reintroduced. As
you know, we lost by only three votes.
We are just beginning to get active support from the prohibitionists in Alabama who seem to feel that there is
still hope  of ratification.
North   Dakota,   Massachusetts,   Ohio,
and New Hampshire, in raising money 
and on ratification work.
After Arkansas, Nebraska and Mon- 
tana have ratified when they meet next
week, one looks for additional impetus
to be given the movement. If we can
only keep up the work we are doing,
we believe that ratification will soon
be accomplished.  It is reported by Miss
Younger, our legislative chairman, that
the polls of the legislatures show that
thirty-five states now have a majority
of votes pledged for ratification. When
the thirty-sixth state is secured we
shall look for quick action.
I hope that this letter is not too long.
There is much else that I desire to tell,
but will  not risk taxing your patience 
further, 
Faithfully yours,
DORA LEWIS,
National Finance Chairman</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/427</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>