<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 07 g</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 07 g. Newspaper clipping: 'Slatery and Others Heard.' (partial clipping)</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 07</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>Slatery and Others Heard                                                                                                                                                          Before  introducing Dr.  R.  F.  Openhimer, also a member of the   present  board,   Mrs.   French   referred  to the fact that Mrs. Belle Karns Morris   was     "unfortunately"     on     the People's ticket, but that friends and supporters of Mrs. French and Mrs.
Miller were anxious that she should be     elected  as  a  member    of    the (missing)                                                            Between   three  and  four  hundred
men and women, among them several   of  the  independent   candidates
for council and school board, greeted
Mrs. French and listened to an ad-
dress into which she injected a great
deal of humor, and sarcasm directed
at the People's ticket and the committee of 18.    Mrs. French made her
talk largely an answer to an editorial
regarding her candidacy    appearing
Monday in The Knoxville News, but
digressed at intervals to discuss the
failure   of the  committee  of  18   to
place her on the People's ticket, and
the action of the League of Women 
Voters   in   withdrawing its   support
from her.    She declared that only a
small   part   of    the     Knox     County
League of Women Voters was lend-
ing  support   to   the People's   ticket,
and   that   later  on   the   organization
would establish itself as the balance
of power in things political.
Repudiation Personal
Mrs. French denied that she had
ever said the People's ticket should
be repudiated because it did not contain a woman, but that she herself
had  regulated  it.
"I also repudiate the committee of
Eighteen! I do not consider that
I would be progressive if I followed
them. Men will be progressing
when they are following me.
though." said   Mrs. French.
She denied that she set the woman's movement above good government, but said that she had
worked for the enfranchisement of
women that good government might
come about. She said that she had
not sought to hold office, and that
she had never worked to put a wo-
man in public office in her life.
Mrs. French referred to the fact
that she was being accused of going
to the camp of the politicians. "They
tell me they are 'slick' politicians." 
said Mrs. French, "but I do not
care, if they treat me well and if
they treat everybody else well. I
cannot help what they do 'on the
sly.'
Would Keep  Men  Straight
The speaker said that many people
did not like her because she spoke
her mind too plainly, and she gave
due notice that if she were elected
to speak her mind would keep the
to speak her mind would keep the (sic.)
men straight." "Perhaps I am bold
about speaking the truth.' said Mrs.
French, "but its rather a relief sometimes among so many liars to see
the naked truth walking about."
She concluded her talk with an ap-
peal for support, to such a degree
that the primary would settle the
matter and she would not have to
continue her campaign for election
on  September 2,
Mrs. S. L. Branch, campaign manager for Mrs. French introduced
Mrs. Thomas Peacock Miller, candidate for member of the school
board. Mrs. Miller stated her
claims for election, the chief one be-
ing her record as a member of the
present board. She said she considered herself the school patrons candidate, and that she would continue
her best efforts to serve them if
elected.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/271</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>