<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 18 e.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 18 e. Newspaper clipping: Who Will Take Care Of The Babies?  and New Suffragist Stunt.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 18</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>WH0 WILL TAKE CARE
OF THE BABIES?
A Happy  Solution   of  a Very 
Troublesome Problem.
Miss Laura Clay in her recent lecture 
at Market Hall told a little story in 
refutation of the old charge that there 
would be no one left at home to take 
care of the babies if women went to 
the polls.
A  tourist,   it  seems,   wanting  to   get 
information  at  first  hand   in  regard  to 
the workings of equal suffrage in Colorado,   strolled  over  to   the  voting place
on  election day.    Presently two women
came along, each carrying a  baby, and
began  chatting with a pleasant looking
individual! of the male  persuasion,  who
stood at the door of the building.    After 
a round or two of merry banter, one of 
the   women   handed   the   man   her   baby 
and went into the booth to cast her vote.
When she returned, the child, in a state 
of high good humor, was restored to its
rightful  owner,   and  the  same friendly 
arms were held out to receive the other 
infant.      Whereupon   this   mother   also
went   into   the   booth   to   discharge her
duty to the state.
"Who is that pleasant looking individ- 
ual that seems to have such a winning 
way with mothers and babies?"' asked
the mystified tourist of a bystander.
"Him;    Oh! that is one of the candidates," was the reply.
New Suffragette Stunt.
London, Fob. 7.&#8212;The suffragettes
have begun a campaign of cutting telephone and telegraph wires. 'Thirty telephone wires were cut today near Dumbarton, Scotland, and many telegraph 
wires between Birmingham and Coventry. Much inconvenience was caused by
the action of the suffragettes.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/389</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>