<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 17 c.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 17 c. Newspaper clipping: Miss Anthony's Birthday.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's suffrage; Birthdays;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 17</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>Miss Anthony's Birthday.       Susan B. Anthony's birthday this month
was celebrated on the suffrage picket line
in Washington in an impressive and beau-
tiful manner.    In  the face of heavy  snow
and rain dozens of young women stood in
line holding high special banners made for :
the   occasion' which   proclaimed   the   un- 
swerving  policy  of the  suffrage  leader  in
holding   parties   responsible   and   putting
"suffrage  first."    Thousands  of men  and 
women streaming  home from  work in  the 
early   evening   paused  to  read  the  gallant
banners   that   so   absolutely   upheld   the
policy of the young banner bearers of today.
The   big   golden   flags  were   lettered   as
 follows:
"We press our demands for the ballot at 
this time in no narrow, captious or selfish
spirit," read the first banner, "but from 
purest patriotism, for the highest good 
of every citizen, for the safety of the republic and as a glorious example to the nations of the earth."
"At this time our greatest need is not
men or money, valiant generals or bril- 
liant victories, but a consistent national 
policy based upon the principle that all
governments derive their just powers from 
consent of the governed."
The third Susan B. Anthony banner bore
this   inscription:   "The   right   of   self-gov-
ernment  for   one-half  of  its   people   is   of far  more  vital  consequence  to  the  nation,
 than any or all other questions',"
So impressed by the line was a Baltimore 
 clergyman   that  he   took   a   picture  of  the 
bannered pickets to show to the young 
women of his Sunday school, promising a 
delegation from his church for the picket 
line in the near future. A woman who also 
caught the truly religions spirit of the 
pageant like procession stepped up to the
leader of the procession and said "I wonder
 if you realize the mediaeval spectacle
you young women present; you have made
us realize, that this cause is a crusdae."
Lawyers, doctors and nurses have stood
on the suffrage picket line on their res- 
pective days this week, and at the "picket 
teas" held at headquarters after the pick-
eting is over each day, different speakers 
have described the new spirit that is ani-
mating the suffrage movement largely be-
cause women are willing to visualize the 
movement to the man and woman on the
street.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/344</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>