<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 45 d</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 45 d. Newspaper clipping: Vote Early And Avoid The Rush.  Knoxville Journal.  [Aug.] 22, 1919.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Voting;</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Knoxville Journal</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>[Aug.] 22, 1919</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook p. 45</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>VOTE EARLY AND
AVOID THE RUSH
Election Commission Starts Educational Campaign.
In West   Eleventh   Ward  One
Vote Must Be Cast Every
36 Seconds,
"Vote   Early!"
This is the slogan which the commissioners of election will urge the women,
who intend to participate in the coming
primary city election, to adopt in order
to avoid the rush at certain hours on
election day and to assure a vote for
all who are registered.
It is now an assured fact that the
coming primary election will be the
largest ever held in this county or
even in this section of the state, as the
registration books reveal the fact that
19,302 men and women have qualified
themselves to participate in the political contest. However, it is expected that
there will not be as many persons cast
their votes as have registered.
The commissioners of election say
that in many of the largest wards it will
be absolutely necessary for the women
to vote in the morning and early afternoon in order that the men may vote
after their work hours. In all the elec-
tions that have been held in this city
or county, more than one-half of the
votes are cast after four o'clock in the
afternoon, due to the fact that the majority of the men voters are compelled
to cast their vote after work  hours.
It is also cited by the members of
the election commission that this move
would not only be to the interest of the
men voters, but will greatly assist the
women, in that if they cast their votes
in the morning and early afternoon the
polls will not be so crowded as during
the noon hour and after four o'clock.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/525</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>