<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 36 e</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 36 e. Newspaper clipping: Mrs. M'Cormick Speaks. [1914?]</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Meetings; Women's suffrage;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>[1914?]</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook p. 36</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>Mrs. M'Cormick Speaks.
"My  idea   of  the object of  this  asso-
ciation," said Mrs. Medill McCormick, of
Chicago,  chairman  of
the congressional committee,
 "is that we
want to
pass national legislation to give
women the ballot.    Among the ways 
open to us to obtain the vote are to secure the passage of the 
Bristow-Mondell resolution which
is similar to the resolution drafted fifty
years ago by Susan B. Anthony and
which requires ratification by thirty-six
states to become effective; to pass the
Shafroth amendment which provides for
submitting the suffrage  question to the
voters of each state through initiative
petitions and to go before the state legislatures for amendments of the state constitutions. The Shafroth amendment is
designed to assist the states to give
women the ballot by going around the
state legislatures. The more suffrage
states we have the easier it will be to
pass the Bristow-Mondell amendment."
Argument in behalf of the Shafroth
resolution was made by Mrs. Antion-
nette Funk, of Chicago, a member of the
congressional committee who appealed to
the delegates not to tie the hands of the
committee in Washington by restricting
 their means of operation.
"Many suffragists seem to think that
the Shafroth amendment is a "tobog-
gan-slide' into suffrage but they are 
under a misapprehension" declared Mrs.
 Blatch. "One of my reasons for objecting to working for it is our funds
 and workers are limited and besides we
 will have to resort to the Susan B. Anthony resolution eventually to gain the vote.
     I  do  not believe  in dividing our
 efforts but think we  should concentrate
every  energy upon the measure that will
bring  us what we want.  The Bristow-Mondell
 amendment gives us a chance to 
avoid  the referendum and with the
foreign element of voters in this country, I
believe it is not well to risk our cause to
a referendum."
Sharp   replies   wore   calleld(?)   forth   from
members   of   the   congressional   committee
and  their   supporters   when      Miss    Mabel
Vernon of Delaware criticised the committee.     "There  are  only   a  few   more   states
which     would   help     the Shafroth amendment," she asserted.  "Why
didn't the congressinal committee
get  out  in  the campaign
 states   and   help   them
instead    of putting their time on something that could not be accomplished in Washington?"

Shouts of "they did help" came from all
over the hall and Mrs. Funk and Mrs. Mc-
Cormick were allowed to tell of the committee's work in the recent campaign.
Mrs. Valentine of Virginia and other
southern delegates said the southern states
would not care to accept the Shafroth
amendment, but that they would more
quickly grant woman suffrage through
their  state   legislatures.
Mrs. Helen Hill Weed of Connecticut,
"General" Rosalie Jones of New York,
and Mrs. Francis Burns of Michigan,
were among the ardent advocates of the
Bristow-Mondell measure, while Dr. Anna
Shaw, president of the association; Mrs. 
Desha Breckinridge of Kentucky; Miss;
Mary Stewart of Montana and Mrs. Grace Wilbur Trout of Chicago made vigorous
pleas for the  Shafroth  resolution.
When debate was closed there were a
score or more of delegates who still
wanted to express their views on the question. Mrs. Jenks' amendment to strike
out was lost by a viva voce vote and
Mrs. Brown's substitute motion for that
offered by Mrs. Blatch was adopted by
a vote of 194 to  100.
A motion offered by Mrs. Trout authorising the national board to endorse and
support a federal amendment for a national
initiative and referendum law was
defeated.
There are perhaps twenty-five million
women in the United States, something
over five million    of whom are    wage- 
earning.    There  are  more&#8212;far  more--
wage-earning women in this country
today  than there  were  men,  women and 
children  in   the   thirteen     colonies   upon the day when
those fundamental statements were penned.
Women,  because they are women, are taxed
without representation.  They are governed without consent.  They have personal and contractual, but no political rights. Those in the twentieth century, in the (missing)
</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/480</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>