<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 41 b</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 41 b. Newspaper clipping: Congressional Union State Branch Is Organized Here.  1918.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's suffrage;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>1918</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook p. 41</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>CONGRESSIONAL UNION STATE
BRANCH IS ORGANIZED HERE
What It Means.
The formation of a Tennessee branch
of the Congressional Union for woman
suffrage was the object of Miss Paul's
visit to the state. , This makes the twenty-seventh state 'branch of the union
formed, and,  as Miss Paul explained in
her talk, these various state branches
are being organized so that they may
help the Congressional union in its work
at Washington in having the federal
amendment to the constitution enfranchising women passed.
As is generally known, the object of
the union is to bring pressure to bear
upon congress to pass the Susan B. Anthony amendment to the federal constitution, which provides for the granting
of suffrage to the women of the nation.
The work of the union is concentrated
at Washington on the senators and rep-
resentatives, and the policy of the union
is against separate state campaigns.  The members of the union believe that the quickest way to obtain suffrage is through the "State's rights" principle.

 The main work of the separate state
 branches of the union to work on the sen-
ators and representatives of their various
states  who  are  opposed  to  the  passage
 of the federal amendment enfranchising
 women, and to do all in their power to
either  convert them  to the cause  or
defeat them  for re-election  to  the  next
congress.
Colors of the Union.
The banquet hall on the fourth
floor of the Imperial hotel was decorated for the occasion with flags and
streamers of purple, white and gold,
the official colors of the Congressional
union.
The banqueters were seated at
small tables, and the room was entirely filled. Hardly another table
could have been placed. The assemblage was a brilliant one, representative of the culture and an intellect
of the city.
Among the out-of-town women
present were Mrs. Hugh Lawson
White, of Johnson City; Mrs. J. N.
Houser, of Mascot, Mrs. K. P. Jones,
of Maryville; Mrs. J. E. Brading, of
Johnson City; Miss Ernestine Noa, of
Chattanooga, and Miss Nancy Lea
Broady, of Maryville.
Upon motion of Mrs. French, it
was decided to send a telegram to
Senator John K. Shields, at Washington, who is known to oppose the
passage of the federal amendment
enfranchising women, asking him, in
the name of the 160 persons at the
gathering, to re-consider his position
on this question, and vote for the
amendment.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/530</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>