<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 21 b.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 21 b. Newspaper clipping: Mrs. Annie Riley Hale Gives Reasons Why Women Shouldn't Vote.  They Should Be Mourning Neglected Duties, Rather Than Seeking New Ones.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's suffrage; Women's rights;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 21</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>Mrs. Annie Riley Hale Gives
Reasons Why Women
Shouldn't Vote.
They Should be Mourning Neglected Duties, Rather Than
Seeking New Ones,
Women Get Same Protection
Under Laws as Men, and
Those Paying Taxes Do So
on Property Earned by Males
men who have, the feminists always
sight(sic.) the weakness of male voters, paying no attention to the strength of the
strong ones. Always, too, they compare
the weak men with the brilliant women,
clamoring for more and newer duties, the
newest woman should be on her face in
the dust, mourning the neglect of other
duties. (Much applause). Woman is able
to swing the world to her notion of
things, yet, ignoring these things, the
newest woman cries for the ballot much
as a spoiled child does for a new toy,
which it soon throws away. The actions
of militant suffragettes are like those
of the spoiled child, to a dot. These
militant suffragettes are so only by reason of the hysteria of disordered minds,
glorified vanity and inordinate egotism.
Those self-constituted martyrs, in addition to sacrificing themselves by hunger-strikes, prison sentences, etc., sacrifice the property and lives of others
and the evil becomes the more. The British
 suffragettes convict themselves of
having no sense of responsibility and no
 sense   of   proportion.       These     militant
 women   are   criminals,   though,   just   the
 same.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/399</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>