<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 29 f.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 29 f. Newspaper clipping: Woman With The Ballot.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's suffrage;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>Unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 29</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>WOMAN WITH THE BALLOT
Dr. H. C. Morrison of Louisville, Ky.,
sets   forth   the   political   expediency   of 
woman suffrage:&#8212; 
Nine states  in  our great Union  have 
conferred upon woman the right of fran- 
chise.    California, Utah. Wyoming, Colo- 
rado, Kansas.   Idaho.  Oregon,  Washing-
ton and Arizona, have given tto[sic.] woman 
the privilege of the ballot.    The indica-
tions are that other states will soon fall 
into line, and it is reasonable to suppose 
in   the  not   distant   future   the   woman-
hood of the United States will have equal 
rights with men at the polls.    The drift 
is so strong in the direction of suffrage
that politicians will be very rare who will
undertake   to   turn    the   onmoving  tide
backward. 
The increase of representation in the
states granting suffrage, will powerfully
influence other states to increase their
representation by increasing their number of voters. However conservative
any part of the country may be on the
subject, no section will be willing or could
hardly afford to entirely outclassed in
representation from other parts of
nation because its women were deprived
of the ballot. Men will reason that if
the  entire   west   gives the ballot to its
women, the east   must do so in order to
compete  with  the west on the floor of
congress;  the same will hold good with
reference to north and south.  The indications are now that the tide of sympathy with suffrage will continue to advance with the idea and it becomes a practical fact.

In the great battle against the liquor
traffic we have been profoundly grieved
and outraged when we have seen illiterate negroes flock to the polls and vote
for the saloon., while intelligent and consecrated women whose offspring were to become the victims of the whiskey traffic, had to remain in subdued silence.
 Any fair mind   must     admit   that  it  hardly
looks  the  proper  thing for  an  illiterate
carriage driver who  pays practically  no
taxes, and is scarcely able to give reason
for his actions, And is often only the tool
in the hands of designing politicians, to
cast a vote to increase taxation, or heap
other  burdens     and     inconveniences  on 
property   owners,   when   the   intelligent, 
cultured woman whose carriage he drives, 
who pays large taxes, must remain silent 
and  inactive.     It  sounds, quite   reasonable when we are 
told     that  taxation  without representation
 is not in harmony with the American idea or with the high
standards of equity.

There are many reason why the citizens of this republic should revere the name of Abraham Lincoln--not the least among them being the fact that he was the first prominent public man in America to advocate women's suffrage, in that memorable declaration which has not become a classic.  "I go for all s_____the privileges (missing) government who assist in bearing (missing)</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/446</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>