<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 43 d</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 43 d. Newspaper clipping: Women Register To Vote In Fall.  Supplemental Registration Three Days Beginning October 13.  August 18, 1920.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Voter registration; Voting;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>August 18, 1920</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook p. 43</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>WOMEN REGISTER
TO VOTE IN FALL
Supplemental Registration Three
Days    Beginning
October 13.
The poll tax question will not enter into the question of women voting in any and all elections this fall
just like the men, in the opinion of
Walter   Warters,     secretary    of   the
Knox  county    election     commission.
Mr.  Warters  states he  believes  that
the   women   can   vote   regardless   of
poll  tax  by  virtue  of  the  fact  that
they were not qualified to vote when 
the   ruling   was   made   that   no   one 
could vote who had not a poll tax receipt   dated   thirty   days   before   the
election or August 5.
Supplemental   Registration
Women however, who have not
registered will be required tp register
in the supplemental registration
which will be held twenty days before
the election of November 2, states Mr.
Warters.
Since the amendment has been ratified Mr. Warters states he believes
the registration of women will be
heavy this fall, because of the fact
that their eligibility to vote in every
election, will command the interest
of women throughout the state. The
great tax question is of great interest
to every woman who owns property,
it is stated, and for the first time
women will be allowed to vote in
the state elections where tax measures are determined.
Strengthens Democratic Ticket
Democratic leaders in the city who
have been heard to express themselves have stated that the enfran-
chisement of women for participation
in every election, will rebound to the
strength of the democratic ticket in
the state and will add measurably to
the prospects of the democratic national ticket from the fact that ratification by a democratic state and
through democratic influences will
make it possible for women throughout the country to vote unfettered in
the November elections. The ratification by Tennessee confers universal
suffrage upon twelve states of the
Union, some of which had refused to
ratify the federal amendment.
Republicans in Knoxville too see
advantage for their party in the action of the state.
It will be argued, say leaders, that
without the aid of republicans the
amendment could not have been ratified, and that Senator Harding exerted his influence to get the legislature to act favorably, limiting his
advice only by the constitution of the
state.
 Provision   of   Constitution
No convention or general assembly
of this state shall act upon any amendment of the constitution of the
United States proposed by congress
to the several states, unless such 
convention or general assembly shall
have been elected after such amendment is submitted.
Miss   Sue     S.   White,     Tennessee
state chairman,    National    Woman's
Party   writes   to     Governor   Roberts 
of Tennessee, as follows:
"Since the decision of the supreme 
court of the United tSates(sic.) on June
1st in the case of Hawke vs. Smith,
I have consulted a number of lawyers, including the solicitor general
of the United States, in regard to the
effect that the decision may have
upon the provision of the Tennessee
constitution which attempts to restrict the power of the general assembly to act  upon amendments  of
the   federal   constitution..... Acting
upon these legal opinions, I am, as
chairman of the Tennessee branch of
the National Woman's Party, submitting to you this formal request
that you call the general assembly
of Tennessee into extraordinary session for the purpose of ratifying the
nineteenth amendment to the United
States consitution.
"This request is made with a full
appreciation of every doubt that
could possibly arise as to the validity
of ratification by the present Tennessee general assembly, and after due
consideration of the contingencies
that might result should the doubt be
resolved against the power of the
legislature to act. In support of the
request I am sending copies of opin-
ios(sic.) by Senator Walsh and Governor
Folk. Every one with whom I have
conferred has concurred in these
opinions.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/513</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>