<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 09 c</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 09 c. Newspaper clipping: 'CROZIER-FRENCH DELEGATION Probably Will Be Seated in Nashville Convention Of the National Woman's Suffrage Association. President Shaw Refuses to Be Side-tracked by Election as President-Emeritus.'  Knoxville Journal &amp; Tribune.  November 11, 1914.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Suffrage; Meetings;</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Knoxville Journal &amp; Tribune</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>November 11, 1914</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 09</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>CROZIER-FRENCH DELEGATION
Probably  Will   Be  Seated  in
Nashville Convention
Of the National Woman's Suffrage Association.
President Shaw Refuses to Be
Side-tracke by Election as
President-Emeritus.
Special   to   The   Journal   and   Tribune.
Nashville, Tenn., Nov. 11.&#8212;-Delega-
tions of women from practically every 
state in the union arrived in Nashville 
Tuesday night and today to attend the 
annual convention of the national Amer- 
ican Woman's Suffrage association 
which convenes tomorrow morning.
The national officers  and  the  majority of the most prominent leaders in the 
movement   for  equal   suffrage   came to
the   city  Tuesday  night  and  eairy   this
morning
Many of the latter are flanked by
large forces of delegates who will stand
by their respective leaders on important
questions  and  issues that may  arise.
The first, official gathering today of
the suffragists was at eleven o'clock at
the Hermitage hotel, when the executive council held a secret session. Mrs.
Raymond Brown, president of the New
York state suffrage association, was
elected temporary chairman. The selection of a temporary chairman was a
significant matter as at this meeting of
the council the policies for the coming
convention and some of the most important questions likely to come up were
to be freely discussed, among the latter
the constitutional amendment or state's
rights   in   securing   the   ballot.
That this particular question could be
impartially discussed was evident,
as Mrs. Brown heads an association
that has declared neutrality on this issue. The council this morning took no
action on any matter, holding the session
merely that there might be discussions
so that the delegates might be better
prepared for action when the proper
time  arises.
The Hermitage hotel, where the national officers and leaders are quartered,
presents an animated scene today. The
suffrage color of yellow greets the eye
from every column and doorway and
streamers hang from doorways and
chandeliers, while large groups of suffragists throng the parlors and loggia as
they get acquainted and discuss the all-
absorbing  topic  of   "the   ballot."
The   national   officers   here   are:&#8212;Dr. 
Anna   Shaw,   the   distinguished  head   of 
the   association;     Miss     Jane   Addams
Chicago, first vice-president; Mrs. Desha
Breckinridge,   Lexington,    Ky.,    second
vice-president;   Mrs.     Caroline  Ruuty
Rees, Greenwich, Conn., third vice-president; Mrs.  Richard  Fitzgerald,  Jamaica   Plain,   Mass,     recording   secretary;
Mrs.   Stanley  McCormick,    New  York
and Chicago,     treasurer;    Mrs.   James
Lees Laidlaw,  New  York,  first  auditor
and  Mrs.  Joseph  Tilton  Bowen,  Chicago,   second  auditor.
These officers participated in the deliberations of the executive council,
which met at the Hermitage hotel at
eleven   o'clock.
Hope For Peace.
Suffrage, leaders say peace between
the parent body and the congressional
union was foreshadowed by action late
tonight by a general caucus of association leaders, when a compromise slate
of officers for the association was made.
This slate is predicated upon the willingness of Dr. Anna Howard Shaw to
accept the position of president emeritus,
a new place in the organization, and
places Mrs. Desha Breckenridge, of
Lexington, Ky., at the head as president.
Dr. Shaw announced her unwillingness to accept the position of president
emeritus, immediately after the meeting.
The caucus was not called by any officer of the association and for that reason its deliberations are characterized
as "irregular" by friends of Dr. Shaw.
It was held in the Hotel Hermitage and
presided over by Mrs. Gertrude Leonard, of Boston, pronounced in her leanings to the doctrines of the congressional
union.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/306</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>