<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 19 f.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 19 f. Newspaper clipping: Equal Suffrage League Members To Meet.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's suffrage;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 19</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>EQUAL SUFFRAGE LEAGUE
MEMBERS TO MEET 

Mrs.  L.  C.  French, president of the
Knoxville Equal Suffrage league will be
at home this afternoon from 2:30 to four
four o'clock, when members of the
league and friends are invited for informal discussion of the live questions of
the day, which will he led by Mr. Collier, formerly of Memphis, speaking on
"The  Future of Democracy."
The meetings of the league are monthly, and the next regular meeting will
not be held until Saturday, February
25th.
In order that members who have more
time to give to a study of the questions
with which the league is concerned may
do so, the home of the president is to
be thrown open informally every Saturday afternoon. Mrs. French will either
lead the discussions or invite some person well informed to do so, and the
presence of Mr. Collier at this afternoon's meeting promises unusual interest. Mr. Collier is one of the best informed young men in the state and is
well known to most of her citizens. He
has lived for a number of years in New
York, which city is at present his home.
At the regular meeting last Saturday
afternoon, there was a general and spirited discussion on the need of good government
 along the  lines of birth registration,
 child labor and compulsory education.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/394</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>