<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 25 d.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 25 d. Newspaper clipping: SUFFRAGE LEADERS ANTICIPATE NO TROUBLE. Tennessee Women Express Faith In Present Legislature.  Chattanooga News.  June 25, 1920.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's suffrage;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>June 25, 1920</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 25</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>SUFFRAGE LEADERS
ANTICIPATED TROUBLE
Tennessee    Women    Express
Faith in Present Legislature.
Prominent women from different sections of the state express their faith in
the called session of the legislature to
make Tennessee the thirty-sixth state
to ratify the Susan B. Anthony amend-
ment to the federal Constitution.
Mrs. Leslie Warner, of Nashville;
Mrs. L. Crozier French, of Knoxville,
and Mrs. Isaac Reese of Memphis, all
pioneers in Tennessee suffrage and
earnest workers in the cause for broad-
ening the field of woman's activities,
anticipate no trouble in the passage of
the Nineteenth amendment by the Tennessee   legislature.
In communications to The News they
express themselves in the following
manner:
"Nashville,   Tenn.
"I anticipate no trouble having the,
amendment ratified by this legislature
at called session. This legislature generously gave all our benighted constitution allowed. I believe the men are
as anxious to give us the vote as we
to have it. We could never have won
with a different legislature.
(Signed) "MRS. LESLIE WARNER."
"Knoxville, Tenn,
"Without   doubt,   the   Tennessee   leg- 
islature in special session will not forego   the   splendid   opportunity   to  be   the
thirty-sixth   state  to  ratify  the   federal
suffrage amendment.
"Tennessee  is   not  so  strictly   a  one-
party   state   that   it   has   ceased   to be
progressive.     Our  republicans  keep  our
democrats  awake   to opportunities.
(Signed)    "L.    CROZIER   FRENCH."
"Memphis, Tenn.
"It seems to me that the legislature
would gladly seize the occasion, if allowed by the governor, of making Tennessee the thirty-sixth state to ratify
the Susan B. Anthony federal amendment, not only because there is an
overwhelming sentiment for woman
suffrage in the state, but it offers the
democratic party a wonderful opportunity to poll a large woman's vote in
the doubtful states of the union, for
the women are anxiously waiting to see
which party will be most active in giving them their freedom.        </dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/424</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>