<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 29 e.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 29 e. Newspaper clipping:  Pinchot Praises Woman Viewpoint.  When Human Welfare is Considered, Woman Suffrage Becomes Certainty, He Says.  The Woman's Journal.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's suffrage;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>Unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 29</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>PiNCHOT PRAISES
 WOMAN VIEWPOINT
When Human Welfare is Con- 
idered, Woman Suffrage
Becomes Certainty, He Says.
Clifford Pinchot has come out strongly
for  woman  suffrage,  and  on  somewhat 
novel grounds.    He writes in  the Penn-
sylvania Suffrage News:--
"To my mind the distinguishing fact 
in the menial attitude of our time is the 
relatively tremendous weight we say on 
general human welfare.    This disposition 
to accept the health, happiness, and suc- 
cess of men and women in the mass as 
the criterion and  touchstone of  civilization is comparatively new.    It seems to
me  well  within   the  bounds  of truth  to 
say that it has made more progress with- 
in  the United States in  the last twelve 
months   than   in   the.   twelve   proceeding
years,  and the advance  in  the next  de- 
cade bids  fair  to  be only   less striking.
 "The moment    the    effective political 
units  in  any    commonwealth     begin   to 
measure national success by human wel-
fare,  not  merely  as an intellectual  pro- 
position but as a practical basis for con- 
crete    action,    that   moment    the    equal
participation   of   women   in   government 
becomes  a.  certainty.     The     reason   is 
simple.     Women     as  a    whole  have   a 
larger stake in human welfare than men 
for   they  are   the   mothers.     They   bear
the heavier share of the burden.  Their 
lives and  their   rights  are  more  sacred
than those of men.
"Women and children first is no mean-
inless [sic.]   phrase,    and   represents    no    accidental custom.    It rests on the obvious
truth that the future is more important 
to the race  than the present,  and  that 
in   times  of peril  those who   prepare  or
embody the future are best worth saving.
"Equal suffrage is coming, as it ought
to come, for the good and sufficient reason  that the welfare or the race and to
its future,  the work and point of view
of  the   women   is
more   important   than
the work and point of view of the
men?"'  --The Woman's Journal.
</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/445</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>