<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 10 d</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 10 d. Newspaper clipping: 'To Arrange For State Suffrage Convention, Made by Local League.' Oct. 4.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's suffrage; Meetings; Organizations;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>October 4 (no year)</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 10</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>To Arrange For State Suffrage
Convention, Made by Local
League.       
The October meeting of the Knoxville
Equal Suffrage league was held Saturday afternoon at the board of commerce.
Mrs. L. C. French, state president, also
president of the local league, conducted
the meeting, which was very largely attended.
The afternoon was devoted to plans
for the Tennessee suffrage convention,
which will be in session in this city
October 28, 29 and 30. The sessions of
the convention will be held in the Lyceum building. The following committees were appointed:&#8212;
Miss Ada Fanz, general chairman of
the committee on arrangements.
Reception Committee&#8212;Miss Lucy
Crozier, chairman.
Homes Committee&#8212;Mrs. Emma
Fanz Price.
Ways and Means&#8212;Miss Sarah Rutherford.
Entertainment. Fund and Information
&#8212;Mrs. Margaret Mann Carson.
Advertising&#8212;Mrs. Marion King Pur-
nell.
Press&#8212;Mrs.  Annie Booth McKinney.
Chairman for subscription to suffrage
publications&#8212;Miss Delia Yoe and Miss Cora   Rule.
 Decorations  and     Badges&#8212;Mrs.   Joel
Tyer.
Luncheon Committee&#8212;Mrs. Sue Barton.
In charge of the benefit card party
&#8212;Mesdames L. C. French, J. H. Anderson, G. W. Denney and R. P. Oppen
himer.
There has been some discussion re
cently as to the legality of Mrs. French's
election to the office of state president, and at the meeting Saturday the
local league passed resolutions endorsing Mrs. French's action at the time
of her election, and declaring her to
be legally the president of the state association.
A called meeting of the league will be
held about the middle of the month, to
further perfect plans for the convention.
</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/315</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>