<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 08 d</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 08 d. Newspaper clipping: 'Gives Advice As To Movies.'  February 10, 1922.  New York Times.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Motion pictures; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women;</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>New York Times</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>February 10, 1922</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 08</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>GIVES ADVICE
AS TO MOVIES
Ignore the Bad Ones, Says
Lecturer at Tivoli.  Mrs. Speed Talks About Better
Films-Co-Operative Committee to Be Formed.
Mrs. Phillip Speed, of the national
committee for better films, of New
York, lectured at the Tivoli theater-
yesterday morning, under the auspices
of the welfare department of Kosmos,
on the subject of "Better Films."
"Better films committees are increasing throughout the south, and their influence is already felt in those communities in which they are firmly established," said Mrs. Speed," and within
the next few  weeks  probably  all  the largest cities in the southern states
will have committees of men and
women actively engaged in the interest
of better films, working in co-operation with all agencies for the sole purpose of promoting the production and
exhibition of better films.
"One of the principal achievements
of these committees you already have
here-and there are but 60O cities in
all the United States who have them--
is your Saturday morning matinees for
the boys and girls, which give clean,
wholesome but none the less fascinating, delightful entertainments for the
children. Parents may send their sons
and daughters to see these programs
without fear that there may be objectionable features.     To   be  sure,   it  is
often said that adolescent boys and
girls very strenuously object to pictures
that are for children alone, but this is
the result of too many highly-seasoned
menus, and will in time be overcome.
"There are three audiences always to
consider-the children, the adolescent
boy and girl, and the adults. There
are also divisions of the latter class,
the ignorant, the average and the above
the average, or the very highest class
of patron. The latter was primarily
the basis of the national board of reviews being formed. Pictures that
were condemned at once by what in
common parlance are known as "high
brows" were not at all harmful, according to the viewpoint of the average
people, and one incident after the other
occurred in clashes between the two
factions. At length, in desperation,
and through the advice of the People's
Institute of New York, which is a
clearing house of invaluable information regarding people and things, a
happy medium was reached in the
forming   of  the  national  board  of  reviews. The   board   is   composed   of  
broad, liberal-minded men and women,
who give due consideration to every
point before rendering a decision. This
board has been of untold value to exhibitors.
of Kosmos. 
"The better film committees  obtain
best results not by knocking a picture,
but by telling of the best points in it.
To knock it is to advertise it in the
best  possible  way.    Exhibitors  would
all rather be praised than abused, and
would far rather show clean pictures.
However,  the  great majority  is their
best patron,  and to that patron they
 have  to  cater if they    support   their
houses.    Therefore,  we must work to
 the  end in view, the general support
of the public of better films.    To that
end we  must work most assiduously.
The music clubs have here a.splendid
field for their work by looking out for
the music that is heard on these occasions.    A   band   of   truth,   of  beauty,
may   be   placed   around    the    world
through the right sort of pictures, and
it may be shown by the light of the
torch  of  education  that is  carried in
the   hands   of   the    states.    Through
school and church the knowledge may
be diffused by  the pictures of educational   films;   there    are    geographical
films&#8212;films of centrifugal nature that
will, in  a few  minutes teach the boy
and    girl    more    about    the    ethereal
bodies that are swinging round us into
space,  more  of  the  worlds   that    are
fixed  or  movable  planets   than  could
be   taught  them  in  a  whole  term  of
plain old-fashioned teaching.
 "Tuberculosis films have gone far
on the road as successful missionaries
of   health   and   hygiene,    and    every branch  of science  has  done its  share
 in later years, a far bigger and better share than ever before because of
moving pictures.
"The family  group is the best medium  for better films.    Strange as it
may seem,  unless a picture   is   high-
priced,   parents  do  not    minutely   inquire as  to  the how  and why  of  it.
Let  a  picture  be priced  away above
the average,  and before parents give
the money  for it to  the boy   or girl,
they  will   find   out  a  little  about   the
nature of it.    Some very beautiful les-
sons may  be learned  from  pictures&#8212;
but   other   things   may   be,   and   are,
learned  from  the  wrong kind  of  pictures.    Form   your  better   films   committees,  and  be  sure to   make   them
broad,   have  one  member  from  every
organization in  your city, church and
school  included,   especially    from    the
Parent-Teacher  associations. Make no
mistake   here,   for   there   must   be   no
narrow  minds  on  the  subject.    Three
out of six pictures shown may be good
ones.    Boost  the  three,    but   let   the
ones  that  are not    good   remain    unmolested.    This is far the better way.
Every one  cannot  like the same  picture- point out the best you can find
in all."
There was a very good attendance
at the lecture, and at its close there
was a strong indorsement of what
Mrs. Speed represented. During her
visit through the state, she has organized many committees, and experts
to continue the work, but always
along the broad lines of the board of
national review. Mrs. Speed left last
night for Virginia, but returns to East
Tennessee in a week's time. The
formation of a better film committee
is to be effected at once. All interested in the work of the committee
are requested to communicate with
Mrs. M. N. Whitaker, president of
Kosmos, or Mrs. Harry Wise, chairman,   or  Mrs.   D.   F.   Beckham,  vice-chairman of the   welfare   department
of Kosmos. </dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/276</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>