<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 03 d</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 03 d. Newspaper clipping: 'Concerning Remark Said to Have Been Made by University Professor in Lecture." (Probably refers to Professor A.A. Schaeffer, 1916).</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Scrapbooks; Clippings;</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>L. Crozier-French</dc:creator>
<dc:date>[1916]</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 03</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>Concerning    Remark   Said   to
Have Been Made by University Professor in Lecture.
It is here stated that Mrs. French
wrote an article complimenting the professor's lecture and here it is implied
that three years later she, with others,
made charges so enormous against him as
to be unbelievable.
I have read in the paper the report
of the lecture. There is no name signed
I have no recollection of having written
it and I do not think it is my style.
But let that pass. I objected at the
time of the lecture so much to some
opinions expressed that I stopped the
speaker and asked him a question with
the hope of hinting to him that he was
speaking imprudently. He did not take
the hint. Immediately on the close of
his lecture I went up to him and tried
to show him my disapproval of a part
of  his  conclusions.
A verdict has been rendered against
myself and several other ladies by a
committee&#8212;a verdict which by insinuation and implication reflects upon our
veracity and our having sympathy for
a  fellow-being.
I propose to write to the gentlemen of
this committee informing them that all
the facts of the case against these ladies
and myself were not laid before them
and that I demand a rehearing and that
we be faced with those who furnished
the material upon which the committee
based their report, which did us such injustice.
L. CROZIER-FRENCH.
</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/170</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>