<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook,  p. 11 a</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 11 a. Newspaper clipping: 'National Suffrage Parade Will Be Remarkable Demonstration.'  February 2, 1913.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's rights; Parades &amp; processions;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>February 2, 1913</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 11</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>National Suffrage Parade, Will
Be Remarkable Demonstration
Preparations are proceeding apace for
the  national  suffrage     parade    to  take
place in Washington on March 3, the
day before President Wilson's inauguration.
There have beeen many equal suffrage demonstrations in America, but
this will probably excel all others in
size, significance and picturesque features. Early in January, the national
association opened headquarters on "F"
street, less than a block from the treasury, and manned its offices, with a competent force, under the direction of Miss
Alice Paul, chairman of the congres-
sional committee, which committee is
working in conjunction with a com-
mittee from the various societies of the District of Columbia.  The informal opening
of these quarters was the occasion
 of an enthusiastic house warming
when   photographers,  reporters and
writers,  to   say   nothing   of the public
in  general,  flocked   to  the  scene
and   hundreds  seeking     admission   were
turned away for want of room.
This parade has been a chief, topic
interest in Washington lately, because of
the agitation   precipitated   by  the   wom-
en's request   for   permission   to   march over
the  route  followed   by   all processions
sincethe days of Jefferson.    The chief of
 police advised the women to be content
with  a   side  street.     This  sug-
gestion was declined with thanks, where-
upon a lively    discussion    between     the women
and   various   high   officials   followed.
The Washington Press took up
the   matter   and in
spirited   editorials, advocated  justice to
the women.    Presi-
dent Taft also put in a good word for
them by saying they have as much right
to the route in question as the men, and
various senators and congressmen took
a divided stand in the matter. The result was a permit for full possession of
tins historic highway from 2 p.m. to
6 p. m.  on  March 3rd.
The  line of  march, therefore,  will be
from   the Peace  monument  at  the foot
of  the  capitol,  to  the white house
on  to Continental  Memorial hail, where a 
rally   will  he held.     Through the influence
of Senator Bacon and   Speaker Champ Clark, permission has been se-
cured for  the use  of   the Plaza, facing (missing) monument, and the steps of the Treasury building, for the formation and  (missing) tableaux that are to be presented-- (missing)
the way, 
will   be   a (missing)
from     the  clouds of a    "winged (missing),"
presumably from Mars, bearing a 
message to ''Miss Columbia," the cen-(missing)
figure of a scene that will be staged [on] the
steps of the treasury department.
Needless to say, an aviatress, Miss Beretta  
Miller, and her machine, will be the 
agents  in tins mysterious  visitation.
The management of  Has pageant   has
been placed  in the  hands  of profession-
als Mrs. Glenna Tinnin and Miss 
Hazel  (missing)
who  are well    known  organ- (missing)
...raiiners..    It  is their  purpose (missing)
is pageant tell,  in the living (missing)
 symbolism, the  whole   dra-(missing)
of woman's progress through (missing)
from   primeval   times   to   her (missing)
[s]tatus in  all civilized   countries (missing)
[w]orld,    The costumes of the ac- (missing)
be copied from mediaeval mod- (missing)
the marshals, horsewomen, her- (missing)
[an]d  standard  bearers  will  all   ap- (missing)
in   traditional   dress.     Miss   Inez
(missing) -and,  in     the     picturesque  equip- (missing)
of a  herald  of ancient  days  will
[lead]  the   procession, followed by troops (missing)
horsewomen, musicians, and the vari-(missing)
 groups and floats  that  are  to form (missing)
pageant.
(missing)ll professions,  trades  and  crafts  in
[which] women engage,  will  be portrayed (missing)
symbolic dress and other devices.  A (missing)an 
and   a   woman   standing  side   by [si]de   and   hand   in   hand   will   represent
the equal  suffrage states, and these actors  will  all  occupy   a  large car   appro-
priateliy   decorated.      Marching   on   fo(missing)
and making a circle about this car, w[ill]
be the  "lone  lorn  women"  of  the non
suffrage states, each woman bound and
handicapped by the chains   of some obsolete  social custom or unjust law.    The
motif of the whole scheme, of course, is
"Votes   for   Women,"   and -wherever   it
is possible to pin  an argument,  point a
moral, or proclaim a sermon, there they
will be pinned,  pointed  and proclaimed,
[wi]th  the hope that they will carry con-(missing)
tion to the
multitudes  that,  shall  as-
[semble] in Washington during inaugural
week. In short, this pageant is to be in the
[na]ture of a new crusade,  combining much of 
the color, fervor and dramatic interest
of the  old  order  with   the   tri-
umphal  enblems  of  justice,  truth   and
progress, vhich belong, to the new order.     </dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/312</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>