<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 25 a.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 25 a. Newspaper clipping: Knoxville Women Are Elated at Ratification of Suffrage; 'Red Letter Day' for America.  Knoxville Sentinel.  August 18, 1920.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's suffrage;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>August 18, 1920</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 25</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>KNOXVILLE WOMEN ARE ELATED
AT RATIFICATION OF SUFFRAGE
'RED LETTER DAY' FOR AMERICA
    **
Expressions of Gratification From Many Throughout City When
Informed by The Sentinel of Action of Legislature&#8212;Had Felt
Disappointed Last Night After Defeat In North Carolina Senate&#8212;
Praise Sons of Tennessee Who Have Given Women the Privilege of Casting Ballot. 
Hurrah!
Women have won their fight!
Hats off to Tennessee scions who
have made this the "Perfect Thirty-
Sixth State" and granted women of
America the right to vote and participate in the government of the country!
These expressions of rejoicing were
voiced by Knoxville women when informed by The Knoxville Sentinel
this afternoon that suffrage had been
ratified by the legislature, although
a reconsideration of the  action of
today is suggested as likely to be proposed.
Enthusiasm and exultation over the
victory was all the greater, because
many suffrage leaders had despaired
of a victory after announcement from
North Carolina last night that the
senate there had defeated the movement.
Announcement of the triumph came
generally as a surprise to Knoxville
women. Many who had not given up
hope had thought action on the question might be postponed and the
emancipation of women delayed.
All agreed that it means the dawn
of a new day for America and the
world. 
MRS. SARAH HENRY HOOD&#8212;
"I'm perfectly delighted. I haven't
had anything to make me so happy
in years. The passage of this ratification measure means that Tennessee
again has the proud distinction, as
at King's Mountain, of turning the
tide of battle to a victorious conclusion of American independence."
MISS ADA FANZ&#8212;"I'm just glad
that it has come about. That is all
that I can say, but I certainly am
glad that it has gone through at
last. I have been out of active suffrage work for several years, but I
rejoice over the victory just the
same."
MRS. R. E. L. MOUNTCASTLE&#8212;
"Good! Grand! You don't mean it.
Tennessee is in line with its past record of being the original volunteer
state. She came into the union under difficulties. She saved the day
for American independence at King's
Mountain. She was the last state to
secede from the Union at the time of
the civil war. She was the first state
to be re-instated. The uniqueness
of the position of Tennessee in history
has become even more apparent after
this last victory in which it turned
the tide for the independence of Amer-
ican women. I personally am more
than grateful to the members of the
legislature who voted for the amendment, and I feel that the suffrage
workers both democratic and republican, should be most thankful for the
favors received from both parties.
The women have fought actively on
all occasion for suffrage, and have
been awake to their every responsibility."
MRS. H. G. MILNOR- "Who?
What did you say? Who did? What?
Ratified? Well&#8212;!!! You don't mean
it? I'm so glad you told me. Was
there a margin of only three votes?
Well! I wonder if Mrs. L. C. French
knows it yet? Don't you reckon
Nashville is wild? I'd sure like to see
that Mr. Seth Walker. I think that
I'll send Mrs. George F. Milton, of
Chattanooga, a telegram of congratulations. New I wonder what the
legislators will give us trouble about
"twill be something, but now that we
have the amendment, we don't care
what it is."
MRS. WALTER BARTON&#8212;"I
think women's sphere is in the home,
and for that reason I have never approved of woman suffrage."
MRS. H. J. KELSO&#8212;"Oh, that is
fine! I am just delighted. Last
night things looked so gloomy that
I had about given it up, but this
morning&#8212;!"
MRS. C. E. Lucky&#8212;"I was so hopeless last night. And it has really
gone through? The only thing that
half expresses it it 'praise the Lord!'
I feel that I am ready now to go to
my grave. I can't express my feelings about this very well. It has
been the work of a life time and it
has brought its reward at last. I am
proud of the men of Tennessee who
have seen their  duty at last."
MISS KATE WHITE, state chair-
man of the research work of the
suffrage movement&#8212;"I am delighted.
This is one of the greatest things for
Tennessee. We women pay taxes,
but are allowed no representation, and
the vote of the women will make a
difference  in  every  election."
MRS. GEORGE F. MELLEN.&#8212;
"This is the concluding part of a
democratic movement started in the
nineteenth century, for the liberation
of all people.    I am glad of this."
MISS MARGARET AMBROSE.&#8212;
"No news could please me better. I
am delighted. We are pleased that
Tennessee showed her colors on this
matter, and we are not ashamed of
Tennessee."
MRS. L. C. FRENCH.&#8212;"Isn't that
great? That's fine! We'll have to
give a big victory celebration the
first Wednesday in September when
the Non-Partisan league meets. I'm
rejoiced, of course, but the only thing
that I can't understand is why those
men in Nashville wanted to delay so
long."
MRS. DON P. TRENT&#8212;"And they
have really ratified? Well isn't that
fine! That is splendid! It is a compliment to Tennessee that it should have
had the opportunity of casting the deciding vote. I am proud that the honor
of completing the ratification program
came to Tennessee. Every woman
should be very happy over the result
of the fight at Nashville."
MRS. N. E. LOGAN&#8212;"Isn't it wonderful? I have just heard it and it
seems too good to be true. Every hope
seemed to be lost last night, and now
here comes the victory! I feel that
women can hold up their heads now and
act like- real people."
MISS LOUISE BIGNALL&#8212;"What!
What again! So we got it? What was
the majority? Well, even if it wasn't a
big majority we got it. How we did
it and by what majority doesn't make
any difference."
MISS JENNIE IRWIN.&#8212;-"Is that
so! Well that is just fine. I just
think that is great, I think everything
of it. Hurrah for the legislature. 1
can't think of anything good enough
to say.'
MRS. H. E. CHRISTENBERRY&#8212;"I
shall send a telegram to Mrs. Annie
Cottrell Waver and Mrs. Ethel King,
who are in Nashville in the interests of
suffrage. The telegram reads: 'Congratulations. Express our regards to
the legislators.! "
MRS. T. P. MILLER&#8212;"Is it really
true? Has the house really passed the
ratification resolution? Really? Truly?
It seems difficult to believe, after the
claims of the antis yesterday and last
night, and after the rebuffs our suffrage workers have had. And yet how
glorious! What a wonderful victory!
How it will bring glory to dear old Ten-
nessee! I am incapable of expressing
my great gratitude to the splendid men
'in the legislature whose support and
votes have made possible this wonderful victory! It means the dawn of a
better day for America and for the
world, that women are to have the ballot and thereby, exercise, a control, and
an authority in the politics of the na-
tlon. How happy suffragists should be
today!"
MRS. SOPHIE HUNTER&#8212;"Oh, isn't
it awful. Just think that we women
will have to go to the polls and take
part in your old politics. I regret the
action of the legislature. Women
should stay at home instead of having
the vote. But I suppose it is all right,
as we are ein the march of what some
call "progress." 
MRS. J. L. MORGAN&#8212;"Well, I hope
those women who have sought the vote
will be happy. I have been content to
leave the voting to the men. However,
now that the women have the vote, I
hope the results will be for the great
good of the nation."
MRS. J. MARION MILLER&#8212;"Has
suffrage really passed? All right. No,
I have nothing to say. We'll really go
to work now, won't we? We'll get busy
and see what we can do.",
MISS HASSIE GRESHAM&#8212;"It is
simply a working out of justice. Sometimes it takes a long time for justice
to be obtained, but sooner or later it
will come. I am very highly delighted."
MRS. WALTER STARNES NASH&#8212;
"I think the eyes of all America were
on Tennessee, and now that the legislature has actually ratified the amend-
ment the women from all over the country will feel grateful to those who put
ratification through."
MISS ELIZABETH TURNER&#8212;"That
is certainly fine. I thought Tennessee
would not fail her women when the
chance came to give them the vote. I
am so glad."
MRS. EMMA RICE&#8212;"Well, that is
fine. I think that is the greatest thing
Tennessee has done in many years,
greatest thing for the women of the
state and the women of the nation. I
any difference."
 This union likewise secured the es-
tablishment of the county   industrial
school, this also being the first insti-   
tution of the   sort in the south.    
Not until 1910 was the suffrage as- 
sociation formed. This was the second 
in the state of Tennessee, the (missing) the 
first being the state organization or(missing)

 May Celebrate Victory.
Plans  are  now being made  for    the
celebration in Knoxville of the victory. This will take place either at the regular
 meeting    of    the     Non-Partisan League, due the first Wednesday in September, or at an earlier date. All
the men and women prominent in advancing the cause will be given a (missing)</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/421</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>