<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 45 e</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 45 e. Newspaper clipping: Equal Suffrage Department.  Want To Reach Goal of 8,000.  Knoxville Journal &amp; Tribune.  August 27, 1919.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's suffrage; Voter registration;</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Knoxville Journal &amp; Tribune</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>August 27, 1919</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook p. 45</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>Equal Suffrage Department.
WANT TO REACH
GOAL OF 8,000
Women Prepare For Supplemental Registration.
League    Will    Hold    Meeting
Thursday Afternoon&#8212;Mrs.
Miller Makes an Appeal.
******************
* *
* WOMEN  ARE  CALLED *
*  *
* Mrs. Thomas    Peacock    Miller, *
* chairman of the Non-Partisan polit- 
* ical league, has called a meeting *
 * of all ward chairmen and mem- *
 * bers of the league to take place at *
 * Board of Commerce rooms Thurs- *
 * day afternoon at 4 o'clock. Plans *
 * for the supplemental registration *
 * will be discussed. They will also *
 * explain in detail "how to vote." *
 * A full attendence is requested.        *
* *
******************
"Let's all pull together, for many
things will come up in the next two
years and we will all want a voice in
it," says Mrs. Thomas Peacock Miller,
chairman   of  the   Non-Partisan  league
"Thursday, Friday and Saturday are
the days set aside for the supplemental
registration and I do hope Knoxville
women will go way over the top and
make at the very least an 8,000 registration,"  Mrs.  Miller  says.
"Many women who have been out of
the city have phoned me regarding this
registration. In the supplemental registration one cannot vote in the primary but one can vote in the general
election and I want all the women who
were undecided and all the women
whose husbands objected to them registering to put on  their thinking caps
and their persuasive caps and take advantage of their opportunity to register
in this supplemental registration. Think
of the power and the opportunity of
the 6,831 who have prepared to exercise their franchise! Personally I really
do not see how anybody can hang back.
It seems to me all the women would
really have the interest of their town
so in mind and in heart that they would
feel compelled to raise their voices for
the advancement of the principles for
which women stand.
"Let's all pull together&#8212;for many
things will come up in the next two
 years&#8212;and we will all want a voice in
 it. It's your city and it's mine&#8212;and
now that the legislature and the supreme court have put this responsibil-
itiy upon us whether we ever craved
the responsibility or not, it is here, and
it has given the women a wonderful
power and we want to use it wisely and
well. I have spoken before of the excellent work of the ward chairmen in
the splendid registration of women in
Knoxville.
"There are two other groups to whom
a great deal of credit of the registration is largely due. The nurses of
Knoxville and the central federation of
labor. The nurses, many of whom belong to the Non-Partisan league, have
been so busy with their profession that,
it was impossible for them to attend
meetings but have been so wonderfully enthusiastic that in the homes where
they were nursing they have been able
to convert many, many women and really make them see their responsibility.
It is surprising how many women
have been able to see the light through
the eyes of the trained nurses of Knoxville.
"The Central Labor union pledged its
support to the Non-Partisan ieague in
promising to do all it coaid to see that
the wives, mothers, sisters, daughters
and sweethearts registered. It has kept
its pledges, for many interesting tales
are told by the men in urging reluctant
women to register. The women in the
fai(missing)es of labor have measured up exceedingly well and we feel it is due to
the men.
"Just let me repeat, let's all pull together for an 8,000 registration for
Knoxville women. We can do it Thursday, Friday and Saturday of this week.
It's an easy thing to do and in the
coming two years let no woman say, 'Oh,
I wish I had registered. I can't vote
or do a thing about this, that or the
other.' Let there be no regrets. Do
your civic duty and register without
fail."</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/517</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>