<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 37d</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 37 d. Newspaper clipping: Chattanooga Leagues Take Separate Paths.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's suffrage;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>Unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook p. 37</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>Chattanooga Leagues
Take Separate Paths.
While the Chattanooga Equal Suffrage association took the stand against
Mrs. French, the Chattanooga Equal
Rights league rallied to her support, and
for their good behavior were rewarded
with credentials to a seat in thf national
convention. Mrs. W. N. Case so far is
the only delegate from Chattanooga to
the big meeting at Nashville next week
who is armed and equipped for war.
Like a German passport, Mrs. Case's
credentials are signed and countersigned
by the powers that were, and she is
fully prepared to have a voice in the discussion that is to come up when the recent disturbances are aired.
Which organization or faction will the
national convention recognize is the
problem that is besetting the minds of
the suffragists and the suffragettes&#8212;the
latter the insurgents. Miss Ervin says
it's utterly impossible for the main organization not to recognize Mrs. McCormick's side, while Mrs. Case is equally
sure that Mrs. L. Crozier French will
come out the winner.
Mrs. Case hinted that the whole trouble started over the national convention
meeting place, and says that body is responsible because they should have designated what city should have this
honor. Mrs. Case said she favored
Nashville because she was afraid Chattanooga could not creditably handle so
large a body of distinguished women.
It appears that recently offers of
reconciliation have been made to the
Chattanooga Equal Rights league by the (missing)</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/487</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>