<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 18 f.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 18 f. Newspaper clipping: Woman Suffrage.  Dr. Broughton's sermon on "Paul and the Women." Ca. 1912.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's suffrage;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>ca. 1912</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 18</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>WOMAN SUFFRAGE
Some weeks since, Dr. Broughton
preached on "Paul and the Women," and
particularly with reference to votes for
women. I heard the sermon referred to,
and enjoyed its beautiful language, always
chaste and above criticism. Its rheotric (sic.)
was without fault; its rounded periods
were so arranged as to form one splendid
gem of literature. But its logic was very
disappointing to me. I went to hear the sermon for the purpose of getting a good
logical, working reason why women should
not be allowed to vote. The text I. Cor.
11-3, "But I would have you know that
the head of every man is Christ, and that
the head of the woman is the man, and
the head of Christ is God." This may&#8212;I
say it: may&#8212;refer to domestic relations in
the mind of the writer. I do not pretend
to enter Dr. Broughton's own domain and
interpret the apostle for him, but I wonder why he did not take for his text I.
(Cor. 14, 4-35,'"Let your women keep silence in the churches; for it is not permitted unto them to speak; but they
are commanded to be under obedience as
also saith the law. And if they will learn
anything, let them ask their husbands at
home, for it is a shame for women to
speak  in  the  church."
This certainly is one step removed from
The home, and the prohibition here is
plain and positive, yet a literal application of this would not be allowed in the
doctor's own church. In I. Cor. 11 immediately following the text, the writer
goes into a detailed uncovered head,&#8212;
certainly a non-essential as applied to the
customs of today. In verses eleven and
twelve, he seems to get away from the
petty controversies of that church and de-
clares a broad equality of man and woman, each essential and equal to the other.
In   Paul's   day,   the   science   of   government was but little developed.    Democracy
was   not   known   to   Paul,   though   perhaps
the  freedom  of    the  individual  had    been
dreamed  of  by  some  of   the   Grecian  and
Roman   statesmen.     In   Paul's     day     the
man's  relation  to  the government  was  to
pay   his   tax  and   be   silent   about   the   administration of public affairs.    He nowhere
referred   to  any   participation   of   his   own
in   affairs   of   state.     There   is   no   "tally  sheet" to show that he ever voted.    Since
he   took   no   part   in   governmental   affairs
except   to   declare   that   "the   powers   that
be are ordained of God," we could hardly
presume,  though he was inspired, that his
writings  could  have  any  relation  or  bearing  upon  political  matters,   except from  a
standpoint   of  general   morals.     We  might
as   well   say   he  forbade   a   high   tariff   or
the  German  submarine  warfare  as  to  say
 he forbade woman suffrage.    But it would
 seem in harmony with Paul's logic In spir-
itual   teaching  for  him    to  declare  in  the
 light   of  present  day   events  that  if    the
 woman is held to be amenable to the law
 In  its  civil  and  criminal  application,     she
 should  have  a  voice  in   making  that law.
 It is as logical that  Gideon's request that
 the   sun   stand   still   until    he  fought    his
battles  proves   that   the   sun   moves   about
 the   earth   as   it   is    to   declare   that   he
 text  forbade  woman   suffrage.    

The man is amenable to the law. If he J
Is a criminal he will be deprived of his
liberty,  possibly of his life.
The   woman   is  amenable   to   the   law   in
every way and in every condition in which 
the man Is. 
The  second  reason    assigned      by      the
 preacher, that women should not vote is a
 physiological   one.   She,   not   being   able   to
 defend the issues of the ballot by physical
strength;   or,   in  other   words,   as   she   can-
not shoulder her musket and march on to
war by the side of her brother, she should
not   be   allowed   to   go   to   the   ballot   box
with  him.   If physical  strength  is  made  a
condition   of   suffrage,   it   would   certainly
give  the  prerogative  of  full  citizenship  to
some   women   and   deny   it   to   some   men.
Many  men of middle and past  middle  life
could not "defend the issues of the ballot"
with the bullet. Within the last few years,
it  is  proved  beyond, a  doubt that our  sisters can render most efficient help in time
of war. If woman cannot go to the trenches
with her brother,  she can go to the fields
and  make  bread  for  her  brother  and  she
can go to the munitions plant and prepare
the   deadly   missiles   to   be   used   in   battle
by   her   brother   of stronger   build.     It   is
agreed   that   the   average   man   has   more
avoirdupois than the average woman; that
in  a  prize fight he could probable  "knock
her  out   of   the   ring,"   out  it    does      not
logically   follow   that   on   that   account   he
should have the greater political privileges,
 or that she should yield to him her inher-
 ent right, if not accustomed right, of voice
in a democratic government. Dr. Broughton
would  not  admit  that might  makes  right,
but his "physiological" argument must lead
to   that.   I   suppose   he   would   escape   that
conclusion by taking refuge in the old claim
of   the   divine   right   of   man   to   rule, a
 principle   common   in   government   in   olden
 times   but   rejected   by   most     enlightened
Christian thinkers of today.
His third reason for opposing full citizenship   to   women   was   a   psychological   one.
His  illustrations  clearly   led   to   the  inference   that   she   is   emotional   rather     than
reasonable; that that Indefinable something
called   "Intuition"   was   the   mainspring   of
her actions rather than a careful consideration of the facts In the matter.  I understood him to teach that she was "sudden"
in  her  decisions,   and  that  these  decisions
could not be affected by an array of arguments however strong; that she would cast
her ballot under the power of "sentiment"
without reference to the consequence of her
action-  But he gave no instance  that such
had actually occurred other than the suffragette demonstrations in London and also
in   some   American   cities,   in   their   effort 
to   secure   what   they   believed  to  be   their 
constitutional political  rights. If we admit 
that  these  militant  sisters  have   shown   a
high degree of excitability, it must be admitted that many a mob of male members
has committed acts of violence to the extent of destruction of property and the taking of human life in the most brutal manner.  If she has gone too far in her disregard of the laws of propriety,  he has certainly gone to a greater length in his disregard   for   law   and   government.   If   the
preacher  would  deny  the  right  to vote  to
women because they are emotional, he sure-
ly would deny it to men when in so many
instances they have been ruled by passion.
The psychological argument fails unless he
can show, and it fails until he does show,
that she has not the mental ability to grasp
the  affairs   of  state.   It  is   here   admitted
that many  women  could   not  give  a  clear
reason why we should or should not have
a   protective   tariff,   and   it  must   also  be
admitted that a large number of men&#8212;the
majority if you please who have voted for 
years,   could   not   give   a   clear   statement 
of their position.  If one  sex Is  denied the 
right because she is ruled by sentiment in 
some Instances, the other sex should be de- 
nied  the  right  because  in  some   instances
he has been ruled by passion.
His fourth reason was that the opposed
woman suffrage because it would be detrimental to the home. In perfect frankness
 and sincerity, if I thought it would be
 detrimental to the home, I would oppose it,
too, with all my strength. I heartily agree
with the preacher that in the home she is
queen. I would emphasize it as much as
he, and all who heard him remember how
he raised his voice on that statement. His
plea for the sanctity of the home. I think 
has never been excelled in beauty or in
power by any writer or speaker of the
English language. It was a most pleasing
expression of the loftiest ideals&#8212;ideals that
can be formed only by the pure in heart
after long experience and closest communion with the Most High. As he painted his picture of what the "queen" should
be in the home circle, I suppose every husband and father was filled as I was with
the striking similarity it bore to his own
fireside. That picture is the sweetest
known to any of us. The mother's influence on the little ones can be measured
only by a standard known to the councils
of eternity. That her mission in this world
is to mother a child and to minister in
tenderness commensurate with the delicacy
of his being, to his bodily wants and to
his mental and spiritual  growth as well,</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/386</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>