<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 19 b.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 19 b. Newspaper clipping: "Contrary to God's Scheme" Dr. Len G. Broughton Speaks on Suffrage,  Pastor First Baptist Church Declares Woman Should Not Have Ballot.'  Knoxville Journal &amp; Tribune.  December 12, 1912.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Clergy; Women's suffrage;</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Knoxville Journal &amp; Tribune</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>December 12, 1912</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 19</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>"CONTRARY TO
GOD'S SCHEME"
Dr. Len G. Broughton Speaks
on Suffrage.
Pastor   First   Baptist   Church
Declares Woman Should Not
Have Ballet,
Dr. Len G. Broughton, pastor of the
First Baptist  church,   in  delivering  his
Friday night lecture in Bible study there
to   an   interdenominational  study   class, fired a broadside  at the equal suffrage
principle, which, caused more than a stir
among the  body  of  students which he
was addressing.      The speaker said that
he   knew   he  was  not  touching  a   very
popular note in taking the position which 
he  was  convinced  was   right,  but   that 
he , nevertheless believed in the truth of
the  position   because   it   was   scriptural
and  that  he  believed  suffrage   for   women  was   not   in   accordance   with   the
ideas of the Creator.
"Suffrage," said Dr. Broughton, "for
women is contrary to the whole scheme
of God. He intended that man should
stand for woman. He intended that
woman should not stand by his side in
his responsibility for anything, but that
she should be by his side for protection.
However, much this may meet with the
disapproval of the people, it is my belief that placing such a responsibility
upon woman will bring her to ruin. All
the history of the past has proven it to
be so.
"Wherever man in the past has been
given large responsibilities, he has been
given the strength with which to meet
them, such is the teaching of the Bible
from 'the earliest dawn of history, down
to the present time. God shows clearly that man should work for, plan for,
think for woman. I am opposed to it
first, because it is contrary to God's
revealed plan for the conduct of creation. Second, because it is contrary
to all historical teaching, and further
more it is contrary to all physiological
principles."
In explaining his position Dr. Broughton  said:    'I   am   enough  of   a   pacifist 
to believe that the ballot  must  be sup-
ported,  if need be by the bullet,  in or- 
der to enforce its meaning.     Outside of
any  Biblical convictions. I believe that
no   one  should  vote,   who   cannot   back
their vote with arms."
The lecture last night was on the
first book of Corinthians. The speaker
discussed it under four headings,
its introductory matter; second, its corrective criticism; third, its constructive
criticism, and finally, the closing words
of the book.
The purpose of the writings in First
Corinthians is to set forth the form
of church order not as to organization,
but as to inner life in the church, he
said. The letter sets forth the thought
that man is the head of woman, and it
was a digression on the modern application and misapplication of this principle, that caused Dr. Broughton to
speak his position on suffrage.
" Next Friday night, he will speak on
the second letter to the Corinthians.
With the close of that meeting, there
will be no further meetings either of Dr.
Broughton's class or Miss Rule's class
and the Friday evening suppers will he
discontinued until after the Christmas
holidays.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/390</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>