<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 05 j</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 05 j. Newspaper clipping: 'Smoke Nuisance To Be Curtailed.'</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Smoke; Pollution;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 05</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>SMOKE NUISANCE TO BE CURTAILED  Constitutional    League    Will
Prosecute Campaign  For
Abatement of Evil
BUY    STOCK    IN    PROJECT
Ossoli Circle Expected to Help
in Selling of Shares&#8212;Try
Device Here Soon
Solution of the smoke abatement
problem for Knoxville was guaranteed yesterday when a group of ladies
at a meeting of the Constitutional
league took ten shares of stock and
pledged themselves to raise the additional ninety shares necessary before   a   certain   type   of   smoke  con-
sumer can be introduced here. 
Within three weeks time one of the
appliances will be in operation at the
Knoxville Pure Milk company,
through the permission of its owner
and persons interested in the experiment are invited to see it.
If the consumer proves to be satisfactory it is expected that the city
will pass an ordinance compelling
factories, mills, etc. to protect the city
from smoke by installing these consumers. The city commission recently expressed its favor of such ordinance, provided a satisfactory appliance should be found, and the expense
to the mill or factory owner was not
too great.
Neal B. Spahr, assistant city attorney, represented the city yesterday at
the meeting. At its close he admitted
that the appliance as explained by Mr.
John Morton, president of the fuel
saving company which manufactures
it "looked like a good thing."
Ossoli circle, the organization which
started the movement by appearing
before the city commission, will take
up the matter further at its meeting
Monday and probably assist in disposing of the shares of stock.
The ladies were most enthusiastic
and greatly interested in getting
smoke abatement, as an aid to good
health and domestic economy. Ten
shares of stock were bought by them
within a few minutes. Ten other
shares sold yesterday to certain business men in the city further reduced the remaining number to be secured to 80.
Mr. Morton explained in detail how
the appliance is worked and quoted
figures to show that far from being a
burden in the way of expense, it actually saves coal because of the heat
which it generates.
Mr. Spahr stated that he thought
the city could force the railroad to
put smoke consumers on all switch
engines, and possibly all trains that
run through Knoxville. It was pointed out that two-thirds of the city's
smoke comes from engines.
Private homes will not be expected
to have smoke consumers, however,
Mr. Morton stated that by a careful
selection of the grade of coal burned,
much of the smoke in the residential
sections could he eliminated.
</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/192</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>