<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 14 a.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 14 a. Newspaper clipping: Tennessee Club Women To Furnish Party Home Room.  Compartment To Be Named In Honor of Mrs. L.C. French.  Knoxville Journal &amp; Tribune.  May 24, 1925.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Organizations; Clubhouses;</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Knoxville Journal &amp; Tribune</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>May 24, 1925</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 14</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>TENNESSEE CLUB WOMEN TO
FURNISH PARTY HOME ROOM
Compartment To Be Named In Honor Of
Mrs, L, C. French.
Club women of Tennessee are to
be given an opportunity to assist in
furnishing- the Tennessee room in
the newly purchased home of the
Woman's Party in Washington, D.
C. Mrs. S. L. Branch, of Knoxville,
state chairman of the Woman's
Party for Tennessee is perfecting
her organization in various parts of
the state, appointing chairmen and
delegating certain duties to differ-
ent clubs. Ossoli Circle, being the
oldest woman's club in the South,
has been given the lead in furnishing this room.
The building as described by Mrs.
Branch, who recently turned from
Washington, is beautiful. It was
purchased by Mrs. O. H. P. Belmont and given to the Woman's
Party as a national home. The
building is on Capitol Hill and was
used as the United States capitol
in 1912 when the capitol was destroyed by fire. It was from one of
the balconies of this mansion that
President Monroe gave his inaugural
address.
Mrs. Branch was told that some
states were being given the privilege of furnishing a room in this
building which could be used by
women of those states when visiting
Washington. As Tennessee was the
thirty-sixth, and the decisive, state to
ratify the nineteenth amendment to
the   constitution   granting   suffrage
to women, it was considered especially fitting that Tennessee should have
a room. Mrs. Florence Bayard Hil-
les, of Delaware, chairman of the
house furnishing committee, ap-
pointed Mrs. Branch as state chairman for Tennessee.
On suggestion of Miss Sue White
of Jackson, Tenn., it has been decided to dedicate the Tennessee
room to Mrs. L. C. French because
of her work in the interest of
women.
Every efort (sic.) will be made, according to Mrs. Branch, to secure furniture of colonial design and authentic
history. The history of each piece
will be written on a placard and
placed near so that visitors can
read it at a glance. In addition to
the history of the gift the placard
will bear the name of the donor.
As it now stands the room requires much preliminary work before it is in condition for furniture.
It will be necessary to scrape paint
and repaper walls, work that is estimated to cost about $200. The woodwork is said to be unusually beautiful, being of an inlaid design of
mahogany, bird's eye maple, and
walnut.
Ossoli Circle is to appoint a committee in the near future to solicit
contributions for both money and
furniture throughout East Tennessee.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/325</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>