<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 33 e</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 33 e. Newspaper clipping: The National Woman's Party.  [1917].</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's suffrage;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>[1917]</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook p. 33</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>THE NATIONAL
WOMAN'S PARTY
Several months after the inauguration
of President Wilson there was organized
in Washington city, "The Congressional
Union," by Misses Paul and Burns. The
object of this union was to procure the
passage of an amendment to the federal
constitution looking to the enfranchisement of all citizens of the United States
regardless of sex. These young women
and many beside recognized that by
state enactment alone the women of the
whole United States would not be allowed to vote for a hundred years or
more. They therefore determined to besiege the national fortress which was
controlled iby the democratic party as to
 the executive as well as both houses of
congress. The siege continued during
the first term of President Wilson's administration, the besiegers being forced
Ito the conclusion that the executive alone
was responsible for the refusal of the
fortress to surrender.  The Congressional Union sent out a
call to the women of the west who had
votes to come to the aid  their eastern
 and southern sisters.
This call met with a generous response
 and a woman's party was organized by
the women voters to work in unison with the Congressional Union for the passage of the federal amendment.  Less than a year has passed but the wisdom of the organization of the woman's party has become so evident that it was decided to merge the Congression___ __________________ it, which was done during ___________________ of both in Washington _________________________________  March.
You surely will feel ashamed to accept your freedom at the hands of women to whom you have given no help at all.  As state chairman it is my duty to appoint a chariman of each congressinal district, who will help me do this by sending in the names of those women who will make good chairmen? It will then be the duty of each congressional chairman to appoint a chairman of each county in her district.  Will not those who read this help along the good work by sending in names of a number of women at each county seat who would make good helpers in the cause? Act quickly, lest the cause be gained before you have a chance to lend a helping hand. 
Miss Carrie Callaway is the secretary
and treasurer for the state committee,
she will be most happy to receive any
donation you would be pleased to send.
We desire to open headquarters at
Knoxville, help to this end will be most
gladly received. </dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/468</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>