<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 45 b</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 45 b. Newspaper clipping: Must Register From Aug. 10-21. [1919].</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Voter registration; Voting;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>[1919]</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook p. 45</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>Must Register From Aug. 10-21.  Estimated by Roy A. Beeler
That From 5,000 to 7,500
Women Will Qualify      
IN CITY AND COUNTY
Election Commission Selects
Registrars at Meeting Next 
Wednesday
The selection of registrars to serve
in the general Knox county registration, which is to be conducted from
Aug. 10 to 21, is to be taken up by the
Knox county election commission at
a meeting to be held next Wednesday.
The commission will have to provide
for the registration of the women as
well as for the men, and it is estimated by Roy A. Beeler, chairman of
the committee, that from 5,000 to 7,500
women may register.
The same books will be used for
both women and men, Mr. Beeler
states.
It is expected that about 15,000 men
will register, Mr. Beeler asserts.
About 10,000 or 12,000 of these are
men residing within the twenty-six
wards of Greater Knoxville.
While the women will be allowed
to vote only in city and presidential
elections, they will be asked to register in the county precincts, as this is
a general registration, and will serve
for the next presidential election,
which will be held in 1920.
The election commission, which is
composed of Mr. Beeler, as chairman,
W. L. Warters, secretary, and C. C.
Hood, will have to select 136 registrars, two to serve at each of the
sixty-eight precincts of the city and
county. Thirty-one of these precincts
are in the city, there being twenty-six
wards, five of which have two separate voting places.
Mr. Beeler states that he is of the
opinion that women can not be legally appointed as registrars in this registration, as the registration is also to
qualify voters for state and county
elections, in which the women can not
vote. He states that if it was for a
city election only, the women might
be appointed as registrars.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/523</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>