<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 02 d</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 02 d. Newspaper clipping: 'To Mrs. L.C. French.' By 'A Citizen.'</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks;</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>'A Citizen'</dc:creator>
<dc:date>unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 02</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>To Mrs. L. C. French.
You are a wiser woman than I&#8212;who
am only an inconsequent citizen of a
rather conservative section&#8212;and it does
not become me to advise you, particularly in public, but "suffer it to be so"
this once for the sake of "progress" which
you so dearly love.
"Don't give up the ship"&#8212;which in
this case is no ship at all, but simply
a prospective little plat in a parkless
city.
You have initiated numerous reforms,
you have valiently led the way in many
noble movements.
Continue, I pray you, in well doing
yet a little longer, and champion this
much neglected cause to a glorious victory.
One swallow, we are told, never yet
made a summer, no more can one man&#8212;
be he mayor or what not&#8212;make a city.
Mr. McTeer was surely jesting when
he put the comfort and convenience of
himself and his horses, splendid animals
tho' they be, before the good and the
beauty of the town, but mayor or no mayor, let us have the park. It is high
time somebody made a move in this direction.
In the last census reports our city
stands out among her sisters in disgraceful distinction thus&#8212;"Knoxville has no
parks!"
What sermons might be preached on
these words for a text&#8212;"Knoxville has
no parks!"
What a commentary they form on the
enterprise  and ambition of her citizens.
The statement has been sown broadcast over the land, and all the world
knows or may know, that Knoxville is
the only city of its size in our country,
in all the world, like enough, which has
not a single park, plat or public square.
Think of it, men, brethren and sisters.
Think of it, and then subscribe not merely one dollar but every dollar you can
rake and scrape together to save this little plat from desecration
A CITIZEN.
</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/161</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>