<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 10 c</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 10 c. Newspaper clipping: 'Municipal Suffrage.' Knoxville Journal &amp; Tribune.  February 9, 1913.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's suffrage; Women's rights; Organizations;</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>A.S.B. in Woman's Journal</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Knoxville Journal &amp; Tribune</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>February 9, 1913</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 10</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>EQUAL SUFFRAGE DEPARTMENT
Editors:&#8212;Mrs. Julia Lucky,  President of Equal Suffrage league, and
Mrs. Sara H. Hood, Secretary.
KNOXVILLE   OFFICERS.
President&#8212;-Mrs,   C.   E.   Lucky.
Vice-President&#8212;Miss Ada Fanz.
Corresponding Secretary&#8212;Miss Margaret Craft
Recording Secretary&#8212;Mrs. M. K. Purnell
Treasurer&#8212;Miss Mary Trigg Jackson.
Mrs. L. Crozier French has been invited by Mrs. John I. Cox and other
ladies of Bristol to give a lecture at
that place Wednesday evening, March
12, on the woman question.
A number of the members of the
Knoxville Equal Suffrage league went
to Washington to be in the suffrage parade. We are anxious to hear how they
fared at the hands of the hoodlums.
Both of the editors of this department are now absent from the city.
Mrs. Lucky is in Florida and Mrs. Hood
went to Washington to help represent
Tennessee in the equal suffrage parade.
Mrs.   French   will   give   a tea to   the
Knoxville Equal   Suffrage league   and their friendds Monday from four to six.  Thise members who went to Washington will be the guests if honor and will tell of the suffrage parade.  All friends of equal suffrage are incited (sic.) to come to the tea. Gentlemen friends will be most cordially welcome.

Mrs. L. Crozier French is an applicant for the position of juvenile judge for Knox County. A number of letters
have  been  written  bo  Governor  Hooper
asking him to appoint her.    The representatives from Knox county have been
requested,   by   a   number   of   prominent
citizens, to introduce     a     bill     making
women eligible to the position.
The Tennessee Mothers' congress holds
the annual convention in Nashville
March. 28 and 29.  Mrs. Robertson is anxious that every mother's association in Knoxville should send it full quota of delegates.  This assocaition has two bills before the present legislature, the mothers' pension bill and a billrequiring all schools to have a kindergarten as a part of of educational system.
There is  talk   of   a   bill   being   introduced to 
niake   women   eligible   to   be members of
 boards of  education.     Not
until 1907 were women forbidden to be
members  of school boards.  It seems 
strange, that when the western and eastern states
were  putting  women  in  important places
 in their schools,  Tennessee should take
  backward   st......
...longer, slower and more toilsome  than
the direct way.
It cost hundreds of New York teachers
six years of arduous work to secure an
equal pay law; and the law applies
only to one city in the state. After
equal suffrage was granted in Wyoming
and Utah, state-wide laws were passed,
without effort on the teacher's part,
providing that when the women teachers
did equal work they should get equal 
pay (Revised Statutes of Wyoming, Section
614(?); revised Statutes of Utah, Section;)   and   the   same   rule   prevails   by 
custom in the other enfranchised states.
The New York antis, constantly threw 
cold water upon the effort of the teach- 
ers for equal pay until after it had suceeded
now turn around and point to
the law as proof that women can perfectly well get anything they want without a vote. But what is the comparative
cost in time and labor?
It took Massachusetts women 55 years
to get an equal guardianship law. In
Colorado the first legislature after women were enfranchised granted it. Mrs.
A. J. George, of Massachusetts, in her
recent lectures in Michigan and other
states against equal suffrage, has been
boasting of good laws of Massachusetts,
including equal guardianship. She omits
to mention, that for six years the "Massachusetts Association...(missing) Further extension of suffrage (missing) en" of which she is a member. (missing) under its official imprint a (missing)
opposition  to equal guardianship
boasts of the equitable property laws of 
Massachusetts, but does not mention 
that they are the fruit of more than half 
a century's effort by the suffragists, with the antis all the time declaring that the
laws were "more than just, to women,."
that women already had "all the rights
they wanted," etc.. etc.
What a vast amount of time and toil
hundreds of women have had to put in
"haggling with prejudice  for penny
worths" of reform which they could have
secured without a twentieth part of the
exertion if they could have had had
''the little mechanism of the ballot," as
Jane Addams call it!
What a vast amount of time and toil
women have had  to put  in just to get
that little  mechanism!    What a saving
of time it will be to the century's very
best   women   when   they   get   it   and   no
longer  have  to   struggle for   it!     Even
the near approach of equal suffrage has
begun to save  women's time.     In   New
York and Pennsylvania this year it was 
not thought necessary to have the legis- 
lative   hearings   which   heretofore   have
consumed  so much time and energy of
suffragists and  antis alike. Why?    Be
cause all parties had put suffrage planks
into their platforms.    When every state
has  adopted  equal  suffrage women can
put into direct work for the public good
all the force  that they now have to expend
 in getting the tool to work  with;
and the saving will be beyond computa-
tion.-   
A.S.B. in Woman's Journal</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/314</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>