<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook,  p. 11 f</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 11 f. Newspaper clipping: Benefit Card Party is Being Arranged.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's suffrage; Card games;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 11</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>BENEFIT CARD
IS BEING ARRANGED
Money Will be Used to Entertain Suffrage Convention
Delegates.
A large number of representative
women   of   the   city   met   with   Mrs.   L.
Crozier-French Saturday morning in the
parlors of the board cf commerce, when
plans were discussed for the entertainment of delegates who will attend the
convention of the State Equal Suffrage
association, which is to convene in
Knoxville the last week in October.
The ladies rallied to the call extended
by Mrs. French in gratifying numbers,
and showed much interest in the convention. 
It was decided to give a benefit card
party for the purpose of raising funds
for the entertainment of delegates. This
affair will be given on the afternoon of
October   8th,   at   the   Lyceum  building.
About a week after this affair, another entertainment will be given for the
same purpose. Details for this have not
been settled upon, and its nature will not
be disclosed until later.
At the meeting Saturday morning,
there was general discussion held on
how to entertain the guests of the convention.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/320</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>