<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 40 f</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 40 f. Newspaper clipping: Shields and Fisher Answer.  Knoxville Journal and Tribune.  April 11, [1917].</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's suffrage; Politicians;</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Knoxville Journal and Tribune</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>April 11, [1917]</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook p. 40</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>SHIELDS AND
FISHER ANSWER
Reply to  Resolutions  of  the
Woman's Party of Tennessee.
Memphis     Congressman     Will
Vote For Full Citizenship of
American Women.
The     Knox   County     committee    of   the
 Woman's Party on March 28, passed resolutions which were sent to the President and
 all  members   of  congress  from   Tennessee.
iCongressman  Austin's   reply   was  publish-
ed several days ago, and those of Senator
Shields    and    Representative   Fisher,   now
appearing,  will  be of interest to the public
generally,   but  more especially  to  suffragists.    The resolutions are as follows:&#8212;
"Whereas the international situation is in
such  a  disturbed  condition  that  none  can
 predict  what a day may  bring forth, and
 it is not improbable that war may shortly
be declared between the United States and
Germany;
Thererefore be it resolved that it is the
(missing)se of this meeting that because in the
(missing) of war the women of this country
equally with the men will be called upon
to carry their share of the burdens thereof,
that now is the time for congres to take the
first step toward the recognition by the
government of this republic of the citizenship of women by the passage of the federal amendment looking to the removal of
the political disabilities of the women of
the whole Union.
"The patriotism of the women of tne
United States is assured, but the pleasure
of their patriotic acts will be greatly enhanced by the knowledge that the government recognizes their right to full citizen-
'ship.
"We most earnestly petition the President and congress to do all in their power
to obtain justice for women before calling
upon them to perform extra duties. Be it
further resolved, that a copy of these resolutions be sent to the President and all
Tennessee congressmen.
Senator Shields' Letter.
Washington,  D.   C.
April 7.
Mrs.  L. Crozier-French,
Knoxville,   Tennnessee.
My Dear Mrs.  French:
I have your letter and a copy of resolutions adopted by the Tennessee Woman's
party and I am very glad to have an expression  of  your  views.
I am sending you a copy of the last edition of the Congressional Directory, and
shall be glad to supply you with any other
documents which might be of interest to
you.
With kindest regards, I am,
Very   truly   yours,
[JOHN] K.  SHIELDS.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/528</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>