<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 06 b</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 06 b. Newspaper clipping: 'Trustees of University Hear Reports and Fill Faculty Vacancies. Decide to Continue Summer School Another Year. Dr. Stough Not Warranted in Making Charges Against Prof. A.A. Schaefer.'</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Universities &amp; colleges; Teachers;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 06</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>TRUSTEES OF
UNIVERSITY
Hear Reports and Fill Faculty
Vacancies.
Decide to  Continue Summer
School Another Year.
Dr.  Stough Not Warranted in
Making   Charges Against
Prof. A. A. Schaeffer.
That Rev. Henry W. Stough, the evangelist, who conducted a campaign in this
city, was in no way warranted in the
statement he made concerning Prof. A.
A. Schaeffer, of the University of Tennessee, and that the evangelist should
have withdrawn these statements as soon
as he saw the letters that were furnished
by him to the trustees of the university, was the sense of the special committee of the university trustees which
took this matter under advisement at
the meeting of the board of trustees held
on Tuesday, at the university. The trustees of the university unanimously adopt-
ed   the  report  of  its  committee.
The meeting of Wednesday was attended by Governor Thomas 0. Rye, Commissioner of Agriculture Bryson and the
largest out of town attendance that has
ever been noted at the meetings of the
board. It was featured by a decision to
continue the Summer school next year at
least, by the election of a number of
professors, and by the annual hearing of
reports. The finances of the institution
remain practically as they were last year,
The meeting was held in the office of
the president, Dr. Brown Ayres, with
the following trustees present;&#8212;
Judge Hu G. Kyle, of Rogersville: H.
Clay Evans, of Chattanooga; Hon. W. P,
Cooper, of Shelbyville, former speaker of
the house of representatives; Mr. J. Ew-
ing Hite, of Gallatin; Spencer F.
Thomas, of Brownsville; Rowan A.
Greer, Bolton Smith and James S. Robertson, all of Memphis; I. B. Tigert, of
Jackson; Governor T. C. Rye, Commissioner of Agriculture Bryson, President
Ayres, Judge Hu L. McCkmg, James
Maynard, Sr., of Knoxville. Mr. Hite
had been reappointed, and Messrs Cooper
and Robinson being new members, the
statutory oath was administered by
Judge Hu G. Kyle.
President Ayres read his annual report
showing that the university had passed
through   its   most   prosperous   year.    It
showed the    grand total    of    student[s]
taught "in our buildings in the regu[lar]
session was 1,278, being an increase [of]
108 over the preceding year,"    The [num]-
ber of graduates was shown by t(missing)
port to have been 172 in all depart(missing)
The  treasurer's   report  was   re(missing)
T. D. Morris, and the report of the (missing)
man of the finance committee, Jud[ge] [Mc]
Clung, with the budget for the (missing)
year,   was   adopted.    In   present (missing)
budget  Judge   McClung  made  e(missing)
tions that were very clear, fore(missing)
satisfactory.-
The legislatuve committee was a(missing)
ed, consisting of Dr. Ayres, Jud[ge] [Hu]
L. McClung. Hon. W. P. Coope
ton Smith, T. L. Ashcroft, C (missing)
Mooney and E. H. Crump.

</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/196</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>