<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook,  p. 13 b</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 13 b. Newspaper clipping: 'The Necessity, Beneficence and Beauty of Law'. Paper Read at Opening Meeting of Ossoli Circle, Monday, October 26th, by Mrs. L.C. French.  1914.  Knoxville Journal &amp; Tribune.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Law &amp; legal affairs;</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Mrs. L.C. French</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Knoxville Journal &amp; Tribune</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>October 26, 1914</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 13</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>The Necessity, Beneficence and Beauty of Law. Paper Read at Opening Meeting of Ossoli Circle, Monday, October 26th, by Mrs. L.C. French.
"Ever the Rock of Ages melts
Into the mineral air,
To be the quarry whence is built
Thought and its mansions fair."
These lines indicate to us that poe
try, no less than religion, science and
philosophy, teaches the indestructabil-
ity of matter, the correlation and con
servation of force and the development
of   the  lower  into   higner  forms;   in
short, the oneness ot the universe.
Accept this statement as true and
the conclusion is inevitable that the
universe is governed by law, inexorable and eternal law, or it might be
more exact to say, the universe is law
executing itself.
Emerson calls the world "a fagot of
laws," immortal and seif-protecting.
If this be true the work of man is to
acquire a knowledge of law so as to
keep   himself  in  harmony  with it.
The assertion has been made that
the instinct for law is primal and exists in every order of creatio. Ruskin
shows us in his Ethics of the Dust,
that clay following out the laws of its
being becomes the sapphire, that sand
reaches up to the opal, while soot or
charcoal becomes transfigured into the
diamond.
The rock crumbles and makes the
soil, from whence springs plant life,
that gives sustenance to the animal
which in its turn on the one hand
gives its refuse to enrich the soil and
on the other its body for food for man,
while the latter by the use of thought
improves himself as well as the animal and the plant.
When the soul of man passes into
the unknown his body mingles again
with the soil and the circle is complete. Thus we see that in nature
every debt is paid to the uttermost
farthing. The necessity of lavv is then
self-evident. the failure of one kingdom to supply the needs of another
would turn the universe into chaos.
Mineral, animal, vegetable and human
all work together for the good of all.
Thus can we truly sing witn the poet;
"Ever the Rock af Ages  melts
Into the mineral air
To be the quarry whence is built
Thought and its mansions fair."
Victor Hugo has beautifully said:&#8212;-
"The human intellect radiates and li1--
tie by little wins, subdues ami humanizes matter." ]
"Sublime domestication." What, ben
*tne.ent and beautiful laws is science
revealing to us dav by Gay. How our
lives are enrched by its .improvements,
discoveries and inventions. J.t tea c he*
us that law exact and inexorable governs both great and small. Tnai m&#171;
bee in its work is as exact and inva- ;.
liable as the stars in their course. Thr
microbe performs its function with th-"
like promptness and preeus.-don tna&lt;
the sun does his.
Religion teaches us that the recog
nition of law and obedience to it is the
proof   of   the   great   and   the   good   of
all time.
Philosophers    have     devoted     the.Jr.
lives   to   the   study  of  universal  theo   !
ries   concerning   it   tending:   alvvavs  to
the end of contributing to the instruction and hauDines.s of ma.n-kind.
Prom all great teachers do we learn
that the practice of virtue is as necessary to the well being of man as
is sufficient food. that, the universe is
founded on morality and surrounded
by goodness.
Says IViarcus Aurelius:&#8212;"No longer
let thy breathing only act in concert
"with the air which surrounds thee. hat.
let thy intelligence aiso now he m
harmony with the intelligence which
embraces all things. For the intelligent power is no less diffused in all
parts and pervades all things for him
who   is   willing   to      draw   it   to   him
and   we   will   know   the   right   and   it,
i will make us free.    It is the personal
| consideration which blinds the eye and
\ obscures the vision.
J      Let   i:s   now   consider   the   divisions
; ef law:
Webster's   definition:&#8212;"A     law      is
that which is laid, sot or fixed, a rule |
of being or conduct established bv an
authority able td enforce its will,"
Eurke  says:&#8212;-"Law     is  beneficence]
. working by rule."
Cosmic or Divine law is that of the j
universe.     Natural law  is  that of the j
individual; eclesiasticai law that of the j
policy   of   a   church;     civil     law   that
which  applies to  members  of a community;  political law that of the government  of said community;   national
law that of communities in their relation to each other.
To formulate these laws, to study
them to shape our lives in harmony
with them and transmit this knowledge and power to posterity is
the first duty of the least as well as
of the greatest. Ignorance of the. law
either human or divine, furnishes no
immunity to the one who violates it.
Recognizing this Shakespeare wrote:&#8212;i
"There is no darkness, but ignorance."
Ignorance of law is that dark shadow
which men have named evil.    Evil has
&gt;&#9632;,/-,    c n V. c* f o &gt;^ &lt;"&gt; &lt;~,  :&#187;p,v^1    ,-ific-+"&#8212;"if"." Ac    rln^l.
jr..    .-ul'^'-rtii!-!.     rvrt-l    tr.^.i.- ca-lll.tr. .10    uttiiv*
ness is simply the absence of light, so
evil is the absence of good or law or
harm, on v. Where knowledge is light
and the. shadows disappear. The first
mandate of Ihe creator we are told:
was "Let there be light."
The last orv of Goethe was:"Light, i
more light," and it is the great need j
of us a'l
Now  we ccme  to  the con'siderat'on !
of those laws which have been  formulated   for  the  government,     of  those
who  are  banded   together  to  transact
business of whatsoever kind. The code,
having been  compiled from  the  rules!
which govern the law rnakirg body the
lawmaking body of England has been
by common consent called parliamentary law, which is intended to  tpach&#8212;&#9632;
Accuracy in business, economy of time, i
impartiality,    uniformity,    order     Are
any  of  these pve  needed  in  the  con**
ducting of a woman's club, or are the^
only   for     "mere   men's."     I   ask   the
question  because T or.ce hea~d a lady
say that she thought the enforcement
of   parliamentary     law     in     women's
meetings was  ridiculous.
Are women so accurate in buMnrsi
that they need no guides? Do they ex-
pedite matters in such a way as to
lose no time? Are they' by instinct
perfectly just and impartial?
Order is heaven's first law, is it also
woman's so that she needs no instruction, no riding in this direction'7
My friends I am not a pessimist, F
have an abounding faith in humanity,
a belief in the power and ability of the
human soul or mind to overcome
every obstacle, but I cannot sco the
lergth of the person just quoted. I
believe that women are not yet so
perfect that they can dispense with
the rule of conducting meetings such
as eur greatest men have found s?
necessary. For these great one* know'
that where there is no law, but every
one does according to her own sweet
will, tRerm is the least of real liberty
and justice.
In   conclusion   let   me     exnress   the s
wish   and   the   belief  that     the   ladies
who are to present for your consider-1
i'V-nn this Ossoli session,     the general
rules  which should  govern     meetings
will be able to show yon most conclu- '
sively   the   necessity^ the   benefit   and
beauty of parliamentary law</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/332</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>