<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>French. Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 36 f</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook, p. 36 f. Newspaper clipping: Both Tennessee Delegations Are Seated.  Knoxville Journal &amp; Tribune.  November 14, 1914.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Politics &amp; government; Clippings; Scrapbooks; Women; Women's suffrage;</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Knoxville Journal &amp; Tribune</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>November 14, 1914</dc:date>
<dc:type>scrapbook</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Lizzie Crozier French Scrapbook p. 36</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>C.M. McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please provide a brief description of the material.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>Both Tennessee Delegations Are Seated.
By the National Woman Suffrage Association Convention at
Nashville, on the Recommendation of a Special Committee&#8212;One Delegation is Headed by Mrs. Crozier-French,
the Other by Mrs. M'Cormick. 
Decision is Reached Not to Limit Work Before Congress to Efforts For Passage of Bristow-Mondell Suffrage Amendment to the Constitution&#8212;Southern Suffragists Decide to
Wage Fight to Add a Southern State to Suffrage Column
Within Two Years. 
Nashville, Term., Nov. 13.&#8212;By a vote
of almost two to one the convention of 
the National American Woman Suffrage 
association here late today decided that 
its work before congress for the ensuing
year shall not be limited to efforts for
the passage of the Bristow-Mondell suffrage
amendment to the federal
constitution.    At an  earlier sesson the national association
declared by a decisive majority that its congressional committee
shall not conduct campaigns against
candidates in any state without the consent of the suffrage association in the state concerned.
The action of the convention on these
matters settled two of the most important questions
before the present convention--question (sic.) which have given rise to 
much division of opinion among suffragists
 during the last few months and
which had significant bearing upon their 
plans for next year's campaign.
The   debate   on  both   issues   was   de-
cidedly spirited and at times tinged with
 factional   bitterness. 
Tonight's mass meeting was in the
hands of the "voters," the program being
under the auspices of the National Men's
League for Woman Suffrage with James 
Lees Laidlaw presiding, and addresses 
by Senator Luke Lea of Tennesee and
men and women suffragists from several  states.
Legislative Battle.
Consideration of the legislative measures
to be supported by the national association
in the coming year was fixed as
a special order of business in the afternoon session.
Much of the opposition to the administration's
plan to work before congress for other measures
in addition
to the Bristow-Mondell resolution came 
from advocates of the "state's rights"  idea  in   the movement.
Mrs. Harriet Stanton Blatch, of New
York, one of the principal champions of
one legislative measure plan, presented 
the   initial   motion   "that   tne   Shafroth 
amendment be not proceeded with
by the national association in the next session of congress."
A substitute motion, offered immediately by Mrs. Raymond Brown of New
York declared ihat "it is the sense of
the convention that the policy of the na-
tional association shall be to support by
every means within its power, in the
future as in the past, the amendment
known as the Susan B. Anthony amendment. And further that vve support such
other legislation as the national board
may authorize and initiate to the end
that the Susan B. Anthony resolution become law.
Mrs. Barton Jenks, of Rhode Island,
then moved to strike out  the  last sen-
tence  of Mrs.  Brown's substitute.    Im-
mediately at least a dozen women  were
on  their feet  shouting  for  a  chance  to
be heard on the motion.
 Miss  Jane  Addams,     who     presided,
recognized    Mrs.    George    W.    Bass    of 
Chicago who spoke warmly against limit-
ing the association's efforts to one measure.
Miss   Kate  M.   Gordon,   of   New
Orleans,  president  of  the  Southern  States        
Suffrage association, favored Mrs. Jenks' motion, 
asserting  that  she   did   not  believe
 in allowing the national board too 
great powers  in  initiating  legislation.
In the California section of the suffrage pageant two banners were carried which attracted considerable attention.  One bore the legend, "Sacremento," the heart of California and the Capitol of the State," and the other proclaimed the proud fact that "Sacremento women had voted the Commission form of government and elected the only woman commissioner in the world."  Mrs. Luella Johnson is the distinguished lady's name, and it is said that under her administration as commissioner of Education that the schools, health and sanitary condition have become ideal.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll8/id/481</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>