<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Lyndon B. Johnson arriving at the Hermitage</dc:title>
<dc:description>Carriage driven by Ruffin Baker carrying President and Mrs. Lyndon B. Johnson, arriving at the Hermitage among a crowd.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The Hermitage was the home of Andrew Jackson. It was built in 1819 and enlarged in 1831. It is a Greek Revival mansion located in Davidson County, Tennessee, outside of Nashville. Today, the house and grounds are a popular tourist attraction for visitors nationwide. Lyndon B. Johnson (1908-1973) was the 36th President of the United States from 1963-1969 and was John F. Kennedy's Vice President until Kennedy's assassination. Lady Bird Johnson (1912-2007) broke new ground by interacting directly with Congress and beautifying the nation's cities and highways. On March 15, 1967, President Lyndon B. Johnson and his wife Lady Bird Johnson made a day-long trip to Nashville. The Tennessee General Assembly invited Johnson to speak at a joint session to commemorate the 200th anniversary of the birth of President Andrew Jackson. Their one-day tour resulted in trips to the Hermitage, the Polk House, Ellington Agricultural Center, Columbia State Community College, and the Tennessee State Capitol.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1967 March 15</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>Nashville (Tenn.); Davidson County (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>Pres. Lyndon B. Johnson's Visit to Middle Tennessee Photographs</dc:source>
<dc:source>2003-067</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Coach drivers; Horses; Carriages &amp; coaches; Crowds</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>2263</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isFormatOf>4568</dcterms:isFormatOf>
<dc:source>I-J-3, Box 1</dc:source>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Lyndon Johnson's 1967 Tennessee Visit</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:type>Still Image</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dcterms:medium>Photographs</dcterms:medium>
<dc:rights>Copyright not evaluated: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll51/id/112</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>