<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Barber. Geo. F. Barber Co.</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Greater Knoxville Illustrated</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Geo. F. Barber Co. from Greater Knoxville Illustrated. Ca. 1910.  Published by the American Illustrating Company, Nashville, Tennessee.  P. 133 (partial).  Pictures Geo. F. Barber, President, and J.H. Ryno, Vice-president and Treasurer.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>architects;</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>American Illustrating Company</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1910</dc:date>
<dc:type>book</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF; 400 dpi</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>C 917.688</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>McClung Historical Collection cataloged books</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>Geo. F. Barber, President, J.H. Ryno,  V-Pres. and Treas.
Geo.  F.  Barber Company.
GEO.   F.   BARBER   COMPANY.
The prosperity of a city is indicated by nothing more than by the imposing and artistic appearance of its buildings, and despite the maxim that commands us to judge not by appearances,
it is the external signs by which a city is judged,
and in this particular Knoxville must be classed
among the leading cities of the South, for a great
part of its architecture is not surpassed anywhere. A very large number of the improvements in the city are the products of Geo. F.
Barber Company. They have designed many of
Knoxville's finest buildings, including the Mc-
Kinney Apartments, Park City High School, Knox-
ville Motor &amp; Garage on State street and the
residences of J. Y. Johnson and Jno. L. Boyd and
many other leading residences and business
structures. The company was established twenty
years ago and has much important work in
hand, and is prepared to give satisfaction in design and construction of buildings for any purpose whatsoever, and the record winch they have
made deserves special attention. They employ
seven expert designers and are well equipped
for their work. Mr. Barber is President of the
concern, and J. H. Ryno is Vice President and
Treasurer.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15136coll3/id/464</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>