<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd"><titleInfo><title>American Eagle In Britain - 1945-mm-24 - Part 1</title></titleInfo><accessCondition type="local rights statement">This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</accessCondition><abstract>Part 1 of Mutual Broadcasting System program American Eagle In Britain, broadcast in arrangement with the British Broadcasting Corporation. Possibly originally broadcast February 24, 1945 (unconfirmed, based on information on torn label and content on other side of disc). Featuring interviews conducted by Cecil Madden and Major Ken Treadwell on location at Dunker's Den of the American Red Cross Rainbow Corner Club in London, England; and Bebe Daniels on location at the 97th General Hospital, England. Features music by the Gremlins/Gremlin Orchestra, under the direction of Lieutenant George Puig (spelling unconfirmed), with conductor Sergeant Tom Frank.</abstract><subject><topic>Mutual Broadcasting System</topic></subject><subject><topic>BBC Radio</topic></subject><subject><topic>WSIX (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.)</topic></subject><subject><topic>American Eagle in Britain (Radio program)</topic></subject><subject><topic>Treadwell, Ken</topic></subject><subject><topic>Madden, Cecil</topic></subject><subject><topic>Daniels, Bebe, 1901-1971</topic></subject><name><namePart>Gremlins</namePart><role><roleTerm type="text" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabular/relators/cre">Creator</roleTerm></role></name><identifier type="local">TR001465_2</identifier><location><url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/1815</url><url access="preview">http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/musicaudio/id/1815</url></location><physicalDescription><form>16 inch metal-based acetate disc</form></physicalDescription><physicalDescription><form>33 1/3 rpm</form></physicalDescription><recordInfo><recordContentSource>Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum</recordContentSource><recordChangeDate>2023-05-08-04:00</recordChangeDate><languageOfCataloging><languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm></languageOfCataloging><recordOrigin>Record has been transformed into MODS v3.5 from a Qualified Dublin Core record by the Digital Library of Tennessee, a service hub of the Digital Public Library of America.</recordOrigin></recordInfo></mods>