<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd"><titleInfo><title>Town And Country Time - 1955-11-05 (copy 2) - Part 8</title></titleInfo><accessCondition type="local rights statement">This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</accessCondition><abstract>Radio program Town And Country Time, originally broadcast 1955-11-05 by WARL (Arlington, VA) - part 8. Special final broadcast of host Connie B. Gay, featuring in-studio and pre-recorded messages from various associates of Connie, including: Pick Temple; Charles Finley [last name unconfirmed]; Mark Evans and Billy Johnson of WTOP; Ernie Sparkman, Earl "Grandpappy" Davis, and Jimmy Oakes of Town And Country Time WTCR (Ashland, KY); James P. Davis of RCA records; Harry Berryhill, Annandale Volunteer Fire Department President; Jane Trimner, Connie's successor as Town And Country Time President; Hank Snow; Jimmy Dean and the Texas Wildcats (including Marvin Carroll, Herbie Jones, Buck Ryan, Bob Elliott, Smitty Erwin, and Dale Turner); Don Tucker of WTCS (Fairmont, WV) and Town and Country Time Vice-President; Dick Barr, WMCA (New York, NY) announcer and former WARL announcer; Sid Barbet of Buyers Associates; Ron Harrell [last name unconfirmed]; Johnny Shuto [last name unconfirmed]; Billy Grammer; "Fiddlin'" Curly Smith and Joe Brechner of WGAY (Silver Spring, MD); Byron Roudabush, Town And Country Time TV director; Murray Nash, President of Murray Nash Associates; Eddy Arnold; Bernie Harrison, writer for the Evening Star; Sam Jack Kaufman, president of the D.C. Federation of Musicians Local 161-710; Kilbourne Castell, former WARL owner; Fred Hand, manager of Constitution Hall; Fred Houwink, of WMAL-TV; Joe Wheeler of the Wheeler Brothers; Bob Keith; Ralph Case; Phil Long, Howard Fisher, and Don Owens, WARL DJs; George Crump, Commercial Manager of WARL; Ray Armand, manager of WARL; Cy Blumenthal, owner of WARL; June [Stuart/Stewart], of WTCR; George [last name unidentified]; Tom [last name unidentified], Town And Country Time Comptroller; George Rowe of the U.S. Department of Agriculture; John Anderson, Arlington Hospital Administrator; and Vince McMahon, promoter. Telegrams from Walter David Kilpatrick of Mercury Records; Mr and Mrs Everett Delozier; Representative Harold D. Cooley; Congressman Joel T. Broyhill; and Senator W. Kerr Scott are read during the program. Note: two sets of discs exist for this content, 'copy 2' is of higher audio quality.</abstract><subject><topic>Gay, Connie B. (Connie Barriot), 1914-1989</topic></subject><subject><topic>WARL (Radio station : Arlington, Va.)</topic></subject><subject><topic>Town and country time (Radio program)</topic></subject><subject><topic>Dean, Jimmy</topic></subject><subject><topic>Texas Wildcats (Musical group)</topic></subject><subject><topic>Carroll, Marvin</topic></subject><subject><topic>Jones, Herbie, 1923-2001</topic></subject><subject><topic>Ryan, Buck</topic></subject><subject><topic>Erwin, Smitty</topic></subject><subject><topic>Turner, Dale (Vocalist)</topic></subject><subject><topic>Arnold, Eddy, 1918-2008</topic></subject><subject><topic>Snow, Hank</topic></subject><subject><topic>Temple, Pick</topic></subject><subject><topic>Evans, Mark, 1917-1988</topic></subject><subject><topic>Johnson, Billy, 1925-2006</topic></subject><subject><topic>Sparkman, Ernest, 1925-2010</topic></subject><subject><topic>Davis, James P., -1963</topic></subject><subject><topic>Trimner, Jane</topic></subject><subject><topic>Grammer, Billy</topic></subject><subject><topic>Roudabush, Byron</topic></subject><subject><topic>Nash, Murray</topic></subject><subject><topic>Case, Ralph</topic></subject><subject><topic>Kaufman, Sam Jack</topic></subject><subject><topic>McMahon, Vincent J., 1914-1984</topic></subject><subject><topic>Kilpatrick, Walter David</topic></subject><subject><topic>Cooley, Harold D. (Harold Dunbar), 1897-1974</topic></subject><subject><topic>Broyhill, Joel T. (Joel Thomas), 1919-2006</topic></subject><subject><topic>Scott, William Kerr, 1896-1958</topic></subject><name><namePart>Jimmy Dean</namePart><role><roleTerm type="text" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabular/relators/cre">Creator</roleTerm></role></name><name><namePart>Texas Wildcats</namePart><role><roleTerm type="text" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabular/relators/cre">Creator</roleTerm></role></name><name><namePart>Jimmie Davis</namePart><role><roleTerm type="text" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabular/relators/cre">Creator</roleTerm></role></name><identifier type="local">TR002154</identifier><location><url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/3701</url><url access="preview">http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/musicaudio/id/3701</url></location><physicalDescription><form>12 inch metal-based acetate disc</form></physicalDescription><physicalDescription><form>33 1/3 rpm</form></physicalDescription><recordInfo><recordContentSource>Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum</recordContentSource><recordChangeDate>2023-05-08-04:00</recordChangeDate><languageOfCataloging><languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm></languageOfCataloging><recordOrigin>Record has been transformed into MODS v3.5 from a Qualified Dublin Core record by the Digital Library of Tennessee, a service hub of the Digital Public Library of America.</recordOrigin></recordInfo></mods>