<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>A Corner of the Library</dc:title>
<dc:rights>While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law.  Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:subject>Shelving; Books; Libraries</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>World War, 1939-1945 -- Europe; Prisoners of war; Diaries</dc:subject>
<dc:description>This page in Mitchener's diary from World War II includes a drawing of the library at the POW camp. On the top of the page, he has written,"For a little learning is a dangerous thing." Underneath this, he has drawn a picture of books on shelves and listed the hours which the library is open. He refers to fiction and reference sections.</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Zagan (Poland)</dc:coverage>
<dc:date>1944-1945</dc:date>
<dc:description>Hardy A. Mitchener, Jr. was captured during World War II after a bombing mission in Germany. He was sent to Stalag Luft III, a POW camp in Silesia.  The library at the camp could seat about 80 men and contained both reference material and fiction &amp; non-fiction works. The Red Cross was largely responsible for providing the books. The most popular books (in decreasing order of importance) were popular novels, detective fiction, western fiction, travel, and biography.  American magazines were also available.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Mitchener, Hardy A., 1919-1957</dc:creator>
<dc:source>Hardy A. Mitchener, Jr. Journal, 1944-1945</dc:source>
<dc:relation>THS 760</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Tennessee Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>33579</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>IMAGE</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/mitchener/id/101</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>