<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of Annie Sybil Thomas Jarrett and William Robert Jarrett, 1940s</dc:title>
<dc:description>Black and white photograph of Annie Sybil Thomas Jarrett with her husband William Robert Jarrett. The photograph was taken in the front of their home in Paris, Tennessee. They each wear dark colored suits and white shirts. Annie Sybill Thomas Jarrett (1881 - 1975) was a teacher and lifelong member of the Republican Party. She was born near Saulsbury, Tennessee. She is the daughter of Harriet and John Thomas Sr. She attended Clay Street School in Memphis, Tennessee, which was at the site of the current Booker T. Washington High School. She graduated with a degree in education from Lane College. She advocated in her community and schools for the teaching of African American history. According to family tradition, she urged family members to vote Republican to honor Abraham Lincoln and the Emancipation Proclamation. </dc:description>
<dc:description>The first generations of African American voters after the passage of the 15th Amendment identified as Lincoln Republicans. This was the party associated with Emancipation and therefore the majority of African American voters voted along Republican lines up until the era of the Civil Rights Movement. There were still older African Americans, born at the beginning of the 20th century, who identified as Lincoln Republican. Notable African American women republicans during this time period include Mary Church Terrell and Ida B. Wells. Portraiture was a highly political activity for African Americans, especially after Emancipation. Frederick Douglass considered photography the most democratic of arts and a crucial aid in African Americans' quest to achieve citizenship because it served as a potent equalizer. Early photographs of African Americans are linked to the first phase of a way of thinking defined as Racial Uplift: an ideology which emphasized education, achievement, and propriety as marks of personal distinction that would refute racist stereotypes and establish a basis for positive Black identities. Photography became the way African Americans visually documented their efforts for full citizenship and political enfranchisement. </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Jarrett, Annie Sybil Thomas, 1881-1975; Jarrett, William Robert</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Portrait photographs; Group portraits; African Americans; African American political activists--Tennessee--Paris; African Americans--Family relationships</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Paris (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>194-</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CHmem_063</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Generations - African American Women's Early Activism in Tennessee</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll23/id/441</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>