<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Copy of photograph of Samretta Griffin Boulware Fritz from her funeral program, 1993</dc:title>
<dc:description>This image from the funeral program of Samretta Griffin Fritz appears to be a studio photograph taken in the 1950s. Samretta Griffin Fritz (1921-1993) was an active clubwoman and member of her church, the Little Leaf Baptist Church. She served as President of the Mission Society and the Baptist Training Union and founded and directed a Girl's Club for Little Leaf Baptist Church. In addition to her leadership roles in the church, Samretta Griffin Fritz was heavily involved in her local municipal community. She was a member of the Executive Committee of the Anderson County Democrats, a member of the Oliver Springs Planning Commission, and worked as a poll worker for many years. She was employed by Anderson County Food Services until her retirement in 1984. She was born November 18, 1921 in Oliver Springs, Tennessee and died January 1, 1993 and is buried in Carter's Bluff Cemetery in Oliver Springs, Tennessee. </dc:description>
<dc:description>Racial segregation barred African American women from white clubs. In response, African American women formed their own clubs. Some clubs were society clubs that offered social activities. Others were community clubs that focused on social causes, activism, and racial uplift work. Whether the club's main goal was to be a society club or an activism club, all clubs functioned as a place for African American women to organize. These sophisticated institutional networks amplified political activity by serving as mass communication systems between neighborhoods, cities, and states. 
Churches were also one of the few places that offered African American women leadership opportunities and gave them platforms to express their educational and political agendas. Because Churches also addressed the civic and secular needs of African Americans, women leaders in church often organized and worked on voter registrations, racial issues, education and healthcare, and other community needs.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Fritz, Samretta Griffin Boulware, 1921-1993</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African Americans; Women; African Americans--Women--Tennessee--Oliver Springs; African Americans--Societies, etc.--Tennessee--Oliver Springs; Clubwomen--Tennessee--Oliver Springs</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Oliver Springs (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1993</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text; Still Image; Photographs; Obituaries</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CHknox_018</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Generations - African American Women's Early Activism in Tennessee</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959; 1990-1999</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll23/id/424</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>