<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Present Gospel Speaker Newspaper, 1941</dc:title>
<dc:description>The Present Gospel Speaker was the newspaper of the Keith Dominion of the House of God Church. Feautred on the front page is a photograph of Bishop Keith, the second Chief Overseer of the House of God Church and the namesake of the Keith Dominion. Bishop Keith would often dress in a suit jacket and tie with a long skirt, or in graduation gowns. Women leaders who served on her council began dressing that way, as well. Bishop Keith did this to make a point about her equality and standing with men. The newspaper features essays, articles, and details about church news, business, religious life, sermons, and information about various educational, housing, and community services available to members. Dr. Mary F.L. Keith (unknown -1962) succeeded Mother Mary Magdalena Lewis Tate as the second Chief Overseer of the House of God Church in 1931. She was an educator and philanthropist and under her administration the House of God Church greatly enhanced its social services and programs; expanded its real estate holdings; and increased membership. Under her direction, the church printed the First Universal Sunday School Lessons, and founded the Keith Bible Institute; the House of God Home for Children in East Chattanooga, Tennessee; and the House of God Home. She died on July 14, 1962 in Chattanooga, Tennessee.
The House of God, Which is the Church of the Living God, the Pillar and Ground of the Truth Without Controversy, Inc. was founded by Mother Mary Magdalena Lewis Tate with the help of Bishop Keith, her secretary who would go on to be the second leader of the church after Mother Tate died. Mother Tate incorporated the church in 1908. After her death in 1930, the church split into three dominions, Jewell, Keith, and Lewis Dominions. The church took on the name House of God Church Keith Dominion at this point, named after Bishop Keith. It is headquartered in Nashville, Tennessee.</dc:description>
<dc:description>African Americans founded and built churches that served multiple civic and community functions. Churches were one of the few places African Americans could gather without the interference or suspicion of white people. Churches became the center of all religious, civic and community life. They provided spaces to educate and organize around social causes, including schools, daycare, voter registrations, veteran services, and racial justice. Because of their multi-purpose use, churches are at the center of African American political activity and serve the secular needs of African Americans that were not equitably provided by federal, state and local authorities.
Churches were one of the few places that offered African American women leadership opportunities and gave them platforms to express their educational and political agendas. Because Churches also addressed the civic and secular needs of African Americans, women leaders in church often organized and worked on voter registrations, racial issues, education and healthcare, and other community needs.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Keith, Mary F. L., Bishop, -1962</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Church of the Living God, the Pillar and Ground of the Truth</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African Americans--Press coverage; African Americans--Religion; African Americans--Women; Women in church work; Women and religion; Evangelists</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Church of the Living God, the Pillar and Ground of the Truth (publisher)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1941</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still image; Photographs; Newspapers</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CHnash_027</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Generations - African American Women's Early Activism in Tennessee</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll23/id/290</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>