<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Colorized portrait of Maggie Adams White, circa 1930</dc:title>
<dc:description>Studio colorized photograph of Maggie Adams White. The photograph is framed and has suffered water damage. The photograph has been re-framed and is missing parts of the color around the woman's mouth. She wears a dark colored top and statement necklace. Part of the photograph appears to be stuck to the glass of the frame. Maggie Adams White (1882-1980) was a milliner and an active Republican in St. Louis, Missouri. She was born in South Carolina in 1882 to Young Adams, who was born into slavery. She went to St. James CME in Collierville, Tennessee and after moving to St. Louis, Missouri became a founding member of Scruggs CME. She was a member of the NAACP and entrenched in local politics. She died in December 1980.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The first generations of African American voters after the passage of the 15th Amendment identified as Lincoln Republicans. This was the party associated with Emancipation and therefore the majority of African American voters voted along Republican lines up until the era of the Civil Rights Movement. There were still older African Americans, born at the beginning of the 20th century, who identified as Lincoln Republicans. Notable African American women Republicans during this time period include Mary Church Terrell and Ida B. Wells.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>White, Maggie Adams, 1882-1980</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Portrait photographs; African Americans; Women;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>St. Louis (Mo.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Rogers Studio (photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>circa 1930</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CHmem_077</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Generations - African American Women's Early Activism in Tennessee</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll23/id/6</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>