<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Certificate of Life Membership for John Thomas Patton, National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, 1961 April</dc:title>
<dc:description>A plaque certifying John Thomas Patton was a life member of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP) in April 1961. </dc:description>
<dc:description>The National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP) is a civil rights organization in the United States. It was formed in 1909 as a bi-racial endeavor to advance justice for African Americans. The NAACP's mission is to ensure the political, educational, social and economic equality of minority group citizens of the United States and eliminate race prejudice. Early women founders and members include Mary White Ovington, Ida B. Wells-Barnett, Mary Church Terrell, Mary McCloud Bethune, and Jane Addams.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Patton, John Thomas </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>National Association for the Advancement of Colored People</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African Americans--Societies, etc.--Tennessee--Nashville; African American political activists--Tennessee; African Americans--Political activity--Tennessee</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>National Association for the Advancement of Colored People</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1961-04</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text; Certificates; Certificates of membership</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CHnash_019</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Generations - African American Women's Early Activism in Tennessee</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll23/id/427</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>