<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of Crozier Family Reunion at Little Leaf Baptist Church, 2006</dc:title>
<dc:description>Group color photograph of Crozier Family Reunion at Little Leaf Baptist Church in 2006. From the reunion book: "The Crozier Family history begins with a slave named Adaline (Adeline) born around 1844 who had a son named Jack (Jackson) Crozier. There are over 150 descendants of Jack (Jackson) Crozier who are farmers, teachers, lawyers, engineers, doctors, nurses, artists, government workers, homemakers, entrepreneurs, and professional football players.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Little Leaf Baptist Church</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Group portraits; African Americans--Tennessee--Oliver Springs; African American families--Tennessee--Oliver Springs</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Oliver Springs (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2006</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CHknox_021</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Generations - African American Women's Early Activism in Tennessee</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll23/id/433</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>