<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of the Forget Me Not Art Club, 1921</dc:title>
<dc:description>A black and white photograph of the Forget Me Not Art Club in Franklin, Tennessee. The fourteen women are arranged in three rows all wearing skirts and white shirts with ties. Alice Otey Patton is sitting on the far right of the second row, with her hands in pockets and wearing a striped skirt. The Forget Me Not Art Club was a society club in Franklin, Tennessee. Alice Otey Patton (1886-1960) was a clubwoman and an important figure in Nashville and Franklin's early twentieth century African American community. Alice Otey Patton was involved with the Forget Me Not Club, a society club, and the World Fellowship of the YMCA. Born to Malinda Southall and Flem Otey in Williamson County on November 16, 1886, she later attended Walden University, a historically black college in Nashville. She married John Thomas Patton on December 15, 1915 and became involved in running the Patton Brothers Funeral Home, the oldest African-American funeral home in Middle Tennessee. She died on June 16, 1960 and is buried in Toussaint L'Ouverture Cemetery in Franklin, Tennessee.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Racial segregation barred African American women from white clubs. In response, African American women formed their own clubs. Some clubs were society clubs that offered social activities. Others were community clubs that focused on social causes, activism, and racial uplift work. Whether the club's main goal was to be a society club or an activism club, all clubs functioned as a place for African American women to organize. These sophisticated institutional networks amplified political activity by serving as mass communication systems between neighborhoods, cities, and states.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Patton, Alice Otey, 1886-1960</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Forget Me Not Art Club</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African Americans--Societies, etc.--Tennessee--Franklin; Clubwomen--Tennessee--Franklin; Women--Societies and clubs--Tennessee--Franklin; African Americans--Social life and customs--Tennessee--Franklin; African Americans--Women--Tennessee--Franklin; Group portraits; </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Franklin (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1921</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CHnash_006</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Generations - African American Women's Early Activism in Tennessee</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1920-1929</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll23/id/124</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>