<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of unidentified group of men and women, circa 1920</dc:title>
<dc:description>A black and white photograph of an unidentified group of men and women. The young women are wearing uniforms with sashes. They are arranged in two rows, the front row seated and the back row standing. This was likely a photograph taken of a one-room class in front of their school or chuch.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Education was a key pillar of African American political activity, especially for women. In July 1920, the National Association of Colored Women's Clubs met in Tuskegee Alabama for their annual conference. At the convention a Resolution on Federal Suffrage was passed that established the political agenda for African American women as soon as they obtained suffrage with the 19th Amendment. The political platform included: building libraries, education, healthcare, preserving and documenting black history, temperance, anti-lynching laws, and enforcing the 14th and 15th Amendments. 

African Americans founded and built churches that served multiple civic and community functions. Churches were one of the few places African Americans could gather without the interference or suspicion of white people. Churches became the center of all religious, civic and community life. They provided spaces to educate and organize around social causes, including schools, daycare, voter registrations, veteran services, and racial justice. Because of their multi-purpose use, churches are at the center of African American political activity and serve the secular needs of African Americans that were not equitably provided by federal, state and local authorities.
</dc:description>
<dc:subject> African Americans--Societies, etc.--Tennessee; African Americans--Social life and customs--Tennessee; Portrait photographs; Group portraits;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Tennessee, Middle</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1920</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CHnash_005</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Generations - African American Women's Early Activism in Tennessee</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll23/id/5</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>