<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Group photograph with Alma Roulhac, circa 1920s</dc:title>
<dc:description>Black and white group photograph of women in dresses, posed against a streamer backdrop. Alma Roulhac is seated in the center of the first row. She was the daughter of Dr. Roulhac, African American physician and was best friends with Roberta Church. The only identified person in the photograph is Alma Roulhac.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Portraiture was a highly political activity for African Americans, especially after Emancipation. Frederick Douglass considered photography the most democratic of arts and a crucial aid in African Americans' quest to achieve citizenship because it served as a potent equalizer. Early photographs of African Americans are linked to the first phase of a way of thinking defined as Racial Uplift: an ideology which emphasized education, achievement, and propriety as marks of personal distinction that would refute racist stereotypes and establish a basis for positive black identities. Photography became the way African Americans visually documented their efforts for full citizenship and political enfranchisement. Hooks Brothers photography studio started in Memphis in 1907. It operated throughout most of the 20th century, and was the second oldest African American business in Memphis, closing after a fire in 1979. Robert and Henry Hooks documented the lives of both ordinary and notable African American Memphians, providing an invaluable record of what life was like in early twentieth century Black Memphis.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Roulhac, Alma B.</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Portrait photographs; Group portraits; African Americans; Women; African Americans--Social life and customs--Tennessee--Memphis</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Memphis (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Hooks Brothers (photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>192-?</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CHmem_006</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Generations - African American Women's Early Activism in Tennessee</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1910-1919; 1920-1929</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll23/id/347</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>