<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of Adeline Crozier, circa 1900s</dc:title>
<dc:description>Black and white photograph of Adeline Crozier standing on a front porch holding a hat and wearing a dress with a white apron. The photograph was taken in Oliver Springs, Tennessee in front of the Diggs House, home of a prominent white family in the area. The Diggs House was next to the Little Leaf Baptist Church, an African American church established in 1890. Adeline Crozier was a founding member of the church. She was born in 1845 into slavery. Family tradition believes her father was William (Bill) Staples, a slave owner, and her mother was enslaved but her name is unknown. Adeline Crozier had a son in 1861 named Jackson Crozier, nicknamed Jack, with Clark Crozier, Sr. a white man. She later married Henry Crozier, an African American man with the same last name, but no known relation to Clark Crozier. She had a second husband named Albert Peak. Their occupation is not certain, but they were likely farmers. Adeline Crozier died in 1926 in Oliver Springs.</dc:description>
<dc:description>African Americans founded and built churches that served multiple civic and community functions. Churches were one of the few places African Americans could gather without the interference or suspicion of white people. Churches became the center of all religious, civic and community life. They provided spaces to educate and organize around social causes, including schools, daycare, voter registrations, veteran services, and racial justice. Because of their multi-purpose use, churches are at the center of African American political activity and serve the secular needs of African Americans that were not equitably provided by federal, state and local authorities.
Churches were one of the few places that offered African American women leadership opportunities and gave them platforms to express their educational and political agendas. Because Churches also addressed the civic and secular needs of African Americans, women leaders in church often organized and worked on voter registrations, racial issues, education and healthcare, and other community needs.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Crozier, Adeline, 1861-1926</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Portrait photographs; African Americans; Women; African Americans--Employment--Tennessee--Oliver Springs; African Americans--Women--Tennessee--Oliver Springs</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Oliver Springs (Tenn.);  Oliver Springs (Tenn.)--Race relations</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>190-?</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CHknox_001</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Generations - African American Women's Early Activism in Tennessee</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1900-1910</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll23/id/438</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>