<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Select pages from "The Decree Book of the Church of the Living God, the Pillar and Ground of the Truth," 1923</dc:title>
<dc:description>A thirty-six page booklet, authored by Mother Mary Magdalena Lewis Tate, that contains the doctrines, rules, rituals, constitution, and governing structures for the House of God Church denomination she founded in 1903. Mother Mary Magdalena Lewis Tate believed the Pentecostal evangelist movement would not last without structure and organization, and she wanted to create a more sophisticated framework for the denomination she founded. In 1908 she held a General Assembly and incorporated the church and adopted the first Decree Book in 1914. A handwritten date on the back cover may read 1923. The following pages are missing: 9-10, 17-18, 19-20, and 27-28. Some handwritten notes in pencil appear on the front and back covers, but are not legible. Later additions have been updated and published. This is possibly the oldest surviving copy of the original Decree Book. The House of God, Which is the Church of the Living God, the Pillar and Ground of the Truth Without Controversy, Inc. was founded by Mother Mary Magdalena Lewis Tate with the help of Bishop Keith, her secretary who would go on to be the second leader of the church after Mother Tate died. Mother Tate incorporated the church in 1908. After her death in 1930, the church split into three dominions, Jewell, Keith, and Lewis Dominions. The church took on the name House of God Church Keith Dominion at this point, named after Bishop Keith. It is headquartered in Nashville, Tennessee. Mother Mary Magdalena Lewis Tate (1871-1930) was a traveling evangelist preacher and one of the first African American women to found a Pentecostal church and have women serve in leadership. She preached for her converts to "do right" and evangelized all over the country, with more than twenty charters for new state assemblies undertaken during her overseership. She was born in Vanleer, Tennessee on January 5, 1871, to Belfield Street and Nancy Hall Street. She married David Lewis at the age of nineteen and had two children, Walter Curtis and Felix Early Lewis. She divorced David Lewis, and around that time began traveling and preaching.</dc:description>
<dc:description>African Americans founded and built churches that served multiple civic and community functions. Churches were one of the few places African Americans could gather without the interference or suspicion of white people. Churches became the center of all religious, civic and community life. They provided spaces to educate and organize around social causes, including schools, daycare, voter registrations, veteran services, and racial justice. Because of their multi-purpose use, churches are at the center of African American political activity and serve the secular needs of African Americans that were not equitably provided by federal, state and local authorities.
Churches were one of the few places that offered African American women leadership opportunities and gave them platforms to express their educational and political agendas. Because Churches also addressed the civic and secular needs of African Americans, women leaders in church often organized and worked on voter registrations, racial issues, education and healthcare, and other community needs.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Church of the Living God, the Pillar and Ground of the Truth</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Church of the Living God, the Pillar and Ground of the Truth--Doctrines; African Americans--Religion; African Americans--Women; Women in church work; Women and religion; Evangelists</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Tate, Mary Magdalena Lewis, 1871-1930</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>The Dispatch Publishing Company, circa 1914</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>between 1914 and 1923</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text; Books</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CHnash_025</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Generations - African American Women's Early Activism in Tennessee</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1910-1919; 1920-1929</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll23/id/173</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>