<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Tintype of Mrs. George Land, circa 1870s</dc:title>
<dc:description>Framed black and white tintype of Mrs. George Land with hand tinted photograph of white child framed behind the photograph of Mrs. Land. Mrs. Land is dressed in a long-sleeved high-necked gown, and is holding a hat with feathered decoration. The white child is sitting on a chair draped with fabric. On the reverse of the photograph is the following inscription: "From H. Minnis 506 Pontatoc Ave, Memphis, Tennessee Picture Brust." H. Minnis is believed to be a member of the family for whom Mrs. George Land worked.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Portraiture was a highly political activity for African Americans, especially after Emancipation. Frederick Douglass considered photography the most democratic of arts and a crucial aid in African Americans' quest to achieve citizenship because it served as a potent equalizer. Early photographs of African Americans are linked to the first phase of a way of thinking defined as Racial Uplift: an ideology which emphasized education, achievement, and propriety as marks of personal distinction that would refute racist stereotypes and establish a basis for positive black identities. Photography became the way African Americans visually documented their efforts for full citizenship and political enfranchisement.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Land, George, Mrs.</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Portrait photographs; Tintypes; African Americans; Women; African Americans--Tennessee--Memphis</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Memphis (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>187-?</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CHmem_004</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Generations - African American Women's Early Activism in Tennessee</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869; 1870-1879</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll23/id/358</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>