<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Group Photograph of attendees at Millington Naval Base Christmas Party, 1940s</dc:title>
<dc:description>Black and white photograph of group including Lovelle Fouse Jenkins at a Christmas party during World War II. The attendees are arranged around a Christmas tree in three rows. Lovelle Fouse Jenkins is circled in the picture. She married Ernest Jenkins, a paratrooper with the 101st Airborne. Also identified is her sister Catherine Fouse, fifth person (moving left to right) on the third row. The Naval Support Activity at Mid-South is a naval base located in Millington, Tennessee. It first opened in 1917. 

Lovelle Fouse Jenkins was an awarded educator, pioneering black librarian, and church leader in Memphis, Tennessee. She served in the Shelby County school system for over 40 years, founded three separate libraries, and participated in the 1965 U.S. Office of Education study on the desegregation of schools in Tennessee. She was born in Haywood County, Tennessee on July 24, 1923. Her family moved to Memphis a year later, taking the L &amp; N Train. She attended Greenwood Elementary School, Booker T. Washington High School, and graduated from LeMoyne Owen, the only historically black college in Memphis. She died January 19, 2007. </dc:description>
<dc:description>Librarians and educators were key pillars of African American political activity, especially women. In July 1920, the National Association of Colored Women's Clubs met in Tuskegee Alabama for their annual conference. At the convention a Resolution on Federal Suffrage was passed that established the political agenda for African American women as soon as they obtained suffrage with the 19th Amendment. The political platform included: building libraries, education, healthcare, preserving and documenting black history, temperance, anti-lynching laws, and enforcing the 14th and 15th Amendments.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Jenkins, Lovelle Fouse, 1923-2007; Jenkins, Ernest; Fouse, Catherine</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Portrait photographs; Group portraits; African Americans; Women; World War II; African Americans--Social life and customs--Tennessee--Memphis</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Millington (Tenn.); Memphis (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Hooks Brothers (photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>194-</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CHmem_009</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Generations - African American Women's Early Activism in Tennessee</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll23/id/128</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>