<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Select pages from "Sparkling gems of race knowledge worth reading," 1897</dc:title>
<dc:description>This book was published by the organizers of the Negro Building at the 1897 Tennessee Centennial Exposition held in Nashville Tennessee. Editor James T. Haley's purpose in conceiving this book was to instigate a moral revolution within the black community. By recounting the stories of numerous, successful blacks, Haley hoped to inspire African Americans to adopt the qualities of "thrift, order, virtue, and manliness." The title page has the following inscription: "a compendium of valuable information and wise suggestions that will inspire noble effort at the hands of every race-loving man, woman, and child."</dc:description>
<dc:description>After Emancipation there was a flourishing of encyclopedias and almanacs published illustrating the progress of African American women and men, in areas such as education, health, entrepreneurship, and religion. This mode of documenting and categorizing achievements allowed for a type of self-governance among African Americans who were outside the dominant political system maintained by white Americans. These published works are linked to the first phase of a way of thinking defined as Racial Uplift: an ideology which emphasized education, achievement, and propriety as marks of personal distinction that would refute racist stereotypes and establish a basis for positive black identities. Coupled with photography, these publications became the way African Americans recorded their efforts for full citizenship and political enfranchisement.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Wells-Barnett, Ida B., 1862-1931; Washington, Georgia E. Lee Patton, 1864-1900; Broughton, Virginia W., 1856-1934; Newton, James P.</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African Americans; Printing/Publishing; Books; Scrapbooks; African American political activists--Tennessee--Nashville; African Americans--Social conditions--Tennessee--Nashville; African Americans--Social life and customs--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Haley, James T.; J.T. Haley &amp; Company 1897</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1897</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text; Still Image; Books; Photographs; Scrapbooks</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CHmem_014</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Generations - African American Women's Early Activism in Tennessee</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1890-1899</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll23/id/147</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>