<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of midwives, 1950s</dc:title>
<dc:description>Black and white photograph of a group of ten midwives standing in front of what maybe the one (only?) clinic when it was still in Horn Lake, Mississippi. They are standing and arranged in three rows. The current jail now occupies the site. Arilla Cross is the woman standing far left, front row.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Healthcare was a key pillar of African American political activity, especially for women. In July 1920, the National Association of Colored Women's Clubs met in Tuskegee Alabama for their annual conference. At the convention a Resolution on Federal Suffrage was passed that established the political agenda for African American women as soon as they obtained suffrage with the 19th Amendment. The political platform included: building libraries, education, healthcare, preserving and documenting black history, temperance, anti-lynching laws, and enforcing the 14th and 15th Amendment.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Cross, Arilla</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African Americans; Women; Midwives; African Americans--Employment--Tennessee--Memphis; Race relations--Tennessee--Memphis</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Memphis (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>195-</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CHmem_018</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Generations - African American Women's Early Activism in Tennessee</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll23/id/348</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>