<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of a Republican Women's Club of St. Louis, 1936 October 8</dc:title>
<dc:description>Oversize original black and white photograph of a 1936 luncheon dedicated to Jesse W. Barrett, by the Republican Women's Club of St. Louis located at the Hotel Jefferson on October 8, 1936. The photograph is in several pieces. It features primarily women, both white and black, seated in rows of tables with a plated meal. Several American flags are visible. There is a head table in the background of the photograph. Photograph belonged to Maggie Adams White, originally from Tennessee. She moved to St. Louis, Missouri where she was very active in politics. She was a member of the Republican party and was on a first name basis with many of the local politicians in St. Louis. Jesse W. Barrett was a St. Louis lawyer and politician who was the Republican candidate for governor in 1936, but did not win the election.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Racial segregation barred African American women from white clubs. In response, African American women formed their own clubs. Some clubs were society clubs that offered social activities. Others were community clubs that focused on social causes, activism, and racial uplift work. Whether the club's main goal was to be a society club or an activism club, all clubs functioned as a place for African American women to organize. These sophisticated institutional networks amplified political activity by serving as mass communication systems between neighborhoods, cities, and states. 

The first generations of African American voters after the passage of the 15th Amendment identified as Lincoln Republicans. This was the party associated with Emancipation and therefore the majority of African American voters voted along Republican lines up until the era of the Civil Rights Movement. There were still older African Americans, born at the beginning of the 20th century, who identified as Lincoln Republicans. Notable African American women  republicans during this time period include Mary Church Terrell and Ida B. Wells.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Republican Women's Club (St. Louis, Mo.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Photographs; African Americans--Women; African Americans--Societies, etc.--Missouri--St. Louis; African Americans--Suffrage--Missouri--St. Louis; Women--Societies and clubs--Missouri--St. Louis; Clubwomen--Missouri--St. Louis; Race relations--Missouri--St. Louis</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>St. Louis (Mo.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Sievers St. Louis (photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1936-10-08</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CHmem_079</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Generations - African American Women's Early Activism in Tennessee</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll23/id/335</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>