<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of Velma Lewis Lester reading in a church school, circa 1970s</dc:title>
<dc:description>Black and white photograph of Velma Lewis Lester, dressed in a uniform and bonnet seated and reading to a group of children. The picture was taken at Lewers Chapel C.M.E Church in Abbyville, Lafayette County, Mississippi. In the photograph she is reading in the church's kindergarten class. In the background are various educational aids. Velma Lewis Lester was from Lafayette County, Mississippi. Her father was born into slavery. The land for Lewers Chapel was donated by slave holders to the Black community after emancipation so that a church could be built. During the week, Lewers C.M.E. Church was used as a school and was one of the first Black schools in Lafayette County, Mississippi. Velma Lewis Lester was educated to the fourth grade at another church school, of which she was a member. Velma Lewis Lester continued to educate herself and was an avid reader. Lewers Chapel also served as a voter education and registration site for the Black community. Velma Lewis Lester was involved with getting the women of the church involved with voting and registering to vote.</dc:description>
<dc:description>After emancipation, the first buildings African Americans built were churches that served multiple civic and community functions. Churches were one of the few places African Americans could gather without the interference or suspicion of white people. Churches became the center of all religious, civic, and secular life. They provided spaces to educate and organize around social causes, including schools, daycare, voter registrations, veteran services, and racial injustice. Because of its multi-purpose use, churches are at the intersection of African American political activity and serve the secular needs of African Americans that are not met by the U.S. Government in the public realm. Churches were one of the few places that offered African American women leadership opportunities and gave them platforms to express their educational and political agendas. Because Churches also addressed the civic and secular needs of African Americans, women leaders in church often organized and worked on voter registrations, racial issues, education and healthcare, and other community needs.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Lester, Velma Lewis</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African Americans--Religion; Women and religion--Mississippi--Abbeville; Church and education--Mississippi--Abbeville; Women in church work--Mississippi--Abbeville; African Americans--Education--Mississippi--Abbeville; Women and education</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Abbeville (Miss.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>between 1960 and 1979</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CHmem_061</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Generations - African American Women's Early Activism in Tennessee</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969; 1970-1979</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll23/id/442</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>