<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Portrait of Jackson Crozier, before 1935</dc:title>
<dc:description>Black and white photograph of Jackson Crozier standing in front of the mobile sawmill he owned in Oliver Springs, Tennessee. He moved the sawmill from location to location with a team of mules and relatives. Family tradition states it was in Kentucky at some point. Jackson Crozier was the son of Adeline Crozier, an enslaved woman, and Clark Crozier, Sr., a white man. He was born in 1861 into slavery, and died in 1935. He married Elizabeth ""Lizzie"" Robinson from Anderson County. A bridge in Oliver Springs, Tennessee is named after him. His occupations were logger, farmer, and saw mill operator.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Portraiture was a highly political activity for African Americans, especially after Emancipation. Frederick Douglass considered photography the most democratic of arts and a crucial aid in African Americans' quest to achieve citizenship because it served as a potent equalizer. Early photographs of African Americans are linked to the first phase of a way of thinking defined as Racial Uplift: an ideology which emphasized education, achievement, and propriety as marks of personal distinction that would refute racist stereotypes and establish a basis for positive black identities. Photography became the way African Americans visually documented their efforts for full citizenship and political enfranchisement.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Crozier, Jackson, 1861-1935</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Portrait photographs; African Americans; African Americans--Employment--Tennessee--Oliver Springs; African Americans--Social conditions--Tennessee--Oliver Springs; African Americans--Tennessee--Oliver Springs</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Oliver Springs (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>190-?</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CHknox_002</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Generations - African American Women's Early Activism in Tennessee</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1900-1910</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll23/id/406</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>