<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Selected Pages from American Red Cross Textbook on Red Cross Home Nursing, 1942</dc:title>
<dc:description>Cover, title page, and selected pages from the 1942 American Red Cross Textbook on Red Cross Home Nursing. This volume belonged to Alice Otey Patton and some pages include handwritten notes on early signs of pregnancy. Nursing was at the core of the International Red Cross Movement at its beginning and Clara Barton, founder of the American Red Cross, first came to public attention as an amateur nurse who provided aid to soldiers during the Civil War. In addition to recruiting nurses to serve during war time, the American Red Cross also published Home Nursing Textbooks to educate and create a network of home nurses across the country. Alice Otey Patton (1886-1960) was a clubwoman and an important figure in Nashville and Franklin's early twentieth century African American community. Alice Otey Patton was involved with the Forget Me Not Club, a society club, and the World Fellowship of the YMCA. Born to Malinda Southall and Flem Otey in Williamson County on November 16, 1886, she later attended Walden University, a historically black college in Nashville. She married John Thomas Patton on December 15, 1915 and became involved in running the Patton Brothers Funeral Home, the oldest African-American funeral home in Middle Tennessee. She died on June 16, 1960 and is buried in Toussaint L'Ouverture Cemetery in Franklin, Tennessee.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Healthcare was a key pillar of African American political activity, especially for women. In July 1920, the National Association of Colored Women's Clubs met in Tuskegee Alabama for their annual conference. At the convention a Resolution on Federal Suffrage was passed that established the political agenda for African American women as soon as they obtained suffrage with the 19th Amendment. The political platform included: building libraries, education, healthcare, preserving and documenting black history, temperance, anti-lynching laws, and enforcing the 14th and 15th Amendments. Racial segregation barred African American women from white clubs. In response, African American women formed their own clubs. Some clubs were society clubs that offered social activities. Others were community clubs that focused on social causes, activism, and racial uplift work. Whether the club's main goal was to be a society club or an activism club, all clubs functioned as a place for African American women to organize. These sophisticated institutional networks amplified political activity by serving as mass communication systems between neighborhoods, cities, and states.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>American Red Cross</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Women--Employment--Tennessee--Nashville; African Americans--Women--Tennessee--Nashville; Women--Education--Tennessee--Nashville; African American nurses; Healthcare</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Philadelphia (Penn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Delano, Jane A., 1862-1919</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Blakiston Company, 1942</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1942</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text; Books; Textbooks</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CHnash_020</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Generations - African American Women's Early Activism in Tennessee</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll23/id/405</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>