<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Program for the 91st Annual Women's Day at Spruce Street Baptist Church, 2008</dc:title>
<dc:description>2008 program for the 91st Annual Women's Day Spruce Street Baptist Church in Nashville, Tennessee. The program includes a black and white portrait of Nannie Helen Burroughs. Nannie Helen Burroughs (1879 - 1961) was an educator, religious leader, orator, and prominent advocate for woman suffrage. She helped establish the National Association of Colored Women (NACW) and founded the National Training School for Women and Girls in Washington, DC. In 1906 in Memphis, at the Women's Auxiliary for the National Baptist Convention, she established the National Women's Day to be held annually on the fourth Sunday of July. Its mission was to promote education, missionary work, and leadership for women in the church. In 1915, she published an essay in support of woman suffrage in The Crisis Magazine, the publication for the NAACP. In her essay, she argued that African American women should be given the vote because they were the only ones capable of protecting black women. This was an argument among some African American suffragists, who maintained that white and Black men were susceptible to corruption and that white women were only self interested, and therefore none would be able to understand or prioritize the needs and safety of African American women.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Racial segregation barred African American women from white clubs. In response, African American women formed their own clubs. Some clubs were society clubs that offered social activities. Others were community clubs that focused on social causes, activism, and racial uplift work. Whether the club's main goal was to be a society club or an activism club, all clubs functioned as a place for African American women to organize. These sophisticated institutional networks amplified political activity by serving as mass communication systems between neighborhoods, cities, and states. 
African Americans founded and built churches that served multiple civic and community functions. Churches were one of the few places African Americans could gather without the interference or suspicion of white people. Churches became the center of all religious, civic and community life. They provided spaces to educate and organize around social causes, including schools, daycare, voter registrations, veteran services, and racial justice. Because of their multi-purpose use, churches are at the center of African American political activity and serve the secular needs of African Americans that were not equitably provided by federal, state and local authorities. 
Churches were one of the few places that offered African American women leadership opportunities and gave them platforms to express their educational and political agendas. Because Churches also addressed the civic and secular needs of African Americans, women leaders in church often organized and worked on voter registrations, racial issues, education and healthcare, and other community needs.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Burroughs, Nannie Helen, 1879-1961</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Portrait photographs; African Americans--Women; African American political activists; African Americans--Suffrage; Women--Suffrage</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>between 1900 and 1920</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CHnash_021</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Generations - African American Women's Early Activism in Tennessee</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1900-1909; 1910-1919</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll23/id/227</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>