<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Scrapbook of Hattye Mae Thomas Yarbrough, 1938-1941</dc:title>
<dc:description>Green string bound photograph album belonging to Hattye Mae Thomas Yarbrough. The cover of the scrapbook reads ""Photographs"" and there are two embossed elks on the bottom right hand cover. Hattye Mae Thomas Yarbrough made this album in early highschool, around 1938. She was in high school from 1938 to 1941. Mrs. Yarbrough was team captain for her basketball team and her nickname was Warhorse. She graduated with honors from Central High School in Paris, Tennessee. She went to Vanderbilt Peabody College and received her degree in Library Science.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Scrapbooking, along with professional encyclopedias and almanacs, became a method of self-documentation for African Americans. This mode of documenting and categorizing achievements allowed for a type of self-governance among African Americans who were outside the dominant political system maintained by white Americans. These works are linked to the first phase of a way of thinking defined as Racial Uplift: an ideology which emphasized education, achievement, and propriety as marks of personal distinction that would refute racist stereotypes and establish a basis for positive black identities. Coupled with photography, these publications became the way African Americans recorded their efforts for full citizenship and political enfranchisement.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Lewis, C. W., Dr.; Todd, Lynwood; Clark, Juanita "Nita"; Sims, Tom; Carlester, Olive; Jackson, Mae Sue;  Hartsfield, Mrs.; Pruitt, Louise; Andrews, Ruth Ann; Jarrett, Vernon Dunbar "Dunny"; Jackson, Ada Belle; L.T.; Pruitt, George; Dumas, James; Sims, Venus; Sims, Vera Mae; Sims, Rosalea; Woodson, Clarence; Woodson, Wilberena; Person, Emma; Thomas, Earlene; Turner, John; Lewis, Harrold; Henry, Allene; Jarrett, Annie Sybil Thomas, 1881-1975; Combs, Hattie 'Sis';  Bills, Lemon; Parham, Clifton; Anderson, Julia</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Central High School (Paris, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Scrapbooks; Albums (Books); Portrait photographs; Manuscripts; African Americans--Education--Tennessee--Paris; High Schools; African Americans--Social life and customs--Tennessee--Paris</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Paris (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Yarbrough, Hattye Mae Thomas</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>between 1938 and 1941</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text; Books; Still Image; Photographs; Scrapbooks</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CHmem_051</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Generations - African American Women's Early Activism in Tennessee</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939; 1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll23/id/383</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>