<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Select pages from "The National Cyclopedia of the Colored Race," 1919</dc:title>
<dc:description>The title pages of a 1919 publication titled "The National Cyclopedia of the Colored Race." The volume includes a number of photographs and profiles of African American men and women. The editor-in-chief was Clement Richardson, a faculty member at Tuskegee Institute who became president of Lincoln Institute. "The National Cyclopedia of the Colored Race" was an encyclopedia about subjects of interest to African Americans. It was financed by a New Orleans-based group of African Americans and published by the National Publishing Company of Montgomery, Alabama. An inner page of this copy is signed by John Thomas Patton, husband of Alice Otey Patton.</dc:description>
<dc:description>After Emancipation there was a flourishing of encyclopedias and almanacs published illustrating the progress of African American women and men, in areas such as education, health, entrepreneurship, and religion. This mode of documenting and categorizing achievements allowed for a type of self-governance among African Americans who were outside the dominant political system maintained by white Americans. These published works are linked to the first phase of a way of thinking defined as Racial Uplift: an ideology which emphasized education, achievement, and propriety as marks of personal distinction that would refute racist stereotypes and establish a basis for positive black identities. Coupled with photography, these publications became the way African Americans recorded their efforts for full citizenship and political enfranchisement.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Tuskegee Institute</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Printing/Publishing; Books; African Americans--Political activity--Alabama--Montgomery; African Americans--Societies, etc.--Alabama--Montgomery; African Americans--Social conditions--Alabama--Montgomery</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Montgomery (Ala.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Richardson, Clement</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>National Publishing Company, Inc., 1919</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1919</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text; Books; Encyclopedias &amp; dictionaries</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CHnash_015</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Generations - African American Women's Early Activism in Tennessee</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1910-1919</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll23/id/208</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>