<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Stereocard of Memphis Exhibit, Negro Building, Atlanta Exposition, 1895</dc:title>
<dc:description>A stereocard depicting the Memphis Exhibit for the Negro Building at the 1895 Atlanta Exposition. Pictured are four African Americans, two women and two men, in an interior setting. The words Shelby County Tennessee can be seen in the upper right corner of the frames. The Memphis Exhibit was organized by Julia Britton Hooks of Memphis, Tennessee. Julia Britton Hooks, an African American clubwoman known as the ""Angel of Beale Street,"" was born free in 1852 in Frankfort, Kentucky. Hooks was a charter member of the Memphis chapter of the NAACP and was the grandmother of the national director of the organization, Benjamin J. Hooks. Julia Hooks became a leader in African American cultural and educational affairs, and participant in the suffrage movement. A stereocard is depictions of the same image from two different angles, that when placed in a stereoscope make the image appear three dimensional.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The Atlanta Exposition was controversial in the African American community, and national leaders Ida B. Wells and Fredrick Douglass encouraged African Americans not to participate. At the Atlanta Exposition, Booker T. Washington delivered the famous Atlanta Compromise speech and laid a proposed foundation for race relations in the Southern United States. African Americans would submit to white political rule in exchange for basic education, due process of law, and economic stability. This included not making demands for the right to vote.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Cotton States Exposition (1895 : Atlanta, Ga.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Stereographs; Buildings; African Americans; Cotton States Exposition (1895 : Atlanta, Ga.); African Americans--Political activity--Tennessee--Memphis; African Americans--Political activity--Georgia--Atlanta; African Americans--Social life and customs; African Americans--Social conditions</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Atlanta (Ga.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Kilburn, B. W. (photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1895</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CHmem_005</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Generations - African American Women's Early Activism in Tennessee</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1890-1899</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll23/id/341</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>