<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of Joseph Falls, circa 1950</dc:title>
<dc:description>Black and white photograph of Joseph Falls, the husband of Reverend Montee Falls. He wears a suit and is angled to the camera. He acted as an assistant minister at Unity Center of Memphis, a Unity denomination church. He was a high school principal and a brick mason. He worked on a number of the buildings in downtown Memphis, Tennessee. He bought land in the Memphis, Tennessee community of Whitehaven and built his own home. He also owned houses and land in Cordova, another Memphis, Tennessee community.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Portraiture was a highly political activity for African Americans, especially after Emancipation. Frederick Douglass considered photography the most democratic of arts and a crucial aid in African Americans' quest to achieve citizenship because it served as a potent equalizer. Early photographs of African Americans are linked to the first phase of a way of thinking defined as Racial Uplift: an ideology which emphasized education, achievement, and propriety as marks of personal distinction that would refute racist stereotypes and establish a basis for positive black identities. Photography became the way African Americans visually documented their efforts for full citizenship and political enfranchisement. 

African Americans founded and built churches that served multiple civic and community functions. Churches were one of the few places African Americans could gather without the interference or suspicion of white people. Churches became the center of all religious, civic and community life. They provided spaces to educate and organize around social causes, including schools, daycare, voter registrations, veteran services, and racial justice. Because of their multi-purpose use, churches are at the center of African American political activity and serve the secular needs of African Americans that were not equitably provided by federal, state and local authorities.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Falls, Joseph</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Portrait photographs; African Americans--Tennessee--Memphis</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Memphis (Tenn.) </dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Hooks Brothers (photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1950</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CHmem_075</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Generations - African American Women's Early Activism in Tennessee</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll23/id/11</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>