<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Select pages from "Pictorial history of the American Negro," circa 1933</dc:title>
<dc:description>Select pages from the book "Pictorial history of the American Negro by Thomas O. Fuller. The book was published in 1933 and includes photographs of important institutions and individuals in the African American community. Thomas O. Fuller was a prominent African American church and civic leader, and author in early twentieth-century Memphis. He was also a prolific writer of books and publications aimed at increasing African American pride, including his own autobiography. Fuller hoped by providing African American history missing from traditional American history narratives, these publications would empower Black youth to continue the established progress of their forefathers.</dc:description>
<dc:description>After Emancipation there was a flourishing of encyclopedias and almanacs published illustrating the progress of African American women and men, in areas such as education, health, entrepreneurship, and religion. This mode of documenting and categorizing achievements allowed for a type of self-governance among African Americans who were outside the dominant political system maintained by white Americans. These published works are linked to the first phase of a way of thinking defined as Racial Uplift: an ideology which emphasized education, achievement, and propriety as marks of personal distinction that would refute racist stereotypes and establish a basis for positive Black identities. Coupled with photography, these publications became the way African Americans recorded their efforts for full citizenship and political enfranchisement.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Cole-Talbert, Florence, 1890-1961</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Memphis Music Association</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Portrait photographs; African Americans; Print/Publishing; Books; Buildings; Architecture--Tennessee--Memphis; African Americans--Political activity--Tennessee--Memphis; African Americans--Social life and customs--Tennessee--Memphis; African Americans--Social conditions--Tennessee--Memphis</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Memphis (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Fuller, Thomas O. (Thomas Oscar), 1867-1942, author; Pictorial History, Inc., 1933, publisher</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 3721</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1933</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text; Still Image; Books; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CHmem_016</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Generations - African American Women's Early Activism in Tennessee</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1933-1939</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll23/id/223</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>