<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of Mt. Olive Baptist Sunday School Meeting, 1935</dc:title>
<dc:description>A black and white photograph of Baptists gathered outside the Patton family home across from Hadley Park in Nashville, Tennessee in 1935. They are arranged in a tight circle, seated in folding chairs. The event was a joint meeting of the Galeda and Metoka classes of the Mt. Olive Baptist Sunday School that was held at the residence of Alice Otey Patton, whose husband was Reverend John Thomas Patton. Dr. John L. Hill, book editor for the Sunday school board of the Southern Baptist convention, was the guest speaker. The gathering brought together both black and white members of the Baptist community. </dc:description>
<dc:description>African Americans founded and built churches that served multiple civic and community functions. Churches were one of the few places African Americans could gather without the interference or suspicion of white people. Churches became the center of all religious, civic and community life. They provided spaces to educate and organize around social causes, including schools, daycare, voter registrations, veteran services, and racial justice. Because of their multi-purpose use, churches are at the center of African American political activity and serve the secular needs of African Americans that were not equitably provided by federal, state and local authorities.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Patton, Alice Otey, 1886-1960; Patton, John Thomas, Rev.; Hill, John L. (John Leonard), 1878-1964</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Mt. Olive Baptist Church</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African Americans--Religion--Tennessee--Nashville; Church work--Tennessee--Nashville; Women and religion--Tennessee--Nashville; African Americans--Women--Tennessee--Nashville; Church and education--Tennessee--Nashville; Baptists--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.); Nashville (Tenn.)--Race relations</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1935</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CHnash_018</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Generations - African American Women's Early Activism in Tennessee</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll23/id/4</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>