<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of Gertrude Bridgeforth, circa 1948</dc:title>
<dc:description>A black and white photograph of 23 year old Gertrude Bridgeforth at the Memphis Fairgrounds. She is seated on a bench, with the sign "Memphis Fairgrounds" depicted in the background. The back of the photo identifies Gertrude Bridgeforth and includes an address and her date of birth.  At about the time this photo was taken, she would drive her father, Frazier Guy, Sr., around the surrounding counties (Nesbet County) to register African Americans to vote. One church they would visit was Avery Church on Church Road. A white man named Bob from Chicago came down and stayed with her family. She remembers they hid him, and then Bob would help get African Americans registered. 

The Memphis Fairgrounds were in operation as a fairgrounds from 1912-2008, when the Mid-South fair moved to DeSoto County.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Bridgeforth, Gertrude</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Portrait photographs; African Americans; Women; African Americans--Suffrage--Tennessee--Memphis</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Memphis (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>circa 1948</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CHmem_017</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Generations - African American Women's Early Activism in Tennessee</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll23/id/122</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>