<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of East Trigg Baptist Church members, 1930s</dc:title>
<dc:description>Black and white photograph of mostly children and adults posing for a group portrait inside of East Trigg Baptist Church. Inscribed on the photograph off to the right hand side are the names Herbert and Bobbie. East Trigg Baptist Church first opened in Memphis in 1902 and has had eight pastors, including Reverend William Herbert Brewster. Reverend Brewster was an influential and prolific Gospel music composer honored by the Smithsonian for his work. 
Frank and Lucille Douglass are also a founding family of the historic black church. Lucille Douglass was an educator and part of one of the founding families of East Trigg Baptist Church, a historic African American Baptist church in Memphis. According to family tradition, she had aspirations of being an educator despite the fact that she never went to college or obtained a formal education. She taught the bible school and spiritual development classes at East Trigg Baptist Church. She was married to Frank Douglass, a founding deacon of East Trigg Baptist Church, who is memorialized on a plaque on the original site of East Trigg Baptist Church. </dc:description>
<dc:description>African Americans founded and built churches that served multiple civic and community functions. Churches were one of the few places African Americans could gather without the interference or suspicion of white people. Churches became the center of all religious, civic and community life. They provided spaces to educate and organize around social causes, including schools, daycare, voter registrations, veteran services, and racial justice. Because of their multi-purpose use, churches are at the center of African American political activity and serve the secular needs of African Americans that were not equitably provided by federal, state and local authorities.
Churches are also one of the few places that offered African American women leadership opportunities and gave them platforms to express their educational and political agendas. Because Churches also addressed the civic and secular needs of African Americans, women leaders in church often organized and worked on voter registrations, racial issues, education and healthcare, and other community needs. Education was a key pillar of African American political activity, especially for women. In July 1920, the National Association of Colored Women's Clubs met in Tuskegee, Alabama for their annual conference. At the convention a Resolution on Federal Suffrage was passed that established the political agenda for African American women as soon as they obtained suffrage with the 19th Amendment. The political platform included: building libraries, education, healthcare, preserving and documenting black history, temperance, anti-lynching laws, and enforcing the 14th and 15th Amendments.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Group portraits; Church and education--Tennessee--Memphis; African Americans--Education--Tennessee--Memphis; Women in church work--Tennessee--Memphis; African Americans--Social life and customs--Tennessee--Memphis</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Memphis (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>193-</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CHmem_026</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Generations - African American Women's Early Activism in Tennessee</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll23/id/434</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>