<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of Minnie Mae Crozier with husband William Julian Hopper, circa 1910</dc:title>
<dc:description>Hand colored black and white photograph of Minnie Mae Crozier with her husband William Julian Hopper. Minnie Mae Crozier was born in 1889 and died in 1966. Her parents were Elizabeth and Jackson Crozier. William Julian Hopper was born in Georgia in 1889 and died in 1942. They were farmers, worked on the railroad, and were traveling produce sellers for their farm produce. Minnie Mae Crozier Hopper was also a seamstress. They lived in Oliver Springs, Tennessee.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Portraiture was a highly political activity for African Americans, especially after Emancipation. Frederick Douglass considered photography the most democratic of arts and a crucial aid in African Americans&#8217; quest to achieve citizenship because it served as a potent equalizer. Early photographs of African Americans are linked to the first phase of a way of thinking defined as Racial Uplift: an ideology which emphasized education, achievement, and propriety as marks of personal distinction that would refute racist stereotypes and establish a basis for positive Black identities. Photography became the way African Americans visually documented their efforts for full citizenship and political enfranchisement.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Crozier, Minnie Mae, 1889-1966; Hopper, William Julian, 1889-1942</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Portrait photographs; Group portraits; African Americans; African Americans--Social conditions--Tennessee--Oliver Springs</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Oliver Springs (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>191-?</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CHknox_005</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Generations - African American Women's Early Activism in Tennessee</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1910-1919</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll23/id/418</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>