<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Prize Medal for Cotton from the Crystal Palace Exhibition, London, (awarded to Dr. Samuel Bond), 1851</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <titleInfo>
    <title type="alternative">Front view of Medal for Cotton, Great Exhibition of the Industry of All Nations, London, 1851</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <name>
    <namePart>Wyon, Leonard C. (1826-1891)</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cre">Creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated encoding="edtf" keyDate="yes">1851</dateCreated>
    <publisher>Memphis Brooks Museum of Art</publisher>
  </originInfo>
  <physicalDescription/>
  <location>
    <physicalLocation>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</physicalLocation>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/296</url>
    <url access="preview">http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/shades/id/296</url>
    <url note="iiif-manifest">http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/iiif/info/shades/296/manifest.json</url>
  </location>
  <abstract>This round bronze medal features a double portrait of Queen Victoria and Price Albert shown in profile. Stamped letters around the edge of the medal include the year in Roman numerals (MDCCCLI) at bottom center and "Royal Mint" to the immediate right. The name S. Bond is engraved on the edge.</abstract>
  <accessCondition type="local rights statement">Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact the Memphis Brooks Museum of Art.</accessCondition>
  <subject>
    <topic>Taking Care of Business</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <geographic authority="naf" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n2007043373">Memphis (Tenn.)</geographic>
    <cartographics>
      <coordinates>35.14953, -90.04898</coordinates>
    </cartographics>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <temporal encoding="edtf" keyDate="yes">1850/1859</temporal>
  </subject>
  <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Project">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Shades of Gray and Blue</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <abstract>In Tennessee, we have all heard stories of life and death on the state’s Civil War battlefields, but what happened to the men, women, and children who stayed at home? Their stories, seen through the lens of the objects that were a part of their daily lives, reflect the ways Tennesseans adapted, coped, and thrived during a war whose reverberations are still felt today. Visit the Shades of Gray and Blue project site for additional options for browsing the collection, contextual essays, and lesson plans. This project is a collaborative effort of the Middle Tennessee State University Walker Library, the Center for Historic Preservation at Middle Tennessee State University, and Vanderbilt University Libraries.</abstract>
    <location>
      <url>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/landingpage/collection/shades</url>
    </location>
  </relatedItem>
  <note displayLabel="Intermediate Provider">Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library,
                Middle Tennessee State University</note>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Memphis Brooks Museum of Art</recordContentSource>
    <recordChangeDate>2023-05-12-04:00</recordChangeDate>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
    <recordOrigin>Record has been transformed into MODS 3.5 from a qualified Dublin Core
                record by the Digital Library of Tennessee, a service hub of the Digital Public
                Library of America, using a stylesheet available at https://github.com/utkdigitalinitiatives/DLTN.
                Metadata originally created in a locally modified version of qualified Dublin Core
                using ContentDM (data dictionary available:
                https://wiki.lib.utk.edu/display/DPLA.)</recordOrigin>
  </recordInfo>
</mods>
