<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:dltn="https://github.com/digitallibraryoftennessee" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Warehouses on Second Avenue</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/">Copyright Not Evaluated</accessCondition>
  <location>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll25/id/1434</url>
    <url access="preview">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p15138coll25/id/1434</url>
  </location>
  <abstract>Street view of the warehouses on Second Avenue showing the Pilcher Building (on the right), Cheek-Neal Building (center), and Spring Brook Buildings (left). Signs for businesses include the B &amp; B Warehouse, Nashville Sash &amp; Door Company, and Nashville Products Inc. The Nashville Sash &amp; Door Company has advertisements for Raynor overhead doors and LOF glass hanging from the storefront. There street and sidewalk are empty. The Spring Brook Buildings have air conditioner units in several of the windows.</abstract>
  <abstract>The Pilcher Building, located at 144 and 146 Second Avenue, was constructed in 1902 for Andrew Pilcher. At the time, it served as his offices and grain business. The building is a four-story, commercial-style brick building with two bays. Three brackets support the cornice. A stone inset on the exterior reads “Pilcher.” On July 6, 1905, the building suffered from a fire and required rebuilding. The damage from the fire amounted to a loss of around $146,000. Occupants have included: Phillips, Webb &amp; Co., Smith, Herrin &amp; Baird Mfg. Co, M. E. Derryberry &amp; Co., and Jones &amp; Hopkins Mfg. Co. The Cheek-Neal Coffee Co. building, located at 148, 150, and 152 Second Avenue, is a four-story Italianate style brick building constructed around 1880. The building consists of three bays with ironwork on the storefront. The façade includes a large cornice, corbelled brick, a limestone stringcourse, and pilasters with capitals. All of the windows are arched. The location is well known as Joel Owsley Cheek, the founder of Maxwell House Coffee, opened Nashville Coffee &amp; Mfg. Co., later Cheek-Neal Coffee Co., at 148 Second Avenue. Other occupants of the building have included: Deeds &amp; Hirsig Mfg. Co., Clements Paper Co., and Alloway Bros. Co. The Spring Brook Buildings, consisting of 154, 156, 158, 160, and 162 Second Avenue, are three-story Italianate style brick buildings constructed in 1869. Brackets support a sizeable overhanging cornice that runs across the roofline of all the buildings. The façade includes stone block pilasters that separate the buildings and stone stringcourses between upper floors. All of the buildings have arched windows with cast-iron hood molds. Each of the storefronts has slight variations. The property was purchased in 1868 by John T. Foote, who built the block for around $140,000. Occupants at the Spring Brook buildings have included McCrea &amp; Co., Orr Bros., Kirkpatrick Bros., and Orr, Scoggins &amp; Hume Grocery.</abstract>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Tennessee State Library and Archives</recordContentSource>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
  </recordInfo>
  <subject>
    <topic>Tennessee--History</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Streets--Tennessee</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Historic districts--Tennessee</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Historic districts</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Historic buildings</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Architecture--Details</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Business districts</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Commercial streets</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Structural elements</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Architectural elements</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Storefronts</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Facades</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Stores &amp; shops</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Brickwork</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Cornices</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Pilasters</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Stringcourses</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Warehouses</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Windows</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Millwork</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Advertisements</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <geographic>Nashville (Tenn.)</geographic>
  </subject>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Library Photograph Collection</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Tennessee State Library and Archives</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <physicalDescription>
    <form>Photographs</form>
  </physicalDescription>
</mods>
