<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Arrangements for the inauguration of the President Elect, on the fourth of March, 1845</dc:title>
<dc:description>This document provides a detailed description of the ceremony plans and procedures for President James K. Polk's inauguration. The plans were prepared by the Committee of Arrangements of the Senate on February 26, 1845.</dc:description>
<dc:description>James Knox Polk was born on November 2, 1795 in Pineville, North Carolina and moved to Tennessee to study law. Over time, he was elected to the Tennessee legislature and eventually to the United States House of Representatives in 1825. From 1835 to 1839, Polk served as the Speaker of the House of Representatives. In 1839, Polk left Congress to serve as the Governor of Tennessee. In 1844, Polk became the eleventh president of the United States. Polk gave his inaugural address in Washington, D.C. on March 4, 1845, from a special platform that had been constructed over the Capitol steps. Many people gathered to hear the speech, but rain spoiled the occasion. During his presidency, the United States expanded significantly with the annexation of the Republic of Texas, the Oregon Treaty, and the conclusion of the Mexican-American War. Polk died on June 15, 1849.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1845 March 4</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>Washington (D.C.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>Polk Memorial Association Collection of James Knox Polk (1795-1849) Papers 1780-1972</dc:source>
<dcterms:references>https://sos.tn.gov/products/tsla/polk-memorial-association-collection-james-knox-polk-papers-1780-1972</dcterms:references>
<dc:source>71-228, 77-013</dc:source>
<dcterms:instructionalMethod>4.63; 8.61; James K. Polk; Growth of the Republic</dcterms:instructionalMethod>
<dc:subject>Polk, James Knox, --1795 - 1849; Presidents; Presidents--United States--Inauguration</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Documents</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>43835</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>I-J-3 &amp; I-J-5, Box 2, Folder 1</dc:source>
<dcterms:isPartOf>James K. Polk Collection;</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Images/jpeg</dc:format>
<dcterms:medium>Documents</dcterms:medium>
<dc:rights>No copyright - United States: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll43/id/13</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>