<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>"I-40 Resolution OK'd by Court"</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <accessCondition type="local rights statement">All rights reserved. The accompanying digital objects and associated documentation are provided for online research and access purposes. Permission to use, copy, modify, distribute and present this digital object and the accompanying documentation, without fee, and without written agreement, is hereby granted for educational, non-commercial purposes only. The Rhodes College Archives and Special Collections reserves the right to decide what constitutes educational and commercial use. In all instances of use, acknowledgement must be given to Rhodes College Archives Digital Repository, Memphis, TN. For information regarding permission to use this image, please email the Archives at archives@rhodes.edu.</accessCondition>
  <location>
    <url access="object in context" usage="primary display">http://hdl.handle.net/10267/29608</url>
    <url access="preview">http://dlynx.rhodes.edu:8080/jspui/bitstream/10267/29608/5/OPE-22_038.jpg.jpg</url>
  </location>
  <originInfo>
    <publisher>Commercial Appeal</publisher>
    <dateOther>2017-08-30T22:22:50Z</dateOther>
  </originInfo>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n88258779">Rhodes College</recordContentSource>
    <recordChangeDate>2019-06-05-04:00</recordChangeDate>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
    <recordOrigin>Record has been transformed into MODS 3.5 from a Qualified Dublin Core record by the Digital Library of Tennessee, a service hub of the Digital Public Library of America, using a stylesheet available at https://github.com/digitallibraryoftennessee/DLTN_XSLT. Metadata originally created in a locally modified version of Qualified Dublin Core using ContentDM (data dictionary available: https://wiki.lib.utk.edu/display/DPLA).</recordOrigin>
  </recordInfo>
  <subject>
    <topic>Overton Park (Memphis, Tenn.)</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Sternberg, Irma O., 1915-2007</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Text</topic>
  </subject>
  <abstract>The county court yesterday approved a resolution "favoring the earliest possible completion date of I-40" through Overton Park.</abstract>
</mods>
