<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:dltn="https://github.com/digitallibraryoftennessee" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Church of the Lord Jesus Christ service, 1995 January 14</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <abstract>Video recording of a service opened by Bill Pelfrey and Carl Porter, who begins the service with a prayer. Carl Porter addresses the congregation and urges members to get into service. When he is done speaking, music and singing has everyone standing and many join in the song and keep rhythm on tambourines or by clapping. As the song progresses, Junior McCormick takes up two serpents and handles before passing one on to other members. A lull in the music is filled with McCormick giving testimony as he handles a serpent. Music and handling continue again until Carl Porter begins to testify. He holds a large serpent as he testifies, and other members of the church can be seen with serpents also. One man handles several serpents. David Kimbrough handles brefly as well. As music once again fills the church, members dance and some are overcome in spirit. Music pauses once again as members make contributions to the church. Though this, Carl Porter preaches to the congregation. As he does, he takes a drink from a jar of strychnine, before passing it to Bill Pelfrey and Billy Lemming who both drink. Carl Porter finishes her sermon and the music begins again. Carl Porter leads members of the congregation to the grunt of the church to dance and as they worship, he and others lay hands on several of them. A female member of the church stands in the center of the crowded floor and is overcome in spirit. She collapses to the floor. The camera pans away from the crowd as she collapses, but she is seen lying upon the ground moments later. A cut in the film shows her standing once again in the crowd. Members and church leaders continue to lay hands on congregants and some are anointed with oil. Many congregants sing and dance with considerable fervor, and a child comes forward to be blessed and anointed with oil by Porter and other brothers of the church. The child is followed by another man who shudders and is nearly overcome in spirit. Many others follow. The music comes to a halt and gives way to the testimony of a church member. He is followed by several church leaders who deliver sermons. Other members of the congregation who testify until the video ends.</abstract>
  <name>
    <namePart>Hood, Ralph W.</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cre">Creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <name>
    <namePart>Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cre">Creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <name>
    <namePart>Hood, Ralph W.  Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cph">Copyright holder</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <subject>
    <topic>Appalachian Region, Southern -- Religious life and customs</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Dance -- Religious aspects</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Extemporaneous preaching</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Imposition of hands</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Lay preaching</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Pentecostal preaching</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Prayer</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Singing -- Religious aspects</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Slain in the Spirit</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Snake cults (Holiness churches) -- Appalachian Region, Southern</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Witness bearing (Christianity)</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Brown, John Wayne, Jr., 1964-1998</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Coots, Jamie, (Gregory James), 1971-2014</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Dunn, Rayford</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Kimbrough, David L., 1951-</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Lemming, Billy</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>McCormick, Junior</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Miller, Shade</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Pelfrey, Bill</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Porter, Carl</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Church of the Lord Jesus Christ (Kingston, Ga.)</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <geographic>Kingston (Ga.)</geographic>
  </subject>
  <language>
    <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
  </language>
  <identifier type="local">MS-074-04-02</identifier>
  <identifier type="local">K-2</identifier>
  <originInfo>
    <publisher>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</publisher>
    <dateCreated encoding="edtf" point="start">1995-01-14</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/"/>
  <location>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16877coll2/id/81</url>
    <url access="preview">http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p16877coll2/id/81</url>
  </location>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Church of the Lord Jesus Christ recordings and photographs</title>
      <title>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson field recordings, interviews, and photographs</title>
      <title>Special Collections</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <relatedItem displayLabel="Collection">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson Holiness Churches of Appalachia recordings and interviews</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <physicalDescription>
    <internetMediaType>video/mp4</internetMediaType>
    <extent>02:02:48</extent>
    <form>Moving Image</form>
    <form>field recordings</form>
  </physicalDescription>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</recordContentSource>
    <recordChangeDate>2023-05-24-04:00</recordChangeDate>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
    <recordOrigin>Record has been transformed into MODS 3.5 from a Qualified Dublin Core record by the Digital Library of Tennessee, a service hub of the Digital Public Library of America, using a stylesheet available at https://github.com/digitallibraryoftennessee/DLTN_XSLT. Metadata originally created in a locally modified version of Qualified Dublin Core using ContentDM (data dictionary available: https://dltn-technical-docs.readthedocs.io).</recordOrigin>
  </recordInfo>
</mods>
