<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:dltn="https://github.com/digitallibraryoftennessee" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Church of the Lord Jesus Christ service, 1999 May 30</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <abstract>Video recording of a service opening with Junior McCormick asking for prayer requests. Members including Brice Anderson ask prayers of the congregation. When all members have spoken their prayer requests Junior McCormick testifies and asks permission of a film crew to take pictures while the service is in session. He calls members to prayer and several come to the altar to pray, others pray in their seats. While members pray, musicians set up. A blind visitor to the church, identified as Don plays guitar lap steel style, though he doesn’t use the steel slide for which the style is named. Members come to their feet as the music begins, and Junior McCormick sings as the guitarists play. After McCormick sings, he invites Don to play and encourages members to glorify God. After a brief pause to deal with some sound issues, Don introduces himself and begins to play and sing. Don says a few words about the acoustics before he turns the floor back over to the congregation. Lucille Church plays keyboard as Junior McCormick sings and members dance and keep rhythm while another member of the church plays harmonica. James Wade testifies during a musical interlude and when he is done, he leads the congregation in song. His song is followed by that of another female member of the congregation after Aunt Daisy gives her testimony. When the singing begins again, Aunt Daisy comes forward to hold the Bible high and pray at the altar. Carl Porter removes a serpent form its enclosure and he, Junior McCormick, Billy Summerford, Lucille Church, Barbara Coleman, James Wade, Gene Sherbert, Lydia Hollins, Cynthia Porter and a man named Tony handle at various times. The songs are followed by testimonies from various members of the congregation. When they are done, Don plays piano and sings as members receive an imposition of hands. Lydia Hollins joins in the song while she handles, and before long, the music pauses and Don testifies once again. Lydia Hollins plays and sings thereafter and her song incites the congregation to dance. As she sings, members again handle serpents. Other members sing and variously handle serpents. Serpents are habitually placed on the pulpit, taken up and returned as the handling and songs continue. More members testify during pauses in the music. The video cuts off during one such testimony and reopens on a different service led by Carl Porter who speaks as the donation basket is passed around. Brice Anderson is called to the pulpit and he testifies and preaches. The end of his sermon is coupled with music and members come to the altar to pray while he addresses individual members of the congregation.</abstract>
  <name>
    <namePart>Hood, Ralph W.</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cre">Creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <name>
    <namePart>Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cre">Creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <name>
    <namePart>Hood, Ralph W.  Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cph">Copyright holder</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <subject>
    <topic>Appalachian Region, Southern -- Religious life and customs</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Dance -- Religious aspects</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Expository preaching</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Homecoming</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Imposition of hands</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Lay preaching</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Prayer</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Singing -- Religious aspects</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Snake cults (Holiness churches) -- Appalachian Region, Southern</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Witness bearing (Christianity)</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Anderson, Brice</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Church, Lucille</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Coleman, Barbra</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Hollins, Lydia</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>McCormick, Junior</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Porter, Carl</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Porter, Cynthia</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Porter, Virgil</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Sherbert, Gene</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Summerford, Billy</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Summerford, Joyce</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Wade, James</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Church of the Lord Jesus Christ (Kingston, Ga.)</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <geographic>Kingston (Ga.)</geographic>
  </subject>
  <language>
    <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
  </language>
  <identifier type="local">MS-074-04-42</identifier>
  <identifier type="local">K-42</identifier>
  <originInfo>
    <publisher>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</publisher>
    <dateCreated encoding="edtf" point="start">1999-05-30</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/"/>
  <location>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16877coll2/id/116</url>
    <url access="preview">http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p16877coll2/id/116</url>
  </location>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Church of the Lord Jesus Christ recordings and photographs</title>
      <title>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson field recordings, interviews, and photographs</title>
      <title>Special Collections</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <relatedItem displayLabel="Collection">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson Holiness Churches of Appalachia recordings and interviews</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <physicalDescription>
    <internetMediaType>video/mp4</internetMediaType>
    <extent>02:42:07</extent>
    <form>Moving Image</form>
    <form>field recordings</form>
  </physicalDescription>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</recordContentSource>
    <recordChangeDate>2023-05-24-04:00</recordChangeDate>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
    <recordOrigin>Record has been transformed into MODS 3.5 from a Qualified Dublin Core record by the Digital Library of Tennessee, a service hub of the Digital Public Library of America, using a stylesheet available at https://github.com/digitallibraryoftennessee/DLTN_XSLT. Metadata originally created in a locally modified version of Qualified Dublin Core using ContentDM (data dictionary available: https://dltn-technical-docs.readthedocs.io).</recordOrigin>
  </recordInfo>
</mods>
