<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:dltn="https://github.com/digitallibraryoftennessee" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Church of the Lord Jesus Christ service, 1997 May 23</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <abstract>Video recording of a service opening with music. Lydia Hollins plays organ, Roy “Bootie” Christian and Billy Lemming play guitar. A pause in the music reveals a woman speaking in tongues. Glen Dukes asks the congregation to pray for an abducted girl’s safety. The film cuts to members praying at the pulpit and in their pews. Following the prayer, Billy Lemming plays guitar as Joel Sherbert sings. Lucille Church sings after Sherbert. As she sings, Bill Pelfrey handles several serpents. He hands one of these to Joel Sherbert. A few moments later Pelfrey hands his serpent to Dewey Chafin and removes another from the box for himself. John Wayne John Wayne "Punkin" Brown Jr. Jr. and Steve Porter also handle. Lydia Hollins sings as Steve Porter dances with a serpent in each hand before replacing them in their box. The music calms down and Carl Porter testifies before the music starts up again. Another lull allows John Wayne "Punkin" Brown Jr. to testify. During his testimony music plays and he sings. Lydia Hollins can be seen twirling. She falls to her knees and crawls to the pulpit to stand. Dewey Chafin continues to handle serpents, as do a multitude of others including Carl Porter, John Wayne "Punkin" Brown Jr., Larry Muncie, Rayford Dunn, and Kirby Hollins. The music ends and Carl Porter speaks to the congregation and testifies. When he has finished, two brothers who are visiting the church testify. Carl Porter invites Brother Dexter to the pulpit to testify. After his testimony he gives a sermon which is followed by animated dancing as music once again fills the church. As music plays, one man can be seen slain in spirit upon the floor as a female member of the church lays hands on an other member. There follows more dancing and a group of women surround a dancing woman as elders of the church lay hands on her. Spencer Evans and Joel Sherbert handle serpents again as do many others including Billy Lemming, Verlin Short, Diane Tucker, and Bill Pelfrey and his first wife. As this continues, other members have their heads anointed with oil. Several members testify after the music concludes and among them are Lydia Hollins, Kirby Hollins, Buddy Jewel, Roy “Bootie” Christian, Sally D. Hunt, and Lucille Church.</abstract>
  <name>
    <namePart>Hood, Ralph W.</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cre">Creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <name>
    <namePart>Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cre">Creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <name>
    <namePart>Hood, Ralph W.  Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cph">Copyright holder</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <subject>
    <topic>Appalachian Region, Southern -- Religious life and customs</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Dance -- Religious aspects</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Gifts, Spiritual</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Glossolalia</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Homecoming</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Imposition of hands</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Lay preaching</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Pentecostal preaching</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Prayer</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Singing -- Religious aspects</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Slain in the Spirit</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Snake cults (Holiness churches) -- Appalachian Region, Southern</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Witness bearing (Christianity)</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>"John Wayne Jr. “Punkin” Brown</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Chafin, Dewey</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Church, Charles</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Church, Lucille</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Christian, Roy</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Dukes, Glen</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Dunn, Rayford</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Evans, Spencer</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Hollins, Kirby</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Hollins, Lydia</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Hunt, Sally D.</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Jewel, Buddy</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Jewel, Ruby</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Lemming, Billy</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Muncie, Larry</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Pelfrey, Bill</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Porter, Carl</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Porter, Steve</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Porter, Tammy</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Sherbert, Joel</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Short, Verlin</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Tucker, Diane "</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Church of the Lord Jesus Christ (Kingston, Ga.)</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <geographic>Kingston (Ga.)</geographic>
  </subject>
  <language>
    <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
  </language>
  <identifier type="local">MS-074-04-30</identifier>
  <identifier type="local">K-30</identifier>
  <originInfo>
    <publisher>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</publisher>
    <dateCreated encoding="edtf" point="start">1997-05-23</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/"/>
  <location>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16877coll2/id/104</url>
    <url access="preview">http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p16877coll2/id/104</url>
  </location>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Church of the Lord Jesus Christ recordings and photographs</title>
      <title>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson field recordings, interviews, and photographs</title>
      <title>Special Collections</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <relatedItem displayLabel="Collection">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson Holiness Churches of Appalachia recordings and interviews</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <physicalDescription>
    <internetMediaType>video/mp4</internetMediaType>
    <extent>01:43:49</extent>
    <form>Moving Image</form>
    <form>field recordings</form>
  </physicalDescription>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</recordContentSource>
    <recordChangeDate>2023-05-24-04:00</recordChangeDate>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
    <recordOrigin>Record has been transformed into MODS 3.5 from a Qualified Dublin Core record by the Digital Library of Tennessee, a service hub of the Digital Public Library of America, using a stylesheet available at https://github.com/digitallibraryoftennessee/DLTN_XSLT. Metadata originally created in a locally modified version of Qualified Dublin Core using ContentDM (data dictionary available: https://dltn-technical-docs.readthedocs.io).</recordOrigin>
  </recordInfo>
</mods>
