<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:dltn="https://github.com/digitallibraryoftennessee" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Prescott revival service, undated</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <abstract>Video recording of a service opening with music and singing. A chorus of members sing as the music progresses and when they are done, one member testifies to the congregation. His testimony evokes affirmation from the assembly and when he is done, music and singing once again fills the church. One female member of the congregation approaches the altar slowly as the music plays and as she walks around as if in a trance, members stop singing and playing music to pray over her and the preacher lays hands upon her. She sits before the altar and handles serpents as the music begins again. The video focuses on her as she handles and convulses slightly before handing the serpent to another member of the church who lays hands on her and then goes to retrieve another serpent. Members raise their hands in prayer all around the two while the music continues. The man who was handling two serpents kneels before the boxes and removes several more serpents and handles them in turn before returning them to the boxes. He takes one back out and hands off a second serpent to another member who handles as well. Other members follow hi including the preacher who testified in the beginning of the recording. When the music stops members chant “Glory to God.” as the preacher again addresses the congregation. The chanting continues until music begins again. More of the women of the congregation begin to walk as if entranced and they are followed by several young men. One of whom receives an imposition of hands from a female member who was walking earlier. They continue walking together briefly thereafter. More members give and receive the imposition of hands as the music progresses. The young man who received the imposition earlier receives it again from many members and he stands weeping with arms upraised as members pray over him. The music pauses to allow a woman who speaks in tongues to come forward. She begins to praise God in English in short order, and the music picks back up. More imposition of hands follows. While woman of the congregation testifies other pray at the altar. She is followed by a preacher who preaches a sermon from the bible. During his sermon he picks up a serpent box and speaks about serpent handling before setting the box on the pulpit. He removes a serpent from the box as he continues and members respond with prayers and adulation. The sermon is followed by more testimony from others in the congregation. As a member of the congregation speaks, the video quality degrades appreciably and the whole film jumps and becomes difficult to see clearly, however audio quality remains comprehensible. The long testimony ends and music begins again in the church. During the music the video recorder is lowered and only the pleats o fa member’s skirt can be seen for a time. The angle changes as the camera is moved in its position. The video reveals a low angle view of the singer and a few members playing guitar as well as the ankles of other members. Video and audio quality degrades as a lone member of the congregation plays guitar and sings. His song is followed by more music and rejoicing by the congregation.</abstract>
  <name>
    <namePart>Hood, Ralph W.</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cre">Creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <name>
    <namePart>Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cre">Creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <name>
    <namePart>Hood, Ralph W.  Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cph">Copyright holder</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <subject>
    <topic>Appalachian Region, Southern -- Religious life and customs</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Singing -- Religious aspects</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Gifts, Spiritual</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Glossolalia</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Imposition of hands</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Lay preaching</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Pentecostal preaching</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Prayer</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Singing -- Religious aspects</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Snake cults (Holiness churches) -- Appalachian Region, Southern</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Witness bearing (Christianity)</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <geographic>Appalachian Region, Southern</geographic>
  </subject>
  <language>
    <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
  </language>
  <identifier type="local">MS-074-09-10</identifier>
  <originInfo>
    <publisher>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</publisher>
    <dateCreated encoding="edtf" point="start">1980</dateCreated>
    <dateCreated encoding="edtf" point="end">2005</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/"/>
  <location>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16877coll2/id/174</url>
    <url access="preview">http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p16877coll2/id/174</url>
  </location>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Services and interviews field recordings, 1985-2002</title>
      <title>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson field recordings, interviews, and photographs</title>
      <title>Special Collections</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <relatedItem displayLabel="Collection">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson Holiness Churches of Appalachia recordings and interviews</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <physicalDescription>
    <internetMediaType>video/mp4</internetMediaType>
    <extent>03:33:24</extent>
    <form>Moving Image</form>
    <form>field recordings</form>
  </physicalDescription>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</recordContentSource>
    <recordChangeDate>2023-05-24-04:00</recordChangeDate>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
    <recordOrigin>Record has been transformed into MODS 3.5 from a Qualified Dublin Core record by the Digital Library of Tennessee, a service hub of the Digital Public Library of America, using a stylesheet available at https://github.com/digitallibraryoftennessee/DLTN_XSLT. Metadata originally created in a locally modified version of Qualified Dublin Core using ContentDM (data dictionary available: https://dltn-technical-docs.readthedocs.io).</recordOrigin>
  </recordInfo>
</mods>
