<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:dltn="https://github.com/digitallibraryoftennessee" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Church of the Lord Jesus Christ service, 1998 June 6</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <abstract>Video recording of a service opening with Junior McCormick testifying before the congregation. He asks if anyone in the congregation has prayer requests and several members espouse their desire for prayers. Carl Porter asks for a prayer for a fellow preacher. After the prayer requests are complete, the congregation prays at the pulpit and in their pews. A cut in the video reopens on more testimony from Junior McCormick as guitars are tuned in the background. Once they are in tune, Junior McCormick sings as the guitarists play and several congregants keep rhythm on tambourines. A member of the church joins him to play harmonica while the music continues. When the music ends, Junior McCormick invites James Wade to the pulpit to testify and preach. He calls the congregation to get into the spirit before leading the congregation in song. He testifies in the brief moments between songs. Margaret Baker joins Junior McCormick at the pulpit after James Wade is finished, and she sings while several members of the congregation stands and dance in place. As her song continues, a member of the church joins her on harmonica while others come to the front to receive blessings and a laying on of hands. When the music ends, Carl Porter testifies then sings, but the video cuts out his song, cutting back to further testimony and preaching. He ends by calling Brice Anderson to the front and he preaches before praying for church members. Following his prayer, members come forward to the pulpit to pray as Carl Porter and Junior McCormick sing. As the singing continues, Carl Porter removes a large serpent from its box and handles. While he does this, Junior McCormick dances with a wild serpent. The camera pans focus to the congregation and reveals several women dancing. They dance together and apart; sometimes joining hands and marching, sometimes laying hands on one another. When the music ends, a member of the church is invited up to the front to be blessed and anointed with oil. After her blessing, another woman in the background can be heard speaking in tongues as another woman holds her hands. She cries as she speaks and other members of the church look on and pray. She collapses to her knees, still holding another woman’s hands as she continues. After she is done speaking, James Wade testifies in a vigorous and violent manner.</abstract>
  <name>
    <namePart>Hood, Ralph W.</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cre">Creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <name>
    <namePart>Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cre">Creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <name>
    <namePart>Hood, Ralph W.  Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cph">Copyright holder</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <subject>
    <topic>Appalachian Region, Southern -- Religious life and customs</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Dance -- Religious aspects</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Expository preaching</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Glossolalia</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Imposition of hands</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Lay preaching</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Pentecostal preaching</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Prayer</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Singing -- Religious aspects</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Snake cults (Holiness churches) -- Appalachian Region, Southern</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Witness bearing (Christianity)</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Anderson, Brice</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Baker, Margaret</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>McCormick, Junior</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Porter, Carl</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Porter, Virgil</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Wade, James</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Church of the Lord Jesus Christ (Kingston, Ga.)</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <geographic>Kingston (Ga.)</geographic>
  </subject>
  <language>
    <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
  </language>
  <identifier type="local">MS-074-04-38</identifier>
  <identifier type="local">K-38</identifier>
  <originInfo>
    <publisher>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</publisher>
    <dateCreated encoding="edtf" point="start">1998-06-06</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/"/>
  <location>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16877coll2/id/112</url>
    <url access="preview">http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p16877coll2/id/112</url>
  </location>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Church of the Lord Jesus Christ recordings and photographs</title>
      <title>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson field recordings, interviews, and photographs</title>
      <title>Special Collections</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <relatedItem displayLabel="Collection">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson Holiness Churches of Appalachia recordings and interviews</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <physicalDescription>
    <internetMediaType>video/mp4</internetMediaType>
    <extent>01:52:30</extent>
    <form>Moving Image</form>
    <form>field recordings</form>
  </physicalDescription>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</recordContentSource>
    <recordChangeDate>2023-05-24-04:00</recordChangeDate>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
    <recordOrigin>Record has been transformed into MODS 3.5 from a Qualified Dublin Core record by the Digital Library of Tennessee, a service hub of the Digital Public Library of America, using a stylesheet available at https://github.com/digitallibraryoftennessee/DLTN_XSLT. Metadata originally created in a locally modified version of Qualified Dublin Core using ContentDM (data dictionary available: https://dltn-technical-docs.readthedocs.io).</recordOrigin>
  </recordInfo>
</mods>
