<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:dltn="https://github.com/digitallibraryoftennessee" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Church of the Lord Jesus Christ service, 1996 October 12</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <abstract>Video recording of a service opening with Branden Nietzel at the pulpit. He asks members who need prayer to come up. He offers the microphone to Carl Porter before leaving. Bill Pelfrey introduces the first song, calling members to get into the service. One member of the church can be seen sitting, playing cymbals and rocking back and forth as others stand and clap along. It is not long before Spencer Evans removes a serpent from the box and handles. As the music continues to play, Joel and Gene Sherbert, and Carl Porter join him in handling serpents. Carl Porter handles several snakes and as he goes to place them back in the box, he is bit. He does not seem overly bothered by the bite and he dances as other members of the congregation pray for him. When the music stops, Carl Porter addresses the congregation saying “I don’t mind getting bit like that.” After a cheer from the congregation the music begins again and Porter gives the microphone to another member of the congregation who sings. Bill Pelfrey’s wife comes forward briefly to lay hands on Carl Porter. Porter brings an other congregant up from the pews to dance at the front with him. Carl Porter imposes hands on several female members of the congregation. When the music ends, Carl Porter testifies and lays hands on another member of the congregation. He speaks again and passes the collection basket around to the congregation. He is followed by several other members of the congregation who testify. The testimony is followed with more music and song lead by a female member of the congregation. A brief interlude in the music gives Junior McCormick time to speak to the assembly. The music plays again and afterward Junior McCormick testifies before Spencer Evans assists him in a sermon. The sermon ends with music and as members begin to dance, Carl Porter removes a serpent from the box and handles again. Others join him in this, including Junior McCormick, Gene Sherbert, Joel Sherbert, Bill Pelfrey and Spencer Evans. Joel Sherbert is almost bitten as he handles. Carl Porter ends the service with a few announcements. The video cuts to an interview with Ethyl Miller who was bit by a copperhead. The film shows a close up of her bite and of the snake that bit her. A brief interview with Carl Porter about his bite ends the video. He shows that he was just grazed by the serpent, though his thumb is still swollen and purple.</abstract>
  <name>
    <namePart>Hood, Ralph W.</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cre">Creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <name>
    <namePart>Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cre">Creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <name>
    <namePart>Hood, Ralph W.  Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cph">Copyright holder</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <subject>
    <topic>Appalachian Region, Southern -- Religious life and customs</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Dance -- Religious aspects</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Expository preaching</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Extemporaneous preaching</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Imposition of hands</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Lay preaching</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Singing -- Religious aspects</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Snakebites</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Snake cults (Holiness churches) -- Appalachian Region, Southern</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Witness bearing (Christianity)</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Evans, Spencer</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Lemming, Billy</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>McCormick, Junior</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Miller, Ethyl</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Nietzel, Brandon</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Pelfrey, Bill</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Porter, Carl</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Sherbert, Gene</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Sherbert, Joel</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Church of the Lord Jesus Christ (Kingston, Ga.)</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <geographic>Kingston (Ga.)</geographic>
  </subject>
  <language>
    <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
  </language>
  <identifier type="local">MS-074-04-25</identifier>
  <identifier type="local">K-25</identifier>
  <originInfo>
    <publisher>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</publisher>
    <dateCreated encoding="edtf" point="start">1996-10-12</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/"/>
  <location>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16877coll2/id/101</url>
    <url access="preview">http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p16877coll2/id/101</url>
  </location>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Church of the Lord Jesus Christ recordings and photographs</title>
      <title>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson field recordings, interviews, and photographs</title>
      <title>Special Collections</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <relatedItem displayLabel="Collection">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson Holiness Churches of Appalachia recordings and interviews</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <physicalDescription>
    <internetMediaType>video/mp4</internetMediaType>
    <extent>01:48:08</extent>
    <form>Moving Image</form>
    <form>field recordings</form>
  </physicalDescription>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</recordContentSource>
    <recordChangeDate>2023-05-24-04:00</recordChangeDate>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
    <recordOrigin>Record has been transformed into MODS 3.5 from a Qualified Dublin Core record by the Digital Library of Tennessee, a service hub of the Digital Public Library of America, using a stylesheet available at https://github.com/digitallibraryoftennessee/DLTN_XSLT. Metadata originally created in a locally modified version of Qualified Dublin Core using ContentDM (data dictionary available: https://dltn-technical-docs.readthedocs.io).</recordOrigin>
  </recordInfo>
</mods>
