<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:dltn="https://github.com/digitallibraryoftennessee" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Church of the True Believers in Jesus' Name service, 2000</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <abstract>Video recording opening with an external view of the church and the surrounding landscape. After a member with a guitar enters the building, the camera cuts to an internal recording in which music plays as members speak with Glenn Dukes. Billy Lemming and another member of the church play guitars as Glenn Dukes meets and greets members. Rayford Dunn and other congregants testify after Dukes meets with everyone. When the testimony ends, Rayford Dunn calls for prayer. Female members of the congregation sing thereafter. One woman testifies before her song and is accompanied by a male member of the church. She is followed by Billy Lemming who plays a 12 bar blues progression on guitar as members begin to clap along and shout out prayers. When Billy Lemming is between songs, Shade Miller addresses the congregation. When Lemming begins to sing and play again, Miller lays hands upon members of the church and anoints several with oil. The woman who sang and testified earlier wails as he lays his hands upon her. Others join in on the imposition of hands. As the music picks up tempo, Shade Miller removes a serpent from its box and begins to handle. He is followed by a congregant identified only as Estel. When the music pauses, Rayford Dunn preaches to the congregation. Serpent handling and music resume and a woman can be heard in the background speaking in tongues. Virgil Porter sings after the handling ends and Glenn Dukes follows him with testimony and song. He is accompanied by Gail Miller, who sings as he plays guitar. Dukes preaches when his songs are done and he is followed by Shade Miller who does the same. Dunn then takes up the microphone and preaches from Hebrews 6:7. Dunn’s sermon is followed by that of another member. When he is done, another member of the congregation testifies. When he is done, the video cuts to another room where music is playing and different people are present. A man shouts as members lay hands on him.</abstract>
  <name>
    <namePart>Hood, Ralph W.</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cre">Creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <name>
    <namePart>Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cre">Creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <name>
    <namePart>Hood, Ralph W.  Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cph">Copyright holder</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <subject>
    <topic>Appalachian Region, Southern -- Religious life and customs</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Dance -- Religious aspects</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Expository preaching</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Glossolalia</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Imposition of hands</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Lay preaching</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Prayer</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Pentecostal preaching</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Singing -- Religious aspects</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Snake cults (Holiness churches) -- Appalachian Region, Southern</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Witness bearing (Christianity)</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Brown, Brenda</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Dukes, Glenn</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Dunn, Rayford</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Lemming, Billy</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Miller, Ethel</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Miller, Gail</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Miller, Shade</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Porter, Virgil</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Sherbert, Gene</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Short, Sister</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Short, Verlin</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Tucker, Diane</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Church of the True Believers in Jesus' Name (Calhoun, Ga.)</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <geographic>Calhoun (Ga.)</geographic>
  </subject>
  <language>
    <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
  </language>
  <identifier type="local">MS-074-06-07</identifier>
  <identifier type="local">C-7</identifier>
  <originInfo>
    <publisher>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</publisher>
    <dateCreated encoding="edtf" point="start">2000</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/"/>
  <location>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16877coll2/id/140</url>
    <url access="preview">http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p16877coll2/id/140</url>
  </location>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Church of the True Believers in Jesus' Name recordings and photographs</title>
      <title>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson field recordings, interviews, and photographs</title>
      <title>Special Collections</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <relatedItem displayLabel="Collection">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson Holiness Churches of Appalachia recordings and interviews</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <physicalDescription>
    <internetMediaType>video/mp4</internetMediaType>
    <extent>02:03:28</extent>
    <form>Moving Image</form>
    <form>field recordings</form>
  </physicalDescription>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</recordContentSource>
    <recordChangeDate>2023-05-24-04:00</recordChangeDate>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
    <recordOrigin>Record has been transformed into MODS 3.5 from a Qualified Dublin Core record by the Digital Library of Tennessee, a service hub of the Digital Public Library of America, using a stylesheet available at https://github.com/digitallibraryoftennessee/DLTN_XSLT. Metadata originally created in a locally modified version of Qualified Dublin Core using ContentDM (data dictionary available: https://dltn-technical-docs.readthedocs.io).</recordOrigin>
  </recordInfo>
</mods>
