<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:dltn="https://github.com/digitallibraryoftennessee" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Church of the Lord Jesus service, 2002</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <abstract>Video recording of an evening service opening with singing and handling of a mass of serpents by Jolo Church members. The music ends and a female member of the church makes a tearful confession. Kirby Hollins calls members of the church to pray for the woman and Bob Elkins joins Kirby Hollins in laying hands on the woman as they pray. They can be seen anointing the heads of several members with oil. Another preacher takes the pulpit and gives testimony after a brief sermon. The blind piano player who sometimes joins the Jolo Church’s service is in attendance. After his testimony, the music begins to play and members of the church dance. Melissa Evans dances in the twirling style indicative of the church. It is not long before members once again take up serpents as they dance. A man handles serpents and the music stops as he glorifies God. Following this members raise their hands in prayer and a visiting preacher interposes hands on a member of the congregation. There follows more singng and dancing while members including Bob Elkins handle serpents. The video breaks off form the service and reopens on an outdoor scene in the daylight. It shows a close up of a truck which is filled with the boxes of serpents. A man describes the serpents within. The snakes are carried in their boxes to the church as camera crews follow. Members of the church file in and greet one another as they set up for the sermon. Gracie Hollins speaks to an interviewer about snake-handling churches and her experiences. The service opens with song played and sung by Eileen. The song leads to Kirby Hollins asking if anyone has prayers and members chime in to ask prayer for members. Kirby Hollins thanks members and welcomes pastor MacArthur from Alabama who is visiting. Kirby then leads the congregation in prayer. A video cut reopens on a view from outside the church where the film crew talks to a man sitting in his truck. He talks about his experience. Following his interview, the video once again shows the service where Lydia Hollins sings and congregants handle serpents. The son of a man who died from a snake bite, who is visiting the church is himself bitten. Members dance with him as he, clearly in pain, tells them to carry on with their prayer. The video cuts to the stricken man sitting in another room with several members of the church who are watching him. His mother addresses the camera and prays over her son. The man talks to the cameramen about belief and bites. After this he recovers enough to reenter the church. Bob Elkins preaches as members assist the stricken man with his makeshift sling. Bob finishes his sermon and another preacher gives a sermon which ends the video.</abstract>
  <name>
    <namePart>Hood, Ralph W.</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cre">Creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <name>
    <namePart>Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cre">Creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <name>
    <namePart>Hood, Ralph W.  Williamson, W. Paul (William Paul)</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cph">Copyright holder</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <subject>
    <topic>Appalachian Region, Southern -- Religious life and customs</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Dance -- Religious aspects</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Expository preaching</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Extemporaneous preaching</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Homecoming</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Imposition of hands</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Lay preaching</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Prayer</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Singing -- Religious aspects</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Snakebites</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Snake cults (Holiness churches) -- Appalachian Region, Southern</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Witness bearing (Christianity)</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Christian, Roy</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Dukes, Glenn</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Elkins, Bob</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Evans, Melissa</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Hollins, Gracie</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Hollins, Kirby</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Hollins, Lydia</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>McCoy, Tim</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Church of the Lord Jesus (Jolo, W. Va.)</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <geographic>Jolo (W. Va.)</geographic>
  </subject>
  <language>
    <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
  </language>
  <identifier type="local">MS-074-03-21</identifier>
  <identifier type="local">J-21</identifier>
  <originInfo>
    <publisher>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</publisher>
    <dateCreated encoding="edtf" point="start">2002</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/InC/1.0/"/>
  <location>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16877coll2/id/74</url>
    <url access="preview">http://cdm16877.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p16877coll2/id/74</url>
  </location>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Church of the Lord Jesus recordings and photographs</title>
      <title>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson field recordings, interviews, and photographs</title>
      <title>Special Collections</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <relatedItem displayLabel="Collection">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Ralph W. Hood and W. Paul Williamson Holiness Churches of Appalachia recordings and interviews</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <physicalDescription>
    <internetMediaType>video/mp4</internetMediaType>
    <extent>01:44:27</extent>
    <form>Moving Image</form>
    <form>field recordings</form>
  </physicalDescription>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>University of Tennessee at Chattanooga</recordContentSource>
    <recordChangeDate>2023-05-24-04:00</recordChangeDate>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
    <recordOrigin>Record has been transformed into MODS 3.5 from a Qualified Dublin Core record by the Digital Library of Tennessee, a service hub of the Digital Public Library of America, using a stylesheet available at https://github.com/digitallibraryoftennessee/DLTN_XSLT. Metadata originally created in a locally modified version of Qualified Dublin Core using ContentDM (data dictionary available: https://dltn-technical-docs.readthedocs.io).</recordOrigin>
  </recordInfo>
</mods>
