<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Civilian Conservation Corps crew working in Pickett State Forest</dc:title>
<dc:description>Black and white photograph of four men raking a forest floor. All are wearing hats. The photo is pasted on loose-leaf paper.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Formed in March 1933, the Civilian Conservation Corps (CCC) was among the first of Franklin D. Roosevelt's alphabet agencies designed to ease the effects of the Depression. The relief agency promoted environmental conservation and intended to build good citizens through vigorous, disciplined outdoor labor. The CCC built roads, hiking trails, state parks and forests, fire towers, bridges, and other public works. Soil conservation and reforestation were CCC signatures. The &#65533;Tree Army&#65533; relieved rural unemployment and keep youth out of trouble.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Watson, C.</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Pickett County (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:date>1934-1942</dc:date>
<dc:source>Unnamed (ccc photographs)</dc:source>
<dc:relation>New Deal in Tennessee</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>41459</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>Still Image</dc:type>
<dc:type>Images</dc:type>
<dc:rights>While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees, that may be necessary for the intended use. </dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll19/id/331</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>