<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Sam Houston at Horseshoe Bend</dc:title>
<dc:description>Engraving of Sam Houston (1793-1863) in battle, holding a gun and sword. A soldier pulls an arrow out of Houston's leg. Several soldiers and Indian warriors lay dead. Indian warriors shooting arrows on the left. Image 9 of 16 in folder. From The Raven: A Biography of Sam Houston. Ensign Houston at To-Ho-Pe-Ka. (An engraving approved by Houston and first reproduced in 'Sam Houston and His Republic,' 1846)</dc:description>
<dc:description>Houston was seriously wounded at the Battle of Hoseshoe Bend (Tohopeka) on March 27, 1814. The American force, numbering 3,300 soldiers and friendly Cherokees and Creeks, overwhelmed about 1,000 of Chief Menawa's Red Stick Creek warriors. Around 800 Red Sticks were killed. The resulting Treaty of Fort Jackson ended the Creek War (1813-1814) and forced the Creek Nation to cede 23 million</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Houston, Sam, 1793-1863</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Tallapoosa River (Ala.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>THS Picture Collection</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Houston, Sam, 1793-1863;Tennessee. Governor;Texas. President (1841-1844 : Houston)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Military officers;Campaigns &amp; battles;Governors;Legislators</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Orr, Nathaniel</dc:creator>
<dc:source>Tennessee Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>26181</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>Still Image</dc:type>
<dc:type>Images</dc:type>
<dc:format>Tiff</dc:format>
<dc:rights>While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use. </dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll19/id/91</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>