<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>General Jackson with the New Orleans Committee of Safety</dc:title>
<dc:description>Black and white engraving, "General Jackson Conferring with the Committee of Safety," depicts the American commander and a group of men standing around a covered table. Decorative border includes a flag and musket resting on a cannon and an American eagle perched atop two flags. From John Frost and William Croome, A Pictorial Life of Andrew Jackson.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Before the battles of December 1814 and January 8, 1815, New Orleans citizens feared Jackson would burn the city rather than allowing the British to capture it. Committees of public safety were organized to encourage residents to protect their interests.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>New Orleans (La.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:date>1848</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>Belknap and Hamersley</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>Library Photograph Collection</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845;Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845. Works. 1986;New Orleans, Battle of, New Orleans, La., 1815;Louisiana--History--War of 1812</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Campaigns &amp; battles;Generals;Presidents</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Devereux</dc:creator>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>28088</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>Still Image</dc:type>
<dc:type>Images</dc:type>
<dc:format>Tiff</dc:format>
<dc:rights>While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use. </dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll19/id/183</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>