<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:dltn="https://github.com/digitallibraryoftennessee" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Transcript of discussion in the Tennessee Senate on Senate Joint Resolution 1</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/">No Copyright - United States</accessCondition>
  <location>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll27/id/1105</url>
    <url access="preview">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p15138coll27/id/1105</url>
    <url note="iiif-manifest">https://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/iiif/info/p15138coll27/1105/manifest.json</url>
  </location>
  <name>
    <namePart>Tennessee. General Assembly</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cre">Creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <abstract>This typed transcript, filed with the original senate joint resolution, chronicles discussion in the Tennessee Senate related to the ratification of the 19th Amendment to grant women the right to vote. The beginning of the discussion focuses on the legality of the special session, and whether the legislature can consider the amendment. The Standing Committee on Constitutional Amendments stated its opinion that the legislature had "both a legal and moral right to ratify the proposed resolution." They asserted that the U. S. Constitution granted the state legislature "full power and jurisdiction" to lawfully exercise this power, and provisions in the Constitution of Tennessee that might be used to deny the legislature this power were "clearly null and void." Anti-suffragists had claimed that the state constitution morally obligated legislators not to act upon the ratification resolution because it was being considered in a special session of the legislature. The Committee concluded their report by saying that the time for national women's suffrage was at hand, and they "covet for Tennessee the signal honor of being the 36th and last state necessary to consummate this great reform." The resolution to ratify the 19th Amendment passed on a roll call vote of 25 ayes, 4 noes, and 2 who were present but not voting. Senator McFarland explained why he did not vote on the resolution. Senator Finley Dorris, a support of women's suffrage, provided a lengthy explanation of why he believed that he was not violating his oath to the State of Tennessee by voting on the resolution.</abstract>
  <abstract>The 19th Amendment to the U. S. Constitution granted women the right to vote. When the Tennessee General Assembly passed the ratification resolution on August 18, 1920, it gave the amendment the 36th and final state necessary for ratification. Suffragists and anti-suffragists lobbied furiously to secure votes during that intense summer in Nashville. The ratification resolution passed easily in the Tennessee State Senate on August 13, but the House of Representatives was deadlocked. When young Harry T. Burn of Niota changed his vote to support ratification of the 19th Amendment, he broke a tie in the House of Representatives and made history.</abstract>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated>1920 August</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Tennessee State Library and Archives</recordContentSource>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
  </recordInfo>
  <subject>
    <topic>Women -- Suffrage -- Tennessee</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Constitutional amendments -- United States -- Ratification</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Women -- Legal status, laws, etc.</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Election law -- Tennessee</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Women -- Voting</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Tennessee -- Politics and government -- 1865-1950</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Law &amp; legal affairs</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Legislative bodies</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Women's rights</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Women's suffrage</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <geographic>Nashville (Tenn.)</geographic>
  </subject>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Tennessee State Library and Archives</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <physicalDescription>
    <form>Legislative records</form>
  </physicalDescription>
  <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
</mods>
