<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:dltn="https://github.com/digitallibraryoftennessee" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Proclamation by League of Women Voters in support of women paying the same poll tax as men</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/">No Copyright - United States</accessCondition>
  <location>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll27/id/1110</url>
    <url access="preview">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p15138coll27/id/1110</url>
    <url note="iiif-manifest">https://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/iiif/info/p15138coll27/1110/manifest.json</url>
  </location>
  <name>
    <namePart>League of Women Voters of Tennessee</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cre">Creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <abstract>The League of Women Voters asserted in this proclamation that the women of Tennessee should be treated equally with men in the matter of suffrage. Since men in Tennessee were required to pay a poll tax, then the women should also pay the poll tax. They endorsed a call for a special session to enact a law for the assessment and collection of poll taxes from women voters in Tennessee, stating that it was fair and just for women to have the same obligations as men did in regard to suffrage.</abstract>
  <abstract>The 19th Amendment to the U. S. Constitution granted women the right to vote. When the Tennessee General Assembly passed the ratification resolution on August 18, 1920, it gave the amendment the 36th and final state necessary for ratification. Suffragists and anti-suffragists lobbied furiously to secure votes during that intense summer in Nashville. The ratification resolution passed easily in the Tennessee State Senate on August 13, but the House of Representatives was deadlocked. When young Harry T. Burn of Niota changed his vote to support ratification of the 19th Amendment, he broke a tie in the House of Representatives and made history. Albert H. Roberts (1868-1946), served as a single term governor of Tennessee from 1919-1921. Roberts hesitated to call a special session of the General Assembly to consider the ratification of the 19th Amendment, in part because many legislators maintained that voting on the resolution in special session would violate their oath to the Tennessee constitution. Rulings from the Attorney General, and pressure from the national Democratic Party, particularly from President Woodrow Wilson, persuaded Roberts to support the special session and the ratification of the 19th Amendment. Though Roberts won national acclaim for his support of women's suffrage, many conservative Tennesseans were outraged. His support for women's suffrage was one reason for his defeat in the 1920 gubernatorial election by Republican Alfred Taylor.</abstract>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated>1920</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Tennessee State Library and Archives</recordContentSource>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
  </recordInfo>
  <subject>
    <topic>Women -- Suffrage -- Tennessee</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Constitutional amendments -- United States -- Ratification</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Equality</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Women -- Voting</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Women -- Political activity -- United States</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Political organizations</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Poll taxes</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Proclamations</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Women's rights</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Women's suffrage</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <geographic>Nashville (Tenn.)</geographic>
  </subject>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>GP 38: Governor Albert H. Roberts Papers, 1919-1921</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Tennessee State Library and Archives</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <physicalDescription>
    <form>Proclamations</form>
  </physicalDescription>
  <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
</mods>
