<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Homer Pittard, author of The First Fifty Years</dc:title>
<dc:date>1960-1963?</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Homer Pittard, author of The First Fifty Years, a history of the institution from 1911 to 1961</dc:description>
<dc:description>Homer Pittard was a Rutherford County educator who had served as principal at McFadden School and Central High School and as Director of University Affairs at MTSU. He also served as editor of The Mid-Stater, an alumni publication. As an undergraduate at the institution, Pittard was a member of the Writers&#8217; Club, the Dramatic Club, and the football team, and he served as editor of the Midlander.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Homer Pittard</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Pittard, Homer; Authors; Books; Middle Tennessee State College;</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:type>image</dc:type>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:format>5 x 7 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright may or may not belong to MTSU; Reproduced with permission of the Albert Gore Research Center, MTSU
</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>May be used freely by individuals for research, teaching, and personal use under the fair use provisions of the Copyright Act; Credit: Property of the Albert Gore Research Center, Middle Tennessee State University, Murfreesboro, TN 37132; For other uses contact The Albert Gore Research Center, P.O. Box 193, MTSU, Murfreesboro TN 37132</dc:rights>
<dc:relation>Alumni Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:publisher>Albert Gore Research Center, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>311</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/mtsu1/id/47</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>