<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>ROTC building, heating plant are latest campus additions</dc:title>
<dc:relation>Sidelines</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Middle Tennessee State College</dc:source>
<dc:date>1954-09-29</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>An article about additions to the campus since the summer of 1954, which included a new heating plant and the ROTC building</dc:description>
<dc:description>ROTC Building, Shop, Heating Plant Are Latest Campus Additions
Three additions to campus facilities added during the summer months include: an extension of the MTSC heating plant, a three wing maintenance shop attached to the college garage, and an ROTC departmental building.
The largest and most impressive of the new buildings is Nathan Bedford Forrest Hall of the ROTC, a two story structure with 14,000 square feet of floor space in its 10 classrooms. It was constructed entirely of concrete, steel and brick veneer at a cost of $123,349.30.
Cartwright Construction Company of Shelbyville built the  new ROTC occupancy.
The building adjoins the Tennessee Bureau of Aeronautics hangar which will be used for equipment of the department.
The new  maintenance shop was built at an expense of some $23,000.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>United States. Army. Reserve Officers' Training Corps; College buildings; Middle Tennessee State College</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:type>image/jpeg</dc:type>
<dc:format>Clipping</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected. Reproduced with permission of the University</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Reproduction is permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only; Credit to Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:rights>
<dc:relation>Sidelines Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/mtsu1/id/699</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>