<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>MTSU Greek history traced</dc:title>
<dc:relation>Sidelines, Feb. 19, 1968</dc:relation>
<dc:date>1968-02-19</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Traces MTSU's Greek system, particularly relating to the fraternities, back to 1961. Also discusses policies set by the Inter-Fraternity Council and Rush Orientation.</dc:description>
<dc:description>MTSU Greek History Traced
The fraternity system at MTSU began in the fall of 1961 when Phi Epsilon was formed as an off-campus fraternity.
Phi Epsilon was the only social fraternity til the spring of 1966 when Sigma Tau Omega was established.
As a result of a study by a faculty- administration- student committee, social fraternities were recognized as campus organizations in the fall of 1966.
Three new  fraternities were formed in the fall of 1966. These were Sigma Delta Zeta, Lambda Psi, and Chi Alpha Pi. 
The five fraternities along with the five sororities make up the MTSU Greek system.
The Inter-Fraternity Council was created because of the need for a coordination and governing body for the fraternities. The IFC consists of the president and a representative from each fraternity. The IFC has its own officers who can not vote and serve only as the functions of administrators of the body. The president may vote in case of a tie. IFC is responsible for all fraternity action. When necessary, IFC can punish a fraternity by fine or by probation.
Another job of the IFC is that of coordinating rush.
The IFC sponsors a rush orientation program. At this program the fraternity system is discussed as it exists both on this campus and as a whole. Each fraternity has a representative speak at rush orientation.
It is the responsibility of the IFC to see that all rushees qualify for rush, according to the requirements set up by the administration. The requirements for rush are that all freshmen rushees must have a 2.3 quality point ration and at least 15 hours, not including summer school. Anyone who has __ or more semester hours and has a quality point ratio of 2.0 are eligible for rush. 
This year's Fraternity Rush Orientation will be on Thursday, Feb. 22, at 7 p.m. in the Tennessee Room of the SUB.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Inter-Fraternity Council; Phi Epsilon; Sigma Tau Omega; Sigma Delta Zeta; Lambda Psi; Chi Alpha Pi; Greek system</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Greek letter societies; College students; Middle Tennessee State University</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Fraternities &amp; sororities</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:type>image/jpeg</dc:type>
<dc:format>Clipping</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected. Reproduced with permission of the University</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Reproduction is permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only; Credit to Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:rights>
<dc:relation>Sidelines Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/mtsu1/id/1207</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>