<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Old Norm opens with 125</dc:title>
<dc:title>Sidelines</dc:title>
<dc:relation>M.T.N. Signal, Vol. 1 No.1</dc:relation>
<dc:date>1961-09-20</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1910-1919; 1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>The front page of a simulated first issue of the school newspaper. Published as the first issue of Sidelines in the 1961-62 academic year to commemorate the 50th anniversary of the school's founding.</dc:description>
<dc:description>USE THE PLANKS
SAVE OUR NEW
FLOORS
m. 01. R
k(ni^^3erM
BASKETBAU SAME
SOUBVIIES
VS.
KING'S DAUGHTERS
SEPT. 28 NO MEN ADMITTED
MIDDLE TENNESSEE STATE NORMAl. SCHOOL
September 20. 1011
OLD  NORM   OPENS   WITH 125
president Pleased Ha)ith 'turnout c^nd Should iBe
t
On Monday mominE. Seplcmbcr II. our school was dedicated. &#187; wns a happy da&gt;'1 It was a grand by and one thai wUt re- nsin long in the memories i[ the eager scholars who
The Wsilors started wendiog their way Trom the Normal Boule- vard (0 the main building about 9 o'clock in the morninf. A steady stream of hugsies and yes, a few of those nois}- "horseless cama- Ets". continued until a [ew min- Qles hefore slartint; time at ten o'clock. Never again will the halls of our temple resound with the scholarly voices o( so many impor&#172; tant people.  Focis. artists, cduca-
Our spacious auditorium was com&#172; pletely tilled. With the exception of those on the stage and a few elderly people down front, the aud&#172; ience stood. The Opera chairs that were ordered had not arrived. With President Jones presiding, the pro&#172; gram was opened with Ihc singing of "America" which was rendered with leal and (er\-or. The Rever&#172; end. Mr. Gibb of Miulreesboro de&#172; livered the invocation. President Jones then introduced Mayor G. B. Giltncr who made the presentation speech for Murfreesboro. This was followed by Mr. Andrew Lee Todd who spoke lor the County. Two beautiful musical numbers were then presented by the young ladies from Tenneisee College. State Superintendent Bnster accepted the Normal plant on behalf of the stale of Tennessee. After his great flight into the realm of oratory WW completed, speeches were made by the Honorable John Bell
After the dedication we accosted a well-drcued gentleman as he descended the front steps of the main building. He wore a high, ilifl collar, rimless spectacles, and his mustache was carefully trim&#172; med. Surely he was some dignified professor from a nearby institu- Uon. Bui no. he was Mr. C, K. Colley, the architect of our Nor&#172; mal planL From his drawing board In Nashville had come the designs for ill or our buildings: the ad- mlniilralion building, power plant. (Continued on Page 6)
Kceble. U. S. Commissioner P. P. Cloxlon. and President Brown Ayera of the University of Tennes&#172; see. Not only were we blessed by one eulogic and informative classic &#8212;but six. Demosthenes would have turned green wilb envy.
the fl
e heal w
. . Muses of the fomm place, the guests and students rclirei the dining hall. Here Misses Ari and Weber served a delicious tempting meal.
We now have enrolled 125 s( ars, who  knows what the future will bring? Perhaps years.  500  may tre' the  far.   misty   fuluris&#8212;1,0007   Oh how our foolish hearts leap ' giddy  milieu   of times like this.
Bctnurs
It may be some time yel before our halls ring with "Carry that ball through," or "Old Norm will get your goat" or "Sis boom. Iwora,
dent. Lee Ellis "Mutt" Weber con&#172; ferred with the President on Fri&#172; day shout a football team. The President, kindly but in a straighl- torward manner, pointed out that the excess campus energy could be expended in the school garden. Later in a more sympathetic mood
stood in the way of a pigskin corps- First, there was no coach employer! for this purpose; secondly, no funds were available lor gear. I.ee
staling that although he had not played any football he had witness&#172; ed several gridiron encounters In Nashville. Also he stated that Miss Jeanelle Moore King, professor of physical training, averred that she could secure fifteen uniforms free of charge from a school in the area,    ft-esident   Jones    indicated
So don't be discouraged. Yet, a land ol husky heroes may be avorting on the green sward of dear old Norm,"
PRESIDENT
, our Presi. dent. He's over sL\ feet six and weighs two hundred and eighty pounds. His physical site is match&#172; ed by his great heart and intcllee- lual capacity. Bom In White County in 1869, he received his education at Onward Seminary near Doyle and Burrilt College at Spencer, Tennessee. He served as superin&#172; tendent of schools in White and Hamilton counties and later was State Superintendent of Public In&#172; struction.
We step around lively when he speaks for who among us wishes to arouse the Hon, or bear, in him? What is behind that mysterious door near the front entrance? Who wishes to find out? You&#8212;or You?
cNineteen, '&#166;^ried and '^rue: Our 'faculty
faculty; Mr. Areh her (Science)&#8212; I. witty, and ab-
Mr, Robert White (Lat&#172; in)&#8212;A good catch for any scheming lass Mr.    Max    Souby    dUslon')&#8212;The
Mr. Logan Gillcntine (EngtUh)&#8212; &#8212;"Spirit of culture embodied *
Mr. W, N. Billingsley (Education)&#8212; Kind, dignified, with Morpheus as constant companion
Mr. aark Woodward (Manual Training)&#8212;Sluch given to levity
Mr- Eugene Tavenncr (Latin)&#8212; Brilliance  with  the  accompani.
ment of Ihc cello
Mr. Pritehetl Lyon (]tlathcmatics)&#8212; Sartorial splendor personiTied
Mr. Harry Clark (Elnglish)&#8212;An Ap&#172; ollo with the wisdom of Ihe ages
Miss Mary Arthur (Domestic Arts) -Diminutive, sweet and precise
iliss Margaret Weber (Domestic Arts)&#8212;The brilliance of her beau&#172; ty matches the sun each morning
Miss Tommie Reynolds (Mathemat&#172; ics)&#8212;Kindness with a medicine ball and a slide rule,
Sliss E. Mai Sanders (Music)&#8212;A drill sergeant with a musical soul&#8212;and a baton
Mr. Belcher (in Chem. 1): "How do you tell the difference between ferrous and ferric iron!"
Dudley Fletcher; "By looking at the label on the bottle,"
LfWi IwMr,  IKmi. fl
M'mn la 3fo iHor r
ed on Normal Boulevard. Tl:i ri- had been a heavy downpour on Tuesday and "Lake Unnecessary" completely covered the thorough&#172; fare. Sam and a fellow mule were' pulling the red farm wagon through the water when he slipped and fell, in a few momenU he ua; completely submerged. E\'er so often in iris struggle, his agitated head appeared above the wafer ytl to no avail. The students on the hanks yelled and screamed, but Ihe waters soon became quiet and cvcr&gt;'one knew that Sam bad gone where all good mules go. We will miss him and so will Ed Lillard who sal helpless in the wagon and watched the poor creature in his last moments. Cannot somclhing be 'Lake Unnecessary?"
'^he Xothario
from  JFarhiia
nil
Ihi
by
I'y
ih
bi.Mlnfl to
M.T.N.    SIONAL
r. w
ai 1
(Ullf   .
r Ih* Gold
lilor ol Ih*
nlin Smllh
.r  M(P*ah
now Hall
panttr. Tha
JOHN SHERWOOD HOLMS V young man from West Ten- "Invaded" our campus, John Sherwood Holmes la. The other boys are I Ihe young ladles arc
laturily (he's some older Ihan of Ihe others) and hli mytter- air of a "furriner" from an- part of the (talc hive made liini popular beyond description. Those of Ihe fair tresses and Im- pliih imllo compete for hli com^ panlonihlp everyday In Mr&#187;. liar tH:e's dining hall.
J. S. was Ihe first iludeni to rcgliter at the Normal. As far back as April ho had written Preil- dent Jonea about Ihe possllitllty ot a Wcsl Tennusee realdenl b&#171;ln&lt; &#8226;dmllteil The rrciidrnl could fInJ till retlrlclloni In the rule* and Invited him lo come atniig. In fact. our goml I'Toildoiii mel him u the railroad tlallon. Kolh a( ihem ivtl* t'lrk In iho r&#171;tl laxl-wigon driwn by K&lt;t IJllanl
Miss Katherine lilonohan ItlMorj}
&#8212;The reincarnation of tlie spirit
of  Andrew  JackMO  in  comely
female form Miss Jeanncttc Moore King (Pbyti-
ca!   Training)&#8212;Borrowed   from
the realm of Lycurgui Mr. Verd Peterson (Agricullure)&#8212;
The sentry at the head of tbe
school garden Mis. L. M. Russell (Education)&#8212;The
feminine Mark Hopkins on Ihe
end of the log Jliss Weesic Griffith (Drawing)&#8212;A
few bold strokes and creation supreme
Conventus Diu Vivant!
A salute to our chapels! Since dedication day on Monday, Sep&#172; tember 11, our daily lea o'clock chapels have been moments well always treasure. And woe to tbe unlucky lass or swain who is found afar from the assigned seat in the auditorium. There is always Ihe eagle eye of Professor Souby, or perhaps Miss Reynolds to check those empty seats.
^Vho can ever forget Miss E. Mai striding onto tbe stage and her masterful leadership in our sing&#172; ing "Come Thou Almighty King"&#8212; will we ever forget it? Miss E. Uai could be a drill sergeant in the yVmerican army. C^an't you just hear her say: "You, Preston, a little more attention, and a little less ^lool-gathering." or "Susie Smith, take your eyes off Professor Souby, and sing," or "Oscar and Quintin. let's hear from the Amen corner." Or can't you hear now President's deep bass laughter when one of his professors is caught flirting with the young ladies. Miss E. Uai doesn't cull Ihem at all.
Our devotionals arc always In&#172; spiring and we ire thankful that our leaders rotate in presenting ihcm. Last Thursday Professor Woodward's tun) came but he had forgotten it. Nevertheless, like &#166; true soldier of Old Norm, he came to the front and opened the Bible. Genesis Just happened to tall to his lot and he read a long selecUon from the "Begits." This was the cause of the soft laughter that ran through the student body.
Classics, yes. Will you citr again hear the like of Professor White's lecture on "Quacks" or profesiot Tavcmer's beautiful renditions on Ihc cello. These are moments of pure Joy. Conventus diu vivanti
Jicttcr Jlnmr
Mrs, Harry Clark, our prvltj- matron at the women's donnltoir. passed on IhU letter to lu. It was wrtllen by De*sie Ncsbitt to b&#171;C folks ii Rucker, Tenneaste. Dent* Is one &lt;xt Mr*. Clark's tine hlgb acho&lt;J girli. We are iiHatlnji tt, by permission, becauw It showt the typical iplrlt ol our yvuUifwl &#8226;cholar* after one wwk ol wtwoL Dear Parents:
t am well and hop* IhU ftarti jrou the tame, Clttsea wet&#187; lIUMtl lail Tucaday and 1 tow tU nt ay leaehen Our |\rliic^l b Hr. milln&lt;sley. ll&#171; la about u &#171;U m crandr^ and u haM Md )uii &#171; loni luoutiteh* Hul be U k kMly man IVski are a(&#171;r&#171;&#171; Mil &#171;&#8226; ktT* (&lt;^ultUuf&gt;] M !&gt;&#8226;&#166;&#8226; D</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Mock newspaper issue; Spoof newspaper issue; Fiftieth Anniversary issue</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>College student newspapers and periodicals; Middle Tennessee State Normal School; Middle Tennessee State College</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Image; Text;</dc:type>
<dc:type>image/jpeg</dc:type>
<dc:format>Clipping;</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected. Reproduced with permission of the University</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Reproduction is permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only; Credit to Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:description>Special Collections</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>378.768 M58si</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/mtsu1/id/694</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>