<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Massacre</dc:title>
<dc:title>Winner of the Silver Star Tells of German Atrocity in the Battle of The Bulge</dc:title>
<dc:relation>Sidelines, Aug. 7, 1946</dc:relation>
<dc:date>1946-08-07</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Describes Hillary Martin's experience in the Battle of the Bulge, which earned him a Silver Star. Martin was a football player for MTSC in 1946</dc:description>
<dc:description>MASSACRE
WINNER OF THE SILVER STAR TELLS OF GERMAN 

ATROCITY IN THE BATTLE OF THE BULGE
When the Blue Raiders take the field on 

September 26 to open the first football 

season at MTSC in four years-- two wearers 

of the Silver Star awarded for gallantry in 

action will be among the G.I. members of 

the squad. 
Hilary Martin of Nashville won his 

decoration in the famed Battle of the Bulge 

by heroically calling on his battery to 

shell the area in which he was acting as 

forward observer in an effort to cover the 

withdrawal of nine survivors of A company 

of the 23rd Infantry Regiment.
Martin, a staff sergeant with Battery A of 

the 434th regiment of trapped in a salient 

north of St. Vith on December 21-22, 1944 

and after all but nine men of the 240 men 

who had been committed to action with him 

had become casualties he crawled into an 

abandoned machine gun emplacement and 

operating his radio to direct artillery 

fire from his battery while he 

intermittently fired the gun to cover the 

withdrawal of the shattered remnants of the 

company to which he had come to command by 

virtue of being the senior non-com left. 
Called for Fire on Self
Receiving the code message from his colonel 

that the battery fire power was all but 

exhausted Martin asked for fire to be laid 

down right on top of his own position to 

slow the German advance.
Abandoning his radio, helmet, and battle 

jacket, Martin withdrew from his forward 

observers and for five days, armed only 

with a side-arm and his slain lieutenant's 

map case he worked his way back through the 

German lines to rejoin his outfit. 
Enroute he ran across a private from 

Philadelphia suffering from battle fatigue 

and determined to evacuate him. Digging 

into a snow bank near Malmandy to avoid 

traveling by day he was within 125 yards of 

the scene of the butchery of 135 medics.
Describes German Atrocity
"The Hienes had captured these boys and had 

lined them up as though they were going to 

march them back when two German tanks drew 

over a little hill and machine gunned them. 

Then the Heines walked about among the 

bodies, kicking and shooting any who showed 

signs of life. Later I saw one of the few 

who survived that massacre and he couldn't 

even hold a cigarette," Martin said.
The Philadelphia youth was holed in with 

Martin during those harrowing minutes. "I 

had to keep him from crying and try to keep 

his morale up, so I didn't have much time 

to worry about myself," Martin explains 

modestly. 
Back to the American lines Martin was sent 

to a medical aid unit to recuperate from 

frost bite and exposure. Two days later he 

was back with his outfit and accompanied
(Continued On Page Two)
MORE ABOUT Massacre
(Continued  From Page One)
them  on  their  re-occupation of St. Vith.
He wears five battle stars among his 

decorations.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Battle of the Bulge</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Martin, Hillary; Silver Star; Ardennes, Battle of the, 1944-1945; World War, 1939-1945--Veterans; Football players; Middle Tennessee State College</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro, TN; St. Vith, Belgium</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:type>image/jpeg</dc:type>
<dc:format>Clipping</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected. Reproduced with permission of the University</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Reproduction is permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only; Credit to Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/mtsu1/id/866</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>