<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Homecoming history</dc:title>
<dc:relation>Sidelines</dc:relation>
<dc:creator>Russell, Shirley</dc:creator>
<dc:source>Middle Tennessee State University</dc:source>
<dc:date>1965-11-09</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>This article describes MTSU's history of homecomings, which began in 1925, the same year the school became known as Middle Tennessee State Teachers College</dc:description>
<dc:description>A Homecoming History
In the fall of 1925 graduates began returning to this institution on a homecomlng basis. It was in this year that the institution became Middle Tennessee State Teachers College and it celebrated its first homecoming.
There was no football queen until 1934 when Mary 

Adams and "Bill" Westzel were designated football sponsors.
Frances Nicholson was crowned "Queen of Love and 

Beauty" in 1935.
The first homecoming parade was organized in 1939. As a result of a gasoline shortage in 1942, a  walking parade with horse-drawn vehicles was seen proudly circling the
public square.
Football was suspended during the war years 1942-45.
Middle Tennessee State University boasts approximately 8,000 graduates scattered around the globe. Many return to the campus for class reunions and view the startling progress made by their alma mater.
Homecoming was formerly a project of the senior class. It is now planned and promoted by the Associated Student Body.
Homecoming is a time of tense excitement and zealous school spirit for students.
It is a sentimental time for alumni as they reflect upon the happy days spent on this campus.
Captain Roger Smith, an alumnus of the class of 1941, composed the following poem on the battle lines somewhere in the South Pacific.
The poem appeared in the SIDELINES September 28, 

1943.
"All that I have left is memories of these days
When we had fun in so many different ways;
I only hope that others at some future date
May enjoy themselves as I did at Tennessee State.

Shirley Russell</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Homecoming; Middle Tennessee State University--History; Middle Tennessee State University; Universities and colleges--Alumni and alumnae</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Alumni &amp; alumnae</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Image; Text;</dc:type>
<dc:type>image/jpeg</dc:type>
<dc:format>Clipping;</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected. Reproduced with permission of the University</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Reproduction is permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only; Credit to Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:rights>
<dc:relation>Sidelines Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University;</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/mtsu1/id/747</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>