<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Library automation: the early days</dc:title>
<dc:date>1982?</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1980-1989;</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Library employees Wilma Marable (left) and Mary Pugh (right) work on two of the first computer workstations used by the library to automate cataloging tasks. The workstations were located in the cataloging department of the Todd Library</dc:description>
<dc:description>The first library at the institution was housed in the Administration Building. Bettie Avent Murfree was employed as the first librarian in 1912. The first library building opened in the fall of 1926, and in 1957 the building was named for Bettie Avent Murfree to show appreciation for her significant contributions to the institution. The Andrew L. Todd Memorial Library, named in honor of a local businessman who was instrumental in the founding of the institution, was dedicated in 1958. The current library, the James E. Walker Library opened in 1999.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Wilma Marable, Mary Pugh</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Library employees; Cataloging--Data processing; Libraries--Automation; Academic libraries; Middle Tennessee State University. Library</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Still image;</dc:type>
<dc:type>image/jpeg;</dc:type>
<dc:format>Photograph;</dc:format>
<dc:format>10 x 8 in.</dc:format>
<dc:source>MTSUMEM010.tif</dc:source>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected. Reproduced with permission of the University</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Reproduction is permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only; Credit to Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University;</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/mtsu1/id/1623</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>