<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Reminiscences of MTSU Library, 1935-40</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Freeman, Isa Lee</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1976</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939; 1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Typescript of a brief memoir written by Isa Lee (Sherrod) Freeman to describe her five years as a librarian at Middle Tennessee State Teacher's College between 1935 and 1940. It describes her relationship with Bettie Avent Murfree, who organized the first library after the founding of the Middle Tennessee Normal School, and her relationship with other faculty on campus</dc:description>
<dc:description>REMINISCENCES OF MTSU LIBRARY 1935-1940 

In a central location of the State Teachers College campus
stood the library. Easily accessible to all other buildings, it
was considered by many of the faculty and administration to occupy
a central place of importance in the academic life of the college &#8226;

In January 1935 when I came as an associate librarian, it
was a rather new building. The library, formerly located on the
second floor of the Main ( Administration) Building, wben I arrived,
stood at the site of the present Peck Hall building. P.A. Lyon
was college president, and Mrs. Bettie Avent Murfree was librarian.
She had organized the library in the early days of the Normal School,
and most of the time she served alone, except for student assistants.
She was about five feet tall and took quick short steps as she
hurried, almost raced, about the two- storied building from 8: 00
until 3: 00 daily except Sunday.
Mrs. Murfree was a delightful person, with an optimistic
attitude, a vibrant personality, and an eagerness to help all who
needed it. After the library hours were finished, she worked in
an antique shop of which she was part owner.
Both of us handled all phases of library activities. Usually
Mrs. Murfree took care of the mail, the periodicals, order work,
and supervised the circulation. I was responsible for cataloging
and classification, for reference work, for teaching "How to use
the library" to freshmen English classes, supervising the student
assistants, and for about four years I taught library science
classes. Dean J. C. Beasley gave me permission to plan a curriculum
for training teacher-librarians who would be qualified to serve as
part- time librarians in elementary and small high school libraries.
My classes consisted of six courses, were open to sophomores, juniors
and seniors, and included enough credit for a minor in library
- p. 2'-
science. Two courses were offered per quarter.
From these classes, the second year students and I organized
libraries in a few Rutherford County schools which did not have
libraries. Among those where we worked as volunteers were Training
School ( now MTSU Campus School), McFadden two times ( the school
burned, and we returned to the new building), Walter Hill, and
Kittrell. The work was rather crudely done; there was almost no
money for necessary materials. But the books were classified by
Dewey Decimal system, cataloged and processed, and arranged
attractively on the shelves. Library Science students put into
practice what they had learned in class, the schools were shown
that the college was interested in them, and library service was
emphasized.

At the college Mrs. Murfree was chairman of a Library Committee
composed of the head of each department plus the two librarians.
About three times a year the committee met to make book selections.
Any teacher or student could make book requests, and order cards
were made for each request. Professional library magazines were
studied for possible orders, and each department head made a list
of books needed by his department. Then at the committee meeting
the book budget was divided into percentages for each department,
plus a percentage for general use. The final order was prepared,
submitted to book jobbers for bids, and the books were ordered.
The library consisted mainly of books, a fairly good magazine
collection, a depository of all goverbment documents, a rather good
vertical file collection, a few recordings, but no other audiovisual
materials. These were the 1930' s: money was still scarce, salaries
were small, students were paid about 35&#162; perhour, and the Depression
still prevailed in state schools.
- p &#183; 3 - 
But they were fun- years! The faculty and student body were small.
We all knew each other. Social life was warm and friendly. All the
faculty members were expected to attend chapel twice a week, and
at intervals we were asked to be responsible for speakers or other
programs. We were expected to attend athletic events, all receptions
given at the President's home, all faculty meetings, all lyceum
numbers presented in the college auditorium, all school dances.
We all marched in the lines for graduation exercises.
The library was not open at night or on Sunday. During part
of school vacation periods we took inventory, went through the
dormitories searching for lost or stolen books, and in general,
prepared for the next school term.
At least half of the student assistants were athletes. The
only scholarships provided were for work, and since the library
needed twenty to thirty helpers, most of them were football players.
Of course the boys were not particularly happy about working in
the library, but there wasn't much choice. A few of them made
excellent workers, but some were. just killing time until the bell rang.
On one occasion I remember Mrs. Murfree's asking me to reprimand
a student who came to work with his shirttail out. lilt didn't look
nice", she said, and also it embarrassed her to have to mention
anything that personal. So I had to. The boy was probably 20 or
21, and I was 22 at that time!
The library had closed stacks. I'm not sure why, but that's
the way it was when I arrived. I guess students weren't to be trusted,
so the circulation desk workers had to locate and bring all requests
to the desk where they were checked out. Faculty members, however,
had stack privileges.
It was quite private in the stacks, and on several occasions
- p.4 -
Mrs. Murfree and I found Mabel Baxter and Homer Pittard, both student
library assistants, doing their "courting" in a remote corner. Others
enjoyed the privacy also, but these two became Mr. and Mrs. a little
later.
Mrs. Murfree always opened the Iibrary in the mornings, and
I locked up at 5: 00 ot 5: 30. On gloomy winter afternoons, electric
lights were needed everywhere. That much use of power at the same
time, frequently blew a fuse. By that hour of the day it would be
&#8226;
impossible to locate a campus electrician ( we had no telephone),
so something had to be done in a hurry. I had heard that a dead
fuse would work if a copper penny was placed behind it. It did work;
the lights came on, and the building didn't catch on fire. I don't
know why! Just lucky, I guess.
Housed in the basement of the library were bound periodicals,
government documents, a collection of state adopted textbooks, and
a small apartment in which a married football player lived. As far
as I can remember, he was one of the very few married students
enrolled in the college, and all other married students were much
older than he was. The basement was damp, and practically all books
were mildewed. At one time I taught library science classes in the
basement, but later we moved upstairs.
Things were never dull in the library. We worked hard and had
long hours, and when extra work was needed, we worked overtime
without feeling imposed upon. The work was rewarding, and fellowship
with other faculty members and with the townspeople brought joy
and a feeling that we were part of a big family.
I never felt that any library job was unimportant, but I did
dread teaching and supervising the book repair. Not much of the
budget could be spent on binding, so it was necessary to carryon

- p. 5 -

a continuous mending program. I really loathed that tedious job,
but it had to be done, and I did it.
There were some outstanding girls who worked as library assistants,
and we became close friends. I enjoyed them, amd they liked library
work so much that they went on to Library School to become professional
librarians. Perhaps one third of these women student assistants
continued in the library field.
Q. E. Smith was president of the college during my last three
years. He was exacting and sometimes demanding; no special privileges
were available for anyone; but he knew all faculty members personally;
he knew what contributions each made; he commended work which he
considered well done; he considered the library important in the
total campus program; and the two librarians enjoyed full faculty
status. President Smith was an excellent administrator.
Of course faculty and student enrollments are much greater
now, and the former friendliness and fellowship are no longer
possible. Much progress has been made and should have been been made,
and the University influence and outreach is much greater than it .
used to be. But with progress a few sacrifices have to be made.
I am glad that I was a part of MTSU at the time I was. They
were happy years, we were made to feel important, and we were
appreciated. I don't recall any professional jealousy in the entire
college. We were free to do our jpbs as we wished; we were encouraged
to use initiative; we could attend any professional meetings that we
desired, of course paying our own expenses. If an employee did not
measure up to what was expected by the administration, he was warned
and advised, and if that didn't work, he was fired.
Because Mrs. Murfree was interested in art, the library had
many beautiful paintings and sculpture pieces. Perhaps they were hers
personally, since I'm sure the book budget couldn't be spent for "frills".

- p. 6 -

But the library was always lovely and had a "homey" look. I am glad.
that I had the privilege of working with "Miss Bettie".
My decision to resign in July 1940 was a very difficult one
for me to make. I had married three years earlier and felt that
homemaking should now be my career, but it took a long time to give
up the job that meant so much to me. Someone has said, " Nothing is
work if you really enjoy doing it", so I can truly claim that my
five and a half years as librarian at Middle Tennessee State
College was happy interlude.
Isa Lee ( Sherrod) Freeman
(Mrs. Lawrence Freeman)

RECEIVED
APR 1 1976
M. T. S U
LIBRARY</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Academic librarians; Academic libraries; Middle Tennessee State Teachers College</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:type>text; application/pdf</dc:type>
<dc:format>Autobiography</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>6 leaves</dc:format>
<dc:source>Freeman.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected. Reproduced with permission of the University</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Reproduction is permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only; Credit to James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/mtsu1/id/1621</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>