<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Signal, 1917</dc:title>
<dc:title>Middle Tennessee Normal Signal</dc:title>
<dc:source>Middle Tennessee Normal School</dc:source>
<dc:date>1917-05</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1910-1919</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>The May 1917, volume 5, number 3 issue of the Signal, a publication of Middle Tennessee State Normal School </dc:description>
<dc:description>&#8226; ..-. cl.-~~"-"'-' l~
M. T. N.
J_ f~..- c~""( I~.- t"-' &#8226;
, . ag 1917
,
II/ -----'~ .... 1 //-.-"-.. .
I"
No. : 3
CONTENTS
MURFREESBORO, TENNESSEE
- tU4t it. ID. N. ~ tgnal
I&gt; edication---------------------------------------------- 2
Dedication. ELIZABETH HORD- -- -- -- -- -- -- -- -- -- -- -- -- ~ - - ~
TIle Seniors -- -- -- -- -- -- -- -- -- - - -- -- r - - - - - - - - 3
e Class of 1917. VIRGINIA PARKER 7
~ orial-----------------------~------------------------ 10
Mr. Housefly. FREEMAN LACKEY- - -- -- -- -- -- 11
. Examinations. W. G. W. -- -- -- -- _ 13
Cu~ nt Events. J. L. MEADOWS U
~ nscription-------------------------------------------- l 5
Virginia's Holiday. GEOFFREY WEAKLEY -- -- -- -- _ 16
Spring. LOWELL BOGLE -- -- -- -- -- _ 18
Can the Ethiopian Change His Skin? CLAYTON LUTHER 18
Jlthletics ~ 26
Se. niorClass 27
Senior Town Girls Entertain -- _ 27
Droomgoole Society- 29
urfree Society 31
Claxton Society 28
(;~ dySOCiety------------------------------------------- 30
Y. M. C. Jl. 33
Y. W. C. A. 32
COuntryLifeClub 33
Glee Club 35
~ okes----=============================================== 36
dvertisements 41
,
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
DEDICATION
By ELIZABETH HORD.
Oh, Seniors, glad and free,
We dedicate to thee,
This little book.
On every page you'll find, .
Some cord your hearts to bind,
Some mem'ry brought to mind,
If you but look.
Your path before lies bright,
Keep ever to the right,
And guard thee well.
Be brave, and strong and true,
That others, knowing you,
May catch this spirit, too,
Live long and well!
.' (
\
,"
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
THE SENIORS
AUSTIN.
Good old long tall mountaineer,
Full of life and all good cheer;
Stars in baseball when on first base,
And toots a tuba with equal grace.
BATTS.
Timid, modest, and refined, .
A model of grace and' beauty combmed,
The like to whom men doff their hats,
Such is the character of Miss Louise Batts.
BLANKENHORN.
A gallant youth and a chivalrous lad, .
How handsome he would look, as a soldier clad.
BLANKENSHIP.
Thy fame as an actor, ne'er will it fade,
In the role of " Hulda," a Sweedish maid.
BRAMBLET.
Her modest looks the cottage might adorn
Sweet as the primrose peeps beneath the thorn.
BROGDON. '
That practiced air and serious way
Wins for you full many an " A."
If thou art fond of the " Ed" thou learnest,
We blame thee not for being so earnest.
CRAWLEY.
" Handsome is that handsome does."
COFFMANN &#8226;
I confess I am not a seer,
But thou wert meant for an auctioneer, "
Though great the distance thou needst not falter,
Thou couldst stand on the Rockies and sell Gibraltar.
CUMMINS.
One good all round athlete,
For he stars with his hands, his head, and his feet.
As grim, as steady, and as sure as can be,
And a voice as deep as the fathomless sea.
DEMENT.
Go easy, my friend, don't offend Miss Dement,
Be you teacher or pupil, you will early repent.
8
DENSON.
Who mixed reason with pleasure and wisdom with mirth,
If he had any faults, they are not known on earth.
DUNN, MARY.
" To know her is to love her."
DUNN, ROBERTA.
Smiles for all but love for none,
For she plucks boys' hearts just for the fun.
DALE.
Thy own free will is thy own good way,
And this alone wilt thou obey.
DELZEL.
" Thou foster child of silence and slow time,"
Whose name no poet can hope to rhyme.
EDWARDS.
Thy wrinkled visage and rustic grace
Reminds us much of the " Rough Stone" race.
GORE.
A foolish lad once tried to flirt, with our friend Miss Johnnie.
Gore,
When he recovered consciousness, quoth that laddie " never
more."
&#8226;
' r &#8226;
GOOCH.
An irresistible tongue of down,
A voice that is a balm to any wound,
But watch her closely when she tries to heal'
Lest at any time your heart she steal.
GREEN.
Though time may wear your youth away,
M~ y you ever be " Younger" from day to day.
GRAY.
A home economist and a cabinet maker,
To the boy who can win her, iny advice is take her.
GROVES.
He's as vain and fickle as a changeful dream,
Yet one has fallen for his false esteem.
IlILL.
On the. enchanted lotos thou must have dined,
For better symptoms are hard to find.
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
LUNN.
Psychology is bliss, Practice Teaching fun,
This is the sentiment of Miss Ethel Lunn.
LUTHER.
A famous debater and a dressy guy,
The sort that girls delight to spy.
MEADOWS. .
A teacher fashioned after Doc's own heart
So deeply in love with the pedigogical art.'
Apollo may hasten in his daily course,
But you can't rush Meadows though he- talk till he's hoarse.
An MCCLEAREN.
Praold marri~ ~ nan wit~ hisfo~ eto~. amiss,
y, what- sIgmficance IS there In - tliIS ?
Ad' . MOORE.
In Iseontented &#183; teacher weary of life
the stuffy little schoolroom with its worries and strife,
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL 5
HUNNICUTT.
Thy dexterous pen and fertile brain .
: Make students fight and Profs. complam.
HOLDEN.
Be was quite studio~ s and wor~ a deep frown "
And his favorite tOpIC was the Cap and the Gown.
HUTCHINSON.
A foppish dandy of the deepest dye,
If he volunteers, how the girls will cry.
LACKEY.
" God made him, and therefore let him pass for a man."
LEONARD.
No matter how little or light ske may seem; .
She helped win the championship of the basket- ball tteam
LOCKE, PEARL.
Not even an earthquake is sufficient to shock'
So calm and quiet is miss Pearl Locke.
LOCKE, WILLIAM.
Of such a freakish dandy, you have never even read,
For he carries a mirror on the top side of his head.
LowE.
" When you do dance, I wish you
Like a wave o'er the sea, that you might ever do nothing
but dance."
COPYRIGHTED 1937 BY VIRGINIA PARKER.
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL 7 &#8226;
FROM A BOOK ENTITLED " THE CLASS OF
1917"
TAYLOR.
&#8226; ' c, loyal, and true,
. cal teacher and a good one too.
typl . VERBLE.
10
f music and manual arts,
vveerr0r susceptible to . CU, pI'd's dart s.
infallible friend and 111 love as true,
t when he. t; ires of one, he gets a new.
WOODS.
silent smiling beauty,
dful of nothing, but only her duty.
TRIBUTE TO ALL.
the boys are brave and all the girls are fair,
d ~ oiher such class, exists nowhere..
CE the CJaSS of 1917 left the dear old haunts of the
Middle Tennessee State Normal, they . have wandered
Car and wide to all parts of the (} arth. Although
they aU started o'ut from their Alma Mater as
teachers, they are now engaged in all kinds of trades
&#183; oos. A few could not be located; some are plodding
obscure ways of life; but a great many have risen to
in their own particular line of endeavor. The members
have a right to be proud of its achievements apd it is
a source of pleasure to give to the public this history
orts and accomplishments.
: oef our boys we are especially proud of because of his hearts of p. oople eve. rywhere. His ~ imple un? er&#173;f
I? OOple and ~ IS magnetIc power of leadmg them mto
thinking have mfluenced a leading editor of the country
&#8226; Edwards is bright enough to be conspicuous, and
ugh not to know it."
laee
to locate Ethel Anderson at first because I looked in
p r. h .
hie or er. She was not among the society women
clUb- women, as I had supposed. Things like
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
Is overwhelmed by nature and all of its charm,
By the call of the furrow and " back to the farm."
NEELY.
Oh! Gladys go call the alumni home, from o'er the land
and sea,
For they can hear none other, for non~ cll: n call1i. ke thee
NUNLEY. . &#8226;
Beware of the girl with the dre, amy eye,
No matter how timid or modes~ or shy,
For if once you are smitten by her magic spell,
" Xou never Cll. ll break it~ o I've heardlboys tell.
PARKER.
Make friends with her whatever you do,
Or else her , prophe. cy will be hot for you.
PINKERTON.
Oh, Herman, have new courage and wait,
For love may come even if ' tis late.
ROBBINS.
Our wish for you in one brief line:
That healtl~ and joy may yet be thine.
SAIN.
She is 1; aken for a Senior wherever she goes,
By her dignified step and the tilt of her nose.
SCOTT, RUTH.
A haughty, heartless homo hater,
Among all her sex there is no greater,
A shrewd politician a. nd a suffragette,
A smooth ci~ izen- Iestyou forget.
SCOTT, LULA.
Another for whom man has no charm,
But not so vicious as to wish him harm,
Whose motto is ever " to stand alone,"
Though she explore the earth from zone to zone.
SOWELL.
Such a dimpled doll- like dainty creature
With happiness written on every feature.
When did you see a' Senior so rare, I
With twinkling eyes so free from care?
STORY.
A pitcher, a cornetist, and a lover all three,
Such a versat&gt; ile fellow you seldom can see.
6
record, Nowhere can there be found a fairer or
ot a single jail- bird and only one lawyer in
preading their influe, nce down through the
e whole world, I hear them singing as they gQ:
, T, N., all hail! guide of our youth,
u thy children on to light and truth.
en death summons us, o, thers shall praise,
T. " all hail! thr, ough endless days."
the author to the Faculty of M. T, N. 1917.
y has entered the Red Cross service. The sick
h~ r que forget their pain under . her gentle
loyal worker for the Y. W. C. A. in the organization
' 1917 was Bessie M, ai Tayl. or. I am sure her old
to kn, ow that she is how a Y. W. C. A. District
TIlE M. T. N. SIG TAL 9
b " II" nt appeal to the jury for acquittal.
rnade ad : 1 d
1a
the elen ant, both the H~. n., Mr. Pinkerton
r the pom't 0 f his arO0 ' ument 111 hiS flow of elo-ndence
f1' 0m Four Corners to the county paper is
the following: " Miss Lily Dale, the competent
ofthl' SpI ace, lost her head last Wedne. sdayffwhen
caught on fire. We hope the lady wIll su er no
from this loss." ..,
' t daily: " A strange mCldent : happened at 114
ael y S . h h "
t last Mond~ y morning. Mrs. ml~ '. w 0 10
Pauline Dement, appeared to her maid to be
unus, ual way. Thinking she was losing her
&#176; d called the doct~ r. Her mind was ; sp. fe hut her
ed, And here if&gt; the ~ onder- she had fallen in
usband,"
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
Fr~~ k Hill is .~ good old cOltntry dpctbr. He has been
di~ ppoin, ted in the 0! lly seripus love affair he ever 4ad and is
rather rusty 0,[ 1 the subject of his age. He is still hoping for
the second case ~ f h~ rt disease to attacjk him and in the mean &#8226;
time h~ says, " Telephone, telegraph, but never tell your age."
They s, ay the ~ ood die yplmg. Adas Verble is enjoying the
best of health on his scientifically mapaged mountain farm. We
are sure he will live to a ripe old age.
The Scott sisters, Lula a, nd Ruth, s~ rted out as loyal suffra&#173;gettes,
feeling that they could reform &#183; the world: After , a y~ r's
time they were content to limit their worl to reforming their own
town. Now they would be supremely h, appy for the privilege
of reforming just two men. ,
Mr. Cummins has made an exhaustive study of Psychology.
He is an authority, a fountainhead of knowledge. So serio" sly
has he taken himself and his work, Spence Holden, the well kpown
poet, who was himself a member of the 1917 Class, felt it apprp-priate
to dedicate these lines to him: ;",
" Unless you stop your solemn ways and take to fun and ch~~~'
Some day something will tickle you, until you die a laughmg!
The newspapers have been an invaluable aid in locating t, he
men and women who were members of the 1917 Class.
This is from a daily of the Middle West: " The Hon. Henna;
Pinkerton in his argument for the defense in the case of the Sta e
Myrtle Brogden is teaching in a rural school of the state. I
is a legend in the neighborhood that she never tells her aae exc t
to a vi. ctI" m of the lackJaw. '" ept
We would hate to admit that one of our members was
thief, but Mertis Leonard has proven herself enough of a klept~
maniac to steal an honest man's heart.
Freeman Lackey has been successful in his Stammer suit at
last. As they have no source of permanent income, I'm sure
They know no Epicurean blisses,
But live on bread and cheese and kisses.
that had not appealed to Ethel for she wished to be more th
cha~ ming bit o~ scenery in the la~ dscape of the. world. She~: a
dediCated her hfe to rural extensiOn work and IS very successf d
in her field. ul
8
EDITORIAL
STAFF.
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
MURFREESBORO, TENNESSEE
ijJ1Jt iI. ijJ. N. ~ igunl
The Staff
MARYSHUGART ~
VERA SOWELL_ -- -- -- -- -- -- -~ -- -- -- -- -- -- ---- - ---_ Dro
HOKE COWEN_ -- -- -- -- -- -- -- -- -- -- -- -- -- -- -- -- -__ _ G
HARVEY DENSON_ -- -- -- -- -- -- -- -- -- -- -- -- -- -- __ -_.~_ C
FANNrE ALLEN LEGGETT_ -- -- -- -- -- -- -- -- -- -- __ ._ .-_ Glee
ANNA MACRAE -- -- ---- ----- Y. W. C.
ERNEST COFFMAN - - - - - - - - - - - ( - - - - - - - - Y. M. C.
CAS MILES - - - - - - - - _- - . J
ItUTH SCOTT _
BESS BLAKE . Country Life
President Wilson's , address to the Americ. an people has
with a decided , respons~ showing that the Americans of
are just as loyal as the Americans of long ago. ONCE at th
cry to arms men felt that the only possible way to serve
fight. ' N" ow ~ ach patriotic person has to decide in which oC
ways he ca. n best serve-- in the trench or in the furrow. r
, Now that practically the entire world is looking to
for food, the furrow &#183; has risen greatly in importance.
responsibility has been so impressed upon the fa. rmers and U
the stJidents that the boys livijl1g on farms feel that they can
serve America by going back to the farm to join the great a
of producers. . ~
In lopkmg over o.. J. lr chapel one can see by the many ho
seats how well our boys have resp'onde. d. Those of us'h nOt
not go are proud of them, for we know theIr work, thoug dill
spectacular as the work of the boys who join the army an
is just as important. Let us salute the patriot- planter!
Editorial Staff
Editor- in- ChieL -- -- -- - - -- -- -- -- -- -- - ---- -- - MILDRED T
Assi. stant Editor -- LULA A
BusIness Manager- - - - - -- - - -- - - -- - - - ---- - - - _- BERNARD
VOL. V
10
FREEMAN LACKEY.
MR. HOUSEFLY.
r In Germs of Disease and Death
11
doors and windows this spring with a complete
::;. ms commonly known to be carried and
. I sincerely trust that you will be can-not
block m .
d
y entI; ance mto your home with
an that ' 11 . In . you WI also continue dumping
! louasneurMe In the 0 pen. Th" IS IS necessary that
e . rs. Fly and the many poor little flies
1ll your town depends upon plenty of nice
f building monuments in memory of loved wa; to the mo? e~ n idea of building n: emorials
t only memorIahze but at the same tune be of
.0.0 Instead of monuments which beautify but
~ rvice, we see everywhere libraries, hospitals,
are not only beautiful but are of definite service.
o &#176; t is seen in our schools all over the land. Now
leaving their Alma Mater, wish to do something
often that they leave a tablet with the names of
upon it, or some other equally useless gift, but
to make their gift in a form that will be of service
hool.
have shown clearly that they have caught this
making it possible for our school to hear some
every year. This meaQs far mpre to a school
,.. Iize for most of us come from small towns
urers never go; and as all of us Im, ow, it is
g in contact with people who have breadth
that we by comparison are able to see our
Btrive to attain them.
e beautiful spirit in which this gift was pre-
&#8226; ces that must necessarily be made by the
apd of the preceeding years, I am sure I
of the entire student body when I say that we
the gift and that we shall try to prove it by
out Qf these lectures as they are brought to us.
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
rotten garbage and manure, and that they m';' y be hatched and
raised to the sublime state of adult flies, and go out for themselv
as traveling representatives of this firm to visit your neighbo~
and supply them with disease and death. You must remembes
that it is only the dead and decayed state of animal and vegetabl r
life ~ hat concerns us in enlarging our business and increasing ~~~
armies.
My firm has for distribution. this spring the very choicest
line of " Consumption" germs which we bring directly froIll the
spittoons of our best patients or manufactures, and deliver in
your bedroom ( if it is not screened) directly to your mouths. I
also have an excellent line of typhoid germs, which I picked up
on my feet in the back yard of the home of a patient, who, by.
the- way, was screened but who was nice enough to our firm to
allow the excretion to be thrown in this back yard. I guarantee
these to be perfectly fresh and free from any effects of a disin&#173;fectant.
I will deliver these to your dining table and on the
knives and forks and the only charge will be " a little sip of milk,"
and here I will manage to leave a few germs especially for those
who drink milk.
I am very sorry to have to state again to my customers that
it is impossible for me to supply them with malaria germs, but I
will state for my fellow colleague, " Mr. Mosquito," that he will
be around on time and will carefully inoculate all who live in
unscreened houses, with this exceedingly popular germ. I will.
state for the mosquito, also, that in order that he gets to the
members of your family you should by all means never screen
your windows and doors.
I would like to announce that should my customers prefer
some other germs than typhoid, tuberculosis or malaria- fe~ er, I
shali be glad to supply them with cholera, diarrhoea, dysentery,
or a mixture of germs which I do not guarantee as to the. hinds,
but I have reason to believe that among them can be found scarlet
fever, measles, and many other contagious and infectious diseases
which the doctors have not been able to dia. gnose by isolating
any certain germ. I am'certain that most of these diseases last
mentioned are in the homes which have not been so selfisH to our
firm as to screen. Now, a few words &#183; concerning the methods I
employed by us in carrying these germs. We light upon &#183; the
s. pittoons, etc., and eat all we want and more than we . can retain
and we are careful to get our feet well covered with it, then we
EXAMINATIONS
13
ByW. G. W.
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
The exam. bell tolls the knell of parting hope,
The faint- hearted students go slowly to the room;
d while reading the questions with which they cannot cope
Between the lines they read their doom.
ow fades the maddening questions from their sight
And all their brain a solemn void holds,
:\" e where their hopes are taking their aimless flight,
As of their death the exam. bell tolls.
The hope of passing, the one thought of the hour
Is slowly lowered in their brain,
And then arose one rhetorical flower,
Out of our mental confusion saved.
Here rests our hopes beneath the mound
Of papers on the teachers' desks,
They promptly died at the exam. bell's sound
And sadly we laid them to their rest.
y out the doors or windows, and down the street to the next
houJ! e where we go in the uncreened door, s or windows, and light
&#8226; the milk or on the food. We also regurdidate the food eaten
a~ t the other house. .
As I have said before I will be around early thjs spring and
" ben I find a house unscreened, or the garbage in open boxes,
etc., I shall take it for grant. eo that I and my family are welcqme,
and I shall l{ j8. ve you plenty of the above darned germs, and
MAKE MYSELF AT HOME. Yours very truly,
MR. HOUSEFLY,
Special Representative Disease Germs.
15
RrTH SCOTT.
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
WHY WE SHOULD HAVE CONSCRIPTION
The questio) 1 as to how we shall raise a sufficiently large
armY to meet present demands has been widely discussed. .. Shal'l: l e use the old volunteer system or shall we resort to conscnptlOn I
Weh, eartily aa0 ree with President Wilson who has endorsed the,
Jatter. . _ .
First, we shall consider this from an economIcal standpomt.
If we use the volunteer system, the best manhood of our country
&#8226; eluding married men with wives and children dependent upon : aero, farmers, and men engaged in other occupations absolutel!
essential to the welfare of the nation wiII be the first to offer their
services. On the other hand, if we use the draft system, those
Blen will be drafted first who are loafing or engaged in some
occupation not necessary to the maintenance of our people. By
this method we will be rid of all loafers and slackers and everyone
will at least be employed in serving his country in some capacity.
Owing to the, present scarcity of food supplies in our country we
must raise our army without weakening the economic resources
, r the country, and this is possible only through the policy of
conscription.
What is the greatest need of our allies now? Certainly we
eannot say that they need our soldiers more than they need food
and munitions. We must be prepared to furnish both, but the
most pressing need right now is for the latter. In order to meet
the demands made upon us and to serve our allies in the best
eapacity the only sensible thing to do is to send as soldiers those
who are not contributing to the supply of food and munitions
and keep those at home who can best serve their country as
tarmers, railroad men, or factory hands.
We , ShOllld be intellig. ent enough to profit by the experience
ot the warring nation, s. AIl of us ! ire familiar with Englilnd's
un. t: ortup, ate expe~ ien~ e. In cqnsequence of the volqnteer system
thou~ ands of men went to the. trenches who were wor: th their
weight in gold to their cou~- trIY in the industries which, t, he
deSerted. What '~ a~ Epgl, apd f~~ ced to , do? She ha, d to recall
all men who were e, fficient along i; ndustrial lines , and resort to
COnsc, npti9n in the end. Engla, nd hJis learned her lesson by a
&amp; reat loss and why can't we profit by her mistake? Frapce had
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
CURRENT EVENTS
. J. L. MEADOWS.
A teacher was once asked this buestion: " Why do you Con_
tinue to study when you have a large store of knowledge already?".,
He answered, " I study that my pupils may drink from a flowing
fountain instead of a stagnant pooL" This thought is empha_
sized in every class- room in the Middle Tennessee State Normal
as is indicated by the attention given to present day topics.
' We are reminded that the same facts which students wiII
have to obtain from the printed page twenty- five years from
today are now coming to us first hand u! 1adulterated by the
whims and prejudices of the pen.
Since oilr great natio) 1 has at last entered the arena in the
world's war we watch the results with eager eyes. While we
entered the war to preserve certain rights of international law
we earnes. tly hope that in the epd the a'utocratic governments
wiII be broken d~ wn and governments patterned after our own
wiII be establi&amp; hed.
Owing to the fact t, hat there is considerable shortage in the
crops in our , country thi, s year and to the imperative need of
/ lending large quantities of food stuffs to our allies across the
sea, the question of increasing ' food products is receiv~' ng very
st, rict : attention throughout our lan, d. In response to this need
there ' is being organized ' all over the country companies known
as " THe Army in the furrows" for the purpose of increasing
the food products. Many of the boys from school have responded
! o this call an, d have gone home to aid in this cause.
We feel that our neighbor ( Mexico) wiII come jnto her 6wn
now since they have set up their government with General ' C~ r~
ranza at its head. Their minister to t~ e finited States was
received by President Wilson this week.
Perhaps th, e event which wiII more directly effe~ t the Middle
Tennessee State Normal School was brought to pass in the Legis&#173;l,
ature recently wh~ m, ~ hroJ1gh the untiring efforts of Presid~ nt
Jopes, a bill was passed by which the State institutions wiII
receive funds for necess: ary improvemel~ ts. By the proviJions
of this bill the Middle Tennessee State Normal will receive
$ 150,000. This money will be used to build a boy's dormitory, a
laundry, and a gym, nasium. The school needs these buildings
badly and the students all hail their coming with delight.
GEOFFREY WEAKLEY.
VIRGINIA'S HOLIDAY
( The character is wholly imaginary and does not apply to any
particular Virginia.)
" Mrs. Rutledge; call the station and see if the ' Flier' is on
time," chorused several girls at once.
The faculty had promised a half holiday , and - a picnic at the
flat rock provided Mr. Jones would give his consent. He 1iad
gone to Nashville and would not return until twelve- fifty- five on
the " Flier." The " Eds." had already carried the refreshments
to the place, and study had practically ceased except for the
mechanical recitations.
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL 17
Mrs. Rutledge Galled, ~ nd the answer w: as discouraging
u h. The " Flier" was four hours l. ate, and Mr. Jones would
8~ t here until four- fifty- five. This would compel them to
\;' ne the picnic until next day.., .
poe A group of girls rushed to their rooms to di~ cuss their diss~-
&#8226; t PresEmtly Virginia stood up. " I Will not study thiS
pollltmen . .
afternoon," she stormed. . "
" But you will get zero for your consolatlOn, warned one of
ber f" riNenodsI. won't. I'll have an excuse from Mrs. Ruit de ge, ~, nd
hat's more I'll have some of those refreshments served to me.
She removed her shoe, and painted her ankle a dull blue.
" How do you like my sprained ankle?" she asked triumph&#173;antly.
And now watch me put one over Mrs. Rutledge." .
She limped out to the great amusement of her littl~ aU? len. ce,
and knocking at Mrs. Rutledge's door she entered stIlI hmpmg
painfully. . d . d
She began, " Mrs. Rutledge, I fell down the staIrs an sprame
y ankle. It pains me so much that I don't feel like studying
this afternoon."
" No Virginia," Mrs. Rutledge interposed, " you must spend
few days in your room, for exercise would only make your ioot
orse."
Virginia returned to her room leaning on Mrs. Rutledge's
arm, who before leaving insisted that it would be better for her
t if she would remain in bed for the rest of the day. Virginia
ent to bed, but the beautiful weather otuside only made her
restless- it was spring.
The chapel hour passed, and in fancy she could see the merry
group eating dinner. One of the cooks brought her dinner to
her, and she was compelled to eat it alone. She now regretted
that she had not waited until after lunch to play her prank.
After lunch the girls gathered around the dormitory in merry
groups as if they were happy. Virginia noted the merriment in
their voices, and noted the contrast between them now and when
abe had seen them in the morning.
However, she had no~ long to wait for presently several giris
entered the ~ o, om- all with grave faces.
One of them spoke, " Vi. rginia, I am heartily ' sorry that you
Ve hurt your ankle, and I do wish you could be with us this
~ o. on. It was awfully l) ard on you to hurt your foot ju. st
ore the picnic.'"
16 TIlE M. T. N. SIGNAL
the draft system from the beginning and that is why she Was
able to send better equipped soldiers to the front much SOon
than England. She simply saved money, time, and valuab~ r
men. "' here would Germany be now if she had depended 0:
the volunteer system.?
Some may say that in all our former wars we have depended'
on volunteers. But the present conditions can not be compared
with those of the past. Moreover, all historians and others who
have investigatep the subject have found that the ineJficlency
and unnecessary expense of our army in the past have been due
to the system of raising the army. In our wars of long duration
conscription had to be resorted to as an extreme measure; so
why not have it at the beginning and thereby economize the
resources of our country?
We hear the argument made that conscription is undemo_
cratic. On the contrary, it is in the highest degree democratic;
for there will be no discrimination of persons. Democracy means
equality of obligation as well as of privilege and opportunity, and
it is not fair for our best manhood to sacrifice their lives in this
war while the loafers and slackers who enjoy the same privileges
and reap the same benefits remain at horne idle. We must have
conscription because it is vital to our democracy, our national
unity, and our manhood.
CLAY LUTHER.
LOWELL AFTON BOGLE.
SPRING
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL 19
d his present condition's; third, his future possibilities. The
firstnof, these questions calls for a record 0 f fa'Fts concern. mg the
" storie development of man. It involves hi~ natural traits and
. dencies; his ability to progress toward a hIgher state. of devel&#173;teDment,
under the conditions which circumstances have placed ; tn. The sec. ond questio, n . d~ ls with his pr~ sent standin~ a~ d
" volves a study of the condItIOns that form and surround hI!&gt; l~ fe
~ today. The third is speculative, , since it~ a,. nswer must be
( ou~ d in the future. Yet we may safely bas'e its answer on the
~ aracter an'd the trend , of the life that has pass~ d. No man's
tomorrow is ~ ntirely a new creation but a result of his past life.
The past, present, and future of a race presents successive steps
in its evolution.
With an understanding of these great questions relative to
the study , of man, let us apply them to a race that within three
J1undred years traveled from the jungles of Africa to the highways
~ American civiliz~ tion:- the greatest distance ever tra- yele, d by
mankind in so short a time.
The prehistoric negro is supposed to have entered' Africa
rom the northeast in a dwarfish type, u. sing only the rudest stone
: implem~ ntsand having np knowledge of home except as a shelter
f'tom his enemies. These tribes made their homes along the east
d west coast of the coni inent. ' There they remained in savagery
- unmolested until about 1500 B. C., when the Arabs touched the
Mrth coast of Africa. These two races blended and formed what
" known as the Ethiopian race. After this, Africa was forgotten
by all other races. For hundreds of years Africa grew into a
nation of barharous tribes. Practicing all kinds of religious
~ stoms of, savagery such as poligamy, the worship of the evil
mt, medicine men, witchcraft, feticism, and hum, an sacrifice.
Such were the conditions about five hundred yeaJ.: s ago when
modern Africa was rediscovered by the Por: tugese.
These people were followed by the Dutch, English, and
French. All of these nations sought by conquest to gain dominion
and power; all warred with one another; all made captives of or
~ eatroyed the natives who, se defree of civilizatio. n ma, de them
iJaferior to their conquerors. Finally the English nation 0' 111&#173;:,
Irinpped all of het competitors apd began to c30pture the savages the wilds of the African jungles and transplanted them to
colonial possession in North America.
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
CAN THE ETHIOPIAN - CHANGE HIS SKIN?
There are three great questions that claim attention when
considering the life and destiny of man or race: first, his' past life;
" What? Are you go. mg to have a picnic?" almost screamed
Virginia.
" Yes," answered her friend, in mock syrup, athy, " and its too
bad th;: tt your foot is hurt &#163; 0 BADLY. . ,
Virg~ nia tl1' r, ned he. r face t~ the wall, anp triE: O to swallo~ a
lump which. aro~ e persl, stently m her throat. She did not know
when her fnends left but w. hen she turned again the_ y were gone,
and she was left alope-- wlth her regrets and with HER SPRAINED
ANKLE 0). ,
Welcome, dear Sprip~ time, welcome we say,
The stars of thy evening, the dews of thy May.
We look fo. r, we long for,
We wait for you, Spring,
And our heart, s hold a song fO, r
The gladnes, s you b, ing.
Walk o'er the meadows and, spri, nkle the rain,
Say to the flowe~ s, " Wake up again."
Give us a , morning
All sunny and bright,
And sta, rs for adorning
The blue field of night.
And let each beam ~ r zephyr that wander~ away
Fro~ n the sweet grassy fiel, ds of i~ s work and its ' play
Find the heJLrt of someone ,. ,.
Who will let it brinK
A. smile like the one
It brought to you, Spring!
18
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
The history of the rest of mankind offers no parallel to the
story of the transportation of the negroes from the jungles of
Africa to the shores of the . North American continent. The
Exodus of the Israelites from Egypt was , a voluntary act which
they believed to be directed by Jehovah, that they might escape
from cruel bondage to liberty. But not so with the negro. The
negro, contrary to his will, without knowledge of his destination
and without hope for the future, was forcibly carried thousands
of miles across an unknown sea to an unknown fate in an unknown
land. Thus uptorn as a weed from its native soil and all of its
surroundings and its past obliterated, difficult was it for him to
believe that in the distant future his new home and its bondage
was to work out for him a higher destiny.
The past movement of the negro race has shown that American
slavery was the first step in the evolution of the negro savage into
a citizen of highly civilized state. The horrors of slave trade
have often been described; they could not be exaggerated. There
were continual scenes of raid, burning villages, cruel beatings and
weary marches from captivity to transportation. The weak ones
often perished on their way to the slave ships which were waiting
at the coast. Then followed the middle passage, where men,
women, and children were herded in the ships in suffocating
masses to die or to live as chance might determine.
Imagination refuses to picture the agony of the poor unfor&#173;tu,
nate captives during their passage to America.
The conscience of Christendom was not sleeping and her
voice was not silent on this great immoral question. Pitt and
Fox fought against slave trade in England, until finally their
voices crossed the Atlantic to the American colonies, and as early
as 1760 the Colonies were passing acts against this ffihuinah
practice. Thomas Jefferson went so far as to attempt to prevent
slavery in the Constitution. These men watched the grow. th
of slavery with great contempt. They realized that slavery was
a sin, a national sin and the nation as a whole was responsible fOr &#183;
it. As a result of their influence there grew from the Great Lakes
to the Gulf of Mexico a strong sentiment against slave trade.
The broader minded men be~ an to realize that the worth of
civilization is never greater than the man at its' center; and the
standard of a nation can never rise higher than the standard of
its citizenship. To furnish all people irrespective of race or
color the c~&gt; ndition whereby they might attain the highest type
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL 21
eitizepship would mean the abolition of slavery. To fall shor
this duty to any portion of our citizens is to fall short of the
, h dest~ ny to which America is appointed. Here for two
dred years this great question was fOj. J. ght between Dempcracy
d Oligarchy. At last they met in deadly conflict. Slavery
e great object ofatt'ack was destroyed. This decisive conflict
~ ved the great problem, but cr~ ated a grell- ter one. To make
ur million slayes free is a great task; but to make these free men
OW numbering twelve million souls, iIljdustrious, progressive,
triotic citizens, is a greater and worthier , task. This is now the
problem confronting the American people.
. , During the many years that the flames of slavery were
. dling, the relation of , the Southern master and their slaves had ar oVlll very close and , coedial. We remember with what fidelity
lor four years the slave guarded our defenceless women and
! ebildren whose husbands and fathers were fighting a, gainst his
om. These ties were so dose th, a-' f; while the masters were
bsent in the field of battle, they could trusit their homes, their
~ ves, their child, Ten, and their property, to the care of their
yes with absolute confidence in their fidelity, which Cas never
~ ra. yed. Many thousap.' Cls of these slaves followed their mas, ters
~' e b, atde front and cared for them and saw that their bodies
hed home dead or alive, and not a single incide) lt can we
d where one of these slave se~ ltinels deserted his master; while
ere were others who remained at home and raised the crops
t fed the Confederate ' army, and suffered without complaint
e privations which came alike to both black and white. The
ve was true to the last notwithstandipg the fact that he knew
&#8226; master was away from home fighting a battle which, if success-
, would result in his continual enslavement, yet he l~ bored
' thCully for the cause of his master. If the negro had yielded
the temptations and suggestions to u~ e the. torch or assasin's
er to destroy his master's property and family, the result
uld have been that the war would have quickly ended, for the
aster would 4ave returned from the battlefield to protect hi &#167; !
me and property. But the negro was faithful to the last to
e trust that had been thrust upon him; during the four years
~ the war there is not a single incident recorded where the negro
eel to outrage his master's family or destroy his property. When
t last he raised his black and humble hands that the shackles
' ght be struck off , those hands were innocent against his helpless
/'
THE M. T. N, SIGNAL
charges and were worthy to be taken in loving grasp by every
one who honors loyalty and devotion.
This means the just coordination of two races under principles
and institutions that have not been surpassed by any race of
people on the globe. One of these races is but a few years out
of savagery, the other, the proud exponent of civilization brough~
about by twenty centuries of human progress; but the hearts
of the two races must beat alike to the Constitution and true
Americanism.
The first step in the life of any people is largely physical apd
must be solved by manual labor. It is said that despisers of toil
are never builders of nations. Labor is the first element in the
development of individuals and of races. This is the secret of
America's greatness- an ancestry of toilers; men to whom industry
is a creed, muscle a virtue, toil a religion. This was the method
by which America was elevated and it must be so with the negro.
Industrial independence must be the first step in the elevation
of the negro in the South. Servitude has taught him one great
lesson, that of toil, But when he received his freedom, there came
a great reaction in his life brought about by the scalawags and
carpet- baggers from the North. They were taught by these
men, that the Southern white man was his enemy when he should
have been taught that he was his friend. He was told that he
was equal to the white man when he was not. ' He was taught
th3; t the government would sustain him when it could not. He
was taught thieving in politics, , and indolence in private life. To
this false teaching can be attributed the misfortune of the negro
and the South since the Civil War. In the novelty of his freedom
old things wer~ forgotten and restraints cast aside. Labor that
had become to the negro the badge of servitude, was now a thIng
of dishonor. Peace, rest from toil, and everything that could be
had in a free and bounteous land were to be his forever. How
unbounded the faith of that lowly people, how deep the disap?
pointment of their hope, how awful the realization of what It '
meant to be poor, black and ignorant in a land where money was
master and the Caucasian a king!
Years have passed, arld the old school of slavery has died
out and a new generation has taken its place. A race of unskilled
toilers, a race that is here to stay as long as the white man. So
it ia the white man's duty to put this race on the road to progress
THE M. T. N. SIGNAl:
. roving its health and establishing a publicly supported
by Imp .
&#8226; dustrial system of educatlOn. .,
lJ1 The negro in America faces those. di~ cultles which have
onfronted every race. Consider the situatlOn. They are sur&#173;e
d d by one of the strongest races of men on the globe.. A
ro~: t~ at leads the world in commerce and indust?, . and w~ th
rthai. S racet, he negro must compete with hand and braIn In solvIng
his own destiny. . d' f
F " such conditions as these hiS greatest nee IS or
acmg h' . h h' . th
d ducated men men who sympat Ize WIt 1m In e lea ers, e, d I' I d
d" task of raisinO" an oppressed people towar Ig It an
I . lhvmte, l\ len who wili lead these millions of black souls to t. heir
I er y. . d bI"
highest life as worthy citizens o~ this great and umte repu IC.
The people that are to lead in thiS battle must not ~ ome fr. om the
I of our cities and factoi'ies but from the IndustPal, and
~;;= ratory schools, and from ~ niveI'si~ ies and c~ I1eges. HIgher
education alone can give to thIS race ItS true birth among the
races of men. .. . I
This problem is not necessarily a. sectional one; It IS natlOna
in its scope. Its solution not only Involves the ~ elfare o~ ~ he
negro, but the future of this republic. . Nearly SIxteen .~ mlhon
hands will aid in pushing the loads upward, or . they will p~ I1
against us the load downward. They will constitute one- th~ rd
and more of the ignorance and crime of the South, or one- th~ rd
of its inteIligence and progress. They.. wiIl contribute one- thIrd
of the business and industrial prospenty of the South or t~ ey
wiIIp', rpve a hindering body in every effo~ t to . adv'anc~ prospen~ y.
The black mim is a constitutional factor In thiS repu bhc: apd wIth
him we stand or faIl. The negroes constitute one- thud ~ f t~ e
population of the South. They hold one- third of her destmy III
their black hands. What the negro does for the South depends
very I~~ gely on what the Sout. h does for the negro. T~ e South
may make the negro the bl; l. Ck, diamond o~ our republIc or s~ e
may let her form into a great cIou, d that wIIl s? me d~ y break In
a storm ofa, narchy over our heads? The ever Incr~ asIng popula&#173;tion
of, the black race will prove either a great factor In the progre~ s
a, nd prosperity of this republic or it will prove a menace that. WIII
retard ever; t movement to national power and glory.. " .
The strength of any nation lies in the health of Its people.
The diSease of one race affect every other race. The death rate
of the nC' 1' ro has increased twenty per cent in the last two decades,
". P
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
an. d thoe white race is largely . responsible for this incr~ e. We
refuse tto let the negr, o buy hom~ s in our c~ ties except in our back
allies. where filth and stagnant water breeds disease. The streets
in which he lives are allowed to go without paving, drainage, and
sewage.. A's a res'ult of this thousimds of this poor race die by
the sweep of an epidemic. Yet the question is asked, who cares
if the pegro , dies out? Every man interested in the economic
welfare of the South must care. The South ' sgreatest need is
for lab( JJ'ers, and the negro is the only available source of supply.
The go"' Vernment estimate of the cost of the disease among the
laboring class of th, e negroes in the South for the year of 1915 is
$.'&gt;, 000,000,000. Every man and woman interested in the health
and hap mess of the white race in the South must aid in the
decrease of the death rate of the negro. If the negro is dying
out the white people must bear tpe guilt for we give him no laws
of sanitation nor do we teach him the laws of self- preservation.
But we allow him to be imposed on by the greed of &#183; the money
shark, tile lust of the landlord, the chicanery of the pot politician.
The weeping of this lowly people ascenAeth to high heaven and
we raise n tour hafl., d to stJ: ty their lamentation. Men of the
South who glorify in the passing of the negro are sanctioning
murder committed by our own race. We must accept the verdict
that the blood of the innocent will be on our hands.
Already th, at blood is on our heads, already the laws of
retribution h~ ve begun to strike back. Whenever a negro dies
of tuberculosis he leaves a train of white boys stricken who have
contractel his disease. Instead of glorifying as some do in what
seems to be the decay of the negro race, self- interest, self- instinct,
self- preservation, humanity, Christianity, all unite in demanding
that we Slay this tide of death. All the disease among this rac. e
can be eliminated by bringing about better housing conditions
and better medical attention. ---..
Aside from the question of social intermingling, perhaps the &#183;
question f negro education has aroused more prejudice than any./
other phase of the negro problem. As a civilized nation we have
long sinc&#8364; accepted the fact that knowledge is power; and that
. any nation that keeps its people in ignorance is doomed to medi&#173;ocrity.
Eut from some cause we have not applied this doctrine
to the colored race of America. We believe in the education of
alI kinds of animals. We believe in extending our learning to
the four mers of th~ earth. We send our Christians to the
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
&#8226; gles of Africa for the purpose of uplifting the negro there, yet
~: refuse to educate the negro in our midst. In the days of
I very and up to the present time a large per cent of the people
sfa the South have deemed" It ess1entra, rlor'mternaI peace, and
; ocial security, to make ignorance the condition of the slave or
the laboring clas, s of the South. There can be no greater ? ur~ e
inflicted on any people than that of being forced to re~ am III
. norance. It will only take one example to put our mmds at
:' se on the question that higher education will elevate the negro.
Of all the graduates of the four greatest negro institutes of t~ e
United States, Fisk, Atlanta; Hampton, and Tuskegee, there IS
Dot a single one that has ever been in jail, but all are pursuing
elevated positions. The record shows that ninety per cent of the
colored race that is in the prisons are without a trade, and that
sixty per cent of them are illiterate. Let us take these great
institutes as worthy examples of the elevation of the colored race
and establish a Tuskegee in every State of the Union by means
of schools supported by the public system, by both races. Let
it not be objected that a system like this would require impossible
means. Education is an investment which no people ever paid
too much for. Indeed, the more they pay the richer they become.
Nothing is so costly as ignorance, nothing so cheap as knowlegde.
Here by this means our recovery must begin, and in this way
alone, and by us alone can it be begun. The educated men of the
South, of this generation, must be responsible for the future of
the South. The educated men of Tennessee must be responsible
for the future of Tennessee. That future that will be anything
that we now command. From every portion of this dear old
commonwealth there comes this night an earnest and anxious
voice to us, saying, shall we command or shall we serve? Shall
~ e rise or shall we fall yet lower? Shall we live, or shall we die?
Gathered in my own mind the voices of you all, with hearts
resolved, and purposes fixed, I send back the gladdening repose:
We shall live, we shall rise, we shall command.
27 THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
" Little BoS Senior, S, ( dp you want to play?
Then on the twentieth of April is the , day.
We're going on a hi, ke at four P. M.
Dop't fail the Senior Town Girls if you love them."
That was the messa, ge that gladdened the hearts of the
Senior boys. Many things happened to modify the plan!" before
the appointed day, but the determ, i. nation to have a gQpd time
never wavered. It wasn't a hike, because it rained, but the
SENIOR TOWN GIRLS ENTERTAIN
The members of the Senior Class have begun to think about
graduation but our plans for Commencement have been cha~ ged
since most of the boys have given up book- lore, for the time
being, to become " soldiers of the furrows." We hope that all
of them will at least come , b'ack and he with us at Commence-ment.
There are rumors in the air that the Junior, S are planning
. to entertain the Senior, tlnext Saturday with an all day picnic. We
certainly hope that their plans materialize for this class has ahvays
been in favor of out- door affairs. As a parting word to the
Juniors, we shall say, " Do as you would be done by," because
you will be Seniors next year.
SENIOR CLASS
The M. T. N. boys then journeyed over to Nashville to play
if the tie. Reager, the M. T. N. pitcher, was stingy. He gave : 0 one free tr~ nsportation to the initial bag, and allowed only
one hit. No M. B. A. play~ r was able to get any further than
the key-.. stone cushion, while M. T. N. r, omped over ; the rubber
twice. The team fielded brilliantly and wielded their bludgeons
in the pinches.
In closing we must mention the names of such stars as Bomar,
Joe T. Smith, Austin, and several others who illumined the base
ball world with their stellar work. Though their spi, kes may
never again rend thes9d of Anderson Field, their names are
indelibly written on t; he. pinnacle of the base ball hall of fame.
E. C. COFFMAN.
There has not been much doing here this spring in an athletic
way. This is due to the fact that the athletes have long since
hied it back to the farm to be a " hero in the furrow." They
hardly had a cha; nce to display their wares tl19ugh seyeral twinkled
as stars of Some magnitude. ' Only three matinees were staged.
The Norma~ lads clo~ tld the season with the grand average of : 500.
The first contest was staged with the Vanderbilt Varsity on
the lo~ al diamond, March 31st. At the close of the nine inning!,
the Normal was nur. sin, g the little end of a 6 to 0 score, wi: th
Rogers on the mound. The first seven innings favored the
Normal. He gave up , only four little mea!" eley hits and thirteen
Vanderbilt swatsmen s1- lccombed to his dazzlin, g slants. The
six markers registered against him were due to the poor fielding
of his team mates.
The next game was played with the M. B. A. on the orne
field one week later. It was plain that the big pitcher was not
in form, although he twirled a steady game. The M. B. A. lads
were so small that un! boys were afraid to do anything lest they
might step on the little ones. But when the melee was over the
sc~. re was 8 to 3' The Nashville boys dented the rubber in the
second and again in the third. The Normal registered three
counters in their half of the fourth, but M. B. A. evened up things
in the next inning. After this both teams settled down and no
one was able to reach the hot corner.
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
&#8226; 26
JUNIORS ENTERTAIN THE SENIORS
CLAXTON LITERARY SOCIETY'
President- &#8226; -- -- - - -- - W. J. Edwards
Vice- Ptesiden, L -- - - - _ Knox Hutchinson
Secretary - 7 -- - -- - - _ Herman Pi, nkerton
Chapl~ ip- --, 7- -- -- --'-- - - - J. A. McCormick
Cr~ t~ c - - - - - _ Delzel
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
The Seniors were delightfully ent~ rtained by the Juniors
Saturday, l\ lay 5th, with an all day picnic. The hiking party
left the Normal at nine a. m. and walked out five miles to the
pi&lt;; fl. ic grounds. The most enjoyable part of the day's, progt: am
was the d~ lici. o: us lunch which was served , at , noon. Th~ party
left for the Normal about 3: 30 and arrived there in time for
supper. The entire day was a success in every respect and , the
Seniors, who are especially fOJld of out, doo! life, unanimously
voted " a day well spent." Their best wish for the Juniors is
that the next year : Juniors will treat the Seniors just as they did.
28
gymnasium made a splendid reception rp, om where all enjoyed
the Virginia Reel until the hour arrived for supper. The table
was beautifully decorated with potted plants apd a c~ nterp~~, ce
of fr, uits. The way the good things tp eat disappeared showed
how well the supper was e, njoyed. Mr. Russell made an excellent
toast. maste! and called on seve,~ l of the girls and boys to respond.
Everybody expressed the~ r plCfLSu; re at this manifestation of a
friendty- spirit , between the boys and gir, ls of the Sen, ior Clas. s.
Reluptantly the party quitted the banquet hall and went in a
body to the patriotic mflss meeting of the Murfreesboro citizen_'
ship.
29
Colors
White and Gold
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
FIGw~ r
Narcissus
DROMGOOLE LITERARY CIRCLE
We are having some real interestingdeb. ates now. Recently
the question: " Resolved, That in the present War the United
States should raise an Army by the Volunteer System rather than
by Conscription," was discussed. The affirmative side was
represented by Messrs. Prater and Gilliam, the negative side by
~ essrs. Coffman ~ nd Baker. It is not necessary for Congress
~ debate the question any longer, for the negative speakers in
this debate have forever settled the question.
Mr. B, urton a, nd Mr. Luther ~ ave be~ n selected to r~ present
us in debate with the Gtady Society. Thi. s promise. s to be: the
iIlost interesting debate the M. T. N. student body ever witnessed.
Prof. P. P. Claxton, United States Commissioner of Educa&#173;tion,
visited us recently. He made an interesting talk to the
socie~ y just after addressing the entire student body in chapel.
Our meetings are being well attended despite t. he (~ t that
SO mp. ny of our boys h, ave gone hom~ to joi, n the " Army in the
Furrows." We are expecting quite a number of them to return
a, nd b~ wi, th us duripg, the cl, o~ ing exercises.
PresidenL Myrtle Brogdon
Viee- PresidenL Lula Scott
1rreasurer Ruth Scott
Sergeant- at- Arms_ - Lillian Beesley
Critic Mae Taylor
DEBATBRS.
GRADY SOCIETY
THE M. T. N. SIG AL 31
Cleo Blankenship President
Johnnie Gore Vice- President
Mary Whitaker Secretary
Virginia Branham .__ Treasurer
Maude DemenL Sergeant- at- Arms
Mildred Taylor . Critic
Our Society has recently been honored by the visits of former
wembers. These are always welcome. They seem to have the
Grady spirit as strongly as ever.
MURFREE SOCIETY
With this term, one of the most fruitful years in the history
of our Society closes. We have enrolled many new members;
enjoyed wise and tactful administrations; and heard some excellent
programs. We are proud of the advancement made by our
younger members. The future success of a society depends
largely on the training and development of these younger members.
Three of the State debaters will be furnished by the Grady
Society. These are ' Vall, Page, and Knott. The latter two will
go to Johnson City. These men are experienced debaters and
have excell~ n, t recprds. 1p their credit We trust that , another
vict~ ry will be adde~ t&lt;:&gt; the many triumphs of this institution.
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
On Friday afternoon, April 27th, the Dromgoole girls, with
Miss Will Allen Dromgoole as their honor guest, enjoyed a
pleasant outing on the Normal farm from four till seven o'clock.
The time was spent pleasantly in playing garnes, in singing, and
in story- telling. Just before returning to the dormitory a delight&#173;ful
picnic supper was served.
At eight o'clock the joint program of Claxtons and Drom:
gooles was rendered. The concluding number was a splendid
talk on " Service" by Miss Droomgoole. After the program a
short social hour was enjoyed by all.
President- - _ Frank Hill
Vice- President- Melvin Crawley
Secretary L. A. Hunnicu: t
Treasurer Gordon DavIs
Sergeant- at- Arms A. A. Goblet
Chaplain Marable
Critic ~ __ Will Story
Colors: Red and White.
Emblem: La France Rose.
Motto: SaPientia et Eloquentia.
A large number of our members left school this term to
become temporary farmers.
Owing to the fact that two members of the play, Mr. Harry.
Moore and Mr. Martin Hayes, joined the army of those in the
furrows, the Dromgooles and Claxtons decided that it would
be best not to give their play, " Our Mutual Friend," by Dickens.
It has been the aim of the society this year to make a thoroU&lt; 7h
study of a specific country at each program. For the past quarter
Spain, Ireland, Germany, and France have been studied.
At the beginning of the, spring term twelve new members
were added to the society. Two or three members have bee
added at every meeting. n
30
' J;' HE M. T. N. SIGNAL
On March thirteenth the sprl, nK term opep, ed. The crowd, ed
hall was suggestive of spring with its va!) es of jonquils here and
there. The girls started out this first meeting with ' enthusiasm
and the prpg, r, a, m , showed wprk.
The girls have eagerly volunteered to be in the essay contest
and since we are putting forth our best we expect good ret, llrns. '
On Friday evening the twenty- third of March , we Eave our
Murfree- Graqy program. After the program those present were.
asked to join in and be, sociable.
All the girls contributed a handkerchief and sqme can~ y_ and _
flow: ers for the . bazaar given on the twelfth and thi, rteenth of
April. The girls were all eil, ger to help and proved themselves
loyal i, ti many ways.
We have studied the lives and works of the greatest En., glish
writers this term. They have been very in teresting and in~ tru.. c&#173;~
ive. They have shown work and talent fr() m those taking par. t.
Y. w. C. A.
Preside, nL Fannie Allen Liggett
Vice- PresidenL Bess Smith
Secret, ary Isabel Atkinson
Treasurer Alexine Brown
We are glad to welcome spring again as it makes it possible
for us to have opr meetings on the campus or in chapel where they
can be erdoyed by a larger number of students.
The Association is very happy ove, r the possession of five
new volumns fo, r our library, " The Bible Story." This is the gift
of the old cabinet. The volumns are bound in American seal. It
is an edition of the Bible in attractive type, profusely illustrated
with masteI:. pieces of the familiar, artists, and with phptographs
of the Holy La, nd. The first vplume is de;&gt; igned for little children,
the others are the Arne~ ipan Revit'ed Version. There are many
splepdid h~ lps i, ncorpo: rat~ d i; n these books.
THE COUNTRY LIFE CLUB
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL 38
The quarter of quarters for the Country Life Club is here.
About the first week or two of this term b~ ts of o, onversation like
The Y. M. C. A. has discontinued its meetings, due to the
fact that the members have volunteered to be " heroes in the
furrow." After supplying the world with enough food to last
until the close of the war, they will be back in full force next fall.
Dr. Winfield Hall delivered'a series of lectures to the student
body this term. One lecture was for the boy. s only. This
lecture was taken from a book' of which : Dr. Hall is the autho &#183; r.
At the close of the lecture the boys purchased about forty' copies
of the book; $ 10.00 of this money went to the local Y. M. C. A. "
The Y. M. C. A. held its an, l1ual election this term. The
Association unjinimously ele~ ted M.' P. Hayes, Pr~ sident; J. M:.
McCormick, Vice- President; John Rooker, Secretary; William
Scivally, Treasurer; and Wendell Atwood, SIGNAL Correspondent.
No better selection of ojlicers could have been made.
, .
The deJe, gates to the Y. W. C. A. Co, nference at. Blue Ridge,
North Carolina, have not yet been elec~~ d, but &#183; we hope to send
more than ever before as a portion of the Student Activity ' Fund'
is to be used for this purpose.
' Y. M. C. A.
Amopg , the , outstanding meetings of the quarter is a joint
meeting of the Y. M. C. A. and the Y. W. C. A. when Mis, s Edith
Sawyer and Mr. Hunpicutt , made ' splendid talks' on " Leader-ship."
The joint meeting on April the foprth at which Miss Ting-liPg,
College Sec; etary . of the Young People's Branch of the
W. C. T. D., talked to us . on " Consecration," also deserves a
pl'ominent pIfice 0,11 this list.
Here, too, we would list t, he Vespers'ervice of April the
fiftee. nth at which Mrs. Cunni, ngham read us the beautiful little
story, " The Cup of Loving Service," by Eliza Dean Taylor.
Probably the most impressive of our recent services was that
one a, t which , Miss Buchanan read for us " Laddie."
thi, s ;. could be heard as one passed through the halls: " Do you
bel~ ng to the Country Life Club? Well, what's this I hear about
them going to Smyrna to the County Teachers' Meeting to . give
a p'rogram." " I'll tell you those Courltry Life Club folks are
going to have a great time tillS spring." " How do you get into
that Club anyway? I hear they a; re not going to take in any
new members after the ~ hir, d w~ ek oJ this qUarter- say let's
join!"
Well, d, u, ring the first three weeks of the term, at each meeting
there was a! crowd of people ready to have their names presented,
and to be sworn into the Club. After that time the doors of the
Club were. c) osed for any new members.
With our membership of about fifty we have had some great
happenings in that Club the last four weeks. One Thursday
afternoon Mr. Elrod, the County Superintendent, came out and
visited our Club, and invited us to go with him to Smyrna on
Saturday to the County Teachers' Meeting. Of course this
invitation w~ s hailed with deligh, t, a; nd on Saturday morning we
the members of the Club were crawling into the automobiles and
" Forces"- all out for Smyrna- they we're envied by every unin&#173;vited
person. Dr. F~: rtig well said, " Lucky fol~ s"- and lucky
folks we were. vVe have all heatd of Southern hospitality, and
since that day the Country Life Club Jolks have decided that
Smyr; na is the . center, for people were never shown mOre hospi&#173;tality
than we were that day- and eats- well, we surely had
them.
The Rural Surveys hp, ve been completed, and we are now
to visit these ~ ommunities that we have been studying, and see
for ouz; selves just what they are.
' We are planning an all day picnic at Caney- Fork Falls in
about two week, s, and also a number ,() f hikes before the close of
school.
ENTRE NOUS GLEE CLUB
/
1-
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
Altho thi; s year the Entre Nous Glee Club has not appeared
on Jrogram, it is indeed here. Since the boys have responded so
loyallu to the " call of the furrow," we feel somewhat left- ha: n. de~
yet we are not to be " weigl: ltd 0 the balances a~ d foun~ wa~ tl~ g,
for with'the coming of sprmgtlme we have received an mspIrat~ on
from the birds on the campus. So by Com~ enc, ementthe gIrls
and the - faithful- few boys wiII come forth wIth such a b~ rst of
harmony and melody that M. T. N. wiII be compelled to SIt back
and take notice. .
Without the boys we wiII not be able to gIve the Operetta
which we had planned lljnp pr, acticed on, but with choruses galore,
e will be ready to respond to the " Call of Commencement
Mus, ic."
34 THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
86 THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
Coach was giving a lesson o, n the circul, ation ot the blood.
Trying to make the matter clearer, he said: " Now, boys, if! stood
on my head the blood, as you know, would run into it, and I
should turn red in the face."
" Yes, sir," said the class. .
" Then why is it that while I am standing upright in the
ordinary position the blood doesn't run into my feet?"
A whisper was heard: " Because your feet are not empty."
Mr. Belcher went into a barber shop and plumping himself
down in the chair, said: " Haircut!"
The barber looked at him a mom~ nt and replied: " Why, man.
you don't need a hairc, ut- what you want is a shine."
A gi. rI was asked to exp'lam why men never kI'SS each other
while women , do. , "
She: " Men have something better to kiss; women haven t.
I
Bomar while in Nashville getting off the street car turned to
the conductor and sa, id: " Much obliged to you, sir."
Lyda M. ( at the table): " I do, not care especially for meat."
Martha D.: " You must be a vegetaria; n then."
Lydo: " No, I'm a Christian." .
Lillia, n Beesley: " I know something good for this SIGNAL."
Bess Blake: " Oh, what is itt Is it something about met"
Lillian: " No indeed. It is something cute."
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL 87
The little Ford submarine
Has n, ow put out to, sea,
And before long you'IJ hear
" We've' whipped old GerJIlany."
She may have the largest boats
That carry heavy loads,
But nothing ca. p quite come up
To those dar) led little Fords.
Ru, th Mee and Mary Whi~ aker always sing " Pretty Baby"
hen &#183; they stand before the mirror painting.
Irene still has a Page.
First Stugent: " Qh, are y~ u going to be inoculatedt"
Second Student: " Why, yes; The whole society is going to
bave its picture made."
Isabel Anderson ( after hearing Dr. Hall state that anyone
ho had insane relatives should not marry): " I certainly am glad
that I have no insanity in my family."
Sarah Lou Sanders ( meeting Mr. White in th. e hall , after
cutting his English): " Mr. White, I didn't . want to see you."
Mr. White: " By George, its mutual."
Bomar: " What ~ do you suppose the Germans would think
if they should see the Star's and Stri: pes waving over the field of
battlet"
Cas: " Why, they would trunk that the wind was blowing."
... t
Wanted to' know what Sue's last promise to Choate was.
Grace: " Joe you are a dear."
Joe C.: " Sho nun"
Pauline: "' Vhere are you going, Grace?"
Grace B.: " Down to the tooth dentists."
-+
III!
, I
II I+ II I III
I
I I iII
II
,+
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL 31)
" Is it easier to supply men or to supply food to our allies r"
" Food."
" Why?"
" Because it takes longer to raise men than it does to raise
Cood."
Dr. Fertig ( to a psychology class): " Anyone ought to marry
his intellectual equal."
Kno, x: " Doc, I shquld have to marry a, n idiot then."
Dr. Fertig after condensing a fifteen minute speech into a
principle, said: " Mr. Denson, if you get that into your head you
will have the whole thing in a nutshell."
Page: " Gentry, what !{ ind of a degree do you get when you
graduate here?"
" My gracious, boy," said Mrs. Barbee, " you do certainly
eat lots for a little man."
" Well, mam," replied Verble, " Maybe I'm not so little as I
look from the outside."
Mary Anderson ( the moming after Parker h.~ d signed up
for the navy): " What gre. at naval victory by the U. S. is reported
this morni, ng?"
Stop- Look- Listen- Something New.
Will remove all rubs and bruises on the heel within ten
minutes. Rub the blister until it becomes raw. Then apply salt
freely. For further information see Clay F. Grove.
Prof. Murphey: " Mr. Miller, have you read the Constitution
of the U. S.?"
. Red Miller: " No:'
Prof. Murphey: " H~ ve you re~ d the Doolar~ tion of Inde-pendence?"
Red: " No."
Prof. Murphey: " Well, what have you read?"
Red: " I have red hai, r on my ne~~."
,
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
Watned someone to beat the following boys' times:
Dale Younger.
Clay Groves.
Leonard Wright.
Knox Hutchinson.
Leah Sullivan: " I heard that Clay Groves is going to enlist."
Mary R.: " Goitg to! He is serving his time now."
Leah: " How's that?"
Mary: " He is Marion's body guard."
The following conversation was heard while on a recent
hike:
Grove: " Marion, if I were to pass away all of a sudden what
would become of you ?"
Marion' " Why, I would stay here. The question is what
would become of you ?"
Elizabeth Banks had ridden qown town in a taxi. When
she got out of the car, the driver held out his hand for the fare.
Elizabeth very politely shook hands with him and said that she
had enjoyed the ride immensely.
When in Nashville Coach takes his meals at " Little Pappa's"
a. nd then crosses the street to the Maxwell House to pick his
teeth.
Elizabeth: " Mr. Locke certainly must be a good man."
Eulalia: " Why?'"
Elizabeth : " Well, you see there is practically nothing betwee
him and heaven." n
38
Bessie Lee Batey ( in Sewing Textiles): " To make cotton
absorbent treat it with an ally ( alkali)."
Miss Parlin: " Miss Wright, name a soft cotton materiaL"
Miss Wright: " Crepe de chine."
Phone 77.
MURFREESBORO JEWELERS.
~~
Everything in the Jewelry Line.
Kodaks, Films and Stationery.
We solicit Your Business.
. F. Leathe, rman aCo.
~ _ _ '-"_ A_"-" _ ...-...- 0 _. _._ 1~ '. '' 1'-_ 1.
/
Blumenthal &amp; Becker I
Magazines, Candy, Cut Flowers and School Supplies.
MURFREESBORO, TENN.
L-_---------- 4~------____+
Goods, Notions, Ladies' Tailored Suits and Skirts, Carpets, Mat&#173;tings,
Rugs, Druggets.
e solicit your business. The store of HIGH QUALITY GOODS. Up&#173;to-
Date Styles and Right Prices.
East Side Square.
A. L. SMITH &amp; co.
Druggists
..-. c~~ I_"_~"-'
~
pry Goods, Notions, Ladies', Misses' and Children's Ready- to Wear
Goods.
II
Shacklett, CasonaRogersI I
I
II
40 THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
M, r. Souby: " What has occured since the Civil War t .
the North and South more completely?" ~ 0 Unite
Miss Henderson: " The : War of 181fl."
. Miss Taylor: " Miss Jackson, why do soldiers eat s I
nce?" . 0 much
Miss Jackson: " Because it is not so heavy to carry."
Mrs. Cunningham ( in giving drawing notes): " Green is h
most restful to the eye." t e
J: ames Peake: " Well, why don't they print text book .
green?". s In
Flora was hearing the class in arithmetic. One of the pupils
watched the figures on the board with a great deal of interest
much. to the teacher's satisfaction. She did several sums especially
for his benefit and as she erased the last figure she turned to the
boy:
" Do you understand those examples that I have just been
doing?"
" N' I . 0, rna m, but I would like to ask a question about them."
" Well, what is it?"
" Where do the figures go when they are rubbed out?"
e.-, &#8226;. b &#8226; &#8226; -..--. _ __ II. - 6- 0__- I _ ..-. __ 0__
w. T. Gerhardt~
Phone 59. I
,
Phone 97.
WHO KNOW.
BUTLER, HOOPER It CO. &#183; ,
CLOTHIERS FOR MEN AND BOYS
~
west Sidit Sqaure.
._-----.
UP- T~-~ ATE PRESSING CLUB.'
Ladles Work a Specialty.
Altering and Repairing,
And Suits Made to Order. I
I
DRY GOODS, NOTIONS, READTY- TO- W~ AR GOODS.
l_-=:;_~_~_~_;_~~_ Y_:_ T.:..__~...~_:_~_ g_ S_ t_~_ d __ en_~_ S &#8226; &#8226;__ J,
E. H. T TU
DENTISTS,
Drs. Jones
Star DR. W. W. JONES DR. J. B. JONES
Barber Shop
Smith &amp;- Kittrell
MARQUIS BRYANT, Prop. Citizens Bank &amp; Trust Co. Building. 1
WE PLEASE :~. : c~ : h~ 23. ::.: h:~:.:~ l
~ iddlB Tenne~~ BB 8tBtB NOPgJaI
An institution designed for the education of teachers for the schools of
Tenn. A large faculty of well educated men and women. A splendid equip&#173;ment
representing a cost of more than a quarter of a Million Dollars. A mag&#173;nificent
student body. Tuition is free, Board furnished at cost of food and
service. Spring term opens March 12, 1917. Summer term opens June 5,
1917. For f~ ll information write Jor catalogue, .
R. L. JONES, President, MUrfreesboro, Tenn.
The correct place to do your shopping. We carry only First- Class, Up_
to- Date DRY GOODS, MILLINERY, CARPETS AND LADIES' READY&#173;TO-
WEAR. YOUR PATRONAGE SOLICITED.
o.
= EAT=
AUERBACH'S CHOCOLATE COV&#173;ERED
CANDIES, CHOCOLATE I
CREAM CAKE5- M. , M. BASS.
Simply Delicious. I
5c thePrl~ e. t
RaglBijd pottep ~ GO., I
_ Distributors I
I
Complete Stock Carried.
Murfreesboro TUllahoma,
McMinnville.
Druggists
~, he New Things First."
o
Laundry
E VERYTHING TO WEAR
FOR ~ VIERY MlErJ! B~ R
OF THE FAM&amp; LY
Price &amp; Buchanan
w. Goldstein ~ Son,
MONEY SAVED ON EVERY PURCHASE.
Drugs and Toilet Articles. Nor: nal Sc; hJj! Sup[. J! ics, Cut Flow rs, Nunally's
Candies OUR SPECIALTlES. Goods Delivere: l at 4 p. m.
. \
,
r
The Young Man's Store. t
MEN'S FURNISHING AND TAILORING.
MEN'S WEAR CO.'
FRAME YOUR PICTURE
Phone 179.
_. _ lI_ lI_ a_ a_ n__ a__ n\_ -'...-..-----------.. a
Let
KERR.' S
DRU&lt; i STORE
PHONE 49. PHONE 49. II.
I ~
~ II~
Home Phone 6. I
Dr. D. O. McNabb I
Dental Surgeon. I
Office Y. M. C. A. Building, ( up- stairs) I.
E. MAIN ST. ,
Opposite Odd Fellows BuiJding. I
PHoN: ms:- Office 65, Res. 463. t
MURFREESB~ RO, TENN. Tip Top Dry Cleaning Co, Dr. D. E. Logan, I
t CLEANING AND PRESSING. DENTIST ,
t Ladles' Work a Specia Ity ,-
MURFREE CLARK aLDG.
Also Repairing and Altering neatly I done. 123 E. Main St.
Join our Club $ 1.00 per month. MURFREESBORO, TENN. I Phone 267.
6- E. Main St. Opposite Jordan Hotel ic.. P-. Hcl- O..- N... E.-. S. :_- 1R1_ es.. 342; Office 739. ~ ~._. u_._ cO
" A FRIEND TO YOUR FEET"
Shoes to meet the particular wants of particular people at a low price for
high value.
sandals and Tennis a Specialty. I BETWEEN THE BANKS. t. Cumbo Phone 641.
1
i
+ I
&#8226; iI
f
I I8I
S, I
.,
i
1rI
IIiI
II III
, I
I
II
-+
&#8226;
.,..",
' 8to '~ e
eets" .
&#8226;
. P. TIT
JOB PRINTING .- t.- c)"' C~ C)_ CI_.- c ~
r
Opposite
Taxi- Cab Service.
DAY and NIGHT.
We Solicite Your Patrona~ 9.
Telephone 66- Both PhoneJ.
Catalogue Work a Specialty
Mail Orders Given promPI Atten-tion
'
Public Square. Clarksvi~~, Telln.
Commiss. ary,
' Where QUALITY
. B. ITH'S TO...............~.
Phone 282
Osteopathic Physician
. W. E. SMITH, Prop.
Autos and Horses for Hire.
Fancy Driving I" igs a Specialty.
Telephone No. 10 2' 20 W. Main St.
DR. M. W. HfNOfRSON,
Earthman's
Ilf:'~ ur appe~ ite is going good, call us. We'll satisfy it.
o If It s not gomg good, call us, and we'll make it go good.
I Masonic Building.
I
, PHONEs- office 111- J; Res. 111- W.
Home Phone 63.
The Home of the Unusual. I Telephone No. 72 and 144. '--'---
II
, I
,. II
+--------+,,..,;;:~.....,~~~ it~~
At Mrs. W. H. Hanes Old Stand.
ALWAYS GLAD TO SHOW YOU.
f",
&#8226; t.
Ot- e~~..- t_~ o.-. O'_ tl'~~~_ t.~~'-')-'-'-'''''''(''-(}_'''''''~. I Murfreesboro I . . . I I~~~~~ RE~~~. RG~' ICM~:. i: he74~ J~:~:&amp;~~~~ diO I
Autos, and Horses and Buggies. I """ ' &#8226; '. I ~ J Call for what vou want, we HAVE IT. ' - vlURFREESBORO, . TEN~ E- SSEE. i
I Fhon" es 46 and 82. .' i t . I COHEN'S CAFE Dr. L. H. Tate I
t SODA, DENTAL SURGEON. ~
i CREAM, Masonic Building. , I CANDY, PHONES 584 and 621. I
I Luncheon and Sandwitches. Home Phone 63. I
I Quality and Service. MURFREESBORO, TE, NNESSEE. t
I ~. THE NEWEST THINGS , I Leo Ferrell IIn Slv) e and and Pump Novelties for I I Worn &#183; t? can always be founa at our "
! Istore. r . I PHOTOGRAPHER The " 8EST FOUR'" Lines of Men's I .
C' 1Oe3 at e carried by us. I Best work at reasonabe prices. Spec- I ial attention given Kodak work. I ' HO'npER ~ HO'E" 0 Phone 329. . U ~ . lJ &#8226; I
I HAY~~~ N! ~~~ p~ 1S0N, T. CANNNON 6HARRli"
1) 111 Goods, Notions, Ladies' ~ uits, ;
Furnishings and MiUinel'l' &#183; J
Special attention given Normal School A share of &#165;. our patronage appreciated. i I Girls. Phone 147. 0 I
.~_~..... t~~~~~ ~_'-)""'_ l.
',.
I
j
(
I,
I
/
, i'
I
f
</dc:description>
<dc:subject>College publications; Middle Tennessee State Normal School;</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Image; Text;</dc:type>
<dc:type>text; application/pdf</dc:type>
<dc:format>Periodical;</dc:format>
<dc:format>40 p.; 9.5 x 6.0 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Not protected by copyright</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit: Property of the Albert Gore Research Center, Middle Tennessee State University, Murfreesboro, TN 37132</dc:rights>
<dc:relation>University Collections, MTSU Miscellaneous, Middle Tennessee Normal School, 1911-1925</dc:relation>
<dc:publisher>Albert Gore Research Center, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:description>Folder 7</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/mtsu1/id/1407</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>