<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>VA to donate land to MTSU</dc:title>
<dc:relation>Sidelines, Feb. 13, 1966</dc:relation>
<dc:date>1966-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>An article about the local Veteran's Administration hospital's plan to donate surplus land to MTSU</dc:description>
<dc:description>VA To Donate Land To MTSU
The Veterans Administration hospital is soon to donate 46.5 acres of unimproved land to MTSU according to an announcement by Representative Joe L. Evins.
The land was declared surplus by the VA and the General Services Administration will transfer the land to the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare
which will in turn transfer it to the State Board of Education and MTSU. 
The university now has a large tract of land by the VA used by the agriculture department. The new addition, when transferred, will be used for growing forage crops.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Land donation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Land titles--Registration and transfer; United States. Dept. of Veterans Affairs; Agriculture; Middle Tennessee State University</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Image; Text;</dc:type>
<dc:type>image/jpeg</dc:type>
<dc:format>Clipping;</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected. Reproduced with permission of the University</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Reproduction is permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only; Credit to Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:rights>
<dc:relation>Sidelines Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/mtsu1/id/745</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>