<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Gore, Bass bring Scope Week talks</dc:title>
<dc:relation>Sidelines</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Middle Tennessee State University</dc:source>
<dc:date>1964-03-11</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Al Gore, Sr. and Ross Bass spoke at Middle Tennessee State College's SCOPE week</dc:description>
<dc:description>Gore, Bass Bring Scope Week Talks.
&lt;br&gt;
Senator Albert Gore, MTSC alumnus, was the kickoff speaker for SCOPE week. He described the current civil rights situation as a "vexatious subject" and expressed the hope that moderation will prevail in the final enactment of the bill now before the Senate. He defended the filibuster by stating that the bill was of such far reaching impact that it needed "lengthy discussion."&lt;br&gt;
In his extemporaneous discussion of the "Implications of the Space Age" Senator Gore said that there is a need to project the real image of American life abroad and that the space age improvements in knowledge, communication and transportation presented "the greatest challenge education has ever known."
He stated that most of the things he discussed at the United Nations were unknown when he was a student here.&lt;br&gt;
Ross Bass, representative from the Sixth Congressional district, was the second SCOPE week personage of international reputation to appear on the campus this week. He appeared in a question and answer session in the Tennessee room last night. Mr. Bass had announced his candidacy for the United States Senate on Monday.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Speakers; Scope Week</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Gore, Albert, 1907-1998; Bass, Ross, 1918-; Middle Tennessee State College</dc:subject>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:type>image/jpeg</dc:type>
<dc:format>Clipping</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected. Reproduced with permission of the University</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Reproduction is permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only; Credit to Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:rights>
<dc:relation>Sidelines Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/mtsu1/id/697</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>