<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Fiftieth convocation salutes past and present</dc:title>
<dc:relation>Sidelines, Nov. 22. 1961</dc:relation>
<dc:contributor>Beasley, N.C., speaker; Boutwell, Lane, speaker</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1961-11-22</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>The text of the invocation and introductory speech given at Middle Tennessee State's 50th anniversary convocation on November 14, which honored alumni, faculty, and students.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Robert Morris Patty, alumnus; Charlie Harrell, ASB president</dc:description>
<dc:description>Fiftieth Convocation Salutes Past and Present
The invocation delivered at the Fiftieth Convocation by 

Dean N.C. Beasley is as follows. 
We thank thee, O God, for thy blessings
For all thy blessings in creation,
For the beauty of earth and sea and sky,
For thy manifold works and 
The wisdom with which though has made them all.
We thank thee O God,
For the happiness of our earthly life
For peaceful homes and healthful days,
For our powers of mind and body,
For faithful friends,
For the joy of loving and being loved.
Almighty God,
make us aware, in our communion with Thee,
of our fellowship with faithful and devout souls,
some of names we remember,
many of names not remembered at the moment
who served thee in the yesterdays, through
service to this college.
Grant to us the privilege to serve Thee through this 

college
in unbroken fellowship of service
with those of the yesterdays.

Following the invocation at the November 14 Convocation 

Lane Boutwell introduced the honor guests with the 

following
golden years of history. In paying tribute to the past, we 

have invited to the platform those people who have made a 

contribution to this college. In expressing our 

appreciation to them, we also offer our thanks to those of 

the past who have held the same office or served  in the 

same capacity," Mr.
Boutwell said.
The Honorable William Baird. As Lieutenant Governor of 

Tennessee and Speaker of the Senate, you represent those 

lawmakers of the past who actually brought into existence 

this institution of higher learning. Please accept our 

sincere appreciation for finding and making means whereby 

adequate appropriations through the years have made 

possible the continued existence of Middle Tennessee State 

College.
The Honorable George F. McCanless and Mrs. McCanless, as 

Attorney General of the State of Tennessee, you serve as 

the legal advisor of this college as it carries on the 

complex program of educating the youth of Tennessee. We 

offer our sincere thanks for your guidance and the advice 

of those who have gone before you.
The Honorable W.R. Snodgrass. The office of Comptroller of 

the State of Tennessee, which you hold, has served this 

college well in providing expert council in the matter of 

keeping accurate records of business part of education. We 

pay tribute to you and your office for the contribution 

you have made to Middle Tennessee State College.
The Honorable W.H. Westbrooks and Mrs. Westbrooks. As the 

representative from Rutherford County in the House of 

Representatives of the 82nd General Assembly,  you have 

joined Mr. Dement in representing Middle Tennessee State 

College and speaking oon our behalf in matters that 

concern us. We are grateful to you and past 

representatives for your support.
The Honorable Edward L. Jennings and Mrs. Jennings. Mr. 

Jennings was a member of the Middle Tennessee State 

Teacher's College Class of 1938, and is a member of the 

Tennessee State Board of Education. This board is the 

governing board to whihc  the president of this college is 

responsible. Mr. Jennings, we pay tribute to you and the 

state board for that administration which has guided this 

institution to the status which it now enjoys.
Mr. Horace Jones. Your father, Mr. R.L. Jones, became the 

first president of the Normal. He received his education 

at Onwaard Seminary, Burrett College, and the University 

of Chicago, and at the age of 44 he resigned as state 

superintendent of instruction to come to Murfreesboro. 

Following his skillful planning and attention to many 

details, the Normal received its first students in 1911. 

We are indebted to him for his guidance during the 

formative years of 1911-1922.
Mrs. Russell Shedden and Mr. Shedden. Mrs. Shedden, we 

wish to pay tribute to your father, Mr. Pritchett Alfred 

Lyon, who served from 1922-1938 as the second president of 

this institution. He received his education at the 

Winchester Normal and Vanderbilt University. His belief in 

the importance of teacher education and his skill as an 

administrator brought funds, expansion, and transition 

froma Normal to Middle Tennessee State Teacher's 

College... a 4-year college. We are grateful for his long 

years of dedicated service. 
President Emeritus Q.M. Smith and Mrs. Smith. At the age
(Continued On Page 4)
Dr. Robert Morris Patty of Covington, Georgia, discusses 

with Charlie Harrell, ASB president, the changes made 

since he was a student here in 1911-12. He was one of the 

first eight graduates of Middle Tennessee Normal in 1912.

Fiftieth Convocation
(Continued from Page 2)
of 47 Mr. Smith resigned the presidency of Tennessee 

Polytechnic Institute to become the third president of 

State Teachers College. He received his education at 

Middle Tennessee State Normal and Peabody College. 

President Jones guided the school through its formative 

stages. President Lyon saw that it survived the depression 

years, and President Smith, assuming office in 1938, 

guided the emergence of the institution as a state 

college. Mr. Smith, your presidency from 1938 to 1958 

covered the broad expansion period. We are grateful to you 

for your foresight, your master plan for expansion, and 

your administrative skills during a 20-year period.
President Quill E. Cope and Mrs. Cope. In 1958 President 

Cope resigned as Tennessee Commissioner of Education to 

become the 4th president of Middle Tennessee State 

College. His education was received at Tennessee 

Polytechnic Institute, Peabody College, and New York 

University. He has met the challenge of mushrooming 

enrollments, curricula changes, continuous building 

programs, faculty expansion, and streamlining the entire 

college program. President Cope, this college has come of 

age. It must innovate, expand, and experiment to meet the 

rapidly changing times. With your five images before you, 

and being equipped with fine administrative skills, we 

know that Middle Tennessee State College is in competent 

hands as we build a dynamic program for the future.
Tennessee Polytechnic Institute Presidetn, Dr. Everett 

Derryberry and Mrs. Derryberry. You represent our sister 

institution who joins Middle Tennessee State College in 

providing a common program of tax supported education for 

the youth of Tennessee. The history of your institution 

parallels the history of this college and as we pay 

tribute to our past we may pay tribute to the educational 

contributions your institute made to other areas of 

Tennessee.
The Mayor of Murfreesboro, Mr. A.L. Todd, Jr. In 1910 

Murfreesboro joined Rutherford County in making a strong 

bid to have the state normal located in this city and for 

fifty years Murfreesboro has fulfilled its promised 

support. We thank you for the many sons and daughters of 

Murfreesboro who have attended this college and for half a 

century of cooperation.
Mr. Jack McFarland. As publisher of the DAILY NEWS JOURNAL 

of Rutherford County and Murfreesboro, you have furnished 

the medium through whihc this college speaks to the 

residents of this area. Since 1911 our activities, plans, 

programs, and service to the area have been made known to 

the public. Without your services, Middle Tennessee State 

College would be severly handicapped in making known its 

total programs. We offer our sincere thanks.
Mr. Baxter Hobgood, Superintendent of Murfreesboro City 

Schools. For many years students from the schools of this 

city and couty have outnumbered the students from other 

Tennessee cities and counties. Without a sound educational 

foundation at the elementary and secondary levels, the 

programs of higher education are hampered. To you and 

other superintendents of this state we are grateful for 

your dedicated work in constantly improving school systems 

throughout Tennessee.
Miss E. Mae Saunders and her guest, Miss Earlene Jennings. 

When the doors of the Normal first opened in 1911, you 

were a member of that first faculty. It was you who 

organized the first chorus, the first glee club and the 

first orchestra. Your name is dear to all who have known 

you through a 50-year period. First, we pay tribute to you 

for your yers of wonderful service, and secondly, with you 

as their representative, we salute the 485 teachers who 

have served on the faculty of this college from 1911 to 

1961. 
Dr. Robert Morris Paty and guest Mrs. Leon Paty Mann. In 

1912 the Normal school had its first graduating class. You 

were one of the 7 graduates. The A.B. degree was received 

from the University of Tennessee followed by 2 years of 

teaching at Webb School. You served with the United States 

Navy in 1917, then received your medical degree from Emory 

Medical School in 1925 and became a medical missionary in 

China. Later you became the Associate Dean of the medical 

school at Emory University and now you are in private 

practice in Covington, Georgia. Middle Tennessee State 

College is proud to have you as an alumnus and we are 

honored by your presence at this 50th Anniversary 

Convocation.
Mr. Charles Harrell and Mrs. Harrell is president of the 

Associated Student Body and is a member of the 1961-1962 

senior class. Dr. Paty, as a member of the first 

graduating class, and you, Charless Harrell, of the class 

of 1961-62, represent the 7776 graduates of this 

institution. In honoring you,  Dr. Paty, and you, Mr. 

Harrell, we pay tribute to all graduates during the past 

50 years.
Mr. and Mrs. Murray Miles of Murfreesboro. Having 

carefully studied our records, we feel that you are the 

most representative of all those parents who have sent 

sons and daughters to this college. The name Miles is 

found throughout the 50-year history. Mr. Miles, your 

brother, Alf was the first coach at this institution. Then 

you attended along with your brothers, Hoard, Cass, 

Andrew, and Kenneth. Mr. and Mrs. Miles, your three 

daughters, Lida, Ernestine, Sara White, and Nena Lou are 

graduates and at present, your son Kenneth Neil, is a 

sophomore. To you and all the parents of the past whom you 

represent, we offer our thanks for your belief in higher 

education and we appreciate the sacrifices all have made 

in sending sons and daughters to Middle Tennessee State 

College.
We bring to a close our tribute to the past. Perhaps the 

one single thing that is symbolic of the passing years is 

the  Alma Mater which has been sung by every graduating 

senior from 1912 to 1961. Therefore, it is appropriate 

that we listen to the Middle Tennessee State College 

chorus sing the old Alma Mater for the last time.
This 50th Anniversary Convocation not only commemorates a 

passing era, but it also serves as a prelude to the 

future. As we move into the future may we find a common 

bond in the new Alma Mater. Let us listen as the chorus 

sings it.
THE CHANGE
Be it remembered that on November 14, 1961 we met in this 

convocation to pay tribute to the past and to be 

challenged by Dr. Bucher in this prelude to the future.
If this college has brought a fuller life to those in the 

past, if it is a force in your life today, if it is to 

have an impact on our national life tomorrow, then I 

charge you to resolve now to be a loyal supporter of 

Middle Tennessee State College. Think on these things as 

we hear the closing prayer and as we watch the 

recessional.
THE BENEDICTION
The closing prayer at the November 14 convocation, 

delivered by Dr. S. Belt Keathley, dean of students, was 

follows:
Heavenly father: Give us the wisdom to recognize a 

milestone as something to be left behind and not a 

foundation upon which one resides. Give us the strength 

and ability to move forward from this day towards whatever 

goals are reasonable and just... towards whatever future 

may challenge our powers on mental generation and useful 

action.
It is good and pleasant to review the past... but may we 

do so only to find strength with which to build, to find 

service which can delineate future action.
Almighty God, we pray for thy guidance ans we launch into 

the years ahead... We earnestly seek thy Son's attitude of 

service... we sincerely pray that this college may be used 

as an instrument of thy peace, as true guide to youth, as 

a trainer of dedicated men and women.
--Amen.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Homecoming; convocation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Anniversaries; College administrators; College teachers; College students; Middle Tennessee State College</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Alumni &amp; alumnae</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Text; Image</dc:type>
<dc:type>image/jpeg</dc:type>
<dc:format>Clipping</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected. Reproduced with permission of the University</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Reproduction is permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only; Credit to Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:rights>
<dc:relation>Sidelines Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/mtsu1/id/1166</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>