<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>YDC members interview Estes Kefauver</dc:title>
<dc:relation>Sidelines</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Middle Tennessee State College</dc:source>
<dc:date>1956-04-11</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Several members of the Young Democratic Club met with presidential candidate Estes Kefauver when he visited Nashville. Pictured from left to right: Bob Brooks, George Gardner, Frank Gardner, James Daniel, Estes Kefauver, Dr. William Windham, Bill Sugg, Lois Stedman, and Georgiana West</dc:description>
<dc:description>Eight members of the MTSC Young Democratic club, 

accompanied by Dr. William T. Windham, advisor, 

journeyed to Nashville March 30 for an interview with 

Senator Estes Kefauver.
Kefauver made a brief visit to the state capitol 

during a stopover in his flight from California to 

Washington, following his presidential campaign for 

the California primary election. The group met and 

talked to the democratic candidate following his 

press conference with Nashville newsmen. The group 

then attended the open house held for the senator in 

the ballroom of the Maxwell House hotel.
Those   making   the   trip   were: George Gardner, 

Bill Sugg, Frank Gardner, James Daniel, Lois Stedman, 

Bob   Brooks,   Harold   Lowe, Georgianna West, and   

Dr. Windham.

Eight members of the college Young Democratic club 

are shown here as they interview the presidential 

candidate, Senator Estes Kefauver. From left to 

right, they are: Bob Brooks, George Gardner, Frank 

Gardner, James Daniel, Kefauver, Dr. William Windham, 

Bill Sugg, Lois Stedman, and Georgiana West.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Presidential candidates; Democratic Party (U.S.); Political clubs; Middle Tennessee State College</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Nashville, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:type>image/jpeg</dc:type>
<dc:format>Clipping</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected. Reproduced with permission of the University</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Reproduction is permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only; Credit to Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:rights>
<dc:relation>Sidelines Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/mtsu1/id/702</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>