<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Children playing at Vet Village</dc:title>
<dc:date>1952</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959;</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Children playing at Vet Village from the 1952 Midlander yearbook</dc:description>
<dc:description>Vet Village was organized immediately after World War II to accommodate veterans and their families who were attending school. Attempting to meet housing needs, in 1946 Congress gave $78 million to move buildings from military bases to college campuses. Middle Tennessee State College also received federal funds to erect small apartments for married veterans and their families. Later, not only veterans but anyone could  live in the apartments and trailers that made up Vet Village as long as at least one member of the family attended the college. Vet Village was practically a city within the campus; it had a laundry house, grocery store, and even a mayor.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Veterans--Housing; Children; Middle Tennessee State College;</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Image</dc:type>
<dc:type>image/jpeg</dc:type>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected. Reproduced with permission of the University</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Reproduction is permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only; Credit to Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>378.768 M58m 1952</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/mtsu1/id/1492</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>