<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Mary Hall: a 20th century pioneer for educational progress in Tennessee</dc:title>
<dc:creator>King, Rita Schaerer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1993-05</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1910-1919; 1920-1929; 1930-1939; 1940-1949;1950-1959; 1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Biography of Mary Ella Hall (1895-1991), a teacher at Campus School and Professor of Education at Middle Tennessee State Teachers College and Middle Tennessee State College from 1929 until her retirement in 1960.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Introduction -- Early life : education and teaching experiences -- Years as a state supervisor -- Years as a university professor -- Dedication to the Delta Kappa Gamma Society International</dc:description>
<dc:description>MARY HALL: A 20TH- CENTURY PIONEER FOR
EDUCATIONAL RROGRESS IN TENNESSEE
by
Rita Schaet: er King, Ed. D.
Peabody College of Vanderbilt University
M~ y 199~
Major Area: School AdministratiDn Number of Words~ 347
This is a biographical narrative of Mary Ella Hall's life and major
contributions to Tennessee's educational progress. The compilation provides a
record of her accomplishments as an elementary teacher, state supervisor,
university professor, professional, and civic leader. Examples of her leadership
activities over a span of eight decades are presented.
Mary Hall was born in Kittrell, Tennessee, in 1895. As a child, she was
given many responsibilities while assisting-- her father, the last Rutherford County
doctor on horseback. These early experiences, combined with family values, a
"; , rich heritage and edlicational background, zealous role models at Ge~ rge
~ .
Peabody College for Teachers, and~ a commitment to serve others, form the basis &#183;
I;
for lifelong leaders~~ p t~~ its. An independent ansi , compassionate nature,
boundless energy, and pi~ neering spirit enabled her to accomplish much in an .
era when women were struggling for professional recognition and equal rights.
Miss Mary began teaching in a rural school before World War I. Middl~
Tennessee State Teachers College employed her as a teacher- trainer in its new
elementary laboratory school. Seven years later she became one of the staJe's
first regional elementary supervisors. She ',; maintained a role as faculty member
_. ... ~
-..'
with the college from 1929 until 1963. She was appointed the first dean of
women in the 1940s and for many'years she was the only woman in the educa:'
"
tion department. In World War II, Miss Mary - rupervised the state- mandated
\,
Extended School Program for children of. working mothers.
One chapter examines Mary Hall's leadership, lifetime commitment, and
influence with Xi State, Tennessee's chapter of Delta Kappa Gamma Society
International. As a state founder in 1935, she served on the executive board,
organized chapters, and provided continuing leadership at state ana chapter
levels in the honorary organization for women in education.
In addition to the documentation of Mary Hall's achievements, the
narrative biography includes many individuals whose lives were affected by her.
She was possessed with charisma, unyielding convictions, an insatiable desire to
improve society, a joy for living, and a sense of humor that persisted until her
, -
:. . death in 1991 at the age of 95.
2
MARY~: A 201! f- CENTURY PIONEER FOR
EDUCATIONAL PROGRESS IN TENNESSEE
Rita Schaerer King
Dissertation
Submitted to the Faculty of
Peabody College of Vanderbilt University
in Partial Fulfillment of the Requirements
for the Degree of
DOcrOR OF EDUCATION
in
School Administration
May 1993
~- lr- 9~ ."
Date
3[ 18' ! q2-
Datte,~, 1/ 3
Date / 1
~ ll ffl2)
Dati)
&#169; 1993
Rita Schaerer King
All Rights Reserved
ii
Mary Ella Hall
1895- 1991
iii
Miss Mary had faith in the future and ~ future generations. She
dedicated her life to enriching the lives of those who passed her
way. This remarkable person is a perfect role model for
generations of young women.
RosalYnD Carter
Excerpt from a letter to Rita King
dated January 28, 1993
iv.,.
r &#183; \ '\,
"
,
TABLE OF CONTENTS
Chapter
I. INTRODUCfION
Page
1
II. EARLY LIFE: EDUCATION AND
TEACHING EXPERIENCES 6
Family Life 6
Elementary and High School Years 16
The College Years -. . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 18
Elementary Teaching Experiences 19
III. YEARS AS A STATE SUPERVISOR 32
.- Background 32
Initiating the State's First Regional Supervisory
P~ 9gram in Elementary Education 36
":. - SuperviSIng the State Extended School Program ~ . . . . 51
~, ~
N. YEARS AS A UNNERSITY PROFESSOR 68
r
Labq~ atory School Teaching ~. '. . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 68
Professor- in Teacher- training ~- . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . 73
Dean of Women 79
Other Contributions to the University 81
v. DEDICATION TO THE DELTA KAPPA
GAMMA SOCIETY INTERNATIONAL . / 89
'"
The Founding and Early Growth 89
Contributions As a Chapter Member 93
Contributions As a State Member 99
For my mother,
Louise Long Schaerer,
who molded my character,
developed an insatiable thirst for knowledge,
and - stimulated my love for the teaching profession
For my father,
HersherEmil Schaerer,
who was responsible for my
industriousness and passion for life
For a special friend,
Dottye Garner,
who listened and encouraged me
To Jenny T~ yis,
for cheering me on
....
'.
'\, ,
ACKNOWLEDGMENTS
I am particularly grateful to Jack Miller, my major professor and commit-tee
chairman, for his patience, support, and advice. It has been a great privilege
to work with him. Dorothy Skeel has been a source of constant support and
was available &#183; for advice and encouragement. Charles Wolfe's comments, advice,
and writing expertise were deeply appreciated. Harry Randles and Tommy
Stovall, former committee members, encouraged and supported my work.
I thank Barbara Klemt, Robin Millsaps Wheeler, and Elisa Walden for
their advice and assistance during the research and writing process. Charlie
Babb was there'for me when I needed advice. The late Bealer Smotherman
made valuable photographs when' 1~ he study was initiated. Mabel Pittard assisted
with many histor, cal aspects of the project. During the past few months I have
relied on my superb format editor, Pat Bryan. Her suggestions, expertise, an~
kindness have been a great comfort.
I gratefully acknowledge the institutions and libraries which provided
assistance: The Education Library, Vanderbilt University; Tennessee State
Library and Archives; Linebaugh' Library, Murfreesboro; Xi State of Delta
. Kappa Gamma Society International; and Todd Library, Middle Tennessee State
University.
--
I am particubuly gratefu: tto members of Xi State, Delta Kappa Gamma
Society International for the t4ne ~! 1d effort expended in responding to question-
'- .....
naires and participating &#183; ~ 11 interviews. My special thanks to Doris Hendrix, the
- l\:: &#187; - ' ....
Xi State editor, who provided. access ' to th~ organization's pictures and
publications.
Individuals at Middle Tenne'ssee State University willingly participated as
needed. A special thank you to: former president, ' sam Ingram; director of the
Alumni Office, Marie Kirk; and to the School of Education. The video inter-view
series, Recollections: The Middle Tennessee Voices of Their Times Series was
a valuable source of information. Thank you to Bob Bullen and Joe Nunley for
, their interviews with Miss Mary.
Mary Hall's relatives provided invaluable support and insight. The
material was gra9iously reviewed by them. The family's historical records and
Miss Mary's personal papers w~ re generously provided. Becoming acquainted
. ~',
with individual family members was a delightful experience.
I am indebted-' to several individuals wh~' served as personal role mo~ els
and mentors through the years. Billy M. ( Pusher) Howell, my first principal
.. provided valuable lessons in leadership and human relationships. Liz Whorley.,
/'
Bradley, my principal from 1979- 1985, was a constant inspiration as an ad- ""
ministrator and leader in Delta Kappa Gamma Society International. The
philosophies of these individuals continue to influence my professional career.
. ... vii ~. ~
The most essential ~ personal ~ llpport for this study came from my friends
Betsy Esa, Nancy Bradshaw, Liz B~ nnett, Nancy Boone, Joan Mann, and each
. - .....
' member of my staff at Middle. Tennessee State University's Campus School.
" ,
Their enthusiasm and encouragem~ nt susta~ ed me.
VI. OTHER ROLES
'-""
Page
114
Professional, Organizati? Ds .,...................... 114
Civic Organizations 0-. : &#8226; &#8226; &#8226; &#8226; &#8226; &#8226; &#8226; &#8226; &#8226; &#8226; &#8226; &#8226; &#8226; &#8226; &#8226; &#8226; &#8226; &#8226; &#8226; &#8226;_. &#8226; 116
Church Involvem~ nt .. ~!..................;...: 120
Political Involvement 123
Family/ Personal Life 126
VII. CONCLUSIONS 131
REFERENCES . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . . .. . . . . . . . . . . . . .
...
- I,.
140
'-"""
' CHAPTER I
INTRODUCTION
Mary Ella Hall dedicated her life to ed, ucational progress in Tennessee.
Born in 1895, she attended school in a rural area of Middle Tennessee during
the early 1900s. As a child and young adult she assisted her father, the last
doctor to visit patients on horseback in Rutherford County. Her career in
elementary teaching began in a three- room school prior to World War I, when
teaching experience and certification were not required. The majority of her
educational training was received during summer classes at George Peabody
College for Teachers_ in Nashville, Tennessee, during the 1920s. Middle
Tennessee State Teachers' College in Murfreesboro, Tennessee, hired her as a
faculty member ' or the college's new elementary demonstration school in 1929.
Six years later she was initiated as a state founder of Delta Kappa Gamma ,
International, an honorary society for women in education. She became devoted
to the organization's ideals. The following year the college released Miss Mary"
,-
-:
from many teaching responsibilities when the State Department of Education
asked her to serve as one of Tennessee's first regional elementary supervisors.
In the dual role of School VISitor and college professor during the 1930s and
~ Ji
19408, she had an impact on programs, teachers, and students. , She was the only
1
2
woman in the colleg~' s departJ; Hent of education through the 1950s. After
retirement in the 1960s, Miss' M~: lrY remained active in educational endeavors
'_ ....
until 3 months b~ fore ~ er death, ip 1991.
" ,
This biographical stud~ of Miss . M~ ry was conducted in the Depa~ ment
of Educational Leadership at George Peabody College of Vanderbilt University.
The research was undertaken with several purposes in mind: ( a) to explore a
Tennessee woman's experiences as a pioneer in ed\ lcational leadership; ( b) to
examine the impact of &#183; her education courses at George Peabody College; ( c) to
document the contributions of a state founder, state president, and devoted life
member of Delta Kappa Gamma Society mtemational; ( d) to provide Middle
Tennessee State University with a historical account of a female faculty mem-
-'
ber's contributions to the institution; ( e) to explore the impact of a woman's
educational endeavors in professional, political, and community organizations;
( f) to study the characteristics ' 1~ f ~ unique woman in various leadership roles;
and ( g) to augment Tennessee's history on women in education.
i
Many aspects' of Mary Hall's life are iiiciuded to illustrate her character
and the leadership skills and traits she possessed. In Educational Adminisir. ation:
&lt; Theory, Research and Practice the authors listed personal traits that have the
/
highest correlation with leadership: intelligence, dominance, self- confidence";
energy or activity, and task- relevant knowledge. l The episodes selected reflect
lW. K. Hoy &amp; C. G. Miskel ( 1982), Educational Administration: Theory,
Research and Practice ( 2nd. ed), New YC? rk: Random House.
3
- these personal traits. O~ her leadership indicators such as intuition, intelligence,
persistence, a sense of humor, deperidability, aggressiveness, commitment,
-.
. .....
accomplishment, adaptabili9'; and s9c~ ability are apparent in the narrative.
, "
An example of Mary Hall's personable nature is evident in the affec- ~
.......~ . ""
tionate name she chose when she entered the. teaching profession. Two sisters
were known as " Miss Hall," so she assumed the title " Miss Mary" to avoid
confusion. 2 Institutions, professional organizati~ ns, coll~ agues, friends, and
relatives referred to her in this manner; therefore, she has been identified as
Mary, Mary Hall or " Miss Mary," in the presentation of her life.
Miss Mary traveled extensively in 49 states and Europe, but her educa-tional
endeavors focused on improvements within Tennessee. Incidents which
.., occurred outside the state are identified. -.
Valuable information was gathered through extensive use of the oldest
research tool: oral history. In- depth interviews over a 3- year period. were held
with Miss Mary to~ gather background material, personal experiences, and
l
information sources.. Friends, colleagues, admini! tnitors, professional associates,
and family members participated in interviews. Other data were collected from
qu~ stionnaires, state department records, newspapers, journals, official docu-ments,
books, bulletins, personnel files, personal letters, photographs, scrapbookS,
plaques, yearbooks, family records, keepsakes, videotapes, and transcripts.
2" Services Set for MTSU's ' Miss Mary' ' Ella Hall," ( 1991, March 8), The
Tennessean, pp. 1B- 2B.
-
4
Participants from ~ ddle Tennessee State University and Delta Kappa Gamma
provided extensive information.
'.
The study had several limitations. . Many friends, relatives, and associates , . , , '\ . , ' ,
were not contacted, because they were ill, incapacitated, unavailable, - or 5le-
.. -.~ ......
ceased. Although Miss Mary was in her 90s, she had a vivid memory of many
experiences, but many had faded with time. She was basically a healthy and
alert individual until 2 months before her death, ye~ minor strokes, major
surgery, and various illnesses had affected her mentally and physically. Being an
unpretentious lady, she possessed very few personal items and documents.
Additionally, since her life spanned the 20th century, many items had been lost
or misplaced.
Repetition is evident in a few -- passages because incidents are presented
from various perspectives. A few passages may seem out of sequence because
several aspects of Miss Mary's life occurred simultaneously. These events were
related separately to provide a: broader perspective and more detail.
t
My intense interest became a hindrane. e to the project's culmination since
every interview, questionnaire, and research segment seemed to lead to other
intriguing bits of information. Valuable time was spent in an obsessive quest to
uncover highlights of Miss Mary's life. As the study reached its closure, I ~-
realized that there probably are more uncovered facts and related stories than
the number found and recorded here. My effort to record 95 years of a full,
active life in a few chapters has been';; an overwhelming yet rewarding task.
5
Another major obstacle was my relationship with Miss Mary, which made
the writing less objective.' As the daughter of an elementary teacher in ~ Grundy
and Franklin cC? untie~,. I kne~ ~ f Miss Mary's' influence as a supervisor. As an
, "
education major at Middle . Tennessee State College in 1964, I knew ht; r as a --~ . ~
professor. As a Rutherford County resident since 1969, I observed her par-ticipation
in civic, political, and professional organizations. As a Church of
Christ member, I respected her conviction and fa~ thfulness. As a member of
Beta Epsilon, a Delta Kappa Gamma chapter in Murfreesboro, I was associated
with her in state, regional, and local meetings for 14 years. As a teacher and
principal at Middle Tennessee State University's Campus School, I was with her
often when she visited as a retired teacher. As a friend and the author of her
biography, I cherished her companionship.
In spite of my relationship with Miss Mary, I believe this biographical
study presents a realistic portrayal because varied sources were &#183; utilized. The
' 1, .
study illustr~ tes the influence one leader can have on organizations, institutions,
and in the lives of people. The documentation confirms her significant contribu-tions
to Tennessee's educational progress in the 20th century.
10
It is not surppsing that _ Miss Mary was a tomboy. She rode horseback,
climBed trees, and wandered'in' the fields and woods. 17 She learned to ; hoot a
'.
gun. She made playhpuses in ~ h~ backyard. . Occasionally she participated in
, "
feminine activities like knitting With, her - grandmother. 18 A favorite plac~ to play
.. -~ ....
was on Pilot Knob, a large hill behind the, house. It was a recreation area for
the f~ mily and the community. Young people came on weekends to shoot- to--
shoot which was a ride down the south side of the, knob on a wide plank that
had a foot rest nailed on one end. Hunters came to trap raccoons, opossums,
polecats, and foxes. l9 A geographer at Middle Tennessee State University
described the hill as the highest point in central Tennessee .20 Early settlers
named the elevated area Pilot Knob because it was used as a signal station by
Indians. 21 During a Civil War skimiish for possession of the hill, an army built
a lookout in a tree and it stayed there until 1920.22 The lookout was a favorite
spot for the children. Mary carried her books there to read. Sometimes she
~, . .
17L. Rogers ( 1960), Light From Many Candles, Nashville, TN: Xi Stat~, Delta
, Kappa Gamma Society International, McQuiddy Printing, p. 246. . ~
18Interview with Mary Lawrence Oliver, August 28, 1990.
1~. Hall " A HIstory of Kittrell," p. 83.
20Recollections, Part I, p. 2.
21p; edmont, n. p.'
22~. Hall, '' The History of Kittrell,',~ p. 82.
11
hiked up and played ht the trees. Family members and friends used Pilot Knob
"" as a landmark, mile marker, and topic of conversation.
, .....
Much of th~ ente. rtainment on a farril in this era was related to work. , '\ .
, "
'' During two of the big days in. the count~~" recalled Miss Mary,
people from all over the community , went from one home to the other
' killing hogs and helping with wheat threshing. There would be 15 or 20
people. We would have three or four tables of people to eat, dinner. It
was a real big day. A day or two before, my mother and sisters and the
cook' would begin cooking pies and breads an~ things so they would be
ready. 23 I
The days when houses and barns were being built were described as similar
events because neighbors came to help. 24 Sometimes during the harvest moon,
Miss Mary would go to a local mill with crowds of people and watch flour being
ground until late in the evening. 25
On Saturday nights. the family gathered in the parlor to dance and play
musical instruments; One sister played the mandolin, her mother played the
. ~ . .
piano, her daddy played the guitar, an~ Mary played the fiddle. Uncle Dave
Macon, a banjo player who was a neighbor, joined the musicians on several
~ .
occasions. When Uncle Dave became a Grand Ole Opry star, Miss Mary ,
enjoyed telling that she had played with the country music legend. 26
23Recollections, Part I, p. 12.
24Interview with Miss Mary Hall, September 9, 1990.
25Notes in the Hall Family Reco~ ds. '
26personal interview with M. L Oliver, August 28, 1990.
.... "
12
The Halls were interest~. d in giving their children a well- rounded educa-tion.
For instance, they had ~ eas~ n tickets to the Chautauqua, a popular
. _ ...
education production from Chautauqua, New York. It opened during the
" T- - ), " ...
summer months under a large tent on. tl!~' comer of Main and University streets
in Murfreesboro. The performers presented lectures, concerts, and plays. The
outing became an annual event for the Hall family. 27
Listening to her parents' stories about their , ancestors was another favorite
pastime. Northern soldiers had invaded the home of her maternal grandparents
during the Civil War. They took all the slaves except two and ripped up carpets
to make saddle blankets. 28 Mary's father had tales about his family's role in the
American Revolution. One exciting story was about his grandfather being
kidnapped and a cousin being scalped by Indians. During the Civil War a
Northern capta~ ~ as critically wounded during a battle for Pilot Knob, so he
and several soldiers stayed WitP the family until he was able to leave. 29 Stories
were also tok~ about her ancestors' ~ volvement in the Colonies' rebellion. 30
Yard arid garden work were part of Mary's farm responsibilities, b1: 1t she
was not asked to help with the crops. However, when she was about 10 ~ ears
old, curiosity led her to the fields. One day she begged to go with the black ,
27Recollections, Part I, p. 19.
28Recollections, Part I, p. 2.
29Recollections, Part I, p. 3.
30pamily Records of Joseph David- Hall.
13
fieldhands so she could learn how to pick cotton. Dr. Hall tried to talk her out
of going, but she persisted. ' When she' returned to the house in about 10
minutes, Dr. Hall asked why she was batk''' so soon. Mary told him she had
" ,. \
...... ' ,
learned everything she needed to know-. about picking cotton. 31
Black families lived and worked 01; 1, the Hall farm and Miss Mary had
fond memories of growing up with them. For instance, she told the following
story about a 10- year old black boy who was found at their front door on a
rainy day by her grandfather; Franklin Donald Hall. He invited the boy to come
in and warm himself by the fire. The child's mother had died and his father
had married a woman who beat him. One side of the smokehouse became the
boy's home until he married. It was called " Bill's house." Miss Mary remem-bered
sitting on his lap to listen to stories about the good things Miss Betsy, her
grandmother, had done for him. 32
Another black named Charlie Butler lived on the farm. In referring to
~, .
his many children, Miss Mary said, " all we needed to do was call one of them
and here they.. came." Many times she wen\. to the homes of neighboring black
families to " eat some good ole cooking.,, 33 Willie Brandon, a black man,. said as
a teacher she drove black children to school just like she drove white children.
31Interview with Miss Mary, April 29, 1989.
32Interview with Miss Mary, April 29, 1989.
33Interview with Miss Mary, April 29, 1989.
"
-',
14
He knew she was cr: azy about _~ s cousins because she cared for them and helped
with their homework. 34
"" 11
Miss Mary had. fond m~ mpries of her first contacts with the automobile,
, '"
radio, and telephone, all of ~ hich were ! ttvented during the last part of-: the 19th
century. She said everyone knew that a man in the community had bought a
car. " We heard this car coming down the Pike.... the dust was just flying," she
reminisced. The driver stopped and asked the chiJdren if they wanted a ride to
school. During the short trip they were scared to death. When the children at
school heard the car coming they ran out to the edge of the highway to see it.
Miss Mary remembered being a heroine for the entire day because she had
ridden in an automobile. The Hall family had the first telephone outside of
.-
Murfreesboro, so people came from all over the immediate area to see and use
it. After they got a radio, people came every night to hear programs. 35
Religion undergirded ~ ss. Mary's value~ and morals and played a major
role in the li~ es of the entire family. The Science Hill Church of Christ had
been established ort the farm by her grandfitther and another gentleman after a
follower of Alexander Campbell came to the farm and explained the Back. to the
Bible Restoration Movement. The family members were baptized, and they .
started having church services in a log house on the farm. 36 When the d~ ath of
34Interview with Willie Brandon, January 29, 1991.
35Recollections, p. 12.
3~. Hall, " A History of Kittrell,". p. 53.
15
family members le~ some nephews without a home, Dr. Hall let them live with
his family. In order to meet this added expense, he bought part interest in a
"
threshing machine. During the day he ran the machine, so he took care of , . , " \ .
, "
patients at night. He assisted ' the boys, financially until they were able ! O
.. -- ..
become independent. 37
When Dr. Hall began using a car to visit patients in 1914, he and Mary
continued to work together as a team. At that time he was 58 years of age and
she was 19. Miss Mary described their cooperative, time- saving method of
changing tires:
I would have to stop the car. Daddy would open the door on his side
and jump out and I would tum the seat over because all of the tools
were under the seat. I would pick up the wrench and the jack and, by
that time, he would have some screws loosened. When I got out, he
would begin jacking up the car, and I'd begin taking out the bolts. By
the time he had the car jacked up, I'd have all the bolts off and he would
pick the tire up and put it on. It got to be such a routine that we could
get a tire changed in about ten minutes. 38
One of Miss Mary's sctddest memories occurred during Middle Ten-nessee's
1918 flu epidemic. About 1 person in every 300 died. Schools and
public places were closed. In one house Dr. Hall and Miss Mary found , a sick
father who was trying to take care of his wife and six children who were - ill.
The next day the father died. The Hall family assisted with the funeral, which ,
37Interview with Mary Lawrence Oliver, August 28, 1990.
38Recollections, Part I, p. 9.
16
was held in the ho~ e. Dr. Hall helped the undertaker roll the casket from
room to room so the childre~ could tell their father goodbye. 39
At an ea~ ly ag~, Mary ~ a~ given tne responsibility of keeping the payment
, ,
books for her father's medical practice. - He charged $ 1.50 for housecaqs and
.. -- ...
$ 10 for delivering a baby. On one occasion he asked her to write Paid in Full
on some large bills that belonged to a poor family. The receipt was given as a
Christmas present. Such acts of kindness filled D~. Hall's life; it was said that
he never turned a sick or hungry person from his door.
Elementary and High School Years
Mary's mother taught her to read before she went to school, so she was
surprised the other children in first ,- grade could not read. She walked 1 mile to
the two- room school in Kittrell and described her experiences there as very
enjoyable. She especially remembered doing the Virginia Reel on the stage
after lunch while a lady playeli the organ. The children had extra respon-sibilities
in the classroom-- the boys made the fire in the pot- bellied stove and the
girls swept the floor. Miss Mary referred to herself as " being daring and'
mischievous" as a student. She laughed and said, " I was forever doing something
f
mean!" Everyone laughed when she heated a stick on the classroom stove and :
/
then used it to singe a boy's hair. " If there was ever any mischief, I was into it,"
39Recollections, Part I, p. 9.
17
she added. 40 Mary's~ parents h~ d high expectations for her. They wanted her to
"" be the best she could be. When she got good reports, they would say, " We
-.
expected that of you." . The high ~ tandards- set. hy her parents made her want to
, "
make good.
In 1913 Mary was one of seven graduates at the new 2- year high school
which had been built from logs donated by the Kittrell community. 41 The
following incident which ' occurred one week after Mary's graduation had a
tremendous effect on her life. During a visit a neighbor asked Mary what she
planned to do smce she had graduated. " I am going to Vanderbilt because I am
going to be a doctor," she responded. Dr. Hall was surprised and displeased by
her response. Later he gave his reasons for opposing her plans: " It is too hard
-
a life and I am not going to let you do it. We don't have women doctors." She
begged, but he said, " Well, I am not going to let you do it, so you might as well
hush. u42 This story was told t~~ Ol: lghout her lif~ when she was asked about her
teaching career. Eleanor Boyd remembered her uncle. She said he
had a very strong personality. More or iess in the family, what he said
was the way it went. He was the patriarch and he believed in the head
of the family as the patriarch ruling the family in what they did in the
way of friendships and careers. 43 ..
,-
4&#176; Interview with Miss Mary, June 4, 1989.
41M. Hall, " The History of Kittrell," p. 69.
42Recollections, Part I, p. 14.
43Personal interview with Eleanor Boyd, July 24, 1991.
,. ...
18
It was not unusual f,? r parents to dictate children's lives in this manner during
this era. While many females were asserting their independence and making
'.
career choices, Mary succumbed to her father's' authority-- a decision she would , . . ,. \ . , ,
regret throughout her life.
. The College Years
Mer hearing her father's opposition, to her college plans, Mary cried for
3 weeks. In a biographical sketch in Light from Many Candles the writer said,
Dr. Hall " considered teaching a much more suitable profession for her, but Mary
was equally determined not to teach.,, 44 When her sisters heard what had
happened, they came home and expressed concern about Mary's future. They
persuaded their parents to send Mall' to Ward Belmont College, a finishing
school for girls in Nashville, Tennessee. Miss Mary said, '' That was an unfor-tunate
thing for: me because I was a little country girl, a tomboy, climbing trees
and riding horses." On the fuit day there she was disappointed in the school
because a roottunate came in and offered her a cigarette although there was a
No Smoking sign posted. Mary was surprised that the girls were not following
the rules. Later she heard them telling nasty jokes. This made her unhappy
,
!
because she had never heard a nasty joke and she did not know what they were :
/
talking about most of the time, so she did not enjoy their conversations. Mary
44Recollections, Part I, p. 18.
19
had never heard offe- tlsive language, so she was miserable. After 1 year, she left
Ward Belmont. 45
-.
Mary trans( erred., to the ~ o: pnal School iIi Murfreesboro. 46 The dorm&#173;'.,
itory was full, forcing her to get a room across the street in a boarding h9use. . """"~ ...
Again she was discouraged. This time a sarcastic teacher '' broke her heart" by
ridiculing her response to a question. After that year, Mary decided she was
through with education. 47
Elementary Teaching Experiences
Two commissioners came to Mary's home and asked her to teach in the
Porterfield community. With 2 years of college work she reluctantly agreed to
. " take the school" at a salary of $ 25 a._ month. 48 The school was located on the
old Hall's Hill Pike between the Hall's Hill community and Milton on the
Rutherford- Cannon county line. The building consisted of three rooms: a
middle hall with a classroom oIl- each side and an auditorium at the end. The
classrooms were in Rutherford County; the stage was in Cannon County. 49 Miss
Mary said, " I think I was eighteen when I began teaching. I had no teaching
45Recollections, Part I, p. 15.
4~. Rogers, Light from Many Candles, pp. 246- 247.
47Recollections, Part I, p. 18.
48" Services Set," p. 2B.
49M. Hall, " A History of Kittrell," p. 209.
20
degree, no training. ~ I had nothing at all. I just knew I had to teach them to
read and do arithmetic.,, 50 .~
'.
This first , teac~ ng expet: ie~ ce in the'" rotal school was described:
, "
I had about twenty- five or thirty pupils from first grade through the
eighth. I had five or &#183; six boys, who were as old as I was. We had nothing
in the school, no materials or anything except the desks. We had long
church- like benches to use as our recitation desks. School would begin in
the morning. We would have a ten- minute break before noon. At
noontime we would have an hour. , The boys had a ball team. I was the
umpire. At one o'clock I would go and ring the bell and everybody
would come into their seat. I had one beginner. He was as pretty a
little boy as I nearly ever saw. His hair was yellow. It just laid in curls.
Just about the time I would start the first class ( after lunch), he would
come up to me and say, " Miss Mary I'm so sleepy" and I would say
" Alright, lie down." He would put his head in my lap. 51
Miss Mary was surprised to find she enjoyed teaching, so a new chapter
in her life began when she took ex~. minations and received a teaching certifi&#173;cate.
52 When family members said they wanted her to teach a nephew in
Kittrell, Miss Mary asked the superintendent for a teaching position in the boy's
school. So, in 1921, she begah teaching where she had attended grades 1- 12.53
She taught fij- st and second grade with four other teachers. 54 The publicly-supported
school term was 3 months followed by a privately supported
5&#176; Interview with Miss Mary, April 29, 1989.
51Recollections, Part I, p. 1.
52L Rogers, Light from Many Candles, p. 247.
53" Services Set," p. 2B.
54Recollections, Part I, p. 4.
" ..
21
subscription school tqat ran for several weeks. Reading and spelling books were
available, but math was learned from blackboards and individual slates. 55 ' Water
had to be brought in fr~ Jll the \ ye! l and fire~ built in wintertime. 56
~ ~ " ...
Sam Leyhew was in ~ ss Mary'sfiEst grade class in Kittrell. His ( amily
lived as sharecroppers on the Hall farm, so. he walked to and from school with
her. He described the classroom:
We had old wooden desks. Up at the front we had long wooden benches
and that's where the classes would come when she called for first grade,
then second grade. All the classes was in there together. She would just
call the class up to the bench. When spelling came we lined up beside
the wall. We had trappin.' If she gave out a word and the one next to
you missed it and you got it, you trapped him. You got ahead and if you
stayed ahead a few days, she would put a little gold star in your book.
We did it like that every day. 57
Miss Mary remembered that t~ e school bus era began when two black
mules named Tobe and Tige pulled the first school wagon from behind Pilot
Knob to ReadYVille and back to Kittrell. 58 The bus was a cattle wagon with
benches built along the sides a" ild acanvas on an overhead frame. Other
wagons came from Cripple Creek and Loafer's Rest. The cattle wagons were
used until 1923, when a stock truck was converted into a school truck. The pine
55L. H. Wiser, L. H., ed., ( 1986), A History of Rutherford County Schools to
1972 ( vol. 1), Murfreesboro, TN: Rutherford County Historical Society, p. 224.
56Recollections, Part I, p. 2.
57Interview with Sam Leyhew, July 8, 1991.
58M. Hall, " The History of Kittrell," p. 71.
22
ceiling could be rai~ ed or lowered as needed in the summer and winter
months. 59
".
Sporting ~ ven~, in the ~ otpmunitY ~ ere- enjoyed by Miss Mary. She
played baseball and served as official scorekeeper for the Kittrell ball t~ am after
I/ o -.. "' l
World War I. Her father taught her to read errors, hits, and runs in the
newspaper. The pitcher for the - team had been discharged from the army and
he would say to his mother, " Give me my dinner, , so I can go play ball with Miss
Mary and the boys!,, 60
Building rapport with students and families was an important part of Miss
Mary's teaching. The following incident is a good example of her willingness to
spend extra time as a part of her commitment to the children. A little girl
invited Miss Mary and the teachers -- to spend the night. There were 10 children
in the family, but the mother insisted that they come. The teachers did not
want to insult the family by not going and rode the school wagon to the house.
~, .
After a big s~ pper they talked by the fireplace, played games and ate popcorn.
Miss Mary described it as " a very happy evening." The next morning everyone
got up early because the school wagon came there first. It was still dark, but a
sack lunch was prepared for each child and a good breakfast was served. Miss r
Mary commended the mother on her way to the wagon,
All my life I have felt sorry for you. Every time I came here with Daddy
to see somebody sick and every two years when Daddy said, '' There's
59M. Hall, " The History of Kitti'ell," p. 7l.
6ORecollections, Part II, p. 6.
23
gonna be a baby up at the Kathy's house," I felt very sorry for you, but I
don't anymore: I feel sorry for those mothers who don't have but one or
two children that don't'know how to do anything. You're just like a
captain of an army, you have them organized. 61
40
World War I began in 19~ 4'. Mis~ Mary and her family were dedicated to
the war effort. Going to the " train depot With- " flocks" of people to say good- bye
to the boys called into service was a sad experience. They would stand there in
tears because everyone knew some of the Y9ung men would not retum. 62
During the war years, Miss Mary's mother was chafrman of the Red Cross Unit
in the ReadYVille community. Sewing machines were set up in the church.
About 3 days a week Miss Mary worked with the women to make bandages,
nightshirts, sweaters, helmets and scarves. 63 Dr. Hall was the War Bond
chairman of the east end of the cou~ ty, therefore, he and Miss Mary went to
every house in that end of Rutherford County to sell. According to Miss Mary,
at the end of the war, Washington recognized the county for selling more War
Bonds than any other county fit the state. She'recalled that there were no
hospitals in the area when the Rockefellers set up the Commonwealth Fund to
establish health units, so Dr. Hall spent many days going to every magistrate to
tell them how valuable a facility would be. 64 They voted for the health uRit.
/
61Recollections, Part II, p. 4.
62Recollections, Part I, p. 3.
63Recollections, Part I, p. 20.
64Recollections, Part I, pp. 20- 21. ,&lt;
24
Dr. Hall and Miss Mary_ were on a visit to see a patient when the news
came that World War I had ended. When they heard bells ringing with horns
, ...
and whistles blowing, D!~, Hall ex~ laimed, " Oh, Mary, that means the war is , ,
over~" He asked Mary to stop on the side' of the road. They got out of" the car
, .. &#8226; -- "' l
and Dr. Hall knelt down and prayed. 65 Many soldiers visited Miss Mary when
they returned from their posts. When a niece asked why so many soldiers came
to her house, Miss Mary replied, " I wrote each one, of them when they were
overseas and this was their appreciation for my part of the war effort., t66
When asked about boyfriends and marriage, Miss Mary explained she had
a bunch of friends but they were " good ole brother boys." She smiled and said
one or two of them became pretty serious and proposed, yet her profession was
always more important than her love- affairs. 67 Dr. Hall did not want her to get
married, recalled 90- year- old Wille Mae Dunn, whose mother worked for the
family. Mrs. Dunn said one t~ e. Miss Mary came down the stairs wearing a
locket that hao been a gift from a man she was " going with." Her father
commanded, " Don't' ever let me see you puf~ that on your neck again." Mrs.
Dunn believed Miss Mary had chances to get married ' but " the old man" w. ould
not approve. 68 A niece, Eleanor Boyd said, " She was attractive in her young~ r
,..-
65Recollections, Part I, p. 22.
66Interview with Eleanor Barker Boyd, July 24, 1991.
67Interview with Miss Mary Hall;', October 17, 1988.
68Interview with Miss Mary Hall, O. ctober 17, 1988.
25
days. With her persQnality and her love of living and her fun- loving attitude, she
had to have a l~ t of boyfriend;.,, 69 Mary Lawrence Oliver, another niece,'
'.
agreed that Miss Mary .? ad maqy ppporturiities ' to marry, but added, " No one
~ - " ...
ever measured up to her father.' i70 .'
Miss Mary's principal asked her to transfer with him from Kittrell to
Woodbury and she accepted. Several people shared special memories of Miss
Mary, the primary teacher, in the Woodbury school~ For example, Beatryce
Mason, a student, related the following about how she entered Miss Mary's
classroom as a first grader in 1924:
Miss Mary took down my whole name and birth date and the information
that she had to have. She had a second grade class in there, too. I
remember the first thing she did was to start talking to the first graders.
She got some colored chalk al! d went up to the chalkboard and drew a
great big picture of a red hen. I thought it was the prettiest thing I had
ever seen. She told us that our first reading book would be the one with
the story of the Little Red Hen in it. 71 .
Mrs. Mason recalled that the ~ oI'Jling passed q~ ckly because the children had
been spellbo~ d. At noontime Beatryce ran home for a dinner meal with her
father, aunt, arid uncIe~ As soon as the blessmg was said, she blurted out, " I
/..
69Interview with Eleanor Boyd, July 24, 1991.
7lJmterview with Mary Lawrence " Oliver, August 28, 1990.
71Interview with Beatryce Mason, June 4, 1991.
26
know what I want to~ do when I get big enough. I want to be a school teacher,
just like Miss Mary!,, 72
Mrs. Maso~' s mother hac;! ~ ied when~ she was 5. Miss Mary's kindness
, . ,
and compassion was very co~ orting~ . Sl:~' shared the following:
One day I was tardy because I was fiddling around at home. I was real
late. Miss Mary said, " The principal has a rule. Unless you ride the
~ agon and you come in after chapel service starts, you must stay for an
hour after school.
Beatryce remembers crying and crying even more when the other children went
home. " Miss Mary did not get any work done," said Mrs. Mason. " She put me
up on her lap and wiped my face, wiped my tears and read stories to me for
the whole hour." Beatryce Mason said she became a teacher because of these
early days with Miss Mary. Later, s~ e said, " I was just fascinated by everything
Miss Mary did. I guess if she had said, ' Why don't you to go out there and
climb to the mdon?' I would have gone somewhere and tried.,, 73
John Bragg, later a state l~ gisl': ltor, was in Miss Mary's first grade class in
Woodbury, T~ nnessee in 1924. He believed it was an advantage to have second
-' llt .
graders in the same classroom because he could hear the second grade lessons.
Mr. Bragg recalled helping some boys set fire to a model house that sat iIi an
,..-
72B. Mason ( 1991, May), " A Tribute to Miss Mary Hall," Xi State News ( Alpha
Nu), 37( 3), 7. I,
73Interview with Beatryce MaSon, June 4, 1991.
27
inside comer of the school. When Miss Mary walked around the comer and
realized what had happened she~ whipped the boys who were responsible. 74 &#183;
..
Miss Mary's , niece? Mrs. B&lt;? yd, was iti-&amp; fiss &#183; Mary's class in 1924. She and
, . '\ . . , -
her brother and sister rode to school with Miss Mary in her model T Ford. The
-~.,... ........... ~
rides were described as being fun and enteI1~ ining. Miss Mary helped the
children make up poems in &#183; the autumn when they would ride along and see the
gorgeous hills. Mrs. Boyd added, " She was always trying to entertain. There
was never a quiet period with her. She was either telling a story or trying to get
something out of you. fl75
Entertaining children in the family was one of Miss Mary's greatest joys.
. According to Mrs. Boyd, Christmas was a '' big occasion" in Miss Mary's home.
" Somehow or another Santa Claus woUld always come by early," she said.
We~ would be eating dinner on Christmas Eve and we would hear
sleighbells.' Aunt Mary would always go to the door and she would say,
" Why, yes, Santa, we are glad to see you this early" and '' yes, the children
are here. Just leave theit, packages!"
Then Miss MarY would play Santa Claus for the family. 76 She accompanied the
children on excursions in the woods and hikes up the steep slopes of Pilot Knob.
When they found grapevine swings, Miss Mary would swing the children on . the
vines.
/
74Interview with John Bragg, State Representative, March 29, 1991.
75Personal interview with Eleanor " Barker Boyd, July 24, 1991.
76personal interview with Eleanor B~ rker Boyd, July 24, 1991.
28
After teaching 3 years in the primary grades in Woodbury and attending
George Peabody College for Teachers during summer months, Miss Mary~
"
decided to furthe~ her , education at the University of Tennessee in Knoxville. 77
. , .\ .
~ \"
The year was 1927.78 To earn money she worked in the cafeteria and " coached"
~ .......... ....
some ballplayers in history. 79 She also wa~ the hostess in a girl's dormitory. 80
During the spring quarter Miss Mary was notified that her father was ill, so she
left UT to return home and help care for him through his recuperation. 81 In
1928, he was stricken with Tularemia. He became desperately ill and never fully
recovered from the illness. 82 Miss Mary continued her education at George
Peabody College so she could spend more time with the family.
Speaking of this educational experience, she said,
I counted it a great day in my- life when I registered for a course in
primary education under Miss Lucy Gage and seemed to find what I had
been , searching for all the years I had been trying to teach. 83
77L. Rogers, Light from Many Candles, p. 248.
78lnformation sheet, personnel files, MTSU.
79Recollections, Part II, p. 10.
80Recollections, Part II, p. 11.
81Degree found in family records.
82Notes in Hall family records. ",
83L. Rogers, Light from Many : Cand! es, p. 248.
29
She said, " Miss Gage was one_ of the grandest human beings I have ever known
in my life ... she put me 0; a c! oud ... she gave me what I was hungry for.' 084
_ 40
Lucy Gage had, been a s't\ ldent at the Chicago Kindergarten Institute in
""\'"'" ~ ' ...
1894 where she was " strongly influenced:: " by John Dewey's educational -:
psychology. 85 Miss Gage often asked her- students, tlDoes the classroom situation
reflect child activity and a setting for child responses or does it reflect the adult
satisfactions of the teacher?" 86 Her philosophy ha: d a profound. impact on Miss
Mary's teaching career and professional life. An article written about Miss Gage
in the Peabody Reflector in 1942, illustrates her early childhood philosophy:
She approaches the education of the child from the natural unfolding
from within. She holds to the belief that growth is achieved by keeping
him in his natural world until he begins of himself to grow out of
it.... She advocated the happy, carefree school which was a compara&#173;tively
new idea during her early years of teaching. . . . The world of little
children is her province. . . . She is the true ambassador from the child
world to the adult world of school- master and parent. 87
Dr. Southall said Miss" 1~ age's philosophy was to let children become what
I &#8226;
they are and; not what we want them to be, to give them direct experiences, and
to develop children's potential instead of molding them into what adults ~ ant
84Recollections, Part II, p. 10.
85C. Bailey ( 1960, June), Life and Work of Lucy Gage, Pioneer Teacher and
Leader ( unpublished M. Ed. thesis submitted to George Peabody College for
Teachers, Department of Education of the Graduate School), p. 27.
86C. Bailey, Life and Work, p. 4,2.
87C. S. Pendleton ( 1942), " Pe~ body College Greets Professor Lucy Gage," The
Peabody Reflector, 15( 3), 90.
30
them to be. Dr. SQuthall also_. recalled that Miss Gage referred to Miss Mary as
one of her best students. 88 .~
During these ye~ rs at P, e,\ body, Mis~ Mary worked in an office on
, . "
campus. She received a Bach~ lor of Science degree on June 8, 1928.89-; In the
......... "' l
graduation address, Bruce R. Payne, the college's president described the
advantages of being an educator during this era. He said, " We stand today, my
fellow students, upon the threshold of the greates~ Renaissance of learning, the
greatest expansion of human intelligence, the most remarkable quickening of the
mentality of the race ever known in the history of mankind.,, 90
Mter graduation Miss Mary began her work on a master's degree. Dr.
Southall became acquainted with her during this time. She said, " Everybody was
so fond of Miss Mary." Dr. Southall realized then that Miss Mary would always
take a leadership role because she loved everyone and was " service- minded.,, 91
Their professional relationship and friendship continued for more than 65 years.
~, . .
88Interview with Dr. Mayeie K. Southall, April 2, 1988.
89negree found in family records.
90a. R. Payne ( 1928, July), " A Peabody Road Map for 1928 Graduates" ( a
farewell message of President Bruce R. Payne to the graduating class at George
Peabody College for Teachers, June 8, 1928), The Peabody Reflector and Alumni
News, 1( 9), 4. I,
91Interview with Maycie K. South~, April 2, 1988.
31
While taking postgraduate courses, Miss Mary worked in an office at
~ .
Peabody. She majored in health and attended classes offered on the Vanderbilt
-.
campus. The M~ ster of &#183; Arts Qe~ ree was - a~ arded to her August 26, 1931.92
, '.
Miss Mary's mother di. ed in 1932. - The black domestic workers as.. sisted as '- ""
she took care of Dr. Hall. He died in 1938 at the age of 72.93
The family's emphasis on education, religion, responsibility, leisure activity,
and civic duty laid the foundation for Miss Mary's ~ uccess in life. The desire to
excel, to personalize relationships, and to improve the quality of life for others
was cultivated during these early years and intensified in the leadership roles she
assumed.
92Degrees found in family records.
93Notes in the Hall Family R&#162; cord~.
'.
\ CHAPTER'n
EARLY LIFE: EDUCATION AND
TEACIDNG EXPERIENCES
Train up a child in the way he should go and when he is old he will not
depart from it.
Proverbs 22: 6
Family Life
The original Stage Coach Road, connecting Knoxville and Nashville, ran
in front of the farmhouse where Mary Ella Hall was born August 9, 1895. The
farm was located in Kittrell, 7 miles east of Murfreesboro, the geographic center
of Tennessee in ~ utherford County. Jonathan Hall, Miss Mary's great, great
grandfather, received a 64o- a~ re ' land grant on- Cripple Creek in' 1810.1 Be
called the ar~ a Piedmont because it was similar to the Piedmont region where he
" ~
had lived in VirgUria. 2 Jonathan Hall's grandson, Franklin Donald Hall, built a
two- story log house surrounded by maple trees in 1840.3 This was the Hall
.. home for three generations.
/
&#171;
lRegistrar's Office Rutherford County Court House, Murfreesboro, TN, Book
K P# 3 ( found in personal papers).
&#8226; J)
2Piedmont ( a synopsis of the family's ' history from the Hall Family Records).
3Notes in the Hall Family Records;'
-- 6
7
Ella Lowe, Miss Mary's J.! 10ther, was born November 6, 1860, the day
Abraham Lincoln was electedUIiit~ d States president. 4 Her family lived
between the BradYVille ~ nd Mancllester pike~ in' an area called Big Springs. 5
" ,
She and Joseph David Hall ~ arried in' . D~ cember 1883.6 Children in ~ the~ family
called her Mammy. Described as a " no nonsense" and " distant" person, her per-sonality
was overshadowed by her husband and Mary. 7 While Mary and Dr.
Hall told stories and entertained visitors, Mammy st~ yed in the kitchen and
prepared a good meal. She was always ready to help family members with their
problems and she was the first one approached when advice was needed. Mrs.
Hall taught Mary to be an excellent manager of money and time. Her compas&#173;.
sion and strength hel~ the family together. She died in 1932 at the age of 72.8
Joseph David Hall, Mary's father, was born in 1854. According to family
history, his childhood days on the farm were filled with hardships and depriva-tions
as a result of the Civil War and Reconstruction. He walked 3 miles to
~, . .
attend school ip Readyville. Later he ' attended Science Hill Academy, a school
l
4Recollections: The Middle Tennessee Voices of Their Time Series, Part I ( 1984),
.. Middle Tennessee State University Archives Program ( video transcript of interview':
taped at MTSU by Bob Bullen and Joe Nunley, Sr.), p. 12. ~
5Recollections, Part I, p. 2.
6Recollections, Part I, p. 2.
7M. Hall ( 1973, Winter), '' The His~ ory of Kittrell," Rutherford County Historical
Society ( Publicati~ n # 2), p. 62. I
8Interview with Mary Lawrence. Oliver, August 28, 1990.
8
on his father's farm. When the schoolmaster thought Joseph Hall knew enough,
he was given a teaching position in the ac, ad. e. m. y. In ofder to attend Vanderbilt '
University, he earned the initial tuition reading medicine as an apprentice in an
uncle's pharmacy. Mary's father graduated in 1883 with a medical degree and
devoted his life to the community. 9 Dr. Hall was an active member of social,
religious, political, and civic groups. It was reported that he knew more people
than anyone in the county. A voracious reader, he kept abreast of current
events and was considered an authority ton Rutherford County's history. Family
records noted his remarkable heal~ h, great energy, keen sense of humo!" high
"
temper when aroused, compassion, and affectionate nature.
The day Miss Mary was born, Dr. Hall cried because he wanted a boy.
The entire community was disappointed. Dr. Hall called her " his boy." JO The
Halls had two older girls, Martha Lowe and Amanda Elizabeth. 1J A son born
in 1885, died at the age of 3.12 Sin~~-' Mary's mother was ill most of the time
and her sisters were too old to be playmates, Mary's childhood was spent with
her Daddy. The experiences Mary had with her father were unique. She
traveled with him ' on horseback and in the horse and buggy, sharing in the
romaJJ. ce and hardships' that-~~ ame with the country doctor's life. There were
9Interview with Eleanor Barker Boyd, July 24, 1991.
JO" A Salute to ' Miss Mary' Xi State Founder," Xi State News, 25( 2), 1.
JJNotes in the Hall Family Records.
J~ Notes in the Hall Family Records.
- t'
.. J/
1
..
9
occasions when he hac! to use crude surgery on kitchen tables. Many times he
~
did not sleep for 3 days and nights. He brought hundreds of lives into the
".
" ....
world and closed ~ any ~ yes in dt? a~ h. He listened to stories of heartache and
, "
sorrow. Healing bodies and c~ mforting' so~ ls brought him joy. l3 Therefo~ e, the
meaning of compassion and nurturing came , to Mary through her experiences at
an early age. For example, if they went into a home where the mother was
sick, Dr. Hall would ask Mary to wash the dishes, cl~ an' the floors, wash the
children's faces, and comb their hair. As part of her nursing responsibilities she
learned to set bones and give shots. This assistance to her father continued
throughout childhood and into her adult years. 14
The horse Dr. Hall rode was a 16- hand strawberry roan named Old Joe,
one of the best walking horses in Rutherford County. l5 Her earliest memory
was sitting in the saddle with her daddy as they rode horseback to see patients.
Before she was 5 years old, he bought her a horse and saddle. The following
~ .
incident was a viery special memory that she shared on many occasions:
The first day I . Tode on my saddle, Dadciy put me up and he pulled and
pulled on my dress but he didn't say a word. When we went in the &lt;
house, he said, " Mother, I want you to make Mary a pair of pants.,, 16
Miss Mary believed she was the first girl in Tennessee to wear pants.
/
13Notes in the Hall Family Records.
14Recollections, Part I, p. 5.
15Hall, M, " The History of Kittrell, i~ pp. 62- 63.
16Interview with Miss Mary, Ap~ 29, ) 989.
" CIIAPTER ITI
YEARS AS A STATE,. SUPERVISOR
Boys and girls, bring a screwdriver to , school tomorrow, so you can
unscrew your desk from the floor. We are going to rearrange them, so
we, can have group work. Miss Mary Hall is coming to visit us. She is a
very special school visitor. By putting the desks together we will show
her that we are up on the latest educational trends in the 1930s. Before
she arrives we must oil the floor, polish the stove, wash the walls and
clean the chalkboards. If we find enough money, we'll get a new coal
scuttle!]
Scenes such as this were happening in 40 Middle Tennessee counties, in
1936, when Miss Mary was appointed- as one of the state's first regional elemen-tary
supervisors. The appointment occurred when the school systems were
struggling in' the throes of a great economic depression. There was, however,
~~ . .
widespread nat~ onal and state impetus for recovery and advancement in all
aspects of education.' Many_ federal acts and rtational professional movements
were fundamental to Tennessee's school improvement endeavors.
Background
An overview of some educational movements and programs, which
affected Tennessee, provide a better understanding of the era and the changes
] A scenario based on " Miss Mary Hall As I Remember Her," a tribute written
by Hoyte Snow, Director of Middle Sch09ls in Metropolitan Nashville.
32
33
taking place in educ,!- tion. Many federal recovery programs were developed
during the early 1930s. In 1933; for example, President Franklin D. Roosevelt
established the N. ationa. l Recovery Administration. Projects were initiated to , , '\ ' , ,
plant trees, beautify school grounds, , and-. provide more jobs. 2 In Tennes~ ee,
.....~ ...
there were 20,000 children without books; , writing materials necessary for their
daily lessons; or extra supplies such as crayons, scissors, and paste. 3 In a 1934
speech, Tennessee Commissioner of Education, Walter Cocking, presented the
following overview of the schools' economic situation and plans for improvement:
There is great need in Tennessee today for new school buildings. But
since new building will be out of the question in many communities for a
long while, we must for the time, make the most of those we now have.
Qeanliness, new paint, constant attention to sanitary conditions, to the
safety of drinking water and other matters which you and cooperating
groups in your community may handle successfully will do much to
improve your school this year. 4
Indirect improvement for the Tennessee schools came with a major boost
to the economy when the Tennessee Valley Authority ( TVA) was created by a
~, .
1933 act of Congress. As a result, more than 30 dams were constructed on the
Tennessee River, making it the largest inte~ ted power system in the world.
2W. D. Cocking ( 1934, April), Tennessee's Educational Program," The
Tennessee Educational Bulletin, 12( 9), 4.
3W. Cocking ( 1934, February), " Present Educational Conditions in Tennessee,"
The Tennessee Teacher, 1( 1), 2l.
4W. Cocking ( 1934, September),' itA' Letter to Fellow Teachers From the
Commissioner," The Tennessee Teacher, ~( 1), 18.
34
Almost all busines~ institutions in the area experienced some benefit from the
economic growth generated'by' the TVA5
The Tenpesse~ Educat! o~ al Conimlssion, a group of . outstanding citizens
, "
appointed by Governor Hill McAllister, met on May 30, 1933, to orgaqize an
&#8226; -~ "' I
investigation on every phase of education in Tennessee. Two hundred
twenty- five committees were set up and over 1,500 people volunteered to assist
in school reformation efforts. 6 The reports from , this commission became an
integral part of the state's educational improvement goals.
Problems faced by Miss Mary during this era included low salaries,
abbreviated school years, and lack of training for teachers. The annual salary of
4,865 Tennessee teachers was less than $ 500 in 1935, with many counties unable
to pay their teachers. At that time $ 869,146 was owed to teachers. 7 Two
hundred schools were open less than 7 months and 81 schools operated less
than 5 months. B In 1938, only one fifth of elementary teachers- were college
graduates. 9
5J. H. Warf ( 1963), Tennessee Education 1780- 1962, Nashville: State" Depart-ment
of Education, p. 13. i
6w. D. Cocking, '' Tennessee's Educational Program," p. 9.
7W. A. Bass ( 1935, September), " Tennessee Schools Lack Support-- Teachers
Underpaid," The Tennessee Teacher, 3( 1), 7.
BW. A Bass, '' Tennessee Schools Lack Support," p. 6.
I,
9Tennessee Public Schools ( 1938), Arlington, TN: Tennessee Congress of
Parents and Teachers.
35
One of the fir~ t indicators of interest in school improvement was the state
department's publication of " A~ Score Card for Elementary Schools" in 1930.1&#176;
A look at some areas scored illustrate the' condition of the schools at this time:
" " '\,
outdoor toilets and a barn or . shed for' horses, a radio, a Victrola ( record~ player) -~ ...
with at least six records, and an organ. Each room was to have suitable
schoolroom pictures, 30 feet of blackboard, adequate cloak rooms, sanitary
water, oiled floors, a , poker, shovel, mop and pail, d, ust pan, toilet paper, and
Bible. Teachers were encouraged to visit in each pupil's home. The continued
commitment to improving the schools' environment became evident in the
bulletin, " Suggested Plan for Scoring the Elementary Schools of Tennessee,"
, written October 1, 1934. An elementary scoring committee was established in
every county to assist the superintendent in ways mutually agreed upon for
improving the schools, especially in raising standards. When the school was
scored, the form was placed on the wall of the auditorium. A report was sent
to the state o~ ce annually. 11
1Op. L. Harned, Commissioner of Education, ( n. d), Score Card for Elementary
Schools 1930- 1931, Nashville: Tennessee State Library and Archives Record Group
92.
11Commissioner of Education ( 1934, October 1), Suggested Plan for Scoring
the Elementary Schools of Tennessee, Nashville, TN: Tennessee State Library and
Archives Record Group 92.
36
Initiating the State's First Regional Supervisory
Progriim in Elementary Education
When Miss Mary was hired in 19~ Q' t~ e' state had approximately 30
,. ,.' , .
supervisors. J2 The ccimmissio~ er of, education, Walter Cocking, projected that
..
50 supervisors would be hiied by the end of the school term. He also ~ reported
that two additional regional supervisors would be hired by the end of March.
The improvement of Tennessee's supervis, ory services was a major point in the
new education program. When Mary Hall was aSked to join the state's en-deavors
to establish a supervisory program and move toward better programs
and facilities in the schools of Tennessee, she entered this position with two
. education degrees, experience in a teacher- training institution, and leadership
experience in professional organiza~ ions. Miss Mary had been involved in
various aspects of school improvement in Tennessee prior to her appointment.
The April 1935 edition of the Tennessee Teacher reported that she had served on
a panel with Miss Lucy Gage'. The session topic was '' The Classroom Teacher's
Problem." Miss Mary was a member of the Laboratory Group at George
Peabody College which was commended by the commissioner for its work on
'' The Tennessee Program for the Improvement of Instruction." The group
worked on the project during summer sessions and its findings effected the '
,-
supervisors' work in the last half of the decade. As a member of this
12W. D. Cocking ( 1936, February), " Major Points in the State Department of
Education Program for 1936," address to Public School Officers Association
meeting, Nashville, TN and reprinted in The Tennessee Teachers, 3( 6), 24.
37
not have guidelines for the new program. In discussing the first years as a
Identifying the best teachers in the rewon for appointment as county
,. '\,
tional Commissio. n. l3 "
,/
13Tennessee Educational Bulletin, 14( 7), ( 1966, November), n. p.
14Permanent Personnel Records, MTSU.
15Recollections, P~ rt III, n. p.
~ 6personal interview with Mary Hall, . March 29, 1988.
17Personal interview with Mary Ha! l, March 29, 1988.
Teachers College, now Homer Pittard Campus School, when the college presi-
Miss Mary was teaching at the' Training School of Middle Tennes~ ee State . -- '"
committee, she assis! ed in the compilation of the Study Bulletin, a publication of
dent, Dr. P. A Lyon, recommended her for appointment to the supervisory
the state department. She ai; o ' served as a consultant to the Tennessee Educa-because
no one preceded me.,, 15 She had classroom experience, two degrees in
two professors when she needed advice. 16 They had an immense influence on
~, .
education, and the support of two outstanding professors at George Peabody
supervisor Miss Mary said, " I didn't know whether I was doing wrong or right
her career as, a supervisor.
;
position. Her services were provided by the colleg~, where she maintained
status as an instructor of teacher training. l4 In 1936 the state department did
College for Teachers, Lucy Gage and Maycie Southall. Miss Mary went to these
supervisors was one of Miss Mary's chief responsibilities. l7 The only counties
38
with supervisors at tItis time were: Anderson, Carter, Davidson, Dyer, Hamilton,
Henderson, Knox, McNary,' M; dsion, Polk, Putnam, and Shelby. J8 According to
'.
Miss Mary, there , were .~ o supe~~ ory guide" l"" ines from the state supervisor or the
, -
commissioner, so teacher ev~ uations &#183; wer~ ' based on opinion and by wha~ the
teachers had to say. J9
Miss Mary recalled her first impression of the rural schools in 1936 when
teacher morale was low and the schools were in ve~ poor physical condition:
The classroom was a little room with a lot of spider webs hanging down
from the ceiling. There was a bucket sitting in the back of the school&#173;house
where the children would go and get their drink. I was really
surprised because I had been to George Peabody College and had been
told that you must have a pleasant classroom, which would include
bulletin boards and pictures of the children's work up on the bulletin
board. You needed a very homey- looking situation with a rocking chair. 20
One section of a state department bulletin, " Making the School Home
Desirable," illustrates the emphasis placed on improvement of school grounds
and classroom environment:
Attractjve surroundings tend to develop the aesthetic, artistic and cultural
habits of the child and at the same time to induce a state of mental
content ' and civic pride. ~
In every classroom the ideals of serviceability, suitability and' beauty
should dominate. In planning the arrangement of the room, an attempt
should be made to utilize fully all available space. A light, airy room with
harmony of design and equipment reflects cheerfulness and comfort. This)'
environment should be conducive to the mental contentment and studY
habits which we desire to instill in every child. ~-
18" They Tell Me" ( 1935, October), The Tennessee Teacher, p. 24 ( educational
news from surrounding counties)
19personal interview with Mary Hall, &#183; March 29, 1988.
20' Recollections, Part III, pp. 1,' 2. .'
39
The modem classroom should be a workshop or a children's
laboratory where children live and learn. Every effort should be made to
make the classroom enVironment a happy, healthy, livable place conducive
to work and study. It - should be remembered that children should
participatt:: acti~ ely in pl~ nnin~ and- providing much that goes into making
their classroom surroundings. _' .
My job was to help the teachers arrange. their classroom to get die
classroom as attractive as possible pecause our philosophy was that the
looks of the classroom had a lot to do with the children learning [ Miss
Mary said]. The environment needed to be as attractive as possible. I
would try to get them to do things to improve the environment with the
classroom. In one county I found that teachers had nothing in the world
to use except the textbooks. I asked them about library books. They
said they didn't participate in that program. I asked the superintendent
about the library program. He said, " The children wouldn't learn any&#173;thing
about library books. They won't even study their lesson." It took
quite a bit of time to get them on the library program. 22
Hillary Parker, a Training School director, said Mary Hall supervised at a
time when '' women bosses were not received very favorably. Many principals
would say, ' I'm gonna run my school my way, not the way that old maid super-visor
says to operate it.'" Joe Nunley, a retired professor at Middle Tennessee
State University, said his motiler' was a teacher in Chapel Hill in the 1930s. The
teachers wer~ not thrilled to see Miss Mary, so they gave her the cold shoulder
on many occasions. When she tried to begin a physical education program
there, the people did not believe their children needed it, since they worked on
farms. She had to confront similar negative attitudes in many encounters during
,,-
this era. Teachers perceived the School Visitor's presence as a threat. Mr.
21State Department of Education Bl: llletin ( 1937), Special Days.
22Recollections, Part III, p. 3.
40
Nunley said she persiste~ by coming back and getting acquainted with
everyone. 23
R. B. Housto~, a st~ te supervisor in Easi Tennessee from 1940 until 1948,
\ '\ . , -
~ ecalled one teacher telling Miss M~ lfY, ~' You've passed through this county three . -~ -:
or four times. You need to come see me be{ pre I wear my Sunday dress out."
Mr. Houston said the supervisors usually spent a day in a school. The records
( attendance information, money ledgers, etc.) were always checked. The
supervisors sat in a room, listened to teachers, and made suggestions. He
referred to her as a personable character who made friends easily. 24
Miss Mary had an innate sense of the social needs of teachers, their need
to belong and to be understood. " I would ask the superintendent to give me the
names of some of the teachers that he thought were outstanding, and I would go
to visit them and be in their classroom a while and watch them work," she said.
Interpersonal skills were utilized to remove suspicions and negative attitudes
toward her positi~ n. Her evaluation techniques were described:
The first thing I would try to evaluate w9uld be their personality. You
can form an opinion about a personality by visiting with them a little .
while. I would talk to them in general about the things that were
necessary to what I was supposed to do. I would talk to them about .
their personality, their attitude toward teaching and toward the children.
I would tell them about the efficiency that I would feel that they had to
have in dealing with other people. I talked to them and had as many-;"
contacts with them as I could before I would be willing to tum in their
names for recommendation for supervisors for the counties. They had to
have a college education. Many teachers at that time did not have
23Personal interview with Joe Nunley, July 29, 1991.
24Personal interview with R. B. Houston, October 16, 1991.
41
mentor to teachers and supervisors alike. Mary Florence Betts became one of
Miss Mary developed close friendships with many educators. She was a
,..-
,;
25Personal interview with Mary Hall; March 29, 1988.
26personal interview with Mary Hall, April 1, 1988.
We worked together as friends, not as supervisor to supervisor and stayed
in each other's home. If I had a real problem, if I wanted to start
personal experiences and asking them to share. It is difficult to work with
people unless you know them well, . according to Miss Mary. 26 She used this
each teacher. She knew the. importanc~ of socializing and being approachable . ~ ....
time to adjust to her. She worked at personalizing conversations by sharing
college education. I investigated . . . their appearance, attitude, and their
interest in their work..~ ~ ou could tell pretty well soon after! 50u got into
the classroom whethe~ the., teacher enjoyed her work or not. ij
-'" .
Miss Mary stressed the ,. iiijportance of having personal knowledge about
"' f- - \ " ...
personalized approach to assess and plan interaction with the teachers.
by having close contacts and getting to know the teachers. Teachers were given
Miss Mary's closest friends during her years as the supervisor of Stewart County
improving health conditions. " 1. m. one classroom all students drank from the same
dipper. Mis~ Mary asked the teacher to put up individual hooks so each child
could hang up his/ her dipper. Mrs. Betts said at that time she was " trying to
in 1940. Miss Betts described one example of Miss Mary's assistance with
confidence." Mrs. Betts continued,
walk in Miss Mary's shadows ... in her footsteps." She related that 194~ to
1950 were her golden years because Miss Mary provided " staunch support ~ d
42
When she ran across something she did not know, she recalled Miss Mary
West Tennessee in 1946, agreed,
/
27Personal interview with Mary Florence Betts, June 25, 1991.
28M. Scott, Questionnaire, August 13'~ 1990.
~. B. Bradford, Questionnaire, ~ epteJPber 15, 1990.
something, I talkeq to her. We involved the parents, the child, all the
clubs and the teacher. Wh~ If I had a real problem with a teacher that I
didn't understand, she could- involve me in a conversation and tell me .
what she knew, and then I would know how to approach that teacher. I
. ~ never felt afrai9 to 3; sk her fqr ,~ ny suggestions or help. I never called on
her but - what she responded. "
As a state supervisor, Mrs.' Betts was responsible for about 30. countieJ.
Other retired supervisors recalled Miss Mary's ability to build warm,
Miss Mary was an inspiratioil to me and very helpful in my learning
about my new job. I guess you could say she was my mentor. I con&#173;tinued
to consult Miss Mary about my problems and plans until she
retired. 29 .. '\ oil. .
take you to such and such county where you can obserVe it.,, 27
saying, " You come up and visit me and see just, how it can be done, and I will
comfortable working relationships. For many years Miss Mary supervised
Mildred Scott in Lincoln County. Mrs. Scott recalled, " At first I was very
~ ervous when she visited my classroom, b_ ut I soon learned that she was a real
friend and very helpful.,, 28 Mary Bradford, supervisor of elementary schools in
Marjorie Sloan was Maury County's Supervisor and a former president of the
the local and state levels, describing her as " a tireless worker who expected
Mtddle Tennessee Education Association. She worked closely with Miss Mary at
43
others to go forward with worthw~ le projects." She knew how to encourage and
empower others.
- ....
Miss Mary's influence on the~ chools in the 1930s and 19408 is evident as
"' 1"- ~ \ ",
_ she described the great respons~ bility she . hC!~ in selecting supervisors for sc~ ool
systems in Tennessee. With a sense of pride" she said,
I had to find good supervisors for every county. I looked for outstanding
teachers to recommend. I would look for pleasing personalities. I would
ask, " Would you be interested in being a supervisor?" Many replied,
" Law, no!" Some of the teachers would be a little bit offended by one
teacher being brought up to be the supervisor. For so long everybody
had just been on their own. You didn't have to talk to them long to find
out what you wanted to know. In selectinjh supervisors you must analyze
them, their attitude and then their ability.
Baxter Hobgood, who later became superintendent of Murfreesboro City
. Schools, traveled with Miss Mary when .. he became a state high school supervisor
in the 1940s. He described her as being imminently fair in everything she did,
including classroom evaluations and criticisms.
~ .
She, somehow or another, - always _ found the opportunity to praise some-thing
whether it was a very poor lesson the teacher had taught or
whether there was something about the school program itself that wasn't
exactly right. Her first comments dealt With things that were good. She
would then start whamming away at the things that she had observed ' that
were not so good that she thought needed improvement. As soon as she
had pointed out the deficiencies and the shortcomings she would then " list
the things she thought could be used to bring about improvements and
made a suggestion very emphatically, but always in a kind tone of voic~.
She always would leave the impression that she meant business about -:
what she was saying. Most of the time the ~ eople took all of this in
good spirit and followed up on the program. 31
3Opersonal interview with Mary Hall, October 17, 1988.
31Personal interview with Baxter Hobgood, November 24, 1990.
44
Superintendent HOQgood and ~ ss Mary traveled together for 4 years,
0&lt;'
visiting hundreds of schools. As they drove along Tennessee's highways, Miss
..
Mary read the entire book, ~ ar and Pe\ ace. Hobgood said Miss Mary asked him
~ , ,
questions about the parts of the b~ ok she' had~_ read aloud to see if he was'
listening. 32
In a letter, Superintendent Hobgood presented a more vivid description
of their travels as supervisors in the 1940s.
Roads covered with ice and snow, spring days on Tennessee highways
where babbling brooks had come to life ... supper with a Stewart
County family and what a supper . . . shindigs on Friday nights prior to
teachers' meetings on Saturday mornings . . . watching hogs run under a
school house . . . seeing two hundred children drink water from the same
dipper ... staYing in out- of- way places where the people went " out- of&#173;the-
way" to make the " school inspectors" feel at home . . . ham and eggs
and preserves for breakfast in that .~ ome that had once been a railroad
inn . . . occasionally seeing that beautiful school where good things were
being done and dedicated teachers were giving children inspiration . . .
the war days '.' . listening to tanks rumble by for hours . . . trying to
drive with lights out . . . swapping stories about the boys over there . . .
running into maneuvers and ~ o~ king ourselve~ out the best we could-- all
these things and so many mare con~ ributed to the riches which came our
way in those; years.
Workshops and inservice training were new terms during this era. Many
teachers left their jobs to assist in activities related to World War II. Hobgood
remembered Miss Mary's work with inservice training. These were programs for
teachers with very little formal education, so inservice training became important
during and after the war years. The supervisors traveled Monday through
32Correspondence to Miss Mary from Baxter Hobgood, April 26, 1964.
45
Friday. Many times they~ stayed in _~ county on Saturday to conduct inservice
programs. 33 Miss Mary described'her responsibilities at this time:
-..
My job was also to meet with, the entire- county . . . the whole system, , \ ,
whether it was city or county, , to go. to~ their monthly teacher's meeting
and meet with them and let them ' see. new ideas and plans for the - ...
schools. It got to the place where we would help them have people ~
choose a school that was a little superior and go and ask them if they
would have a day in which we could invite the whole school system to
come to their schools and see what they were doing. We would let the
children have a day off and let the teachers come all to one place and
meet. AIl the teachers in the system had a major meeting at least once a
year. 34 '
The professional development program was designed in 1937. The first
site chosen for this Saturday visitation program in Middle Tennessee was the
Training School at MTSU where Miss Mary had taught elementary children for
6 years. The program was initiated for t~ achers and supervisors. Sixteen
elementary, county supervisors of Middle Tennessee attended the conference. 35
The Training School teachers were to carry on their work as a regular school
~ ,
day, although the emphasis for the~' speci~ day was reading. The supervisors
observed a lesson ~ with the experience chart in first grade, a textbook lesson in
......
second grade, group reading in third grade, reading for pleasure, and music in'
fourth grade. 36 Lunch was followed by a conference period presided over by &#183;
33Personal interview with Baxter Hobgood, November 24, 1990.
34Recollections, Part III, p. 2.
35Elementary School Supervisory Acti~ ities, 2( 5), p. 3 ( 1937, November 4).
36Elementary School Supervisory Activities, p.' 3.
46
. Lee Thomas, the state s~ pervisor &lt;:&gt; f education, who presented Miss Mary as the
regional supervisor. The report rr~ ril that meeting said Miss Mary told the
. ., ....
group she had visited. in so. me coun~ i~ s " where- children who were beginning
, ,,~
~ hool were given primers the fir~ t day of sc~_ ool." Mer visiting the various-:
counties, she felt the need for a reading program, and for that reason the
program at the Training School had been planned. Miss Mary expressed the
hope that the supervisors had obtained some w~ rthwhile ideas from the visit. 37
In the 1939 February edition of The Tennessee Teacher, Training School
Principal Frank Bass, said an invitation was sent to county and city superinten-dents
and to supervisors to bring a limited number of their teachers to the
school. The excellent response made it necessary to limit the number of visitors,
the average number was about 150 each - Saturday. The demonstrations fell
under five headings being stressed by the state program for school improvement:
These were Attractive School Home, Teaching Material and Devices,. the
Ubrary, Visual E~ ucation, and Curriculum Improvement. 38 The conference
became an annual event at the Training School ttntil the 19608. The conference
exists today as the Annual Education Conference and is sponsored by the
~ ucation Department of Middle Tennessee State University. Miss Mary sat at
/
37Elementary School Supervisory Activities, p. 7.
J,
38p. Bass ( 1939, February), " The Teacher College Training School as a
Demonstration Center for Teachers in Service," The Tennessee Teacher, 6( 6), p. 28.
.. "
47
a front table during tht? 1990 conference banquet. She was recognized for being
"'" the conference founder and for ' her support since 1937.
. ...
Miss Mary had very' strong " b~ liefs about teaching ethics, values, and
, "
, patriotism. Mary Tom Berry, f? rmer chair ~? f the Elementary Education ~
Department at Middle Tennessee State University, said Miss Mary had a
tremendous sense of value that should be taught to children. She believed they
should be taught by example. Dr. Berry heard a tea~ her tell the following story:
Miss Mary came to a school to visit when she was state supervisor. One
of the first things she did was to go in the principal's office and say, " You
don't have the American flag up. Every elementary school should have a
flag up." The teacher said it was really a reprimand, but in a way she
was trying to get a point across. Miss Mary thought children should know
the flag should be over this school. The teacher who told the story said
she never saw the flag without thinking of Miss Mary. 39
Commissioner of Education, W. - A. Bass, told Miss Mary to begin super-vising
when she stepped on the school grounds. 40 According to Mary Cantrell
who was teaching in a two- teacher school, Miss Mary took this advice literally.
~, .
On one visit Mi~ s Mary picked up a piece of paper that had blown out of a
;
burned barrel and said, " Your playground connnittee isn't functioning!,, 41 She
realized the importance of a school's outward appearance.
Miss Mary recalled another supervisory visit,
When I went inside I would go to the teacher and introduce myself. r
would tell her that it was the first year I was working and that I had
39Personal interview with Mary Tom Berry, August 5, 1991.
4Opersonal interview with Baxter HobgO, od, November 24, 1990.
41M. Cantrell, Questionnaire, August .~ 4, 1990.
48
come to help ht{ r in any way that I could. , I asked if she had any
problems and s{) metimes Jhe would say that she didn't. I'd know tha. t she
wasn't telling the truth tlien~ because all teachers have problems. I would
sit in the back and listen - to her. A lot.. of times she would send the
children out . to play' and I ~ quld tell lier that I had come to talk to her
ab6ut things she might do and asked her if she had any plans made for
her teaching. The first year I was visiting them, they told me they did
aI1 42 . -, . ' not have plans ... at . - .
Prances Conry of Palmer, Tennessee, remembered experiences with Miss
Mary when, as a supervisor, she visited the local schools. " She was a great help
to beginning teachers as she showed us better teachi~ g materials and learning
methods. She had a way of making us think nothing was impossible.,, 43
One day Miss Mary came to the Training School at Middle Tennessee
State College. Andrena Briney Green, a teacher there in the 1930s, recalled
Miss Mary saying,
" I'm going to bring a special visitor." Every single room had " culminated"
( completed units). We were in a transition period. We were getting set
up for the next unit, so the walls were bare. Miss Mary brought the
special visitor. She looked around and said, " Well, I could have taken
him to Po Dunk Center and ' shown him just as much.,, 44
In incidences suth as this one, Miss Mary's sharp humor took the sting out of
~
what could have been a strong, critical remark.
Miss Mary described an approach used to involve parents in school &#183;
,
improvement. She said,
42Recollections, Part III, p. 1.
43p. Conry, Questionnaire, October'. 8, 1990.
44Personal interview with Andrena Briney Green, July 12, 1991.
49
Few schools had, PTA organizations. Most of them did not even want it.
One time I visited a one- teacher school up in the mountains of Ten&#173;nessee.
The school was In bad condition. My car got stuck in a mud
puddle out in front of the school. I told the teacher she must improve . --.
the classroom to help the ~ hildren's learnirig. I mentioned to her dif- \ .
ferent programs she could have. The teacher said, " the people in that
community are all bootleggers and they won't do anything to help." " Miss
Mary asked, " Who is your best bootlegger in the community?" She ~
named a man who had quite a bit of , money. He also had six children in
the school. Miss Mary advised, " Well, you call all the parents in and get
him made chairman." Miss Mary told her how to have different
committees-- one to work the driveway., She recommended that the holly
and pine trees in the community should be set around the building to
help the looks of it. She also recommended that someone paint it.
The next year, Miss Mary found a different situation. She described the
improvements:
Everything I had mentioned had been done. There was a nice driveway.
They had fixed the roads. They had shrubs brought in from the woods.
The building was painted a nice._ soft yellow. The dirt dauber nests were
all down. The teacher said the bootlegger had been the best chairman
possible. He had seen to it that everything was done. He furnished his
wagon to haul gravel into the area. He and his wife and all the parents
had come in and fixed that school. 45
Miss Mary wrote out parent committee lists with &#183; specific duties to help the
children, the teacher, and the school.
Although the outside appearance of the school was important, Miss Mary
thought the teachers had to be effective and motivated internally. '' Teachers
must want to teach," said Miss Mary. " A lot of people are teaching just to have
~
45Recollections, Part III, p. 8.
50
a job., t46 This is an e~ xample of the nonprofessional attitudes supervisors found
in schools.
' ..
I went into , a sch901 one 9ar, [ said MISS , Mary], and it was really evident
that it was a bad situation. ' 1 said. to the teacher, " You are not enjoying
this work." The teacher responded, ." No, I am not. I am only &#183; te~ ching
until we have enou~ h money for - Jolm to payoff the mortgage and'then I
am going to quit.' t4 .,
It was not uncommon for Miss Mary to encounter this type of attitude in her
travels.
Miss Mary's advice to teachers was to love the children first. She met
many who teachers didn't love children. Her teaching philosophy was evident in
these comments:
I believe the most important thing a child can get is love and understand&#173;ing.
I would tell the teachers that they must appreciate the fact that
every child was a different indiVidual and they must know the child, know
his background, know the home situation, and [ know] what help he could
get from home in his schoolwork. The teacher can't teach a group of
children unless she knows the difference in individuals. You need to
know and have them tell you all they can about themselves. That's the
way you form an opinio~.. Developing human character is one important
thing the teacher must keep in her mind. You need to know about
people and understand their temperament and their ideas and all you can
about them. ~
Miss Mary's nurturing philosophy was communicated to the teachers in her
, region according to Leola Fouts who said, " I began teaching on a per-mit
... right out of high school. She gave me more pride in my work and /
46Recollections, Part III, p. 4.
47Recollections, Part III, p. 4.
51
Confidence in myself. She~ was very likely the reason I chose teaching as my
life's work., t48
. _ ...
" \ Supervising the State Extended School Program
Miss Mary became the state Supervisor" of Extended School Service in :
1944. The state's division of elementary schools and Middle Tennessee State
College provided her services on a part- time basis. The state department of
education utilized federal funds to provide supervisory assistance for this pro-gram.
Several Extended School Service centers had been established across the
state by this time. 49
Headlines such as the following created great concern for the welfare of
c~ dren with working mothers.
&#8226; Children are Found Abandoned All Day in Locked Cars
&#8226; Doorkey Children Roam About with the Home Door Key Tied About
Their Necks
These reports brought together the Childrens Bureau, Works Project Administra-tion,
and the United States Office of Education. A committee known as the
Joint Planning Board on the Day Care of Children was formed to " give assis- &#8226;
tance and counsel in developing various day care services as are needed in
,/
48L. Fouts, Questionnaire, October 29~ 1990.
49Commissioner B. O. Duggan, letter in ~~ ate Archives dated August 20, 1943.
52
relation to the defense , emergency." SO The Joint Planning Board recommended
expanded use of the school plari~ grounds, and facilities after school, evenings,
.~
weekends, holidays, . and v~ cations.~ l According to Lucille Rodgers in Light from
\ ~ '\ . .... " .
Many Candles, S2 Miss Mary traveled about'the state setting up and supervising . . ~ .. -... ....
the new program. The bulletin, Education for Victory described the staffing,
scheduling, and design of the all- day school program. Teacher hours were
scheduled to provide adequate supervision for childre~ at all times. The ratio of
professional staff to children was usually one adult to 10 or 12 preschool
children provided there were few, if any, 2- year- olds in the group; with one
teacher to 30 or 35 children for the school- age group. Trained volunteers were
1) Sed to assist the ' regular staff during periods of the day when more adult
supeIVision was needed, such as during - mealtime, rest periods, story hours, and
crafts or music activities. 53
Mary Cannon, a retired teacher in East Tennessee, said,
~, .
Teachers and board members in both East and West Tennessee heard
about MiSs Mary Hall's program during and after the war. Superinten&#173;dents
started to listen to Miss Mary Halt and her presentation of the
needs of small children. She was not afraid to speak out in her beliefs
50J. Lund ( 1942, January), " Defense and America's Children," School Life,
/ 27( 4), 110.
51J. Lund " Defense and America's Children," p. 110.
52L. Rogers, Light from Many Candles, p. 248.
53" Summer Programs in Extended School Services" ( 1943, August), Education
for Victory, 2( 4), p. 22 ( bulletin from U. S. Office of Education, Federal Security
Agency).
53
for the benefits of children. Her work hastened the number of kindergar&#173;tens
opened in. each schopl. system in the state. 54
Miss Mary saw major improvement in the rural schools of Tennessee
-.
during her years in' supeivision. Educatio~ had progressed in spite of adverse
conditions. A report called " Major Trends-- in Rural Education 1930- 1940,'~ the
."
September 1940 edition of the National Education Association cited improvement
in the following areas: 100% improvement iI; l classroom procedures, average
amount of training for teachers, equipment and supplies, and library service.
Major improvement was seen in courses of study, supervision, and inservice
training. The weak areas were the number of one- teacher schools, per- pupil
expenditure, the amount of turnover, and salaries. 55
Miss Mary resigned as regional Supervisor on March 30, 1949, after
working for 13 years in this role. She trained teachers, organized workshops and
conferences, recruited county supervisors, improved classroom and school
environments, wrote bulletins aIfd guides, and devoted time to curriculum
development arid improving Tennessee schools. Although Miss Mary had a wide
range of educational knowledge and expertise, her greatest skill was exhibited in
her innate ability to motivate and encourage others.
,.
54M. E. Cannon, Questionnaire, September 27, 1990.
55" Progress in Rural Education" ( 1940, September), NEA Research Bulletin,
18( 4), 141.
House built by Franklin Hall in 1840 in Kittrell, Tennessee. Mary Hall by Reuel Goodloe, her first cousin. Seated: Franklin Donald Elizabeth McCracken Hall, Mary Hall's grandparents, July 1897
"
r
The Victorian- style renovation of the Hall home encompassed the original . "'.
. _ ....
\
'-
Mary Hall, 1898
56
\,
57
-."
Left to right: Elizabeth Hall Barker, Mary Hall,
Martha Lowe Hall McFarlin, 1902
-.
\,
Mary Hall, 1910
/
59
Mary Hall enjoying her favorite pastime,
horseback riding, 1912
60
Mary Hall, 1920
61
,"""
'. ..
\,
Mary Hall, 1924
/
0(
62
D . J~'~-"""'"
63
/
'\', Miss Mary was the only female in the Education Department at Middle
Tennessee State University for many years, 1951
65
-.
Miss Mary and Dr. Maycie Southall, 1985.
Courtesy of Xi State News. -
67
Back row: Elizabeth Hall Barker and Martha Lowe Hall McFarlin.
" ' F~ ont row: Ella Lowe Hall, Mary Ella Hall, Dr. Joseph David Hall, -.
...
Miss Mary Hall honored as, a Xi State Founder of
Delta Kappa Gamma Society International, 1985
66
'.
CHAPTERlV .
,. \,
YEARS AS- A UNIVERSI'IY PROFESSOR
" You haven't had an education until you've had Miss Mary.
Ma~ ha Adkerson, Retired teacher
Laboraton School Teaching
Miss Mary began her career as a professor in teacher education at the
Training School of Middle Tennessee State Teachers College in Murfreesboro in
1928. College students who were studying to be teachers came to the elemen-tary
school for training where " teachirig and learning processes were ex-emplified."
These future teachers observed in classrooms and also had to prove
their " fitness" for the teaching profession by working with students. J The
building was described as having " splendid facilities" such as a library, gym&#173;nasium,
and stage as modem additions. 2 MiSs.. Mary was the first teacher to
move into the buildJng. In her judgment, the demonstration school offered the
ultimate in education and was the state's best school because most of the
/
&lt;
lH. Pittard ( 1961), The First Fifty Years, Murfreesboro, TN: Courier Printing,
p. 135.
2H. Pittard, The First Fifty Years, p. 136.
68
~ .
teacher there.
69
,,-
-:
For the next, 6 ye~ rs Miss ~ ary taught- third grade in the northwest
,. '\
"
3Recollections, p. 16.
4Personal interview with Miss Mary Hall, April 1, 1988.
5Personal interview with Zadie Key, October 11, 1990.
~
classroom on the main floor. As many - as &#183; _ eight college students worked with her
teachers had attended classes at Peabody. She exhibited pride in being a
having comfortable, attractive classrooms resembling the home environment,
at one time. She applied everything she ha~ learned about teaching from Miss
Lucy Gage, her George Peabody College professor. 3 Since Miss Gage advocated
The year was described as exciting and busy by Zadie Key, one of Miss
Miss Mary added window curtains, flowers, and a bird to the room. 4
Mary's third graders in 1929. The children were constantly doing things and
because she not only taught subject material, she taught by example-- to care
pallet. Miss Mary would prop him up and milke sure the children did not tease
mitted to treat him differently. In this way the children learned to accept
about people, to develop interests in things, and to be compassionate. Valuable
studying various projects. Mrs. Key believed Miss Mary was a great teacher
everyone as individuals. 5
lessons were taught " without preaching," recalled the former student. To
or ridicule him and that he was included in their activities. No one was per-illustrate,
she told about a crippled boy who was carried to school on a wooden
70
An article written by Miss Mary in the November 1935 issue of The
Tennessee Teacher was titled " HOw Can a Teacher Perform the Greatest Service
-"
to His Students?" It illustrated Miss Mary'" s- philosophy in training future
- " '\,
teachers.
The teacher has served well if he enriches the child's life through the
mastery of skills and techniques, the ' development of talent, and guides
toward an appreciation and fuller understanding of his world. But when
he has left an indelible stamp of God's great truths on his mind, and
helped to develop a moral character With a sense of justice, and respect
for the rights of others, when he leaves with him a memory of his own
character . . . the teacher has then helped to give our country its most
valuable possession and has rendered the child his greatest service. 6
Other valuable lessons were taught through Bible stories. Miss Mary
recalled when one student cried after his mother said he was too sick to attend
school. The mother thought the illness had upset him, but he said he was crying
because he wanted to hear Miss Mary's Bible story about the '' worst thing that
ever happened to people." Miss Mary was contacted by the boy's mother to
find out which story she planned. to read, so the' passage could be read at home.
It was the 20th: chapter of Exodus, the story of the seven plagues sent on the
Egyptians. 7
As a disciplinarian Miss Mary was strict, yet compassionate. She paqdled
.. children, but she did not embarrass them in front of the classroom. The cloak-
,-
&lt;
room, an enclosed area in her room, was used for such occasions. A boy was
~. Hall ( 1935, November), " How Can a Teacher Perform the Greatest Service
to His Students?" The Tennessee Teacher, 3( 3), 30.
7Recollections, Part III, p. 7.
71
paddled who had been in trouble as a first and second grader. He was wearing
a red sweater and brown corduroy pants the day she asked him to take off his
belt and let his pa~ ts d~ wn. She, put him - across her lap and gave him about
,. -\
&lt; t-_ " "-
" three good whacks." The boy went to, hi~ grandmother's after school_ and said,
" Grandma, I sure have got to be a good boy this year because Miss Mary is the
best whipper I have ever seen!" It is obvious that this type of discipline made
her uncomfortable because she said, " My day was almost ruined" and " It tore me
up to do that." However, she believed corporal punishment was worthwhile.
The general sex bias at that time was evident when she stated that she would
not paddle a girl since it would break the child's heart. 8
Andrena Briney Green, a Training School teacher in the 1930s, recalled
Miss Mary's ability to inject clever sarcastic remarks and to be amusing. Since
Miss Mary always " took on the prevailing movement" in education she let the
children decorate orange crates for storing their things in the workroom when
" creativity was a big deal." When the principal, J. C. Waller, saw the crates he
said, " Well, at last Miss Mary, you have succ~ ded in getting your workroom to
look like a henhouse!" A few days later at the end of a long faculty meeting he
was demonstrating the proper way for students to leave chairs in the library
when Miss Mary retaliated by saYing, " Well, Dr. Waller, I want to tell you, rhen
you were born a man, the world missed a chance for the best old maid that ever
has been." The rest of the faculty would not talk to him in this manner, said
8Personal interview with Miss Mary Hall, April 1, 1988.
the cafeteria and he asked the staff to avoid discussions about school and
72
and current events. Entertaining doctor tales were related by Miss Mary, but
/
&lt;
13Personal interview with Hillary Parker, July 18, 1991.
9personal interview with Andrena Briney Green, July 12, 1991.
1~. Pittard, The First Fifty Years, p. 260.
IlPersonal interview with Andrena Briney Green, July 12, 1991.
12" Services Set,", p. lB.
" \
'-
other in this manner. Principal Wall~ r s~ t . aside a special table for th, e faculty in
children during their lunch period. Mrs. Green described Miss Mary as " an
the graphic details made them " unpleasant" and " too much" to take during a
'. Miss Mary had a professional relationship. which allowed them to speak to each
Mrs. Green, but he and Miss Mary had this type of interaction regularly. 9 Since
Dr. Waller was a graduate of . p~ abody College, 1&#176; it can be assumed that he and
excellent conversationalist" who was impressive in discussions about books, plays,
Her affiliation with the Training School remained strong, however. As a college
~ .
the early childhood curriculum &#183; course~ were being developed she worked with
professor in the 1950s, she brought college students to the school for observa&#173;tions
and participation. J3 When a kindergarten program was being piloted and
meal. J1 Miss Mary left her position at the Training School in 1936 when she
became a supervisor and returned in 1942 to teach sixth grade for 1 year. J2
the staff in the 1960s. Through the years she was a guest in the school for
" il&lt;
special occasions.
73
After I became the principal in 1988, Miss Mary visited often. Sometimes
she read books and poems to' = Classes in the lobby, but reading to third graders
-..
in the classroom where she started teaching- owas her delight. Her reading voice
" \,
seemed to mesmerize the children. ~ en . students showed her how to operate
a computer, she was thrilled. After the sc~ ool's yearbook was dedicated to her
in 1989, an autograph party was held in the library where she sat in a rocking
chair, gave her signature and had something special to say to each child. The
school celebrated the 60th anniversary of the building in the spring of 1990 and
invited Miss Mary as a special guest. When the Parentrreacher Club presented
her with a large bouquet of roses during a meeting in October 1990, I said,
'' Miss Mary, you don't have to stand up." She responded with a quick retort:
'' Why, it would be rude not to thank- this group of nice people." With my
assistance she walked to the podium and graciously expressed appreciation to
the organization.
Professor in Teacher- training
-- Ii\.
Miss Mary taught college classes in the department of education fr~ m the
early 1930s until the early 1960s. Most of that time her classroom was lo~ ated
, in the basement of the Kirksey Old Main building. Her office was the back of
/
her classroom. J4 Lucy Yarber, a student of Miss Mary's in the 1930s wrote the
following:
14Personal interview with Mary Tom Berry, August 5, 1991.
74
As a college teacher, she never once appeared before her class with the
'' blahs'' or in. an angry Q~ , hopeless mood. Every day was a new day filed
with innumerable opportunities for changing or improving attitudes &#183; and
acquiring skills in unlimited." aspects for better living. She taught us as she
wanted us to teach our children-- to- enjoy, respect, and acquire subject
matter. J5 .\ " \. '
Former students praised Miss Mary's pragma~ ic approach to teaching. Mabel
Pittard was a teacher when she took one ' of Miss Mary's classes during a
summer session in the 1930s. Mrs. Pittard especially remembered Miss Mary's
'' little' gimmicks" for classroom teaching and her practical ideas for motivating
children, getting their attention, and developing participation. J6 Hoyte Snow, a
1948 student, recalled, " That particular class was absolutely the most practical
one I have ever had in all my educational experience.,, 17
Former students described the rapport they enjoyed with Miss Mary.
Many described her as a kind- hearted person who was willing to help any way
she could. She knew how to put people at ease by making them comfortable
around her as a teacher. 18 ~ ss &#183; Mary never married, so married students were
surprised at her understanding and compassion. One student who was the
-- lilo
mother of four sons and a homebound teacher was very frightened and ~- at--
ease until Miss Mary started the session by telling everyone to get their pporities
15L. Yarber, Questionnaire, November 3, 1990.
16personal interview with Mabel Pittard, October 13, 1990.
17H. Snow ( 1990, October), Miss Mary Hall As I Remember Her ( available
from the author, 9370 Crockett Road, Brentwood, TN 37027).
18Personal interview with Mabel Pittard, October 13, 1990.
75
in order. She said most of them were wearing four hats: first, they were wives
with responsibility to their husbands; second, they were mothers and were not to
neglect their children; next, the~ were teachers, so their pupils were depending
" \
on them; and last, they were enr~ ll~ d ~ her class. J9
Dr. Will Bowdoin '' was very proud,. of Miss Mary just being there." Their
philosophies coincided, therefore, he depended on her and grew to love her. 20
The education department's annual holiday gathering was held in Miss Mary's
Kittrell home. The men were impressed with her homemade wine which was
served in the basement. 21
Colleagues spoke concerning their relationship with Miss Mary in staff
meetings. Clarence Greever sat beside Miss Mary at department meetings every
Tuesday. As Miss Mary watched him doodle during one session she stated that
she would like to have a blouse with fancy sequins to match his drawing. He
drew a blouse with his design. She took the drawing and had the blouse made.
Joe Nunley, Sr., a professor in the early 1960s, recalled her ability to " push her
point" or reason with the faculty " smart alecJcs.." He thought she enjoyed any
" feuding" that occurred. He remembered when someone came up with some .
absolute way of teaching, she could tum the idea around by " putting in her two
f
19Personal correspondence from Amy Chapman, November 10, 1990.
2Opersonal interview with Ruth Bowdoin, November 13, 1990.
21Personal interview with Ruth Bowdoin, November 13, 1990.
76
cents worth." 22 She was the only woman, but she was not intimidated. Before
groups and with individuals, her opinion was expressed without hesitation to
peers and those in high positions. Dr. Ralph White, chair of the &#183; MTSU
,. \,
Department of Leadership, agreed, s~' ying, " She was not reluctant to tell you
what she thought even if it was a critical c,?~ ent.,, 23
Dr. Finis Poole, a professor in the education department in the 19508,
worked with Miss Mary for about 6 years. He was reminded of her many
efforts to guard the morals of the college. When Miss Mary saw couples
embracing or making improper advances, she would remind them that this
'' wasn't nice" behavior. 24 Another example of Miss Mary's vigilance in monitor-ing
student behavior was found on a paper in the alumni office which reported
tnat on April 22, 1953, Miss Mary saw a girl smoking in the administration
building hallway after the students had promised " faithfully" not to smoke. 25 In
an interview in 1977, her concern for students' welfare was evident. She
~, .
suggested that many of their problems &#183; were related to the home environment,
22Personal interview with Joe Nunley, July 29, 1991.
23R. White, Questionnaire, July 19, 1991.
24Personal interview with Finis Poole, August 21, 1991.
25MTSU Alumni Records.
77
the divorce &#183; rate, deteriorated morals, the loss of pride, and lack of desire for
learning. 26
'"
The training school director, Hillary Parker, worked with Miss Mary as
.. \
'-
she placed observation students from tpe education department with elementary
children at the Training School in the 19508.,. He said,
She was well- informed and experience- trained herself, so that she could
tell it " like it was" when lecturing to her classes. Students knew and felt
her earnestness in what was needed arid required in successful teaching in
Tennessee's public schools. She could cite examples in ' this county or
that county' of what was done to improve educational practice. She
would plan for class visits to see on the spot examples of what was going
on in different schools. 27
Bob Womack, a colleague, agreed saying she turned out teachers who knew
what they faced. 28
A personal friend, Virginia Woodfin, provided the following anecdote to
illustrate Miss Mary's independence and courage: Miss Mary was teaching an
adult education class in Altamont, a small community in the Grundy County
' 1, '
mountain area in the 19508. There had been an epidemic of cars being stolen
and stripped in the area, but that did not deter Miss Mary. One evening
around nine o'clock as she was driving over the mountain to Jasper she realized
. a truck was following her. Fearing that the ' driver planned to apprehend her
26p. Skipper ( 1977, August), '' The Emeriti: Still a Life to Live When it's Time
to Depart the Company of Scholars, MTSU Today, p. 26.
27Personal interview with Hillary Parker, July 18, 1991.
28Personal interview with Bob Womack, June 1, 1988.
78
and take the car, she tried slowing down and speeding up, but the truck stayed
right behind her. When she pulled into a filling station in Jasper, the truck
-.
driver parked, got out, and came to her car... " Lord, Miss Mary," he exclaimed,
,. \,
" what are you doing in Grundy Couno/. in'. the middle of the night? The man
~
was in her adult education class and he had followed along to ass'ure her
safety. 29
Miss Mary retired August 31, 1960.30 . Sam Ingram, former dean of the
education department, said Miss Mary had earned the affectionate title of Miss
Elementary Education by this time. 31 On three occasions she was called out of
retirement to teach education courses. 32 Dr. Will Bowdoin, chairman of the
education department, allowed Miss Mary to assist with the selection of her
successor. When Dr. Mary Tom Berry arrived to interview for the position, she
realized Miss Mary was a legend, and it would be difficult to fill her shoes.
During the transition period Miss Mary was portrayed as being gracious, sweet,
~, .
and supportive. The last time Miss Mary went to her classroom with Berry, she
29Personal interview with Virginia Woodfin, July 8, 1991.
3Opersonnel files, MTSU president's office.
31Personal interview with Sam Ingram, June 2, 1989.
32Personnel files, MTSU president's office.
79
picked up three or four little things with her purse and walked out, leaving the
files, books, and items' collected ' over the years. 33
Dean of Wnmen &#183;
On February 2, 1945 when Miss Mary w~ asked to take the position as
the college's first dean of women, she said " no" because she was scheduled to
visit some ~ county schools. She had no recourse because the college president
and the commissioner of education had made arrangements for her supervisory
work on Tuesdays and Thursdays and campus work on Monday, Wednesday, and
Friday.
The college &#183; president wanted her to keep the college women on campus.
Some were " running off' to Nashville without telling anyone. In dealing with
these problems, Miss Mary's values, stamina, courage, and kindness were
demonstrated. The duties were a big challenge because they were so different
from \ vhat she had been doing. .. she described the girls as being rebellious and
said they did not want to be disciplined. There was a rule that the girls should
be in their room by a certain time every night and they were to sign out with
information about where they were going and what they were going to do. The
majority of their excursions were walks downtown for shopping, picture shows, or
,-
&#171;
church. 34
33Personal interview with Mary Tom Berry, August 5, 1991.
34Recollection, Part III, p. 11.
80
Four girls were going to Nashville without permission, so Miss Mary
decided to let the girls' in the donnltory set up their own committee and write
the rules. The rules stated. that no o~ e should le~. ve and everyone should be in
,. \
their room by 10 o'clock. Two weeb later' a girl was trying to get out of her
boyfriend's car at 11: 30 p. m. The boy saId they- had been to a Nashville cl~ b
and she had had too much to drink. The boyfriend and Miss Mary put the girl
to bed. The next day Miss Mary called the girl's mother and had her dismissed
from the college.
On at least one occasion Miss Mary had to engage in a little detective
work to protect morals on the campus. This particular incident was described as
" a pretty hard problem to solve." A doctor's wife called and said, " There is a
. young girl there who is the mistress of my husband." Miss Mary had the night
watchman monitor the girl's routine. He saw the doctor letting her out of the
car, so Miss Mary waited until everyone was gone for Thanksgiving to talk to
~
the girl. After explaining the sitii'ation ~ he said, " I do not want you to be in the
dormitory . . . your room is not available anYmore. The girl threatened to take
. ~
Miss Mary to court, but she moved out." 35
A joyous occasion during this time was described by Miss Mary. A girl
from Oklahoma fell in love with a boy from Jamestown and they wanted to ~ et
married. Her parents were deceased and she did not have a home, so she
asked Miss Mary if she could be married on campus. The wedding was held in
35Recollections, Part III, pp. 12- 13.
81
the Student Union Bu~ ding. Miss Mary said, " We had quite a nice wedding
with all the fixins.,, 36
'.
Miss Mary remembered attending partIes and dances with the girls. Each
'. " \ .
quarter they would go to a different dorm. for activities. After the war &#183; was over
~
the soldiers asked the girls to dances at the ,: USD. Miss Mary accompanied
them. 37
Being a disciplinarian was not enjoyable for Miss Mary. After a few
months she went to the president's office to see if he had found someone to
take her place. He raised her salary and offered to raise it some more if she
would remain in her position. Without hesitation she responded, " Mr. Smith,
you haven't got money enough to make me stay on here doing that . . . I want
to be out in the schools and with the children.,, 38
Other Contributions to the University
' 1. .
After ret~ ement various honors were bestowed on Miss Mary by the
university. Quill' E. Cope, the college president, presented her with a certificate
for a " rightful and significant place in the fifty- year history of Middle Tennessee
, State College" on May 19, 1962,39 but the greatest honor came the next year
36Recollections, Part III, pp. 15- 16.
37Personal interview with Miss Mary Hall, April 26, 1990.
38Recollections, Part III, p. 14.
39Certificate, personal papers.
82
when the announcement was made that a dormitory was being named for her.
The university president presented the good news and explained the trouble.
school officials were having with the ~ ame.. '~ We can't call it Miss Mary Hall
" \
Hall," he said. " May we c~ ll it Miss M~ ry Hall?" She was honored. 40 ~ tudents,
~
teachers, and friends wrote letters to congratulate her. Presented here are some
excerpts from these communications:
I am only one of thousands who love you.
John Bragg, a state legislator and former student41
One of the pleasant memories I have of my student days at MTSC is of
you: Your friendship, your conduct, your inspiration and your leadership.
Albert Gore, Sr., student42
You are one of those rare individuals who can provide inspiration to your
students, humor to your fellow workers, and an enthusiasm for life that
makes everyone a better person for having known you.
Sam H. Ingram, Chairman of the Education Department43
Your energy, your enthusiasm, and your optimistic outlook have served as
a stimulant at times when I might have otherwise been discouraged.
Quill E. Cope, President, Middle Tennessee State College44
4Op. Skipper, " The Emeriti," p. 26.
41Letter to Miss Mary from John Bragg, March 19, 1964.
42Letter to Miss Mary from Albert Gore, Sr., March 27, 1964.
43Letter to Miss Mary from Sam ~. Ingram, March 25, 1964.
44Letter to Miss Mary from Quill E. Cope, March 19, 1964.
83
The dedication ceremony was held in Woodmore Dining Hall in April
1964.45 Governor Frank G. clement gave the dedicatory address, and Commis&#173;sioner
of Education, J. H. Warf pre~ ided. &#183; The dedication tribute was:
. " \,
To those who have lived well, laughed often and loved much; who have
gained the respect of mankind; ' YhQ have filled their niches and ac-: &#173;complished
their tasks; who gave of themselves to leave the world a bit
better than they found it. 46 '.
On March 8, 1991, The Tennessean quoted Miss Mary as saying this was one of
the happiest days of her life. 47
As Miss Mary entered her retirement years, she was involved in what
would become one of her greatest accomplishments in improving education in
Tennessee-- the establishment of state- supported kindergartens. John Bragg, a
state representative, said: " Men didn't think too much of kindergarten. The
women's viewpoint was almost one voice crying in the wilderness., t48
Ruth McDonald, retired director of elementary programs and staff
development for the Metropoli~~ n, Nashville Schools, said:
Public kindergartens in Tennessee owe their existence to the persistence
of Maycie Southall and Mary Hall. Years before other educators were
willing to accept them and before the public generally had any interest in
them, they were talking to civic groups, legislators and governors about
them. They were urging that local chapters and Xi State actively support
the effort to make them a part of the educational program. Their &#183;
45Dedication invitation to Miss Mary Hall, personnel files.
46program for the Dedication Ceremony, April 26, 1964.
47" Services Set," p. 2B.
48Personal interview with Representative John Bragg, March 29, 1991.
84
success, after many years, had great implications for young children of the
state. 49 ,
Miss Mary's strong co~ tment to the establishment of Tennessee
-~
kindergartens is evident ~ - her speec, h, " Wo. men's Responsibility In Improving
Education":
We hear a lot about " educating all the children" and within the last
decade we have, in all of our states, developed excellent programs for the
homebound, the retarded, the handicapped, and most of our states are
working on programs for the gifted. Yet seven states do not have
kindergartens as part of the state educational program. Tennessee has a
law prohibiting the use of state funds for kindergartens.
It was decided that the PTA would survey parents; the AAUW
would survey business firms and ACE would survey first grade teachers as
to the value and need for kindergartens in Tennessee.
What is the next step? To get a law passed which will provide
state aid for public kindergartens in Tennessee and thereby improve the
state program of elementary education. 50
Dr. Berry, faculty members and-. students in the department of education
assisted Miss Mary with the survey. 51 Dr. Southall credited Miss Mary for the
legislative endeavors on the bill. 52 The influence Miss Mary had with the poli-
~
ticians was tremendous, accordiIig to D~. Berry, because she either knew most of
49Personal correspondence from Ruth McDonald dated May 9, 1979 and
reprinted in D. L. Brown ( 1981), Maycie Katherine Southall: Her Life/ and
Contributions to Education, Nashville, TN: McQuiddy Printing, p. 240. &lt;
50Speech given by Miss Mary Hall ( notecards found in her personal posses&#173;sions,
date and place unknown).
51Personal interview with Mary Tqm Berry, August 5, 1991.
521. Wheeler, Questionnaire, August 4, 1990.
',. " Elementary Education in Tennessee." Stories from her past helped students
".'
85
them as their teacher or she had been associated with them at the state depart&#173;ment.
53
".
A pilot kindergarten class was established "" in the university's laboratory
,. \,
school in the-- Iate 1960s, and the Early C~ dh~ od Program for teacher training
"
was developed. 54 In time, the kindergarten'e~ anded- to two classes. - For mo~ e
than 25 years, college students have benefited from direct experiences with the
kindergarten children and teachers. The curriculum courses have evolved with
research and trends in primary education, but the basic purposes of the original
programs envisioned by Miss Mary are intact.
Marion Hamilton, a retired professor in the department of education,
referred to Miss Mary as the best resource on the history of early childhood in
Tennessee. She served as a guest speaker- in Dr. Hamilton's classes on at least
15 occasions and used a paper she wrote for the lectures, " Background of Early
~,
relate to the history of education, and according to Hamilton, " Students remem-bered
Miss Mary's talk more than any other aspe~ t of the class. 55 Her last
guest lecture was in 1989. During this time she also visited Miss Mary Hall, the
dormitory named in her honor, to talk with the college girls who resided there.
Estelle Fann, the dormitory's housemother, especially remembered Miss Mary /&lt;
53Personal interview with Mary Tom Berry, August 5, 1991.
54Personal interview with Mary Tom Berry, August 5, 1991.
SSM. Hamilton, Questionnaire, July 16, 1991.
86
telling the students that they would never become too old to enjoy life. " Just
look at me!" she would exc1aiih. 56
Miss Mary's monetary ger: terosity to- ilcademic programs was evident.
, ,. \,
During the administration of Preside. nt Quill E. Cope, she was presented with a
~
certificate for being " a member in Good ~~ anding with the First Fifty Club and
for her loyal contributions to the Loan, Scholarship and Development
Foundation." 57 Boyd Evans, director of MTSU's Foundation, said Miss Mary
represented the school of education at meetings when the organization was
founded in 1962. She attended meetings until a few months before her death.
She always made comments to the trustees at some point during each meeting,
even when she was not on the agenda. Her statements stressed the importance
of the foundation and the need for personal commitment to financial support.
As a consistent financial contributor, she exemplified her convictions. She, asked
Mr. Evans to visit in her home. When he arrived she would say,. " I have heard.
~, '
.. what is going on?" Mr. Evans believed MTSU was her life. 58 In 1976 she
made a contribution to the Doctor of Arts cwd &#183; Health Services Campaign
Funds. 59 In the fall of 1978, Miss Mary gave $ 3,000 to establish the Miss Mary
56relephone interview with Estelle Fann, January 23, 1993.
57Certificate found in personal papers, undated.
58Personal interview with Boyd Evans, November 5, 1992.
59Correspondence from Boyd A Evans, Director of MTSU's Foundation,
August 16, 1976.
87
Hall Scholarship in elementary education. 60 The scholarships were personally
presented at the annual Academic Awards Banquet. As a trustee of the &#183;
.~
university's foundation in 1981, she received- a certificate for " selfless and
" .\
.... '- ~
devoted contributions" and for her "~ te~ al role in the enhancement and
continued progress of the university as a premier institution for higher leam&#173;ing.,,
61 The Women of University Housing presented Miss Mary with a certifi-cate
for " Years of Dedicated Service" March 7, 1985.62 The Middle Tennessee
State University Citizens Award was given to her December 1988 for supporting
the Biology Club's recycling scholarship program. The project provided scholar&#173;ships
for more than 70 students. 63
The MTSU Alumni Association benefited from her support. Miss Mary
regularly attended the annual Alumni Banquets at the university. Mer attend-ing
the 1990 event, she wrote the following in a thank you note to the associa-tion:
" I was asked why I keep going and I said, ' I get more kiss~ g and hugging
~
then than all the rest of the ye~ r put. together." t64
6OCorrespondence from Boyd A. Evans, November 15, 1978.
61Certificate from MTSU Foundation, November 21, 1981.
62Certificate found in persona</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Hall, Mary Ella, 1895-1991; Educators; Women college teachers; School management and organization; Laboratory schools; Middle Tennessee State College; Middle Tennessee State Teachers College; Delta Kappa Gamma Society. Xi State (Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro, TN; Kittrell, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Biography</dc:format>
<dc:format>Book</dc:format>
<dc:format>x, 147 leaves</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected. Reproduced with permission of the creator</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>May be used freely by individuals for research, teaching, and personal use under the fair use provisions of the Copyright Act</dc:rights>
<dc:relation>Peabody contributions to education. Ed. D. series</dc:relation>
<dc:publisher>George Peabody College of Education, Vanderbilt University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>no. 945</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>LB5 .G42 no. 945</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/mtsu1/id/1329</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>