<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>MTSU to lead drive for Viet Nam support</dc:title>
<dc:title>MTSU to lead drive for Vietnam support</dc:title>
<dc:relation>Sidelines, Dec. 12, 1965</dc:relation>
<dc:date>1965-12-07</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>MTSU's student body president coordinated a Vietnam support petition which was circulated at other Tennessee colleges and universities. The article also discusses a student body president meeting to be held in Nashville to present the petitions to the governor.</dc:description>
<dc:description>MTSU To Lead Drive For Viet Nam Support
A petition to be sent to President Lyndon
B. Johnson in support of his policies concerning Viet Nam will be circulated on campus this week.  It is one of twenty such petitions which will be circulated at colleges and universities throughout Tennessee.
Under the leadership of A. S. B. President Bert Wakeley, MTSU is credited with coordinating the drive.
A meeting will be held on December 11 in Nashville with all student body presidents of participating schools on hand to present the petitions to Governor Clement who will  in turn relay them to the President of the United States. With MTSU spearheading the event, other schools who will attend are: Austin Peay State College, Belmont College, Bethel College, Carson-Newman College, E.T.S.U., King College, Memphis State University, Milligan College, Peabody College, T.T.U., University of Chattanooga, University of Tennessee,  U.T.M.B., Vanderbilt University, Tennessee State University, Fisk University,University of the South. More schools may join the movement during the week.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>ASB</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Vietnam War, 1961-1975; Petitions; College students--Political activity; Middle Tennessee State University</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Student organizations;</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro, TN; Nashville, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:type>image/jpeg</dc:type>
<dc:format>Clipping</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected. Reproduced with permission of the University</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Reproduction is permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only; Credit to Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:rights>
<dc:relation>Sidelines Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/mtsu1/id/750</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>