<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>"Kennedy 'dissents' to 12,000 at Vanderbilt"</dc:title>
<dc:title>Destiny of dissent</dc:title>
<dc:relation>Sidelines, March 28, 1968</dc:relation>
<dc:creator>Brooks, Sylvester</dc:creator>
<dc:contributor>Hillard, Tom, photographer</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1968-03-28</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>A review of a speech given by Robert Kennedy at Vanderbilt in March of 1968, taken from MTSU's Sidelines Newspaper.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Kennedy "Dissents" to 12,000 at Vanderbilt
EDITOR'S NOTE:
The following is a review of presidential hopeful 

Robert F. Kennedy's speech "The Destiny of 

Dissent" given at Vanderbilt's Impact 

pre-symposium on Thursday, March 21. This was 

written by Sylvester Brooks, vice-chairman of the 

recently organized Students for Kennedy at MTSU.
This country is on the brink of a newer world. It 

is up to America to determine whether or not it 

is to be a better world. It is essential that we 

have leaders of courage, foresight and 

conviction. Such a man is Robert F. Kennedy. Here 

is a man brave enough to stand behind conviction 

and courageous enough to reassess when 

circumstances deem it necessary. He seeks the 

presidential nomination in behalf of the American 

people who desire unity In their country and 

peace in the world.
At Vanderbilt University, Senator Kennedy spoke 

strongly and clearly; and 12,000 voices roared in 

agreement with this great American. He came to 

Tennessee, not to promise peaches and cream, but 

to tell it like it is.
Often times, we find it extremely difficult to 

accept the truth; but if this country ever 

chooses to ignore and denounce the truth, it 

loses its heritage and its only hope for the 

future.
The Senator thinks it is time for American people 

and President Johnson to make a re-assessment 

concerning the war in Vietnam, He said a few 

years ago President John Kennedy pledged to help 

the Vietnamese people win their war. He did not 

pledge to win it for them. Yet in 1968 we labor 

under the heavy burden of winning the war for 

them. The war in Vietnam has in fact become an 

American war. All nations look toward Vietnam. It 

has become the theater of the world.
Our leaders are, therefore, resolved that this 

should be our greatest performance. But such has 

not been the case. In reality, it has perhaps 

been our worst performance. The United States, 

the strongest nation in the world, is being 

contained by one of the weakest. Yet our leaders 

continue to march us to the eve of destruction, 

neglecting our common sense and doubting our 

intelligence by painting the darkest sky blue and 

telling us we're winning the war.
To add even more to this dilemma the President 

has removed himself from the American people and 

in so doing has lost their confidence. How long 

can a democracy exist when confidence does not? 

Senator Kennedy is concerned as we all should be. 

He spoke plainly with a certain irrepressible 

confidence in those to whom he was speaking.
We sense that this is not what the American 

spirit is all about. We see all this and we ask, 

does this serve the national interest? I say it 

does not. In what way does the war's present 

course advance the security of this country, the 

welfare of Vietnam, or the cause for peace in the 

world? So I dissent."
While we spend billions of dollars thousands of 

miles away from   home,   our cities rot and our 

summers get hotter. "Tanks have patrolled 

American streets and machine guns have fired at 

American children. So again-- I dissent."
America is a great nation&#8212; and the American 

people are a great people. We are going to be 

strong and confident again, because today, like 

eight years ago, we seeK a strong and confident 

leader. We are not going to be bewildered by 

fantasies or blinded from the truth for very 

long.
For such is the nature of America and the 

heritage of its people. Even so, while there is 

so much to dissent from. While there is so much 

to stand up for, there is so much to stand 

against.
So Senator Kennedy dissents&#8212; I dissent, and I am 

sure that you dissent. For the time has come for 

all of us as Americans to examine and re-examine 

ourselves and look at our world and our country; 

and then choose a a new president. That man 

should be none other than Senator Robert F. 

Kennedy.
&#8212;Staff Photo by Tom Hillard
APPROXIMATELY 12,000 PEOPLE filled the Vanderbilt 

Gym last Thursday night to hear Robert Kennedy at 

the Impact pre-symposium.
-Staff Photo by Tom Hillard KENNEDY WAITS for 

many of the spectators to sit down after a 

standing ovation.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Kennedy, Robert F., 1925-1968; Presidential candidates; IMPACT Symposium (Vanderbilt University); Vietnam War, 1961-1975</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Nashville, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:type>image/jpeg</dc:type>
<dc:format>Clipping;</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected. Reproduced with permission of the University</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Reproduction is permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only; Credit to Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:rights>
<dc:relation>Sidelines Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/mtsu1/id/1112</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>