<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>"Buchanan Dramatic Club is Cultural Influence on Campus"</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Jones, Frank</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1936-06-05</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Frank Jones, a twenty-five year veteran at the State Teacher's College, wrote this short history of the beginnings of the Buchanan Dramatic Club in 1936. He discusses the nature of the club's first plays and follows the club's evolution over the years of Rebecca Buchanan's tenure.</dc:description>
<dc:description>BUCHANAN DRAMATIC CLUB IS CULTURAL INFLUENCE ON CAMPUS - It was during the year 1925 - 1926 that the Dramatic Club of the State Teachers College was first organized with Miss Rebecca J. Buchanan of the Department of Speech as director.  Prior to that, dramatic work, under Miss Buchanan's guidance, had been done in the literary societies, but with the passing of the societies the need was felt for an organization devoted entirely to dramatics. Among the presidents who have served  the club are Marion Capps, Elizabeth Stevenson, Katherine Brown, Esther Talley, John Oliver, Ed Bell, Roy Dowdy, Katherine Chambers, Edwin Tarpley, Cecil Webb, and Owen Griffin.The first play produced by the Club was Booth Tarkington's "Seventeen". Among the outstanding productions of the Club,
under Miss Buchanan's direction were Oscar Wilde's " Lady Winder-mere's
Fan" in which Perry Williamson and Katherine Brown
played with notable success. A memorable event in the history
of the Club was the staging of R. C. Sheriff's " Journey's End"@(
with Ed Bell as Stanhope, Roy Dowdy as Osborne, and Albert Gore in
the role of Raleigh. The difficult stage setting was handled
with signal success. Another colorful and pleasing production
that lingers in the memory of S. T. C. plagoers was " Milestones"
by Knoblett and Arnold Bennett in which the work of Katherine
Chambers, Florence Betz, and Roy Dowdy was most gratifying.
In a lighter vein, but most pleasing, was " The Patsy" featuring
Dorothy Gwinn, Katherine Chambers, and John Oliver.
In 1932 Miss Buchanan because of illness was obliged to
resign the directorship of the Club, and for more than a year
the organization continued without any definite leadership,
putting on a series of one- act plays. The Club suffered a
decline during this period but in 1934 under the leadership
of Cecil Webb, Edwin Tarpley, Jane Mankin and others, it
was revived and with Mrs. Marion Edney ( the former Miss Dorothy
Bachtel of the Science Department), the Club took on new life
and began an ambitious series of plays which it has continued
since. " Little Women" in which Martha Moore Gracey starred
as JO, was a signal success; the spectacular " Hunch Back of
Notre Dame" with Cecil Webb in the title role was a feat in
staging.
Following Mrs. Sadney'J resignation as sponsor of the
Club, Mrs. Marshall Burns was chosen sponsor, With " Candida" in
1935 and " Ghosts" in 1936 the Club ventured into the realm
of serious drama. Both of these plays were ably directed by
Miss Esther Licker who brought to her work a wide knowledge
of play production. The effective stage settings by J. B.
Peyton, the art director of the Club, have been a notable
feature of the productions of the past two years.
Time fails to tell of the many who have made the work of
the Dramatic Club a success. Its achievements have been due
no less to the work of those who have played the leading roles
than to those who have sustained the high level of the Club's
presentations in the minor roles, to those who have borne
the brunt of the technical side of production, and to the rank
and file members whose interest and loyal support have kept
2
&#183; ' 3
the Club a live and growing organization.
It was in 1934 that it was decided to name the Club for its
beloved founder and director for many years, Miss Rebecca J.
Buchanan. Miss Buchanan, who had been a member of the faculty
from 1913 to 1932 as teacher of speech and a member of the
Fnglish department, received her training at the famous Boston - Sc h0 0 1 0 f Expre s s ~ n~ n de r 0r. S. S. Cur r y . Prio r t 0 com i ng t 0
S. T. C. she was a member of the faculty at Belmont College.
Though no longer active in directing the work of the organization,
she continues to inspire and influcence its endeavors and the
Buchanan Dramatic Club in the sincere and effective work which
it has done has sought to live up to the high standards which
she set for it.
By FRANK JONES
S. T. C. - 25 YEARS OF SERVICE
Friday, June 5, 1936
</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Drama; Theater; Buchanan, Rebecca J.; Middle Tennessee State Teachers College--Faculty; Middle Tennessee State Teachers College</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Text;</dc:type>
<dc:type>application/pdf</dc:type>
<dc:format>Article;</dc:format>
<dc:format>3 p.; 8.5 x 11 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright may or may not belong to MTSU; Reproduced with permission of the Albert Gore Research Center, MTSU</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>May be used freely by individuals for research, teaching, and personal use under the fair use provisions of the Copyright Act; Credit: Property of the Albert Gore Research Center, Middle Tennessee State University, Murfreesboro, TN 37132; For other uses contact The Albert Gore Research Center, P.O. Box 193, MTSU, Murfreesboro TN 37132</dc:rights>
<dc:relation>Middle Tennessee State University Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:publisher>Albert Gore Research Center, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:description>MTSU Theatre, Series 2&amp;3, Box 2</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/mtsu1/id/1588</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>