<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Quintin Miller Smith memorial service</dc:title>
<dc:source>Middle Tennessee State University</dc:source>
<dc:date>1976-04-08</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1970-1979</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>A program from the memorial service for Quintin Miller Smith. Smith was president of the institution from 1938-1958.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Interestingly, the program for the memorial service of Smith was acquired quite by accident. Walker, Digital Initiatives purchased extra copies of The First Fifty Years by Homer Pittard, and the program was tucked within the pages of one of the volumes.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Memorial Services
In Remembrance 01
QUINTIN MILLER SMITH
President
Middle Tennessee State University
Murfreesboro, Tennessee
from September 1, 1938
until September 1, 1958
In Memorium
Tennessee Room
Student Union Building
Middle Tennessee State University
April 8, 1976
2: 00 p. m.
Personification of consistent achievement in a career dedicated to the improvement of
education, Q. M. Smith served as a college president for 38 years, longer than any other
person in Tennessee history.
A man who loved young people, understood them, shared in their joys and sorrows their
ambitions and achievements he was one who was regarded with esteem and appreci~ tion.
In 1911, as Middle Tennessee Normal first opened, a young man with four years teaching
experience in his native Humphreys County, enrolled with aspirations to improve as a
teacher. Asserting leadership in forensics, publications, and scholarship Mr. Smith
graduated from the Normal to move on to the University of Tennessee and later to
Peabody College where he earned the B. S. and M. A. degrees. While successfully filling a
high school principalship he studied law at night and became a licensed member of the
bar
Organ Prelude
Scripture- Praye
" Open Our Eyes" - McFarlane
University Varsity Choir
Presiding ...
~, ributes:
. Mrs. Margaret Wright
Dr. Robert Garrigus
Directed by" Mr. Neil Wright
Dr. M. G. Scarlett
He became President of Tennessee Polytechnic Institute in 1920. Then, in 1938 when
Middle Tennessee State College sought a third president to bring the institution out of the
diminution and confusion of ~ he exhausting years of the Great Depression, Q. M. Smith
was chosen.
As a product of this school he became the source of reinvigoration that saw a student
body increase from 550 to 2,245, the erection of 13 new permanent structures, the
growth of the campus from 205 to 604 acres with a comparable increase in staff. With
rare perspkacity he developed a comprehensive conspectus for the expansion of
professional, vocational, and liberal arts programs that were ultimately to culminate in
University status.
" As an Administrator" . . . . . . . .
" A Friend - Personal and Professional"
" A Community Remembers"
" A President's View" .....
Prayer
and
Mr. E. W. Midgett
. Dr. David Dodd
. Mr. John Rucker
Dr. M. G. Scarlett
Mr. Eugene Sloan
Although education, his own a~ d that of others, was the driving force in Mr. Smith's life,
he was a dedicated family man and active in the work of his church, civic and fraternal
orders.
He was twice President of the Tennessee Education Association, President . of the
Tennessee College Association, chairman of the committee that framed the Tennessee
Teacher Retirement System, a member of the Board of Directors of the Chamber &#183; of
Commerce, a bank vice- president, : Chairman of the Rutherford County Democratic
Executive Committee and the Planning Committee.
He was a commissioner and vice- president of the Tennessee Council of the Boy Scouts of
America and was awarded the two top adult honors of that organization. He was an
intensively patriotic citizen. He served as a commissioned officer in the Navy in World
War I and retired as a major USAR. This interest led him to bring the ROTC program to
MTSU and to maintain membership in the American Legion for more than half a century.
The University is indeed proud and thankful that Mr. Smith came this way.
" Benediction and Seven- Fold Amen" - Lutkin
University Varsity Choir ..... Directed by Mr. Neil Wright
. f
. f
</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Smith, Quintin Miller; College presidents; Middle Tennessee State Teachers College; Middle Tennessee State College; Middle Tennessee State University</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Image; Text;</dc:type>
<dc:type>text; application/pdf</dc:type>
<dc:format>Program</dc:format>
<dc:format>4 p.; 5.50 x 8.75 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright may or may not belong to MTSU; Reproduced with permission of the Albert Gore Research Center, MTSU</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>May be used freely by individuals for research, teaching, and personal use under the fair use provisions of the Copyright Act; Credit: Property of the Albert Gore Research Center, Middle Tennessee State University, Murfreesboro, TN 37132; For other uses contact The Albert Gore Research Center, P.O. Box 193, MTSU, Murfreesboro TN 37132</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Albert Gore Research Center, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/mtsu1/id/1296</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>