<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Olivia Woods oral history</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Woods, Stenia Olivia Murray</dc:creator>
<dc:contributor>Rowland, Betty, interviewer</dc:contributor>
<dc:source>Albert Gore Research Center</dc:source>
<dc:date>2001-06-19</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969; 1970-1979</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Excerpts of an oral history with Olivia Woods, the first African-American student at Middle Tennessee State University. Woods shares her memories of attending college at MTSU as both an undergraduate and a graduate student during the 1960s and 1970s</dc:description>
<dc:description>1. Woods' experiences as first MTSC African-American full-time undergraduate student -- 2. Woods' and son's experiences on campus as African-Americans -- 3. Woods' experiences with female dress code -- 4. Woods' experiences as graduate student during 1970s.</dc:description>
<dc:relation>(clip 1) http://content.mtsu.edu/cdm4/audiofiles/wood/woods1.mp3 ; (clip 2) http://content.mtsu.edu/cdm4/audiofiles/wood/woods2.mp3 ; (clip 3) http://content.mtsu.edu/cdm4/audiofiles/wood/woods3.mp3 ; (clip 4) http://content.mtsu.edu/cdm4/audiofiles/wood/woods4.mp3</dc:relation>
<dc:subject>African Americans; African American college students; African American graduate students; Race relations; Women college students; Dress codes; Middle Tennessee State University</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro, TN; Nashville, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Still image; Sound</dc:type>
<dc:type>image/jpeg; audio/mp3</dc:type>
<dc:format>Oral history; Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright may or may not belong to MTSU; Reproduced with permission of the Albert Gore Research Center, MTSU</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>May be used freely by individuals for research, teaching, and personal use under the fair use provisions of the Copyright Act; Credit: Property of the Albert Gore Research Center, Middle Tennessee State University, Murfreesboro, TN 37132; For other uses contact The Albert Gore Research Center, P.O. Box 193, MTSU, Murfreesboro TN 37132</dc:rights>
<dc:relation>Middle Tennessee Oral History Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:publisher>Albert Gore Research Center, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>MT2000.046</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/mtsu1/id/1347</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>