<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Dromgoole literary society, 1916</dc:title>
<dc:description>Dromgoole Literary Society, one of the earliest organizations on campus, reportedly named for a local writer</dc:description>
<dc:description>The Dromgoole Literary Society may have been named for Will Allen Dromgoole, who was born in Murfreesboro and began her writing career after returning to the area to care for her aging father. Amongst her varied career, Dromgoole worked for the Nashville Banner, served in the Navy during World War I, and edited literary publications. Her many literary achievements include books, stories, thousands of poems, thousands of newspaper columns, an operetta, and plays. In her work she depicts a diversity of residents of East and Middle Tennessee--hill folk and the poor and wealthy, black and white of Nashville. Dromgoole is buried in the Evergreen Cemetery in Murfreesboro.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Literature--Societies, etc.; College students; Middle Tennessee State Normal School; Dromgoole, Will Allen, 1860-1934</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Group portraits</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:type>image/jpeg</dc:type>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Not protected by copyright</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit to Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:rights>
<dc:relation>University collection</dc:relation>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/mtsu1/id/1369</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>