<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Normalite, 1922 October</dc:title>
<dc:source>Middle Tennessee State Normal</dc:source>
<dc:date>1922-10-01</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1920-1929</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>The Normalite was a Middle Tennessee State Normal School publication</dc:description>
<dc:description>IN MEMORIA~ I
DR. JAMES W. FERTIG
BORN OCT. 12, 1859
DIED SEPT. 21, 1922
f
Head of Education Dejtartment
Middle Tennessee Normal
1912- 1922
DR. JAMES ' V. FERTIG
Memories- ANON ; 3
But I Lived Through It-:- E. W. DUCK A
. Life's Eternal Query-" JACK" 6
Buckskin- JAMES DAVIS 6
Causes of The World War- R. W. JOHNSON 7
Please Carry Me Back- BOB PARTIN..~ 10
Why The White Coat Farm Failed- MARGARET
WATSON ~ ~ 11
- .
Every Day Life- NELL HENDERSON 14
M. T. N. Version of Antony's Oration- B'GEORGE 15
First Aid to the Injured- EMMA BECTON 16
The Recognized Need of Physical Training 17
Pep- DOROTHY LYON .20
Dreams- SARAH KEEBLE CRENSHAW .21
You Is Or You Ain't- H. P. OGDEN 22
Shakespeare Surpassed- PHILIP MANKIN ~. 23
I Am a Socrates in Face- BOB PARTIN 26
Ps. I BioI II- ANON 27
From The Etude- GLEE CLUB 28
Editorial Page _ : 29
Hits, Runs and Errors 31
Literary Societies 33
Faculty 37
Chapel Talks ~ 40
Lyceum Notes 42
Locals 43
. Why Study. Public School Music? 0&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226; .45
Alumni 46
Y. M. C. A 48
Y. W. C. A , 50
Exchanges 51
Athletics ..........................................................&#8226;&#8226;...&#8226;..._ 52
Glee Clubs _ 55
Art 56
Fun 59
It Pays to Advertise ro
Advertisements 62
MEMORIES
Soft tones of music thrilling with their sound;
The olden haunts of olden days wherein
Move other forms than those that there have been;
The twilight walk when silence falls around
The quieted earth while heaven's cope is found
In all the glory of the evening star,
And glinting through from mystic realms afar
Faith lifts the soul above its earthly mound.
All these and : more awake my memory,
And with a touch of sadness turn my mind
' To life's past acts my dearest friends to see.
o though for their fond presence 1. repine,
The deep impression that they left on me
Makes my heart grateful for the days behind.
- ANON.
THE NORMALITE
BUT I LIVED THROUGH IT
It was the third of June 1919 that the following almost
fatal incident happened to me. I had promised , my " buddie,"
Mr. James Malory, that I would meet him at six o'clock in the
Parc Monceau. James was my clo'sest buddie throughout OUf
service in France. He was a young man about my age and
his home was at White Pine, Tenn., near Knoxville.
True to my promise I was there on time and I expected
him to be, for he was always punctual and true to his word.
But owing to some disastrous circumstance he never came. ,
His failure to come is a part of my story.
I had waited thirty minutes and was in the act of ris&#173;ing
from my seat with the intention of giving him up when I
heard my name called. And the puizling part was that it was
a woman's voice who called. " What woman in Paris or in
France, who can speak clear English, knows me?" was the
startled question that flashed through my mind. I confront&#173;ed
her' as I faced about with a " Y- e- s-' m." Her enunciation
and costumle were truly American. I judged by her general
appearance that she belonged to some of the most prominent
aristocracy of America.
Again she addressed me by my name and related a sad
experience that happened to her the day befo~ e Ilear Orleans.
In company with her husband she had been in a train wreck
in which her husband had been killed. In the confusion fol&#173;lowing
the disaster all of their money which was in the pos&#173;session
of her husband was stolen. The result was that she
was a penniless stranger in a land whose people spoke a lan&#173;guage
of which she knew not a word. Moved by a feeling
of pity for her I was anxious to help her so I asked, " Can I
assist you in any way ?" " Yes," she replied, " I am directed
to Hotel where I am to meet my brother who is
en route from Blois. I would appreciate your assistance in
helping me get to that place." Needless to say, I accepted the
invitation to render whatever aid I was able. Besides I con&#173;sidered
it a duty as well as a source of pleasure. In those
days it was a rare privilege to be iIi such society. I was so
charmed in her presence and so completely lost to my sur-
THE NORMALITE 5
roundings that when I came to my senses we had ridden three
miles out of ou~ way. We immediately left the car and took
a taxi in order to make up the time we had lost.
After a ride of forty minutes we drew up in front of the
............................ Hotel. We entered the hall, an old Napoleanjc
building with a poor system of lighting and ventilating. Car&#173;rying
her two traveling bags I followed her into a room that
was as " dark as pitch." I crouched up in one corner and
waited for her to switch on the lights. Instead of switching
on a light she lighted a candle and locked the door. " Why
does she want that door locked &#183; ?" I thought. My suspicions
were aroused. I began to think " What does she want with.
me here?" I wished I were away &#183; and would have backed
out if I could but there was nochance for retreat.
She opened OI1. e of the tr. aveling bags and withdrew a for&#173;ty-
five automatic pistol. Taking me by the arm she said,
" Come." I refused; but she pressed the ; muzzle of the auto&#173;matic
to my spinal column and said, " Go." I moved forward
in a crouching position~ wondering and fearing, stumbling and
falling in the dim light, and guessing what would happen
to me next.
I stumbled over a dark soft object, wrapped in blankets.
She said, " Stop, take this body to the river, and drop it in.'''
" Body to the river and drop it in," ran through my mind.
" No, I will do no such a thing,". came to my mind; but I did
not say it- my tongue was too stiff, , my throat was too dry!
I stooped to examine the body and of all the horrible sights
I ever saw this was &#183; the most horrible! Though it was three
years ago, I can still see it as plainly as if it were last night.
It was the body of my buddie! The body, half wrapped in
United States army blankets, revealed the bruises, cuts, and
torn places from which the blood was still oozing. Three
thousand miles from home in a strange country, in a strange
city, and in a strange place he had passed into the great be&#173;yond
in this terrible manner~
I was aroused from the deep stupor into which the shock
had thrown me by a healthy punch on the head with the au &#183; &#183;
tomatic and reminded that I had better carry out , her orders.
The idea of such a horrible job 1' 0 be imposed on me almost
6 THE NORMALITE
ran me wild! For a moment I stood silent looking for - a
way of escape, but 1 saw none. A storm was rC! ging out&#173;side
which a'dded to the terror- of the situation. The thunder
was constantly roaring, the wind was howling furiously, and
by the - ftas~~ s of the lightning I could see the rain descend&#173;ing
in torrehts. Yet there was no way of escape. I drew up,
clinched my fists, gritted my teeth, and ' shouted, " Murder!
Murder ! Murder!
This awoke my buddie and he kicked me out of bed.
- E. W. DUCK.
LIFE'S ETERNAL QUERY
Did it ever occur to you that a man's life is full of cussed&#173;ness?
He comes into the world without his' consent and goes
out against his will, and the trip between is exceedingly rocky.
When he is little the big girls kiss him; when he is big
the little girls kiss him. If he is poor he is a bad manager;
if he is rich he is a crook. If he is prosperous everybody wants
to do him a favor; if he needs credit they hand him a lemon.
If he is in politics , it is for graft; if he is out of politics
he is no good to his country. If he doesn't give to charity
he's a tightwad; if he does it's for show. If he is actively &#173;religious
he is a hypocrite; and if he takes no interest inre&#173;ligion
he is a heathen.
If &#183; he is affectionate he is a soft mask; if he cares for no
one he is cold hearted. If he dies young there was a great fu&#173;ture
for ~- im; if he lives to an old age he has missed his
calling.
If he doesn't fight he is yellow; if he does he is a brute.
If he saves his money he is a miser; if he spends it he is a
loafer. If he gets it he is a grafter; if he doesn't get it he is
a bum'.
SO WHAT'S THE USE? - JACK.
I$ UCKSKIN
J.... Dam, S.. tia er. de, Model School
I was visiting Mr. Wilhoit out west on his ranch. His
THE NORMALITE 7,
ranch was very w~ nderfu1. All around you could see noth&#173;ing
but great plains. If you were to go ten miles from the
ranch you would have a very hard time getting back.
Mr. Wilhoit had a very ' interesting pony named Buck&#173;skin,
for his coat was the color of buckskin. Mr. Wilhoit
told me that if I were to get lost and Buckskin were with
me he would bring me back home. Buckskin had been trained
to round up the cattle and do everything necessary for the
horses to do. Buckskin was the best of them all.
One cold night when the snow was very deep, Buckskin
and I started for a little village a short distance away. Neith&#173;er
Buckskin nor I knew the way but we soon learned that a
sleigh in front of us was going to the same village, so we
stayed behind them until we reached _ the village. When we
reached the village I tied Buckskin on the outside of a house.
A great snowstorm came up and it was very cold. When
I went out to get Buckskin he was gone. Evidently he had
untied himself to go somewhere it was not cold. , I followed
by his tracks. I soon heard him neigh,' and I soon found him
in a ditch.
We started for home, but the sleighs we were following'
soon began' to branch off, some to the right and smne to the
left. We - didnot know which way to go. Buckskin wanted
to go one way and I wanted to go the other. I insisted, that
my way was right and after much persuading I got him to go
my way.
We went on do\ vn the traii and sodn reached a: ranch.
The man told us to follow certain stars until we reached the
man's house and we found the way home. .
When we reached home I- gave Buckskin some hay and
oats. Then I was sure Buckskin knew Imore than I.
CAUSES OF THE WORLD WAR
In taking up the study of the World War we must turn
back and review the principles and outcome of the Franco&#173;Prussian
War, 1870- 1871. At this time we find Prussia to be
the central power of the' German Confederation. She saw it
was her chance to crush France and annex the Northern part
of her territory to her own Empire. In the years 1870- 1871
she was successful in doing this; and by the treaty of Frank&#173;fort,
March 10, 1871, France was forced to cede to Germany.
almost all the territories, Alsace and Lorraine, and pay an in&#173;demnity
of $ 1,000,000,000. This is the real prelude to the
World War that began in 1914.
Prussia had crushed Austria in the war of 1866, but at
the close of this war Austria and Hungary were united into
the Dual Monarchy and Bismarck, the Imper. ial Chancellor of
the New German Empire, soon showed that he desired to
hold Austria- Hungary as an ally to Germany. While on the
other hand he hoped to hold France in isolation and finally
extend the German Empire further South.
There were many perplexing problems from time to
time for the great diplomat, Bismarck, to decide. Russia and
Austria- Hungary were both expanding to the South- east and
each one was trying to get possession of the Balkan Prov&#173;inces.
In the Russo- Turkish War 1877- 1878 Ru. ssia was suc&#173;cessful
in securing a large tract of Turkish territory. But
Austria- Hunga~ ywas very jealous of this action and appealed
to Germany for help. To settle the question the Congress of
Berlin was called and a large part of the conquered territory
was given to Austria- Hungary. Up to this time Germany
was able to hold the friendship of Russia through the Three
Emperors League, a league formed by the Emperors of Rus&#173;sia,
Austria Hungary, and Germany.
But Bismarck now saw a further need of isolating
France, and he also saw that he must choose between Austria&#173;Hungary
and Russia for an al1y~ He preferred Austria- Hun&#173;gary.;
so in 1879 he formed ' a Dual Alliance between Germany
and Austria- Hungary. Three years later Bismarck added to
his power Italy, and formed the Triple Alliance in 1882.
For the next decade it was known that Germany was by
far the strongest &#183; InJilitary power in Europe while Great Brit&#173;ain
was Mistress of the Seas. During this time Russia was
still hoping to extend her' Empire into the Balkan Provinces,
and decided she would like to have the cooperation of France
in doing so. Friendly letters and visits were exchanged and
made &#183; between the officials of the two countries which led to
8 THE NORMALITE
THE NORMALITE 9
the ~ ntente ~ ordiale made between 1891 and 1.894. For the
next few years existed the Triple Alliance of Germany, Aus&#173;tria-
Hungary , and Italy on the one hand and the Entente
Cordiale of France and Russia on the other with Great Brit&#173;ain
playing neutral.
By 1900 Great Britain was leaning away from Germany
but not necessarily toward the Entente Cordiale; for in 1898
England aJId France' were on the verge of war, and Fran'ce
yielding to England's desire is all that prevented it. And in
the Boer War 1899- 1902 a number of people favored a union
of France, Russia and Germany to crush England. But France
would not unite with Germany unless she would give back
the t~ rritories of Alsace and Lorraine, and Germany would
not do this. But thanks are due to the young French lead&#173;er,
Deplasse, who about this time began to form. friendly re&#173;lations
with England. Through his efforts and the work of
King Edward VII of England an Entente Cordiale was made
between England and France in 1904. Yet this came very
near being destroyed through the Russo- Japanese War 1904&#173;1905.
For Japan, the ally of England, was fighting Russia,
the ally of France. But in the end it turned out for the best
and in 1907 Russia and England formed an Entente Cordiale
which with France united into the Triple Entente. From
1907 to 1914 we have the Triple Entente striving against the
Triple Alliance. During this period the Triple Entente was
strengthened; for iri 1911 Japan renewed her. treaty. with
England, while Italy was leaning away from the Triple Al&#173;liance,
though she remained on paper in the Alliance until
the beginning of the World War.
During the first Balkan War of 1912- 1913 between Rou&#173;mania,
Bulgaria, Serbia, Montenegro, and Greece against Tur&#173;key
the allies captured a great portion of the Turkish terri&#173;tory
in Europe. The second of these wars was over the spoils
of the first war in which Roumania, Montenegro, Serbia and
Greece fought against Bulgaria. In this way Serbia, &#183; the
kinsmen of Russia, secured a large part of the territory claim&#173;ed
by Bulgaria, an ally of - Austria- Hungary, at the close of
the first war. It was now very plain that war could not be
averted much longer, and Germany and Austria- Hungary
" PLEASE CARRY ME BACK"
were rapidly preparing for war while they waited for a ch~ 4}
to act. This came when the heir to the Austrian throne wa,$.
murdered in Sarajeuo, Bosnia, , and the Serbian Government
was held responsible for it. Austria- Hungary issued a most
unreasonable ultimatum to the Serbian Government. which
they could not afford to comply with. . Hence war began
July 28, 1914 and in six weeks all the leading nations of Eu&#173;rope
and. Great Britain ' were fighting in what is known as
the greatest war of the world.
- R. W. JOHNSON, Normal, 1922.
10 : THE NORMALITE
I approached the Normal with galloping heart and buzzing
head
. With hesitating steps and muffled tread
Bent on exploring the mystery
That awaited within for me.
Sadly, I up the steps and entered the door,
I saw a sea of faces that I had never seen before.
Pretty girls, old maids and ugly men~ too
Talking and laughing with nothing else to do.
I might have laughed if a limb I had lost or a fortune I had
missed
But never could I laugh in a place like this;
There was a smile, a, name called, a hand clasped.
The clasp didn't hold and the smile, didn't last.
He only said " Who are you? Where are you going? Where
have you been
Then turned me over to Mr. Wynn.
I faced him: and said yes and no like a fool
And signed for things that I never d~ eamed were taught in
school.
" Come to dinner," they said, I didn't feel that I wanted a bite,
When I looked the mess hall over I found I was feeling right.
That night I lay sleepless in my room,
Crying like a baby crying for the moon;
I was a sad child fighting my troubles alone,
Praying for God to pick m'C tip and carry me home.
T~ E NORMALITE 11
I wished that the buildin, gs here might, burn '
Or some old aunt at home might die in her turn.
I cried and prayed out my: soul bits by bits
Hoping that morning might bring me , smallpox Or epileptic
fits. .
One thought that would not let me rest,
" To stay at home is best."
With all such thoughts charging through my mind
The next night I wrote home " I like M. T. N. fine."
I give you the melody at random', the moral ~ ithout charge
For, " A little head, a little wit
A big head not a bit."
My head is EXTRA large.
- BOB PARTIN.
WHY THE WHITE COAT FARM FAILED
" So it's lightbread again, as usual? 1J
" Well, Bob, you know and I know that I cannot cook and
of course you recognize the impossibility of having a negro
cook here. Why, that would spoil our whole color scheme
which has just worked beautifully so far and you know you
promised never to interfere. You said you liked the idea of a
" White Coat Farm'" when I proposed it.' ,
" But, Nell, we must eat and I for one am getting exceed-,
ingly tired of lightbread, aren't you?"
" Yes, but, 1 can stand it a while longer, can't you ~ I'm
sure we can soon get a competent white cook from some&#173;where."
Bob nodded assent and Nell erased a commanding frown
from her brow and replied, " That's, a dear', I knew you
wouldn't . mlind it so awfully much.' ,
So, Bob, without complaint, munched his toast for break&#173;fast
and sandwiches for dinner every day for two more long
weeks, and still Nell had not procured a cook.
Through her untiring searching and advertising for a
competent white cook num1bers of black ones had responded,
only to be turned away from the " White Coat Farm."
Bob noticing Nell's persistence and admiring her for it,
resolved not to '~ omplain and began searching for a white
cook but with no a vail. He even asked his friends if they
knew of a competent white cook and they only laughed at
the idea, asking him had he forgotten his boyhood days and
his old black mammy? This was a question which almost
caused himl to try to dissuade the determined Nell from her
now seemingly impossible project. Finally in desperation he
bought a cook book, carried it home to Nell, and remarked
casually as he gave it to her, " I thought perhaps you might
be interested in this. The publishers guarantee that anyone
can learn to cook by using it."
Nell took it, glanced through it, dwelling a bit on " How
to Make Biscuit," and then replied with a sigh, " Oh, Bob, if
I only knew how to cook, this book might help me, but as it
is, there's no use for me to try only to waste material."
Bob, who had been watching her intently all the while
was rather anxious as to what course he should pursue and
finally decided to let the matter drop for a while.
A few days later, his appetite for lightbread thoroughly
gone, he suggested that they try taking their meals at a near&#173;by
boarding house. You see they only lived a short distance
from the city and they had their car. Nell willingly consent&#173;ed
and replied that she too was tired of lightbread and fan&#173;&lt;.:
ied that even a boarding house biscuit would taste good to
her. They found the boarding house fare' good enough for a
while, but even tha~ soon grew monotonous. In fact, Bob
was just on the verge of sending for his " old black mammy"
when he rece- ived a letter from his mother telling him that
Mammy Roxie would be there on the next - train to cook him
a biscuit that he could eat.
Of course, he met the train and Mammy Roxie not only
saw that he was glad to see her but also that there was some&#173;thing
worrying him. So just as soon as they started to the
" White Coat Farm" she said, " Marse Robert, my chile, I
guess I callated jes' right when I ' lowed that city gal what
you , m\ arried couldn't cook nothin fittin' fer a jay bird ter eat.
Dat's the reason I come and I's powerful glad, cause you sho"
looks lak you needs a good square meal." To which Bob,
although still loyal to Nell, just couldn't keep from saying, " I
12 THE NORMALITE
THE NORMALITE 13
feel better already, Mammy Roxie, and now that you are
here 1 hope that you can prove to Nell that you will not be
an objectionable feature, even thuogh you are as black as
tar. You see she is determined to have everything on our
little farm white, but so far she has failed to get a cook. At
first she will be awfully opposed to your stay. ing, but, please,
for my sake stay and prove to her that you are the most ca&#173;pable
cook there is."
The listening black mammy quickly replied, " 1 don' know
' bout her not lackin' me, but ef dey's anything ah kin do, hit.'
cook- an- an Marse Robtre you kin count on me stayin'."
They were almost there and even at a distance the ex&#173;trem(
e whiteness of the place so impressed : Mammy Roxie
that she asked, " How in de name ob peace does you all keep
eberything so white?" And Robert answered, " Nell is re&#173;sponsible
for that."
When they arrived, fortunately for them, Nell was out
searching for a cook that would meet all requirements, and
the note which she left told them that she would not get
back for lunch but would be there in time to get dinner some&#173;where.
This was just what Mammy Roxie wanted, a chance
to prove her capability, so with her aid Robert ordered it
bountiful supply of groceries, and departed for his work with
a light heart and a keen appetite.
He hurried through with his work and went to the house
early in order to be there when Nell arrived. He had bee~
there only a short time when Nell came in, tired, discouraged
and hungry, never for one minute realizing what a treat
awaited her.
Robert escorted her to the dining room telling her on the
way that he had at last gotten a cook, the best cook to be
had and sure enough there she stood waiting to serve them
one of her typical Southern dinners. Nell started to protest
but her appetite kept h~ r from it. After Robert explained it
all to her and after having eaten the preserves of Maimlmy
Roxie's own make, which she brought with her, and real bis&#173;cuit,
Nell could do nothing but admit her defeat but she did
it bravely. When they had finished eating she said, " Well,
Bob, you've won the day and although Mammy Roxie is coal
EVERY- DAY LIFE
black, she is a decided acquisition to our " White Coat Farm."
- MARGARET WATSON.
Miss Buchanan :-" Give the plural of monk."
Student :- uMonkey."
THE NORMALITE
" Vhy sometimes forsaken by friends and all?
Why stumbling blocks which cause us to fall?
Remember, where with these you have to contend
You get out of life, what you put in it, friend.
This life is a puz: zle I'll just declare
Why all these crosses so heavy to bear?
Because without crosses to weight us down,
At the judgm'ent, we wouldn't appreciate our crown.
Why do we sometimes feel lonesome and blue?
Why all these troubles we have to live thru?
Why have to study? Why not born wise?
Because, without troubles, earth would be Paradise.
Why all these pains we have to endure? .
Why life so uncertain? We never are sure.
Because if we knew when we'd draw our last breath
We'd think of nothing, except our death.
14
Though trials will come, they never will cease
For in heaven alone is there perfect peace.
But we can make life more nearly worth while
If we'll only take courage and oft'- times smile.
- NELL HENDERSON.
Why every day some kind of ache?
Why now and then a fierce heart break?
Why don't we do more work thru love?
Eecause life so perfect is only above.
THE NORMALITE
M. T. N. VERSION OF ANTONY'S . ORATION
Friends, students, faculty lend me your ears;
I came to blame History X not to praise it.
The deeds that men do are recorded;
The truth is oft interred with their bones;
So let it be with History. The learned Wynn
Hath told you History was required.:
If it were so, it was a grievous task,
And grievously have we studied it.
Here, under leave of Wynn and the rest&#173;For
Wynn is an honorable man;
So are they all, all honorable men~
Come I to speak of History X.
It is my terror, despised and rejected by me:
But Wynn says it is required;
And Wynn is an honorable man.
It hath sent many captives home to study,
Whose wai- lings did the gentle zephrys fill?
Does this in study seem required?
When that we have recited, Sims hath wept:
Instruction should be made of sterner stuff:
Yet Wynn says it is required;
And Wynn is an honorable man.
You all did see that on recitation
I thrice presented him a learned answer,
Which he did thrice refuse: was this required?
Yet Wynn says it is required;
And, sure, he is an honorable man.
I speak not to disprove what Wynn spoke,
But here I am to speak what I do know.
You all did take it once, not without cause:
What cause withholds you then , to mourn with me?
O &#183; judgment thou art fled to brutish beasts,
And men have lost their reason.
Bear with me;
My mind is in the classroom there with History,
And I Imust pause till it come back to me.
-" B'GEORGE.
15
The State of Tennessee re r .
precious than gold, founded the ~ i~~~ g that lives are more
mal to stand as first aid t h ,. e Tennessee State Nor-l
ot e mJured m' db'
sou s of her, boys and girl S. m s, odles, and
. 1 s. mce the Nor I
m 912 she has always b f rna was dedicated
t h
een ound stretch'
o t e injured minds of T mg out her hand . ennessee.
, There are very few places where th' .
mg for culturei can be f d , e mmd whIch is striv-consists
of mathemati e
h
. as at M. T. N, The best food r h cs, Istory educat' L'
IS , It is only when ' h' lOn, atm and Eng-rea~
ize how hungry y~~; ::' in; d a tas~ e of English that you
a bIg dose. really IS and resolve to take
The student body is ver cation for the facult y gra~ eful to the Board of Edu-
. y we are permItted t b f
Ize that we cannot succeed' h ' 0 oast 0, We real-hope
to, without thel'r . m t e mtellectual field, as we
aSSIstance
The Normal student's h . . Instead we have a ne p YSlcal. education is not forgotten
h
. .. w gym whIch see b . .
eac mdlvldual " Com d ms to e saymg to , e an try ME" Af
challenge we will find no sr r . ter accepting the
a body of strong and robus/;; lmsdan? Clumbsy Claudes but
oys an gIrls.
So often the social side f I'f .
with the M. T. N p ' 1 F O I. e IS neglected, but not so
. h . UpI s. our ltterar .,
ere. Two for the ' I d Y SOCIetIes are found
b glr s an two for th b
ers are urging the ne ' I e oys. The old mem-
. injured by the lack of S: C~ UfI 7~ ho have or have not been
become a member of th ' o. ee perfectly free and easy to
t
e socIety of their h'
ests are grand' Th c Olce. The con-is
enchanting The e pr. og: ams. are splendid and the spirit
. . se socIetIes WIll u t b '
tram us for service. proo uned talents and
Often we hav ' I' boro engage It e. sOtchla s m which the citizens of Murfrees-
. IS en that f wrinkled brows and th we orget frosty heads and
. e vows" " h
mmgle in the games of childhoo~ ome . av: made, but all
freshed by a good cold d . . When tIred we are re-rmk
and re- enter the game. At
17
THE NORMALITE
Locke ami Rousseau, philosophers of the seventeenth
century, pointed out the need of physical training in words
that are classic. Locke says, " Keep the body in strength and
vigor, so that it may be able to obey and execute the orders
of the mind." ( Written in 1690.)
Rousseau says, " If you would cultivate the intelligence
of your pupil, cultivate the power it is to govern. Give his
body continual exercise; make him robust and sound in order
to make him wise and reasonable; Let him be a man in vig&#173;or
and soon he will be such by force of reason." ( Written in
1762.)
From the time of Locke and RousseaU to the present day
educational philosophy has been advocating physical training.
Dutton and Snedden, in a volume dated 1908, says: " Atten&#173;tion
has been called to a possible fourfold division which
should prove helpful in adjusting means and determining the
relative importance of various educational procedures, These
four aims h' I t' I . I d It " are p ySlca, voca lona, SOCIa an cu ure..... &#183; &#183; &#183; &#183; &#183; &#183; &#183;
The relati~ e importance of physical education in this
broad sense is such that it should undoubtedly be given first
THE RECOGNIZED NEED OF PHYSICAL TRAINING
last we bid each other goodnight realizing that " AI1' s wel1
that ends well." Often we find students who are strong mental1y and
hysical1y but injured spiritual1y. The Normal has two or&#173;~
anizatiOns ready to aid them. The Y. W. C. A. for the
girls and the Y. M. C. A. for the young men. These organ&#173;izations
stand for the best of life. Connected with the Y. W.
C. A. is morning watch. In this the day is started right.
Sunday afternoon we come together again for Vesper
service. So often noble examples are given us which enable
us to climb higher. Then the members of these organi: za-tions
are always ready to lend a helping hand, to sympathize
with others and cheer them on. And " It is the littlest thin~ s
that count after all.' , So it is that the Middle Tennessee
~ tate Normal stands as first aid to the injured,_ EMMA BECTON, -
THE NORMALITE
FIRST AID TO THE INJUR&#163; D
16
19
THE NORMALITE
states having done excellent work in
erned the . m. a~ ter, s~~ ee others have done little or nothing. As
hysical trammg w bI" d to rej ect a large percentage of
p result the army was ~ Igephysically fit. On this point Dr:- &#173;~
en who should have. el. e~ in School Hygiene, U. S. Bureau
. d S Small, speCIa IS
WIllar .
of Education, says: f' the first draft were re-fi
r cent 0 men m d
1. Thirty-. ve pe unfit. Allowing for under- height an
J
. ected as phySIcally ' ther of which argue general phy&#173;.
y defects, nel ' re-speCIal
sensor t less than twenty- five per cent were
sical unfitness, no. fit That means th~ t 2,500,000
J
. ected for real phySIcal ufn 21
ness
d' 30 were unfit for military
t h ges 0 an , . .
men between e a d full measure of serVIce m
f fi t to ren er r f
service; t~ ere ore un unable to get full returns from 1 e
any capaCIty; the~ efore A 1 number of women doubt-in
work and happmess.. ~ equa "
ff r f rom disqualIfymg effects.
less su e
2. .~ .. -._.- ---- ... -
3. . --........... 000 bo s and girls of school
4 . " There are about 25,000, y t highway of
. arching along the grea
age, 6 to 18 years, m.. how that at least fifty per
youth. NumerouS investtgatIO; sai; ments that ilmpede normal
cent of these have defects an d . that they live at home
development in ~ reater .0: lessm~;: e~: less unhygienic; that
and at school tn. ~ ondltIO~ S 1 education- play, athletics, gym&#173;they
lack the pOSItIVe physlca . h' otential man and
to realIze t elr p nastics, work necessary _
woman power." . d should
THE TIME REQUIRED. Thirty mmutes a ay
h 1 and three hours a
be the minimum for elementary sc 00 s
week for high schools. ..' the public schools- the
. The aims of physical tratnmg In
results for which it is held responsible, are.
( 1- Temporary relief from enforced qUIet.
( 2 Iimprovement of posture. . .
( 3 Development &#183; of general bodIly VIgor.
( 4 Improved functioning of the vital organs.
( 5) Social and moral training. . 1 ., g must
11 - d for physlca tramm
A part of the time a owe h h the day.
be devoted to temporary relief~ scattered t roug
THE NORMALITE
place in a completely integrated scheme of social economy.
In the evolution of schools there was first taken up those ed&#173;ucational
functions which the home could least well perform,
and naturally therefore school education has been tradition&#173;ally
cultural, because the home, the church , and the shop long
retained their efficiency as special educational agencies. But
it can hardly be questioned that physical, social, and vocation&#173;al
education are, in the order named, more important than
cultural education."
Administration of Education in The United States, pageg 426
The following resolutions were adopted at Atlantic City,
Feb. 28, 1918, by the assembled representatives of ninete ~ n
national organizations called together by the United States
Commissioner of Education, P. P. Claxton, to discuss, " The
Physical Welfare of Children in War Tilmes."
I. " That a comprehensive and thorough going program
of health education and physical education is absolutely need&#173;ed
for all boys and girls of elementary and secondary school
age, both rural and urban, in every state in the Union."
II. .
III. " That the United States Bureau of Education
should be empowered by law and provided by sufficient ap&#173;propriations
to exert adequate influence and supervision in
relation to a nation- wide program of instruction in health
and physical education."
IV. __ __ ._ .. .
V. " That federal recognition , superVISIOn and support
are urgently needed, as the effective means, under the con&#173;stitution,
to secure that universal training of boys and girls
in health and physical fitness which are equally essential to
efficiency of all citi; zens both in peace and war."
For many years Denmark, Switzerland, Germany, and
Sweden have made thorough physical training a regular part
of the curriculum in all schools. In the schools for boys in
England, where the leaders of Great Britain have been ed&#173;ucated,
ga1mes and physical sports have been given the same
importance and regularity as the cultural subjects. In France
in recent years the same attention has been given to it. In
the United States local conditions and interests have &#183; gov-
18
THE NORMALITE
dents' and before long everyone of ~ s
in the other stu NOR'MALITE means to us and we Will
pep , hat our b
will realtze w k ' t what it ought to e.
11 d o our part to ma e I Ie see we have a clean peppy
a f sboro peop , If the Mur ree . d d be ready to back us In any-
' 11 t behtn us an d hI' hoo1 they WI ge k W. hat town wants a dea sc 00 , sc t underta e. , We
thing we want 0 1 that will help the town to grow,
h want a schoO ' d' let's make Murfreesboro t ey Ie behtn us, so
need the town peopnd show them we've got plenty of pep, ,
d of M, T, N. a l' the game, on the Side
pro U We all have our part to pay, tn , and in all the activi-
.' ' n our class room, ' ,
line, in our socletl~ s, lIt's all join hands and pull together,
ties of the s. chool , s~ ~ est school anywhere! It's up to us!
L et'S make 1t the ve Y d - d' ' ded we fall!
'? U ' t d we stan, IVI NT
Will we do 1t. 111 e I an' " EVERY STUDE
And don't forget our s ~~ EVERY SCHOOL ACTIV-CONSCIENTIOUSLY
BACK _ DOROTHY LYON,
ITY," -
DREAMS
d
that come when life is young,
There are reams d '
And all the world one grand play- groun ,
1 d but. h surely seems,
They're on Y reams, b t they don't I've found,
They should come true- u '
There are castles built and painted gilt, ' d
By the joyful hands of a man a? d ma~ o e
They're filled with hope, but here s ~ y, r, d
Don't build a house, till the foundatton s a1 ,
d by parents staid
There are dreams that are rna e ,
For the children they hold on t, he1~ knee, ' 0
The girl and the boy, their h~ arts. pndel; n: efie: e me,
But they seldom come true tn th1s wor ,
d ' 11' hen we're gone So, the world goes on an WI, W .
With dreamls to keep hope ever gleamtng;
But I've come to know, and it's always , so,
That the best of a dream is the dreamEtnNgSHAW
- SARAH KEEBLE CR '
THE NORMALITE 20
Something of posture training can be accomplished in thi
part of the time by use of three- minute - drills. For develop
ing bodily vigor and improved action of the vital organs, a
hour a day or more is needed, but with thirty minutes a da
it is possible to teach activities that will not only help secur
the desired results but which the pupils can practice by them&#173;selves
out of school hours.
The aim of this Department is to give to those who g
out from this Institution as teachers, material that can b
used in their daily lesson plans along the lines of physical
training. This Department will give in each issue material to
be used in the primary grades as well as in higher grades.
It is absolutely essential that the bodily training of our
future citizens begin before they have acquired wrong hab&#173;its
in posture and in life which, may result in a permanent
handicap to the individual all his life.
The responsibility of right training rests on all teachers,
but a hundred- fold on the primary teacher, for
" As the man is, so was he trained in the beginning."
PEP
What is school pep? By the way, some students act
as if they thought the definition of pep was just to sit around
and hold their hands and let the rest of the bunch do all the
peppy things. Now what if each one of us felt that way
about it? Wouldn't we have fine foot- ball games, basket&#173;ball
games, base- ball games and other school activities? Wake
up, Bunch, and let's all get plenty of pep!
The main thing in winning the game is due to the pep of
the school, to its yells and songs, and showing the team we &#173;are
back of them. Of course they will fight harder to win
and show the bunch on the side lines that they can return
good for good by carrying our blue and white over .
A good way to put pep in our school is to advertise it
in our NORMALITE. Put it to the people so strong that
they can read pep and good school spirit in and between ev&#173;ery
line, Encourage every sfudent to start helping by put&#173;ting
something peppy and snappy into our magazine to arouse
Sitting by a cheerful fire one evening, I was deeply e~-
d l &#183; n the intricacies of a " Gwan- to- bed'" story, when m grosse .
E rnest with a look on his face that would have made came . . .
iobe look like Ben C. at the begmmng of vacatlOn.
" What's eating on you?" I growled. " Can't you see I'm
tudying? I've got to finish this thrilling artjc1e so that I
~ an read those two wonderful books everyone is going wild
about-' Tracked by a Female Detective' and ' Stolen from the
Altar.' I haven't got time to be fooling around; I'm going to
cultivate my mind."
" Aw, go on. You always did go in for that deep stuff.
I'm in trouble, old man. I've got to chatter on ' Tendencies of
Modern Literature' in English tomorrow."
" Ah! you have a wonderful subject, old thing," I ejacu&#173;ulated,
now wide awake. " Perhaps th. e greatest distinction
of modern literature is the ease with which the numerous
masterpieces are produced. Take Georgie Sheldon, for in&#173;stance.
A. L. Burt Company advertise forty- eight produc&#173;tions
from the remarkable pen of that talented writer, while
poor Hawthorne has only four novels to his credit. It took
Gray years to write his short " Elegy," but Masters comes
along with an intensely artistic, uplifting book of poems en&#173;titled
" Spoon River Anth. ology" and puts Gray into oblivion.
" And what's the secret? Gray bothered himselt with
rhyme and meter and carefully studied his thought; but the'
modern poet doesn't have to worry ~ bout rhymes, rhythm,
melody, or anything else- all he has to do is to divide his
words off into lines and begin each line with a capital. Sim&#173;ple
enough, which goes to show how ignorant the older so&#173;called
poets were not to think of it. Wouldn't Poe be de&#173;lighted
to see some of Amy Lowell's exquisite poetry, when
~ e was so highly pleased with the freedom Longfellow used
In his ' Evangeline?'
" This most reasonable VERS LIBRE movement is the
natural outcome of our remarkable age. We require liberty
today.. Why should poetry require meter and rhyme when
prose does not? Can't I - call a star a pearl, hair purest gold,
22
THE NORMALITE
. YOU IS OR YOU. AIN'T
You IS, or
You AIN'T.
I{ you AIN'T
You can't say'you IS.
If you IS,
You can't say you AIN'T.
You can't be partyl IS
And partly AIN'T.
Nor can you be
Wholly IS
And partly AIN'T,
Any more than you can
Be partly IS
And wholly AIN'T.
You just IS,
Or you AIN'T.
If you is a slacker
; ou AIN'T a N o: malite.
You can't be
Partly Normalite
And partly slacker
Nor can you be
Wholly slacker and
Partly N ormalite
Any more than y~ U can
Be wholly Normalite
And partly slacker.
. You just IS a Normalite
Or you AIN'T.
If you IS,
You lS.
If you AIN'T
You AIN'T. '
Which IS you?
Or AIN'T you?
- H. P. OGDEN.
THE NORMALITE
SHAKESPEARE SURPASSED!
23
or eyes blue as the sky in free verse as well as in the old
slavish style of Byron, Poe, Hugo, Milton, Goethe, Shake&#173;speare,
Dante" and Hornet? I think this idea should be ap&#173;plied
to music also.
. " I look for wonderful results from the fecundity of the
hra~ n~ of ~ ur ~ o~ er? geniuses. With such a lot of intensely
upltftmg, IdealIsttc hterature, voicing the faith, trust, purity,.
; a~ d. uns~ lfishness characteristic of the Imodern day, and in&#173;:
sttllmg Its potent essence into the American mind, we are
' Sure to at~ ain an ide~ l. state of civilization. By coming into
contact wIth the noblhty of theme, the purity of style, and
the culture of thought in such popular American books as
' In Love with a Liar,' ' His Seven Wives,' ' Love and a Lie,'
' From the Altar to the Poorhouse,' ' When Love Commands"
' Sweet Love's Atonement,' ' A Tortured Heart,' ' Twas Love'~
Fault,' ' Wedded by Fate,' and ' Paradise Almost' Lost' the
mind of the public will become so elevated that wing~ will
shortly appear on the shoulders of our pious fellow citizens!
" Why everyone reads now. The other t1igh4 I found
~ aul B. sit~ ing up after twelve perusing ' I Confess,' a maga&#173;zme
so typIcal of the purity of modern fiction. ~ In Love with
a Spaniard' has actually such wonderful characteristics that
it kept hi, m from his lessons. When children used to read
'~ ilgrim's Progress,' n() wonder they grew up to be duellists,
p~ rates and swashbucklers. Now- a- days, every child has at
hIS command the educational juveniles, such as ' Cootsy Coon's
Journey to Dreamland,' or ' Sammy Slow and Tilly Quick in
Moonsyville.' Or else, he may read Jesse James' or Zane
Grey's novels and see men made into sieves in real a la mode
style.
" And then the American public has the wonderful ad&#173;vantages
of the movies. When the future American citrzen
s: es t. he ? ero applauded for wrecking a train or decapitating
h. ls wI. fe 10 a decent style-,. we may be sure he is getting the
nght Ideas for guiding his moral existence.
" M . oreover, we find the modern short- stories so educa-tIOnal
and profound. The writers do not have to take the
trouble to think up a new plot now. They use the time- hon&#173;ored
one with new variations. John and Jim love Mary;
2S
24 THE NORMALITE THE NORMALITE
J h
n but John ha's five other wives. Mary kills
M ry loves 0 , .. b h d a . d marries John. Then Jim kIlls them ot, an
these WIves an . fi d . . g off Brooklyn Bridge. We sometimes n
nds by Jumpm . . e b f these wives to be seven or eight to gam ong-the
nurn Ser 0 fmes in movies the number may be still &#163; ur-
&#183; nality orne 1,' k f 1 &#8226; t d as in the case of Pharaoh, for the sa e 0 a
ther augmen e ,
nation- wide sensation. - .
" The great difference in value be: ween mo~ ern ~ Iterature
and old literature is shown by the differences 10 pnce. You
t 1
1 of Shakespeare's works for $ 2.35; but here comes
can ge a . . b k 1
H rold Bell Wright out of the west With hIS old 00 neat y
~ t d over and sells a million copies at about $ 2 a copy.
pam e, ' f11 f f I
' Main Street'- that wonderful creation so u 0 ~ rest u
influence on the mind seeking culture and entertainment&#173;flashes
up before the American man, a~ d has actually the
power to squeeze from him about two of hIS wonderful dollars
made in the : modern system of trade' 1
Plato was just an old fogey when he said a poet is born
and not made. Why, I see the ' Art of Versification' adver&#173;tised
for $ 1.75. It is a pity these instructors do not have time
to give us some real masterpieces. It would really h. e1p the
world so much. I hear that Carl Sandburg composes hIS poet&#173;ry
with a Ouija board. Don't tell anyone I told you, though,
because everybody would go to writing it, and he wouldn't
get more than $ 10 a line for the ' products of his genius.
" I saw a poem the other day which is so exemplary as a
typical modern day specimen that I committed it to memory.
' My handboy, Cupid, lays his thumb
On the electric button of your heart,
And peals a loud summons for answers to his presence;
And when, ah when, ah when,
Your mind arouses from its lethargy,
I t will send a vicarious plenipotentiary.
To welcome my servant.'
What a wonderful idea of love 1 How poor ' My love is
like a red, red rose' sounds in comparison!
" Well, Ernest, I hope you won't think I'm using fb. ttery
tonight. I hate mean servility in praise, but modern liter&#173;:
ature, especially poetry in its MODERN MANIFESTA-
- PHILIP MANKIN.
I AM A SOCRATES IN FACE
TIONS, is so ramarkable and so significant of the good civ&#173;ilization
we are now approaching that I never tire of praising
it as I have done tonight.
Well, good night, I'm tired of talking. I've got to read.
I'm going to read ' Hank Hawkins' Courtship for a Thir. &#173;teenth.
Wife, and go to bed."
THE NORMALITE 27
. PS. I AND BIOL II.
People are just dying to ride in a hearse.
They met on the bridge at midnight,
But never to meet again,
One was an east bound cow,
The other a west bound train.
Slang Translated
Blessed I &#183; S the student that sleepeth not in Biology II,
Nor forgetteth his number,. .
N misunderstandeth the questlOn,
or h . I
Nor sitteth in the seat of t e ~ Igg er. .
But his salvation is rememberm. g the dIfference between
Vorticella, Gregarina, and Gomulm.
And with this knowledge doth he create favor in the
eyes of Professor Davis. .. .
And he shall be an authority on Pandorma and EUdon~ a.
And whatsoever he answereth in class shall not be dIS-puted.
The idlers are not so;
Therefore, they sha11 not pass the test, nor be found in
the congregation of big " A's,"
For Prof. Davis knoweth the studious
But the paths of the idlers and disturbers shall be lined
with " e's" and " F's."
Our Motto: Always keep in front of a mule and back of
a gun.
If a cup is a mug and a mug is a face, I know a girl who
has a pretty loving- cup.
This is a dirty trick said the frog, turning a flip in the
mud.
Whether it is castor oil, twins, or trouble, the supplyal&#173;ways
exceeds the demand.
26 THE NORMALITE
Oft' I am asked how can thou live?
Cursed as thou art
As he only can give
That gives every man his part.
Cursed I am as he decrees
By his infinite grace
Forever to wear the face
Of a modern Socrates
But God gives to every man a prize
Some, sublime beauty, others the wit and
Wisdom of the wise.
To Ime he gave an overflow of brain
Such ~ s my head could not contain,
And he could not waste
So he beat them in and left the
Club prints on my face.
Finis
Composed to the tune of a silly grin
By Robert L. Partin
Assisted by The Divine Afflatus
Dedicated to. the memories from the mirror.
Mr. Wynn was walking down the street concentrated
on his class in Education VIII. He stepped off into the gutter
with one foot but continued walking unconscious of the fact.
He met Mr. Sims who asked him how he felt.
" I felt fine when I left home he replied, but
Lave developed a limp in my left leg."
WANTED- To know why Mr. Hams moved his place
in the dining hall to sit next to Gladys Bond.
EDITORIAL
THE NORMALITE 29
. ' Ne have jnst begun what promises to be the best year
Editorial Staff
CYRUS DEMENT Editor- in- Ch~ ef'
ELIZABETH GRIGSBY Associate Editor- in- Ch~ ef
E. P. EAVES Athl~ l~
ROBERT PARTIN Y. M..
MARGARET WATSON Faculty
HANNAH GRAHAM BELCHER Locals, Fun
T. E. CLARK Societies, Lyceum
MARY HILL KING Exchange
HESTER ROGERS Alumni
GERALDINE GRIGSBY Y. W. C. A., Glee Club
. Buainess Staff
]. E. WINDROW Business Manager
CARL E. BRANDON Associate Business Manager
: MILDRED RIDLEY Associate Business Manager
W. T. WYNN FacultyAdviser
Application made for entry as second- c1
f
as
C
s matter II ~~ ~ ol~ 7~ ice at
Murfreesboro, Tenn., under Act 0 ongress, a , .
. Monthl by the students of Middle Tennessee Normal, Mur-publtshed
Y freesboro, Tennessee
. t' to Business Manager. Advertising rates
Add all communtca lOns .
. ress furnished upon request. .
FROM THE ETUDE
THE NORMALITE
I
am
sure
that
matiy
of you
have often
heard that very
famous old say-'
ing concerning the
fact that there
is always plenty of
room at the top. But
you know this is only
partly true, because there
is plenty of room at the
top for just a few of the
very best, while all of the
others, must, of course, find
their places down below. If
you are one of the very best, or .
at least if you are going to be one
of the very best when your time
comes, whether it be violinist, singer or
pianist or whatever you choose, you
will be able to find a place at or near
the top. If you are going to be better than
the best you will find a great plenty of room
at the top with no one else there to crowd
you. But you know it is a long hard pull and
there is no time like the present to make a start
on your upward climb. So here is wishing you
success and- a happy time when you reach your goal.
- GLEE CLUB.
28
' In the new yells you sho~ tld hear Miss Monohan " ROAR."
31
THE NORMALITE
HITS, RUNS, AND ERRORS
. d t' " so ordinary." Yes, Mrs. Barbee says nOIsy con uc IS
we notice it in, the dining hall.
11 f L' ' s dates for the George Bates hasn't cornered a 0 OUlse
year. She's opposed to monopolies. ' ld
Gladys and he have made up again. We knew they wou
from past experience.
Only one bed- bug has been caught in ' the new dormitory.
' d barrassment all engaged Caps suggests that to avOl em
o- irls should wear some sort of elmlblem. b
. is not required in a
No, Algernon, a mowing machme
campus course.
time chapel closed on time.
Once upon a
. . German marks is offered to the
A prize of ~ eve;:;~~:: est dress on Hallowe'en night.
i\ 1T girl weanng ,
rns us against eating raw meat. Won t
Physiology wa b . ham and peas on Sunday?
&#183; &#183; te a book anl11ng
omeone WI I .'
. me one told a joke whICh nobody m
Once upon a tIme so .
d had heard gefore. the croW __--
Here's a fresh one: h d man and
Go
d made the world and rested; he t en r: r a e
h
de woman since when neIther God nor
rested; then e ma '
man has rested.
t of a yarn spinning contest.
Announcemen P f Wynn Davis, and Irvin Cobb.
Contestants: ro s. ,
First prize to be given for the oldest y:. r~ has been told
Second prize to be given for the yarn w lC
oftenest to the same crowd.
A
. time M- is- s- S- a- u- n- d- ers admitted that the sing-gam
upon a
ing in chapel was pretty good.
THE NORMALITE
in the history of M. T. N. The manner in which the student
body has taken up the work of the year and the spirit shown
in doing this work strengthen our belief that the signs of the
time are being read aright.
In like manner we are - most optimistic over the prospects
for THE NORMALITE this year. We have been able to get
out the first issue up to the standard and on time. We wish
to express our appreciation to the student body for the hear&#173;ty
cooperation which has made this possible. You have in&#173;deed
done your part toward making this issue what we want
it to be. As the year passes let us continue to work togeth&#173;er
to make each issue a little better than the one before. It
is up to you. Continue as you have begun and we have no
fears as to the result.
Remember this is your magazine. You will make it what
it is to be. Its success is your success; its failure will be your
failure. It is your school spirit expressed in material form.
If your school loyalty is something big, then THE NORMAL&#173;ITE
will be something big. Are you interested in something?
Can you interest others in that thing? Then write it up for
THE NORMALITE. Look about you for material. The dai&#173;ly
life of the school is full of &#183; material suitable for these pages.
J\ vail yourself of this material and write it up in readable
form. If you haven't something new to write about, give us
something old in a new and original way. Lowell said,
" Though old the thought and oft' exprest, ' Tis his at last who
says it best."
And don't forget the little blue and white box in the hall&#173;way
patiently waiting to receive your contributions. It is an
even bet as to whether the box or the editor receives the
greater thrill as a manuscript is dropped into the box. Rest
assured that the box receives the shorter one, for instinct
seems to tell the editor when there is a treasure awaiting
him. Or perhaps it is the glad expression of the box that be&#173;trays
its secret and leads , the editor to turn the Woolworth
lock and rob the faithful little box of its prize. But we can't
be thrilled too often. We hope you are from Missouri.
30
32
The masses of humanity are eager for the opportunity
to listen to genuine, earnest and forceful speakers who can
bring to their attention such information as will furnish them
with food for thought. No accomplishment along the lines
of the teaching profession is more desirable, or will enhance
one's tact and ability as leader of his community, than that
of public speaking.
New students, with this in view, the Claxton Literary
Society is at your service. It endeavors to offer to all mem&#173;bers
the best opportunity to develop their oratorical talents,
whether outstanding or latent. Gentlemen, if you would get
your moneyjs worth at the Nmmial you will identify your-self
with one or the other of the Societies.
The Dromgooles andClaxtons gave their usual joint pro&#173;gram
at the first meeting o'f the Fall Term. Addresses of
welcome were delivered by the presidents of both Societies.
The program consisted of readings, dialogues, musical num&#173;bers,
and contests followed by refreshments and social hour.
A large crowd was present and all sitting and standing room
was taken.' .
The Claxton Society ~ et in its first regular sessi() n Oct.
3. After the usual opening service the regular work was ta-ken
up. .
As the last congress did not settle the bonus question
THE NORMALITE
Let us hope he hasn't received Noah's instructions abo t h
duty. u
Had you heard about the NORMALITE? W h ' d . d . e t oug
we Just rop a hint; may be you'd like t d . the box. 0 rop an arttcle
~ he boys must be on time to fill their " dates" at the irl
dormItory. Otherwise nothing will be there to fill th g em.
It is rumored that. our foot ball team went to Bowlin
?" reen. Perh. aps they dId. We've heard a lot. about the Bo
mg Green gIrlS lately. w
Wooh: orth made another sale recently. Misses Schardt
and Fontame are wearing new ornaments on their ears.
Duck has had an operation on his nose. Trying to chang
your quack , Edward?
Carl Brandon says it is five miles to town when a fello
walk. s alone, but only a half mlile when measuring steps wit
a chIcken. .
. Somebody tell Eddie Burns how many fire engines in th
cIty.
Household Hints for Misaea Margaret Ward, Louise TempI
ton and Elizabeth Grigsby:
1. To entertain men, feed the brutes.
2. To keep servan. ts chloroform and lock in the cellar.
. 3. To prevent accIdents in ~ he kitchen fill the ' kerosene
wIth water.
4. To get rid of peddlers buy all they have.
. S. To make biscuits light drench with gasolene and ig-mte
before serving.
Here's to Mary Frances Bray,
The tiniest member of the class.
She was drinking lemonade one day,
And fell heels over he' 4d i~ the glass.
THE NORMALITE
Claxto. Society- T. E. Clark, Editor
33
Dromgoole Society
THE NORMALITE 35
MURFREE SOCIETY
The Murfree Society bega'n its program for the year
with a joint meeting of the Grady arid Murfree Societies. An
entertaining program was given with participants from each
society. After the progra~ a social hour was enjoyed and a
hearty welcome was given the new students.
On the second Tuesday afternoon : miembers of the Mu~ &#173;free
Society enjoyed a debate, " Resolved that a campus course
should be given." All students will be interested to know that
the affirmative won.
The Murfree Society has had many visitors and pros-
Grady Literary Society
On September 26, the Grady Literary Society entered
upon another year's work with a joint program and social
hour with the Murfrees. The officers elected for the Fall
Term are as follows: Paul Eaves, President; Philip Mankin,
Vice- President; George Bates, Secretary; Ben Chrisman,
Treasure~; E. S. Ford, Chaplain; Paul Burton, Sergeant- at&#173;Arms;
Bruce Overton, Critic; F. F. Pollock, Theodorics.
It is our intention this year to make the Grady Society a
prominent element in the life of the student and of the whole
school. We wish at all times to make our society spirit work
for the good of the school as a whole and to cooperate with
other school features so as to make school life more pleasant,
more profitable, and more complete. Our desire is to supply
the student with educational factors not easily or pqssibly
acquired elsewhere, but which go to make up a broader and
fuller character. Some of these are cooperation, fellowship,
inf~ rmation, ability to speak sanely and creditably before a
public audience and to conduct publiC meetings; and a keen,
sportsman- like rivalry with. our rival society, always tending
to the highest quality of work and stimulating to the great&#173;est
measure of honest and spirited effort. The Grady goal
is to perform a type of work which will live and be condu&#173;cive
to the best results in the impressions wrought into the
characters of those connected therewith.
34 THE NORMALITE
satisfactorily to all concerned it was decided to give the Clax
ton orators a chance. After four excellent speeches tw
" iur" . and. two " ag. m" the ach. on of our last congress on' thi
questton, . It was decided that the bill should have been passe
thus makmg our w~ r heroes unlike the Ford car in that they
would have somethmg to run on other than past reputation.
Other subjects of note are in store such as the stri&#173;question,
the labor question, and imlmfigration question. So
of these will likely be used for our new members to cut the
" Society teeth" on. Watch the program and see what's goin
to happen next.
Realizing that it is " the early birds
worms," and that we must " become fixed in our habits a
early as possible," a large majority of the new girls have fall&#173;en
in line with the Dromgooles and are ready for work.
. . The first meeting of this tf; rm was a very interseting
Jomt program between the Dromgoole and Claxton Societies.
After the program a very pleasant hour was spent in contests
in which everybody became acquainted. Refreshments were
another interesting feature of the afternoon.
A number of former Dromgoole members are back' thi
term and they are always glad to speak a good word for th
~ romgooles: At our regular . meeting last Tuesday the pres
Ident asked If there were those present who would like to sa
something for the society. A number of former member
made improm\ ptu sp~ eches about other Dromgoole days. W
mean to make this year just a little better than any that ha
ever been. .
If you have not already lined up with one of the socie
ties do so immediately and let it be the Dromgoole. We bi
you welcome; and as work is the greatest panacea for hom
sickness we promise to keep you so pleasantly engaged th
there ' won't be time for you to get homesick.
We are just a great big family of sisters, having a goo
time while we are busy at improving our minds, and we ar
glad to add you to our family.
Mr. Brackin :-" What is an allegory, Miss Murphy?"
. Miss Murphy, eager to display her knowledge :-" An al
leg~ ry is animal that lives in the swamps of Florida."
Familiar Saying. on the Campua
1 haven't cracked a book yet.
I'll bust you.
There's some one in this class who isn't here.
Gosh Ding!
Isn't he just too cute, for anything.
Git for home Bruno.
THE NORMALITE 37
Margaret Wabon, Editor.
Mr. Lyon mayor , may not have been born great, that is
not for us to decide, but this we do know, he certainly has
achieved greatness and also had greatness thrust upon .. him.
Mr. Holmes still holds the Normal purse strings.
The McDonald sisters are again clkking the typewriteJ&#173;for
the president and for the dean.
Miss Tommie Reynolds ran away to Europe this summer
and although she enjoyed her trip immensely, she says there's
no place like M. T. N.
Mother Rutledge is back at her post and says she may be
a bit off in the knee but she's all right in the head.
Mrs. Gillentine says sh, e has traveled all over Tennessee,
from one end of th. e state to the other. That was &#183; her va&#173;cation.
, Mr.. and Mrs. Woodward spent their vacation in Indiana.
. Miss Fontaine certainly. was rewarded for her energy
expended in the Art Department when " Our Nor~ al" won the
first prize in &#183; the Normal School Art ~ hibit at the State Fair.
Among the exciting things that Miss &#183; Schardt did this
summer she says there is one thing she learned to do and
35 THE NORMALITE
p"' ctive members at their meetings. They hope to increas
&lt;:,..:; r number having q~ ality as well as quantity to make th
term a successful one. Come and join us and help us whil
we help you. We need each other.
The following officers have been elected for
Term:
President- Ruth Kelton.
Vice President- Grace Daniels.
Secretary- Clara Sawyer.
Treasurer- Margaret Ward.
Critic- Mary Hill King.
Chaplain- Vera Williams.
Sergeant- at- Arms- Gladys Howard.
Mr. Ogden :-" Mr. Miller, why do hens lay eggs in
daytime ?"
Cy Miller :-" Because they are roosters at night."
Geo. Bates, answering a &#183; question in Ed.: " God
but I don't." ,
Mrs. Gillentine :-" Then God gets the credit."
Mrs. Lyon :-" 1 want to register to vote."
Clerk :-" What is your occupation?"
Mrs. Lyon :-" 1 haven't any."
Mr. Lyon :-" Yes, she has; she's my manager." .
And the Clerk forthwith wrote, " Manager of the Norma
School." .
39 THE NORMALITE
Coach Miles :-" I've heen trying every way &#183; in the world
to get married."
Azilee :-" Well so far you haven't."
Coach :-" Let's us get married." -
Azilee :-" I'd like to know who would have us."
New Student, -~ xalmining course card: " What ar~ these
numbers for on the right side?"
Senior :-" They are numbers of rooms." - - -
N. S. :-" There are five numbers; I didn't know I was to
have but one room."
Hatley, in Music I :-" But- Miss Saunders l- er; I,- you, I
don't-" "
Miss Saunders :-" Aw, shut up you're as fussy as Old
Burton."
h 11
' n the intermediate grades and Miss Anne prd&#173;J{
Mars a 1
. . the upper grades. .
way In h M Wynn is very busy with all the dutIes of
Althoug r. E S ff
. h I'll finds time to help THE NORMALIT ta
his offIce e s 1 &#8226;
henever they need It. .'
w . M f ee still reigns supreme 10 the hbrarx &#183;
MISS ur r , D ' t
Mr. and : Mrs. Gracy have charge of the Boys orml ory
this f~: rFaculty was delightfully entertained with a . char~ ing
W d sday September 27, by the Domesttc SClen(" 2
1 ncheon, e ne , . k'
u t Miss Williams, our new instructor 10 coo 109,
Departmen . " Th h
1
believes in an old saying revised thus, at t e way
sure Y h h' t hs " to the Faculty's heart is throug t elr s omac .
Mr. Belcher :-" Who was that laughed aloud?"
Student :-" It was I, Sir." "."
M B" I h r :-" You should laugh in your sleeve 10 class. r. e c e . . "
Student :-" 1 did, but my sleeve had a hole 10 It.
Ruth Lee :- I'Since the boy's donmitory has been built
the girls can't see the sun rise." -
Paul Burton :-" But you can look toward the east and
see the sons rise."
THE NORMALITE J8
that was to make a speech, the occasion being at Springfiel
school opening. --
Miss Buchanan reports an enjoyable vacation spent with
her home folks.
Miss Monohan gets younger looking all the while. That
must be due to her return to the Normal.
Miss Saunders is just as musical as ever. She and Miss
Shepherd, our new violin- instructor, are planning quite a mu-sical
year for M. T. N. -
Miss Little is like a candle, whether her vacation is long
&lt;&gt; r short, the longer she stands, the " Littler" she grows.
Mr. Davis spent his vacation in the bookstore.
Mr. Belcher turned time backward a bit by visiting the
scenes of his childhood in Georgia.
Mr. Brackin took a course at Peabody and then went on
a camping trip. He is very much elated over Vandy's Sta&#173;dium
at present.
History teachers must be like circuit riders. It seems
that ours come from Louisiana and go to Michigan. Mr.
Sims talks about Louisiana almost as much as Mr. Moody did.
It is generally understood that Mr. Ogden is very much
opposed to the adoption of the Campus Course simply because
were it required all the grass and hay on the campus would
soon wear off. - "
Coach Miles is training his team to win the next games
this year even ifVandy defeated us. .
Miss Louella Wilson, a former student, is our new physi&#173;cal
training director and plans great things when the new
gym is ready.
Mr. Horace Jones has quite a troop of sold~ ers in hi~ de&#173;partment
this year.
Dr. and Mrs. Fertig spent their vacation in California.
Mrs. Barbee is s. till in the best of spirits. Her onl
thought being to get enough prepared so that everybody has
plenty to ~ at. -
The Model School has the same efficient critic teachers
this year as last. We are indeed fortunate in having Miss
Mamie Jackson as instructor in the primary grades; Mrs. J.
41
THE NORMALITE
HOME ECONOMICS CLUB
' Tis better to have loved and lost
Than to have married and been bossed.
Quizzes to quizzes and quizzes to dust
If quizzes don't get me the final must.
Mrs. T. E. Clark, President
The Home Economics Department is presenting a m. ost
pleasing appeara~ c~ in her new. ad?~ nments. The beautIful
cabinet conslstmg of forty mdIvldual lockers and ample
neW . . . d h
e f
or hanging &#183; garments, whIle In constructIOn an w en
spac .' .
finished, adds greatly to the convenience of the Do\ mestIc Art
classes; and the splendid new sewing machines make the
work much lighter.
Another addition to the department is the practice house,
soon to be completed. This house is to be occupied by a
different group of girls each quarter. The group will live as
a family, practicing the arts of household man &#183; agement in.
the most practical and scientific way.
A Home Economics &#183; Club has been organized with a large
enrollment.. Much interest is displayed and an interesting and
instructive program has been planed for the coming year.
The officers of the organization are as follows : Mrs.
T. E. Clark, President; Vera Williams, Vice President; Nelle
Twitty, Secretary; Gladys Bond, Treasurer; Hortense Crab-tree,
Sergeant- at- Aflms.
On Sept. 27 the faculty was delightfully entertained
with an informal luncheon.
Among the other social events of the season, was a re-ception
on Oct. 6, given by the household management class
to the domestic art and domestic science classes. A rather
unique contest was the source of much amusement. The very
valuable priEe was won by Miss Mildred Orr. After the con-test
an ice course was served.
With the new equipment, unusual interest in the work,
and our able instructors, Miss Little and Miss Williams, we
are anticipating a very successful year's work.
THE NORMALITE
~/~
,-"~~""",,,_-"'''''--''~__~. J ~- -..::( J,~ tA
Pe~ ple of . all tastes, dispositions , and professions can fin
somethmg to mterest them in our chapel talks If itb t
that" van. ety I. S the spice of life," then &#183; every . student aet rthu
Normal ? as an opportunity to lead a highly seasoned exis
ence.
. &#8226; ~ t different times during the past month we have bee
InspIred by interesting talks by the ministers of tow
Messrs. H3. lmpton, Gray, Anderson and Coleman have evince
a . de~ p ~ nte. rest in us and our school. We give them a cor
dIal Invitation to visit us again.
. A Utalk" set to musI. c was the contribution of Miss Kath-enne
Johnson. Her delightful presentation of several vocal
selections furnished a most enjoyable chapel program.
" Lutu.. ImpreuioDa"
He gently took her in his arms'
He pressed her to his breast- '
The lovely color left her cheeks
And lodged upon his vest.
- GEORGIA L. PINKERTON, ( By &#183; permission and apology).
. Mrs. Gillentine :- uHortense, please go outside and brin
us a sample of a horse's mane." . .. .
Hortense on her return-" That horse kicked so I couldtt
get part of his mane." .
Mrs.. Gillentine :,:,,- uWhere did you try to get it?"
Hortense :~( CWhy, off of his side, of course."
40
43
THE NOR),{ ALITE
Hannah Graham Belcher, &#163; dito,
d faculty had a rare treat and op-
The student body an h &#183; b &#183; t sent out by Frank
. h f rm of an art ex 1 1 h &#183; b &#183; t
Portunity In teO . d A 1 &#183; d Arts. The ex 1 1 , S h 01 of Fme an pp Ie .
Alva Parson s c o. . I designing costume deslgn-d
fork In commercIa ' d &#183; ly
consiste ? w. . The charts were excee mg
ing and Intenor decoratlOn. &#183; 1 f Mr Parsons who
int~ resting and were made by. the pUPI so &#183;
lectured here early in the spnng.
- .. rin the long- suffering male
At last wIth a tnumphant g h ld red their knapsacks
It &#183; have s ou e
element of our popu a 10~. &#8226; th ut one backward glance
and invaded the new dormItory WI 0
a t the old Moffit Hall. .
---.-.- the day when the new
All are impatiently awaltmg me of basket ball
. ltd nd we can have a ga -
gym wIll be comp e ea. n the spectators. .
without danger of casualties almo g. .
- - tl disappointed when they
Many students were grea. Yd. b t Mr Sims his able
M M dy had reslgne , u . , h d
learned that r. 00 t &#183; t that they have a
and much- liked successor, has seen. 0 1 _
very little spare time in which to gneve. _
charming addition in the person of
The faculty h~ s had a. h hysical training.
Miss Wilson who 1S conductmg t e p .
. it the Normal i'elt a thrill of
Every person connected Wit .'-
THE NORMALITE
. Why he ahouldn't have a chance to make the ball team.
F - ierce lessons
L- ate hours
U- nexpected tests
N - othing prepared
K- nocking at your door.
A new dish is being se. rved in the dining hall called " Rice&#173;a-
la- scraps." The recipe is _ simple. Scrape the table over a
dish of cold rice. ~ erve _ after three ~ ays without stirring.
" Tubby" &#183; Howard says Coach will have to let three girls
hold him in the games; two can't reach around him.
T. E. Clark, Editor
For the past several- years this school has been peculiarly
fortunate in having each year some five or. six lyceum pro&#173;grams
which are. equal to the best of the programs rendered
by the Lyceum Companies. The p. rogram for this year is not
yet complete and there1' ore it is impossible to announce in
this issue of THE NORMALITE the exact dates of the pro&#173;grams.
We are assured, however, of five numbers for this
year. These numbers, which will consist of perhaps two lec&#173;tures
and three musical programs, will be presented by the
best talent the country can afford.
Look for the announcements in the next issue of the
rmagazine.
42
45
THE NORMALITE
WHY STUDY PUBLIC SCHOOL MUSIC?
and intellectual value of the study of ~ usic
The cultura:
1
knowledged by leading educators 10 all
. today genera y ac
15 h untry
parts of t e co ' t . League has seen fit to adopt the follow-
The Commum Y
. g creed: I
lU ,.' necessity not a uxury. 1 MusIC IS a , . .
, h'ld has an inherent nght to mUSIC.
2. Every c 1 h .. means to civic i1mprovement.
3, Unity throug mUSIC IS a .
p triotism is developed by mUSIC. d .
4. a,. d h'p regardless of race or cree , 15 s. Sp1nt of comra . es 1 ,
induced by mUSIC. - . k
, ' most useful in constructlOn wor . .
6. MUSIC IS higher form of citizenshIp,
7. Music tends to encoulrage at. for mental moral, and
Music is a powedu cur~ 1ve , 8.
physical ailments. . h most use-ic
being the universal language 1S t e
9. Mus h d &#183; the Americanization move1ment.
ful means ~ t an 10 betterment of a community,
Since these th10gs lead t~ a to foster this development
it is the work of the teac er
through the children of the school. d quate knowledge of the
To do this she must have an t
a
e I the theory of music,
subject; she must understand n~ on. y . d learn-but
be able to help children in hsteIl1n g to mUS1C an
ing of the composer and his wodrk. beautiful piece of music
Who can thoughtfully stu y a . without
as a bit of literature and then give it self- express
lOn
- d &#183; &#183; t 11 benefitted j) being morally an sp1n ua Yd &#183; t her that she be
It cannot be demanded of the ~ ra e h ea. c lled upon to
a specialist in all of the different hnes s e 1S ca -. b &#183; l &#183; ty
blance of natIve a 1 1 ,
teach but she imay have some sem .' t dy
, h bTt by senouS s u .
musically, and supplement suc ~~. 1iA. AY SAUNDERS.
mE NORMA1. ITE
Miss Williams, the new Domestic Science teacher, won
instant popularity among the faculty when she gave them a
luncheon September 29. The student body isn't entirely proof
against such tactics.
pride when it was announced that our art department ha
won first prize among the Normal exhibits at the State Fair.
The Girl's Glee Club met for the first time Oct. 2, and
perfected its organizations. Plans for the work were dis&#173;cussed
and everyone is looking forward to a successful year.
1
Another honor has come to our worthy and much- hon&#173;ored
M. T. N. This time, it is through the poultry depart&#173;hlent.
Mr. Gracey carried off prizes in the State Fair and in
the lo~ al show here..
The science department offers better opportunity for
laboratory work this year than ever before in its history
This is due to the fact that a large Cllmount of new chemical
supplies and apparatus has been received.
Middle Tennessee Normal has had a stirring revival- an
old- fashioned camp meetin'. The opening sermon was preach&#173;ed
by Rev. Cyrus Dement in the old Normal meetin' house on
October 11. His sermon appealed to all backsliders to re&#173;pent
of their sins and become inflated with Pep. His remarks
were followed by exhortations ftom Deacon - Windrow and
Sisters Grigsby and Bond. Immediately the mourners bega
to confess. Everyone got religion. The meeting continue
on Thursday and Friday with splendid results. The reviva
has brought all believers to a realization - that " PEP" is the
only means of salvation for the Normal.
44
Prof. Sims :- When' did the revival of learning begin'?
Setliff- Just before Exams.
Huffiness ( reciting in History X): " When this soldier
landed in New York he was bust-, burst-, bust-, burst.
Aw, I guess. he was busted."
,- g'to know or too old
A man marries when he s too youn -
to care.
. h- en sh- e's too kind to look or too A woman marnes w " ,
blind to see.
47
THE NORMALITE
Mr. Clifford Stark, ' 20, is attending Peabody this year.
Mr. Rupert Smith, ' 21, whom so many know not only as a
Normal athletic star, but as a Vanderbilt star as well, is now
Coach at Springfield, Tenn.
Miss . Mary Burton, ' 18, who late last summer became
Mrs. Bill Mason, is now living in Johnson City, Tenn.
From the large number of Alumni who are in attendance
at the Normal this year with the view of doing further study,
:", e judge that the vision of higher education and better things
IS being caught. .
}. iis
s
Carrie. ' 21, is t. eaching music in her home town, Harts&#173;ville.
Mrs. Harvey Pearcy visited us the 30th. She is pleasant-ly
remembered as }. iiss Mary Elizabeth Davis.
Miss Ruby Harris is now teaching in Chattanooga:
Mr. Jackson Batey ' 21 is attending U. T. and expects to
finish the University work this year.
J eanetta Edwards ' 21 is also back at her place in the city
schools of Chattanooga.
Mr. ~. H. Wheeler ' 20 is principal of school at Athens,
Tenn. Mr. N1. P. Hayes ' 18 now holds a very responsible posi-tion
with the Students Educational Publishing Co., as sales-manager.
Misses Aliene McDearman ' 21 and Alice Johnson ' 18 are
at U. T. this year.
Mr. Ralph Shelton is at Stanton, Tenn., principal of the
school at that place.
NEss Beulah Coleman ' 18 and Miss Sara Reeves ' 19 are
now at their post of duty at Snoddy, after a very interesting
summer trip through many of the noted cities of the East.
Mr. I- larry Lee Page, ' 17, who was a well known orator
while'in this school, is now a prominent lawyer in Gaines-horo,
Tenn.
Miss Elizabeth Rosson, ' 17, has charge of the County
Demonstration work in a number of counties near Roanoke,
Va.
THE NORMALITE 46
Heater Rogers, Editor
. We are glad to note that M C
him a corps of teachers from M ;. N' M. Elmore took wit
Margaret Ward Kathleen S d . . to Hurstburg. Misse
Clara Harris They d . an ers, Mildred Copenhaver
Miss '. are omg splendid work
Valhe Rosson, a graduate of ' 21 ' ..
week- end recently Sh . ' vIsIted us on
M' . e IS now attending Peabod
ISS Esther Jackson is teachin on L y.
Miss Margaret Crick' t ? ookout Mountain.
Richard City. IS eachmg Domestic Science a
Miss Le . J S nme ane anders is at Richard Cit .
Mr. Frank Bass now P' . I yagam. , nnclpa of the Fa' S
came down to the State F . d rmmgton chool
see us" air an accidentally came over t
Mr. Willia1m Beasley is teach' . M M' Ing maury Co t
C
ISS Dora Cooper is teaching near her hom un y.
ounty. e
William and V' t K IC or eene are now att d' P
Miss Isabel Anderson ' 19 . . en mg eabody.
Michigan. IS now domg scout work in
Mr. Fred Brandon is at L . C' .
ual Arts in the city h' h h- e1nOlr Ity, instructor of Man-
. Ig SC 00.
MIss Mary Jane Alexander ' 20 . ..
this year in Columbia U. . ' , IS contmumg her study
. mverslty.
MISS Alma Browning ' 19' h' teacher in a Normal S h ' I .' IS t IS year acting as critic
c 00 m South Carolina. Her sister
49 THE NORMALITE
nroll a large number of the boys before the campaign to e .
I es The athletic department has plans to prOVide sports cos .
. volley ball, basket ball, baseball, tennis and other sports.
~ ther plans for the welfare of the boys will be made from
time to time and in this way we hope the " Y" will prove its
value to the young men students who will go out as teachers
of the young , men of this and other states.
The State Y. M. C. A. Student Secretary has been with
us twice in our meetings and promises us to be of much ser&#173;vice
during the year. He told us of his recent survey trip to
Europe in the interest of the Student Y. M. C. A. and gave
a live and interesting account of the conditions in the war
infested regions of European Countries. On this second visit
to us he inspired the " Y" boys with an outline of the purposes
and possibilities of the " Y." He also told us that we have
the best planned program of any organization of the state
which he has visited. It is up to the young men to put this
prograJm over, so come and join hands with us and help us
while you are being helped by us.
" Gentlemen of the Jury: My task is very easy. The ac&#173;cused
has confessed; a defense is impossible; and yet I want
to add a few words. There on the wall I see a picture of the
Crucified and I pay homage to it. There it hangs in this hall
of justice where you condemn the guilty. But why do we
not hear anything of Him in our schools? Why does Sandot,
the murderer, for the first time see this picture in the hall
where the law will punish him?
If the attention of my client had been directed to the
Crucified while he still sat on the benches of the school he
would not sit here on the bench of disgrace and infamy. You
brag of your culture, and yet are barbarous; you spread athe&#173;ism
and lustfulness among the people and yet are astonished
When the people reply with crime and vulgarity.
- Contributed by the Y. 1- 1. C. A.
A FRENCH LAWYER'S ADDRESS TO A JURY
Troubles are like babies, only grow larger thru nursing.
THE NORMALITE
48
Robert Partin, Editor.
" Study to show thyself a rov
that need not be ashamed P? h led ~ n. t~ God, a workman
Truth." , fIg t Y dIVIdIng the Word of
The y~ M. C. A. sent the I .
Ridge Conference last year that~ gest delegatIon to the Blue
school. Our five dele t k as ever been sent from this
ga es too an at' .
and activities of the conf f c Ive part In the . work
erence rom urn .. b
and doing diving stunts tId' . ~ lrIng aseball games
religious work The to ea Ing In BIble study and other
. . y re urned to s h I
co. nference with message f h c 00 at the close of the
soc eer and' . .
coming year of " y" k 0 InSpIratIOn for the in-wor.
ne of our d I
ner, was selected to ser h e egates, Edwin Shof-ve
on testate .
he was not able to return to h I h' commIttee, but since
has been selected to serve 0 StCh'
oO
t IS. year, John C. Cook o n IS commIttee
Ur organization took u - it .
week of school wI'th I't . PI s work promptly the first
s regu ar Thur d .
and began making plans for th ' s ay evenIng meeting
efficient cabinet has been selec: e~ e~ tshwork. A complete &#183; and
of all the departments PI h good men at the head
work of the year. Thes' I ans. ave been completed for the
which has already b e pans . Include regular morning watch
een , meetIng on h fl dormitory ever . . eac Oor of the boys'
ly Bible study ~ amsSornIngd' Plans are completed for the week-f
es un er a compete tId or large atte d n ea er and we hope
n ance at these classes
The b . .
mem ershlp campaign is in full .
SWIng and we expect
THE NORMALITE 51
Mary Hill King, Editor.
Our exchanges last year were both a delight and an in&#173;spiration;
doubly so because it was the NORMALITE'S first
We sI'ncerely trust that we shall be able to greet
season.
r: u this year with a bigger and a better NORMALITE. Dur- g our first year we felt that we gave nothing and took much
from the exchanges that came to us. This year we hope to
give as well as to take. We desire to thank each and every
one of our exchanges for their able support last year, and we
hope that each of your publications will appear ~ n our desk
this year.. Weare also anxious to extend our hst to other
schools.
Already each of the following schools have sent in a copy
of their publication: " The Antelope" from Kearney, Nebras&#173;ka;
" The Pleiad" from Albion, Michigan; and " The Student"
from Warrensburg, Missouri.
We wish to call attention of the students to the Exchange
Table in the library and we invite you to look over the pub&#173;lications
which come to us from other schools.
Sam's girl is tall and slender,
My girl is fat. and low.
SaJm's girl wears silks and satins,
My girl wears calico.
Sam's girl is fast and speedy,
My girl is pure and good,. ",:
Do you think I'd swap my gIrl for Sam s gIrl
You know darn well I would.- Ex.
THE NOR- [ ALITE .
Geraldine Grigsby, &#183; Editor.
A large number of the boys in the dormitory are from
dairy farms. They still have the habit of arising at the early
milking hour...
September 18, found most all of our Y. \ V. girls smilin
brightly over the campus and ready for the year's work an
the problems before them. Quite a few of our cabinet wer
not permitted to be back in our midst but we hope to suppl
their va~ ancies in the near future, for we have many efficien
and capable girls alm'ong us.
We have had our regular Wednesday night services, on
of ' which was with the Y. IV1. when their State Student Sec&#173;retary
was present. Our service of October 5 was most im&#173;pressive,
being our rceognition &#183; service in which over forty
girls gave themselves to the cause and work of this Christian
organization.
The Y. W. C. A. is looking ahead to greater and higher
things, and more especially since Mrs. Rutledge and Mrs.
Fertig are back with us we feel no~ hing can stand in our way.
Miss Williams had been telling her pupils about the dis&#173;covery
of America and ended saying, " All this happened over
four hundred years ago."
One of her pupils looked rather startled then said, " Gee!
but you sure have a good memory."
.50
52 THE NORMALITE THE NORMALITE 53
E. P. Eaves, Editor.
Prospects for a foot ball team .
ly good at M. T. N. this fall of firs~ rank are unusu
squad of big, stalwart husk' Coach Mt1~ s has corralle
ing in the fundamental~ of t[ fellows, wIth proper tra
strong and powerful el ep
ga~ e, should develop into
. even. ractIcally th . .
team is made up of e entIre Varsl
. . . new men, many of wh h
tIcIpated in this r f om ave never pa
Miles has had a I: i~~ ul~ p~ rt kbefore.. Thus it ~ s that Coac
men in the underlying prin~~ le: ooft~~ n these mexperience
them the various m &#183; th d f e game, presenting t
e 0 s 0 attack and h .
and what to do on both d f . ' s ? wmg them ho\
C '. . e enSIve and offenSIve play
aptam Kmg at quarterback has played with N . I f
several years. The spirit and knowled e of th orma. or
he possesses, together with his ower g .~ game which
through the line sh P. and abIltty to plunge
. ould prove a great asset to the t : M'II
qe::: t~ yIghht half Id '
s probably the fastest man on the t:: r;:;. F; e:
e spee s around the dfl'
at full hack hits the line har en or ong gams. Simmons
tears through th _ . d. He runs low, and often be
n hI . e enemy hne when it seems to he impreg-a
e. Hawkms who holds the position of right half is a vaJ-bl
man to the team. He runs well and possesses great
ua e
driving power.
The linemen are all big fellows and should present a pow-f
1 defense against any team. Davis at center, though play&#173;~
r uhis first year of football, is a good man. He is good at
In~ sing the ball to quarterback, and he knows how to use his
~ ands against the enemy. Smith and Baker, the two huge
t: ckles, are dependable men and should give the enemy a
great deal of trouble throughout the sea~ on. Bennett and
Yarbrough at guards are powerful cogs m the Normal ma&#173;chine.
When the play is called over their territory there is
always sure to be an opening in the opposing line. Puckett
and Wolfington hold down the end positions in an excellent
manner. Both are good at tackling and catching passes.
Jones, Normal's big tackle, suffered a wrenched knee in the
Vanderbilt game. It is thought, however, that he will soon
be on the field again. Delay, the swift half- back, received a
broken arch in practice which will probably keep him out of
the game for the relmainder of the season.
In case of injury to the first team &#183; men, Coach Miles has
a strong aggregation of " subs" who by no means are to' be
thought of as " scrubs." The second team piloted by " Our
Captain" Windrow consists of a group of hard- fighting, good
spirited players. So stubborn are these lads that they fre&#173;quently
hold the first team for downs, and occasionally they
fight their way to a dangergous proximity to the Varsity's
goal line.
Vandy Defeat. The Blue and White, 38 to. O.
On the mo~ ning of Sept. 30, the Normal clan journeyed
up to Nashville to encounter the McGuginites. At three
O'clock the battle began on Dudley Field. Though outclassed,
the Normal lads put up a game fight and proved their line
almost as strong as Vandy's, for practically every touch- down
made by the Black and Gold was scored either by the air
r. oute or on end runs. Jones and Sidney Smith played a bril&#173;hant
game. The Vandy line frequently wavered and gave
Way under their slaughtering attacks. On ' ofle oc~ sion De-
THE NOR~ A~ ITE ss
Overture
De Sandman's Song- McKinney
Violin Duet
Zingarese Serenade- Silver
Solo Dance
Thou h the Men's Glee Club had met several times in
. f mal ;" hearsal, the organization of the club was perfect-
1e0d oorn Thursday evening, O&lt;,: t. 12. Mr. J.. S. HoI. mes . waEs reS-elected
President; Frank Huffman, VIce- PresIdent, . .
Ford, Secretary and Treasurer.
A large number of the men have already bec. o~ e ~ en:-
b f . the Glee Club and more are expected to JOIn WIthIn
hers 0 t f d~ ys. We hope to have a Men's Chorus of ~ fty
t e nex ew . EMS un
th O IS year. Under the able direction of MISS. . h ay a k-ders
we look forward to a profitable year In c orus w? r .
The'club have already begun work on a concert to be gIven
I. n conJ. unet'lOn WI'th the orchestra during the present term.
PROGRAM
Mr. Brackin :-" How are you by now, Mrs. Rutledge ?".
Mrs. Rutledge :-" Well, Mr. Brackin, I'm a little off 111
the leg but all right in the ! lead."
Orchestra
Girls Chorus
Selected
Girls Chorus
Miss Wilson
The Chambered NautI. lus Entire C. horus
Poem by Oliver Wendell Holmes, Music by Feans
The Blue Danube- Strauss - Orchestra
Normal School Auditorium Nov.
THE NORMAL. ITE 54:
lay, Normal's half- back, dashed around. Vandy's
twelve yard gain.
M. T. N. FaDs Under KentQckian's Attack. Score 31 t
On Oct. 6, Coach Miles with his legion of warrior
vaded the Blue- grass state for a struggle with the la
West Kentucky Normal. Our boys were tired and worn
having traveled all day, and they were in no condition to
their best football. The Kentucky boys were eager for
venge, for they still remembered the disastrous strug
with M. T. N. on the gridiron. They had felt the fang
the Blue and White in the past.. However, in this game
clearly outplayed our lads in every phase of the game.
is the first time the Blue and White has ever suffered de
from the Red and White clan of Kentucky.
Bethel Defeats Normal by Small Score, 9 to O.
On the afternoon of Oct. 13, in one of the hardest fou
games ever witnessed on No~ mal Field, the Blue and W
suffered defeat from Bethel College by the small score 0
to O. The nine points secured by Bethel came as a result
fumble and softy. The spirit and fight of the Normal bu
was commendable throughout the entire game. On one
casion the Kentucky boys were held for downs on Norm
three yard line. Stars of the game were Simmons, Da
and Smith.
The remaining schedule for the season is as follows:
October 20- Bryson College I? ayetteville
October 28-- S. P. U C1arksville
November 4-- Sewanee Freshmen Murfreesboro
November II- Vandy Freshmen Murfreesboro
November'IS- Cumberland University.. Murfreesbo'ro
November 24-- Union University .] ackson
Robert King :-" Well, if I fall down on my high and 10ft
literary ambitions, at least I can set up as a teacher of ath&#173;letics."
Fifth grade pupil, at home: " Mother Mrs. Marshall's a
smart woman; I bet she reads every word in the paper from
" Mutt ' and Jeff' ' to " Gasolene Alley.'
57
THE NORMALITE
. . "' It is highly important that
f Chicago, says. . f h
niversity 0 d the aims, purposes, and values 0 t e ac-
'- drS understan . I'n school Unless they do un-teaC."'"
&#8226; hey superVIse . . .'
t ' vities which t f all parts of their teachmg tIme, en-
I h purposes 0 &#8226; ., h
derstandted ' 11 ften be wasted on actIVItIes t at
d public fun s WI 0 ergy, an
little value.
have f S teachers is to discover the dreams
blern or us a
The pro g people whom we teach- draw them
and I'dea1S of the yotu' n late them and direct them m. to rI. ght
10 them, SImu' .
out, deve p. ke them active instead of paSSIve.
hannels- that IS, rna
c .' d being advanced by the leading educators
There 15 an 1 ea A .
bi as teachers is to educate the mencan
that our pro em . . . h
. 1'&#163; d that his life is led In hIS leIsure ours.
youth for I e, an '.,
We are in the age of the automatIc machme. The wor~-
. , hours are short, his leisure hours are lo~ g- and It
l. Oghm' aIn'fs Tell me how a man spends hI. S Ie'lsure and I'll t e11
IS IS 1 e. . h' f
you what he I'S. We are told that the bulk of hum. an mlsc Ie
is done in spare time and that unless &#183; ~ ur Amer~ can g~ n. tle-en
and gentlewomen appear in due bme and In suffICient
; umbers civilization will be wrecked by machine- made bar&#173;barians.
And it is the teacher's duty to cause them to appear.
I am not against vocational training. I believe in it. But
if we would educate our youth for life we must put more
stress on the cultural side- and give it to him early, he may
never go' to college. That is one of our mistakes. We often
save for college what we should teach in a si, mple way in the
primary grades.
The Atlantic Monthly says in a. recent issue: " History,
literature, science, art, music, all these give life a meaning
and to leisure inspiration- concern in all that man has done,
is doing, and is about to do on this planet." .
Think what it would have meant to many of our home&#173;sick
boys when they were " on leave" " over there" during the
world war if they had had enough knowledge of art to have
been interested in finding original masterpieces of paintings,
architecture, and sculpture. They wer. e there. The boys
Were there. The opportunity was theirs. But they did not
We cannot e~ cape from Art's principles for a single da
Wheth~ r we are Interested or not, realize it or not, all of
are desIgners. When we dress ourselves or set a tabl b'
h
~ w
a ouse or factory, or write a letter, plan the farm buildin
or decorate a shop window, arrange a vase of flowers gs
plant the garden, write an advertisement or make a hat p . or
b ' f I . ' aID a eautt u pIcture or layoff the corn ground, we are design_
. ers.
ART
THE NORMALITE
A : ery mistaken idea is that art is the busines!, i only of
the artIst. One artist has said: " When artists will forget to
think of their occupation as a thing apart, and of themselves
as distinct from mankind, when they discover that they are
craftsmen and belong to the great company of masons and
goldsmiths and carpenters, with Donatello and Ghirlandajo
and Michelangelo, they will' get back their great traditions
and come to their own again."
One of the truest artists I ever knew was an old chimney
builder- one of nature's noblemen- who loved his work and
put his heart into it. He was an inspiration to me as a child.
He considered his work so worth- while that he was satsified
with nothing short of his' best. " A good chimney and a pret&#173;ty
chimney" was what he said he wanted to build. It was
what he did build, and he was noted for them far and near.
And I gather now, from the things he said then, that he got
his inspiration from the wonderful works of Nature~ Re&#173;membering,
all this long time, the things he said I would cer&#173;tainly
class him an appreciative as well as a creative artist.
For I don't think I have ever known anyone who appreciated
God's handwork more.
When all of us realize that the home reflects the taste of
its home- makers; the costum~ reflects the taste of its wear&#173;er;
the school- room reft~ ts the taste of its teacher; the farm
reflects the taste and pride of the farmer; the appearance of
the place of business reflects the taste of the business man;
that our outside life reflects the soul thCl; t is within us- thett
will we come ittto our own!
Samuel Chester Parker, of Educational Methods in the
THE NORMALITE S9
Can You Imagine:
Helen Brown on _ time for meals,
Clara Sawyer eating one biscuit,
Hortense Crabtree not talking,
Huffiness reading the Bible,
Paul Eaves without a package of mints,
Puckett without Margaret,
Carl Brandon talking sense,
Ruth Lee with a beau
Geraldine Grigsby without a grin????
. Pres. Lyon ( in chapel): " I hope all you new students
WIll be at home in a few days."
Life is short only four letters- three quarters of it is a
" lie" and half of it is " if."
Mr. Clark ( To his daughter who has had some Home Ec&#173;onomIC.
S)'. " Mar]' orie, I thought you would cook for us af-ter
you had studied Domestic Science."
Marjorie ( Demurely): " Oh, I was learning to cook for
two,"
New Student :-" How much are your rooms?"
Proprietor :-" Five dollars without bath and six dollars
with."
N. S. :-" Well I'll take one without bath; I'm just going
to be here nine months."
THE NORMALITE
have the tra~ mng to grasp it. An interest _ has
to save man's reason.
Art in other words is not for the few, but for all. R
ognizing the fact that every child and every adult is a design
er, that he must design either poorly or well every time
exercises his judgment in arranging or choosing colors
shapes, it is our purpose in the Art Depa; tment to deve!
the individual's power to make good choices and arrang
Iments. It is the- special aim to present the subject in such'
simple way that every earnest student can comprehend an
successfully use the principles of fine spacing and color. W
further aim to develop the powers of observation, apprecia
tion, and visualization coupled with thorough co- ordinatio
of eye, hand, and mind resulting from continued practic
which will enable one to transfer a mental image to paper. I
short we hope - to develop good designers for every- day lif
who will consistently interweave the principles learned int
their own school and community that they may cultivate th
tastes of those whom they teach, so that they, in turn, wit
produce and appreciate that which is best.
- MARIE FONTAINE.
When the Prof. Bawled Us Out.
I did laugh and she did cry
I got busted and she got by
Tell me not in a mournful tone
When you weep you weep alone.
Breathes there the student with pep so dead,
Who never to himself hath said,
" This is my own, my own dear school?"
- I f such there be he is a fool
Ii such there be go knock him well,
Hit him hard and make him yell,
Kick him high, kick him low,
Break his neck and let him go.
Paul Burton finally got his name in THE NORMALITE &#173;even
if it did go in by way of the joke columns.
58-
Just a moment there, Bertram, before you close the
NORMALITE; and you too Julia. I would a word with thee,
my dears. Have you read every line? Sure you have. My,
but didn't you enjoy it? But " The fictions of the
imagination and the enthusiasm of sentiment must give place
to the sober realities of business."
" Isn't it so." You know it is, don't you?
Wouldn't it be fine if you could move into that little
house built just for two- as you were planning last night, with
all those luxuries you were talking about? Of course you
would. I know how it is, because I've done the same thing.
But you know why don't you, Bertram? And you do too,
don't you Julia, though you won't let on?
Don't you remember last &#183; night, son, when you let go of
the last fond embrace ( only we don't have them here) after
you made all those plans, and you stepped out in that chill
air you realized that you need a new overcoat. And when
you got back to your room you found that old last year's suit
looking too tough to wear much longer~ Then when you pull&#173;ed
off your shoes you found them all worn, &#183; ready &#183; to dissolve
partnership~ But that isn't all you found; you found your
sox were no good from the shoe top down. When you pull&#173;ed
off that old shirt you got two summers ago you found it
fra\ zzled- at the cuffs and iIi the neckhand - and a hole in each
elhow so you couldn't laugh in your sleeve any longer with-
: Mildred S. :-" Wonder if : Mary Hill is out yet?"
Louise T. :-" Why, yes! Has she been sick?"
Mildred :-" No, but she said she couldn't go out until she
got her new shoes."
Louise :-" Well, I saw her limp by today."
Mr. Duck after a class discussion of a cow's digestive
system " s
M
- ay, Mr. Ogden, I'm glad I haven't four stomachs."
r. Ogden :- HWhy?"
.. Mr . Duck :- HBecause I can't get even one filled at the
dmmg hall."
And these old limp collars! And what
ut it leaking fout. decent fellow to have a cold with or to
o hiefs or a
handkerc .' the dining hall! When you looked over
u e a an. apkIll dIII you realized that your outfit would rnak e
' our 5 t 0 ck III trkal' e, on that PhiladelphI. a tn. p 100k'hke I rene
# , ' Fran III 5
BenjamIn from Paris, In fact you need about every-tie
return h ' d' dt
- &#8226; Cf man away from Mot er s armng nee e
- that a ) ounb thIng for from a pint of gasolene to remove those
ever had any use
e 5 ots to a regular Beau Brummel.
grea ,\ ndPyoU too Julia. I know just exactly what . you need,
. , t gOl'ng to enumerate. The enumeratIOn would
but I m no
merouS to mention. But don't you worry for one
e too nu .
. t you dear things. I can fix that up all nght. I am mtnU e,
a regula r Aladdin at fixing the i. mpos. sible.,
_ ow here's what you do and It WIll be all nght. Just turn
oyer the next page. See, what did I tell you? There you
have it. A classy ad offering the very things you need. And
over on the next page! My, the very things you want. And
look how cheap! And look over on that other page! Did
you ever see such nice things advertised? And all right here
in Murfreesboro, too! Isn't that nice? All you've got to do
is to run down town next Saturday and just buy to your
heart's content. But won't you make that last check from
home look like thirty cents when you go in all those stores
and ): msiness houses that advertise with the NORALITE and
tell them " I SAW YOUR AD IN THE NORMALITE, NOvV
BRING ON ALL YOU GOT. I WANT TO TRADE WITH
THEM AS TRADES WITH US!"
THE NORMALITE THE NORMALITE 61
IT PAYS TO ADVERTISE
60
PHONE 77
LEADERS IN
IN BlTSINESS FOR
AT ALL HOURS
Meals and Lunches
SOUTH SIDE OF SQUARE
j\ TOM &amp; SHACKLETT
DRY GOODS AND READY. TO- WEAR
YOUR HEALTH
Stickney Drug Company
-
Complete Line of School Supplies
- Parker Fountain Pens
Ever Sharp Pencils
, Magazines and . Novels
DEALERS IN
Telephone 96. 103 Public Square
Groceries, Fruits And
Vegetables
w. E. CANTREll &amp; CO. CITY RESTAURANT
AT
BUTLER, HOOPER &amp; McCORD, Inc.
" The Good Clothes Store" &#173;WEST
SIDE SQUARE
PHONES 8 AND 68
OPPOSITE POST OFFICE
HIGH CLASS CLOTHES, HATS AND
FURNISHINGS
c. 1- 1 . . BYRN &amp; SON
Authorized Buick Sales And Service
Goodyear And Kelly- Springfield Tires
COMPETENT MECHANICS
SJ1lith [ 1 Fletche..,
~ . s
. u. vtl9ger~ .
MURFREESBORO
Mr. Henry' Truett
&#183; EXCLU &#183; SIVE . AGEN &#183; rrs OF
Spaulding Sporting I
Goods and I
Bradley Sweaters I
o i too 0 on' . () () () ( 0
o
,..
() () () () 4 ()......()~ e,
o~()
~. I
c Cater to the Wants I
c of the Norm~ l . .. 1
c Boys and G: lrls I
o COMPLETE &#183; LlNES' . oF &#183; 0 , .
c Wearing Apparel
-.... and Accessories)
-
HENRY KING &amp; COMPANY
Succenor to Boulevard Store
Murfreesboro- McMinnville- Tullahoma
FISK RED TOP TIRES
WHOLESALE GROCERS
Agents for
Groceries, Cigars, Tobacco, Soft Drinks
High Grade Candies, Gasoline
Comer Normal Boulevard and East Main Street
PHONE SIS
LEWIS BRINKLEY
Allen Service
Automobile Accessories, Oils and Gas
TIRE SERVICE
Free Air And Free Water
PROMPTNESS
PHONE 811 W. MAIN 5T
MURFREESBORO, TENN.
Phone 69
C. B. LEATHERMAN &amp; COMPANY
Dry Goods And Ladies Ready~ T&lt; rWear
We Appreciate Your Patronage
SERVICE
North Side Public Square
PHONE 240
Telephone 361
Quality Furniture
SODAS
Hand Painted China, Parch&#173;ment
Shades, Eleetroliers, Nov&#173;elties.
Cards for all Occasions.
Orders Filled Promptly
MRS. D. E. LOGAN
MISS FANNIE NICHOL
ART CHINA SHOP
McKNIGHT AND
PARTEE
FORMERLY JACK'S
Us
Make You a Suit to Your Individual Measure.
Let
We Guarantee Satisfaction.
READ &amp; RIGGS
E. L. ROGERS &amp; COMPANY
Gents' Outfitters, Clothing and Shoes
SAMPLE SHOES A SPECIALTY
Whitman, Norris &amp; Hollinsworth Candies
CIGARS
LUNCHES
We T. GERHARDT
Merchant Tailor
Phone 59
Cleaning Pressing
Altering
- ELECTRIC SHOE
SHOP
Your Patronage
Solicited
119 South Church St.
A. L. SMITH &amp;
Druggists
MAGAZINES, SCH
SUPPLIES
CHOCOLATES
Cut Flowers For
All Oc &#8226;
Misses E. and
Earthman
Exclusive Millinery
128 North Church StJ
NEW BONNET
&#183; If You Need A
BONNET SHOP
WE DO HEMSTITCHING
GROCERIES
STORE OF FRIENDLY - SERVICE
OPPOSITE FIRE HALL PHONE
H. M. TUTT, Proprietor.
. FREE DELIVERY
Join the Normal Class at the Methodist Sunday School
. ALSUP SHOE
COMPANY
" Where only the Best
is good enough"
SMART FOOTWEAR
IMURiFREESBORO - TENNESSEE
Home Phone 13
- WHAT WE WANT
JOHN DeGEORGE
East Side Square. Phone III
Hot Chili in Winter Time
Ice Cream in Summer Tillie
Anything . good to eat and clriak
ALL THE TIME.
. EVERYTHING TO WEAR FOR THE
ENTIRE FAMIlY'
OLD RELIABLE
TAXI SERVICE
Phone 11
EPH HOOVER, Mgr.
Cumb. Phone 147
Opposite P. O.
ELROD'S BOOTER\,
</dc:description>
<dc:subject>College publications; Middle Tennessee State Normal School;</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Text; Image;</dc:type>
<dc:type>text; application/pdf</dc:type>
<dc:format>Periodical;</dc:format>
<dc:format>61 p.; 6 x 9.5 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright may or may not belong to MTSU; Reproduced with permission of the Albert Gore Research Center, MTSU</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>May be used freely by individuals for research, teaching, and personal use under the fair use provisions of the Copyright Act; Credit: Property of the Albert Gore Research Center, Middle Tennessee State University, Murfreesboro, TN 37132; For other uses contact The Albert Gore Research Center, P.O. Box 193, MTSU, Murfreesboro TN 37132</dc:rights>
<dc:relation>University Collections, MTSU Miscellaneous, Middle Tennessee Normal School, 1911-1925</dc:relation>
<dc:publisher>Albert Gore Research Center, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:description>Folder 2</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/mtsu1/id/1403</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>