<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Viet Nam support petition</dc:title>
<dc:title>Vietnam support petition</dc:title>
<dc:relation>Sidelines, Dec. 14, 1965</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Middle Tennessee State University</dc:source>
<dc:date>1965-12-14</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>MTSU, under ASB President Bert Wakeley, headed a state-wide petition effort in universities to show support of Johnson's Vietnam war policies. MTSU's petition was more than thirty-five feet long.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Harold Smith, ASB vice-president;  Tom Peterson, freshman-class president; Bert Wakeley, ASB president</dc:description>
<dc:description>THE VIET NAM SUPPORT PETITION of more than 35 feet in length is pictured above in the hands of Harold Smith, ASB vice-president, at left; Tom Peterson, recently elected freshman class president, at center, and Bert Wakeley, ASB President, at right. The signature-filled paper was presented to Governor Frank Clement this weekend for transmission to President Lyndon B. Johnson and thus to the Armed Services in Viet Nam.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Associated Student Body</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Vietnam War, 1961-1975--Public opinion; Petitions; Middle Tennessee State University</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:type>image/jpeg</dc:type>
<dc:format>Clipping;</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected. Reproduced with permission of the University</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Reproduction is permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only; Credit to Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:rights>
<dc:relation>Sidelines Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/mtsu1/id/749</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>