<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Mid-Stater : alumni bulletin, v. 2, no. 4 (Spring 1961)</dc:title>
<dc:title>Alumni bulletin</dc:title>
<dc:contributor>Pittard, Homer, editor</dc:contributor>
<dc:source>Middle Tennessee State College, Alumni Office</dc:source>
<dc:date>1961</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>The Mid-Stater began publication the fall of 1959. Homer Pittard was its first editor.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Vol. 2- No. 4 Mu rfreesbo r o, Ten nessee Spring Issue, 1961
Stark, Wood, Overall Choices For 1961
CLIFFORD STARK
In the upper hallway of the Adminis&#173;tration
Building hangs a series of class
pictures depicting the rather austere vis&#173;ages
of grads past. One of these entitled
simply " Normal, 1919" displays twenty&#173;two,
three- year diploma recipients, one
of whom is a bespectacled young man
with a firmly set jaw. This is Clifford
Stark from Dickson County. Probably
Clifford would have preferred a group
picture of one year later, for in 1920 he
was one of six students who received a
four- year diploma in vocational agricul&#173;ture.
For the next forty- one years agri&#173;culture
was his passion and his life .
After his Normal days he taught agri&#173;culture
at Christiana High School while
attending Peabody College where he re&#173;ceived
his M. A. in 1924. The next year
he entered Cornell University and re&#173;mained
as a graduate student and a
member of the faculty for twenty- seven
years. Upon reaching the age of com&#173;pulsory
retirement he returned to his
first Alma Mater as head of the Agricul&#173;ture
Department. This department pros-
( Continued on Page 4)
RANDY WOOD
The May 21, 1941, Side lines carried
pictures of the Senior Class. Included
among these as vice- president was Ran&#173;dolph
C. Wood of Morrison, Tennessee.
He was dressed in tuxedo and from all
appearances could have been groom and
at worst, best man at a front society
page wedding. But this was far from the
true picture for the tuxedo was a photo&#173;grapher's
prop and Randy had anything
but a " bed of roses", financially, at Mid&#173;dle
Tennessee State Teachers College. In
fact, his room on the second floor of
Jones' Hall doubled as sleeping quarters
and a store. He literally worked his way
through college.
After graduation he opened a radio re&#173;pair
shop in Gallatin, Tennessee, later
adding a stock of records. These proved
so popular that by 1950 he converted to
the record business and added a trade
name, " Dot", because he was now re&#173;(
Continued on Page 2)
See You At The
Banquet
PRESTON OVERALL
Preston Vaughan, " Putty," Overall
came to the Middle Tennessee State Nor&#173;mal
School in 1911 as a student in the
Model School. From 1912 to 1916 he was
enrolled in the high school department.
After a stint at Castle Heights, a year in
the Normal department, two years in the
First World War, and then two addition&#173;al
years back in the folds of the Normal,
he graduated with a three- year diploma
in 1921. With the determination of " I
have just begun to fight", he entered
Vanderbilt and later Peabody, receiving
his B. S'. from Peabody in 1922. Later he
did graduate work leading to the M. S.
at Iowa State College.
After teaching one year at Livingston
Academy in Tennessee, he moved to Ten&#173;nessee
Polytechnic Institute at Cooke&#173;ville,
where he has served with phenome&#173;nal
success for thirty- eight years. He
coached football, and at times, all other
sports, through the years from 1943 to
1946. Later he came out of retirement
to lead the Tech gridders to two Ohio
Valley Conference championships in 1952
( Continued on Page 2)
President Cope's Message ...
As the end of the Fiftieth Year of operation of Middle Tennessee State Col&#173;lege
approaches, we are looking forward to our annual alumni banquet on the eve&#173;ning
of May 20. Last year we had excellent attendance at the banquet and we an&#173;ticipate
a larger attendance this year.
Dr. Pittard, Mr. Abernathy, and other faculty members have performed in ' an
excellent manner in working with various Alumni Chapters. During the year new
Chapters have been organized in Nashville, Lebanon and Oak Ridge. Contact has also
been maintained with Chapters that were organized in previous years.
During the year 1961- 62, Middle Tennessee State College will commemorate its
first fifty year's of operation with appropriate ceremonies and. events. We will need
the support and best wishes of our alumni in connection with t. his celebration.
May I urge you to be present at the banquet on May 20 and join us in paying
tribute to three outstanding alumni, Dr. C. N. Stark, Mr. P. V. Overall, and Mr.
Randolph Wood who will be recognized with appropriate ceremonies.
From The Association's President ...
It may be that for you, like myself, it has been many years since you were
a student at Middle Tennessee State College. How completely different the
campus looks from what we knew then. Where once there were only open fields
( in 1930), and the President's home dominated the whole area, is now one
beautiful rectangle with a drive all its own which opens on Woodbury Pike.
The field where the " tall corn" grew with the path leading to the " boarding
houses" on Woodbury Pike, is a community all its own.
The area in front of the old dining hall where we hunted " four leaf
clovers" under the watchful eyes of Miss Tommy and Mrs. Rutledge, is dwarfed
by the imposing buildings surrounding it. Also, I believe when you come back
to the Alumni Banquet, May 20th, you will wonder how it held all of the three
hundred and fifty students whom we bragged about.
Over the years State has grown into an institution which ranks with any in
the South. Our Library is the " Staff of Life" of which scholars are bred. Our
football team under Coach Bubber Murphy wins games " with clock- like pre&#173;cision."
Our faculty is still the best in the land. Of course we don't know them like
we did Mr. Frazier, Dr. Belcher, Prof. Woodard or Mr. Davis, but if you will
come to the Alumni Banquet, you will find many things that are familiar. You
will find that the present faculty is just as friendly and just as interested
as the old timers were. You will find a new president. who is young in years, but
old in experience. He keeps " open house" to all and is ever ready to meet old
grads with a hearty hand shake and a smile of welcome.
Why am I reviewing the years when you know these things as well as I
do? Just one reason, I want you to meet me at the Alumni Banquet. Whether
it has been thirty, twenty, ten, five or two years since your graduation, we
can review " the ties that bind" and sing our Alma Mater as we did many years
ago.
Dyer Delves
Into Delinquency
The April, 1961 Vital Speeches of the
Day carries an address by J . Pope Dyer
(' 29), Social Science Department head at
Chattanooga Central. It is entitled " The
Present Juvenile Delinquency Picture"
and was delivered before the Hemlock
S c h 00 I Parent- Teacher Association in
Chattanooga. Pope is a constant con&#173;tributor
to periodicals and is in great
demand as a speaker. He has long been
regarded as one of the top history teach&#173;ers
in the South and has received na&#173;tional
recognition in this regard on
more than one occasion.
Pope, one of the great admirers of
the late Dr. C. C. Sims, will award a
medal in honor of his college history
teacher to the outstanding stu den t
selected by the Political Science Depart&#173;ment.
This will be a part of the
Alumni Banquet program.
Lookout Club Elects
Thelma Williams
The Chattanooga club, oldest of the
M. T. S. C. alumni clubs, met at its an&#173;nual
banquet on the evening of March 21.
The meeting place was Wimberley Inn
with Marvin Lane presiding. The pro&#173;gram
consisted of music by M. T. S. C.
Women's Trio, brief remarks by Bob Ab&#173;ernathy,
Dr. Bob Womack, and the alum&#173;ni
secretary. Afterwards color slides of
the college campus were shown. New of&#173;ficers
elected were as follows: Thelma
Williams, president; Elizabeth Davis,
vice- president; Thomas Dye, treasurer;
and Mary N. Royer, secretary. Some sev&#173;enty
alumni were present and plans were
discussed for initiating a club project.
P. V. Overall - - -
( Continued From Page 1)
and 1953. The fine facilities of his de&#173;partment
at Tennessee Tech are a trib&#173;ute
to his leadership and abilities, and
the football stadium is named in his hon&#173;or.
There are other honors, almost too
numerous to mention, that have come his
way. For example, he was recently nomi&#173;nated
to the National Football Hall of
Fame. Really the reflection of his suc&#173;cess
lies in the glow that comes from those
hundreds of Eagle athletes of years past
when his name is mentioned. He had the
rare talent of molding groups of boys,
many times extremely shy in ability, into
creditable and winning teams. His popu-larity
among those of the athletic world
has never abated. Playing with the Nor-
C. P. Parsons
mal " Pedagogues", his hulking two hund&#173;red
and sixty pounds quickly was labeled
" Putty". Shortly thereafter, the Normali&#173;ties
added " Little Eva". He was captain
under Johnny " Red" Floyd in 1917.
" Putty", the man from Snell, Tennes&#173;see,
will be long remembered because
men have memories for those who be&#173;friended
them during the frequently try&#173;ing
collegiate years.
Randy Wood - - -
( Continued From Page 1)
cording. The name " Dot" was given to
the new enterprise because " I wanted a
name that would be short and easy for
the public to remember". Dot's first re&#173;lease
sold 10,000 copies, a rather stirring
tribute to his fast developing business
acumen.
2
Later. in a business transaction with
Paramount Studios in Hollywood, Cali&#173;fornia,
he transferred the home office
of Dot Records to California. He re&#173;mained
as president of the successful
company and gained new status as vice&#173;president
of Paramount. Dot has subse&#173;quently
become one of the most import&#173;ant
recording companies in America.
Despite his meteoric rise to an un&#173;excelled
eminence in the entertainment
world he is described as " the nicest man
in the business".
Randy lives in Beverly Hills with his
wife, Lois Henry, also an alumna of M. T.
S. C., and three children, Linda, Larry,
and John.
From the dormitory store in Jones
Hall to a suite of offices in Hollywood
is a king- size leap that struggling col&#173;lege
men anywhere could attempt to
emulate or could gain inspiration.
" Fifty Golden Years"
Theme For 1961- 62
September of 1961 will launch a year&#173;long
celebration of the 50th Anniversary
of Middle Tennessee State College under
the title of " Fifty Golden Years" and
designed to follow the theme of " A Tri&#173;bute
to the Past and a Prelude to the
Future."
A number of interesting items has been
planned, all of which will call public
attention to the semicentennial observa&#173;tion.
A new and original Ama Mater is
being composed and a college flag is
being designed. Both are scheduled to be
dedicated in an impressive Homecoming
game half- time program in early Novem&#173;ber.
A 50th Anniversary decal for the
rear window of automobiles will be
ready for distribution by mid- summer.
The college stationery for next year will
carry a special design commemorating the
fifty- year service of M. T. S. C. to Tennes&#173;see
and an attractive new brochure will
be sent to all high schools and prospec&#173;tive
students in the mid- state area.
A Golden Anniversary " Midlander"
is now in the planning stage and the
staff is assembling special pictures
and historical data for this edition.
Another outstanding publication will
be a " History of Middle Tennessee
State College" written by the alumni
secretary. The " Sidelines will carry a
new masthead which is now on the
design board in the Art Department.
Of special interest to the Alumni will
be a twenty- minute sound film in color
which will capture the beauty of the
campus in Autumn, bring you up- to- date
on the campus buildings, give you a
glimpse of the colorful operas and plays,
and let you experience once again the
varied activities on the campus during
a typical school year.
Most appropriate during the 50th
year celebration will be the establish &#183;
ment of a special committee to start
M. T. S. C.' s own museum and archives
and have it located on the campus. The
Alumni will be called upon to take
an active part in this program during
the years to come by finding and sup&#173;plying
appropriate materials for this
project.
Four outstanding programs are planned
for the year of celebration. A formal
semicentennial convocation, with a color&#173;ful
procession of flags, college chorus,
faculty in academic attire and platform
guests, is scheduled for the fall. Arrange&#173;ments
are now being made to have an
outstanding speaker for this occasion.
The 1961- 62 Homecoming will be one of
the highlights of the year as special
emphasis is being placed on the parade,
' the half- time activities and a luncheon
honoring certain alumni. Sometime dur&#173;ing
late winter or early spring, the entire
mid- state area will be invited to attend
the biggest and most outstanding public
program ever to be brought to the
campus. The year will close with the
annual Senior- Alumni Banquet celebrat&#173;ing
''' Fifty Golden Years."
Plans Include
New Alma Mater
During the Homecoming celebration,
October 21, 1961, on the occasion of the
football game with the University of
Chattanooga, a new Middle Tennessee
State College Alma Mater will be in&#173;troduced.
Back in 1914 during the forma&#173;tive
years of the Normal, Parson L. F.
McConnell, an Episcopalian lay reader
turned student, w rot e the lyrics to
" M. T. S. C., All Hail." He did a beautiful
job but as for the music the words were
adapted to an old Russian hymn. Con&#173;taining
something of the old Czarist
lilt, the students have found it difficult
to sing and at half century very few are
even familiar with the words. Members
of the Music Department have made in&#173;numerable
attempts to " Americanize" it
but have at last thrown in their " do's"
and " re's."
Those interested in trying their hands
at writing new words and music may
send entries to Neil Wright of the Music
Department. A prize of $ 250.00 will be
awarded to the winning entry. These are
the rules:
1. The Alma Mater will consist of one
stanza in hymn style ( four parts,
harmonized).
2. The music and text shall be origin &#183;
al.
3. The College is to be referred to in
the text as " Middle Tennessee."
4. The manuscript, without the com &#183;
poser's name, is to be submitted in
a sealed, blank envelope within an
evelope. Outside envelope to bear
the entrant's name, address and
telephone number.
5. The contest is open to anyone ex&#173;cept
faculty members of Middle
Tennessee State College. Any num &#183;
ber of entries, each under separate
cover, may be submitted by the
same person.
6. All copyrights and all rights of
performance and use of the win&#173;ning
entry shall become the sole
property of Middle Tennessee.
7. Deadline of entries: June 15, 1961.
8. The decision will be announced by
3
What They Are Doing
Don McDaniel (' 58), who last year
taught at Tullahoma High School, Tenn&#173;essee,
has moved to Murfreesboro, Tenn &#183;
essee with his Wife, Barbara, and two
sons. He is now employed in the in&#173;surance
field.
Elbert Bishop (' 27) is Registrar at
Palm Beach Junior College, Florida, and
is secretary of the Association of Florida
Registrars.
H. B. McDonough (' 27), who has been
principal of East Junior High School,
Nashville, Tennessee, has been elected
vice president of the Tennessee Educa&#173;tion
Association. This places him in line
for the presidency next year.
William Wharton (' 30) writes Bob
Abernathy that he is five years away
from retirement in the Memphis school
system. When that day comes, the quail,
ducks, and crappie in the west Tennessee
area will need to be alerted.
Carl Brockett (' 28), for many years
Superintendent of D a v ids 0 n County
Schools, now is Director of the Division
of Retirement for all public employees
in Tennessee.
C. O. Riggs (' 28), Superintendent of
Sumner County Schools, Tennessee, reo
cently returned from a visit of Russian
schools. Roy Dowdy (' 32), Superintendent
of Lebanon Schools, Tennessee, enjoyed
the same privilege in Norway last Spring.
Charles Oliver (' 30), former principal
of Marshall County High School, Tenn&#173;essee,
and later Petersburg, is now serv&#173;ing
Marshall County as Superintendent
of Schools.
COMMITTEE MAKES
CHOICES
The committee selected to review nom&#173;inations
for this year's choice for Three
Outstanding Alumni were: Bill Com&#173;perry,
Chairman, Rollie Holden and Mar&#173;garet
Jarman Perry. The committee at
its February 14 meeting was guided en&#173;tirely
by the written nominations received
by the Alumni Office. Pictures of the
1961 honorees will appear in the current
Midlander and will also be hung in the
Honor Gallery at Andrew Todd Memorial
Library.
July 15, 1961. The winner will be
notified and the prize made payable
immed iately after the announce&#173;ment.
9. The judging committee reserves the
right to reject any or all entries.
Incidently, Miss E. Mai Saunders, who
was around when the original was written
and who inspired the Parson to write
the words, has given her blessing to the
project.
lIThe First Fifty Yearsll
HISTORY OF
MIDDLE TENNESSEE STATE COLLEGE
Written By the Alumni Secretary
This history is being issued as a part of the Semi- Centennial activities
beginning in the Fall of 1961 . It will contain approximafely 200 pages
in attractive permanent hard bindery.
Other items found in the volume are:
&#8226; Pictures of athletic teams. early faculty members, campus activities,
and early buildings.
&#8226; The role of politics in establishment of the institution and during sub&#173;sequent
years.
&#8226; listing of all Faculty members, 1911- 1961, indicaitng years in ser&#173;vice
and areas taught.
&#8226; Human interest stories associated with faculty members and students.
Present plans are for the volume to be ready for delivery by the
middle of September. Your response will assist the college in deter&#173;mining
the number of copies to be printed. The pre- publication price
is $ 3 .00, and the regular price ( after July 1, 1961) is $ 4.00.
Publication is non profit. Subscriptions by alumni and other in&#173;terested
people will assist the college in pa rtially defraying engraving
and printing costs.
To Reserve Your Copy, Clip Coupon Below and Return
To: BOOKSTORE MTSC
Enclosed Find Check 0 Money Order 0 For Sum of $ _
Please Forward Copies of " THE HISTORY OF MIDDLE TEN-NESSEE
STATE COLLEGE":
NAMEE _
ADDRESS, _
CITY STAT. E... _
PROPOSED ...
50th
ANNIVERSARY
SOUVENIR RECORD
As a memento of the 50th anniversary, it has been suggested that a
45 RPM record be made, possibly containing brief comments by the
President and older faculty members, greetings from retired faculty,
brief selections by the band, chorus, Ha rp Singers, a bit of college his&#173;tory,
etc. Total playing time will be about thirteen minutes. The record
will be produced only if there is sufficient demand by the alumni.
IF INTERESTED CLIP COUPON
AND RETURN BY JULY 1/ 1961
To: Lane Boutwell, Speech Dept. M. T. S. C.
I am interested in a souvenir record at a cost of approximately
$ 1.50.
NAME. _
ADDRESS _
CITY STATE _
This Is Exploratory Send No Money Now
Atomic City Or~ anizes
Group of Oak Ridge Alumni and college representatives planning April
12 meeting.
Fifty M. T. S. C. alumni gathered at Holiday Inn in Oak Ridge in the
evening of April 12 to organize a new alumni club. Officers elected were:
John Cowan Lyles, president; Roy Norris, vice- president; Emily Muse
Rucker, secretary; and Norman Hildreth, treasurer. The program consisted
of brief talks by Bob Abernathy and the alumni secretary, and showing of
campus color slides. Several committees were appointed including a group
to prepare a constitution. Other Atomic City alumni wishing to affiliate
should contact Emily Rucker at 118 Princeton, Oak Ridge.
Annual Banquet Program
The program for the annual Alumni Banquet again
this year will be given almost entirely by alumni.
President Parsons has dedicated himself to streamlin&#173;ing
the activities of the evening so that the finale will
come at an acceptable hour. The program indicated
elsewhere on his page should prove extremely interest&#173;ing.
Alumni should return reservation forms by the
May 17 deadline. This year the Commencement Sun&#173;day
program has been eliminated since it was found
that very few of the nation's colleges still retained
this type of program. Graduation exercises will be held
at Jones' Field at 5: 30 p. m. on May 26.
ALUMNI- FACULTY- SENIOR BANQUET
Meeting of Nominating Committee ( past presidents)
6: 00 p. m. Dining Room A
Banquet
Presiding: Charles Parker Parsons, Alumni Association
President
Time: May 20, 6: 30 p. m.
Place : College Campus, Tennessee Room
Program :
Invocation- Jesse Wiser
Music- Joseph Smith and Gay Jennings
Margaret Wright, Accompanist
Introduction of Retiring Faculty Members and
Guests
Presentation of C. C. Sims History Award&#173;J
. Pope Dyer
State of the College message&#173;President
Quill E. Cope
Presentation of Three Outstanding Alumni&#173;President
Cope assisted by Johnny Bentley, Senior
Class President
Election of Officers
Alma Mater
Benediction- Ross Spielman
Dinner Music by the Townsmen
NEW CLUBS
Lebanon Yardmasters: John Greer, Miles McMillan, Paul
Wooten, Allie Coe Baker.
Delivering the charge: Lynn Banks, Ross Spielman, John
W. Johnson, Mrs. J. E. Browder- Davidson County Officers.
Davidson, Wilson Alumni
Launch New Clubs
Clifford Stark -
( Continued From Page 1)
pered and grew under his expert and
dedicated direction. He left again in 1957
to spend two years in Madras, India,
to lend his great talent to the Indian
farmer. Upon the insistance of his wife,
Pauline, who feared for his health, Dr.
Stark returned to the States at the close
of his two- year tenure. Again he became
affiliated with his first Alma Mater as a
member of the agriculture and science
faculties.
At this point, Dr. Stark has two peeves.
The first came with his conversion to the
field of agriculture some forty- five years
ago. He has been constantly alarmed at
the apparent lackadaisical attitude held
by many people toward the great base of
American economy. This has driven him
to great mental and physical activity for
its cause. The second is his great snarl
with retirement, for to him seventy years
represent only a relative position in life.
He still remains much of the drive and
energy that have carried him to an envi&#173;able
position in American agriculture.
And for those in the know, agriculture
has not heard the last of Clifford Stark.
Approximately one hundred and ninety
Davidson County alumni met for organ&#173;izational
purposes at the Maxwell House
at 6: 00 p. m. on March 24. The Sacred
Harp Singers presented a musical pro&#173;gram
followed by an address by Presi&#173;dent
Quill E. Cope. Molly Malone served
as toastmaster. Officers for the new club
are as follows : Ross Spielman, president;
Lynn Ba nks, vice- president; Mrs. J. E.
Browder, secretary; and John W. John&#173;son,
treasurer. The very successful meet&#173;was
the culmination of months of intense
activity on the part of Ross Spielman,
John Bass, Lynn Banks, Ken Stockton,
Jim Loften, and many others. Immediate&#173;ly
after assuming the presidency, Ross
. presented a full list of committees and
announced plans for an alumni dinner
dance and picnic for the future.
4
Officers for the new Wilson County
Alumni club are: Miles McMillan, presi&#173;dent;
John Greer, vice- president; Allie
Coe Carrington Baker, secretary; and
Paul Wooten, treasurer. The meeting was
held in the Wilson County High School
cafeteria on April 6 with one hundred
and seven in attendance. Attending from
the college were Gene Sloan, Dr. Jim
Martin, Bill Stokes, and the alumni sec&#173;retary.
Margaret Wright and her Women's
Trio presented a musical program. Spear&#173;heading
the organization were Miles
McMillan, Roy Dowdy, Herman Chumbley
and several other " elder" Raiders and
Raiderettes. President Miles has an&#173;nounced
that the next conclave will be
at Cedars of Lebanon Park in the early
Fall. The menu will be bulwarked with
barbecued chicken.
</dc:description>
<dc:subject>College publications; Middle Tennessee State College</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Alumni &amp; alumnae;</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Image; Text;</dc:type>
<dc:type>text; application/pdf</dc:type>
<dc:format>Newspaper; Periodical;</dc:format>
<dc:format>6 p.; 8.5 x 11.0 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright may or may not belong to MTSU; Reproduced with permission of the Albert Gore Research Center, MTSU</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>May be used freely by individuals for research, teaching, and personal use under the fair use provisions of the Copyright Act; Credit: Property of the Albert Gore Research Center, Middle Tennessee State University, Murfreesboro, TN 37132; For other uses contact The Albert Gore Research Center, P.O. Box 193, MTSU, Murfreesboro TN 37132</dc:rights>
<dc:relation>MTSU Collection, University Publications, The Mid-Stater</dc:relation>
<dc:publisher>Albert Gore Research Center, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:description>Box 1</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/mtsu1/id/1283</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>