<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>New course is offered in atomic age physics</dc:title>
<dc:relation>Sidelines, Oct. 1, 1958</dc:relation>
<dc:date>1958-10-01</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>MTSC offered a year-long course in atomic age physics, also available via television, to anyone who was interested</dc:description>
<dc:description>New Course Is Offered In Atomic Age Physics
The 'Sidelines' provides a 'Letters to the Editor' column for letting off steam, praising campus life, and offering 

opinions on world affairs. Letters are encouraged from all students. Address your letter to Pat Turner, Box 137, MTSC. Letters are held in confidence by the editor, pending publication. All letters must be signed in order to be printed, although names will be withheld if so 

requested.
Dr. Quill E. Cope, president of MTSC, has announced that the college will offer undergraduate and graduate resident credit for "Atomic Age Physics," a course 

sponsored by the American Association of College Teacher Education and televised over WSM-TV, Channel 4, each morning from 6:30 until 7 o'clock, Monday through 

Friday. The program begins Monday morning, October 6.
Inquiries relative to the course should be addressed to Dr. J. Eldred Wiser, head of the science department. Registration will be held in Dr. Wiser's office in the 

science building Saturday, October 4, 1958, from 9 a.m. to 11 a.m. Dr. Douglas Shields, associate professor of physics, will be coordinator for the course which will be 

adapted to fit existing catalog course 342, 420, and 550 of the physics division curriculum. The courses will extend over the full three quarters of the academic year and carry four hours credit each quarter or a maximum of 12 hours resident credit for the academic year.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Nuclear physics; Physics--Study and teaching; Correspondence schools and courses; Middle Tennessee State College</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:type>image/jpeg</dc:type>
<dc:format>Clipping</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected. Reproduced with permission of the University</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Reproduction is permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only; Credit to Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:rights>
<dc:relation>Sidelines Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/mtsu1/id/1128</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>