<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>"It's getting 'drafty' here"</dc:title>
<dc:relation>Sidelines, Nov. 7, 1967</dc:relation>
<dc:date>1967-11-07</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Provides details of how MTSU's Graduate School would be affected by the new draft law.</dc:description>
<dc:description>It's Getting 'Drafty' Here
Impact of the new draft law may have a major bearing on graduate programs at Middle Tennessee State University next year, according to an analysis prepared by the American Council of Education's Commission of Federal Relations.
"Unless changes are made by amending either the statute or the regulations governing Selective Service, enrollment in the first two years of graduate and professional schools next fall will be limited to women, veterans, men physically disqualified and those over 25 years of age," according to the statement prepared by John F. Morse, director of the Commission.
Dr. Ralph Kirkman, dean of the Graduate School at MTSU, stated that he was personally hopeful
that the national policy will be revised. The Council of Graduate Schools of the United States, to which MTSU was admitted this year, has referred this matter to the Committee on Selective Service and Educational Deferments which takes the position that all fields of graduate study are equally critical and that deferments based on disciplinary priorities are not in the national interest, Dr. Kirkman explained.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Deferment</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Draft; United States. Selective Service System; Graduate students; Women; Veterans--Education; Council of Graduate Schools in the United States;  Middle Tennessee State University</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:type>image/jpeg</dc:type>
<dc:format>Clipping</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected. Reproduced with permission of the University</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Reproduction is permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only; Credit to Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:rights>
<dc:relation>Sidelines Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/mtsu1/id/1114</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>