<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Murfreesboro State</dc:title>
<dc:relation>Sidelines</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Middle Tennessee State Teachers College</dc:source>
<dc:date>1941-01-23</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>An editorial describing problems with changing the school's name to Tennessee State; the writer decided that "Murfreesboro State" would be the best option</dc:description>
<dc:description>Murfreesboro State
Last year a drive was started here in Murfreesboro to change the name of the Middle Tennessee State Teachers College to just plain Tennessee State College. The move had hardly gotten under way when news came from East Tennessee State Teachers college, at Johnson City, that they had already adopted the name Tennessee State, This was a big blow to our hopes of getting away from the old "If you come here you're gonna be a school teacher" tradition. But now another idea, an even better idea, has been brought forward by West Tennessee STC; thep have changed their name to Memphis State. Surely no other school can copy that name.
All the teachers colleges and schools using Initials are trying to change their names; trying to take on a more general air, so that they might attract more of the better students.. Surely, there are many of the better students who would come here to school if the TEACHERS in our name did not scare them away. Many students might desire to study science or music but have no desire to teach. Why should they go to another school when we have the facilities to serve them as well or better than any other school in this part of the country?
TPI has changed to Tennessee Tech; West Tennessee STC has changed to Memphis State; East Tennessee STC has changed to Tennessee State; so why don't we all work together and get rid of this tongue twisting paragraph that has heretofore been our name? This move is not official, and will not be until the student body gets behind it with enough force. Let us all promise ourselves to never use the old name again; from now on let us be just MURFREESBORO STATE.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Name change</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Middle Tennessee State Teachers College; Universities and colleges--Names</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:type>image/jpeg</dc:type>
<dc:format>Clipping</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected. Reproduced with permission of the University</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Reproduction is permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only; Credit to Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:rights>
<dc:relation>Sidelines Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/mtsu1/id/688</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>