<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Normalite, 1923 January</dc:title>
<dc:source>Middle Tennessee State Normal School</dc:source>
<dc:date>1923-01-01</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1920-1929</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>The Normalite was a Middle Tennessee State Normal School publication</dc:description>
<dc:description>A Letter- PHILIP MANKIN 2
1
Comparison of American and English Constitution-
HANNAH BELCHER 3
What is to Become of the Home- MARGARET SANDERS 4
A l\ 1edley- SETH STUART : : 10
Letters to Annie Laurie 11
Editor's Notes 13
Hits, Runs and Errors c&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226; 15
Physical Education " 16
Home Economics 22
Literary Societies ...................&#8226;............... ':..~ .24
Faculty 27
Chapel Talks 29
Locals 30
Alumni 32
Y. M. C. A 34
Y. W. C. A 35
Exchanges 37
Athletics 39
I t Pays to Advertise .40
Advertisements 43
COMPARISON OF AMERICAN AND ENGLISH'
CONSTITUTION
Although comparisons of the American and of the Eng&#173;r
h constitutions are constantly being made, and although the
t: o forms of government are strikingly similar, sti~ l the fU~ &#173;damental
laws of America and of England are decldedly dIf-ferent
in their natures.
In the first place the American constitution is a creation.
It was the result of their political experiences. In a way it
was an experiment, and the outcome was doubtful.
On the other hand, the English constitution ' is' a growth.
It was begun way back when a settled form of government
was first established in England, and it has developed from
this early form.
The American constitution is a formal written document..
Our fore fathers put in ink all the principles upon which they
wanted our government founded. They meant to draw up a.
rigid code which would regulate the laws of the land; but.
their hopes have not been realized. Instead of rigidity our
constitution has developed a decided elasticity. This has.:
come about through a free interpretation of its principles..
Almost anything can_ be read into it ~ hrough the medium of
loose construction.
The opposite is true In England. The English people:
really have no constitution. It does not exist as a legal writ- &#183;
ten paper. It is a combination of customs and traditions,.
there being only three definite tangible principles such as the
Magna Charta, the VV rit of Habeas Corpus, and the Bill of
Rights. But the English people are bound strictly to the pYin&#173;ciples
of their constitution, intangible as they may seem to
us. It is practically impossible to change it, although it is
constantly growing. This is true since it becomes necessary
sometimes to make some new decisions which immediately
become part of the constitution, and, there'fore, a precedent
for all future cases of a similar nature. Thus the American
constitution is growing very little but constantly changing
=
- PHILIP MANKIN.
A LEITER
What is a letter? ' Tis a bit of you
Before me as I read.. YOur thoughts, your heart
Lie in its lines and from their covert start
Smiling to greet me with a feeling true
As in the twilight heavens clear and blu~
! he ev'ning star welcomes the rising moon.
It comes to me like some remembered tune
Bringi~ g in outlines mystic to my view '
The scenes and friends of gray- haired yesterday
When you were with me and our closest thou&lt; Yht
W . b e mterchanged with friendship's ease. My way
And yours have parted since; but still are fraught
Your letters with the soul I miss. Today,
I find therein the presence I have sought .
- HANNAH G. BELCHER.
WHAT IS TO BECOME OF THE HOME?
THE NORMALITE s.
.' rId' he knows no other. For a number of
d It IS his wo , ., l'f
. I' flueoces that operate upon his unfoldmg I e
the on Y tn .
earsb se that the home furnishes . Some parents thmk tha. t
e to. ture to be petted and fondled, as may SUIt
babe IS a crea 1
b bl. ms 0 f h'IS elders, until he is old enough to be capab e
t e W &#8226;&#8226; f rmal education and discipline. Recent stud-f
recelvtng 0 .. I ? s of childhood have shown that such a view IS ut~ er y er-
Ie Th hild begins to dev~ lop the moment hIs senses
roneous. e c . d b h'
are stl. mulated by the strange sights a. nd soun, s a out 1m.
o , he doesO't know what you do for hIm nor the thtngs yo, u
H doesn't understand a father's love and a mother s s~. e . d
k nduare, but there is not one of these thmgs that oe. s not
ke impression on his plastic nature. ~ ater on he WIll ~ n-rstand
and later on other influences begm to touch the child
e in such a way as to modify the influence of the home. But
r a &#183; long time the home has a distinct ad: anta~ e o~ e~' all
her educational agencies. It has a great, Silent, IrreSistible,
ennanent influence. Our habits are formed under the mould-
&#8226; g power of the home. The most illustrious sta~ e~ men, the
ost distinguished warriors, the most eloquent mlmsters and
he greatest benefactors on human kind owe their greatnesS
o the fostering influence of the home." Napoleon' knew and
felt this when he said, " What France wants is good mothers
and you may be sure then that. France will have good sons."
The homes of the American Revolution made the men. Their
Buence reaches yet far into the inmost frame and constitu &#183; &#183;
on of our glorious republic. It is just because of this subtle
power of the home to influence all human beings that earnest
n are today anxiously inquiring, " What is to become of
e home?"
The home Qf the nineteenth century may be likened unto
great river; its surface, broken by waves and lashed by
rnpests hut just beneath the turmoil the water moving
uietly, steadily, onward to the sea.
One wave that ruffles the surface of the great river is the
evalence of divorce. Marriage is the most sacred of all hu&#173;an
ties and on it is founded the home. But divorces are
eadily and rapidly increasing. United States leads the so-
4 THE NORMALITE
in practice, while the English constitution never changes, but
is growing constantly.
Another'difference in the two systems is the theory of
powers of government. The American constitution provides
for an almost complete separation of the executive, legisla&#173;tive
and judicial branches of government. Each department
is to be nearly independent of the other two in the discharge
of its duties, but is not completely free. The check and bal&#173;ance
syste~ prev~ nts the usurpation o'f too much power by
anyone department. In England all departments are respon&#173;sible
to the same head, the prime minister.
Although the two governments attain the same end,
they use . somewhat different methods. One is typical of a
new and experimenting nation, the other is typical of an old
conservative people.
( Prize essay' delivered at spring commencement 1922)
The proble &#183; m of the home is not America's problem alone,
but the problem of the world. It is a world problem in that
it is accorded the place of pre- eminent importance in the
making of manhood and womanhood. It is a world problem
because the home has no equal as an educational agency. It
is a world problem in that the home has the most lasting in&#173;fluence
of all institutions. Finally, it is a world problem today
because ne. wspapers, magazines and books are filled with ar&#173;ticles
on the home. And what say these articles? That the
homes are changing. If so, in what direction are they headed?
Some &#183; one has said of late years the home has suffered
~ omething in the nature of a partial eclipse. Is this position
of the home merely incidental to human progress or does it
mark a downward step of a potent and divine institution?
it~ influence upon childhood as well as upon all individuals
will help to show why the pr. esent condition of the home is
not' merely a thing to be known and passed by.
. ment of our social being." The home is everything to the
" Our nature demands home. It is the first essential e1e-
7
THE NORMALITE
n home- makers, hous~ &#173;""
e hear and see wo
me
. ' b Is it because they
where VI &#8226; g for a JO . b .
every others c1atnO nn en have become 0 - nd tn ' me wom
pers a ? Indeed no! but so L' n Abbott express-en't
anY &#183; . for public work. yma . " It seems
ith a manta . f 11 when he sayS.
": of this so beautl u Y
h
ld think it greater work
Views an s ou ' t
15 me that any wom men and women than 1
range to art in governing grown , ho are able to govern
lJgve a P rown men and women W or who out of the
to tna~: gWe admit the_ work of ~.~~~~;~ but it isn't com-
:: l~ a; makes the
k
stfa:~: ~; he~ whO' out of the plastic
. h the wor 0 table Wit &#8226; In "
made the living LlncO " tones thrown upon the
f today are as S , ,. h t
The amusements 0 ,. cirdes on the river unOl: ey a
. kOng ever- enlarglng ,
tet rna 1 d '
t reach the waters e ge. to be regarded as a
. . h home has come. ' .' f '
In. some Cltles t e f " 1 hould a v01d as ar as
b f the amI Y s .
ce which all mem ers 0 a h" it, of leaving home In
Y
cano Hlndividuals now have d ' l'n order to be born;
d t b amuse even '
der to eat, in or er 0 e h their clothes and when
ey return to it in order t~ s ~ h: n~: lY resort for them." Th~~
t eyare so sleepy that bed musements have large-nt
but our a .
s an exaggerated stateme Th girl no longer gIVeS
ly been taken away from the home'
h
ehome but at the clu, b.
h h dance at er
et tea, her lunc eon, er .' how' at the thea-
, . t the plcture s ,
e boy spends his evemngs a ,
r or the club room. be likened to
.' . the home may
Indifference to reltglon ln h' h t only touch
. d th stream w lC no
ks of ice floatmg own e ' l t . difference to
1 Shall we e In
surface but flow far be ow.' .
etigion go deeper in home life? . l' the
b utiful object eSSo n
The most precious and ea ' ties has
d h heathen commum
Christian religion has presente t e h h Ids of the
B h t of the ouse 0, ' be~ n the missionary's home. ut w a " th labor in
, d b ' ld the house ey
ome land? " Except the Lor Ul ,
in who build it." . but no
f . 0 is the stream
You may think as the sur ace lS, s ,
called Christian world in the number of divorces. Among
all civilized nations she is surpassed only by Japan. " But
statistics cann t record the destruction of hopes, the blighting
of character, the blunting of the moral senses that are the
consequences of the broken marriage vow. Nor does the
larger part of the wreck and ruin eve'r come to view- the dis&#173;cords,
fhe strifes , the shame , the nervous breakdowns, the
ins~ nity, the , suicides and the resulting shock to friends and
relatives that often precede and still more often follow di&#173;v?
rces. However th. ese thin~ s are trag~ dies to the man and
the woman involved, are' as nothing when compared with
the~ fundamental unfairness, cruelty and crime against the
child in robbing him of his di~ it~ e right and heritage the stu&#173;pendous
formative influence ofa true and untainted home.
Only a thorough student of history can get even a glimpse
into the magnitude and multitude of the calamities involved
in such a growing dissolution of the home. Divorce, though,
is a symptom rather than the disease of the bi-, eaking up of
home life.
, While the divorce evil ruffles the surface of the great
river, the heavy wave of women in business may break it into
f() am. ' '
It i~ ~ trikingly apparent that more and more modern fem&#173;inism
is withdrawing the best of women from marriage and
, /,'
motherhood" and is tending toward the overestimation of
public work. The modern, complaint of wom~ n is that the
care of the house has divorced her, from growing interest,
from literature, from the newspaper, partly from music, en&#173;tirely
from p~ litics.' If this complai~ t b~ justly made it should
not be, for of all human beings the mother should be the most
educated. She should have a knowledge or' publ, ic affairs ( not
meaning she. has to ta; k. e the stump; let the woman who isn't
a mother and hasn't a home do that.) The mother should
read current literature and she should be interested in all
th'ings her husband and children are interested in. For as far
as , the home and ' a family are concerned, educate a w'oman
and you educate a household; educate a man and you educate
one. She is being t'empted by the professions open to her,
THE NORMALITE
- there is an evermoving undercurrent in the great river
which the storms and tempests can not check.
. I1f1 w. e knew the home only as we read of it in print' es-pecla
y m newspapers, there would be great cause for alarm
but we must remember that newspapers print the exception_
al, not the usual conditions and their reports of life are not
much more accurate than portrayals of life upon the st
M bl' . . age.
ore pu IClty and Importance is given to criminal and di-vorce
cases than any other forms of litigation. These reports
not, only have the prominent part and place in our own pa&#173;per
but also receive notoriety in all daily news. Does this
prove that these are the most pr, evalen't and influential fac&#173;tors
, in life? By no means is this true for it will be a dan&#173;gerous
time when the scandals and number of divorces are
not reported but in their' stead the acts of goodness and the
num~ er of happy homes, for since it is the exceptional that
receives the most lime- light we may know the acts of good-
, ness and happy homes are. in the minority, when they are se&#173;lect.
ed for press publicity. The honesty and integrity of our
upnght men and women, who form the great mass of our
population, are never mentioned. The thousands of husbands
and wives who live happily together and bring their children
up in a spirit of virtue and peace are not ever known.
The foundation of the home is love. It is the depth of
, our great river. The home is not without its charm and no&#173;bility,
for its brick and mortar enshrine a spirit which is wor&#173;shiped
and for which much may be s~ crificed. Lessons in
love, patience, self- control and unselfishness are learned as
persons live together sharing one another's joys and sorrows,
discouragements and aspirations. The husband loves to' come
home after the trials and cares of the husy day are ~ ver and
find happiness. He is glad to know when he hears his front
door close behind him he has shut the world of business out&#173;side
and has his world of happiness within. " Pere Hyacinthe,
the great French pulpit orator, gives us a beautiful word pic&#173;ture
of the mystic power of the home to shape the soul of
man as he describes the return of a father to his family after
the day's work." ' Now, he says to himself, ' 1 shall have twO
8 THE NORMALITE THE NORMALITE
that will be like balm to my mind and heart:
e hours fl' k' . h' h'
t his fireside, and ee s qUlc enmg Wit m 1m
~ wna .
b I
&#183; deepest in man- deeper than sCience and pol-hie:
les ' . -
t
han business and the tOll and tumult of modern
deeper "
h
i aspiration of human nature. He takes upon hiS
e 0 Y . 1 . k h' f
g
est child and the htt e mnocent stro es IS ace
youn' .
ba pY hands- happy because pure. Dear httle hands!
h; Y fondle the wrinkles ~ f his ? row and the scars of
unds t and in the breath of the child the father breathes,
ere a breath wafted from Paradise! He listens with
at those simple but sublime prattlings that are utter-he
language of men and partly in the language of men
rtly in the speech of angels." Pere Hyacinthe has shown
peace and quietude of the home to a person in the
but love and home influence lives long after the family
s been broken. It was the thought of home and the
nation to protect the family that led the American
o victory. Many a hardened criminal and outlaw has
oved to tears by a mother's presence and the thoughts
orne. This theme not only has moved crimimlls but
udiences of cultured people. Years ago some twenty
people gathered in the old Castle Garden, New York,
Jennie Lind sing. She sang, as no artist had ever
e compositions of Beethoven and Handel. At length
edish singer thought of her home paused, and began
ep emotion to pour forth " Home Sweet Home." The
e could not stand it. An uproar of applause stopped
ie. " Tears gushed from those thousands like rain."
en and Handel were forgotten but Howard Payne
d over the great masters of song~ " Home , that was
d that held, as with a spell those twenty thousand
What is the charm that lies in this simple home song,
it live? The answer is easy. Next to religion the
ntiment in the human soul is that of home affec&#173;is
the depth of the river that is really worth while
after all. ' , '
may therefore, feel assured that the family is not to
om the earth. Established in the olden time, contin-
, A MEDLEY
" We were crowded in a cabin,
He cast his eyes down at the floor,
Then looked above his head,
He could not think at all, Oh, no!
And this i~ what he said:
1' 1
- SETH STUART.
THE NORMALITE
LEITERS TO ANNIE LAURIE
both great and small
Id that my tongue could utter
U I ,
e Celestial Wal s .
he night before Christmas,
clocks were striking the hour
es there a man with soul so dead,
the dark church tower.
nie Laurie:
y oom- mate tells me Lemon cold cream is best. I use
&#183; gtlt. Which do you think will make me most attrac&#173;Hettie.
too young to use creams and oint&#173;Annie
Laurie.
Annie Laurie:
ch time I smile or speak to my girl in the dining hall
utledge frowns at us. Could you help me correct this
IOn). Seagraves.
. rtainly, my boy, eat at another table. But do you
I the proper thing to flirt in the dining hall?
Annie Laurie.
Annie Laurie:
&#8226; gentleman friend came to call when I was not expect&#173;tn.
My hair was in poppi- yops and my complexion not
e sures are like pOJ&gt; pies spread;
I have crossed the bar,
eyes forget the tears they shed,
Clen like a baleful star!
() h ring, for liberty!
et who will be clever,
stood on the burning deck,
' fa on foreverl
THE NORMALITE
ued throughout the generations ministering to the d
d d
. .' . eepest
nee s an to the hIghest satlsfactIOns of humanity, l &#183; t repre
sents a force both human and divine. To doubt it ~
. .. . s resto~
ra. tton IS to dIstrust the . fun. dam. ental instincts and aspl. ra.
tIOns of man. Not only wIll It surVIve, but it shall also corne.
to occupy a yet more majestic place in the hearts and I b
of the race." . a ors
After all it is the depth of river that really counts.
- MARGARET SANDERS.
" There was an old woman who lived In a shoe
And life the sweeter made, '
I've b. een looking all over creation for you,
With the poor crooked scythe and spade.
There stood the senior all frightened and blue
Of olden days many poems &#183; he knew;
Yet when called upon to recite a piece,
His fuddled mind did start, then cease.
10
" Into the sunshine,
Bob- o- link, bob- a- link,
Tell me not in moundul numbers,
Spink, spank, spink.
" It was the Schooner Hesperus .
Th~ breaking , waves dashed high,
l! nder a, spreading chestnut tree
I would lay me down and die.
THE NORMALITE 13
unications to Business Manager. Advertising rates
furnished upon request.
e past few months we have labored in seasen
good of the NORMALITE and we feel justly
Busineas Staff
OW &#183; &#183; Business Manager
DON &#183; &#183; Associate Business Manager
T LEY &#183; &#183; &#183; Associate Business ~ lanager
. WYNN Faculty Adviser
Editorial Staff
ENT Editor- in- Chief
GRIGSBY Associate Editor- in- Chief
. Athletics
: A. RTIN Y. M. C. A.
WATSON Faculty
RAHAM BELCHER Locals, Fun
KING &#183; &#183; ~~~~~~~~ &#183; .~~~~~~~ &#183; .~~~~~~~ &#183; . &#183; .~~~~~~~~~~~ &#183; .~~:~.~:.~.~~~~ E~~ cae:;
OGERS .............................................................. Alumnl.
GRIGSBY Y. W. C. A., Glee Club
de for entry as second- class matter at the Postoffice at
boro, Tenn., under Act of Congress, March 3, 1879
nthly by the students of Middle Tennessee Normal, Mur&#173;freesboro,
Tennessee
A good leader is a good follower.
Be generous in feeding your mind; nourish it and ca
for it well. _ Selected.
Annie Laurie.
THE NORYALITE
Dear Annie Laurie:
I am afraid I'll flunk on Practice Teaching, because I've
devoted too much time to my beaux. Could you infiuence
Mrs. Marshall in my behalf?
Dessie Bray.
Try sharing all of your candy with the teacher in ques.
tion. . Annie. Laurie.
Dear Annie Laurie:
I have been going with a young man ( twice) who said
I was his ideal but on the last three open nights he has gon
with some one else. How can I win him back?
Mary Hurt.
My Dear Mary: Always let the young men seek your pres
ence, not you seek theirs. Have patience and I feel sure your
trouble will soon be o'er. Annie Laurie.
Dear Annie Laurie:
My sweetie sent me a string of pearls Xmas. Mother
has said I must return them. Please tell me what to do.
Louise Templeton.
Dear Louise: Do as your mother suggests. Never accept
a handsome gift from a young man who is only your friend
Annie Laurie.
Dear Annie Laurie:
Mack told me goodbye as I was leaving in the
way,'. Mrs. Rutledge saw us. What shall I do?
Margaret W.
Take your medicine, my child, experience should ba
taught you that such a course was not wise at M. T. N.
Annie Laurie.
on. Since then he has acted strange and indifferent.
would you advise me to do?
G s B--- g ( Vcitor's Girl.)
Stay dressed up and act natural.
prouj&lt;; L, of ,,! he results. This result has been reached through
the' dilige'nt effort of the individual members of the staff and
the hearty co- operation of the student body. We are grate&#173;ful
for this help and we trust that it will continue.
Our aim, is to get out a magazine of quality rather than
quantity. It is not the purpose of the NORMALITE to carry
a great mCl: ss of worthless material for the sake of bulk. We
want a real~ live, worthwhile magazine whose worth is based
upon : merit due to the quality of the stuff it contains. We
shall not attempt to enlarge ' the magazine, but rather shall
we b~, mo~ e careful in selecting from the great mass of ma&#173;terial
which we receive only that which deserves to be pub&#173;lished.
This will require more care on the part of our con&#173;tributors
in preparing their articles. You should not expect
a carelessly prepared manuscript to receive any considera&#173;tion.
Devote some time and thought to what you turn in and
make it of value. Be more careful in the preparation of your
manuscript. We cannot accept articles illegibly written on
scrap paper. We have neither the time nor the inclination to
decipher the puzzles contained in such manuscripts and to
copy them for the publisher. If you cannot write legibly
have some one write it for you or have it typewritten. Please
sign your names to all contributions. If you do not wish to
have your name published make a note of it and we will with &#183; &#183;
hold its publication, but it is necessary to know the source of
what we publish. Otherwise it will be thrown into the waste
basket where it rightfully belongs, for what is not worth
acknowledging is not worth a place in our magazine.
Department editors, please see that your departments
are written up in an interesting manner. Make these depart&#173;ments
live and interesting to our readers. This can be done
by getting to the point and not covering up what you have
to say with a lot of words.
Ap material for publication must be in the hands of the
editor' not later than the seventh of the month for publication
in the issue of t, hat current month.
Everybody get busy and do something for the NOR&#173;MALITE
and let's make it better every time.
Margaret Ward: You don't know what it is to love.
Puckett: I don't eh? Haven't I been to every play, read
every popular novel, an~ got hopelessly into debt all for your
sake?
THE NORMALITE 15
HITS, RUNS AND ERRORS
Some minds are like concrete- thoroughly mixed and
permanently set. - J. P. D.
It is rumored that we are to have some form of open
evening entertainment this term. Who knows! We may.
Correct this sentence: " You may have anything you
like on your course card," said Mr. Wynn to a new student.
The only genuine superi~ rity is that of the mind or char-acter.
- Selected.
Lela : McDaniel: Why are you like a light house?
Frances Easley: I s. ppose because I am so brilliant.
Lela: Nope, it's because you're light In the upper story.
Miss Fontaine: With one stroke of the brush I can
hange a smiling child into a weeping one.
e Mildred Ridley ( dryly) That's nothing I can do the same
thing with a paddle.
Huffman says he is afraid John Christian is competing
with. him in vocal exercise. The result is awful.
" Keep on Working Fast"
If the way looks gloomy,
And your chances slim,
And the situation's puzzling,
And the prospects grim,
And difficulties keep pressing,
Until all hope is past;
Always have good intentions,
And keep on working fast.
- J. POPE DYER.
14 THE NORMALITE
" GOOD POSTURE AND HOW TO TEACH IT"
THE NORMALITE 17
FOUR TYPES OF BAD POSTURE
I. " Fatigue" Type
&#183; This type is the commonest type because though the
habitual carriage of some people, it is the
collapsed or relaxed position that one nat&#173;urally
assumes when fatigued ( Fig. 2). In
this position the neck and head drop for&#173;ward
and the upper part of the trunk sinks,
backward, the lower trunk slopes forward,
which gives three distinct lines indicating
the axis of the three main divisions of the
body instead of one continuous, vertical
line.
HOW TO JUDGE CORRECT AND INCORRECT POSTURE
Test One: The Vertical Line.
The long axis of the trunk of - the body is a vertical fine.
A line may be dropped from the front of
_ the ear to the forward part of the foot as
shown by line in Fig. 1. In poor posture the
the ear to the forward part of the foot, as
forming one continuous vertical line, are
. broken into two or three zigzag lines as
explained in Fig. II. This test serves for
estimating the poise of the entire body ex&#173;cept
the shoulders, which &#183; should lie flat on
V~~: k4: tthe back. This test may be applied both to
.~( J~. children of all ages and to adults.
their collapsed posture and imperfect carriage, their slouch&#173;ing
gait, and in extreme cases their inability to stand erect.
16 THE NORMALITE
Physical Education
Department
":' hat i. s Good Posture? It is that erect position of the
b. ody In ,: hIch each part and each organ is in its correct rela&#173;tIve
postIOn with the rest of the body.
Why should we stand in Good Posture? Because erect
carriage of the body is necessary;
( 1) for full vigor and health
( 2) t? preve~ t. waste of energy in maintaining the up&#173;rIght
posItIon and
( 3) to admit proper growth and development with chil-dren.
. To make plainer what is meant by each of these points,
It may be' stated that only in the perfectly erect position of
the body are the great organs of the trunk- heart, lungs,
st~ mach and others which constitute the main working ma&#173;chInery
of the body- in a position to perform their work to
the b~ st adva~ tage; while in the habitual bad carriage of the
body In w~ lkmg, st. anding, sitting, or in occupation, may in&#173;terfer.
e serIously wIth the great functions of circulaton res-piration,.
digestion, elimination, etc. '
The body is an upright column, but one that is broken
with joints at many points- head, hips, knees, ankles , and
throughout the length of the spine with its vertebrae. In a
perfectly poised standing positon, the different parts and seg&#173;ments
are so balanced that comparatively slight effort is nec&#173;essary
to maintain the position.
The relation of erect posture to intelligence and brain de&#173;velopment
is marked and of great interest. Among the most
marked characteristics of idiots and mental defectives are
THE NORMALITE 19
The class should be divided into two groups- Division I,
composed of those who pass the test, and Division II, of those
who' do not pass. Both groups should take their gymnastics
at the same time, but stand in two distinct groups, which en&#173;ables
the teacher to concentrate attention, on the division
most needing help for correction. This grouping also in&#173;cites
Division II to work for promotion to Division 1.
The Triple Test consits in judging each child's position
in ( 1) standing, ( 2) prolonged marching ( four or five min&#173;utes),
and ( 3) selected exercise.
I. Standing Test
Look the pupils over in profile. Those not standing in
good posture should be asked to move to one side. After
looking them over from the side of the room, those who stand
well shouid be made ready for the next test.
2. Marching Test
The pupils selected for their good standing position
GROUPING FOR POSTURE AND " THE TRIPLE TEST."
IV. " One- sided or Lateral Curvatures."
These types of defects are most, readily seen from the
front or back. These de-
~. \ fects, of which lateral curv-
) ature of the spine is the
FR;,~::' &#183; . , condition most. often indi-cated
and for which one
shioud be most watchful.
See Figs. 5 and 6. This con-
: J' . S. 3-~. fa dition may be discovered by
~ ~{ J&amp;. uu one shoulder being lower
~' ~. than the other, by the head
being carried on one side, or by a tipping or yielding of the
shoulder to one side habitually- so that the hips are of un&#173;even
height. A curvature may be detected by tracing the
iine of the spine itself down the back with the fingers, or one
shoulder blade may be more prominent than the other.
18 THE NORMALITE
&#183; ! I. " The Obliterated Lumbar Curve" Type.
This type is one in which the lower part 0'&#163; the back is
straight. The natural inward curve of
the spine at the " small of the back" is
obliterated, and the back is straight
or even bowed outright. ( Fig. 3.) Ac&#173;companying
this straight lower back,
' the line of the neck and head protrude
as'in the fatigue p6sition. This post&#173;ure
is one of the most harmful, but as
a standing position is less frequently
found than the fatigue position.
III. The " Bantam" Type.
The " bantam" type is induced by over- exertion, rather
than by relaxation as are the fa tigtie and
flat- back positions. Thi stype comes from
a mistaken effort to lift and expand the
chest, which draws the chest forward, like
that ot a bantam. ( Fig. 4.) The upper part
of th~ spine is overextended, so that it
forms a marked exaggeration of the natu&#173;ral
curve in the small of the back. This
position is a mistaken effort on the part of
the child to " make himself tall"- an effort ~ J-.'. 4:
I . f . ~~ '.~
t lat IS 0 ten mduced by unwise commands - ~ rr- v.
from his elders. To guard against it in children, where it
does the most harm, one should be watchful for the extreme
hollow. in the back, as well as for the lifting too high of the
chest.
should be given a test in marching. An effort should be made
during the test to distract their attention from any artificial
effort for posture, by drilling on facings, marking time, etc.
As the marching proceeds, old muscular habits will reassert
themselves, and many pupils who can hold a correct position
for a few minutes of quiet standing will fall into habitual
faulty attitudes as they march. As these faults occur, the pu"
pils should be dropp. ed out of line.
3. Exercise Test.
The third test is designed to show the strength and co&#173;ordination
of those muscles that are weak in poor posture,
particularly those that hold the spine erect. In certain ex.
ercises , especially those that put the arms in an upward po&#173;sition,
the back muscles, if weak, allow the body to react with
poor positions. Head drooping forward, the upper chest sink&#173;ing
backward or if the lumbar region muscles be weak ali.
over- extention backward may occur, ( Fig. 4) - leading to the
excessive hollow in the ba&lt;; k.
System of Testing.
The Triple Test should be given each month to entire
class. Posture fluctuates in individuals as conditions of fa&#173;tigue,
lack of sleep, poor nutrition or illness of any other kind
may effect it.
Division I should be composed of those who have habit-tially
good posture Rated A.
Division II composed of those who are good most of the
time, but who may fluctuate somewhat Rated B.
Promotion for Posture
One of the essential elements in the success of this
group- teaching for posture is the zest with which pupils work
for promotion from Division II to Division 1. The test alone
will not arouse this interest; the grouping must be a distinct,
systematic part of each lesson. This cannot be too strongly
stated. The interest of the pupils in promotion is one of the
most marked features of these methods, and the teacher
should arouse pride and ambition to this end.
Hints for Obtaining Good Posture.
Splendid results may be obtained by keeping the " Good
LUELLA W. WILSON.
AN EXPERIMENT
THE NORMALITE 21
Lost: A nice blonde moustache. Please return to Paul
Caroll.
Habits' ' before the child's mind. Have charts made
posture " H H &#183; h"
gested ODe posture idea. For example: ead 19,
" sCughin In," " Stand Tall," and any other'slqgan that I. S h &#183; 19hIY
d criptive of good posture. Care must be taken that these
sleosgans do not lead to over- exertion or to the ". bantam" type.
A banner may be awarded for ~ he month to the class
who has the best record in posture or to the class that shows
the greatest gain.
Special attention may be given to the posture grade on
the report cards sent home to the parents each month.
Above all children should be made intelligent not only
as to the poi; ts of good posture, but as to the reason for it.
They should know that it makes room for the lungs to act a~ d
to develop, helping to strengthen them so that they can reSIst
disease and properly purify the ' blood, that the heart and gen &#183;
eral circulation, the stomach and digestion, are all bett~ r
when the organs concerned are given proper room for th~ lr
work. They should know that in poor posture the 0PPOSlt~
of all this is true.
When it comes to teaching of poultry, Mr. Gracy is a
marvel. He wished to demonstrate the economic feeding of
a flock so he devised the original plan of using a food to
which ~ little sawdust was added. The fowls seemed to do
just as well on this diet, so he decided to use more sawdust.
This time the food was made one- third sawdust. On this the
birds really seemed to improve, so the elated prof~ ssor in&#173;creased
the ratio to one- half sawdust.- The flock sttll seem&#173;ed
to do just as well so he thought then he would give them
nothing but sawdust. He was delighted to find that they
Seemed to enjoy this fare. One fateful day he s~ t some
of the eggs and what do you suppose hatched out. - wood
peekers.
20 THE NORMALITE
Who said that the Home Economics Club would not be a
success? We just want to see the color of the hair of that
person. Since our organization in September we have had
several very delightful meetings and social hours. The two
meetings of November were held in the Dromgoole Hall
which proved to be a much better place for them as it gives
us more room and also access to a piano.
For a long time the boys had been sniffing the good odors
floating out from the kitchen but not a single man was al&#173;lowed
to cross the threshold. All the cooks and sewing ladies
had been working hard and saying nothing to anybody about
what they were doing. On Thursday, Dec. 14, the doors were
thrown open and all of the boys who received invitationsc'on&#173;sidered
themselves lucky fellows. It was a gay party that
gathered in Room 17 at three o'clock. The room was attrac&#173;tively
decorated in Christmas colors, and a large Christmas
tree stood behind a screen , at one end of the room. In the
first contest : Mr. Cyrus Miller and Mr. Bruce Overton repre&#173;sented
the two sides of the room. The object of the contest
was to eat three crackers and whistle, and the way Overton
did put those crockers away-! He certainly showed a great
deal of skill and speed. Of course we were not present on
Christmas day when that turkey was set before him, but I
think anything you might want to bet that he did justice to
th'e old bird would be safe. Overton will never starve from
eating at the dining hall unless something keeps him from
being on on hand when the bell rings. There was another
very clever " Ice" contest that Miss Marvel Bass and Mr. Wil&#173;liam
Byrns won. The screen was then taken down and dear
old Santa Claus himself came in to be with us for a while and
to giye out the presents which loaded the tree. Everyone
was remembered with a delightful and ' appropriate gift. Af&#173;ter
Santa delivered all the gifts he wished each a " Merry
Christmas" and hurried back to his preparation for the com&#173;ing
holidays. Large trays of Christmas candies were then
passed and it was voted unanimously that the cooks are cer-
23 THE NORMALITE
, h? " Ham and peas" is that w at you say.
Have them the ye'ar round every Sunday, :
Well the reason is this, now don't look gruff&#173;It
takes all that time to get enough."
( Written in the girl's dormitory during a rain)
0, you numerous little rain. drops!
Just before my window gli~ m~
Gliding on, down the electnc hne. .
How much you are like so many hves
Gliding on, down the line of time.
You glide along one by one until
To Mother Earth, who consumes all,
You drop, as all soo, n or late must do.
Don't be disheartened; there is, one always
' Trailing in your footprints close behind,
Waiting to fill your place upon the line.
- B. C.
ODE TO THE RAIN DROPS
tainly on their job. Everyo~ e who came enjoyed the time
d pronounced the party qUlte a success.
an The last meeting of the quarter was held on Friday, , De-b,
15 to elect officers for the coming quarter. The ,&#163; 01&#173;cern
er ,
lowing officers were elected: ' '
Winnie Wilson, President.
Mary Hill King, Vice President.
Emma Overby, Secretary.
Mrs. Bryan Lyon, Treasurer.
Gladys Smith, Reporter.
Miss Little, Critic. ,
The Home Economics Club has proved to be a greatsuc-d
uring the first quarter of its existence and we are sure
cess , dT b
that the work will be carried on with the same 11gence y
the new staff of officers. '
Wanted: . .
A Cook; will'trade a Baker. See ~ 1l1dred Shlppey.
THE NORMALITE
HOME ECONOMICS CLUB
22
)
25 THE NORMALITE
. ch a way as to prove most profitable and so as to rk 10 su .
edound to the honor and advancement of t~ e Grady Llterary
eiety.
Dro~ oole
We are indeed glad to have so many for~ er Dron: gooles
k with tis this term, many who were not here dunng the ~~ term. A familiar greeting in the halls is, " Sure I am glad
h &#183; D I?" b back and how are t e romgoo es . . o e , ..
With our new ~ o~ ps of officers we ~ r~ expectmg to do
more work this term than has ever been done before. The
&#171; icers for the winter term are:
President Georgia Bell
Vice President Hannah G. Belcher
Secretary Gladys Bowling
Treasurer Verna Eason
Sergeant- at- Arms Florence Woodard
Critic Geraldine Grigsby
Claxton
The Claxton Literary Society, i~ its search for a likeness
of a distinguished literary character, chose the bust of Long&#173;ellow.
In the person of Longfellow we have for example,
for study, and for emulation the most widely known and
loved of all American authors.
In his writings he reflects, not the surface but, the deep "
under currents of American life. He was the poet of the
Whole people. He cherished the love of ~ me, ~ ome~ y vir&#173;tues
and American traditions. He was a behever tn umversal
peace.
Longfellow's bust stands in the poets corner. in West&#173;lIlinster
Abbey symbolizing his fame among Enghsh speak..
ing people. Children celebrate his birthday symbolizing his
hold upon the human heart. . .
Just as we who live today inherit the products of thls
eXcellent man, and others of- his type, 50 are we who are, and
Who are to be, Claxton's the inheritors of the traditions, du&#173;ties
and obligations of our Claxton predecessors. Thu: . does
it fall to us to carryon, to contribute to the tradltions,
achievements and history of our society just as the duties and
THE NORMALITE
T. E. Clark, Editor
Grady
Feeling the desire of accomplishing some genuine ser&#173;vice
for mankind and of establishing a far- reaching precedent,
the Grady~ turned their society into the state legislature dur&#173;ing
two meetings of the past month for the purpose of con&#173;sidering
a bill requiring all women to keep secrets. Human&#173;itarians,
' philanthropists, suffragettes, George Harvey, tem&#173;perance
leaders, etc., may be interested to learn that after
the expenditure of much eloquence, pro and con, the bill fail&#173;ed
to carry.
New officers elected for the winter term are as fol&#173;lows:
President, Bruce Overton; Vice- President, W. C.
Hicks; Secretary, Guy Hatley; Treasurer, Edward Duck;
Chaplain, Philip Mankin; Sergeant- at- Arms, L. A. Huffines;
Critic, Cyrus Dement; Theodoric, Edwin Windrow. .
We wish to invite all new men to visit our society, and,
if they find it convenient, to become one of our fellowship
and aid us in the efforts we are putting forth in the endeavor
to accomplish something really worth while.
Standing at the end of the term and looking back over
this quarter's work, we feel the satisfaction of having accom&#173;plished
much towards the goals of true endeavor. And when
a new year dawns from out the mystic haze of the future,
we look forward with pleasure to carrying on our society
burdens. of citizenship s~ ip from the shoulders of t~ e aged to
the shoulders of the youth.
Henceforth the workings of the society will be carried on
under the lifeless gaze and silent criticism of this master lit&#173;erary
man. From his position on the library case he should
be a speechJ~ ss' contributor to the interest, spirit, and enthu&#173;siasm
of the society. Although we have but a cold, lifeless
form of him we should feel that we have an honored guest
in our midst.
In our society work there' are times when all pep seems
to be gone, when programs are dull, when attendance is slim,
and when everything seems at a standstill , but remember that
Longfellow said:
Let us, then, be up and doing,
With a heart for every fate;
Still achieving still pursuing,
Learn to labor and to wait.
C. J. \\ TOODSON, News Reporter.
Murfree
As Father Time rings his bell of greeting to the New
Year and the echo of the old is heard only in the distance,
the Murfree girls are once more extending their greeting
HHappy New Year." Again we are together with the spirit
that it takes to make any society a success. \
Delightful programs were enjoyed last term, including
several joint meetings with the Gradys. Especially were those
programs a pleasure in which the participants told us of the
life and writings of Mary N. Murfree. May this term prove
such a success with the Murfree Society that the one for
whom she is named, be honored by the part we play in the
student activities.
The officers for the following term are:
President Louise McKnight
Vice President &#183; &#183; &#183; &#183; &#183; &#183; &#183; &#183; &#183; &#183; Mildred Shippey
Secretary ~ Betty Lauderdale
Treasurer Jaunita Hale
Sergeant- at- Arms &#183; &#183; &#183; &#183; &#183; &#183; &#183; &#183; &#183; &#183; &#183; . &#183; &#183; Helen Brown
Critic Louise Templeton
27
/
THE NORMALITE
Margaret &#183; WatSQo, .. Editor
The arrival of the Christmas holidays found both student
body and faculty in anxious readiness for the journeys to
their respective homes and judging from the reports, all
reached the old horne in time to hang their stockings on their
accustomed nail where Santa Claus found them and rewarded
each according to his goodness.
Miss Schardt spent the holidays in St. Louis.
Miss Saunders and her mother visited relatives in Ken &#183;
tucky during the holidays.
IVlr. Wynn visited in Pulaski and Nashville. He deserves
the distinction of being the only faculty member who went
on a big Christmas Hunt.
Mrs. Gillentine toured th. e eastern portion of the state in
interest of the D. A. R.' s. She was cordially received and
enjoyed the trip.
Some one asked how Mr. Brackin spent his vacation and
Mrs. Rutledge said, " I don't know what he did but I have an
idea that he stayed at home and tried to get his head intact."
Mr. Ogden who for the past few weeks has been serious&#173;ly
ill, &#183; is improving rapidly and will soon be able to resume
his regul3: r duties.
Mrs. J. K. Marshall attended the State Democratic com&#173;tnittee
meeting in Nashville on December 28. She also vis-
26 THE NORMAUTE
Room 50 is the point of curiosity this month.
Parks to another place did go,
And broke the heart of poor AVO.
Said Georgie rather rash,
" Marvin, you'll have to shave that moustache,
If with me you wish to go,
For how it scratches, I do know.
ited relatives in Franklin and on January 1, attended the
Qpeing of the State Legislature. .
Miss Fcmtaine visited friends and relatives in Davidson
and Robertson counties during her vacation.
Miss Mamie Jackson returns from her vacation feeling
fine for a year's work with the tots in the Primary Depart&#173;ment.
Misses Ordway, Monahan, Buchanan, Little and Wilso~
and Mrs. Rutledge spent the holidays with home folks.
Mr. Horace Jones spent the holidays in Memphis with
Ex- president and Mrs. R. L. Jones.
Mr. Sims visited in Fayetteville . during the holidays.
Mr. Davis and family are now pleasantly located in their
. new home on the Woodbury road.
Mr. Belcher spent the holidays at home as did also Mr.
Woodward and President Lyon. The latter was making prep&#173;arations
for the large number of new students who are with
us &#183; for this term.
We regret to lose Miss Reynolds, who is now at Pea&#173;body.
We know she hasn't forgotten us because she paid us
a visit recently. '
Mrs. Fertig spent the holidays in New York with her
daughter, Miss Ruth Fertig.
Mr. and Mrs. Gracey and family report a big Christmas
and are again at their accustomed place " keepin. g" the Boys
Dormitory.
The Faculty and Student Body extend deepest sympathy
to Mrs. Barbee in her bereavem'ent and hope that she can
soon return to her post in the dining hall.
THE NORMALITE 29
Margaret Watson, Editor.
After Christmas;
Burns was cooler,
Dement was saner,
Stone was softer.
Who all apologized for not sending the Christmas card
this time? And who all sent a New Year card because he
had received a Christmas card?
Before the holidays we were indeed fortunate III secur- &#183;
noted speakers for chapel.
Reverend Mr. Hill spoke on the subject of the harm of
the use of alcdhol and tobacco.
Ex- Governor Brumbaugh of Pennsylvania, favored us
with a very interesting and instructive talk on Physical Ed&#173;ucation,
~ rging the need of its' adoption by the American
public.
Since the holidays . we have been favored with talks by
President Lyon on " Getting The Year Started Right" and Mr.
Sims on Andrew Jackson, one of the Five Greatest Amer&#173;icans.
Maj. Shores of the Canadian Mounted Police was with
us one day in chapel and also that night in a Lyceum num&#173;ber.
28 THE NORMALITE
The Christmas season was a busy and successful one,
judging by the numerous pens and eversharp pencils one sees
dangling from long black ribbons. Old students coming back
on Wednesday felt a pang of homesickness when they saw
the bevy of strange faces. But it wasn't long before every&#173;body
knew everybody else and felt perfectly at home once
more.
Cy Dement has been traversing the halls for several days
with lagging step and sleepy eye, due to the morning watch
he kept in Chattanooga on January the first.
Weare all excited. Several girls have found a good&#173;looking
man on the campus.
If any o'ne has ever doubted the presence of ingenuity'
and' versatility among the students of the Normal, he should
have gone to the " Stunt" program given shortly before
Christmas. His doubts would have been removed.
If all our lyceum attractions are as attractive as the first
one proved to be we have a great deal to look forward to.
Major Schoof's lecture was rich in thrills and adventure and
his words were an inspiration to both boys and girls. Es&#173;pecially
were his trophies of war and the chase. We were
unable to recognize some of our own fellow students when
they adorned themselves with some of the major's red, but&#173;ton-
trimmed jackets and non- descript helmets. l\ tlajor
AN APPEAL
If a visitor to your home should come,
You wouldn't talk and hum;
Or you wouldn't rattle your seat
Till you couldn't hear him speak.
THE NORMALITE 31
When to chapel you go,
And the programs are long and slow,
Don't twist and squirm
Like a dying worm.
Stirely you've pride enough in M. T. N.
The good- will of all visitors to win,
Then be courteous to those within our gates,
If it does tire you to sit still and straight.
- F. E. R.
The other day Mrs. Brackin brought out one of those
long- necked pickle bottles. Little Thomas, Jr., upon seeing
it exclaimed, " Oh, Mother, that bottle has a neck just like
daddy's."
Schoof's sword tricks were very entertaining, although a
slight degree of uneasiness was sometimes visible on the first
row of seats.
Every student and teacher was grieved to learn of the death
of Mrs. Barb~ e's daughter, on January the fourth. All ex&#173;tend
their heartfelt sympathy to Mrs. Barbee in her sorrow.
Hon . P . L. Harned, Hon. J. T. Fowlkes and Supt. J. B.
Brown were honored guests of the Normal during the first
week of the quarter Their mission was to accept formally
the new buildings on the campus, including the boys'. dormi&#173;tory
and the gymnasium. We hope they will return soon and
will not be so rushed for time.
Mr. and Mrs. Davis, erstwhile rulers of the Moffat House,
have abdicated in favor of Mrs.}. H. Bledsoe.
The NORMALITE congratulates Mr. and Mrs. Ogden
on the arrival of their new son, Harry P., Junior.
THE NORMALITE
Hannah Graham Belcher, Editor.
30
Weare very sorry to report that Miss Lennie Jane San&#173;ders,
a member of the Richard City faculty, is at the time of
this writing in St. Thomas Hospital where she underwent an
operation for appendicitis on December 11. She is doing well.
however , and we hope that by the time this issue of the " Nor&#173;malite"
appears she will be strong again.
Preston Overall, ' 21, better known as " Putty," is acting
as coach and as teacher of agriculture in the High School at
Livingston, Tenn. .
Terrill Twitty, ' 22, is now principal of the High School at
Blanche, Tenn. .
Miss Mamie Q'uandt, ' 22, has charge of the Second Grade
in the East End Grammar School of this town, and is also
taking some work at the Normal.
Miss Leadford, ' 18, is now teaching in Stillwater, Okla.
Cas Miles, ' 20, brother of our honored coach, is coach at
Central High School of Nashville and is takinO' some work b
at Peabody College.
Louise Bond, ' 20, is at horne, this year, near Franklin,
Tenn.
R. E. Haney, ' 20, is principal of the High School at Ad&#173;ams,
Tenn.
Mr. A. W. Smith, ' 13, is Dean and Registrar of T. P. 1.,
which school has as its President another member of the 1913
32 THE NORMALITE
Hester Rog~ rs, Editor
THE NORMALITE
class, Mr. I. M. Smith, as was noted in the December issue
of the " Normalite."
Dewey Hunter, ' 20, who taught for a while in New Mex-ico,
is now a farmer, and is teaching near his home in Sum-ner
County.
Bessie " Blake, ' 20, is now Mrs. George Sullenger of Nash-ville.
Miss Anna B. McFadden, ' 17, who was critic teacher in
the Nofmal for several years, has for the past few years been
teaching in the Grammar School of Murfreesboro.
Herman McDonough, ' 22, is principal of the High School
at New Middleton, Tenn.
Miss Winnie Darden, ' 21, who taught Domestic Science
last year, is now teacher in the elementary grades of the Mt.
Pleasant school.
Miss Effie Whitehead, ' 14, who taught for a number of
years in Shelby county, is now married and living in West
Tennessee.
Miss Leona Graham, who is teaching in ' 01ashington,
Georgia, was visited during Thanksgiving by Mr. Burcham,
WHAT IS JOY?
Oh what is joy?
T s it not the care- free life of a boy?
Little does he know of the trials of man
With his hook and line and old bait can.
The boy now to a youth has grown,
Little by little time has flown;
Still he is free from the cares of life
Free from all its struggle and strife.
The youth now a man in his office sits,
Before him is work he cannot quit,
As it towers above him with might and main
I bet he wishes he was a boy again.
- W. B. GREEN.
THE NORMALITE 35
Geraldine Grigsbyt Editor
1923 holds many plans for the Y. W. C. A. Among them
are the Membership Campaign, World Fellowship drive, a
Rummage sale and a play.
The membership campaign is usually put on about two
weeks after the beginning of the new term, and is always a
marked success. There are about twenty- five new girls in
our midst, and the Y. W. is anxious to enroll each one and
assign some interesting task to be performed.
We hope that the World Fellowship Campaign will fol&#173;low
the membership enrollment; and at the present, we see
no reason for its not doing so. The plan for conducting this
drive has not been determined, but will be announced at a la&#173;ter
date.
The regular semi- annual Rummage Sale is a thing of joy
and pleasure forevermore. Each one contributes his or her
share, and we usually have quite a variety and quantity of
ready- to- wear, etc. This date will also be announced later,
so be prepared to respond freely when you are called upon.
Quite a bit has been said of the play, " The Country Gen&#173;tleman,"
which we think will be up to date in two weeks.
The Y. W. is proud to see so many familiar faces back,
but especially do we welcome those faces yet a little strange
to us.
To give the new students a homely feeling and take away
&#183; Jot THE NORMALITE
As a re~ ult of the visit of Mr. Hulburt to Middle Tennes&#173;see
Nannal m November and through the efforts of the Y. M.
C. A. and the Y. W. C. A. interest in the needs of Russian stu&#173;dents
wa~ created among the student body, and we are pleased
to ~ ake It known to the public that this student body is now
canng for twenty- three Russian students for one year.
Another result of Mr. Hulburt's appearing on the Y. M.
C. A. program during the fall term was the organization of&#173;the
World Polity Club which meets once per month instead
Of the regular "&#165;" meetings on that night. This club will
nave one of the regular meeting nights during January when
a study of France will be made.
On the night of December 8th, the Y . M . c. A. assisted
by the sister organization gave one of the most unique pro&#173;grams
that has ever been given by these two organizations.
. ? ur organization has fulfilled our fondest hopes in mak&#173;mg
Itself so helpful and important a part of the student life
here and we wish to extend to the new students a warm wel&#173;come
to our regular Wednesday night meetings.
Now that the Christmas holidays are over the next thing
to look forward to is term examinations.
Correct this sentence: " I am so glad to get back to the
fare at the dining hall," said a student who had been home
for the holidays.
DO YOU KNOW THE FOODS OF THE ANCIENTS?
There was a Prof. named Wynn,
Who was so exceedingly thin,
That when he essayed, to drink lemonade,
He slipped through the straw and fell in.
37 THE NORMALITE
Mary Hill King, Editor.
We wish to thank those with whom we are exchanging
papers. Most of the schools that we have sent publications to
have been very prompt in responding. We feel like the main
purpose of an exchange department should be constructive
criticism from other schools. As it isn't as easy to see your
own faults and mistakes, as it is for some one else to see
them we desire a criticism from every paper we exchange
with,' even though it may not be so pleasant, as we would
wish. From your criticisms we hope that we may correct
our mistakes and make the NORMALITE the biggest and
best edition published. We hope that in next month's NOR&#173;MALITE
we may mention in our ~ xchange list, many new
acquaintances.
The following publications have been received:
Montgomery Bell Bulletin, Montgomery Bell Academy,
Nashville, Tenn.; The Highland Voice, Pure Fountain High
School, Smithville, Tenn.; The Peabody Volunteer, Peabody
Demonstration School , Nashville, Tenn.; Broadcaster, Ridge&#173;ly
High School, Ridgely, Tenn.; Pleiad, Albion College, Al&#173;bion,
Michigan; The Student, Central Missouri State Teach&#173;er's
College, Warrensburg, Misouri; , The Columns, West Ten&#173;nessee
State Normal, Memphis, Tenn.; Tennessee College
Magazine, Tennessee College, Murfreesboro, Tenn.; Hava&#173;lind
Acts, David Lipscomb College, Nashville, Tenn.; The
THE NORMALITE 36
any " make believe" blues, our first meeting was an informal
" get acquainted" gathering, each girl giving her name and
address.
The Y. W. C. A. greets you all , and hopes for you a most
successful and prosperous year.
Vegetables occupied the most conspicuous places at all
the great Greek banquets.
Cabbage was adored by the Egyptians and they raised
altars to it.
Alexander found the onion in Egypt, and had it culti&#173;vated
in Greece and given as a food to his troops.
Goose was a favorite dish with the Egyptians but their
religion forbade them to eat onions.
The Romans liked egg plants and borrowed names for
them as; beau- faha- Fabius. lentil- Ienticula- Sentulus. Peas-cicerantium-
Cicero. '
The Roman women made excellent black puddings.
Orion, of Greece, invented white sauce.
Bacon was a great utility food among the early Romans.
Asparagus was raised by the Romans, weighed 3 pounds
and grew 12 feet in height.
The Emperor Cladius was fond of mushrooms. He was
poisoned with them by his fourth. wife, Agrippa.
Parsley was used to decorate Horace's banquet balls.
Leek is the National emblem of Wales and has a long
and strange history.
Garlic was given the Roman soldiers as an excitant
In Ancient Rome olives made their appearance in the
first course.
The Christmas Plum Pudding is of Teutonic origin.
- ANON.
Time is one's greatest asset.
The boys who. got a f. ree. shave before Christmas saved a.
big barber bill when their mothers saw them.
Mr. Clark ( at the phone talking to President Lyon) : Did
you have an ad in the paper for a boy to fire the furnace at
the Gray cottage?
Pres. : Lyon: Yes, but I have a boy now.
Clark: Does he give satisfaction?
Pres. Lyon: Yes; I have no complaint to make.
Clark: Well if he fails to give satisfaction call 567.
Mr. Brashear ( to Clark) Well you missed the job.
Clark: No, I have the job; I was just checking up on
myself to see if I were giving satisfaction.
- B. B. YEA~ WOOD.
THE NORMALITE 39
E. P. Eaves, Editc! r
Basketball is King around M. T. N. at present. All road! S
lead to the gymnasium. A rather heavy schedule has been
provided for both boys and girls and it is hoped that the re&#173;sults
will prove more satisfactory than those of the foot ball
season. This can be made more nearly possible by co- opera&#173;tion
on the part of the student body. Let's sh0' Y our loyaltr
to the team by being present at every game , and furthermore
let's give our vocal cords a real test. Let our slogan be, " 1' 11
meet you at the gym."
Quite a bit of enthusiasm and spirit was exhibited by the
students during the class tournaments recently held. in the
new gymnasium &#8226; The honor goes to the Fourth Year Girls
and to the Junior Boys.
During the finals these teams played a brand of ball
clearly superior to that played by any Qther team. This tour:"
nament was very valuable in that it enabled Coach Miles ana'
Miss Wilson to discover good material for the Varsity Five~.
The R. O. B. B.' s are still alive. Watch their work!
38 THE NORMALITE
Echo, Hume- Fogg High School, Nashville, Tenn.; Antelope
State Teachers' College, Kearney, Nebraska. '
Havalind Acts- This is a good publication, your poems
are especially good.
Tennessee College Magazine- A few good jokes might
help your magazine. As a whole this is an interesting pUb&#173;lication.
Highland Voice- A well balanced paper. The story, " A
Christmas Tragedy,", by James Lee, is very interesting and
well written. Your column entitled " Nonsens. e" is very
amusing.
Montgomery Bell Bulletin- You seem to have lots of
pep and school spirit.
Shall we adopt Pennsylvania's slogan?
We believe we have been purely bred,
We know we are strictly led,
We anticipate being loyally wed,
Now will some one please see that we are more wisely
fed - R. W. J.
Ceo. Bates almost picked Prof. Woodward up for a ride
' down Main Street one day.
staring after them &#183; wjht a broken heart. All our fondest
hopes ha~ been shattered at one blow. While we were stand- &#173;jng
in this preoccupied way we were almost knocked from
our feet by some one rushing by us. We followed the hur&#173;rying
figure to see th ecause of his excitement. We soon sav, &#173;for
just as he turned a corner he ran almost into the arms of
Julia. We knew without further thought that this excited
fellow was Bertram and we now knew the cause of his hurry.
It didn't make us any happier to watch the happy greeting
of the two and compare it with that we had just received, so
we just stood envying their happiness.
After a few moments of low talk and soft looks they
made a start toward a taxi stand. Instinctively we followed
them as a hungry man follows a baker's wagon though he
knows the sight of bread will only increase his hunger. Al&#173;most
mechanically we got into the same taxi which they had
taken and we were the only three passengers. We had con&#173;sideration
enough for the happy couple to take the front seat
with the driver and to leave the back seat to them.
It would be a crime to tell of the happy cooing and love
making that took place on that back seat in five minutes, but
we felt that all the time lost during the separation of the hol&#173;idays
was being rapidly made up. By this time we had
thought ourself into such a miserable state that we had de&#173;cided
that the only thing left for us would be a sensational
suicide. But after we had progressed a few blocks they seem~
ed to wake from their trance for we heard Bertram say, " Do
you realize sweetheart that we are back in old Murfrees&#173;boro
?"
" I surely do, dear," Julia replied, " and doesn't it seem
good to be back in a progressive town where the merchants
know that it is good business to advertise?"
" It's like coming home after a trip to Africa," Bertram.
said.
And so their talk continued for some minutes as we drove
down Main Street and across the square. As we passed the
different business houses they would name the merchants
who adv~~ tise in the NORMALITE and would enumerate
THE NORMALITE
IT PAYS TO ADVERTISE
The day before the winter term began we ' went down to
the. depot to see the students come in on the two four- thirty
trams. We hadn't been. there but a few moments when both
trains came puffing in and it was indeed a fine sight to see
the students come pouring from the trains. Among those
who got off, we incidentally saw our best girl, though of
course we had no idea that she was to come in on this train.
Somewhat elated at the sight we started up to greet her, but
we were somewhat taken back by the sight of a youn&lt; T man
who was giving her rather close attention and whose : tten&#173;tion
seemed to be very much appreciated by her. We thought
perhaps he might just be a passing acquaintance so we ad&#173;vanced
and gave her the glad hand of greeting. She didn't
seem as glad to see us as we had been dreaming during those
two weeks that she woula. be, but she seemed quite a bit en&#173;grossed
with the fellow with her. However, she treated us
in a decent manner though rather cold and introduced us.
She pr. esented the fellow as her friend from home who was
to be a student here during the winter term. We noticed
that she placed speci{ l emphasis on the words home and
friend, and this was more noticeable when she appeared to
be in a great hurry to be going and not over anxious that we
be a part of the crowd.
The couple left us rather unceremoniously and we stood
THE NORMALITE 41
- JESSIE HASTINGS.
A RAG CARPET
How many boys went to Chattanooga to see their girls
Christmas? It is rumored that a " My Girl Lives in Chatta&#173;nooga"
club will be organized soon. Charter members will
be Burns, Dement, Stone. Members will be received on pre&#173;senting
proper credentials.
Henry Truett Representing
OPPOSITE POST OFFICE
MURFREESBORO, TENNESSEE
HIGH CLASS CLOTHES, HATS AND
FURNISHINGS
AT
BUTLER, HOOPER &amp; McCORD, Inc.
" The Good Clothes Store"
WEST SIDE SQUARE
c. ~ I. BYRN &amp; SON
Authorized Buick Sales And Service
Goodyear And Kelly- Springfield Tires
COMPETENT MECHANICS
PHONES 8 AND &amp; 8
SJ1lith B Fletchet-. S
' arttggerg
~'" -
42 THE NORMALITE
the things which they intended to buy from each house dur_
ing the term.
This talk gave us a new thought. and we decided that
even if all hope of happiness was gone for us it would be
foolish for us to destroy ourself, for even if we did SHE might
not be as sorry as we would hopefor.
So we decided that instead of drowning ourself we would
drown our disappointment and sorrow by getting busy, and
we decided that a good way to get busy would be to con&#173;tinue
preaching our old slogan and make it one of Our New
Year resolutions which is " WE TRADE \\ lITH THEM AS.
TRADES WITH US."
I was once a little seed, planted in the ground. I came
up and made a beautiful stalk of cotton. I grew and soon
had large bolls of white cotton. The negroes picked me and I
was made into cloth. After I had been dyed blue, I was fold&#173;ed
into a bolt of cloth and shipped to a store in Murfreesboro.
I stayed packed back in a shelf for almost a month. At
last I was sold to a woman, and made into a dress. She wore,
washed, and ironed me until I was almost worn out. Then
she packed me back in a sack with some rags.
After a while she tore us into strings and wove us into
a rag carpet. I am now spread out on the floor and swept
wth a broom every day. Sometimes I am taken up and near&#173;ly
beaten to death. But I like to look back and see how I
have grown from a tiny seed and become so useful.
When you are just a little seed lying in ' the cold ground,
do not be discouraged, but remember if you try you will be
something great after awhile.
TOTAL RESOURCES OVER $ 1,800,000.00
4 per cent. Paid on Savings Account.
and
Newspaper, Book
GARAGE
EVERYTHING FOR THE
AUTOMOBILE
Telephone 38 118 West Main Street
TENNESSEE
THE HOME JOURNAL
PUBLISHING CO.
Hirsbrunner &amp; Miles
Dodge Bros.' Motor Vehicles
SERVICE
SODAS
L. H. WEHRLE
Paint, Glass and Var&#173;nishes
Auto Painting A Spe&#173;cialty.
Murfreesboro Bargain
House
Everything for Men
Sam Licker
T. B. Carlton
FORMERLY JACK'S .
LUNCHES
That's what you get when you
trade with
BROWN BROS.
ICE CREAM CO.
MURFREESBORO BANK &amp; TRUST CO.
Whitman, Norris &amp; Hollinsworth Candies
' READ &amp; RIGGS
Ice Cream, Sherbets, Ices, Sand&#173;wiches,
etc.
" Brown Ice Cream Pies"
Get these from the Y. W. C. A.
at Normal
Tel~' phone Us Your Orders For
Ice Cream
Free Delivery to the Normal
Everything you buy from us is
- sold with the guarantee of sat&#173;isfaction
or your' money back.
" 100% for M. T. N."
Brown Bros. Ice Cream Co.
PHONE 444
PRICE AND
QUALITY
CIGARS
ELROD'S BOOTERY
EVERYTHING TO WEAR FOR THE
ENTIRE FAMILY
Smyrna
H. H. WILLIAMS, Cashier
C. B. BELL, Ass't. Cashier
Tel. 800
In, corporated
Cars- Trucks And Fordson Tractors
Authorized Dealers
First National Bank
LEAVE YOUR LIGHTS ON, OR WE
CAN~ T PAY FOR THIS AD
Murfreesboro
GEORGE W. HOWSE, Pres.
JNO. M. BUTLER, Vice p. res.
CAPITAL $ 200,000 SURPLUS $ 40,000
EARTUMAN- WILSON- ELKIN MOTOR COMPANY
OLD RELIABLE TAXI SERVICE
PHONE 11
EPH HOOVER, Manager
MURFREESBORO LlGUT &amp; POWER COMPANY
Opposite P. o.
Home Phone 13
TENNESSEE
JOHN DeGEORGE
WHAT WE WANT
East Side Square. Phone 1"
Hot Chili in Winter Time
Ice Cream in Summer Time
Anything good. to eat and drink
ALL THE TIME.
SMART FOOTWEAR
MURFREESBORO
THEQIXIJC0.
Opposite P. o.
Murfreesboro, Tenn.
4% Paid on Savings
SAVE
For the glorious privilege of
being independent
Stones River Bank
&amp; Trust Co.
Cumb. Phone 147 .
...... oaQJCUt 0 () 0 () 0 04 Ii
to the Wants I
of the . Normal I
Boys . and Girls I &#183;
I
COMPLETE LINES OF ;
e Wearing Apparel I
and Accessories I
EXCLUSIVE AGENTS OF I
c Spaulding Sporting I
Goods and I
Bradley Sweaters i
.~&#8226;&#8226;() 0 ..... 0 .. &#183; 0 ..... 0.-.&lt; 8
Agents for
HENRY KING &amp; COMPANY
WHOLESALE GROCERS .
Murfreesboro- McMinnville- Tullahoma
LEWIS BRINKLEY
Successor to Boulevard Store
Groceries, Cigars, Tobacco, Soft Drinks
High Grade Candies, Gasoline
Comer Normal Boulevard and East Main Street
PHONE 515
FISK RED TOP TIRES
Automobile Accessories, Oils and Gas
TIRE SERVICE
Free Air And Free Water
PROMPTNESS
PHONE 811 w. MAIN ST.
. MURFREESBORO, TENN.
Alien Service Station
Special Attention and Prices Given to School
Students and Directors
We Wash Everything but the Baby, and Return
Everything but the Dirt .
COOK'S LAUNDRY
}. E. COOK &amp; SONS, Props.
MURFREESBORO TENNESSEE
AT ALL HOURS
Meals and Lunches
SOUTH SIDE OF SQUARE
CITY RESTAURANT
LEADERS IN
PHONE 77
DRY GOODS AND READY- TO &#183; WEAR
YOUR HEALTH
IN BUSINESS FOR
DEALERS IN
TelephoDe II. 103 Public Square
Groceries, Fruits And
Vegetables
Complete Line of School Supplies
Parker Fountain Pens
Ever Sharp Pencils
Magazines and Novels
W. E. CANTRELL &amp; CO.
TATUM Ct... SHACKLETT
Stickney Drug Company
BETWEEN . MURFREES&#173;BORO
AND NASHVILLE
TELEPHONE 727
" RED" HARVEY
T A X I
SERVICE
Leave Leave
Murfreesboro Nashville
( Jordan Hotel) ( Maxweil House)
8: 00 A M. 8: 00 A. M.
11: 00 A. M. 11: 00 A. M.
1: 00 P. M. 1: 00 P. M.
3: 00 P. M. 3: 00 P. M.
5: 00 P M. 5: 00 P. M.
Murfreesboro and
Both Phones 90
Eagleville, Tenn.
Phone 439 Phone 458
Woodfin &amp; Moore
AMBULANCE SERVICE
J. T. Woodfin B. C. Noore, Jr.
We Guarantee Satisfaction.
SAMPLE SHOES A SPECIALTY
Let Us Make You a Suit to Your Individual Measure. .
Tennessee
Walk AC, ross the Square and
Save the Difference.
W. Side Square. Phone 184
CLAYTON &amp;
DRAPER
SHOES
STAR PRESSING SHOP
Expert Pressing
And Cleaning
ALLEN BROS., Proprietors
Phone 243
CASON'S GARAGE
STUDEBAI&lt; ER CARS ' REO CARS
All Kinds of Repairing And
Shop Work
. 746 East Main Street
LEE A. LIVELY STUDIO
Murfreesboro, Tenn.
l\ 1urfreeshoro
The Favorite With
Up- To- Date Young
. Men.
SPECIAL PRICES TO NOR~ AAL STUDENTS
STAR BARBER SHOP
Horton Gr06cry. Company
Staple and Fancy
Groceries
Feed and Seed
PHONES 260 AND 88
Orders Filled Promptly
Quality Furniture
North Side Public Square
PHONE 240
Telephone 361
MRS. D. E. LOGAN
MISS FANNIE NICHOL
McKNIGHT AND
PARTEE
ART CHINA SHOP
Hand Painted China, Parch&#173;ment
Shades, Electrol~ ers, Nov&#173;elties.
Cards for all Occasions.
Gents' Outfitters, Clothing and Shoes
ELECTRIC SHOE
SHOP
Your Patronage
Solicited
119 South Church St
E. L. ROGERS &amp;- COMPANY
w~ T. GERHARDT
Merchant Tailor
Phone 59
Cleaning Pressing
Altering
FOR LADIES AND
GENTS
OPEN DAY AND NIGHT
SJANITARY CAFE
GROCERIES
STORE OF FRIENDLY SERVICE LEO FERRELL
OPPOSITE FIRE HALL . PHONE 895
H, M. TUTI, Proprietor.
FREE DELIVERY
Join the Normal Class at the Methodist Sunday School!!
PHOTOGRAPHER
Phone 69
c. B. LEATHERMAN &amp; COMPANY
Dry Goods And Ladies Ready- To- Wear '
We Appreciate Your Patronage
COOK'S SERVICE STATION
. AUBREY COOK, Mgr.
" You Can Find It There"
GAS, OIL, TIRES AND TUBES
FREE ROAD SERVICE
TELEPHONE 37 303 WEST COLLEGE ST.
FIRESTONE TIRES.
High Grade Work At Very Reasonable Prices.
SPECIAL PRICES TO NORMAL STUDENTS
KERR'S DRUG STORE
We Make Sick People Well At Little Cost
TELEPHONE 179
Misses E. and M.
Earthman
Exclusive Millinery
128 North Church St.
A. L. SMITH &amp; CO.
Druggists
MAGAZINES, SCHOOL
SUPPLIES
CHOCOLATES
. Cut Flowers For
All Occasion.
If You Need A
NEW BONNET
BONNET SHOP .
WE DO HEMSTITCHING
'~ Where only the Best
is good enough"
. ALSUP SHOE
COMPANY
TRY
SUBSCRIBE TO THE NORMALITE
Next to Jordan Hotel
/
VVHOLESALE GROCERS
ARNOLD'S BARBER SHOP
NORYl~ t\ L BO: YS INVITED
CONSUMER'S SUPPLY COMPANY'S
ICE CREAM
CONSUMER'S SUPPLY COMPANY
112 Easi Main Street
A1URFREESBORO WATERTOWN
TO TASTE OF NArrURE'S SWEETS
RAGLAND: POTTER&amp; CO &#8226;
</dc:description>
<dc:subject>College publications; Middle Tennessee State Normal School;</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Image; Text;</dc:type>
<dc:type>text; application/pdf</dc:type>
<dc:format>Periodical;</dc:format>
<dc:format>42 p.; 9.5 x 6.0 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright may or may not belong to MTSU; Reproduced with permission of the Albert Gore Research Center, MTSU</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>May be used freely by individuals for research, teaching, and personal use under the fair use provisions of the Copyright Act; Credit: Property of the Albert Gore Research Center, Middle Tennessee State University, Murfreesboro, TN 37132; For other uses contact The Albert Gore Research Center, P.O. Box 193, MTSU, Murfreesboro TN 37132</dc:rights>
<dc:relation>University Collections, MTSU Miscellaneous, Middle Tennessee Normal School, 1911-1925</dc:relation>
<dc:publisher>Albert Gore Research Center, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:description>Folder 4</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/mtsu1/id/1404</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>