<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Wearing letters other than "T" violates rule</dc:title>
<dc:relation>Sidelines, Oct., 6, 1957</dc:relation>
<dc:date>1957-10-06</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Students at MTSC could face action from the Associated Student Body if they wore the letters of other schools on their clothing.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Wearing Letters Other Than "T" Violates Rule
Don Franklin, president of the "T" club, which is composed of MTSC students who have won a varsity letter, wishes to call the attention of the student body to a prohibition in the ASB constitution, restricting the wearing of letters or numerals from other schools on sweaters by students of MTSC.
The "T" club requests all students to refrain from wearing the letter of any other school, secondary or college, on the campus of the college. Failure to comply with this regulation will lead to action by the Associated Student Body.
This rule is observed by all major colleges and universities as a mark of respect for the members of the student body who have won athletic recognition.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Associated Student Body; ASB</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Schools--Insignia; College sports; Middle Tennessee State College</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:type>image/jpeg</dc:type>
<dc:format>Clipping</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected. Reproduced with permission of the University</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Reproduction is permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only; Credit to Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:rights>
<dc:relation>Sidelines Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/mtsu1/id/1115</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>