<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Dedication of the Murfree, Forrest and Todd buildings</dc:title>
<dc:date>1958-03-25</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Printed invitation to attend a dedication ceremony in the Alumni Memorial Gym on March 25, 1958 for three campus buildings. Accompanied by audio clips of remarks about the history and significance of each building made during the dedication ceremony.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Audio clips: 1. Dedication of the Bettie Avent Murfree Language Arts Building -- 2. Dedication of the Nathan Bedford Forest R.O.T.C. Building -- 3. Dedication of the Andrew L. Todd Library Building -- 4. Tribute to Andrew L. Todd.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The Tennessee State Board of Education and faculty of Middle Tennessee State College cordially invite you to attend the dedication of The Language Arts Building to be named in honor of Bettie Avent Murfree, The Reserve Officers' Training Corps building to be named in honor of Nathan Bedford Forrest, The Library Building to be named in honor of Andrew L. Todd.  Tuesday, March the Twenty-Fifth at ten-thirty o'clock in the morning, Nineteen Hundred and Fifty-eight, Alumni Memorial Gym, Murfreesboro TN</dc:description>
<dc:relation>(Clip 1) http://content.mtsu.edu/cdm4/audiofiles/fifthieth/Dedication_Murfree.mp3 (Everett Derryberry)&lt;br&gt; (Clip 2) http://content.mtsu.edu/cdm4/audiofiles/fifthieth/Dedication%20Forrest.mp3 (Belt Keathley)&lt;br&gt;(Clip 3) http://content.mtsu.edu/cdm4/audiofiles/fifthieth/Dedication_Todd1.mp3 (Quill E. Cope)&lt;br&gt; (Clip 4) http://content.mtsu.edu/cdm4/audiofiles/fifthieth/Dedication_Todd2.mp3 (Barton Dement)</dc:relation>
<dc:subject>College buildings; Dedication services; Middle Tennessee State College</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Building dedications;</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Still image; Sound</dc:type>
<dc:type>text; audio/mp3</dc:type>
<dc:format>Speech</dc:format>
<dc:format>Invitation: 3 x 5 in. Audio clips: 3:13 min.; 3:38 min.; 7:36 min.; 5:55 min.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected. Reproduced with permission of the University</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Reproduction is permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only; Credit to Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>378.768 M585g</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/mtsu1/id/1422</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>