<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>MTSU Buchanan Players present "A&#8230; My Name Is Alice"</dc:title>
<dc:date>1988-04-14</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1980-1989;</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>A program for the MTSU production of "A&#8230; My Name Is Alice," a musical revue conceived by Joan Silver and Julianne Boyd. The show depicts scenes from women's lives through monologues and songs</dc:description>
<dc:description>The Buchanan Players was a campus organization that provided a workshop environment for students in the theater arts. They performed new plays and also produced and directed their own plays to obtain parts not available in main stage productions. The purpose of the club was to train students in dramatic production and to prepare members for the national dramatic fraternity, Alpha Psi Omega.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Women; Revues; Drama; Theater; Middle Tennessee State University;</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Image; Text;</dc:type>
<dc:type>application/pdf;</dc:type>
<dc:format>Program;</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright may or may not belong to MTSU; Reproduced with permission of the Albert Gore Research Center, MTSU</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>May be used freely by individuals for research, teaching, and personal use under the fair use provisions of the Copyright Act; Credit: Property of the Albert Gore Research Center, Middle Tennessee State University, Murfreesboro, TN 37132; For other uses contact The Albert Gore Research Center, P.O. Box 193, MTSU, Murfreesboro TN 37132</dc:rights>
<dc:relation>Middle Tennessee State University Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:publisher>Albert Gore Research Center, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:description>MTSU Theatre, Series 1, Productions, Box 3</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/mtsu1/id/1590</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>