<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Normalite, 1922 November</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Middle Tennessee State Normal</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1922-11-01</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1920-1929</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>The Normalite was a Middle Tennessee State Normal School publication.</dc:description>
<dc:description>November, Illustrated Poem- PHILIP MANKIN 3
The Black Coffin- PHILIP MANKIN .4
A School Idyl- M. HATTS 8
Boosters Good and Bad- E. B. B _ _ 8
The Rural School Problem- W. BRUCE OVERTON 10
Mill Creek Ford- MARION CAPPS .: 11
Interesting Cat Species- ANON .14
Echoes From the Staff at Breakfast- AN INVITED
GUEST _ 14
What Is The R. O. B. B. ?- ANON 15
Stenographic Report of a Typical Chapel Talk- ANON 16
Heroes and Heroines in Shakespeare- VIRGINIA HALE. 17
Just Flapper Talk- A REAL FLAPPER 18
The Bachelor Girl- EXCHANGE 21
Once An Indian- ALSEY LEE HAMS 22
An Untilled Field of Education- D. L. MANIER 23
A Suggestive Declaratio of Independence- C. DAN FORD.. 26
- PHILIP MANKIN.
NOVEMBER
The soft and radiant spirit of the night
Gleams down upon the sleeping earth.
Divine
In mute appeal the leafless trees outline
Against the solemn moon's unearthly light.
The f~ rms of nature sleep; the spectral
rite
Of some weird spirit in the silent shrine
Of the . dark forest speaks of death. The
WInd
Weeps in chill accents for the summer's
flight.
Yet in the heart glows J. ife's eternal cheer'
A deeper fellowship pervades the air '
And gleams with soulful warmth upon the
drear
Exp. at; se of Aea'dened nature. Ev'rywhere
A hVIng SPtrlt lights the dying year
Eor pow'r of life and love and God is there.
--- -,\ - - \
~-=-: I
Fun 66
It Pays To Advertise 69
The A. B. C. of M. T. N.- ANON &#183; 28
the World Polity Club 29 ,
: Skeeters- BELL 29
Announcement , 32
Literary Societies 36
Editor's Notes 33
Faculty 41
Chapel Talks , &#183; 44
A College View- EXCHANGE 46
Home Economics Club , 47
Locals 48
Hits, Runs, And Errors 50
Alumni - 52
~ 1. T. N. At 7 : 15 A. M.- DOROTHY LYON 30
i.
Making History- A BELL RINGER 31
i,
Do It Now- EX. CHANGE 32
&#183; Y. M. C. A 55
Y. W. C. A 57
Exchanges _ 58
Athl~ tics 61
Glee Club 63
~
, Correlation of Music With Other Subjects- E. MAY
SAUNDERS 64
4 THE NORMALITE THE NORMALITE
THE BLACK COFFIN
As Crewe threaded his way down the dark avenues of
the gloomy forest towards his home hidden in its outskirts,
he pondered over the mysterious threatening note he had re&#173;ceived
a few days before. The gloom of night had fallen over
the foot- path, and the chill wind wailed moaningly through
the bare branches of the trees. The cloudy sky, in which no
star glimmered, weighed down upon the earth like an im&#173;mense
shroud. A vague and unaccustomed sense of dread
lay heavily on Crewe's heart as he slowly picked his way
through the night.
The note that disturbed his thoughts had been thrust un&#173;der
his office door a few days previously in the city he was
now leaving behind him. Singular alike for its terseness, its
mystery, and its ominous import, it read as follows:
" If you do not stop your oil wells and leave this city in
two days, you are a dead man." ( Signed) NIHIL
Although he hacLbeen startled for the time being by this
formidable threat, he had lost all thought of it in the bustle
of the following days' business. He was naturally of a brave
and reckless temperament, and had no intention of following
the injunctions of the note.
But now his utter helpless against the bloody machina&#173;tions
of a relentless society of anarchists loomed up before
his imagination.. An assassin seemed to lurk behind eve~ y
ghostly tree rising indictinctly into the night. Crewe w. as m
that state of mind when one builds up in his imaginatIOn a
horror out of every natural occurrence. The creaking of a
limb startled him, the sighing of the wind made him shud&#173;der
and the crackling of a twig seemed to forebode the ap&#173;pro~
ch of some weird presence out there in the night. Crewe
felt glad his famly was away on a visit. As for himself, he
believed he could escape this indefinable danger as he had es-caped
so many others. .
He now approached his home. It was a large, ra. mbhng,
old two- story house, with an air of mystery that pervades . an
old building, and a sense of cheerlessness and depressiOn
common to large houses a'( vay from all neighbors and unten-anted
by an expectant family. Trees came to within twenty
feet of the dark walls, giving it an added shade of gloom. A
spirit of loneliness, dreariness , and despondence brooded . over
the place.
No welcoming bark greeted Crewe. Wondering where
his faithful watchdog was, he started up the steps to the front
door. His foot struck something soft. Striking a match, he
saw his mastiff stretched out dead. With a sinking of heart,
both of grief at the dog's death and a fearful foreboding, he
unlocked the door, struck a match, turned the lights on, and
carefully locked the door behind him. He then turned off the
lights and went up the dark and creaking stairway to his
room on the corner\ of the second floor.
The big house se'e. med deserted. Crewe wondered where
his valet, Clark, was; but Clark was accustomed to going to
a neighbor's house about three miles away to spend the night
while the family was gone. Before this he had always told
Crewe, however.
Building a fire, Crewe sat down by a table and began
reading a newspaper. His first glance rested on a paragraph
relating the mysterious disappearance of Henry K. Coleman,
a wealthy oil operator living about twenty miles away. He
was meditating on this incident, and deriving new apprehen&#173;sions
for his own safety from the similarity of his case with
Coleman's, when the lights went out.
After vainly waiting ten or fifteten minutes in the dim
light of the room for them to come back on, Crewe took a
ca. ndle out of a drawer and lighted it. On looking out the
wmd? w, he. was puzzled to see the lights still shining in
t~ e dIstant cI. ty. The cre~ king of a tree branch and the snap&#173;pmg
of a tWIg aroused hLm. Glancing dOwn to the skirts of
~ he murky woods, h~ saw three or four dark figures carry&#173;mg
~ large black object. They disappeared in the shadows.
Feelmg the presence of some gruesome object behind him,
Crewe turned from the window.
Th All was quiet throug~ out the lonesome and dreary house.
e candle threw out a dim and flickering light castino- gro&#173;~
esque shadows down the obscure stairway. Th~ fire w: s dy-mg
out A hea . . f
. vy premOlllttOn 0 some vague, mysterious
6 THE NORMALITE
rible headsman. The pistol snapped on empty hulls~ and he
desperately threw it out of the window in a , paroxysm of
terror.
The tall figure seemed to grin with a sar&lt; Jonic lustre from
his black eyes shining through the holes of his mask. Not
a sound broke from any throat. All was silent in that room
of tragedy save for the mournful sound of the wailing wind,
rising and falling like a moaning spirit shut out from heaven
and doomed to endless wandering, blown about by the gales
of fate. The candle was gradually burning down into the
~ ocket, threatening to overwhelm the room in complete dark&#173;~
ess, except for the glimmer of the dying coals in the fire&#173;placeo
There cam'e into Crewe's mind, with that strangeness
in which an idea comes to one in the hour of peril, the thought
that his life was going to expire with the short- lived candle'
and he thought of Macbeth's soliloquy on the brevity of hu~
man existence.
The masked man with the glittering axe slowly approach&#173;ed
Crewe, while the latter retreated towards the wall near
the mantel- piece. The only door in the room was occupied
by the four shrouded men with the black coffin and barred
from approach by the advancing assassin. The window was
fifteen feet from the ground , and just above a large deep
open well. '
o~ rewe looked about for some weapon. He saw the utter
~ uttll. ty of struggling with the man with the long- handled
as~ mg axe. He finally drew up with his back to the wall
~ gamst a large, tall, life- size picture. The table with the d _
109 candle was close on his left hand Th .' Y
withi f . e executIOner, now
deli ~ ten eet of ~ rewe, seemed to gloat with the fiendish
olaf a ~ ephls~ opheles Over the utter inability of his
VIC 1m to extncate hImself from his bloody toils
SUddenly, Crewe bec .
his back . ame aware of the large picture at
o The meanmg of the words " pict" " do " .
on the cl t d . " or, wntten
K os~ oar darted mto his mind. If only he could do it!
nockmg the candle out . kl
his would b d qUlC y, he hurled the table at
- e mur erer ran h' h d .
picture, and almost fai' d . IS an. SWIftly up and down the
button IOn nte WIth excItement on finding a small
one corner. . When t hI'S was pressed, the picture
presence out there in the night aiming at his destruction ob&#173;sessed
Crewe's mind. He was startled from the awful agony
of terrorized suspense by the stealthy turning of the front
door knob. Knowing that the door was locked, he felt sure
that whoever it was would have to stop there.
This hope was . cruelly shattered, however, by his hearing
a key grate in the lock and the door swing open. Stepping
to the head of the stairway, he looked down into the shadowy
hall, and saw at the foot of the stairs five black figures, one
of whom had a gleaming skull for a head.
Crewe stumbled back into his room and locked the door.
He wondered how the front door key had come into the pos&#173;session
of his assailants.. Only Clark had another key. Was
his valet in league with his foes? Little time for thought
was left, however. He s.. tepped quickly to the closet to get
his revolver. On his opening the door, a sight of appalling
horror awaited him. There outstretched on the closet floor
weltering in his blood flowing from numerous knife wounds
lay the dead body of Clark. On the inside of the closet door,
Crewe saw written with the dead man's blood the two words,
" pict," " door."
Seizing his pistol hastily, and observing that each cham&#173;ber
was filled, he Stepped back into the room and awaited
the oncoming of his executioners. He did not have long to
wait. With slow, deliberate tread, and a rustling sound that
sent a cold shudder over his frame, Crewe heard the figures
approach. He heard them set something down on the stainl
landing. Then a key turned in the lock, and the door slowly
swung open.
It was an appalling sight that awaited Crewe's expectant
eyes. There on the stair- landing stood four grim figures
draped in black and with black masks over their counte&#173;nances
by the sides of a black and yawning coffin! In the
doorway stood a tall, black, silent figure with a hideous mask
upon his face in the shape of a skull from which radiated a
horrible iridescent gleam, while in his hand he held a sharp,
shining, long- handled axe, similar to a battle are or the awful
executioner's axe, instrument of woeful, historic destruction!
Crewe madly pulled the trigger several times at the ter-
THE NORMALITE 7
8 THE NORMALITE THE NORMALITE 9
slid aside, and Crewe ran down a dark stairway to an open&#173;ing
in the woods about a hundred yards from the house.
Dashing towards the town, he saw the forest lighted up, and
looking back saw his home in flames.
- PHILIP MANKIN.
A SCHOOL IDYL
Scold it in, mould it in;
All that they can swallow.
Fold it in, mould it in;
Still there's more to follow.
Faces pinched, and sad, and pale,
Tell the same undying tale-
Tell of moments robbed from sleep,
Meals untasted, studies deep.
Those who've passed the furnace through,
With aching brow, will tell to you
How the teacher crammed it in,
Rammed it in, jammed it in,
Crunched it in, punched it in,
Rubbed it in, clubbed it in,
Rapped it in and slapped it in-
When their heads were hollow.
- M. HATTS.
BOOSTERS GOOD AND BAD
Away, away back in the days of the Anglo- Saxon we
find the booster singing songs of his native land; painting
the horrors of war; reverencing the many gods; making us
feel the cool ocean breeze; and praising the mighty deeds of
the heroes. The world gives them credit for our first liter&#173;ature.
Had it not been for them we would have no Beowulf,
which thrills every heart as we see the beautiful tall and
handsome leader, as we fear, crumble and fall; we would have
110 Pier's Plowman with its wonderful lesson; and we would
have no Paraphras~, with its thrilling story of the beginning
of time.
It was " pep" that led Harold successfully over the ocean
and to victory at the Battle of Hastings. The same thing led
his people on to victory in a literary line, as they crushed the
cold feeling of the previous writings and stamped ' the works
with love, religion, and chivalry. You remember it was by
them that the deeds of King Arthur and his Knights of the
Round Table came into a written form. Of course, there were
legends of these deeds, but no written record, until a real
" live wire" took the dope and created a wonderful history.
This awoke some sleepers and very soon the story was spread
throughout England and part of Europe. But it doesn't stop
there- all through the ages these deeds have been used as
subject- matter. Tennyson gave them to us in such pictur&#173;esque
manner that, as we read them today, we must feel the
chivalric atmosphere: So it is that " good boosting" is the
life of anything.
If boosting can make the deeds of heroes hundreds of
years ago immortal, what can it do for our own heroic men?
Are we going to fall down on the job that men could put over
centuries ago? No! ! ! We are for M. T. N. as a whole, for
her faculty, for her student- body, for her literary societies.
for her NORMALITE, and for her " Team." We are backing
her up in every phase of the word. Who? Not a few lead&#173;ers,
but ALL!
Realiz. ing that in unity there is strength, we will be
found ~~ lhng t~ gether until we reach the goal for which we
~ re st~ lvmg- Vlctory! Some how or other, we are all work&#173;mg
with the same purpose in mind and there is no echo to
return from our yells and songs but V- i- c- t- o- r- y!
. In the bygone days some one said, " It pays to adver&#173;tlse."
RearIz'mg t h'IS to be true we have the NORMALITE
af
paper through which we can let the present pupils th~
ohrmer ones' ou. r parents, our frt. ends, and the State k' now
: at we are domg. All we need is for everyone to be a good
ooster and the thing will be kept going.
boosSt uch his life ' that, W h'Ile on one hand, we have the good
to helepr twh a uses all of h'IS energy, soul and body in trying
bo
. e contestants reach the goal' on the oth
oster IS found H d .' er a poor
but leaves it all' f ~ h oes ~ othmg for himself or anyone else,
or e ot er fellow. This kind of person is
10 THE NORMALITE THE NORMALITE n
not needed here. In fact, we can get along better with
h1 &#183; m. But the" peppy" fe11ow WI'I1 carry us over the top. Out
- E. B. B.
THE RURAL SCHOOL PROBLEM
Today the greatest problem of education is the rural
school. The educational foundation for the rural boy and
girl . must be improved before they will be capable of com&#173;peting
with the boy and girl of the city. This problem is
much greater than it seems at first thought. The town sys&#173;tem
will not meet the requirements of the rural district; it
must be suited to the environment of the children. To obtain
a system of this kind some one will have to be placed in
charge who has an interest in the rural district, in the chil-o
dren, and in the advancement of education. The politician
who is continually hiring teachers for the strengthening of
his political standing must be replaced by the educator who
has the interest, the welfare and the improvement of the
children as his goal.
The teacher who has only finished the grammar school
must be replaced by the teacher who has shown enough in&#173;terest
in the teaching profession to take special training to
prepare himself for the vocation. Before teachers of this
calibre can be secured the people of the rural community
must be made to realize the difference between a trained and
non- trained teacher; the salary of the teacher will have to
be increased to such an extent as to be an inducement to a
good teacher, to be on an equal with the work being done,
and to place the teaching profession on a higher basis.
A home must be provided for the rural teacher or he has
to quit the profession when the life of solitude no longer ap&#173;peals
to him, for it is almost impossible to find a place to
board for one, much less two. The teacher should live in the
community so that he will be a part of it and not one who
enters on Monday morning and leaves on Friday afternoon.
Until the teacher becomes a part of the community there is no
hope for him to get the cooperation of the people. If he
stays in the community and has any life in him, social activ-ities
can be planned by the school that will bring the parents
ogether, to see and realize what their children are doing; to
Jeam the value of cooperation and thereby create a greater
interest in the school.
Heretofore the rural school house has oeen located in
the roughest place possible; in many instances where there
was only enough level land to build the house. This has
meant no playground and has made athletics impossible. This
must be changed and suitable playgrounds must be provided
so that athletics can be encouraged, for they are the life of a
school. The teacher who fails to encourage athletics must
be replaced by the teacher who can place himself on a plane
with the children and see their view of such activities,
The one room school must go; the time of consolidation
is at hand. The value of consolidation has been proved be&#173;&gt;:
ond any doubt; more teachers, better system of classifica&#173;tion,
and larger schools have proven far superior to the one&#173;room
o~ e- teacher school with poor equipment.
&#8226; Un. t1l these changes are made, education in the rural dis&#173;tnct
w1l1 remain in the present rut. It is up to the t h
who are . h eac ers
praparmg t emselves for the profession to unite and
act as a body in demandm' g the ' Improvements necessa to
place the pr~ fession on a higher basis. Time has shown~ hat
~ o one outsIde of the profession will demand th
bons Th I f ese Correc-
. e ? eop e ~ the rural district cannot be blamed for
::~~:: mtghthe Im~ rovements, for the teacher has never
e necessIty of a change Th d
ment in the rural school will co . e ay of advance-made
to realize the value a d me when these people are
ments; the duty of bringi n th~ eedbof the nece~ sary improve&#173;teacher.
ng IS a out rests with the trained
- w. BRUCE OVERTON.
MILL CREEK FORD
It had been a beautiful s rin
was descending fr h p g. day; but now a cool breeze /
dindot'lDterrupt thom tI e mountams. C00I breezes, however
Jack was e p easures of Jack Huron. '
a forester. His whole life had been a series
. of romances; for he was fond of outdoor sports. Noth'
pleased him more than a ride in the moonlight over the w~~ g
ribbon of road that extended from his home to an untold d~ te
tance across Mill Creek. IS-This
creek was fed by various mountain streams. I
fact, the creek itself headed in the mountains. When thn
spring thaw set in, its waters, which were ever rushing, wer:
to be heard from a great distance. Then it was that the mill
men went to the dam, and restored their property to safety.
No one could tell when such a freshet would come. It gen&#173;erally
came as a surprise.
As I have said, it had been a lovely day. As Jack rode
away, he noticed a yellow moon rising from its eastern por&#173;tal.
He was overjoyed with the fact, and set spurs to his
black saddler, with the hope of riding several miles before
returning. When he reached the ford, he made no attempt
to slacken the pace, but splashed through the swift blue wat&#173;-
ers without so much as a thought of how treacherous they
were. Thus he rode straight ahead for several miles; but
upon realizing that the hour was growing late, turned, and
slowly rode back towards home.'
When the horse and rider once more approached the
ford, it had swollen greatly. The moon was high in the heav&#173;
&#183; ens; but Jack had never known so great a change to occur
in Mill Creek in so short a length of time. He wondered
bow it all came about. So long did he ponder as to worry the
patience of Midnight, which was a horse of wonderful in&#173;telligence.
As Jack gave him rein, he snorted wildly before
entering the swift, cool waters, which glistened under the
moonlight.
He trembled as his sides were submerged; and once,
even stopped, as if trying to regain his footing.
Jack, who was standing in the saddle, rather than sit&#173;ting,
swore softly as the horse splashed through shallow wat&#173;er
to dry land. There he dismounted, and looked admiring&#173;ly
at the silver current as it swirled on its reckless way down
the creek. valley. It was a wonderful sight; for no rain had
13 THE NORMALITE
for several days; and yet, this stream had doubled' its
locity in just a few hours time.
Suddenly there came a deafening crash; then' a lull)
hich was foIIowed by a thundering roar. It had come from
somewhere up the creek. What could it be?
" The dam I The dam has broken loose !" cried Jack as he
wung into the saddle. " Perhaps I can reach the hills." As
be spoke, he spurred Midnight forward.
It became a race between life and death. The dam was
situated only a few hundred yards above the ford. And when
pressure became strong enough, the structure gave way, let&#173;ting
free an untold amount of water.
As Jack Huron sp- ed along the highway, he realized that
be had to fight for every inch. If he could only gain higher
ground, even though it be in the creek valley, he would be
comparatively safe. He could hear the crash of huge tim&#173;bers
as they gave way to the deluge. Above that awful roar
could be heard the snapping of great trees as they" were
broken down and forced to enter the current. Each second
broug~ t t. he ftoo~ nearer to Jack. The noise grew louder;
and ldnlght neIghed in a wild, mysterious manner.
~ SU~ denl&gt;: he saw the great silver wave break through the
orest mto View. He leaned forward nd k .
words into M'd . ht' . a spa e pleadmg
I mg s ear. There It was only a few rod-away
j now it hurls itself upon them Th :;
itb hi Spurs; but in '. . . e man struck deep
the fast; novl'ng h vam, for the giant wave had struck
orse and ride I both. But it . r, camp etely submerging
was over m a moment &#183; f M'd'
of being carried from th h' h , or I nIght, in spite
right. As SOon as he ~ a Ig w~~, had managed to stay up&#173;shock,
he plunged fo dd suffiCiently recovered from the
rwar , a few st k
once more on dry land Th ro es, and they stood
the current. . ey had reached the outer edge of
Jack had somehow m
he as half strangled an~ n~ ged to stay in the saddle; but
back to the highway and trenched to the skin. He rode
had almost caused his d urned . for a look at the thing which
s &#183; er river, surging forwe::~ u~ lon: It was now a mighty
)) e. The noise was dreadful ~ a~ mg dark . objec~ s of ever;
, t e scene slckenmg. Then
THE NORMALITE 12
ECHOES FROM THE STAFF AT BREAKFAST
INTERESTING CAT SPECIES FOR BIOL
THE NORMALITE 15
ly good, I'll have to taste again." She' tasted
fiDally said, " It must be some kind of crystallized fruit."
et Watson piped in ~ d said, " Taint neither, it's
lIiIIIIIlWlt- iOOks like it and tastes like it, too."
Can you picture Paul Eaves eating grapefruit garnished
maple syrup? .
iss Little, perched in the high chair, was as tall as any
Hannah. Belcher inherited such a love for physics, that
ordered a test tube to drink her coffee through.
Carl Brandon ordered a spoon to eat the dahlia petals
his finger bowl; he said the editor- in- chief drank his.
r. Oark: " Say folks, I thought this was to be a break&#173;It
must be a Hallowe'en party- just look at the candles."
Windrow: " Say Partin, why don't you eat your waffle?"
n in astonishment replied: " Huh, what do you take me
? Do you think I'll eat a toasted powder puff."
r. Lyon: " Miss Geraldine Grigsby will now give us a
to" The horro)' stricken Geraldine replied " 0
L, on I . can't I've. eaten every crumb of my toast,." To,
. lIllinre the sItuation Mary Hill King replied, " This breakfast
for a King."
&#8226; Lyon. then said to the hostess, " Miss Williams, feed&#173;LfYON
IS no easy job, but you have certainly proven
"' h~ equal to the task."
CyruhS Dement expressing his appreciation for the unde&#173;onor
sa'd " I
. I, never have had enough to eat, but Miss
~ s";' hls breakfast and this staff they comfort me."
~ d a; r~: ca~ e ~ cross the campus at a Ichabod Crane
it pay toe~~:? bme to play janitor for Miss Williams.
AN INVITED GUEST.
This . WHAT IS THE R. 0 B B?
IS the query th t &#8226; &#8226; &#8226;&#8226;
itory, in the hall a c. an be heard on all sides, in the
OR the campus ': tays, III the classrooms, in the dining
qU~ stion in a fe'w
an
1 ? n the. streets. I propose to answer
it is and noth' p am straightforward statements. It is
mg more. Its origin began at its begin-
14 THE NORMALITE
~ ::: i~ a~ a~.~~~~~~.'.'~~~~~~.'~~~~~~~"~~~"~~"".'~".'''~~''''''~''''~~:~~~''''~~~''.'~''''~~"".'~~"""~"~"~~'~~:~ e;:;
A methodical cat catalogue
A blooming cat catalpa
A preying cat catamount
A fighting cat catapult
A fatherly cat ~ cats paw
A disastrous cat ::; catastrophe
A falling cat cataract
A saucy cat catsup
A religious cat catechism
A supporting cat : caterpillar
A medicinal cat catnip
A useful cat catacomb
he became conscious of a stinging pain. Was the wind
so cold before? His horse neighed and upon touch ofe:~ r&#173;spurs,
he bounded off towards home at a furious pace. e
- MARION CAPPS.
While waiting for the hostess to announce breakfast
Windrow got over anxious and said " Ladies first," no sooner
said, than Carl Brandon pushed impatient and inquisitive
Windrow in and the ladies followed.
When Hester Rogers appeared dressed I. II her " best,"
some one said, " What's the grand idea?" She replied, " 0,
I'm dressed up to a~ oid the dish washing."
They say women have more curiosity than men; this in&#173;stance
proves otherwise: Mildred Ridley did not even have
enough curiosity to come, but Mr. Ogden came, saw, and a. te.
The second course was so tempting that the editor- In&#173;chief
ate plate and all , and was given a second serve. Some
breakfast, eh!!!! .
Some one complimented the marmalade, and the host~~
replied, " Guess what kind it is?" Elizabeth Grigsby sal ,
HEROES AND HEROINES IN SHAKESPEARE
17
I think
History
THE NORMALITE
ce we are to be favored with Fritz Leiber and his
Soon, it might be interesting to some of us to discuss
heroes and heroines in Shakespeare.
Shakespeare's writings we find no real heroes. It is
. th&amp; t some of his characters are heroes, in that they are
, but they are not classified as real heroes since they
Dot dominate the play. Not one of his men presents a
feet mQral portrait.
There . ar. e many men 1.11 h'IS dramas who di. splay certam.
&#8226; hquahttes, but Ruskin says: " Shakespeare has no he&#173;~
has only heroines." As a usual thing we think of
ltla1ll characters' h 1 b'
h . 111 t e p ay emg the hero and heroine C IS not th . ,
e case 111 many of the Shakespearean plays.
o prove this st t 1 .
a ement et us follow several of hiS plays.
t have something to do with this question.
I find this statement true,. but perhaps the
uld tell you more about It.
t" iscoreported that five hundred people Were ma, ssacred
Of those places the other day. I don t know
near some . ., b th t
true the rel&gt; 0rt is, but I hope It Isn t true, ecauseh a'
be a d1 &#183; rty trick if it is true. I don.' t k. now whet er. It
Turks massacring Greeks or ChnstIans massacrmg
enians. If I am wrong in this statement I hope some
ill correct me. .
Later on they needed something else to keep thm~ s go&#173;the
ruler of some of those countries, at least I thmk he
a ruler, for they called him " Must- a- saw Camel's Paw&#173;"
ent over to one of those cities ( you can ask one of
other teachers which one, for I can't say it) and called a
conference. I think the purpose of this peace confer-must
have been to confer about peace, but I am not sure.
will ask some one who knows perhaps you will be able
out.
ould like to go deeper into this interseting subject but
not permit. I hope you all now have a clear under-
-~ ing of the Near East Situation. - ANON.
Stenographic Report of a Typical Chapel Talk, Taken
Oct. 25, 1922-
When I thought of a suitable topic for my talk tOday I
thought of three subjects of interest; namely, the Hall- Mills
murder case, the Lloyd George situation, and the Near East
tangle. I don't know much about the first two of these and
I thought the students would not know much about the last
so I decided to tell you all I know about that subject.
The chief interest is centered about Smyrna which is lo&#173;cated
in that part of the world somewhere, but I am not sure
just where. This city must have been built some time in the
past though I cannot say for sure that it was. If I am wrong
on this point you can ask some one of the other teachers and
find out correctly. My Geography and History are not very
good today. Any way Smyrna was destroyed at one tim:,
and, so far as I know, it must have remained destroyed until
it was rebuilt, but I am not sure about this. .
Thrace also enters into this struggle. Thrace IS near
Macedonia, or perhaps Macedonia is nearer to Thrace than
Thrace is to Macedonia. I can't be positive as to the exact
location of these countries though. I am sure, however, that
both Thrace and Macedonia are mentioned either in Geog: a&#173;phy,
History, or the Bible; but as to which of these mentIOn
these countries I cannot say. . f
Constantinople is also important to an understandll1g 0
thi. S questI. On. I thm. k perhaps I. t was Constant'Ine or some
other emperor who founded Constantm. op1e, but you had. be1t-ter
look that up for yourselves. What rnakes Constantl110P e
important is the fact that the Dardane11es, or whatevIerdyOU
call. them are somewhere near there. Thi. S rnakes Eng kany
inte, reste" d in Greece because France I. S m. terested I'n Tur e
THE NORMALITE
ning and not before. l. ts purpose I ca~ no. t now confess. It
has a purpose and nothmg else. Its pnnclples are just wh
they should be. For furth er m. fonnatl. On don't ask me. That
letters stand for the Royal Order of Blinking Buzzards e
weird troupe. It is compo~ ed . of men belonging to the gro~;
Men outside of the orgal11zatIon do not belong. What it is
I cannot say, but it is nothing wrong.
JUST FLAPPER TALK
19 THE NORMALITE
&#8226; Ie argue the modesty of long skirts. Modesty,
e peop . ' 11 b ' d If ' mmodesty is present It WI e eVI ent no matter
s~ les of the dress may be. In my mind, this is a
c wearer not the worn,
ot make this discussion complete and leave out
hair. On some people it is beautiful; on others it is
awful. A girl should use her imagination enough
herself with short hair before she goes to the bar&#173;I
am sorry to say some don't do this and as a re&#173;ely
disappointed, but I do think if a girl desires
and believes she would look well in it, and then
ve it bobbed, she is just a coward, that's all! As
hair going out, I don't believe it ever shall. It is
y liked.
back to character stuff now, are not flappers con&#173;hough?
They catch all the criticism going. Peo&#173;ell,
she is just living for pleasure, all she cares
s and a good time." And that is all right too, for
be the use of living if you get no pleasure out of
&#8226; for boys and girls desiring each other's com-
JUst nature. That is why both were put here, I
what would one be worth without the other?
most part a flapper is happy just because she can
&#8226; life there is always something which is thrilling,
18 a life sup t S k por er. ay, honest now, haven't you
at some people and turned away with a sigh
OUrself' " I d' . Won er If he or she ever had a thrill
r life?" Th
ere are folks like that. Just look
lee' b f em, ut or my part I'm not looking for ' em
are not j t I .
&#8226; k us p easure pursuers either. They
h;: to. come up against the world and its
~ th e gtrls of tOday know more than their
ey have to and they are braver. The line
THE NORMALITE
Maybe you think the flapper is about to make her ex'
since long skirts and high coiffures have entered, but, old tO
b . h . t much as s you are all wrong. The flapper IS ere JUs as .
d ' t cogl11ze her has ever been, though perhaps you on re , ' t i
readily in the lo~ g skirt; nevertheless that flapper spldrl s
. If An a underneath just waiting a chance to assert Itse .
sert itself it will, too, just you wait! . ? But I
After all what has dress to do With character. ' t fro
' ust take I come to character later. At present, you J . t pro
me these old long, dangling dresses are not gOlOg ore t
, There a
so popular as the short, comfortable ones. . h ve
k &#183; h' h If yOU a many points in favor of short s Irts, w IC , do
. II' Then IDeo, sense, you know Without my te 109 you. ,
Take for example, " Hamiet." Hamlet, the leading charact
rather than being a hero, is a coward. Again in the gr er,
tragedy of " Macbeth" we find Macbeth possessing one of :~ t
weakest wills. In the " Merchant of Venice," we find that A ~
tonio has a good heart, and friendship pure enough even :
die for his friends, yet he is not a moral hero. 0
Shakespeare saw the finer virtues and qualities of hu&#173;manity,
and brought them out in his women characters. The
womemn of Shakespeare are mostly the very soul of virtue.
In them, he sets forth perfectly balanced characters, portray_
ing love and tenderness, combined with wit and skill. Many
of his plays depend upon the women characters not only to
support interest in the plot, but also to give them their mean&#173;ing
and purposey In the play " Measure for Measure," if Isa&#173;bella
were omitted, there would really be no story. In the
" Merchant of Venice," we find Portia to be self assured and
confident, and as she dominated the play, she is the real hero&#173;ine.
Let us consider " Romeo and Juliet." I t is not Romeo,
but Juliet, who displays courage and patience to the end. ,
In all of the works of Shakespeare, as well as the affairs
of today, we must look to the women, rather than the men,
for the truly heroic , and the greater virtues.
- VIRGINIA HALE.
18
THE NORMALITE 21
. t s much right to your way of thinking
have JUs a .
&#8226; . 0 my friend, let's forget It.
o lOme, s - A REAL FLAPPER.
ith all these other cheerful chaps
We heartily agree;
ho would not pay ' most any tax
To know that he was free!
d: t. W" haRt do'you get to eat at tIle d1' 11ing hall?
. emm1e"- nants.
THE BACHELOR GIRL
He's got the mash, you've Kot the cash;
Kick all you like, dod rot it!
They're gOing to make you pay the tax
Because he hasn't got it.
Yes, go ahead arid pay the tax;
' Tis best to be a bach.
Than have some twelve or fourteen kids
And for their living scratch.
I loved a girl that Time shall ne'er
From my memory blot her;
But should I payout cash because
The other fellow got her?
es, be a sport and pay the tax,
We hate to hear you bellow;
The married guys they envy you&#173;The
lucky bach'lor fellow.
es, pony up and pay the tax,
a use to stand and blow'
Then hear yourself called casuaily " Just her old beau."
- NEWSPAPER EXCHANGE.
THE NORMALITE
of poetry that runs: " The modern maid is
fits the flapper.
Yes, the girls of today are living in a hard age f
. . Or the
world IS more w. icked than ever before. But has not the worId
always been wicked? ot such an educated wickedness
haps, but WI. Cked J. ust the same, and there have been a pfer-flappers
back 1 &#183; 11 anci. ent h1' story Wh0 knew how to master seiwt-uations.
Remember Cleopatra don't you? I am not justi&#173;fying
her either, but nevertheless, she had something of what
it takes.
There, I ran away from my subject. What I meant to
: say was that the modern girls are the sweetest and most un&#173;selfish
of any girls yet, and they are most willing to help oth&#173;er
people and is not helping others one of the biggest, most
real things we can do? I am not talking about all girls now,
for there are, of/ course, extremes and exceptions but I believe
la.. m about right for an average.
These extremes and exceptions will always be found too,
- tor it takes all kinds of people to make up this world of ours,
-. and that is right, I suppose, for after all, what kind of a world
' would it be if we were all alike! -
I believe there are two classes of flappers. The juniors
' and seniors, the difference between the two bein~ t~ at the
seniors have had a little more experience than the Jumors. A
junior flapper holds the day until a senior flapper comes along.
then very naturally the junior falls into second place. Ever
. .? notIce It. I k like
Folks must condemn flappers just because they 00 b
they do look; that is, they look the part they plaY'
d
~~ tpr::
cause they are what they are and becaus~ the. y &#176; h are
tend to be anything else, I. S why,' 111 , my estlmatlOn' t ey
far above these " you'll be surprised" kind. &#8226;
b d as these an
Generally speaking, flappers are not as a .' that
1 &#183; h ld into behevl11g
gel- faces who go around foo 111g t e wor b told me
they are saints. I know t1lI &#183; S &#183; IS ' nght, too, for a oy
so, and boys know. . t offend
In this dis- cussion I may have sal'd some. thll1g a honest
I h . t wntten my
you. If I have I am sorry, but ave JUs .' f ee coul1-
opinion and I may be all wrong. H owever , thiS IS a r
20
THE NORMALITE 23
ben an owl called out loud and clear " Who l
hoI? We ran on our tip- toes until we reach~
The Indian life was a thing of the past.
- ALSEY LEE HAMS.
Delivered by D. L. Manier at Commencement.
Spring 1922.
in ~ erica today a serious farm problem. Its
commonly acknowledged; and remedies for its
fl" OPSed on every hand. In the interpretation of
however, opinions differ.
problelh of America, is not as it is sometime
f
. . s
o mcreasmg the fertility of the soil, of im-crops,
or even of. conserving our food, forests
1resources. It IS not the problem of I'
b
&#8226;. ncreas-self
usmest" s efficiency of the modern farmer ;
some Imes thmks, adding to his store of
bi5..: lU. lYdeS. lrable. But they are only constituent
Issue; they have their bearing and relation&#173;are
not the real problem as it must be rec-
~~ eiSrural popu~ ation, the first thing that
the starthng migration to the cities
okn riunrtaol tshois. city- ward movement and see its
decreased ~~ ety. The . mere fact that the rural
of progress a:~ ; seno~ s problem. In fact, it
people are requir:: sioe~ lty, when o~ ly a small
eel years ago it to k . eed the entire popula-produce
th fda mne- tenths of the Amer&#173;takes
seveent00 supply for thOIS country. In
Wh
&#8226; d. e in theyUpe. r cent of her populatI. On to
is required t mted States only one- third of
&#8226; not a large0 produce our food supply. This
&#8226; per cent of th
on the farms I ~ population that
. n fact, It would mean a
... UI" &#8226;&#8226;. LLED FIELD OF EDUCATION
THE NORMALITE
ONCE AN INDIAN!
It was in my early childhood that I want d
d
. b h' .. e to be a I
Ia. n ecause t a. t p. nm. ltlve state of life afforded mor tn I n.
atlO. n and'less dlsclpl1Oe. This desire was especi. allye t0 er &#183;
dunng the spr10g of the year. It was durin tl s rone
1 d
.. g 1ese warm d
azy ays that I hved 10 dreamland, or the life f . an
inary Indian in all his pomp and glory under th 0 an nnag.
k
' ll' d fi h . e azure sky
' 1 mg eer, g t10g battles against hostile trib &#8226;
O
es.
ne morning in April, 19-, my youngest broth
1
. . h er and I
were p aymg 10 t . e back yard when a yellow butterfty at
tracted our attentIOn. We both ran to catch it b t b .
. fl . ' u y
zig- zag ymg we were led only into a deep hollow amid cliff
of rock and big trees, where a swift brook was flowing
k k
. ov
a great roc rna 10g a roaring noise. We both decided n &#8226;
er to return to civjlization again. We were going to beco:~
Indians. This ~ as our home where man had not even see
as we thought. We began to work in earnest to build us
hut. We then went hunting and were soon laden with de
and other kinds of game for dinner and supper. A long a
desperate war was inflicted upon us by a hostile tribe. Tb
war raged several hours but at length the last man of the e~
emy was killed and as a natural consequence peace was re
stored. We ate our imaginary deer and bear until we wer
filled. We talked over how Father and Mother would c
for us when they learned that we were real Indians. Ho
sorry they would be for being " mean" to us. After we ha
talked over our sorrows and griefs, we decided to see ho
deep the water was at the foot of the cataract. On advancin
a loose stone rolled from under my feet and leaped over ~ h
water fall. We amused ourselves for several minutes rol
hn
stones over the fall. The ga. me at last grew old. We pr
ceeded to measure the water by wading into it. A water bat
tie took place between Red Eagle and Black Hawk. I w
Red Eagle and my brother was Black Hawk. Black Ha~
being younger than I, had to gain the victory, or else ourbo:
dian life would hav. e ceased abruptly. We ag. ain tadlke'nd caonse
how they would miss us. We were real Indians an I b gu
quence were barred from civilization. The mOon had e
' 22
25 &#183;
statesmen and leaders, which it ha &#183; s fur-e
are to meet this evening is o~ e of keep&#173;the
older men with their cap~ tal , their experi-
&#8226; influences; and on the other hand make it
young people to work out and realize in the
their ideals and aspirations.
lude, then, that the farm problem consists in
pon our farms a class of people who have suc&#173;ring
for themselves the highest possible class
y in the industrial, but in the political and so&#173;telative
status, moreover, that is measured by
of Am~ rican ideals.
main solution lies in the improving of country
some of the means by which this may be done.
st important and the outstanding feature of
ty is its schools. What about the rural high
running, is it performing all the functions that
ry school should? Or, are we not in our crave
~ culture about to swing the pendulum too fal-ight
of those things that are essential to the
the hap? iness of a civilized social being? The
a techmcal school but a real community school.
not only a building and a curriculum for the
ever running fountain of enlightenment an
, ntent for the entire community. Here is'the
d ty and I might say the duty of the rural teach&#173;ti
and : ush, for,: ard wholesome, social and rec&#173;eae;'
headut It. Will require a person with rare
t' ' a big heart, and one that is " up" and
Ime.
, neIetdshoofultdhebecount ry I. S t~ e improvement of the
d way to the ~~ e whos: Ideals and methods ap&#173;elfa
h eds of ItS constituents and pro&#173;&#8226;
Trhe ehre on earth wh'lIe seeking their salva-ing
meedc' urch should not only have the priestly
tween lmator between G0 d and man, but it must
an and man. I t must uO. lte the com-
THE NORMALITE
higher standard of living if a great man
h f A
. Y more would
t e arm. ccordmg to economic theory th 1
th f 1
&#183; e more w
on e arm means ower pnces for our products a de k
wages for farm laborers, which will result . n 10\ V
d
. m a small
uctlOn per man, and this will mean a lowerin er pro-d
d f 1
&#183; . h' h . g of the ta
ar 0 Ivmg w IC IS the very thing that we d0 not S 11-
We need not worry ourselves about the relati want.
are k. ept, on the farms fo. r the economic eqUi~ Iben~ uummbseerekth' at
to adjust Itself to changmg requirements. We d log " 0 not adv
cate the present. b. ack- to- the- farm" slogan that I. S now cu0r--
rent. The commiSSIOn on Country Life says that thO
" b k h f'" IS presen
. ac - to- t e- arm movement. IS for the most part unSC'len
tdic and unsound as a correctIve of our economic and . ' 1 soc
eVl s.
We do not care how many migrate to the cities, but w
,: ill have to take noti~ e as to the ones that are in this migra
tlOn. When w~ consider the fact that it is the very cream
of the rural population that is now leaving the farms it be&#173;comes
a problem worthy of our deepest consideration.
There are two classes in this rural exodus that we can
not afford to see go in staggering numbers. One of thes
classes is the retired farmer who has accumulated some mon
ey and has ripened in years of experience that is now force
to go to the city to provide educational and social advantage
for his family. The other class is the young people who ar
teeming with ambitions, bubbling over with ideals and aspira
tions, but are cramped and held down in a stagnated rura
society. The only thing that they can do is rebel and mO
V
out or suffer with their environments.
You can readily see what this has resulted in. The crea
is leaving. The rural district has been called " the cradle 0
. . f h' h the world ha
the race." It IS m fact, the hot bed rom w Ie
d
&#183; t be culled oU
always drawn its leaders. If that hot be 13 0 ssive wha
so. as to leave only the unambitious an. d unprogreday ru'le t
wJ1l be the product of the cradle that IS to some
. ' 11 nIt in a deg
e
world. You can readily see that this WI res ' t cannot 100
erated rural population which will mean that I
24
- D. L. MANIER.
A SUGGESTIVE DECLARATION OF INDEPENDEN
M. T. N.
said campus courses, and orgamzmg its
sball seem most likely to secure the safety
the boys. .
&lt; L. ...--- t uld dictate that campus courses long
~, wo \' h' not be entirely done away WIt Just to
f a few members of the faculty; and, ac-
&#8226; ence hath shown that the student1s are no. t
er such abolishment. But when a ong tram
eel upon the girls, and campus courses are
our right, it is our duty to throw off such rules
pus courses for the happiness of the students
ucb has been the patient suffering of the stu&#173;it
~ ecome necessary now to institute the
course.
ore, the students of the Middle Tennessee
&#8226; general student body assembled, do, in the
authority of these students, state that these
of a right ought to be, free and independ-
4! future, they shall have the right to campus
of the privileges which campus courses af&#173;I1MlDIllOrt
of this declaration, we mutually pledge
hearts for such campus courses.
- C. DAN FORD.
you to explain the grades on my report card.
I have no " A's" on my report for that grade
really would be ashamed to have a " B" which
ou can see then why I am proud of t'he " c"
correct.
~''' I h
S ave stand for dandy and the two " F's"
OoUusde. e&#8226; mother, my report I. S one of whI. ch you
dutifUl and studious daughter,
MARGARET PERRY.
THE NORMALlTE
muity in useful, wholesome everyday affairs. It can
the love of God without showing the love of man. not t
Last but not least, come the recreative Sports. " All
and no play makes . Johnny ~ dull boy." Systematized ~
must always react m orgamzed recreation. The great
j&gt; orations which have large numbers of employees are
ing the need and provl'd'mg means 0 f attractive recre ste'e
Yet the rural people have practically no organized recr: a~.
to satisfy their natural cravings. Skating, hockey, volley
ball, basket- ball, debating- clubs, reading societies, boy- scoU
. and the campfire- girls are only a few of the wholesome s &#8226;
and recreative activities that' should be pushed forward wi
the greatest zeal. And the only way that this will ever
done is for us to realize the " crying need" of the social
starved rural people. Our fundamental aim is happier fa
- ers and not richer farms. The improved a~ res must yie
not only corn but civilization. Lasting improvements a
economic succe'ss cannot come until farmers in some w
shall have attained a broader outlook on the wholesome, t
attractive, and the recreative aspects of life, upon these thin
- depend the unity and prosperity, the happiness and conte
ment of the American farmers.
When in the course of human events it becomes . nec
sary for the students of Middle Tennessee Normal to dlssol
the bands that connect the two sexes, and to ass~ me'hamlo
their fellow men, the free and equaI statt. On t0' vhlch teaf
- of nature and nature's God entt. t1ed them, a decent rehspectus
said fellow men demands that they shall declare t e ca
that impel them to separation. . t faculty a
We hold these truths to be self eVldent- tha . I d to cef
students are created equal; that theaI t ter are e. ntlt e nd
tain campus n. ghts; and among t hese are life, liber1ty, maade
' Pursuit of campus courses; and, whenever any ' rtU'se the rt.
the faculty becomes destructi. ve 0 f these ends, 1I I laying
of these students to alter or abolish such ru es,
' 26
29
- BELL.
ub there shall be no class distinction but all
teachers and pupils will stand on an equal
u have an interest in world affairs and a will&#173;heart
to make the world a better place for hu-'
join us.
crimes of modern student life is the ignorance
nts and a lack of knowledge of world affairs.
aim of this group to provide a rrieans of eli~ &#173;nce
in the most pleasing way possible and to
house for the study and promulgation of any
causes. The following officers were elected:
&#8226;&#8226; Brackin; Sec., Miss Emma Becton; Treas.,
on, and Historian, Mr. Paul Eaves.
and in the spirit of brotherhood to ex&#173;,
. until it reaches around the world to
of serVice .
f these desires " The World Rolity Club" of
o ormal was organized with a three- fold
essee .
n intellectual aim to study world affaIrs; a so-t
togegther and discuss the results of that
beeenevolent aim to render servI. ce wherever need
"' SKEETERS"
Apologies to the Author of " Daisies"
' ng when I go to bed,
the ' skeeters overhead'
are the little demons li~ ht
haunt the shadows of the night.
often while I'm dreaming so,
my head those skeeters go;
a~ e the little insects fair
flit upon the midnight air.
hen at morning I an. se
nb~ t a skeeter in the skies'
e Itten us aII and settled d'own
e meadows of the town.
THE NORMALITE
THE " A. B. C." OF M. T. N.
THE WORLD POLITY CLUB
Athletics honorably played.
Beautiful campus.
Christian ideals.
Deserving patronage.
Excellent equipment.
Founded by Godly men.
Goal, greater service.
Honor system throughout.
Instruction inspiring.
Junior College standing.
Kampus kept klean.
Libra~ y, workable, modern.
Many special departments.
Not the biggest, but the best.
Old in experience.
Pleasant social surroundings.
Quality, not quantity, our aim.
Rules, firmly and fairly enforced.
Socials, societies, scholarships many.
Teachers wide- awake.
Unity in all things.
Veracity, vital and valuable.
Worthy, warm hearted matron for girls.
Xtra fine faculty.
Youth's fountain and paradise.
Zealous that we may reach the zenith.
_ ANONYMOUS.
M ber of pupils a
On Tuesday, Nov. 14, at 4 P. f ., a num I' sO
teachers while assembled 1.11 room 42 hea. rd afoplekcuaclaror ss tb
which proved to be a cry from a suffering. h hun
seas. TheI. r hearts were so touched at the wall of ht e desl.
. 1 Ie that t ey &#8226;
homeless, and apparently friend ess peop I ' nterest
. t Ilectua I to know just how they live, to have an 111 e h an sy11l
theI. r problems and achI. evements, t 0 create a urn
28
30 THE NORMALITE THE NORMALITE 31
- DOROTHY LYON,
~---- &#173;M'AKING
HISTORY
M. T. N. AT 7: 15 A. M.
r
is completely overloaded with ribbons, ties, papers
dresse
and letters.
M. T. N. is a scene of confusion and disorder at seven. However, the girls leave, not thinking of their room, but
fifteen in the morning. The breakfast bell rings at that time . g that by some streak of good luck they will' get to
and while a few girls are ready to start to the dining rooIt h; P~ tables before all the teachers do, or thatMrs. Rutledge
at the first tap of the bell, the larger part of the girls are jus1 t '~ be late, and the blessing will not have been said, ,
being awakened from their peaceful slumber, and are hurry. WI There are ddzens of girls throughout the buildings mak&#173;'
ing as fast as they can to get dressed; for to most of the girl' ing equally as great an effort to get to breakfast and appear-the
breakfast bell is the rising bell. ing as untidy. ..
When the long pealing sounds of the bell are heard, thE The entire scene at seven- fifteen IS certamly one of con-girls
on the first floor hear above them bed- springs shakin~ fusion and disorder.
and squeaking, and girls jumping out of bed on the floor, The!:
a conversation something like this may be heard.
" Oh Sarah, where in the world is my stocking? I lefl
it here last night, and dear me! both of my garters are gone
Do you suppose they were misplaced during the feast? Mis! " When in the course of human events" some event stands
Tommie is always the first person in the dining room, and: out more prominently than all others it is frequently char&#173;am
always the last. I promised her yesterday I'd never be acterized as a part of history which is being made to be hand&#173;late
again." ed down to succeeding generations. In the truest sense of the
" Oh Helen, get another pair of stockings, there are m) word history is daily being made at M. T. N,
striped ones, roll them in, grab those bed- room slippers, hur On the night of the thirty- first of October residents in
ry up, we are going to be S0 late." and about the vicinity of the campus were peacefully lulled
While they are continuing their conversation they find to sle. ep or perhaps from sleep by the steady clang! clang! of
the few articles of clothing that they are to wear' and hurry the big bell on the dining hall. At ten- thirty o'clock the first
through the hall to the dining room, , peal of t~ e old bell rang out on the still night air arid with
, .. . the steadmess and regularity of the beat of the heart the
Their hair IS very poorly combed, they have on SOiled ding dong of th b 11 t' d ' 1 fi h' A M A
' dd' . kl k' . &#8226; e e con mue untl ve- t trty .
miles, a wnn ed s Irt, stnped hose and bed room slippers. steady dri 1 f" h h h . h dd "
A h h
' , zz e 0 ram t roug out t e mg t a ed to the Slg-s
t ey run t rough . ., the hall Sarah IS trymg to put on her nificance of the accompII'Shment 0 f t h'IS h'Itherto unheard 0 f
middy- tie m order to cover up the spots of soup that were feat.
on her m, iddy from the day bef. ore. ... Wh. en we turn back the pages of hi. story we are some-
.. Behmd them they leave their room m a very untidy can tunes discouraged at finding that so few men in modern days
dlt, lon. The closet door was left wide open; dresses, coat= Cstoalnd out prominently as dI'd such men as NapoIeon, Caesar,
skirts, crackers and sardines are all in a heap on the closet umbus, Washington, Lincoln and Peay. But the devising
f. loorh. Tw'do trunf ks are open, one tray out of the trunk, andd acnod &#8226; accomplishment of th'Is feat shouId gi. ve us comfort . The
m t e m~ die 0 the ~ ed, dresses, night gowns, pajamas a? . nung years will be crowned with glory, for we have in our
othe. r articles of clothmg are scatte. red all over the floor. Dldr' nwUisddsot men of ingenl'ous m'mds whose profound and ba aincde
ty dishes are on the table; empty tm cans on the wash stan . &#8226; m acco. mpanied by such indomitable wills as those who
two laundry boxes are open in the middle of the floor. The cal1' ied through such an important undertaking as did these
32 THE NORMALITE THE NORMALITE 33
bell ringers who will make a mark in the world.
Thus has history been written, a precedent been estah
lished, a demonstration of the presence of genius been madt
and the bell been rung all in one night.
- A BELL RI GER.
ANNOUNCEMENT
CcI..,/' n.
T he Iatter part of November the Y. MI C. A and the " Y S/ tJ"" t&gt; r.
W. C. A will present the " Country Minister" in the audita
rium. Preparation has already begun on the play and indica --- l~".~
tions are that this will be one of the best entertainments tha _------------;----------==--------=-=---=-:-=- &#173;will
be offered to the student body during the year. pubfished Monthly by th students of Middle Tennessee Normal, Mur-fteesboro,
Tennessee
DO IT NOW!
If you've got a job to do,
Do it now!
If it's one you wish were thru,
Do it now!
If you're sure the job's your own,
Don't hem and haw and groan,
Do it now!
Don't put off a bit of work,
Do it now!
It doesn't pay to shirk,
Do it now!
If you want to fill a place
And be useful to the race,
Just get up and take a brace-
Do it now!
Don't linger by the way.
Do it now!
You'll lose if you delay.
Do it now!
If the other fellows wait,
Or postpone until it's late,
You hit up a faster gait-
Do it now!
Address alt communications to Business Manager. Advertising rates
furnished upon request.
Application made for entry as second- dass matter at the Postoffice at
Murfreesboro, Tenn., under Act of Congress, March 3, 1879
Editorial Staff
CYRUS DEMENT , Editor- in- Chief
ELIZABETH GRIGSBY Associate Editor- in- Chief
E. P. EAVES Athletics
ROBERT PARTIN Y. M. C. A
MARGARET WATSON Faculty
HANNAH GRAHAM BELCHER Locals, Fun
T. E. CLARK Societies, Lyceum
MARY HILL KING Exchange
HESTER ROGERS Alumni
GERALDINE GRIGSBY Y. W. C. A, Glee Club
Business Staff
J. E. WINDROW Business Manager
CMARL E'BRANDON Assoc'late Bus'mess. Man. ager
ILDRED RIDLEY Associate Business Manager
_ W. T. WYNN Faculty Adviser
EDITORIAL
As this number of the ORMALITE goes to press we
J4
35
girls who can adopt the following as a part of their
can be admitted to membership in the R. O. B. B.
My mother told me not to smoke
I don't.
or listen to a naughty joke
I don't.
They made it clear I must not wink at handsome men
I don't.
To dance and flirt is very wrong
I don't.
I kiss no boys not even one
I don't know how it's done,
You wouldn't think I had much fun
I don't.
THE NORMALITE
b f re We just can't help it. There
we were eO &#183;
than f that makes us feel that way. .
&#8226; ' de 0 us . d iSlSl &#8226; &#176; d we retire to our rooms tire ,
d Y IS over an ld e a ' f thoughts won't return to our 0
wonder lour . " N I e f moments before we saypur ow
just a ew t to do as little. boys and girls at
as we wWeree wwiolln think of the old school and know
kne. e. d 11 that goes with it, its faculty of earnest
Jove It an ha are endeavoring to help us, and for the
omen, w 0 men and young women wh0 work to-n&#8226;
oble yohunogod of themselves and thei. r fe11ow man. y for t e g . h O
&#8226; d
these thoughts our hearts will fill Wit gratttu e
Ie
. we receive through our school and when y; e
881ngs - k ., .
heads for our own little private than sglvmg serVice
breathe a fervent prayer for our school and whe~ we
our respective place the following week ~ e ~ Ill be
men and women, inspired with a determmatl? n as
that of the Pilgrim Fathers to do our parts m the
life. Having done this we can more earnestly say,
enee " Our Father, we thank Thee."
f. Ogden proposes raising funds to buy a bell for the
to ring whenever they feel so inclined. But that would
the fun, except on rainy nights. .
THE NORMALITE
are thinking of Thanksgiving Holida d
h
. ys an the s' .
t e oc. casIOn. We turn back the pages of Ti Igntffican
centunes and read of the first Thank " me Or
the Pilgrim Fathers. sglvmg service held
After a winter of indescribable hardshi s .
time over half of that little band of n t' fP dunng w
f
. k' a Ion ounders .
rom SIC ness, disease hunger cold and th pensh
d
. ', eattack of th
lans. the. y went to work with a spirit ofpersevereance ld
termmatlOn, characteristic of them. They pI t d . an
I
. an e their
cu tlvated them faithfully and when harve t t' cro
k h G
s Ime came th
&#176; f new t ath od was good to them and had blessed thei. r e
orts a~ d ad caused food for the coming winter to be r
duced m abundance. Even the menace of the Indian P
been removed, for peace had come between the white
and the red.
Their hearts filled with gratitude and tha14!~ sgiving a
&#176; being the devout and religious people that they were th
must needs give expression to their feelings.
Calling the Indians in to take part in the services the
devoted a week to feasting, praying and giving of thanks.
Thus was the first Thanksgiving service held in Ameri
Since then for three hundred years this nation has alwa
sent up its thanks to God on the last Thursday in Novembe
for His Divine guidance and provision. Sometimes it ha
seemed difficult to find many things for which we as a na
tion could be thankful, but by looking about us we see hun
dreds of blessings on every side.
Again by Presidential Proclamation the thirtieth of No
vember 1922 has been set aside as a day on which we sha
give thanks unto the Lord for His goodness. This day wit
find many of us in our homes with those we love and hoi
most dear. And so this is our first blessing, that we hav
those whom we love and who love us. As we go back to th
old home and with. brothers and sisters, cousins, uncles, aunts,
fathers, and mothers we visit the fa" miliar scenes of our child&#173;hood
our hearts are softened. If we have been a little hard
ened by disappointment and trials of life we forget them fo
the time and enter into the spirit of the occas. ion. We mar
not realize it at the time but we will be just a httle better a
37
THE NORMALITE
d rofit from the activities in which
pleasu~ e an p hers- is called upon to take
d especIally teaC
. feel that in our society we are pre-
&#8226;. mll1d we . . d
15 In '. ' 1" of teachers and CItIzens, an are
onsIbl ItIes . G d
the resp . h ' d als which inhere 111 the ra y
to ards the hlg I e
Society.
Murfree Society
The Murfree girls are now ready with much interest to
a . Goin," and make this year's record the best. We
an tnerease in membership of about ten per cent over
Claxton Society
. . . the Claxton Literary Society has a
all lI1dIcatlOnS
f a very successful year. The new mem-ospect
or .' h k &#8226; 11 are showing a profound 1I1terest 111 t e wor
eir ~~ tendance and by their willingness to serve on
am1sim. provements on the Claxton ha11 are under way.
tatue of Longfellow has been purchased as an orna&#173;the
library case. Steps have bee~ taken to ~ x the
banner so that it may be more easIly put on dIsplay.
tions are being made concerning draperies for the
&#8226; Soon the hall will look a great deal more attrac-it
now is.
Oaxtons and Dromgooles gave their second joint
of the year in Dromgoole hall Oct. 31. As this was
e'en several of the numbers were in keeping with the
ghost story by Prof. Belcher was enjoyed very much
The music for the program was furnished by the Clax&#173;_
... "", o.- &#183; I. estra with one of the Dromgooles presiding at the
e Claxton Orchestra made its first appearance on the
lPlrq} l! l'a'm at the joint meeting. All the members were" not
ent but a splendid showing was made. In the near future
eet to have the organization completed and be able to
r it as a special attraction for our programs.
THE NORMALITE
T. E. Clark, Editor.
36
Grady Society Notes
ld GThe Grad. ie. s have entered into this year's workW'Ith t h
o rady. SpIrIt and enthusiasm. Interesting and instructtiv
pr~ grams have been given throughout the last month. It i
bemg endeavored to bring up before the society such topic
for debate as closely concern student life and the future citi
zens and, teachers of America and such as will offer mos
pro. fit from research and presentation. Some of the topic
whIch have been discussed are trade education in hig
schools, government control of coal mines in the United
States, and the question of equal rights and privileges for the
young ladies at the Middle Tennessee State Normal.
There is a pleasure in looking backward to the scenes 0
former activities and taking note of all the events, places, an
personalities which have given us delight and helped to mak~
the best that is in us. From this retrospection, we realia: e
the part that the present plays in the future and that we ar
largely outgrowths of our former experiences and have bee
shaped by our bygone associations. The various activities
of school life with which we have been connected become a
part of us and lay the foundation for all our future activities.
Such is the place a so&lt;: iety occupies in school life. Not only
does the present , cooperation and fellowship afford immediate
enjoyment, but they give us permanent development and offer
us something to take away into future life so as to enable us
39
THE NORMALlTE
Af the program a social hour
Belcher. ter
&#8226; f hments serv ~ d.
re res
as my children took my advice they are all succeed-
~ HY AND BIOGRAPHY
I b nd girls of our beloved state
years the &#176; I: c: tion. They grew up in com-
L '" for an e f hools and under inefficient
h rt terms 0 sc . d ?
S 0 blame for this? The chtl ren.
But who wa? s tNo o They were dent. ed t hI'S prop-g
teachers, . Th un f h lack of trained teachers. e
because 0 t e h' h'l
h' They became eager for t e1r c I-to
see tiS. d
d ntages than they themselves ha en-better
a va f b
I
e together to discuss plans or a et-poop
e cam . t
1909 the decree went forth that my eX1S en~ e
e possible and that my duty woul. d be to tram
1911 they put me in the geographIcal center of
state, just where I wanted to be. I was s~ happy
non' I was happier still with the duty whIch had
m:' but most of all I was happy with my' four
wer~ to help me press onward to a successful
tell you something of them for they are beau-e,
and efficient. .
r I had entered upon my work, so pleased with
ith my helpers, I called each of them to me to
ds of encouragement into their ears. " Murfree,
so intelligent, so alert, you have the whole world
Go forth and make yourself worthy of your
bo has set such a noble example." " Dromgoole, my
my handsome girl, there is mt. ch good to be
&#8226; world and you are worthy of your task. Follow
that the one is doing for whom ynu y ere named
lei will be proud of you." " Claxton, my boy, so no&#173;trong,
take up the work of that able educator for
med you and help the world to " get wisdom."
son, capable and determined as you are, may you
equal that literary genius and orator for whom you
but may you set an example for the whole world
38 THE NORMALITE
Dromgoole Society
We are indeed proud of the work the Dromgooles hav
been doing this term. At least fifty new members have bee
taken into the society and others have expressed a desire t
join. The new members have shown that they are willin
workers and are anxious to do all they can for the good 0
the society.
Weare planning to have a bazaar in a few weeks, and'
is very interesting to hear each member planning what sh
can contribute.
The programs this term have been unusually good. Som. e
one has said, " We become like those with whom we aSSOCI
ate." Our faculty members must be sure their exclmples ar
good, because a mock faculty in Dromgoole Hall two week
ago, showed very clearly that we are remembering how they
ac~ .'
The Dromgoole and Claxton societies met together &#163; 1 Dromgoole Hall on Hallowe'en and enjoyed a very derIght u
program. One of the most interesting numbers was a ghost
that of last year and each member is active d
the Society, an eager to
The Mu. rfree girb have purchased a PI'Cture of M
Murfree which they are proud to have to ke . &#8226; ary
Hall. ep m the Soci
The Murfree Society felt highly honored t h
A R . 0 ave th
. . meet m the Murfree Hall on Thursday 0 e
I nterestm. g talskwere'given on the life and w' orckts. 2o6f' M1a
N, . Murfree. After the much enjoyed program Was rende
dehghtful refres. hments were served by the Mur free gt. rlsr
As the festival days were approaching on Hall ' .
. 11' . owe en
especla y mterestmg program was enJ'oyed. PumPk'IUS a
gh. osts adorned the hall and ghosts and witches greeted u
MISS Reynolds gave us a very interesting account of her tr
to Europe and we are anxious to hear more. Mrs. Edwar
who was present at our meeting presented us with some flo
ers which added to the attraction. We are anxiously wai
ing for the rest of the festival days.
THE NORMALITE 41
Margaret Watson, Editor
ent Lyon went into West Tennessee on offical bus&#173;tly.
Incidentally he stopped over in Memphis for
our former president, Prof. R. L. Jones, from
rought greetings and messages of good cheer to
body.
&#8226; T. Wynn spent several days attending the M. E.
at Fayetteville.
, S. Gillentine spent several days in Washington,
cling a confederation of women's clubs. She was
ental in bringing a number of noted speakers to
ro during the recent D. A. R. convention.
utledge's daughter and attractive little son were
' tors at the Normal.
ary Ellen Fontaine attended the Dowling family
Robertson County, Sunday, October 29.
J, K. Marshall, critic teacher in the intermediate
de a speech in behalf of the women voters at Shel&#173;OctOber.
Anne Ordway, critic etacher in the upper grades,
t from scho 1 . .
absence thoe on akccount of Illness for a . few days.
of '. wor was very ably earned on by
effICient practice teachers.
tlls has taken charge Qf the Sunday afternoon Bi-
- MIDDLE TENNESSEE NORMAL.
Mr. Ogden's recent speech on Eur? pean afffairost rwemhoin
us of a speaker who said, " A certain wr~ t~~- I org
was- said er- ah- I- er forgot what he sal~.
ing. They are sending out over the state of Tenll
pab. le teachers who are carrym. g the work to succeesssee
are also developing Christian leaders, doctors, statesms~ n
entists artists, literary men and women, orators and &#8226;
others , who are pursum. g worthy occupatI. Ons. ' ma
. My children think so much of their worthy namesakes t
each of them will give a biography of his or her OWn na
sake. One biography will come in each of the following f
numbers of THE NORMALITE. As my children are all
same age and of equal importance, I shall try to be polite
giving the girls preference. Dromgoole and Murfree
" draw straws" as to who comes first. Then if Murfree com
first of the girls, Claxton will come first of the boys, or
Dromgoole comes first of the girls, then Grady will come fi
of the boys.
THE NCfo,;.\ L1TE
What I got from a Recitation Oct. 22, 1922.
1. Two ~ ensible questions asked.
Z. All questions repetitions from form~ r lessons. h
J.' Teacher showed a lack of preparation. Must a
attended one of Murfreesboro's numerous clues.
4. Stressed, " We cannot afford to do such things." W
the deuce wants to?
5. Shot a fragmentary line of hot air. . d k d a
6. Ten minutes before the close of the peno as e
thought question.
7. Gets by too easy, methinks.
We have been wondering how many perfect lessons cauel
have been prepared W. ith the comb &#183; m' ed efforts a, nd eNn'erhgtyW
pended m. n. ng. mg t1le be11 a11 m. ght on Hallow. e Iefnib1911 . ba
would also like to know how many 0 f the fait 1 u e'n Pst
wo. uld stand in the ram. one hour to pi. epare a lesson 1
chology for instance.
ble class in the boys' dormitory. This class is being conduct&#173;ed
under the auspices of the Y. M. C. A.
Miss Jackson, critic teacher in the lower grades, and
Miss Little of the Home Economics Department assisted the
Y. W. and Y. M. in their Hallowe'en social by posing as palm
readers and clairvoyants. Several members of the faculty
were present at the social and enjoyed the evening's enter&#173;tainment.
Mr. Davis is very busy harvesting his crop of peas and at&#173;tending
to the building of his new house which will soon be
completed.
Mrs. Davis is busy adjusting herself to being mother to
the Moffit House girls after having to give the care of the
boys over to Mr. and Mrs. Gracey.
Mr. Gracey accompanied the poultry judging team to
North Carolina. During his absence Mrs. Gracey was visited
by her mother, Mrs. John Adkerson, of Smyrna.
Mr. Miles labors in season and out in his efforts to keep
the football players in good fighting condition.
Miss Wilson, of the Physical Training Department, has
begun her basket ball work with the girls preparatory to the
opening of the new gymnasium.
Mr. Belcher is devoting himself so closely to the large
classes in Science, that he rarely has time to leave his habi&#173;tation
in the basement. However, we know that he is ex&#173;pounding
the wonders of science by the fumes which occa&#173;sionally
emanate from the laboratories.
In like manner the hammering, sawing, and planing
heard in the Manual Training Shops show that Mr. Wood&#173;ward
is busy carrying on the work in that department.
Miss M'urfree, our able and accommodating librarian, is
ready at all times to assist the students in exploring the bound
volumes of knowledege which are under her care.
The very capable manner in which Mrs. Barbee continues
to minister to the physical wants of the student body keeps
her endeared to our hearts as is no other member of the in&#173;stitution.
Mises Monahan and ' B~ chanan assisted by Mr. Bracki~
have a department on the north- east corner of the second
42 THE NORMALITE
THE NORMALLTE
. ~
: moor from whIch all indl'c t' 1 .
a IOns ead us t b r o unknown lores of Hist E' 0 e leve that hither-
. . ory, nglIsh and E
emg mterestingly searched ' xpression are
Th h out.
oug the campus is gold and b
frosts Mr. Ogden is gett" rown from the early
. mg It and the far' .
/ Wmter. The business l'k h m m condItion for
- I e urn of th ' 1
ures us that Our supply of ' Ik e ensI age cutters as-hroughout
the winter months~ 1 and butter will continue
Mr. Holmes and the M' M
t &#183; l f Isses ! cDonald k'
e al s 0 the business side of h . . . ar. e . eepmg the
ood condition. t e mstItutlOn In Its habitual
Mr. Horace Jones is conductin
rtment of the school . g the rehabilitation de-m
a manner who h .
f, to the institution and t th IC IS a credit to him-
Misses Saunders Rey Old e department which he serves
T , no sand Sh h d .
. . N. will not lack fo . . ep er guarantee that
ynolds is strong on probrl musIc
f
tMhls year. Though Miss
d . ems 0 athe t' 1
omg much toward the b ' ld' rna Ica concern she
11 be a credit to the sch lUI Ing tip of an orchestra that
M' 00.
ISS Williams spent the k .
on her return was wee. - end In Nashville recently
sin. accompanIed by her brother and her
Miss Schardt went on her '.
dar Hill the latter part of Octp~ nodIcal week- end visit to
Mrs F t &#183; 0 er.
. er ~ g, who accompanied the Y W .
the Blue RIdge Conferen 1 ." C. A. delegatIOn
e of the Y. W C A h Idc~ ast sprIng, attended a confer&#173;.
. . e In Atlanta a few weeks
ago.
1\{ " My Teacher
y teacher aIn t satisfactor tuh . ,
reckon she tell dat h'l y. me, MIS Mally. What
Sh ' 1 c 1 e yestIddy? .
e ow dat IV sp II f
pe1ls ivy. e our, when even a idjut ' ud know
T 11 Strange e er- sorry b
0unt t ut you haven't enough money in
F' 0 cash. this check. your
aIr Customer- That's stran
to cash the last one I h d g;. h~ h~ re was enough mon&#173;a
, an t IS Isn't nearly as large.
45 THE NORMALITE
~ paign just before the game with Bethel and accomplished
\\' Onders in that line.
Of course there are always scores of announcements that
tnust be made most every day. There's often quite a clam&#173;oring
among the faculty when several of them want the floor
at once.
Other members of the faculty that have appeared at chap&#173;el
hour are: Mr. Davis, Mr. Woodward, Mr. Belcher and
Mr. Gracy.
One of the most instructive and inspiring of our chapel
talks during October was that of General Hoyt Stewart. He
explained in a general way the principles of the Constitution
and brought to the attention of the students the necessity for
a higher type of law- abiding citizenship. In conclusion he
traced the American Flag in its march of advancement and
pointed the way toward a higher form of Americanism.
Mr. Sims gave us an interesting talk on what we could
do to promote the welfare of the Normal. One of his most
striking points was that, while we should always praise our
s~ ol , it took more than hot air to build a reputation. He
sta d that the school would be judged by what we, its stu&#173;d
s did, and that we would be judged, to some extent, by
th school's reputation. Thus it is to the mutual advantage
of chool and pupil that the faculty and student body do the
hi est possible type of work.
A novel chapel exercise was given by the Home Econom&#173;class
4 a. The members of the class wore dresses which
themselves had made, and exhibited them from the plat-
Mrs. Rowe gave a brief history of Home Economics
e schools. Everyone appreciates the splendid work which
department is doing. Mr. Wynn in introducing the
ker changed the Scripture reading to " Every woman
eth her gingham dress and weareth it."
On October the twenty- seventh Mr. Gracy talked inter&#173;gly
of the trip he and his Poultry Judging Team made
orth Carolina. He told us of their work, their kind re&#173;ion,
and the results of the contest. After showing the
d h had the pleasure of meet &#183;
Thus far the student bo Yh as when they visited us
. . t ' S of t e town,
ing four of the mmls el H ton Dr. Anderson and
They are' Dr. amp ,
at chapel hour. . h' ne of our students.
D C leman w a IS 0 h
Dr. Gray. Also . r. S
o
. h e~ tended an invitation to all t e
Mrs. Fredenck mIt t" given in their honor
. men to attend the recep lOn
ex- servIce . L ' on f h Amencan egl .
by the local pO, st 0 t e . oke in interest of the Sta-
Mr. Gleaves of VanderblltMs~ h' game and as a result
. 11 for the Vandy- IC Igan
dium, especla y t d at that game.
I 11 represen e ' Norma was we tunity pass to g!\~
' d t Lyon rarely lets an oppor Pres! en
us a sermonette. . ded the prepondero~
. ho ughly expo un
Mr. Brackm so t ro h I that there's no danger nol
theme of Love, rec~ ntl~ at cape d ot being able to diagnd
of a Normalite falltng m love an n
his own case. . llotted to him to cond
k up the tune a ,
Mr. Wynn too . us some queer answers wh
chapel one day by readmg to
he had received on exam papers. the front,
bhors vacant seats near
Miss Saunders . a
d
f this fact real often.
d h remm s us 0 chapel, an s e. Y M. and Y. W. conduc
The representatIves of the. I
. t' manner recent y.
chapel in a very mteres mg d' ery successful " p
The Editor- in- Chief conducte a v
&#183; 44
.' that flashes by
Who 1S 1t now d dropping eye,
With scanty clothes an ld gladly die?
e sap wou
For whom som A Flapper.
47 THE NORMALITE
The Home Economics Club
So nigh is grandeur to our dust,
So near is God to man,
When duty whispers low THOU MUST,
The youth replies I CAN.- Emerson.
Mary had a little curl
That hung upon her ear.
And every night when she went to bed,
It hung upon the chiffonier.
Some Happenings of the H. E. Club
Ada ].- What is a doughnut?
Frances E.- It's a hole surrounded by bad cooking.
" I am worried about my complexion, doctor; look at my
face." said Mary Hill King.
" My dear Miss King, you'll have to diet."
Oh, I never thought of that; what color do you think
would suit me best?
Miss Cullum- What caused aU the commotion in the li&#173;rary
this morning?
Miss Brandon- It was only Miss Little trying to explain
Miss Murphy that she had only bumped her head on a
ttom shelf.
Miss Eggleston- Fifty years ago girls married before
y were twenty; nowadays they are thirty before they
' nk of it.
" We get wiser every day. In another fifty years we
n't marry at aU."
Mrs. Clark-" I see by tonight's paper that Paris says
men are going to wear their dresses longer."
Mr. Clark- It's a good thing, you never wear a dress
month.
The Home Economics Club had its first social meeting
&#183; on Thursday, November 2. After a short program several
new members were taken in. A contest was the feature of
, the afternoon. The prize was awarded to Miss Gladys Smith,
. after which delightful refreshments were served.
.:........
h . hard earned kale
Who is it spen? s \ a~: t a woeful tale
Who makes th1s p h t'he male?
. d adly t an
Who 1S more e A Flapper.
_ THE COLLEGIATE WORLD.
- h~ h' h many a
us impression w 1C . h to
To correct the e:~~~:~ l all night on the 31std ~~ a;; rofS'
that one fellow rang d' hifts. We under stan 1 h aod
state that it was wordketh~ nfi~ st shift, while Profs. Be c er
d Ogden ha k Gracy an h'ft at daybrea .
Davis had the last s 1
. ild and winsome coot
Who was th1s w 11 the boot
d poor Adam pu
That ma e f hat forbidden fruit?
And taste 0 t A Flapper.
, iden fair
This Cleopatra mCa r tore his hair,
h great aesa
For w om . so debonair?
Who was th1s vamp A Flapper.
. . dd called Salome
Who was th1s b1 y . f h' dome h Baptist 0 1S ,
That robbed Jo n man leave home?
de mere
The one that ma A Flapper.
THE NORMALlTE
46 . d d the members he mtro uce
h' h Mr Barnes won, d h chool
medals w 1C h had so ably represente t e s brief re-of
the team, w 0 ercise Mr. Ogden gave a .
At a recent chapel. e,:- 1 events of Europe and AS1a.
. of the stirring pohtica
V1ew _-----
A College View
~ You can't put anything over on old Normal. She may
lag a little once in a while along some lines, but she always
catches up with the band wagon. It's a settled and a great
satisfaction that we at least have a secret organtzation for
our progressive boys. It is very appropriately named " The
Royal Order of the Blinking Buzzards," a select title for a
select crowd. Whenever you see two distinguished looking
gentlemen greet each other in the hall with a grotesque sign,
know that they are " Blinking Buzzards" trying to live up to
their motto, " Be Hard."
The Murfree Society were hostesses for the local D. A.
R. chapter at four o'clock on October the twenty- sixth when
a memorial meeting was held for Miss Mary Noailles Mur&#173;free,
or Charles Egbert Craddock, Tennessee's gifted story&#173;teller.
Beautiful tributes were paid to Miss Murfree's life,
work and influence. At the completion of the interesting
program, light refreshments were served.
The newly organized band under the direction of Mr.
Golden of Nashville, is progressing nicely. Before long it will
be out on the athletic field inspiring our snappy rooters.
The Home Economics Club entertained The Normalite
Staff with a delightful breakfast in October. The staff
recommends the club as one of the most worthy and interest&#173;ing
organizations in the school.
After a complete rejuvenation the Moffit Hall is again
occupied by Normal students. But this time, instead of boySr
they are girls who moved from the dormitory. All reports
indicate that peace and happiness reign up on the hill.
Every Normalite now has a chance to become a hero- or
heroine, by rescuing his Alma Mater from her dilemma. The
trouble is this. Old M. T. N. needs a new school song. She
must have it. The field is open and competition is absent, so
here's your opportunity to become popular and famous.
One of the most enjoyable events during the past month
was the Hallowe'en party on October the twenty- eighth. Ev&#173;erybody
. came and everybody had a good time. It seems that
the spooks had made special plans that no one was to have
a complete nervous system when he left. If ghosts, and
witches, and clammy hand- shakes, and tragic prophecies
didn't destroy a fellow's happiness and comfort, then the elec&#173;tric
shock was applied, and in extreme cases the Bad Man
gave chase. Some don't seem to have recovered yet.
Some , more honors have come to M. T. N. Our Poultry
Judging Team, which participated in a contest in North Car&#173;olina
from October 18- 22, made a splendid record. Mr. Barnes
brought back the standard bronze medal and the silver util&#173;ity'medal.
The team consisted of Messrs. Barnes, Russell, '..
L. Johnson and Marshall Johnson with Mr. Gracy as coach.
They were gone five days and were cordially and hospitably
entertained during their visit. We have just cause for pride
n our Poultry. Judging Team.
The faculty and student body have been very fortunate
In being able to attend the evening programs of the D. A. R.
conference which was held in Murfreesboro early in Novem&#173;ber.
Several noted speakers appeared on these programs.
Friday, Nov. 3, the delegates to the D. A. R. conference
ere present at chapel. State Regent, Mrs. L. S. Gillentine,
presided. A number of the delegates made short talks to the
students. On that day Gov. A. A. Taylor also addressed the
student body, after which he rendered one of his famous se&#173;lections
on the " fiddle."
His four sons were then introduced and they gave a num&#173;er
of excellent songs.
Mrs. Foster Spain, Jr., added to the program with a vo&#173;cal
solo.
THE NORMALITE 49
THE NORMALITE
48
51
.. ':. ;,'
THt: NORMALITE
5. For Sale:
The following articles found. in or about the build&#173;ing
will be sold for charges.
3 pink powder puffs.
1 handkerchief, monogramed " Z"
1 barlow knife ( blades all broken out.)
1 watch ( it doesn't run.) .. : 5r:;'~
1 notebook ( filled with scrap paper.) .- :" if
1 parasol ( cover torn off, ribs bent and handle missing)
See Mr. Holmes.
6. To Let:
Any number of open evening dates. Men only need
apply. See Agnes Parks, Verna Eason, Elizabeth
Grigsby and Geraldiine Grigsby,
7. Wanted: A new girl for Coach Miles.
8. Wanted: A bright colored dye for a sweater. See
Carl Brandon.
10. For Sale: One used pipe, and a broken package of
cigarettes. Will exchange for mints or chewing gum.
See Paul Eaves.
11. Lost: All the dignity which I ever possessed. See
Mr. Brackin.
I fear nothing in the universe but that I shall fail to know
Diy duty; or knowing it that I shall fail to do it.- Mary Lyon.
history we would advise him to have a good Geography
glossary close at hand.
wanted:
1. New airs to be set to music. Green's one and only
chord catches anything in music.
2. An unusual " stude" who can get a word in edgeways
when conversing with gatlin- gun Brackin.
3. To meet the guy who will admit that he was the one
who created the disturbance in the boy's dormitory.
4. A ' substitute for ham and peas for Sunday dinner;
must be economical, distasteful, and easily prepared.
No other need apply.
Love thy neighbor as thyself; but stay in thine own room
during study hours in the dormitory.
Lost : A whole night's sleep by everybody within a mile
of M. T. N.
_ Prof. Woodward is again troubled with his old affliction
" Automalitis." Treatment s Take two doses of Monroe nigh~
and morning and you will be all right, Prof.
The next time Mr. Ogden makes a talk on European
The eighth wonder happened recently when " Profs."
Woodward and Belcher decided to snap into it from now on.
A duty need not be unpleasant.- Mary Lyon.
A profession is a dignified calling which requires prepa&#173;ration
and lasts a lifetime.- W. T. W.
HITS, RUNS, AND ERRORS
Tasks taken upon ourselves seem lighter than those im:
posed by others.- St. John Crevecoeur.
We thought the soul of woman was one of the things
that held men most; but,
George P.
Harvey he,
Sez this kind o'thing's an exploded idee.
No man who has once heartily and wholly laughed can
be altogether irreclaimably bad. The man who cannot laugh
is not only fit for treasons, stratagems, and spoils; but his
whole life is already a treason and a stratagem.- Thomas
Carlyle.
THE NOR' ( ALITE
Huffman has added band practice to that of vocal exer&#173;cise.
What plague will we have next?
The teacher has not commanded respect in the past be&#173;cause
she has not deserved it.
i ,. Mrs. Adas Verble, better known to Normalites as Miss
Elizabeth Moore, ' 18, and her husband, Mr. Verbal, ' 17, are
- now residents of Chattanooga, where Mr. Verble has a re&#173;:
sponsible position as teacher in the High School.
Miss Verda Broome ' 22 and Miss Sarah Goodrich ' 20
have positions in the Clarksville Grammar School.
Miss Margaret Sanders ' 22 is teaching in Chattanooga.
Mr. Cind Mrs. W. W. Harmon are now in school at Pea&#173;body,
where they expect to ge't their degrees in July of 1923.
Misses Margaret Lowe ' 19, Katherine Lowe ' 17, Eulalia
Sanders ' 18, Annie Lou Ragland ' 21, and Mr. Clarence Brun&#173;er
' 13 have positions in the schools of Murfreesboro.
Miss Fana Wilkerson ' 22 is teaching near Johnson City.
Miss Dessie Nisbett, ' 13, has charge of the school at Old
Jefferson, in Rutherford County.
Miss Annie Bowen Knox, ' 21, has returned to Mt. Plea&#173;sant,
where she has charge of the Domestic Science in the
high school.
Miss Mattie Frost Bell has charge of the Domestic Sci&#173;ence
at Anniston, Ala., again this year.
Mr. Oscar McPeak, who recently married a Dyersburg
belle, is now located in Nashville.
Mr. Thomas B. Abernathy, ' 16, is doing scout work in
Alabama.
Miss Clarissa Crenshaw, ' 20, who received her degree
THE NORMALITE S3
from Vanderbilt this spring, is now teaching History m the
High School in Chattanooga.
Miss Martha Moon, ' 20, now has charge of the primary
work in the Christiana High School.
Miss ' Susie Lee Grigsby, ' 19, is at home this year.
Miss Bessi. e Lee Batey, ' 20, now Mrs. G. W. Haynes,
has charge of the Domestic Science in the Smyrna High
School.
Miss Louise Glaus, ' 22, whose marriage to Mr. Paul Ma&#173;~
on was an event of intere~ t during the last summer quarter,
IS now pleasantly located m her farm hom'e near Lavergne.
Miss Elizabeth Leigh, ' 22, is spending this year at home.
Miss Elizabeth Schnieder, ' 18, is now Mrs. Richardson
of Springfield.
Robert Liggett,' 19, who was in the Normal during the
spring term of 1922, is principal of the High School at Left&#173;wich,
Tenn.
Lucile Maples, ' 19, is teaching at Lascassas, Tenn.
Miss Ethel Grigsby, ' 19, now Mrs. Anderson of Tulla&#173;homa,
is teaching in the Tullahoma schools.
Misses Lennie J. Sanders and Margarite Crick, mem&#173;bers
of the faculty of the Richard City School, were recent&#173;ly
visitors in McMinnville.
Leona Graham, ' 22, is teaching in Washington, Ga.
Virginia Darden, ' 18, who was a leader in the activities
of the Normal while a student here, is now Mrs. Watson of
Cedar Hill, Tenn.
Oran McMahan, ' 20, has been at West Point for the past
two years.'
Stanley McMahan, ' 21, is taking work in Peabody'.
Helen Sawyer, ' 22, is teaching near her home at Brent&#173;wood,
Tenn.
Pauline Hobdy, ' 20, who was in Peabody last year, is
now teaching English in Kentucky.
Ruth Hobdy, now Mrs. Cummins, who taught in the
schools of Chattanooga last year, is teaching in Kentucky.
Weare glad to learn from Mr. Lyon's account, in chapel
that the Tribble High School at Dover, Tenn., which he has
recently VI. s. Ited, ' IS rna k'mg such splendid progress under the
. ....... -.- . ~ THE NORMALITE
Heater Rogers, Editor.
S2
Edna Swift seems very much interested in " the rolling-
Stone."
Louise Burkitt: " Oh, I want a fur choker so bad!"
Edna Swift: " I do too. I want a black one."
Louise: " I don't. I want a Brown one. I had a Brown
suit- or"
A Music Leason
Hams: " Miss Saunders, will you please tell me some of
the names of the notes, so that I can practice for band work?"
Miss Saunders: " Ruth, please take him in the next room
across the hall- Gym."
Hams did not hesitate; his face looked like a beet as he
cleared the door. The door went pang! just ' as a shout of
laughter from the Glee Club went up to the ceiling.. '
" That is one of those music experiences," he muttered in
an undertone.
THE NORMALITE 5S
Robert Partin, Editor.
The Y. M. e. A. work has progressed beautifully through
the month of October and has so fulfilled our greatest hopes
and expectations that it would prove its value as an import&#173;ant
part in the student life of the young men. Under the ear&#173;nest
and able leadership of the president, Blaine H. Shelton,
the regular Wednesday night meetings have been inspiring
and helpful to all the young men who have availed themselves
of the opportunity of attending these services.
Among those who have appeared on the program with
messages to the boys are Prof. Wynn, Messrs. Carroll, Clark,
Dement, and Cook. Mr. Cook gave a report of his trip to
Nashville in conference with other state delegates, and ex&#173;plained
the plans under way to reorganize the State Student
Y. M. e. A. in such a way that each organization in the state
will have greater power in shaping the policies of the work.
A handsome victrola and a careful selection of records
have recently been purchased for the use of the young men.
The Sunday afternoon Bible Study Class under the lead&#173;ership
of its President, Mr. P. E. Burton, and its instructor,
Prof. Sims, is progressing nicely. We would like to have all
the boys join this class for the hour of study on Sunday after&#173;noon.
To the young men who have not yet entered the Y. M. e.
A. organization let us again extend to you a cordial invitation
to meet with us in our morning watch services every morning
54 THE NORMALITE
direction of its present group of teachers who are all gradu&#173;ates
of the Middle Tennessee Normal. e. M. Elmore, ' 22, is
principal.
SPl? nce B. Holden, ' 17, has a position as teacher in Ar&#173;kansas.
Beulah Overall, ' 16, is spending this year at home in
1\ 1urfreesboro.
Ethel Anderson, ' 17, who taught for several years, is now
Mrs. Harry Cline of Washington, D. e.
Mrs. Martin Luther, better known here as Helen Gance,
16, is now living at Burns, Tenn.
Ethel Ford, ' 21, has a position this year as teacher in
the Elementary Department of the Gordonsville High School.
Miss Mary Frances King, ' 18, has recently accepted a
position as teacher on Lookout Mountain.
Cornelia Clark, ' 20, who for the past two years has taught
Domestic Science in Chattanooga, was quietly married to
William Hall Davidson of Murfreesboro on Oct. 26, 1922. The
beautiful home wedding was witnessed by a host of friends.
After their ' wedding trip, this couple will be at home in Mur&#173;freesboro.
Windrow: " Did you know that kissing is the language
of love?"
Elizabeth: " Well, why don't you say something?"
and our Wednesday night meetings and thus avail yourselves
of the opportunity of developing the young man four square
for which principles the Y. M. C. A. stands.
THE NORMALITE 57
We are happy to say that, it seems we have the best
group of workers this fall that have ever entered M. T. N..
' Every girl is taking an active part in our Y. W. work, and is
ver ready to do her part.
We have great plans before us: for the coming year,
many of which we expect to develop this fall.
The Y. W. and Y. M. play to be given the first of De&#173;cember
we are glad to say is being worked up well, under the
student direction of Misses Bond and Bray. We expect noth&#173;ing
else but that it shall be a wonderful success.
Nov. 6, our Student Friendship Drive will be opened, and
it is our hope and desire to raise quite a fund for this purpose.
About three weeks later during the week of prayer, our
World Fellowship Drive will be put on. Just how it will be
conducted, we are not yet ready to say. Individual canvass&#173;ing
is always good, or we probably will organize ourselves
and work in teams for small pay. This plan has been worked
out and tried; we know that it can be successful.
Another thing on the hearts and minds of us all is the
Pauline Alsup memorial. Many discussions have been brought
up, and quite a few suggestions have been offered. Before
the year is gone we hope to have some form of a monument
to the memory of our 1921 Y. W. C. A. president.
THE NORMALITE
The other day Miss Vera Williams received the follow&#173;ing
note:
My dear Miss Williams:
Pardon my calling your attention to the fact, but you
have pulled Johnny's right ear until it is larger than his left.
Please pull his left ear for a while.
We caught Johnson and Brier in the Library looking for
their names in " Who's Who in America."
Hark the students voices sing
Take Tutt's pills, take Tutt's pills.
Hear the rustle of the students' wings
Students' voices meek and mild
Two for a man, and one for a child.
Naughty, Naughty- Archie.
How dare you, you bad thing!
We'll have to get you a guardian.
English XXI Salad
Take the contents of:
1 Kimball's English Grammar.
1 Dictionary.
4 Outlines.
8 or 9 Stories.
Mix well in a gentle conglomeration. Serve on notebook
paper and present to Mrs. Fertig.
56
Prof. Belcher says the fellows who rang the bell all night
on Hallowew'en night haven't gray matter enough to be
teachers. Anyway they showed that they have endurance
power which is more essential for a successful pedagog.
. Acuff: " They say Dement is wandering in his mind
Since he went to Chattanooga.
Huffines: There is no danger; he can't wander far.
Let us enlarge our school by expanding ourselves.
When you find a one dollar bill in your pocket, it serves
only as a reminder that you've forgotten to pay a bill some
place.
When ice cream grows on macaroni trees,
When Sahara sands are muddy,
When cats and dogs wear B. V. D.' s,
That's the time I like to study.
THE NORMALITE 59
When you start to kiss a girl don't fail to blowout the
light. Shadows don't lie.
----
Mr. Smith : John, what is your prescription for long life?
John: Eat all you want, drink everything you want, and
stay single.
the following request: Please tell me just what you want
me to tell you.
Miss Rosa: J epp, quote the saddest verse in the Bible.
J epp: There , is a crying for wine in the streets, all joy
is darkened, the mirth of the Lord is gone. ( Isaiah 24 : 2).
Salesman: " I'm selling invincible wire, Mister, why
don't you fence your field and be up to date?"
Farmer: " Speakin' of bein' up to date, young fellow,
. can't you see I am using wireless."
THE NORMALITE
Mary Hill King, Editor.
" Smile awhile, keep smiling,
For while you smile,
Another smiles, and soon
There's miles and miles of smiles."
When I first went to see her
I showed a timid heart,
And when the lights were low
W e sat t h u s far a par t.
But when our love grew stronger,
We knew its joys and bliss,
We knocked out all spaces,
And wesatupcloselikethis.
She: ( drinking a chocolate malted milk) I do love any&#173;thing
that has chocolate in it.
He: I ate chocolate pies for dinner.
Jones I never knew what to do with my week end.
Smith: Why not keep your hat on it?
If love is blind, passion is cockeyed.
Our first number of the NORMALITE has been sent to
many colleges and high schools. We trust that these schools
will gladly exchange their editions with us. We shall appre&#173;ciate
not only your paper in return, but also, any suggestions
you will give us. We have one more school to add to our
- exchange list, Ridgely High School, Ridgely, Tenn.
Teacher :" Where is aluminum most found?"
Student: " In kitchen ware."
A student in class not understanding the question
CHINESE PECULIARITIES
The Chinaman shakes his own hand instead of yours.
He keeps out of step when walking with' you.
Ruth Lee made a motion at Bible Study last Sunday that
girls be allowed to make dates as well as boys. Ave Mc&#173;Glosson
seconded the motion.
Minister ( meeting Paul Burton on Salem pike) :
" Why, Burton, aren't you going to church tonight?"
Burton: " I'm on my way to a place of worship right
now."
THE NORMALITE 61
One of the greatest assets to any institution is good ath&#173;letics.
It's the biggest drawing card and advertisement that
a school can have. Clean, wholesome, and uplifting athletics,
comprising and embracing that fundamental spirit of co- op'
eration between faculty, student body, and team does more
to attract the eye of the public than anything else. The pub&#173;lic
judges an institution largely by its athletics. You can help
make our athletics better by manifesting a real school spirit.
The boys on the athletic field are revived with new determi&#173;nation,
they have an incentive or stimulus to action if you
show and prove to them that you are interested in their suc&#173;cess.
Therefore, let us co- operate and assist our team to the
best of your ability. It's a duty that you owe to yourself, to
the lads who represent our school on the athletic field, and to
your institution.
Bryson Falla Before The Blue And White
On the morning of Oct. 16, the Normal eleven journeyed
' Over ot Fayetteville to encounter the Bryson squad. At three
o'clock the teams locked horns. It was a real battle; man
against man, foe against foe, each desirous of victory. The
Bryson lads were enveloped with " pep" and put up a game
THE NORMALITE
He puts his hat on in salutation.
He whitens his boots instead of blackening them.
He rides with his heels in his stirrups instead of his toes.
His compass points south.
His women folks are often seen In trousers, accompa&#173;nied
by men in gowns.
Often he throws away the fruit of the melon and eats
the seeds.
He laughs on receiving bad news. ( This is to deceive
the evil spirits.)
His left hand is the place of honor.
He says westnorth instead of northwest and sixths four
instead of four sixths.
His favorite present to his parent is a coffin.
He faces the bow when rowing a boat.
His mourning color is white. ~~
To bore a hole he uses an instrument that works up and
down instead of around. - EXCHANGE.
Little drops of water, little grains of sand,
Make the mighty ocean and the pleasant land; but by
actual calculation it has been estimated that, though this be
true, it will require 6611 years to consume enough weiners in
the dining hall to make a string encircling the globe.
I know it sounds impossible, and if I hadn't seen it I
wouldn't have believed it either, but the other day I saw one
Ford inside another Ford an'i there was still room for a Duck
on the back seat. - BELL.
Something unusual has come over Mrs. Barbee. She
gives us tea- cakes every meal.
60
Mr. Sims: " What ails you, Ford?"
Ford: " My heart is aching." ( Akin.)
One of the workmen doing the finishing work in the boys"
dormitory went into the bathroom Saturday mornng. lJe
found Bruce Overton lying stretched on the floor of the
" tomb" with the shower turned on full force.
" What's the trouble," asked the workman, " are y0' 4
hurt ?"
" No, replied Bruce, " I'm waiting for the trough to fiJI SO
I can take a bath."
fight. So well did they fight that at the end of the first h
the score stood: Bryson 12, Normal O. alf
The Normal boys, ever noted for their gameness
. ' enter~
ed the second h. alf with renewed energy and determinat'IOn
The change whIch they mad. e was almost equal to that .
Pickett's clash! the two lines met. The groans of the wou ~ f
ed and dying could be heard far in the distance. Again n d-
agam. the capta. m, s cIear VO. Ice rang out, and the onslauagnh
was repeated. Nothing could resist that powerful blue an~
white line. The lust of battle gleamed from every man's
eye. When the war clouds at last rolled away the score
~ tood: Bryson 12, Normal 13. Stars, Bill Smith and Phillips.
THE NORMALITE 63
chorus, composed of sixteen, is now working faith&#173;several
numbers to be given at an early date. Also
e and mixed quartets are hard at work. With the
orts of these two special bodies, together with the
b, we are expecting great entertainment along the
here, let us sa'y fa ew words concern. mg our band
e all are so 1.11terest &#183; ed 111. We have at the present'
enty- five instruments and musicians that have joined
" thron. g' and we are expect11. 1g to be hI. ghly enter-speCIal"
OccaSI. Ons during the months to come.
orus thus far has gi. ven one chapel program. An-members
of the Glee Club consider themselves very
e in having such rare opportunities as are offered by
this year. In it they get a knowledge of the best
est class music as well as the training in voice, to
g of the pleasure derived from the work.
rollment for this year is the largest we. have ever
t seventy- five including both boys and girls, and
increasing love for music we are expecting to reach
ed mark by Christmas.
Monday and Thursday our Club meets for special
and here we spend many happy hours singing, un&#173;direction
of Miss Saunders, the strains we love so
THE NORMALITE
Normal Subdues S. P. u.
On Oct 27 the Blue and White eleven invaded the city of
Clarksville to struggle with the gridiron warriors ( f S. P. U.
Our boys entered the enemy's territory with no other pur&#173;pose
than that of bringing home a victory. This they did,
even though they suffered many penalties at the hands of a
seemingly hostile referee. Practically every time the Normal
lads would carry the ball to within striking distance of the
enemy's goal, they would be. penal. ized for fifteen or twenty
yards. Finally Bill Smith, not giving the referee a chance to
call a penalty , tore through S. P. U.' s line for a touchdown.
Smith kicked goal. Score: S. P. U. O. Normal 7. Every
man on the Normal team played an excellent brand of balL
Stars: Bill Smith and Bennett.
62
other program was rendered at the banquet given
gates of the Tennessee Medical Society.
THE CORRELATION OF MUSIC WITH OTHER S
JECTS IN THE CURRICULUM
65
Noble
THE NORMALITE
SONG BOOKS
Small Songs for Small Singers- Neidlinger.
Primary Melodies- Educational Music Course.
Songs of the Child- world- Gaynor.
: Mother Goose Set to Music- Elliott.
The Most Popular Mother Goose Songs- Hinds,
&amp; Eldridge. - E. MAY SAUNDERS.
f erception cards will make this phase of the first grade
o P .
work most attractive. , ' 11 b k .
The subjects of the second grade WI e ta en up In our
next issue.
Wanted- Andrew Jackson's recipe for beautiful white
complexion. If found, leave in Mr. Holmes office.
TYPE LESSON
I have it. R. O. B. B. stands for Royal Order of Bell Boys.
...~ i.:. _,
.~-;'- !
Ma. mie Jackson, Supervisor Primary Grades. . ~.~,
The Mother Goose rhyme " To Market" was used in the
primary department as a word drill, after it had been work&#173;ed
up in music reading and language.
Word cards were placed upon the board- which is the
market place. The cards are the " fat pigs." As a word is
called for some child skips to market and buys a " fat pig," by
recognizing the word called for and returns to his seat with
it while " To Market" is sung. He must be at home when
" Home again" is reached in the song.
The child's object is to see who has a certain number of
" fat pigs" when the game is over.
" My room- mate," said Ruth Brandon, " sent two dollars
in answer to an advertisement of a sure method of getting rid
of superfluous fat."
" And was the information what she wanted?" asked Mr.
Jared.
(' Well, she got a reply telling her to sell it to the soap
man."
64 THE NORMALITE
There is always a time and place in the school life of
child for music. As the children Imarch into the room,
them sing a good marching song or, play for them a march
the phonograph. By this means you will be etsablishing wi
in the child a feeling for rythm, resulting in a quiet orde
entrance. Before they take their seats they should sin
familiar song, in this way saving time as well as stimula
the memory. For at least ten songs should be memorized
the upper and twice that number by the lower grades dur
the year.
In the pri, mary grade when seat work is passed, or
the class is changing, they should sing or again listen to
phon~ graph and march to its rythm. The work in teach
numbers may be made lighter by the use of singing ga
songs, and' stories. For the number 3, use " Three Little
tens," a song found in " Songs and Singing Games" by Cr
ford; the number 6, " Six Little Birds" by Gaynor; the n
bel' ten, " Ten Little Indians" from " Singing Games," C
ford; a further list of songs as well as stories will be gi
later. In the writing lesson the oral stroke may be done
effectually if a song such as one of the following be
" Mulberry Bush," " Jolly is the Miller," " Swinging;"
downward stroke to the rythm of Airy, Fairy Snow Fla
Jack Frost; or the Pendulum.
Include in the list of memory verses those which
been set to music-" The Swing" by Stevenson; " Little S
man" music by Brahaes, " Cradle Song," " Sleep Ba
" Sleepy Gaynor;" or " Three Little Sisters" by Gaynor.
The Mother Goose songs if used in drill lessons by me
THE NORMALITE 67
( Answering numerous questions before ex-
Miss Little:
. Ah ' pears to have gone and married mahself to de
uss of It.
, h'"
hoIe worl . wa .
Excuse for Boys
I' " Why aren't more boys killed?"
F00 . h Id ' 1' . h h "
Sage.. " Because lady teac ers cou n t lve WIt out tern.
Mrs. Gillentine: " You were not here yesterday, Bates,
where were you.?" "
Bates: " At the cemetery.
Mrs. Gillentine: " Anybody dead?"
Bates: " Yes, all of them."
Mrs. Fertig in English XXI: " What kind of a noun is
kiss, Mr. Huffines?
Huffines: It's both common and proper and agrees with
me and you."
" Well," exclaimed Brother Coleman, that's enough to
try the patience of Job."
" What's the matter, dear?" asked his wife.
Last Sunday I preached from the text, " Be ye, therefore,
steadfast" he said, but the printer made it read " Be ye here
for breakfast."
Gentleman in town: " What are you doing in town now?
It's after five."
Normal Girl: " There now! I knew I had forgotten
something."
;;- riss Little ( lecturing to class in sewing:
The old- fashioned girl used to stay at home when she
had nothing to wear."
In No'Hurry
Frank Bass: " I h
IIIent Won't last." ave a presentment that our engage-
Grace D &#183; " Oh F
forever." . . , rank, don't say that; I hope it will last
THE =; ~ ~ MALITE
When Tom Brackin was a small
resident of the town espied him one
office.
" Good morning, little nian," said he. " What's your na
" Same as Dad's," was the quick reply.
" Of course, I know, little boy, but what is your
name?"
" Same as mine, sir."
Still he persisted: " I mean, what do they say when
call you to breakfast?"
" They don't never call me; I allus gets there first."
Biology XIII
Coach: " Bates, when a man has tuberculosis,
' Should he spit?"
Bates: " In the fire."
Sam had just , married. After three days of married
he returned to his job looking somewhat woe- begone.
" Sam," said his employer, " you look as if you had
in a battle."
" Yo' j es bet ah has, boss," replied Sam.
( ..... 11....
.... II~
~
E:
Ford and Miss Akin were walking to church Sunda
rather dilapidated Chevrolet passed them.
J " That sounds like a threshing machine," said Ford.
" I like Fords anyway," answered Miss Akin.
THE NORMALITE 69
NOTE:
Through an error Mr. Leo Ferrell's ad was left out of the
October issue of the NORMALITE.
IT PAYS TO ADVERTISE
The other day, the day we had a thirty minute campus
course after Sunday lunch, we were sitting under the shade
of one of the trees on the campus with our best girl. We had
strolled as far away as we dared and we thought we were
entirely alone for the little confidential talk we had on our
mind.
But just as we got comfortably settled we heard voices
on the other side of the dump of bushes raised in anger. The
first note warned us that it was a lover's quarrel and, though
we were not trying to be eavesdroppers, we didn't &#183; fee1 like
moving we were so comfortably seated. Then, too, we
thought we might be needed as mediator in case the thing got
too serious.
. " You old mean thing," Julia was saying, " I'll never be-lIeve
another thing you say."
" Now, honey, what in the world is the trouble with you?"
Bertram asked in hurt surprise.
" Didn't you tell me last week that we would meet down
town Saturday afternoon and go to a show?" asked Julia in a
tone of bl' h. ng sarcasm.
THE NORMALITE
ams) " A fool can ask questions that a wise man ca
swewr."
Emma Overby: " That's why we are all going to
Miss Jackson: " Johnnie, why are you always
foot of the class?
Johnnie: " It . doesn't make any difference, Mis
son, you teach the same thing at both ends."
Mrs. Barbee: " There are two mice in the pantry.
shall I get rid of them?"
Student: " Just shut the door and let them s
death."
In 1922 Ben Chrislman was walking with Kathleen
She stumbled slightly over a small stone.
" Did my little darling hurt her poor little foot,"
Ben.
Again they were walking in 1927, but as a two year
ried couple. Kathleen fell over a large boulder.
" Get up, you cow; can't you see where your are g
Ben demanded.
Alberta: " Do you know Humpy has asked me
times to---"
Margaret: " Oh! How thrilling! Tell me about it."
Alberta: " Of cours &#183; e I said ~ yes'. He asked me
with him on. the football picnic."
" Gladys Bond, what makes you lick stamps ?'~
Grace Daniels. " Don't you know it isn't sanitary?"
" I wasn't licking them," answered Gladys sadly.
just kissing them good- bye."
----
Webster Revised:
Mollycoddle- A cross between a sissy
darling. " d
Pussyfoot- A guy who sneaks up behind you, hI e
hind the sofa when you propose, or listens at your key
and then gets you in the worst place possible and spreads
glad news to the world.
68
THE NORMALITE 71
' th his story. He had hardly begun until she
nt on WI
be wre tent. ng to every word he said.
was IS h a charming listener Bertram grew eloquent as
With suc .
ntinued. .
he C" OYou see, I had J' ust bought that box of candy when. I re-d
I had to doll myself up a bit. You know, I told
meuwbDearde sent. me a good S. Ized check last . week. so I went
yo d to the Stones River Bank and depOSIted It. But, be-
~ roun I pulled out THE NORMALITE and looked to see
l. teve whed, their ad, before I went m. . When I saw that we d' 1d
If we'd a" That's where I do my bank'mg." Wh' 1le I was I00k- ! sa
l
h, ugh the ads I made a list of all those firms that sell 109 t ro
h &#183; I wanted and that had an ad in THE NORMALITE. I t lOgs
found Smith &amp; Fletcher; Butler, Hooper &amp; McCord; Gold-stein's;
Alsup Shoe Co.; E. L. Rogers &amp; Co.; W. T. Gerhardt;
Elrod's Bootery; The Dixie Co.; and Clayton &amp; Draper.
I made a B- line for the nearest place and the first thing
I told them was, " I saw your ad in THE NORMALITE." That
little password worked like a charm. I never received such
courteous treatment. Before I had finished I went in every
one of those places, and I had bought at least three dollars
worth from everyone. I spent eighty- four dollars first and
last and the funny part is I didn't intend to buy but about
eleven dollars worth, when I started, but everything they
showed me was so nice and so cheap I just couldn't help it.
But I didn't get nearly all I want so I've got to go back next
Saturday and spend a lot more.
And, you know, every place I went in there were from
one to ten Normal boys just as busy as could be buying stuff.
Before I left town I stopped in at the Star Barber Shop
an. d had a haircut, a shave, and a shine. While I was doing
thiS I got me a ticket from the Star Presing Shop and had
myoid suit cleaned and pressed. I had an old pair of shoes
along so I took them down to the Electric Shoe Shop and left
them to be repa. lred. n my waOy down I met up'WIth a bunch
of ormal fellows who took me into John De George's place
T
to
get some ice cream and drinks. I was just coming out of
utt's G S .
f rocery tore WIth my pockets full of stuff I'd bought
Or Sund . h
ay nIg t supper when I met a whole gang of fellows
THE NORMALITE
" To be sure I did, little girl," Bertram answe d
why I didn't come I. S one t h'mg I wanted to tell you reb'
thI. S occaSI. On". a 0
" Well, you needn't tell me," pouted Julia, " I won't b
it. . Somebody told me you were in Read &amp; Riggs' ~
whole bunch of fellows.' , \ V
" Sure I was," he answered, " we went in there to get
ice crea, m, cold drinks, cigarettes, tobacco, etc. You see
advertise in THE NORMALITE. But listen, honey, ha
you been curious to know what I got camouflaged in this
wrinkled newspaper? .
" N0, I haven't and I won't be," Julia snapped back.
Bertram grinned and was not the least bit daunted, as
began to unwrap a rectangular shaped parcel. JUlia
tended that she wasn't looking, but peeping out of the cor
of here eye, she saw the name " Whitman."
" Oh, Bertram, I'm sorry I said what I did."
" That's all right, little one. I got this there , too, so 1
eat it."
They were silent for a moment or two when we sta
our little confidential talk that we had on our mind.
Evidently, Julia had eaten all she cared for by that ti
so she began again.
" Surely it didn't take all afternoon to do that little spe
ing." .
" No it didn't, I was just going to tell you the remamde
" Yo, u needn't do it, for I don't want to hear . It," she
swered. ' f
" That settles it then. I'll tell you," said Bertram, ' or
woman always wants what she says she doesn't."
. " Tain't so" Julia fired back.
, .' " No " I know it is " answered Bertram m a stern VOIce.
young lady, you ' just be quiet. I'm the man of : his hou
that is this house that's going to be. So you had Just as VI
begin learning to be obedient."
. " All right," answered Julia sulkily, " have your way,
I'll not listen to a word." d
She turned her head half aside, but Bertram seeme
know that she was going to listen to what he had to say
70
73 THE NORMALITE
I s grinned and pulled out slips that they had just like
fel ow
them. . h d
Some of he fellows III t e crow wanted to stop at Lee A.
Lively's Studio to have their pictures taken so we decided
that it was time to start out to the Normal to get there in
. e for supper, for you know we never pass the Boulevard
~: re, now being ~ perated b~ Lewis Brinkley, without stop-ping
in and spendlllg somethlllg. .
But before we left town we stopped III at the Old Reli&#173;able
Taxi Service to see Eph Hoover about hiring some cars
to take a trip next Saturday.
You see, Julia, our motto is " Normal students backing
our advertisers."
During all of Bertram's story Julia had sat an interested
listener.
Her pouting face was now wreathed with smiles.
" You're the good sport, Bertram. And you were right
in not meeting me to go to the show, for instead you showed
the right spirit of a good NORMALITE.
" Oh, you dear thing," Bertram said, " I knew you would
understand. I could just take you in my ar-," But just as he
was making a suspicious looking move Mrs. Rutledge pressed
th~ button and . the bell began to ring. With a look of disap&#173;pOllltment
on hIS face Bertram assisted Julia to rise and they
hastened away to the dormitory.
Though we hadn't been able to say a word to our girl
about the thing we had so much on our mind we were not so
very f ' .
. sorry, or we were glad to learn that our motto was be-
:~: racticed by the students, I mean the one which says
TRADE WITH THEM AS TRADES WITH US." ,
Nell T.: " I want to look at some mirrors."
Clerk' " H d . . an mIrrors ?"
Nell &#183; " N
. 0, some that I can see my face in."
I t is said th t E B '
, a mma ecton s heart is turning to Stone.
Gladys: " Wh k' . .
abeth? at l11d of candy IS that you're eatlllg, Eliz-
Elizabeth' " P . unchboard."
THE NORMALITE
on their way to the City Restaurant to get some sandwie
and coffee so I went along. One of the fellows in the ero
wanted a rug for his room so we all went down to MeKni
&amp; Partee's store and helped him buy it.
Then I went over to the Stickney Drug Co. to get
some stationery and magazines. I happened to remetn
that Dad had asked - m. e where he could buy wholesale groe
ies right, so I went in A. L. Smith Drug Store and pho
him to be sure and buy from Henry King &amp; Co. While I
in there a couple of fellows from the Normal came in and l'
never saw fellows buy like we did, everything from sha
cream to Mary Garden.
I thought I was about ready to leave town but' the
lows I was with all started down to the Sanitary Cafe to
a lot of stuff to bring back to fill up on over the week- e
Then we needed more groceries so part of the crowd w
to Horton's Grocery and the other's went over to W. E. C
trell's. Then there were a couple of fellows wanted s
paint . and varnish for the furniture they are making in
l\ tlanual Arts Departme'nt so I started over to L. H. Wehr
with them. I stopped on the way at C. H. Byrn &amp; Son's
got me a pocket knife and some razor blades. One of the.&#163;
lows got him a new razor.
Three or four fellows from the Normal in their cars ca
along and told us we could ride out after they had been do
to Cason's Garage to get some repairing done.
Then here came along another bunch going down to
len's Service Station for gas, oil, etc.
While we were standing there a bunch of Normal &#8226;
came pouring out of the Art China Shop, The Bonnet Sh
and Misses E. &amp; M. Earthman's Millinery Store. Of eoU
we followed them around the street and a lot of them ' W
in C. B. Leatherman's, Elrod Bros. and Tatum &amp; Shacklet
You never saw girls loaded down with bundles and packa
as they were. That crowd must have spent a thousand d
lars that day.
I noticed everyone of them had a little slip of ~ a~ er ~
asked the, m what that was. One girl said, ' Why thiS IS ~ t
of people that . advertise in THE NORMALITE.' Some 0
72
4 .
per cent. Paid on Savings Account.
MURFREESBORO BANK&amp; TRUST CO.
TOTAL RESOURCES OVER $' ,800,000.00
SERVICE,
SODAS
Murfreesboro Bargain.
House
Everything for Men &#183; .
Sam Licker
T. B. Carlton
L. H. WEHRLE
Paint, Glass and Var...
nishes
Auto Painting ASpe&#173;cialty.
FORMERLY JACK'S
LUNCHES
CIGARS
BROWN BROS.
ICE CREAM CO.
That's what you get when you
trade with
Whitman, Norris &amp; Hollinsworth Candies
READ &amp; RIGGS
PRICE AND
QUALITY
Ice Cream, Sherbets, Ices, Sand&#173;wiches,
etc.
&#8226; " Brown Ice Crea. m Pies"
Get these fr. om the Y. W. C. A.
at Normal
Telephone Us Your Orders For
Ice Cream
Free Delivery to the Normal
Everything you buy from us is
~ o) d ~ ith the guarantee of sat&#173;Isfaction
, or your money ba~ k.
" 100% for M. T. N."
Brown Bros. Ice Cream Co.
PHONE 444
PHONES 8 AND 68
OPPOSITE POST OFFICE
MURFREESBORO, TENNESSEE
AT
BUTLER, HOOPER &amp; McCORD, Inc.
" The Good Clothes Store"
WEST SIDE SQUARE
HIGH CLASS CLOTHES, HATS AND
FURNISHINGS
c. 1- 1. BYRN &amp; SON
Authorized Buick Sales And Service
Goodyear And Keny~ Springfield Tires
COMPETENT MECHANICS
Mr. Henry Truett Representl
North Side Public Square
PHONE 240
Quality Furniture
Telephone 361
McKNIGHT AND
PARTEE
ART CHINA SHOP
Hand Painted China, Parch&#173;ment
Shade., Electrolier., Nov&#173;elties.
Card. for all Occa. ion&#8226;&#8226;
Order. Filled Promptly
MRS. D. E. LOGAN
MISS FANNIE NICHOL
ELECTRIC SHOE
SHOP
Your Patronage
Solicited
J ,9 South Church St.
E. L. ROGERS &amp; COMPANY
Gents' Outfitters, Clothing and Shoes
SAMPLE SHOES A SPECIALTY
Let Ua Make You a Suit to Your Individual Meaaure.
We Guarantee Satisfaction.
w. T. GERHARDT
Merchant Tailor
Phone 59
Cleaning Pressing
Altering
SANITARY CAFE
FOR LADIES AND
GENTS
OPEN DAY AND NIGHT
1&gt;_ 0 () 0 () 0 ()
I- ICater to the
t of the Normal
I B d Girls ' 0 oys an
J,. COMPLETE LINES OF
IWearing Apparel . I and Accessorzes
i EXCLUSIVE AGENTS OF iSpaulding Sporting i Goods and i Bradley Sweaters
. o0 0 000
MURFR ESBORO ~ TENNE. SEE
Cumbo Phone 147 Home Phone 13
FERRELL
PHOTOGRAPHER
" You Can Find It There"
COOK'S SERVICE STATION
AUBREY COOK, Mgr.
We Make Sick People Well At Little Cost
TELEPH'ONE 179
High Grade Work At Very Reasonable Prices. --
I KERR'S DRUG STORE
SPECIAL PRICES TO NORMAL STUDENTS
GAS, OIL, TIRES AND TUBES
FREE ROAD SERVICE
TELEPHONE 37 303 WEST COLLEGE ST.
FIRESTONE TIRES.
LEO
azl:
East Side Square. Phone 1
JOHN DeGEORGE
WHAT WE WANT
Hot Chili in Winter Time
Ice Cream in Summer Time
Anything good to eat and drink
ALL THE TIME.
SMART FOOTWEAR
THEQIXIJ C0c
EVERYTHING TO WEAR FOR THE
ENTIRE FAMILY
Opposite P. o.
Stones River Bank
&amp; Trust Co.
Murfreesboro, Tenn.
4 % Paid on Savings
SAVE
For the glorious privilege of
being independent
ELROD'S BOOTER
CASON'S GARAGE
STUDEBAKER CARS REO CARS
All Kinds of Repairing And
Shop Work
AT ALL HOURS
Meals and Lunches
SOUTH SIDE OF SQUARE
IN BUSINESS FOR
. PHONE 77
LEADERS IN
DRY GOODS AND READY- TO- WEAR
YOUR HEALTH
TATUM &amp; SHACKLETT
DEALERS IN
Groceries, Fruits And
Vegetables
Teleph- one 96. 103 Public Square
w. E. CANTRELL &amp; CO. CITY RESTAURANT
Complete Line of School Supplies
Parker Fountain Pens
Ever Sharp Pencils
Magazines and Novels
Tennessee Stickney Drug Company
Walk Across the Square
Save the Differeace.
W. Side Square. Phone 1M
LEE A. LIVnYSTUDIO
746 East Main Street
Murfreesboro, Tenn.
Staple and Fancy
Groceries
Feed and Seed
PHONES 260 AND 88
The Favorite With
Up- To- Date Young
Men.
Murfreesboro
STAR BARBER snop STAR PRESSING S
Expert Pressing
And Cleaning
ALLEN BROS., Proprietors
Phone 243
SPECIAL PRICES TO NORMAL STUDENT
norton Grocery . Company CLAYTON &amp;
DRAPER
SHOES
GROCERIES
STORE OF FRIENDLY SERVICE
H, M. TUTT, Proprietor.
FREE DELIVERY
Join the Normal Class at the Methodist Sunday School!!
Allen Service Station
Agents for
FISK RED TOP TIRES
Automobile Accessories, Oils and Gas
TIRE SERVICE
Free Air And Free Water
PROMPTNESS
PHONE 811 W. MAIN ST.
MURFREESBORO, TENN.
HENRY KING &amp; COMPANY
WHOLESALE GROCERS
Murfreesboro- McMinnville- Tullahoma
OPPOSITE FIRE HALL
BONNET SHOP I
If You Need A
NEW BONNET
WE DO HEMSTITCHING
. ALSUP SHOE
COMPANY
" Where only the Best
is goo</dc:description>
<dc:subject>College publications; Middle Tennessee State Normal School;</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:type>text; application/pdf</dc:type>
<dc:format>Periodical;</dc:format>
<dc:format>73 p.; 9.5 x 6.0 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright may or may not belong to MTSU; Reproduced with permission of the Albert Gore Research Center, MTSU</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>May be used freely by individuals for research, teaching, and personal use under the fair use provisions of the Copyright Act; Credit: Property of the Albert Gore Research Center, Middle Tennessee State University, Murfreesboro, TN 37132; For other uses contact The Albert Gore Research Center, P.O. Box 193, MTSU, Murfreesboro TN 37132</dc:rights>
<dc:relation>University Collections, MTSU Miscellaneous, Middle Tennessee Normal School, 1911-1925</dc:relation>
<dc:publisher>Albert Gore Research Center, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University ;</dc:publisher>
<dc:description>Folder 3</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/mtsu1/id/1405</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>