<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Civics program : Campus School</dc:title>
<dc:date>1952</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Middle Tennessee State College Campus School civics program, "American Way of Life," during the 1952 presidential election</dc:description>
<dc:description>The School has had many names--Demonstration School, Training School, and Campus School. In 1985, the name officially became Homer Pittard Campus School in honor of Homer Pittard, a Rutherford County educator who had served as principal at McFadden School and Central High School and as Director of University Affairs at MTSU. The original purpose of the Campus School was to serve as a teaching laboratory for aspiring teachers. Prospective teachers meet children in real situations in an effort to give the children and the college students the best and latest in content and procedure. Campus School endeavors to make its classrooms, its various activities, and its daily routine as real-world as possible.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Civics; Political science; Students; Laboratory schools; Middle Tennessee State College</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Still image;</dc:type>
<dc:type>image/jpeg</dc:type>
<dc:format>Photograph;</dc:format>
<dc:format>8 x 10 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright may or may not belong to MTSU; Reproduced with permission of the Albert Gore Research Center, MTSU</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>May be used freely by individuals for research, teaching, and personal use under the fair use provisions of the Copyright Act; Credit: Property of the Albert Gore Research Center, Middle Tennessee State University, Murfreesboro, TN 37132; For other uses contact The Albert Gore Research Center, P.O. Box 193, MTSU, Murfreesboro TN 37132</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Albert Gore Research Center, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>009</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/mtsu1/id/1200</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>