<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Middle Tennessee Normal Signal, 1912</dc:title>
<dc:title>The Signal</dc:title>
<dc:source>Middle Tennessee Normal School</dc:source>
<dc:date>1912-12</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1910-1919</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>This is the first issue of the Middle Tennessee Normal Signal, also called the Signal</dc:description>
<dc:description>December, 1911
Voluine 1. Number 1
&#183; " ibble mennessee
Normal ~ ignal
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
VOL. I MURFREESBORO, TENNEESSEE
TABLE OF CONTENTS
NO. 1
PAGE
The Gospel of Thomas Carlyle- Pauline Ridley___________ 2
ThePedagogue ------ 4 ~
Through Na: r: row Passes to the Heights- Vema Sheffield 5
The Modem Minotaur- Lucy Alexander 9
Student Christian Work:
Y. M. C. A.- W. A. Haynes 14
Y. W. C. A.- Ada Sorrells 15
Sylvia's Wedding- Anna Lee Fox 16
The Meaning of the Grail- Bess Conger 13
Poem- Chemistry 21
The Conspiracy of Aaron Burr- Q. M. ,.. 22
Madame Bovine's Gym. Stunt- Annie Harris 25
Editorial 29
Athletics- The Gridiron- A. B. Rhodes 32
Society in M. T. N. 34
Poem- All Sorts and Conditions of Men ... 36
Societies ~ 39
Wise and Otherwise__ .. 44
{
j,
2 THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
THE GOSPEL OF THOMAS CARLYLE
PAULINE RTDLEY.
N an' age of conventionality and scientific self&#173;satisfaction,
Carlyle and his doctrine rise above_~. &#183; '"
the level of the creeds of his day like some vast.? &#173;mount~
in peak, up the'sides of which small growths
, may creep, but in the rare atmosphere of the summit of which
it is useless for them to aspire to live.
To Carlyle, the Englishmen of his day seemed to be the
most blind, phlegmatic, matter of fact of many generations
of phlegmatic Englishmen, and he wishes to arouse them from
their self- satisfied lethargy. to an appreciation of the wonders
and possibilities' of the universe. He believes it the duty and
privilege of the journalist and literary man- whose function,
rightly understood, he places alongside that of'the priest- to
affect this awakening.
Nowhere is the desire to arouse better seen than in his
attitude toward' science. He scoffed at the scientist who,
thinks to catalogue nature and by scientific means account
for each phenomenon. N~ aur says Carlyle, is the " Garment
of God," and as such reflect he different phases of the mind
and the heart of God. e should regaro its simplest and
most often repeated phenomena with wonder and reverence..
, . All things that we see, Car, 1yle tells us, are the clotheS
of the spirit, symbols of the idea which is real. All things
are constant- ly changing, and much of the trouble and hypoc&#173;risy
of the world is caused by the attempt to preserve institu&#173;tions,
or the SYmbols of things long after the spirit is dead- has
been outgrown and cast aside. Viewed according to the
standards of his day, this doctrine of change was one of the
, most revolutionary which Carlyle preached.
Politically, Carlyle was a radical and he prophesied many
reform movements which he afterwards lived to see. His
doctrine of " Hero Worship" was not compatible with democ&#173;racy,
but he thought that it was only through democracy that
we can advance to something better, and, in so far as it is a
growth towards something higher, he considers it good.
In the chapter on the " Dandiacal Body" Carlyle seems
to foresee even the sociological crisis of today when Labor and
Capital clash.
Carlyle was in accord with the other leading spirits of his
day in attempting to make humanitarianism more a matter
of reason than of sentiment, in trying to render practical man's
aid to man.
The three phases through which every thoughtful life
must pass, Carlyle illustrates in the life of Tuefelsdrockh, the
hero of " Sartor Resartus." The first phase might be called
birth. Here it is that through his love and loss Tuefelsdrockh
in his despair first learns that he has a soul, even as in the
" Marble Faun" the hero first learns through sin that he has
a soul. " Spiritual music," says Carlyle, " can spring only
from discords in harmony; but for Evil there were no Good, as
victory is only possible by battle."
The second phase is defiance, a challenge to fate to do
its worst. This is temporary because the soul is in darkness
even though it has made a step upward , tow? fd resurrection,
which is the last phase. In this third phase the soul is saved
by awakening to interest in others and learning that, " It is
only with Renunciation that Life, properly speaking, can be
said to begin." " He that findeth his life shall lose it and he
that loseth his life for my sake shall find it."
Carlyle had two distinct styles, the one distinguished by
simplicity and dignity, and the other very much like a volcano
in eruption. Both these styles are strong and forceful. Of
the first, his night piece, which is .. considered &#183; one of the two
most beautiful in English, is a good example. It is found in
chapter three, " Reminiscences." , ' I
. - 1ft the second style where he coins words, transposes, and
takes what other liberties he will- indeed seems to toss up the
words and let them fall anywhere- the c! itics say he assumes
to gain, more quickly, the attention of slow- going British
readers. We had rather differ with critics and say it is spon&#173;taneous,
that, like Browning's rugged style, it is the result
of a divine carelessness of construction and is the most natural
expression of the great earnestness which so burdens the
language that each sentence carries the weight of three. Car&#173;lyle
seems to be to prose what Browning is to poetry.
It seems to me that in " Heroes and Hero Worship" with
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL 3
4 THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
its teaching of sincerity and clear seeing, Carlyle forever
, allies himself with the idealists. Idealists for practical pur&#173;poses
may be divided into two classes- those who present to
us beautiful pictures, about which we like to dream and fondly
fancy we shall resemble when God has created a new heaven
and a new earth, passive &#183; idealists, such as Tennyson and
Ruskin; and those who present ideals so real, so forceful that
we would be " up and doing" here and now. They convince
us that we are kings in very truth if we would arise and claim
ouI birthrights- be the masters of our destinies, the captains
of our fates. They teach us that, " The end of man is an
Action and not a Thought." Such idealists are Carlyle and
. Browning, and if all the creeds of all the churches and all the
Bibles of the land should suddenly be destroyed, man might
still enter safely the " Narrow Way" by living according to
the Gospel ' of Thomas Carlyle.
THE PEDAGOGUE
~~ NY good school teacher is a gentleman or a lady
which ever the case may be, and" worthy to be
treated as such. Old Fogy is always ready to
take off his hat to them; used to take off his coat
too, but that was always by special request. In all the recollec-tions
of the past, none are brighter than of the teachers to
whom Fogy gave trumped- up excuses for not knowing his
lessons.
The first to whom I went, when wishing to punish me,
did nothing more than rap me over the head with a pencil or
pull my mane a little; but as I grew older and did not do
better, the manner of punishment varied from the dunce cap
to the shingle. I would take either the dunce cap or the
shingle tho' in preference to the switch. The dunce cap didn't
really hurt you- just " touched up" your feelings a bit, but
when a switch came " a larruping" around your legs, there
. was " sumpin doin," and you can bet your life that the teachers
in my days were good judges of timber- the way they selected
tough switches was a caution. Of all three modes of punish&#173;ment,
I preferred the shingle. Must have been because it
THE: M. T. ~ &#183; N. SIGNAL
!: Spreads the pain . over, a larger surface reducing it to a minimum
} per unit area, and , then : too it makes , a saund . so much . out of
} proportion](;) th. ehuri. t that you hav. e the fun , of thinking . you
Jooled the teacher.
Teachers 1have changed their i~ ctics &#183; now . and &amp;&gt; n't tdo so
: much lickitlg. Some one has ~ said,," lf ' y. DU can't , reach ', em
thru their pride, then r. each " em Jhru ! heir'hide'~ pFettygood
. doctrine , in ~ myopini0n. . They used to take thehicle extreme
': but now . th~ yreso. rt . to p'ride~ no wonder tho Jhe pride ~ f
~ some pupils now~ a~ da: Ys is.&amp; 0 con. spicuo, us - that it needs cur&#173;.
tailing.
On ~ our1eachers rests fhe '~ perity , of the Urilled . States
: as a nation. This . does not ,: seem io he regardeq, however, if
, we look . at the isalaries;. teachers , are the most pOG&gt; rly paid
Jprofessional people in . the , V\ lorlq, still th~ . have t~ keep' up
.: appea( anc. e~, even. if . they Jio hav. e 10 .. make a porter~ house&#173;:
steak appearanceznD. faSJi&gt; up- bone salary.
Here~ to h0ping , that the. s. e pillars . of ~: our ~ vernment ~ may
lhave hetter and . ea~ y times llwalling them. &#183; ~ FO. GY. P. HOOL.
' THROVGlI ~ NARROW PASSES 1: 0 THE HElGBTS
l'ERNA &#183; : SHEFFiEL1).
-,~~~ ~,
~~~~ STORYtS pages ~ are replete ~ viith examples ' oImen
' MTho qy;' succe. ssfulJ; y oombating life's battles gained
t ~ , fer themselves fame and hon~ r am~~ g their fellow-i
~ men. WJlenwe read the bIographies of S( i) me of
-~ the &#183; vrorld'.. s best .. son!:), . there instinctively arises within our
&#183; : hearts&lt; ClPJ:. ofnlUlQ . revcerence for tho. si \ who hav_ e proved them&#173;~
selves . thegreatesLQLthe he1\ oes, py . the~ mannerin which they
: have overcome . obstacles in their paths 1.0 _ success.
Ther. e is . llQthmg: Im&gt; re natural for . an, yY0ung . person who
. desires . to do something ;- and to be s. omething in . th~ s world
. than to picture . tID himself ihevictories . and triumphs that
'; await him '~ Qn . the world's bn&gt;... ao field f) I battle~" Some one
jhas said that the very . fact that Jife is represented to him as
~ an aggre_ s. siv. e . conflict, . slu&gt; uld . b. esufficient to convinc. e him
6 THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
that to gain the victories and triumphs of which he dreans,
he must either march in the van of those who are fighting its
battles, or beat time among the indiscriminate rabble of the
advancing host.
There is but one way of obtaining. greatness and that is
through labor. Was it not hard labor and perseverence that
enabled Julius Caesar, Napoleon Bonaparte, Washington, and
many others to reach the height of fame and honor? Itwas
Abrah~ m Lincoln, born in a little floorless, log cabin, without
a chance to go to school, without' teacher or books- with
barely the necessities of life- who won the love and confidence
of the people through his practical wisdom while he was
president during the Civil War. If you would know the
secret of his success, look at the poor, lank, awkward boy- the
" Rail- splitter"- faithfully cutting trees on the little farm
during the day, and pouring over his Arithmetic and Grammar
in the evenIng by the dim light of the pine- torch.
He rose from an humble cabin home to the White House
only &#183; by work and perseverence, having endured many hard&#173;ships
and having overcome well nigh insurmoumtable difficul&#173;ties,
leaving a name and a record that is loved and cherished
by every true American.
In another log cabin in the backwoods of Ohio, a poor
widow, with an eighteen months old baby is left, wondering
if she will be able to keep starvation from her door. Her
little son grew and in a few years we find him chopping wood
and tilling the few acres of land that he has cleared in order
that he may pelp his mother. Every moment that he was
not at work in the field he spent reading borrowed books, for
he had not the means with which to buy them. When he was
sixteen years old he applied for a position to drive mules on
a canal tow- path. Not long after, , he went to an academy,
paYing his way by ringing the bells and sweeping the floors,
and by doing extra chores on Saturdays and at. night. He
then went to Williams College where in two years ~ graduated
with honors. He reached the State Senate at the age of
twenty- six, and Congress at thirty- three. Twenty- seven years
from the time that he applied for a chance to ring the bells &#173;and
sweep the floors at Hiram College, James A. Garfield
became President of the United States.
Today, our hearts grow still, and we tread softly, as
gently wafted o'er the waves by the evening breeze, there
comes to us a solemn remembrance of the recent great sea
disaster. The waves of woe, in which the Titanic steamer
was engulfed, are still at high tide within our hearts; for who
has been untouched by the passing of that heroic and knightly
soul- that one who bore without reproach the name of gentle&#173;man-
Major Archibald Butt.
When Major Butt was in Louisville last autumn as escort
to the President on that exhausting Western tour, whose
harmful effects on his health gave the impulse to the Major's
fatal " rest- cure" voyage, the " President played the second
fiddle," and " One Archie," as the Washingtonians called him,
was the one who received most attention.
More than a score of years ago, the Major was a tenderfoot
newspaper reporter in Louisville- only a poor lad, dependent
upon his daily earnings for a living. But with a dauntless
courage and a heart that knew no such word as fail, in spite
of poverty and other difficulties, he made himself greater than
a President- the guide philosopher of a pair of Presidents, and
a hero that a whole nation mourns.
Such examples are worth more to the young people of
Arne' a, today, than all the we~ lth of the Astors, Vanderbilts,
and Goulds.
The expression of the Ancient scho! ar, that " The gods
lay a price upon every true and noble pleasure," is but repeated
by the later poet who said,
" Heights by great men reached and kept,
Were not attained by sudden flight,
But they, while their companions slept,
Were toiling upward in the night."
There is no wealth, there is no greatness, there is nothing
in this world that gives us true joy except that which is made
by work or thought. The men most admired by us are those
who have put forth all their energy to ~,. ach the goal set before
them. Alexander Hamilton said th~. " Genius is the fruit
of labor and thought." When Demosthenes was asked what
was the first part of an orator, what the second, and what the
third, he answered, " Action, action, action!"
" Adversity in early life often lays the foundation for
future . prosperity." It takes away from the hearts of the
THE M. T. N.' SIGNAL 7
/
.!
I'
8 THE- M. T. N. SIGNAL
y'OUllg the pleasing but vain imaginations and sh~ ws to tbm
that to reach success they - must travel the road that calls fQr
ener: gy and - action to surmc&gt; Unt its difficulties..
, ' The: e - is some~ ng in the - fixe~ purpose of an~ o~ e t? rise
aoovemlsfortunes.. &#183; I. t . has been &#183; saId that, ~', OPPOSlt1( i) ll IS the
whetstone , oy '&lt; which .'&lt; 1 high: ly tempered natare is p01ished and
sharpened." History ; gives hundreds . of. examples ( i) f men who
haveseizeca , opportunIties to bring about results that were
tho: ught -; to ~ be impossible by those who had less determina&#173;~
i0n. True, there has been but @ ne Napoleon, but the Alps
that ' 0PPOS~ the y; oung people of America, today, are not sa
high nor ' so dangeJ! ous as the ' summits crossed by the Corsican_
Success is not measure&amp; so much by what a man actually
accomplishes as by the &#183; OPIlosition he h~ met and the courage
: wi1' ll which ~ he has kept up the ~$ tmggle. " It was by defeat
that Alexander learned the art ! Qfwar." We should not wait
for . great opportunities but &lt; seize ' small occasions : and make
tbem great. Many , men have reached the topmost round
on the ladder of fame . by improving the few : and seemingly
. insignificant opportunities that came , their way:. Our greatest
&#183; men ; and women have not as: a rule come from palaces with
' brewnstone fronts, they have not lived : a life of e. ase and
luxury; their palace. s have been cabins, their abundance has
&#183; : consisted of trials, ~ uffering ; and toil. But " In the blackest
soil grows &#183; the fairest flower, ; and the loftiest ; and strongest
$ pring heavenward among the rocks."
Rightly has it been said that the first literary efforts of
men's lives have cost them years of careful study; the finest,
: most delicious fruit that we enjoy has cost years of care,
, patience and ., culture; hoarde is the result of years of self
, denial- in fact, everything worth having cost some effort t@
- obtain it. Penn said, " No pain, no palm; n~ thor~, no throne;
' no . gall, no glory; no cr(} Ss, n() cr@ wu."
The determination that was in' the boo@ m ~ f NapOle() ll
- when he said that if he ~ ttempted ta make. an " adVaBce int@
Jtaly, there wt&gt; uld bellO Alps to check his pn~ gress" is what
'. should be found in the heart of every young man or womaa
who intends to make the most of his (}) r her@. f) p@ rt1iUlities jIl
life. Encouraged by the thought that after the cross comes
the . crown; after the toils and struggles come the day of recom..
- pense; . after the headache. s and heartaches &#183; of the searches for
THE MODERN MINOTAUR
~ sdom, comes the priceless pleasure of its~ posses;; ion and' the
love and respect- of his fellowmen; everyone shoJlld; be stimu&#173;lated
to a higher ambit40n than that. of him; whQ; WQuld, if he
could, reach the height without. a struggle.
We have not &#183; wings'~ we cannot soar-;
But &#183; we have felt t. o scale and climb"
By slow degrees; by more and more,
The cloudy summit of our tim~.
THE M. T. N.. SIGNAL 9
Lucy ALEXANDER. P'
/ 11~ 1\.- UA ,
the ancient days of Greece ' when ' its history
consisted mostly of legends, there lived on the
island of Crete the powerful king, ~ Minos. Here
in the : labyr: inth of Daedulus the king ' ihad caged
: a horrible monster known as the MinQtau(, whose head was
that rof a man and body that of a &#183; horse. Since Jh. e Grecians
' had once'offended this king, he demandetl that they send each
year fourteen of their most promising youths to be fed to the
, Minotaur. Each year - the ' Ship , qf Death, ' riggetl with sable
( sails) set forth on its fatal mission to this island, bearing aboard
, the despairing' victims whose . farewell iSobs. mingled with the
groans' of ' fathers and mothers maddened by their loss and
frantic with grief. ". '
Only a legend, yet how terrible! To : sap a nation's life
~ io. glut a demon! ' fo s~ a city yielding: up its youth;- fourteen
eac~ yea. r--- a=: sacrificej, to Greed. How, barbarous the age in
, which" sueD astate could exist! But in , our., own land there is
another monster more horrible, than Grecians ever knew, not
a creature- of fancy but a'demon of, fact. His tribute must
be paid througnout" the year,--- each day,.~ each night. Every
State nas' felt' his&lt;: ra~ ges. His maw is:: ever enlarged with
continuous gorging.. Tbis monster, ' is. CHILD LABOR, and the
victims of his greed, are little: children.
The sacrifice of the Grecian youth to the Minotaur was
,. a penalty imposed upon them: by: aJev~ pgeful king; the sacrifice
10 THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
of American children to this Modem Minotaur is the penalty
imposed upon them by heartless corporations with only dollar
marks for a soul. America boasts of a democracy founded
of the people, by the people, for the people; a democracy
offering equal opportunity and protection to every individual;
a democracy admitting no social distinction save that which
is differentiated between virtue and vice. And yet, is not
democracy weakening and really on trial, both in political
affairs and social intercourse? In politics the will of the
people has been so persistently frustrated that every assertion
of the people's sovereign will has been hailed as a great triumph.
In social life the extremes of wealth and poverty have grown
wider and wider, until the claim of equality seems to be a
vjsionary dream when contrasted with the solid facts of life
about us. .
Why a democracy with these two extremes in society- its
class of millionaires on one side with few children, surrounded
by all possible luxury and wealth, while, on the other side, the
poor wage- earner with countless numbers of children, who are
themselves forced to work for their maintenance in factories,
mines and other hideous holes, which sap their bodies of
vitality and their souls of visio~? Again, I ask, why this
difference? Are we asa nation so money- mad that we are
willing for the boys and girls, who are to become the future
fathers and mothers, to be sacrificed to the God of Greed; to
be slowly but surely starved, both mentally, physically and
morally, in order that iron- hearted commercialism may amass
its paltry sheckles?
Vast sums of money are expended annually upon our
army and navy for the alleged protection of life. Then why
not spend at least one-!~ th as much upon the army of Ameri&#173;can
children, in the w, ay of schools anf1~ sanitary surroundings,
thereby banishing ignorance, poverty and crime, from which
more than seventy thousand perish each year in the Southern
and Eastern States alone?
A few years ago, two citizens left the land of their birth
to seek their fortune in foreign lands. They took services
with the revolutionists, were captured, and shot. Our Gov&#173;ernment
did not hesitate or delay; there was no splitting of
hairs nor endless debates as to the cost of rendering aid.
. Warships were hurried across the seas, marines were landed,
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL 11
the United States Government was behind them to give
tion to those who, living in foreign countries, yet claimed
called for the protecting folds of the Stars and Stripes.
ous of her citizens abroad, why so neglectful of her children
home? Are not the lives of eight thousand babies, which
. h each year in New York alone from causes preventable,
valuable as the lives of two adventurers who seek their ease
and fortune in foreign climes? The American eagle is a noble
bird, but the American children would like to view it at closer
range. Why send it so far away, when it might be protecting
many lives at home.
Witness a cavern where this Modem Minotaur forces
tribute. Visit our country's mines, where you will find four
times as many breaker boys under fourteen years of age, as
there are stars seen with the naked eye. What is a breaker
boy? A boy who sits in the bowels of the earth from early
mom till late at night. A boy infolded with such clouds of
du t, clogging his lungs, that the light from the small lamp
hung upon bis cap scarcely reaches to the slate and coal which
ru hes by his feet. He strains to see this slate, which he
mu t pick from tbe whirling mass, and when a piece. more
jagged tban the rest gashes his gloveless bands, the coal that
ru hes on is smeared with human blood. Suppose he stops
to rest? There is no rest. That he may not forget, sometimes
a mine " boss" stands near with a threatening whip, to keep
this small machine of flesh and blood from slackening his
speed. How vividly is his physical, as well as moral, condition
portrayed in the heart- words of Tennyson:
" . . . . . . But what am I?
1 infant crying in the night,
An infant crying for the light,
And with no language but a cry."
Witness the 1,500 little boys of ten years and under in
the glass factories, rushing out at two and three o'clock on
cold winter mornings in order to be on time, pale- faced girls
tying flues to willow plumes in rooms dinl1y lighted and poorly
ventilated. Travel on southward to our cotton factories and
hosiery mills. View the havoc wrought here. Mere infants
rushing from loom to loom in search of broken threads, amid
a Niagara roar of machinery and a storm of lint in their faces.
, -
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL 12
Not merelyr tens and scores ; and hundreds, but tho~ saIl( is
these little ones go toddling to these mills, which suck the ~
marrow: f~ om their bones. It is- no wonder that in Chattan
a few: '. m&lt;!&gt;- nths ago these~ &#183; factory - children entered in upon
suicide' compact and two of their number escaped this Ii .
hell by swallowing laudanum,. - l
" In addition': to effective , child- labor laws, we need
pulsory" education.. ( fake conditions ' in our own little to
of Murfreesboro. : Do you find the children of the poor distri
any.; less haggard and . pale, &#183; with bodies any less dwarfed, t
those of the pencil factory district? No, if anything they'
worse and , more depraved. , The children. of the pencil fact
are~ occupied,.: althougli: in a cloud ot pust, &#183; while the chi!
of the :' slums" are allowed to , run at large and play in fil
. and dirt of backyards and blind &#183; aJ) ey..&#163;
LOOK Into some of the homes of our little town, where the
shacks, called houses, are huddled together so closely that
neither air, sunlight nor drainage are possible, and where as
many as six or eight human beings are packed into one small
room to sleep. ' Twas in such a place as this that I saw a few
days ago a ragged, dirty girl of ten whose hair had kinks of a
year's growth in it, sitting in the kitchen doorway caring for
a month old baby, wrapped in rags enough to smother even
, the girl herself. At her feet wallowed a hog, splashing over
. all surrounding object'S the' mud which it had gained from
mud ~ puddles easily accessible. ,;'
.:, Is jt only the ignorant Dago and the indolent Pollock
that live in these conditions? Are they onty immigrants who
have moved . into our. town and pushed themselves into our
industrial -- labors? We might . ease : quf. cO~ Science somewhat
'. were it only so. But, alas! thes~ , people are the descendants
of our English forefathers in ~ o~ vei~ s flowed the purest
blood of the Anglo- Saxon ra&amp;., Long d~ pletion, insufficient
: nourishment, ignorance and isolation frQm society and church
. have &#183; . rendered the offspring of the Puritan , and the Caval\ er
l. a - wretched caricature on humanity. The sacred influenc. es
, of the home have been destroyed by the prey of the Modem
: Minotaur. Even the home- maker, the mother, has been
forced to blunt her nature by the exhausting toil. AcroSs
, the cradle- comes a fiend- like cry, ~ nd the startled baby hears
the Minotaur's stern command, " He who ' eats must work."
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL 13
no what is this home? THERE IS NO HOME. It is
dezvous; an ill- kept place where tired bodies sleep; a
y, not to live. And where now are the products
me, honor, hope, virtue and reverence for God?
~. lQ b the poisonous weeds of hatred, malice and despair.
the moral standards, the child's ideals and the
of i ambitions? The criminal records of Pennsylvania
dy with this answer: " Our criminals are mainly those
are embittered by too early toil." An Indiana
ry offers this testimony: " Of the two hundred boys
to u annually for employment, only ten per cent are
. barged on account of drunkenness." The census is
too, howing that the future illiterate is now the child
. toiling, and that the coming makers of the home are
only diseased and dwarfed progenitors. Vitality is gone
maturity comes, and with each succeeding generation
deepens. He who should have stood erect as " the
t ork of God" sinks in life's storm, a shattered human
hild- Iabor is eating the heart out of our nation.' This
growth must be cut away. Our lawmakers are trying
ooy the evil, but an aroused public must come to their
The word of Theseus to slay this Minotaur is an aggres-
. public conscience; an earnest, bold persevering zeal that
. not wane till this Upas tree be uprooted. We can invest
our li es in nothing nobler or better than helping make possible
t every child be educated and delivered from the bondage
of ul and body that impelled Mrs. Browning to cry from
depths of a true, tender soul:
" They look up wi their pale sunken faces,
And their look is dread to see,
For they mind you of their angels in high places,
With eyes turned on Duty.
' How long,' they say, ' how long, 0 cruel nation,
Will you stand, to move the world on a child's heart,
title down with a mailed heel its palpitation
And tread onward to your throne amid the mart?
Our blood splashes upward, 0 gold heaper,
And your purple shows your path!
But the child's sob in silence curses deeper
Than the strong man in his wrath."
14 THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
STUDENT CHRISTIAN WORK
Y. M. C. A.
W. A. HAYNES.
Upon the shoulders of the young men of today the world
of tomorrow must rest. Then should not the young men put
forth every effort possible to prepare themselves for the great
future responsibilities?
The student Young Men's Christian Association offers
opportunities to young men to prepare for life's work. It re&#173;quires
purity of life, honor in classes, clean athletics, high ideals,
and Christian fellowship. These are essential to character.
The Y. M. C. A. especially offers opportunity &#183; to young men,
who expect to teach. They will need the training of Christian
leadership for Sunday school and various forms of church work.
The first meeting of our Association for this year was
attended by six of the old members and several new students.
Of the latter, quite a number gave in their names for enrollment
as members. The work has gone right on. The Association
has heard a very interesting address by Rev. A. G. Smith,
several talks by Prof. Peterson, and quite a number of dis&#173;cussions
upon the various problems of life by different members
of the Association.
The Y. W. C. A., aided by the Y. M. C. A., gave a Hal&#173;loween
entertainment for the members of the dormitories and
literary societies, which was enjoyed very much by all.
All young men, both old and new students, are invited
and urged to attend the weekly meetings of the Association,
and to become members of an organization which has among
its membership, not only Sunday school pupils, but also
members of the gridiron squad.
Members of the Y. M. C. A., let us continue our work
for the Association. Let us impress upon our fellow students
not by word so much as by deed that this organization gives a
young man an enthusiasm to excel and to belp {) th~ t~ t{) ~ A\: e\
in life's work. Let us develop leaders, real, earnest, strong,
and virile leaders for all phases of life.
The Young Women's Christian Association is the one
factor in girls' school lives ' that draws them nearer to God. It
is the tie that binds them together in the beautiful service
of the Master.
Our little Association is very wide awake and is doing
things. Its cabinet consists of a group of influential Christian
girls who stand for purity of life and the best of work. Shall
we tell you of a few things y/ e are doing?
We think the most important part of our work is the
" Morning Watch." In this, the girls meet each morning and
spend the best part of the day in communion with Him who
is the Giver of all good and perfect gifts. It is here that we
gain courage and strength to meet the difficulties and duties
of the day.
The girls of the school are very welcome and w. e urge
thep1 to come to our devotional - meetings, one on Sunday
night and the other on Tuesday afternoon. On Tuesday we
have a program, you should come and be with us.
We keep in direct touch with the Association at large.
Misses Susanna Webb, Ethel Davis and Margarette Stoner
represented our Association at the Conference held in Nashville
the last of October.
We are not lacking in the social feature. A beautifully
planned Hallowe'en party was given by the Y. M. C. A. and
Y. W. C. A. to the student body. The dining hall was artisti&#173;cally.
decorated with pumpkin- heads and autumn leaves. The
fun of the jolly crowd only grew merrier when the ghosts
appeared, and as to the " Fates" of the night we are not able
to say.
Our work was given a new impulse amd additional inspira&#173;tion
by the visit of the Travelling Secretary, Miss Roberta
Dubois. She helped us in a measure to reorganize a. nd put
ourselves on a firmer basis for work. On Friday night of her
visit a beautiful little reception was given to the Y. M. C. A.
in Mary Green Hall in her honor. At a late hour refreshments
were served.
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
Y. W. C. A. Notes
ADA SORRELS.
15
There are many other things that we are doing. We
again extend a cordial invitation to each girl in school to
attend our meetings, and would gladly welcome her into our
helpful company.
16 THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
SYLVIA'S WEDDING
ANNIE LEE Fox.
NE morning last Fall as I went down to breakfast
I felt that something unusual was about to happen.
When my always- calm- and- serene maid of all works
rushed helter- skelter into the breakfast room with
a tin pan, feather duster, and a rag doll in her hands, I was
sure of it.
" What on earth are you going to do with those things,
Sylvia?" I asked in amazement.
Sylvia wriggled find twisted, finally managing to blurt
out, " Why, I'se gwine ter sot- Laws, honey! Whut is I
thinkin' ' bout? I can's sot no tabbel wid dem things."
After many mishaps and rather amusing incidents upon
Sylvia's part, we at last finished our morning meal. By the.
time the house had been put in order I felt surer than ever
that my presentiment had been correct.
Not hearing the usual, " Shall we gatter at de ribber," a
little later I went down stairs to see what was the trouble.
Imagine my horror and amazement when I beheld Sylvia&#173;Sylvia,
the tried and true- bowing and performing fantastic
steps, while the gardener from next door whistled and patted
to the tune of " Lindy."
Though very much astounded at my maid's behavior, I
was sufficiently fascinated to watch the little comedy. As
Sylvia caught sight of me, her mood changed as quickly as
if ( in the words of Sylvia) she had " got religion," and she
began to cry.
Of course I was quite puzzled over this unusual behavior.
After so long a time I was able to gather from Sylvia's dis&#173;jointed
and hysterical sentences that she was to be married,
that night, to a " Mutherdis parson." I told her ~ hat she
might go home and attend to the trousseau, while I, in a
desperation, started to find an appropriate wedding gift.
The next morning I felt that if there was only a law that
prevented maids from ever marrying I would be always
happy. Such things being impossible, I started to arise but
sleep proving such a great temptation, I gave myself up to
one of those blissful little " cat- naps." I dreamed that nice,
hot cakes were coming up stairs, humming the wedding march,
and as I would go to catch one it would jump from my hand
and cry, " Methudis' parson!"
Awaking with a start I realized that the strain of " De
beau' 1, beautiful ribber" wasn't a scurry trick of the dream
man's, but the real voice of the ever loyal Sylvia.
I was so curious to hear of the wedding that I quickly
dressed and descended to the breakfast room, where I found
a beautiful, black- but- beaming Sylvia. She carried cups and
plates as though nothing out of the ordinary ( such as matri&#173;mony)
had ever happened to upset her peace of mind.
" Well Sylvia, how was the wedding?"
" Oh, Miss Lucy, hit wuz de beautifulest weddin' eber
seen in dis town. We had all decerated wid yaller and red
tissue paper roses, and de grandest thing of all wuz a hansom
gold star hanging right ober de mantel- piece. I tell yo' it
sho did make dem niggars eyes shine wid jealousness when dey
seen dat star. We had it at ma's funeral but didn't see no
use ob wastin' it on a grabe so we jist saved it and it sho did
come in handy.
" De house wuz plum packed wid onent niggars an' I wuz
duturmined to show dem sompin whut would natcherlly make
dere mouths stan' wide open. I done it too, Honey!
" I wuz in de kitchen an' I had de doah locked so nobody
cud see me ' till I made de grand entrance. Well, Erastus
Jones struck up de tune ob, ' Wont nobody be dere but de
happy,' an' I opened de doah wid a flourish, an' holdin' my
haid up lak a queen I marched myself out in dat crowd. Dem
niggars turned ' most white dey wuz dat suhprised.
" My hair wuz all pampidooed, and a paper rose wuz
stuck, kinder croquettish like over one ear. I had tuck some
gold paper an' made teeth look awful hansome, an' I jist
grinned all de time. But laws, honey! you jist orter saw my
veil, it wuz long an' flowin' like and kotched up wid a elegant
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL 17
18 ~ HK' M~ T. N. SIGNAL
gold pin right behind. r &#183; yo' ' memberdat dress yo' woah at
dat rose tea- party? ~ &#183; Well, ' I had on~ dat, very same &#183; &#183; dress, wid
a'long trail made ,00 cherry'silk, attached.
" It looked so hansome : nat I cud .' jest feel- dem. niggarS'
eyes on me,- same' as 1f I hcfd'- Deen ' ar snake-. chatrrier. I never
turned my haid, to der tighUnor dei~ le- ft, ~ tirl- I2got , to' de long
tabbel . whar de weddin' , supper wuz..:/ ( 1 ' groaned, inwardly.
as I : had-- a mental image ' of- my' &#183; Qiminished larder., " ':
, " l: bowed kinder keerless like and.- wid a: floutish of, my
hand said, ' Frends it gives me sich &#183; pleasure &#183; to be- wid yo. all
terrnght dat I hardly ' members " nuf maimahs~ tQ thank. yo' one
and all fur de fine presents andJnovtyoall pitcbAn and ' hope
yoselves to a. ything dat &#183; yoah' might" , see.' ' Miss, Lucy, de
way dem niggars hoped' dey selves yo'r would hab...~ thought
dat dey hadn't liacl'rro white~ folks victUals ' for- Q- weekPL; ;"',
, Sylvia seemed so takeifrup' &#183; Witli, &#183; her &#183; . desciiption Ithat I
feared to stop her/ but my- curiosity ' caused me~ &#183; to ask, " &#183; Well
Sylvia, what abouf the bride:: groom:?; How ' did, he act?" .. '
" Lawd, Miss Lucy! yo' know dat owd'acious , niggar' ain't
neber come , Yit." . -. - .' :- ,
&#8226; "~' l!' 13: L. C. --, :':-.'
Lf_' ~ '- &#8226;. ' ,;;,~ ~~_;~.
" The cup, the . cup itselfi from which OUl; Lorcf .~. . ,
. [ - Drank at tb~ dast sad supper wi; th }~ is o~., ;-. 1f tv.. ; ,
And if a~. mattcould s. ee it qr to~~ hjt, ".:, j c' ~'{;' &#8226;&#8226; ,&gt;"
.. He was' healed at Qnce- by faith of qll-. hi~ ills;~- i'iT ,.
. , ,- But the times grew to . &#167; uch evil t~ at theJlol&#165;, CU, R !. -,
Was snatched( away! t&lt;&gt; r. Heaven and di~ ppeareq.:" E-:::
l~ t() ~ u. cb. rom.(} r~ d~ ~ Vi. thad fallenthe knig] &#167; : tSofthe, Table
Round, the knights of Aftlii1r,- ~ i1ower.. 01- c- niva} ry; ': favorite
heroes of Mediaeval : Romance~ '- LaIieelot), &#183; thes~ Great;", had
sWung- his' proud lance low~ Cat ~ t1ie ffeet&gt; of ; llis ' If! ueenJl Bold
Geraiilf -' was c- apturea~ hean ' arid~ s'OuI By the- sweet sIniles of:. tl: ie
bt'l~- eyed Emd. r
r ' Garetll.- liad'" fduna: his~ Lynette; Holy vows
fong since - taken : were begiiining to paU - and' chafe the, &#183; adv- en-turous
soul of (~ hivaliy.- " .. ': :. .
19
! .~ &#183; One hUndred . an. d &#183; , fifty,:: clraj,;&amp;,* l! er~~\&#165; e. f- e;~ at ' rihe~ T' 9' pl~ l
Round~ atknight in _~ ve~.&#163;~ a~: i. s- ave fOBe,' 09 ~; chfl- in iant~ stj~ a! lY
graven :- ancg &#183; cc~ ed:; wjth ] scroH~ C! l. Jjn. es;, ' O: PJY' 1. on~ &#183; had;. eve!
dared to seat himself ther:.~~;;:; t1): js~ was', - Merlin~( Jh:~ I19\ d sage;,
seer ! 3.. nd...- rprQph~ t:)} gi\ ijqingj hand! &lt; gfy[: Arth~~ &#167; :; fl&#8364; s! iJl~.,;~ Even
~ e, rtile.:' f&gt; ower{ yl;:: ha@ rh~~~ l eng. 1Jl.(~. 4!;. al~ 4': lQ!?~ fQJje'l" E1r\_ fro~:: tl} e'
brilliant :~. seTnplag~ Q( yf{ lorl: ~ rrd ; cPl: lftl; y~ gr~ ce, spqt~! le( t~: WJlY 1.
as it_:} w~ r~,'~ by;-_~ Q. me lirresistq1) I@ j.} 1Q) Veli'.. s: upgrior- lf~ vgn:." ~ o l!,~~,
magi~_ ' aJ't. :~: AIld 0SQ, : thtt{~~ at; e~ i '. :~. tood i&gt; shrou_&lt; l~ d. l! P.&gt; ~ y~:
tery~ unoccupied. ,~ J'_ ' I _~'
_,-' , Thetyear- s p, asse~ t Jleetingl&#165;;;; Jchiyalry~~ s.: 5lJ~ ose,!&gt;. udded
modestly s) V~ t11DJ ~ b~. wi\ d ~ m: i. Qel1f. G&gt; i (~ M~ rnr.; Ola ~ n~ land~~'~
grew : up ... w. itQ.' i , rank- qnd~ n9i~~,' wee9~ i' and: t} llder tlte ; tenper
care : of ~ Art1nrr,-:.{ t, 1; ll-, bJown 4a~ tlung it~ j s- w~~ tll~ ss~ thfQ~ g!' lout
the. ah:- andfaJl~ rthe" gre~ t,- wilg. sP8G~' Ift. hq- IDi!! gdth. e fout to:- a
semb, lanee of, its:- fairne. ss;:.;~ 1) i1. h~ t:: tbe~ Ros~, tl!- fJt bloqrpe. d had
liveq . fQr. eyer~) to off~ r its- f, wj! l~ l:~~~ pti_:~ l.\ tl- ki~~ tIs: chalice,~ of
dewy ~ sw. e- et- ID: e~~ &#183; to tbeL~ il) Sfgf~ tij~. J) Vbol~ lWi~, WQtrld!--- 7' BUt1th~
realistic iSjD~ ver;. i1l] lJlq: rtal; ~~~ I].:; g~ B~ auty,~ had: l;&gt; JQOm~ p,-. was
she des: tin~ q ' t.~ bfa&lt; lE;~;. JQ Ja&#162;.~~ Jlto3fa shatt~ r~ djIl} assl.'-- a ft- agraQt
memQ(&#165;;~~- il E2:::. 1S1&#163;:&gt; ,,- j" j1\': 7 r'&lt; 3J!~~. Brr: f) f:: -.:;; 1.11 ~ ;~: ll~ t, &#183; .... r.; ~:.'
'-.~ Qn~ the!. day &#183; w1.' l(~ n &#183; - itb~ i; 1o~ ely~:( pJgss9m:.,; first- rd &#183; roop. ed &#183; . its
head;-- caro~ ~ Gala: ha~ f. Ltp. e:; wbi- t~ ~ onQr!&#165; J; .::~ J: 1it~ ! soule9, tenger
eyed, and~ tru&amp;-; , Youngesto: f &#183; , therknights;~::~( J:~ q! l~ j. h~ bravest
of all. Arthur led him forward to the. g~ gt &#183; ~@ l~; ~ he , bri! lian. t
assemblage~ tur'! le4-:- tfrLgr~~ t:! hjm. '} Np. s~ at"" r~ main~( Lfpr the
beautiful y0t! th, I only; ' I' 4erlin:~; sh~ i i fi~; ~ ustere,. forbidding,
stood iD&lt;;-, t~ e"'! l1ightyr cir9Je-' J- U1]. QG. cupi~ s! J." .;(; alahad,. advanced
fear1e~ sly- an.~ i:. while: the,; . gI: eit~ ~&lt;!! 1qu~ 1J~ y a19lfg- the ' hall, ' on
thatf sw~ et- . s~~ er. night. f;} re &#183; &#167; ~~ te&lt; t h. im~ e~ t,-_ thus, claiming his
own.: .' i\ pcl as ! hey "! i? at, - th~ r~ ip~~~ r.:~ E1~ t. o : th~! t1 : tp~ yision _ of
the , HoIY'Gr.&amp; il bi&amp; l~ eI!: iIl],~. g~ I~~ J) &amp;~~":..: '.,., ) .,- ~ , __ -
': ,_," Whel!! l1e: gI9ryJ~~ d- passeft~ Ad 911Jy tJ: l~~ re( l~~ tion r_ ematned
in. the ~~ e~~ hof Jtle: ~ ghts, . Gaw~ t~ e.;;; tp~ FR~~ y, ; sp~ a~ g to l! is
( eet~ witb., flashil3. g, ex~ s 4! J. d , swore.... b~{ ore; them all" that pn that
day.~ d~ dthe~ st, art, inq~ est,(} J th~ if~ oJ&#165;.: G~~! l~ Qp:, heaq! 1g . t~ e~ e
w~ J.:. d~ &#183; Jil). e f. knjght~! i~: r9se. n f! S ~~ 1J.~ J! 1q. 1! J.: i? pd: : repfta~ e~ Jhe, Y9" o/:
Thus it was when Arthur re- entered " the noble hall. " Oh,
knights, ye leave me," he cried, " leave me to follow a wandering
fire, a will- o'- the wisp, to be lost in the quagmires many, to
return no more." So it happened that Camelot, fair city
20 THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
of towering minarets and quaint old balconied buildings, stood
deserted. When the year was over, the few who returned
guided their horses ' mid heaps of ruins and glory fallen to
dust. Camelot, the Fair, had fallen.
Ages of mankind have. been thrilled and stirred to the
heart by Arthur and his knights. England, France, Germany
and the sunny land of Italy have been aroused from their
sleeping beauty and stirred to life by the Celtic kiss, and to
the magic touch have answered with po try, painting, sculpture
and song.
Many authors have been inspired by the Arthurian
legends, but Tennyson has made them peculiarly his own.
With him we step across the portals of ~ magic land, into
a country of witchcraft, music, lore, tilting knights and ladies'
favors- a constantly shifting scene of romance and adventure.
In all stories of the Grail, character contrasts with char&#173;acter
as daylight with darkness and light with gloom; Sir
Launfal in his beautiful youth and golden mail, scorned the
leprosied petitioner who accosted him at the gates of the
castle of Pride, but when the years weighed heavily upon his
shoulders, and Time had marked with careless fingers his
bent old form- when arrogance had been torn from his soul
as the rich attire from his body, and his heart had been humbled
by a wise God, he saw the folly of his youth and understood
the spirit of Greatest Love.
Though there are many weaknesses easily discerned by
the critics, the quest has not been in vain. Not in vain has
Arthur gloried and died. The quest alone has been worth
it all. The lesson learned has s~ rvived the encroaching rust
of centuries and defied the forgetfulness of the human mind.
As a priceless jewel preserved in story and song it rests in the
heart of man today. From the quest he has learned the way
to the Life Beautiful- the life of service. He has fastened
his eyes on the stars and grasped at the Highest, the Sweetest,
the Purest his God may give. He has learned the disregard
of trivial things, and though he fall by the wayside, with
courage does he rise again to face the world- hope renewed.
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL 21
Three months have elapsed, comprehensive volume,
Since, to all college girls a foe,
You came forth to vex and gall ' em,
And drive them to despair, you know,
With your laws and theories, old and new,
Formulas, symbols, and equations, too.
What doom the fates intend, is hard to say,
Whether they'll live through, that nearing day,
Of examinations awful.
Frolic and fun and youthful prank,
Haste, seek quickly some other rank;
Chemistry's made, to hunt you down,
Destroy your power, make you frown,
And in your place, put miseries galore&#173;Did
ever volume plan so much before?
For three months past, a host of busy girls
Have puil'd their glossy curls
Golden and brown, by night and day,
Trying to learn that H2 S04,
Which means sulphuric acid, must be kept- off the floor
Or if it they accidently spill,
Let it be on their hands, they 800 will heal. t
Well! let the fates decree whate'er they please;
Whether these girls will drink from failure's cup
Or, literally, book, eat you up,
This I can say, you've troubled them no little
And in the future you'll desist no tittle;
Ever by your power, in your haughty prime,
With full determin'd aim, to baffle every claim
Of happy girls who meant to have a good time.
22 THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
THE CONSPIRACY OF AARON BURR
a. M.
HEN the House of Representatives of the United
St~ es decided the Presidential election in 1800,
it _ obably changed the future of the American
nation. Most assuredly did it determine the after-career
of the defeated candidate, Aaron Burr, for had he been
elected President at this time, he would in all probability have
been considered one of our great and honored men.
He was an able, but reckleSs and daring, soldier and
politician, who, judged from the work of his later life, had
vastly more personal ambition than patriotism. He had as
. a Republican leader, been very successful, politically. How&#173;ever
after his defeat for the Presidency, which was - nothing
but right, as Jefferson was recognize~ as the Republican
Presidential candidate, the very little patriotism which he
had ever shown, seemed to have been driven out of him.
He intrigued with the Federalists, which resulted in his
independent candidacy for Governor of New York. He did
not have the unanimous support of the Federalists in thiS race
and was defeated, probably by the efforts of his bitter enemy
and rival, Alexander Hamilton. He blamed Hamilton for
his political downfall and as a consequence challenged him
to a duel which resulted in the physical death of Hamilton and
the political death of Burr. His political prestige in the
United States after this time probably didn't amount to as
much as the postage required to solicit a vote.
It was very soon after this that he first showed signs
indicative of his having conceived the idea of an " Empire in
the West." And so when he left New York, he was probably
serving a double purpose; to escape. from the public, and to
further his scheme of separating the West.
Several prominent men joined his plan, among others,
United States Senators Dayton and Smith, and General
Wilkinson, Commander of United States troops in the West,
the one who afterwards intrigued him.
He returned East for the purpose of obtaining England,
through her embassy, as an ally. Failing in this, he called
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL 23
on all his old friends, and employing Catilinian tactics, he
invited all who had grievances against the government to join
his expedition.
Now having all the following obtainable, he started West
again, accompanied by his daughter, Theodosia, wife of
Governor Alston of South Carolina, and who was to be queen
of the new empire. Though to be queen of the country- to- be,
. she did not for once suppose that there was anything wrong
with the plan of her father. This fact is not surprising as
Burr never let her see anything but the chivalrous and gentle
side of his character. ,
One of his most important followers was Harman BIen&#173;uerhassett,
whose island in the Ohio was the base of supplies
for the expedition, . and whose fortunes were &#183; completely
destroyed by the enterprise.
. Burr seemed to be very popular in Nashville about this
time, even dining at the home of Andrew Jackson, but he
received no support of note from there during his opera&#173;tions.
President Jefferson had all this time been receiving warn&#173;ings
concerning Burr's character and designs, but he didn't
think them of enough importance to investigate. Burr,
however, had been arrested, tried, and acquitted at Frank&#173;fort,
Ky., being defended by Henry Clay, afterwards to
become famous. Having completed his plans; and fitted out
an improvised fleet on the Mississippi, Burr was peacefully
floating down towards New Orleans, when he heard of his
betrayal by Wilkinson and the proclamation of President
Jefferson to arrest all implicated in the plot. His only aim &#183;
now was to escape.
He left his band of followers at Natchez and put out
across the count: nr only to be arrested in north Alabama, and
carried under guard to Richmond. Here he was tried in the
United States Federal Court, Chief Justice Marshall presiding,
and the government taking the offences.
A certain amount of antipathy existed between Chief
Justice Marshall and President Jefferson, as the proceedings
of the trial show. The defense of Burr was in the hands of
Edmund Randolph and Luther Martin, while the offence was
led by a brilliant young attorney, William Wirt. . The rulings
were generally conceded to be favorable to the defense. He
even went so far as to summon President Jefferson as witness.
But the latter refused on account of public duties.
Although there was no doubt in the mind of anyone that
Burr was guilty, he was acquitted, the reason being given as
lack of sufficient evidence. This was the third time Burr had
been acquitted. He went to Baltimore where he embarked
for Europe a virtual outcast. He remained in Europe until
the War of 1812, when he returned to America and entered
his old profession, making a comfortable living until his death
in 1826.
Although Aaron Burr probably deserves to be detested
more than any other character in American history, with the
exception of Benedict Arnold, he has just as surely been
judged too harshly by the majority of the American public.
Though he was a bitter enemy of Alexander Hamilton, and
no doubt wished him out of the way, duelling was customary
and just as honorable then as a law suit is today.
The feasibility of his plan for the separation of the Western
country is evident for several reasons, among them the fol&#173;lowing:
( 1) There were no railroads and consequently the Appala&#173;.
chian Mountains formed, to some extent, a natural boundary.
( 2) The original thirteen States tried to take advantage
of the newer Western States in attempting to gain a greater
percentage of representation in the National Government than
should be allowed the newer States. Though the East did
not succeed in this, still it did not tend to enhanc~ the affection
of the West for their sister States across the Appalachians.
( 3) Though the Western citizens had asked the Govern&#173;ment
time and again to obtain from Spain the right for free
navigation of the Mississippi, this had not been done. Th~
independent spirit of the West did not care anything for a
government that was of no benefit to its citizens.
( 4) It was at that time the opinion of the most promi&#173;nent
men that the West and the East would eventually sep&#173;arate.
However much we may detest Burr, the politician, his
private life is worthy of our highest admiration. His person&#173;ality
and chivalrous attitude toward women were very pleasing.
Shouler describes him as, " One whose restless and romantic
ambition was the more dangerous because of his utter want
24 THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
ANNIE HARRIS.
MADAME BOVINE'S GYMNASTIC STUNT
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL 25
lm HE . more cultured pe? ple, those whose SOUlS. are T &#183; dehghted by " the chmie and fl. ow of words that
move in measured file and metrical array," are
wont to spend hours in the subtle enjoyment of
the genial sparkles of the gentle Whittier, the " magical rythm
and musical rhyme" of Longfellow's poems, the sad sweet
verses of Jean Ingelow, or the grand and deep thoughts of the
bard of Avon. But for some reason- perhaps a lack of appre&#173;ciation-
they utterly neglect the soothing, gently flowing
lullabies of Mother Goose. But why should they be so much
ignored? No poet writes in better metre, no one selects words
more harmonious, and all will grant that no poet has ever
yet surpassed Mother Goose in imagination. One poem
especially deserves attention. It may be called this sweet
poetess' masterpiece- the " Kohinoor" in her crown of poeti&#173;cal
gems. It begins thus:
" Hey, diddle, diddle, the cat and the fiddle,
The cow jumped over the moon;
The little dog laugtred to see such sport,
And the dish ran away with the spoon."
The heroine of this beautiful poem deserves unstinted
admiration. No gymnasium has ever aided in the development
of an athlete whose feats could in any way compare with that
of this illustrious daughter of the Bovine family. Not only
was she a very athletic cow, but she was also an aesthetic
of conscience and generosity;" and we must all agree that
this character was a menace to the welfare of our nation as we
read from Edward Everett Hale's " A Man Without a Coun- .
try"-" And for that flag, never dream a dream, but of sewing
her as she bids you. . No matter what happens to you, no
matter who flatters you, or who abuses you, never look at
anpther flag, never let a night pass but you pray God to bless
that flag."
26 THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
cow; she plainly showed that she was not content with the
society of " dumb driven cattle" and with the coarse things
of earth, but longed for things higher- for new fields and
pastures green among " the star- blossoming fields of the mid&#173;night
sky."
She was also a lover of music, and was greatly influenced
by the " concord of sweet sounds." We find her enraptured
by the mellifluous strains drawn forth from an old fiddle by
some Mademoiselle Grimalkin; . Mother Goose does not tell
us that these feline musicians are graduates of the Cincinn~ tti
Conservatory of Music, or that they had been instructed by
some of the old masters in Germany; nor does she tell us that
they performed beautifully upon the lyre or the harpsicord.
She does not say that they possessed an old " Cremona" by
Stradivarius or Amati; she does not even tell us that they
played upon a violin, but in her own beautiful, simple style,
tells us that they were " cats" and with a " fiddle."
One can imagine the grandeur of the music by the inspiring .
effect it had upon its auditors, upon our heroine in particular.
Surely, Orpheus did not draw forth from his lyre sweeter or
more heavenly strains. . Those soul inspiring melodies, " too
lofty for language to tell,'; falling upon the appreciative ears
of our heroine served to increase her disgust with things
terrestrial and to quicken her desire for things celestial. Look&#173;ing
heavenward, .
" She saw the moon ascending
Like a gentle queen and blending
Her long robes of golden splendor
With the starlight in the skies,
' Till some little stars came thronging
Round about her, and seemed longing
To bewitch her by the sparkle
And the twinkle of their eyes."
' Twas enough. She immediately started upon her expe&#173;dition.
What volumes are expressed in the simple statement,
" the &#183; cow jumped over tbe moon." One can imagine her
graceful form wheeling its flight out into the mysterious realms
of space, where
" Monstrous forms o'er h~ aven's nocturnal arch,
' Seen by the sage in pomp celestial march;-
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL 27
See Aries there his glittering bow unfold,
And raging Taurus toss his horn of gold;
With bended bow the sullen Archer lowers;
And there Aquarius cQmes with all his showers
Lions and Centaurs, Gordons, Hydras rise,
And gods and heroes blaze alongthe _ kies."
All this grandeur and sublimity were ost upon Madame
Bovine who was ever capable of appred1ting the beautiful.
Taking note of her surroundings, she sees
" Worlds on worlds compose one universe,
Observes how system into system _ runs,
What other planets circle other suns,
What varied beings people every star,"
and if Pythagoras' theory is a good one, she listened with
delight to " the ' language that is heaven spoken, the matchless
music of the Seraph spheres."
Mother Goose does not tell us anything of the general
appearance of this cow that leaped over our own world's
satellite, but we prefer to think that she was a " mu1ey," as
it wou1d have been awkward to have gotten her horn~ ngled
in the tail of some comet, while journeying through space. We
shall refrain from cracking the very old joke, " beef was higher
at that time than ever before or since."
But coming back to earth, we find that " the little dog
laughed to see such sport." We are not told whether it was
a good- natured laugh, an ugly snarl, a hideous grin, or a
mocking, sarcastic lau{ h. One imagines it was this last kind
of a laugh; a laugh promoted by envy because he could not
accomplish the same feat. Just for all the world like some
people. There are many people in the world who, had they
been present on that occasion, would have joined heartily in
chorusing that laugh.
Many excellent morals might be drawn from this gem
among Mother Goose's melodies. Many of earth's creatures
are fond of attempting things so far above their capabilities,
that they do indeed seem to be trying to jump over the moon;
but unlike our heroine, they fail to meet with success and only
make themselves objects of ridicu1e.
But we, created in God's own image, can not always be
satisfied with the grosser things of life. Let us strive for
28 THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
things that are better though there be little dogs to laugh.
We need not, however, try to scale the heights at a bound,
but round by round we may ascend the ladder of learning; day
by day we may grow in the grace of God, ever repeating unto
our better selves,
" Build thee more stately mansions, oh my soul,
As the swift seasons roll;
Leave thy low vaulted past;
Let each new temple, nobler than the last,
Shut thee from heaven with a dome more vast,
' Till thou at length art free,
Leaving thine out- grown shell
By Life's unresting sea."
NO. 1
. j STAFF
MURFREESBORO. iE~ NEksSEE
THE M~ T. N. SIGNAL
literary magazine published by the students of the Middle
Tennessee State Normal School.
Editor- in- Chief _
Q. M._ SMITH.
Associate Editors
Grady Society__'__ ' .:. .: : __ -- J. B. THOMPSON
Claxton Society JOHAN BRUMBERG
Murfree Society . ' BESSIE CONGER
Dromgoole Circle .:__ SUSIE SMITH
Business Manager
OSCAR MCPEAK.
EDITORIALS
Introductor
The magnitude of our undertaking is fully realized as we
assume the tedious duties of editing this newly established
magazine. No precedent has been furnished. We are without
a guide. No road has been made plain. We grope about In
amaze of uncertainty and wonder which way to move. Through
this wilderness where some say may be found wonderful pos&#173;sibilities,
which to us, however, seem unassured, nothing
appears to light our pathway save the bright rays of hope
that come from promised student support.
We wish to thank our fellow students for their willing
assistance and earnest sympathy while the first issue of ' our
paper was being prepared for publication. As it is' necessary
that we have the cooperation of the entire school as well as
the vital interest of each individual, in order to make this
magazine a ' success and a help, we therefore beseech you to
join heartily with us in making it all that it is expected to be.
With the united effort of the staff and the student body,
the magazine will, unquestionably, be a profitable under&#173;taking.
But just as a great enterprise is sometimes hindered
and even stopped by the frivolity of some of its champions,
just so maya school paper be brought to failure by the caprice
of some of its supposed- to- be- advocates. There are fancies
to be delighted which are distorted; there are tastes to be
suited which are peculiar; there are appetites to be gratified
which are dissipated. If we should undertake to humor every
such whim, we would be led to folly; if the magazine should
attempt to meet every DEMAND, it would be doomed to failure.
Having placed the ideal of the SIGNAL high above anything
that bears not the marks of dignity, we design to maintain
this ideal to the best of our ability and suffer tlfe consequences.
The choice, general selection, arrangement, etc., of
material for a college paper never meet the approval of all.
The reason may be only " because." We do not pose as
literary critics; we are not ready to boast of our refined taste;
nor are we over- confident in our editorial qualifications. We
are keenly conscious of our inability. The very delicacy of
our task makes us so. However we shall try to give every
complaint our careful attention and shall at all times be glad to
take at value received any advice of the wholesome sort.
Our . duties and responsobilities are new to us. You can
contribute your part to no more advantage nor can you help
us in any better way than by making them clear to us. Point
out our obstacles to us by showing us where they were. Let
every one lend a hand and this paper will be a GO.
The first issue of our magazine is intended to be repre&#173;sentative
of what it shall be at all times. It intends always
to magnify the virtues of the institution from which it goes.
Its policy shall be to give publicity to excellence wherever
found within our sphere, and to be true to the ideals of M. T. N.
30 THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
THE Manager is indebted to Messrs. McKnight and
Goldstein for their help in soliciting advertisements. These
boys have been faithful in their work and have made praise&#173;worthy
assistants.
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
Our Squad
31
To say that the boys who labored on the gridiron this
season have distinguished themselves is putting it too mildly.
They have won the applause and challenged the admiration
of all who ate at all moved by the exhibition of courage of the
highest type.
Not only did the boys receive hardly any encouragement
and but very little support, but the odds seemed against them
in almost every case. The Faculty nearly turned its back and
most of the student body but a deaf ear. They were left
" tremendously alone."
But in spite of this, they went on and on; they did attract
attention; they did let themselves be known; they WON. Boys
that have it in them to win that way, have the pluck and
courage of the one who dares and does. Every man is a hero
and is genuine mettle from helmet to cleats.
Thanks
We are very grateful indeed to Miss Webb for lending
her splendid talent toward the designing and preparation of
cuts and cover design, and for her excellent suggestions in
many other things.
ALL members of the school possessing literary talent or
having a surplus of wit and humor in their system are cordially
invited to contribute articles to this magazine. Do not be
afraid and predict the death of your literary career, before
it has been born; just release the tension on your abilities and
let us have the opportunity to SIGNALIZE your success.
&#8226;
. ARTHUR RHODES.
The Gridiron
This, the first issue of the SIGNAL, would be incomplete
without a theme on the athletics of our school. The school
maintains a number of classes in physical training under the
excellent direction of Miss Jeannet M. King. These classes
include gymnastic dancing, German ball, military exercises.
basket ball, tennis, etc.; yet the one branch of athletics around
which most interest has centered is football, and, consequently,
I shall deal chiefly with this game as put up by our valliant
crew.
After the iealous fight our boys have put up in ushering
forth Normal foot ball amid defeat, with little encouragement,
and less support, may the cloud of gloom never enthrall com&#173;petitive
athletics. Football has only reached the gray dawn
in M. T. N. The coming year we expect the team to accom&#173;plish
vastly more than could have been expected this year.
Although the Faculty encouraged the idea of football,
circumstances prevented them from giving their much needed
support. A kind word of encouragement and approval is
always welcomed, but a foot ball team demands more than
sweetmeats. The game itself is not delicate and the pigskin
can never be pushed over the goal line by a crew nourished
on dainties alone. Besides an unfaltering support, there must
exist good material guided by a hard working coach.
33 THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
material we had was some of the very best, but there
coach among the members of the Faculty and no one
secured. What student would assume the respon&#173;Of
coaching the team, was the question that lingered
minds of the entire crew. At last the question was
in the auditorium. There was perfect quiet through&#173;hall;
the entire body assumed the appearance of
; one of the students was elected coach by unani-consent
when suddenly the walls vibrated with the
cry of " Weber!" " Weber!"
He and the team have fought heroically and although
too weak to play the champion college teams, both
and team have accredited themselves meritoriously.
boys have played a clean game, and regardless of defeat,
have put forward an example by which all athletics
be conducted. Not one of our adversaries has hesitated
us that we were among the cleanest teams they have
But I dare not close without having mentioned a few
trophy bearers of the season. " Hefty" Warren and
. " Brunner have held their positions with enviable fame.
pmer player ever rushed the ball against a strong defense
McKnight. Ragland's speed is wonderful. Ridley,
, and quarterback, has shown coolness of judgment
IOUirhOUt the year. He is honored with having made the
score against Vandy Reserves, which is the best eleven
have met. He did this by his famous drop kick from the
'- eight yard line at a very acute angle when he had only
seconds to make the play.
Oar adversaries have the odds against us in scoring, but
manner in which the team has rallied to the front in battle
has won for each member of the team that fame for
erence which will long hence be cherished in the alumni
student ranks of our alma mater. Our opponents say
t we rushed the ball ten yards to their three. They have
, ented us for superior tackling and for our end runs,
also for efficient coaching.
The members of the team take their furloughs with
' tancy and file off the gridiron to be heard of at a future
Basket Ball
Basket ball practice is now beginning in dead earnest.
If there is anything in the presence of good material, a " crack"
team will be developed this season. Most of the " old heads"
of last year have shown up with good spirit. In a few days
the select crew will be signed up, when the scrubs will delight
in showing them a " time." If other teams don't watch out,
" Old Norm's goin' to git their goat" this year.
34 THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
SOCIETY AT M. T. N.
The Hallowe'en season was appropriately celebrated by
an old- fashioned party given by the Christian Associations
on Saturday evening, November 29th. All the guests were
provided with pumpkin heads and paper sack gloves and were
told to act as natural ( being pumpkin heads) as possible, and
to show a friendly spirit by wearing their gloves out in hand&#173;shaking.
The " chaperons" in their landmark clothes, served
somewhat as a damper on the spirits of the crowd, however.
Mr. Q. M. Smith and Miss Grace Shelley were elected the
King and Queen of the " Pumpkin Patch." Contests were
engaged in, and after characteristic Hallowe'en refreshments
of peanuts, apples, grapes, and stick- candy, the fortune- telling
booths were besieged by curious young people, eager to know
what fate had in store for them.
On Friday evening, November - th, the Young Women's
Christian Association gave a reception to the Faculty and
students of the Normal in honor of Miss Roberta DuBose,
Student Secretary of the Association. No formal programme
was given, but all enjoyed the social intercourse of an informal
. gathering.
A wedding in the student body always rouses quite a
furor of social interest and such was the case when Miss Lettie
King entered upon her new life. The Murfree Literary
Society, of which the bride- elect was a member, held a mis&#173;cellaneous
shower in her honor on Saturday sfternoon, Decem&#173;ber
7th. Every detail of the programme was carefully planned
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL 35
carried out and the whole afternoon proved enjoyable.
DUIIlber of beautiful and useful gifts attested the love and
will in which the students hold their friend leaving them.
The people of Murfreesboro and the students and Faculty
the Normal were given an unusual treat when they were
carried " around the world" by the Dromgoole Literary Circle
ovember 9th. The route led from the three countries
in the United Kingdom,- England, Ireland and Scotland- by
way of Holland, Italy and America, even to far- away China
and Japan, and the characteristic food of each nation was
~ en of at each stopping place. As a finale of the evening
a grand concert of nations was held in which each country
&#8226; tum did some stunt peculiar to themselves and showing
their national characteristics. In the end, every country,
different as they were, united themselves in one firm band,
singing:
Proudly our banner now gleams with golden luster,
Brightly each star shines, in the glorious cluster;
Dromgooles, forever more,
And peace and union,
Thruout our happy band!
The boys of our Normal not only excell in good looks,
book- learning and athletics, but they have displayed a social
instinct developed to an enviable point. Altho Friday the
thirteenth should rightly have been a " hoo- doo" day, still
forty of the girls considered themselves quite lucky in getting
an invitation to the boys reception held in Forrest Hall on that
evening. Partners for the walk over to the boys' dormitory
were chosen by a shuffle of the young ladies' names, altho the
way in which some CERTAIN couples were matched up, gave
grounds. for suspicion. The reception rooms were appro&#173;priately
decorated with the Normal colors and pennants, and
in the front hall Mr. and Mrs. Peterson received their guests.
The five minute conversations on the " Faculty," " Football,"
" Nanoes," " Holidays" and " Weddings" proved quite instruc&#173;tive,
and the girls say that what they didn't learn about the
'' Nanoes'' was made up for, by what the boys DID tell them
about their hopes of matrimony. The game of " Consequences"
was played later in the evening, and Miss Frances Thomason
and Miss Ada Sorrels pryved easily to be the belles of the
occasion. An orange ice was served at the close. Ten&#173;thirty
came entirely too soon for veryone and all the girls
left with the . unanimous opinion that the boys had given them
the best party of the year.
.36 THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
ALL SORTS AND CONDITIONS OF MEN
q-. t-~~ &#183; ~ f~
A t rough politician
Comes leading in the train,
And no Goliath like him
Has lived since the days of Cain';: 1
He has a big position, " y.
But our " boss man" fills it full; J
And the kindly twinkle in his eyes
Proclaims him " a yard wide and all wool."
A most charming little man
We are fortunate to know,
And if he were only single,
We would like him for our beau.
He has the manners of a Chesterfield,
And looks " spic and span and new;"
I think he seems incongruous
With Latin roots, don't you?
One was " bred in old Kentucky,"
That grand old blue- grass State;
No thor? ugh bred out- speeds his ~ ongue, r. J h,. j}
Which goes at a two- forty gmt. U~. , ' j4/ Vri-.. tJ.. A
He is great on Reading and Speaking, ) ~ ,1 I \
Teaches you to elocute, bow, and stand; It' t ~
But of all he whizzingly tells you,
Not half do you understand.
One can expatiate in Civics,
Modem and Ancient History too; r
Does he, so popular with the girls, ?~ ~
Need be introduced to you? ~--;. ~ L'
!'" 11')
\ ' ,"" '-'- vt..-
37
v:~~, tJvI~
.":--; ,- L 1),
l~ r~
\ ~
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
A kind, good man approaches,
And he blushes like a girl;
He explains " precepts" and " concepts"
Till your brain is in a whirl;
The most learned of all the faculty,
But his ideas make us quail
About that period of evolution
When the monkey dropped its tail.
Of all events of history
He can give the dates, ' tis said,
Whether seated on the table top
Or standing upon his head.
One lives among his test- tubes,
Bunsen Burners and such like;
When he calls, " Attention, students!"
Then you had better hike;
If you've chanced to break some retort,
Or dulled those instruments fine,
Then Mercury has dropped below zero
Away down in your spine.
" Monsieur" likes the " Mademoiselles,"
And gives them their own sweet way;
When " Parlez- vous Francais?" he asks you, /) , t
Would you answer, " Si vous plait?" ~~ J Iv~
So jovial and good- natured, (' .-- J ' ! I.. I
There was never a merrier quail I J ~ t- 1\ " t-.,..~
That repeatedly whistled his " Bob White,"
From his perch on the top of a rail.
One is a noted Rhetorician, ,., J
To whom much credit is due; 7" 1YdA~'
He lives in a world of letters, , ' (: (~
And interprets sucl:! things for you, prM~ ' r f~ ' 1
Until the beautiful gems of language. ./
Whose charms before seemed concealed,
Come sparkling in radiant splendor,
With all their beauties revealed.
38 THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
But some men must be practical, 4( 1 ! II
. And of this class we have two; .. I
One can build a house to live in, ) y J ()~
And furnish it through and through. ~.~ .
He will teach you to make baskets and boxes, ~
In his Manual Training class,
And if you're inclined to be timid,
He can give you instructions in brass.
The other can teach about plant life,
About crickets and all kinds of bugs,
lie believes in scientific farming, .
And close his pet theories hugs.
But if this life be worth the living,
These bodies must be fed;
His pigs will make meat and gravy,
And his corn will make us bread.
And now comes the last an~ the dearest, A ~ I
His name you can readIly guess; !~,::\ J'" Y\
A lion in intellect, only, " ..... '
Nothing fierce, but all gentleness; l) .; f~~~ ~ ~
He deals in co- sines and angles,
And all Mathematical lore,
But all in his own quiet manner;
He's our Lyon without the roar.
rSOCI
GRADY LITERARY SOCIETY
J. B. THOMPSON, Editor.
In the month of January, 1912, about twenty- five young
men of the Nomial School met for the purpose of organizing
and estabiishing a literaty society. This meeting resulted in
the present Henry W. Grady Literary Society.
It is the intention of the Society to have a debate each
week and to give every member a chance to speak in public.
This organization stands for the best interests of its members
in particular, and the school in general. _
At the first meeting of the Society during the present
school year, it was with some sorrow seen that the majority
of the old members were absent, tho' this was more than
counter- balanced by the number of new members taken in.
The members of the Society have taken a forward step
not only in the development and evolution of their forensic
talents, but also in the &#183; furnishing and decoration of the Grady
Hall. The work of the Society during the past quarter has
been unexpectedly enthusiastic and progressive. However
work is not all that is in the Grady curriculum, as was shown
by the excellent reception recently given it by the girls of the
Murfree Literary Society, which we are sure has not been
surpassed this season.
The good results of literary work carried on in this Society
stand unchallenged. Several students of the Normal realize
this, with the result that the prospects for new members and
better work are very bright.
40 THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
We cordially invite any and all young men to visit our
programs and become a member.
OFFICERS.
President Rion
Vice- PresidenL Thompson
Secretary Goldstein
Treasurer Abernathy
Flower
Narcissus
Colors
White and Gold
DROMGOOLE LITERARY CIRCLE
SUSIE SMITH, Editor
Tye Dromgoole Literary Circle was organized January
23rd, 1912, with forty charter members, for the purpose of
developing literary talent and pleasant social ties in our school
life. Its motto, " Learn to Stand Alone," was suggested by
Miss Will Allen Dromgoole in honor of whom the circle was
named.
The name is peculiarly fitting inasmuch as Miss Drom&#173;goole
is a Murfreesboro woman and one of Tennessee's most
gifted writers. It was by this meanS that the circle wished
to show its recognition of her notable achievements in literary
endeavor.
In accordance with the plan adopted, the work of the
Society for this year will be devoted to the study of modern
writers. Miss Dromgoole being first on the list, in addition
to the study course, original papers and other outside work
are presented at each meeting.
The book plate shown at the top of the page was designed
by Miss Dromgoole. The significance of the circle is easily
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL 41
seen. The belt and buckle denote strength; the books, learn&#173;ing;
and the laurel branch, victory. Near these is placed our
state seal.
The first officers of our Society were: Lucy Alexander,
President; Susie I. Smith, Vice- President; Add- Lee Porter,
Secretary; Lucy L. Williams, Treasurer; Mary Lindsey, Critic;
Mary Suell, Marshal.
The present officers are: President, Susie I. Smith; Vice&#173;President,
Kate Caldwell; Secretary, Alberta Lewis; Treasurer,
Frances Thomason; Critic, Ada Sorrells;- Marshall, Louella
Wilson.
THE CLAXTON LITERARY SOCIETY
lORAN BRUMBERG, Editor.
It is evident to all great thinking people that in order
for a young man to feel perfectly at ease among his fellow
men, he must be a ready conversationalist; a debater on the
great issues of the day, a ready reader, and able to be a just
critic of others' doings.
It was for this purpose that sixteen young men in our
school banded themselves together at the beginning of the
second quarter of the school year of 1911- 12. It was not an
unwise move. These young men, enthusiastic over their aim,
developed such remarkable talent and power, that when the
time came for the first inter- society debate in May, 1912, they
won the laurels. of victory over their worthy opponents, the
Gradys. The debating honors of the Blue and White belong
to the Claxtons.
In the course of time, about sixty young men have been
members of this Society. It is steadily growing in numbers.
Our gates are always open to receive any young man of honest
intentions, who desires to become a member of this " Circle
of Brothers."
OFFICERS.
PresidenL Brunner
Vice- President Haynes
Secretary Hutchinson
Critic Templeton
Treasurer Smith
42 THE M. T. N. SIGNAL
Corresponding Secretary McKnight
Chaplain Brumberg
Colors: Purple and Gold. Flower: White Rose.
THE MARY N. MURFREE LITERARY SOCIETY
BESSIE CONGER, Editor.
The Mary N. Murfree Literary Society met for the first
time January 23rd, 1912, with thirty- three charter members
and accepted the Constitution and By- Laws offered by the
Committee on Organization.
At a call meeting February 9th, the Society adopted for
their colors Black and Gold, and agreed on the Black- Eyed
Susan for their Society flower.
At a regular meeting March 5th, the following officers
were elected: Miss Onie Martin, President; Vice- President,
Miss Verna Syeffield; Oral Critic, Miss Helene Hudson;
Sergeant- at- Arms, Miss Lettie King; Recording Secretary,
Miss Margaret Smith; Secretary and Treasurer, Miss Berry
Waller.
Many interesting programs were rendered during the
year, chiefly literary in character, and marked especially by
a study of Greek Myths. The last meeting for the spring
term of 1912 was held May 14th, and happily concluded a
prosperous year for the Society.
The gold medal offered for the best essay written by a
member of the Dromgoole or the Murfree Society was awarded
to Miss Verna Sheffield, the Murfree Representative, who
used as her subject, " Through Narrow Passes to the Heights."
On September 24th, 1912, the Society met with a decided
increase in membership, for reorganization. During the
ensuing fall term, the Society has taken up the study of the
" Old Masters," a course which has proven to be most profita&#173;ble
and interesting.
The Murfree Hall is rapidly being furnished through the
efforts of the Society members who are ably assisted in this
undertaking by their Grady brothers and their honorary
members: Miss Arthur, Mrs. Clark, Mrs. Gillentine, Prof. Lyon,
THE M. T. N. SIGNAL 43
Prof. White, Dr. Fertig, Mrs. Swindell, and Miss Tommie
Reynolds.
With the membership inspired by the work done in the
past, there is strong probability of even greater work to be
done inthe future, and the aim of the Murfrees- The advance&#173;ment
of the Society as a whole by the development of the
individual- seems destined to reach a glorious realization in
the years ahead. .
SMILES
Lives of great men all remind us,
We can make our class sublime,
And by asking foolish questions
Take up all the teacher's time.
If a body see a body
Flunkin' in a quizz,
If a body help a body
Is it a teacher's bizz?
Life is real, life is earnest,
We must strive to do our best,
And departing, leave behind us,
Note books that will help the rest.
WISEAND OTHERWISE
---. 1,
( MUTT) WEBER.
Prof. Lyon-" James, what is a polygon?"
James-" A dead parrot."
Prof. Peterson-( in Biology) " Cats are very closely related
to man."
McPeak-" Professor, is that the reason some old ladies
are called cats?"
( And they say some of the pupils became offended.)
Prof. Gillentine-" Claud--- &#173;Covington
( dreaming)-" Signals?"
Miss Frazier while looking in the mirror, was heard to
exclaim: " Oh you beautiful doll."
President Jones ( during stimmer term)-" Alliadies= over
sixty years of age, will not be required to get in upper berth
of double decker beds. And the electric light bill increased.
And the Bull Moose party vamoosed!
" Here yo' Rastus, whar's dat can of lard I tole you to
git?"
" Lor, maassa, it was so greasy it done slipped my mind."
45 .~
Isaac~" H(;) w.- much , doiyou geLfoLYQUf money?'!.;. '
Jacob-" Nine per cent." ". '
lsaac-" Mein Gott! What do you think the Lord will
say when, he lwks. PQWll_&lt;: n\ O ~ es yOJl char~ ng pine per cfnt?"
Jacob-" Why- when he looks down; the nine will look
like a six." ( Don't it?) .
Fresliman~ EmeFald,:" I: 1
Sophomores- Blarney Stone.. &#183; .. , &#173;Junior-
s6. G~ Ston~:, .!.':.
Seniors- TQml1 : S: tQm~ H' t: "
Bill-: iSay- oo.' TI : Mol9\ t1I&lt; Hike tQ.: Qe th~ F.( enl; hoen$ l.\$. o;; Ni-,
Phil-" Why?"
Bill~:~ eGause..; ihe.: papersaYS ik~ ml;) 1:~ es: a9-. n&lt; l9A@'.!,
women."
Dr. Kenney-" Insects can see only a short ' distance."
Thompson-" Dock, I had . a - bumbl~ ~ to chase me a
mile."
McPeak-" Oh well, they can smell."
Wanted- To be a ladies man- Rowell.
Prof. Gillentine-" What do the poems L'Allegro and
III Penseroso represent?"
Miss Fox-" Happy Holligan and Gloomy Gus."
Papa, who was Shylock?''''
" Shame on you, Bub, g~ read your Bible."
Hays ( in Nashville, after an auto had passed, followed
closely by a motor cyc1e)-" Wonder why they did'nt leave
that dum colt at home?"
Reed ( sighing after he had finished his seventh ham
sandwich)-" Wonder if Prof. Lyon could prove my exterior
angle equal to the sum of my opposite interior angles?"
46 THE- M. T. N. SIGNAL
Ragland ( after Sewanee game)-" Where have we been?"
Gannaway-" Skating of course." . .
Row L-" Great show. She played the star part splen-didly."
Row A-" Eh? Oh yes."
Row L-" Don't you think' she was well supported?"
Row A-"( enthusiastica1ly) Oh fine, so far as I could see."
Important- Dn December 9, 1912, A. D., Rev. Johan A.
Bromberg, President of Baraca, wore a hat to school.
Goldstein":"'"" McKnight, why don't you borrow a new
face?"
McKnight-=-" Ah, don't get icy; I'll slip all over you."
Has Covington found his hat yet?
Lost- A stick ' pin- Thomas Ridley.
I
t
l
.
WHO ISYOUR TAIlOR1 J. B. GANNAWAY 3 SON
Men's Wear Co.
Murfreesboro, Tennes" ee.
-&lt;~~ W-"
Phones 67 and 467.
High class fancy groceries and
everything good to eat.
ONLY FANCY GROCERY IN TOWN .-' __---"-' c --'- _ *- ------------...._ ......._.._-.._ ........_-- -*
The House tor YOl. Jg Dlen who want Snappy II
Clothes at a medium price.
I SAME GO'ODS FOR LESS MONEY. I
*-- -_..- -- ------------ .. IBUTLE~ HOOPER'&amp;- CO~'
I - '. .. ..' .
I Headq~ arters for high grade Clothing il
and ~ 1trnishings I
*_________ N_ or_ th_ Side Squa- re-.---- lei .. *
A. l. SMITH, DRUGGIST John L. Russell
~: CITY TAILO~
II I East Side Square. Phone 357.
r-
: i~. sTflR 6f1R6ER SIlOP~~
. School Supplies, Magazines, Cut c. F. Featherston, Prop.
Flowers and Candy. Hot and Cold Baths. Open at all hours.
East Main St...
I'AVENT l PRiCE, Druggists'
~ Normal School Book. s ~
Goods Delivered at Normal School at 4 p. m. every Day.
Toilet Articles, Stationary, Candy
il-iW.
GOLDSTEIN &amp; SON'S i
I Family Outfitters i == II
Everything to wear for every member of every family. I Sole distributers Dependon Hosiery. " The wt: ar I resisting kind".
I PHONE 588. ..,.
PHONE 65.
Phone 500. 110 W. Side Square. Phone 170. East Main St.
&#8226;, Frellh bread and" cakes
baked every day.
Home made Candy a specialty.
Best work at reasonable prices. " Flashlight and srronp
work guaranteed. Kodak finishing.
Studio East Main St.
Whole8" ale and Retail
Staple and Fancy
Groceries.
fRANK fARRIS 8 SON McKNIGHT'S BAKERY
J. A. SHELTON Photographer
I II
Jt
i. SMITH I KITTRELL.'
Correct, place for Ladies to do their shopping.
We carry only first class up- to- date Dr, Goods,
Millinery, Notions and Carpets. . I YOUR PATRONAGE SOLICITED.
i&lt;- *
SODA,
CREAM,
CANDY
Of Tennessee State Normal are
invited to visit us when in need of
footwear.
The Faculty and Students Cohen's Cafe
~
Hooper Shoe Co. Luncheon and Sandwiches
Quality and Service
Hot and Cold Baths
North East Corner Square
french DfY Cluaning CO. LET KERR'S DRUG STORE
~ ~
. Phone 515 ~ FRAME YOUR PICTURE 0
CLEANING, DYING AND PRESSING . PHONE 179
HAD YOU EVER THOUGHT O'CONNOR'S BARBER SHOP
Of THIS?
Osborne Brothers aTe the only : M: er&#173;chants
in tQwn who can furnish
you everything you want to
eat. Try us and you will
find out.
"::. " .". ".: - .
. t:!~. DRUGS AND STATIONERY4i: 1
====~- PERFUMES======
M. F.- Leatherman I Co.,
STA ARD DRUG CO.,
Phone 45
~ SHOES OF ~ UALITY AND STYlE&#8364;)
_ .. . _"'_. .. THE BEST MAKES ==== Large and Varied Assortments.
For Men, Women and Cbildren. &#8226;
J. B. ~ A.: R: RIS
DRY- - GOODS, NOTIONS, LADIES' TAILORED
SUITS And SKIRTS, OARPETS. MATTINGS,
RUGS, DRUGGETS.
East Side Square
Dry Goods, Notions, Ladies, Misses'and Children's
Ready- To- Wear Goods.
~ We Solicit Your Busine58 ~
Phone 77
Shackfet~. Cason &amp;. Rogers
</dc:description>
<dc:subject>College publications; Middle Tennessee State Normal School;</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Image; Text;</dc:type>
<dc:type>text; application/pdf</dc:type>
<dc:format>Periodical;</dc:format>
<dc:format>46 p.; 9.75 x 6.50 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright may or may not belong to MTSU; Reproduced with permission of the Albert Gore Research Center, MTSU</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>May be used freely by individuals for research, teaching, and personal use under the fair use provisions of the Copyright Act; Credit: Property of the Albert Gore Research Center, Middle Tennessee State University, Murfreesboro, TN 37132; For other uses contact The Albert Gore Research Center, P.O. Box 193, MTSU, Murfreesboro TN 37132</dc:rights>
<dc:relation>University Collections, MTSU Miscellaneous, Middle Tennessee Normal School, 1911-1925</dc:relation>
<dc:publisher>Albert Gore Research Center, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:description>Folder 6</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/mtsu1/id/1406</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>