<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Coed Codes, 1967-68</dc:title>
<dc:source>Middle Tennessee State University</dc:source>
<dc:date>1967-1968</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Pamphlet on the coed codes for the 1967-68 academic year at MTSU. Dress codes, behavior codes, and general rules are covered in this publication.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Prefatory statement: A Middle Tennessee State University student is expected under all circumstances to show respect for order, morality, and the rights of others, and to exhibit in her daily living a high sense of personal honor and integrity. The following rules and regulations request nothing more of a student than is described in the foregoing sentence.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Coed Codes
Middle Tennessee State
University
'.
STANDARDS OF CONDUCT FOR WOMEN STUDENTS
HOURS TO REMEMBER
Closing Hours
Freshmen
After 8: 00 p. m. each student must sign out every time
she leaves the Residence Hall, whether it be for a
destination on or off the campus.
A MIDDLE TENNESSEE STATE UNIVERSITY STUDENT IS EX&#173;PECTED
UNDER ALL CIRCUMSTANCES TO SHOW RESPECT FOR
ORDER, MORALI'IY, AND THE RIGHTS OF OTHERS, AND TO
EXHIBIT IN HER DAILY LIVING A HIGH SENSE OF PERSONAL
HONOR AND INTEGRI'IY. THE FOLLOWING RULES AND REGU&#173;LATIONS
REQUEST NOTHING MORE OF A STUDENT THAN IS
DESCRIBED IN THE FOREGOING SENTENCE.
Monday through Thursday
Friday and Saturday
Sunday . . . . . . . .
Sophomores
Monday through Thursday
Friday and Saturday
Sunday . . . . . . . .
Juniors and Seniors
Sunday through Thursday
Friday and Saturday . .
.10: 00 p. m.
.12: 00 p. m.
.11: 00 p. m.
.10: 30 p. m.
.12: 30 a. m.
.11: 00 p. m.
.11: 00 p. m.
. 1: 00 a. m.
Every student who " signs out" must " sign in" upon her
return.
Residence Hall Visiting Hours
Women are permitted male visitors in the lobby during
the following hours:
Monday through Thursday:
Freshmen Women .4: 00 p. m. until 10: 00 p. m.
Sophomore Women. .4: 00 p. m. until 10: 30 p. m.
Junior and Senior Women. .4: 00 p. m. until 11: 00 p. m.
Friday and Saturday:
Freshmen Women .1: 00 p. m. until 12: 00 p. m.
Sophomore Women. .1: 00 p. m. until 12: 30 a. m.
Junior and Senior Women. .1: 00 p. m. until 1: 00 a. m.
Sunday:
All Women 1: 00 p. m. until 11: 00 p. m.
J
Quiet Hours
Every student is expected to show consideration for
others at all times. General quiet hours are:
Women students are not permitted to wear sportswear in
classroom buildings, Library, Student Union Building
( except to pick up mail), new University Center,
Cafeterias and the Administration Building.
SPECIAL PERMISSION
During examination week ( closed week) quiet shall be
observed at all times.
Specific quiet must be maintained at all times after
11: 00 p. m.
Monday through Thursday
Friday and Saturday
Sunday . . . . . .
.8: 30 p. m. to 7: 30 a. m.
10: 00 p. m. to 10: 00 a . m.
. ALL DAY
Culottes are the only divided type of ;!~ that will
be permitted at dances-.---
Men and Women will not appear in the lobby during
visiting hours unless well- groomed and dressed pro&#173;perly.
( Men wearing shorts may call for their dates
but may not visit except on Friday and Saturday
afternoons. )
Appropriate dress for an outing is acceptable, but
good taste is expected. If there is any question as
to the proper dress, consult the House Mother.
All special permissions are to be obtained from the
House Mother in each Residence Hall.
A printed form for Freshmen and Sophomores covering the
usual requests requiring parental consent must be on
file with each House Mother.
In all cases of visits away from Murfreesboro Freshmen
and Sophomores are required to fill out a special per&#173;mission
card and ha'/ e it signed by the House Mother.
All women are required to fill out a special permission
card to spend the night out of the residence hall.
Sportswear may be worn to:
Art studio classes
Baseball games
Bicycle riding
Bowling
Band practice on the field
Carnivals
Decorating for dances in
Tennessee Room
Decorating floats
Drive- in movie
Golf
Horseback riding
Laundry
Parades
Picnics
Play practic e
Play in snow
Pep meetings
Rifle team practice
Shopping Centers
Skating
Track meets
Tennis
Town
All plans to spend the night out of the residence hall
the night of a dance must be c leared with the House
Mother by noon the day of the dance.
To visit other colleges, women must have a letter of
permission from parent mailed to House Mother giving
student's name to be visited and the dormitory in
which she resides.
When a student requests to spend the night i~ the home
of a young man, specific written permission will be
required from her parents. This permission must be
mailed directly to the House Mother.
DRESS
Appropriate campus dress includes dresses, skirts and
sweaters and/ or blouses, suits, and culottes which are
dress length. None of these should be more than two
inches above the knees.
2
When crossing the campus to participate in any of
these activities, women students living on the West
side of the campus are expected to go by way of the
driveway which runs parallel to North Tennessee
Boulevard. They may cross the campus after passing
Rutledge Hall. In going to the art studio classes
or band practice, they should use the sidewalk be&#173;hind
the Business Building. Women 3tudents living
in Wood Hall a~ d Felder Hall will be expected to use
the road going by the Maintenance Building toward the
football field, and those in the High Rise will go di&#173;rectly
to the area of activity.
When crossing the front campus to participate in any
of these activitie~ wrap- aroundskirt should be
worn in warm weather and a full- length coat in cold
wf.~ ather.
3
Women students are permitted to wear sportswear on
campus on Friday afternoqns from 3: 00 p. m. until
8: 00 p. m. and on Saturdays until 8: 00 p. m. This does
not include halls and classrooms of classroom- bUi~ gs,
Library, Student Union Building ( except to pick up
mail), Ad~ a~ Building, Cafeterias, and the
~ University Center .
Short shorts may be worn to physical education classes
or while engaging in active sports. ( A coat or skirt
must always be worn over short shorts when leaving
or entering the dormitory, and while the student is
enroute to or from physical education classes.)
Women students must not appear on the campus with
their hair rolled up.
1. Excessive noise
2. Returning to the hall 15 minutes late or more
3. Any student signing out or in for another
student
House Mothers will send students to Council for other
offenses at their discretion.
DEMERIT OFFENSES
After a student has acquired twenty demerits during a
semester, she will be placed automatically on a week's
" campus." The following constitute cause for receiving
demerits:
1. Noise in dormitory
2. Playing record player or radio too loudly
3. Using typewriter after 12: 00 p. m. in bedrooms
4. Lea\ ing clothes or dishes to soak in bathroom
sinks
5. Hanging laundry in the hall or in windows
6. Engaging in conversation from the windows with
male students
7. Entertaining male guests in the lobby before
or after visit ing hours
8 . Making or accepting phone calls after 11: 00 p. m.
during the week and 12: 00 p. m. on Friday and
Saturday
9. Negative report on room inspection
10. Cooking in rooms
11. Failure to sign out
12. Failure to sign in
4
Demerits for other offenses will be assessed by the
House Mother in consultation with the Dean of Wo~ en.
GENERAL RULES
Any student leaving or entering the dormitory after
8: 00 p. m. must leave and enter by the front entrance
of her own dormitory
Women students are expected to go to their respective
Residence Halls immediately after any night program
or activity on the campus ( provided the activity is
later than the normal closing hour for the student
involved.)
Any student not conducting herself properly at any
time will immediately be subject to a " campus."
Smoking is not permitted in classrooms or the Library.
Popcorn poppers and coffee makers are the only cooking
utensils permitted i~ s-.---
Telephone conversations should be limited in length
to ten minutes.
After dark all window shades and blinds are expected
to be close~ r tilted in such a manner that anyone
from the outside cannot see into the room. When a
student retires and turns out the lights, she may
raise the blinds or shades in any manner.
Intoxicating beverages are not to be brought into the
Residence Hal ls. Any case involving drinking will
cause the v iolator~ be liable for s~ ere discipli-nary
a,~ tion ~ dismissal from theUniversity.
Students are not permitted to visit men's residence
halls, including University Park. Any student found
v isiting in a man's room, apartment~ ouse, or motel
will be liable for d i s m i s s a l from the~ erS;: t~
Any student caught stealing or with stolen goods in
her possession will be liable for d i s m i s s a l from the
University
Any student who spends the night out of the Residence
Hall without- permISSIOn- wIl~ liable- for- dismissal
from the University. -- - --- --
Any student found tampering with or going out of panic
~~ specified hours will be liable for severe
5
Television sets are located in the dormitory complex
for the student's enjoyment. Women are requested
not to have television sets in their rooms.
In case of a mass demonstration within the area of
the dormitories bordering on a riot or raid of any
description, each student must go to her room imme&#173;diately,
lock the door, and turn out the lights .
Talking and throwing objects of any nature out the
window is forbidden. Any student found encouraging
or taking part in ~ r i ot- or ~ raid is subject to
severe disciplinary action.
Guests are expected to abide
rules and sign a guest card.
guest is responsible for her
by the Residence Hall
Each student who has a
room rent and conduct.
GENERAL INFORMATION
Residence Hall meetings are held in all of the
Residence Halls the first Wednesday night of each
month at 10: 00 p. m. in Freshmen Residence Halls and
10: 30 p. m. in all other Residence Halls. Attendance
is required. Permission to be absent must be obtained
in advance from the House Mother.
Men are not to take luggage to women student's rooms
without permission of the House Mother.
Nothing is to be placed on the doors of rooms except
women's names with the exception of Christmas decor&#173;ations.
The University reserves the right to enter any room
at any time. Rooms will be checked on Tuesday of
each week for order and cleanliness. Rooms must be
left in order when students leave for the week- end.
Students are responsible for rooms and room furnish&#173;ings.
Damage to same will be reported to the Univer&#173;sity
Administration which will determine and assess
the amount to be paid in reparation.
READ BULLETIN BOARDS DAILY Ig! lOranCe
which has been posted twenty- four hours
~ tedfor an excuse.
of any notice
cannot ~
Sun decks on Monahan Hall and the
will be open from 7: 30 a. m. until
( weather permitting).
High- Rise Dormitory
4: 30 p. m. daily
Pets are not permitted in the Residence Halls.
No firearms or fireworks are permitted in the Residence
Halls.
Freshmen living in the dormitory are not allowed to
have cars or other motor vehicles on campus or in
Murfreesboro.
Any woman student who gets married while residing in
a Residence Hall is required to report immediately to
the Dean of Women.
Any woman student who has special permission to remain
out of the Residence Hall past normal closing time for
personal reasons will pay the student hostess on duty
at the rate of one dollar per hour for the time past
the closing hour.
Infirmary hours will be posted on bulletin board. If
a student becomes ill, she should report immediately
to the infirmary. If illness occurs during the night,
she should report to the House Mother.
Students are not encouraged to baby sit. No
permission will be granted for baby sitting.
are not permitted to baby sit in areas where
students are housed ( Dormitories, University
Apartment Houses, etc.).
late
Students
men
Park,
All Residence Halls will be closed during the
Christmas holidays. There will be week- ends when all
Residence Halls except one will close. On these
specified occasions students are expected to check out
of the dormitory as soon as possible after their last
examination or class. Students who find it necessary
to remain on campus during such week- ends must see
the Dean of Women.
Women may visit in the Residence Halls on Friday and
Saturday nights . Any exception to this must be
cleared with the House Mother. A charge of seventy&#173;five
cents per person will be made for each night.
6
Women may not do men's laundry in the Residence Halls.
Students should report any fire to the House Mother
or Hostess and go to the nearest exit immediately.
Residents are advised to become familiar with the
locations of exits and fire extinguishers. For
further instructions check the bulletin board.
Tampering with or setting off fire alarms and ex&#173;tinguishers
except in case of fire s u b j e c t s ~ s t u d e n t
to disciplinary action-.--
Each girl is issued a key for $ 1. She should keep her
door locked at all times as the University is not re&#173;sponsible
for any loss.
FRATERNITY HOUSE VISITATION
Women students may visit in the pUblic areas of
Fraternity Houses during the following hours and
then only when the House Mother is present.
Sunday through Thursday.. 4: 00 p. m. until 10: 30 p. m.
Friday. .4: 00 p. m. until 12: 00 p. m.
Saturday 1: 00 p. m. until 12: 00 p. m .
Classroom wear is the suggested dress for vis itation
in Fraternity Houses except for special occasions.
Women students should not visit Fraternity Houses
unless specifically invited or escorted.
Women students who pla~ to attend a Fraternity party
on another campus must have a letter sent from their
parents to the House Mothe r for such occasions.
DEFINITION OF k~ M. T. S. U. CAMPUS
1. Students must be in their Residence Hall by
7: 00 p. m. - in their room by 10: 00 p. m. - no
visitors after 10: 00 p. m. Students are not
allowed in lobby after 7: 00 p. m.
2. There will be no overnight visitors allowed
during a " campus".
3. A " campus" may be changed in case of an emer&#173;gency.
4. Parents may visit durillg a " campus".
A more strict " campus" may be enforced at the dis&#173;cretion
of the Dean of Women.
IF THESE RULES ARE BROKEN, A STUDENT WILL BE RE&#173;CA~
USED.
COMMITTEE ON STANDARDS OF CONDUCT
FOR WOMEN STUDENTS
FOR 1967 - 1968
OFF- CA~ US HOUSING Name Class Position
No undergraduate woman student may live off- campus
without first making application for a dormitory
room and securing permission from the Director of
Women's Housing.
In the event there are unoccupied rooms in a resi&#173;dence
hall at anytime, the Unive. rsity re. serves the
right to require any undergraduate student renting
a room off campus to move into a residence hall.
No undergraduate woman student may live off campus
during the summer unless she lives with reIa~
or at home
8
Martha McDaniel 4
Linda C. White 4
Lee Crowell 4
Ellen Martin 2
Sherry Odum 3
Betty Strong 4
Mary Lynn Townes 4
Jan Whiteside 3
Sherian Brown 1
Yolanda Brumit 2
Linda Hall 3
Virginia Harley 2
Betty Ann Hart 2
Bonnie Hearn 4
Ann Keister 4
Ellen Martin 2
Carol Moore 2
Linda Nance 1
Patricia Prahl 4
Reba Price 4
Cathy Stone 4
Sherry Williams 1
Mrs. Judy Milholland
Miss Martha Hampton
Vice- President - A. S. B.
Incoming Vice- President- A. S. B.
Dormitory Council
Dormitory Council
Dormitory Council
Dormitory Council
Dormitory Council
Dormitory Council
Dormitory President
Dormitory President
Dormitory President
Dormitory President
Dormitory President
Dormitory President
Dormitory President
Dormitory President
Dormitory President
Dormitory President
Dormitory President
Dormitory President
Dormitory President
Dormitory President
Director of Women's Housing
Dean of Women
</dc:description>
<dc:subject>College students; Behavior; Dress codes; College publications; Middle Tennessee State University;</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Image; Text;</dc:type>
<dc:type>text; application/pdf</dc:type>
<dc:format>Pamphlet</dc:format>
<dc:format>6 p.; 4 x 8 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright may or may not belong to MTSU; Reproduced with permission of the Albert Gore Research Center, MTSU
</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>May be used freely by individuals for research, teaching, and personal use under the fair use provisions of the Copyright Act; Credit: Property of the Albert Gore Research Center, Middle Tennessee State University, Murfreesboro, TN 37132; For other uses contact The Albert Gore Research Center, P.O. Box 193, MTSU, Murfreesboro TN 37132</dc:rights>
<dc:relation>MTSU Collection, MTSU Miscellaneous</dc:relation>
<dc:publisher>Albert Gore Research Center, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:description>Box 2, C-D, Coed Codes folder</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/mtsu1/id/1287</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>