<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Victory in Europe</dc:title>
<dc:relation>Sidelines, June 26, 1946</dc:relation>
<dc:date>1946-06-26</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Two stories: one about Omaha Beach and the other about Hitler's hide-a-way. World War II service experiences of State College veterans Earl Glover and Robert H. Garrison. Glover was involved in the capture of Berchtesgaden, Germany, where Hitler's Eagle Nest was located. Garrison fought on Omaha Beach on D-Day.</dc:description>
<dc:description>VICTORY IN EUROPE
TWO STORIES, ONE ABOUT OMAHA BEACH AND THE OTHER ABOUT HITLER'S HIDE-A-WAY
Editor's Note: Dave Adamson's experience among the headhunters of the region beyond Dinjan, India and Billy Burch's record in downing Jap Zeroes were the subjects of two previous articles of service experiences of State College veterans. This week we turn to the European theater for stories from Earl Glover and Robert H. Garrison. By plagiarizing from Mr. Sloan's English 112 themes the Side-Lines picked up these two interesting sketches.
Earl Glover entered service in December 1942 and a year later was in the European theater. He spent two years overseas where he earned five battle stars, two arrowheads, three presidential unit citations, the French Frouguerre, the Combat Infantry Badge, the Bronze Star, the Silver Star and the Purple Heart. He is a sophomore from Tullahoma. 
He describes his most interesting experience thus: 
It was a beautiful day in May, and we were advancing on the town of Berchtesgarten, Germany. I had read and heard a great deal about this place so naturally I was excited.
As we entered the outskirts, huge masses of German soldiers, officers and enlisted men were giving up to us without battle. I don't recall the amount in number of these masses of men, but I remember seeing great multitudes of them standing in the fields. 
Saw General Kesselring
The day then reached one of its highlights. We received a message that General Kesselring was coming in and to be on the lookout for him. At this time he was commander of all German forces, in Europe. When he came in. I realized that this day would probably be the last day of the war. 
(Continued on Page Three)
MORE ABOUT
Victory in Europe
(Continued From  Page One) 
After sending him and his staff back, we advanced on to Berchtesgarten. Once inside the city, everything seemed normal so we went up the mountain until we reached Hitler's home. Here we lowered the German flag and raised the Stars and Stripes. We then received orders to stop and rest. We prepared for the night to follow at once. Then another order came. This order I had been waiting to hear for years. The order was as follows: "Do not fire unless fired upon." I then realized that this was the end of the war.
Garrison Hit Omaha Beach
Robert H. Garrison was with the 227 Field Artillery and saw service with the First, Third, Ninth, Seventh and Fifteenth United States Armies. He was in the forefront of the D-Day operations on Omaha Beach and operated against St. Lo. Garrison is a freshman from Alexandria. His graphic account of experiences two years ago this month follows:
On May 17, 1944 we left our camp at Okehampton, England, after being stationed there for one year for what we assumed to be the pre-invasion events of western Europe.
Leaving Okehampton, we traveled about twelve hours to the southern tip of England near Falmouth to our staging area. Here we were processed in the usual manner and eventually briefed as to where we would land, what our mission was. The information was that we were to strike on Omaha beach, a designated strip of the coast of Normandy inland from the Cherbourg Peninsula.
On the morning of May 31 we received orders to leave for our respective places. At midnight, May 31, we left for our L.S.T.'s which were concentrated at various points along the English Channel.
Pre-invasion  Briefing
Within the next few hours we were in Falmouth Harbor. It was not long before other vessels joined us making a total of eleven. The second night we left only to return. This was June 4&#226;&#8364;&#8221; we were told after the invasion that June 4 had been selected as D-Day, but due to weather conditions it had been canceled for 48 hours. On the 
(Continued On Page Four)
MORE ABOUT
Victory in Europe
Continued   From  Page  Three)
morning of June 5, we left again. After a few hours of sea we came to Plymouth England. It was here that we met a large number of vessels. The day passed quietly until about 2100 hours or 9:00 o'clock in the evening we received word over our loud speaker system that order had been received to continue our journey. The message read: "According to signals received, tomorrow, June 6, is D-Day. Approximately 6:00 o'clock in the morning is H-Hour. We will start across the Channel about midnight tonight. If nothing happens, tomorrow at 10:00 o'clock we will be on the coast of France. Good luck."
We proceeded throughout the night to the designated point. We arrived about 1100 hours. The invasion was a bout five hours old and was not going so good. We started into the beach, but due to heavy artillery fire we turned our to sea about one mile off the coast. After a few days of hard work and clearing the snipers, we were in the position to meet attacks that the Germans pulled. According to plan, the city of St. Lo was to have been taken D plus 3, but it wasn't until D plus 49 that the city fell inot the hands of the Allies, of course, about 40 days of this time was for the preparation of the big assault on the city. The days following this brought about the liberation of France and eventually Germany.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>World War II</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>World War, 1939-1945--Campaigns--France--Normandy; Berchtesgaden (Germany)--History; Hitler, Adolf, 1889-1945;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>War; War allies; Military tactics; Veterans; Students</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Omaha Beach, Normandy, France; Berchtesgaden, Germany</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:type>image/jpeg</dc:type>
<dc:format>Clipping</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected. Reproduced with permission of the University</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Reproduction is permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only; Credit to Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/mtsu1/id/1120</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>