<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Skylines, v. 1, no. 3, July 24, 1943</dc:title>
<dc:title>Sky lines; Skyline; Sky line</dc:title>
<dc:source>11th College Training Detachment, Army Air Forces</dc:source>
<dc:date>1943-07-24</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Skylines was a publication of the 11th College Training Detachment at MTSC during World War II. This issue has articles about the aviation students; Lieutenant Lawrence Pattock; Navy Air Corps reservists; the reorganization of flights; a pilot who's parachute ripped after he bailed, but he survived; members of the College Training Detachment; and the baseball team</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Newspapers; United States. Army Air Forces. College Training Detachment, 11th; Military cadets; Air pilots, Military; World War, 1939-1945; Middle Tennessee State College;</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:type>text; application/pdf</dc:type>
<dc:format>Newspaper; Periodical;</dc:format>
<dc:format>4 p.; 9 x 12 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright may or may not belong to MTSU; Reproduced with permission of the Albert Gore Research Center, MTSU</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>May be used freely by individuals for research, teaching, and personal use under the fair use provisions of the Copyright Act; Credit: Property of the Albert Gore Research Center, Middle Tennessee State University, Murfreesboro, TN 37132; For other uses contact The Albert Gore Research Center, P.O. Box 193, MTSU, Murfreesboro TN 37132</dc:rights>
<dc:relation>MTSU Memorabilia Collection, Oversize</dc:relation>
<dc:publisher>Albert Gore Research Center, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:description>Box 1</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/mtsu1/id/1314</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>