<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>American Negro</dc:title>
<dc:title>Guest editorial : the American Negro</dc:title>
<dc:relation>Sidelines, March 18, 1968</dc:relation>
<dc:contributor>Brooks, Sylvester Patrick</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1968-03-18</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Discusses equality and sense of belonging in America.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Guest Editorial
The American Negro
For almost two hundred years Americans have endeavored to make America the showplace of freedom, equality and democracy. Many good people have worked very hard to make this nation what it is today. Yet with all our glory and beauty so much is so wrong with our country. Our views of freedom and equality have become blinded by those Americans who are foreign to the basic American belief &#8212; that all men are created equal &#8212; endowed by their Creator with certain inalienable rights.
So it has become a lonesome thing to be a Negro in America. I am almost overwhelmed by a feeling that says &#8212; you don't belong. Then I tell myself this is my home &#8212; I have to belong here; I have nowhere else to go, and nothing more valuable to me than America. I love this country, 1 simply want to become a part of it.
I have talked with many people about the numerous problems that exist in being a Negro in America. I am shocked when they say &#8212; It's bad, but that's the way it is &#8212; or &#8212; That's rotten, but it's just something you'll have to live with. It is strange how seemingly sympathetic people can be so purely apathetic. Even so, I say it is not the way it should be, and it is not something I am going to live with.
All that Negroes want is respect. As human beings, we ask no more than that, as Americans we deserve no less. For we too have endeavored to build America. Then it is too much to desire to enter the mainstream of American society? At this very moment with their fellow Americans, Negroes are fighting thousands of miles across the sea in the name of freedom, democracy, and the American way. I have looked and looked, and I wonder- at home where is the freedom? Where is the democracy? Is this truly the American way? If Americans can fight and die together, then my God when they come home, why can't they live together?
If it is wrong to help build a nation, and expect to be a part of it, then again we are guilty. Even so, the sweat from our brow too has watered the nation and made it grow. We have to love this country, it is our home &#8212; and we are tired of being strangers in our own land.
I long for the day when any American anywhere in this country can stand and proudly say &#8212; this is my country, and these are my people. So, let us not be petty when our cause is so great. For it is a time for courage, and a time for challenge. Neither the faint hearted nor the fanatics are   needed. Let us throw from our ears the cries of the extremists on both sides. And let us stand together without hatred, with respect for all, and with the same devotion that possessed those who built this nation &#8212; and let us endeavor to rebuild it. The problem before us today is indeed great, but I believe that the American people are greater.
Sylvester Patrick Brooks</dc:description>
<dc:subject>African Americans--Social conditions; Civil rights--United States; Racism--United States; Middle Tennessee State University</dc:subject>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:type>image/jpeg</dc:type>
<dc:format>Clipping</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected. Reproduced with permission of the University</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Reproduction is permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only; Credit to Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:rights>
<dc:relation>Sidelines Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/mtsu1/id/1130</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>