<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Normalite, 1923 May</dc:title>
<dc:source>Middle Tennessee State Normal School</dc:source>
<dc:date>1923-05-01</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1920-1929</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>The Normalite was a Middle Tennessee State Normal School publication</dc:description>
<dc:description>Commencement Program and Class Roll 3
Seniors _ ~._._._ 4
Sidelights on Members of Senior Class 5
Feathertop's Brother- ICHABOD IRVING 7
The Home Ec Club- MARVEL BASS 10
The Treason of Society- ORA TODD 12
World Polity Club- EMMA BECTON 15
Pepys Up- to- date 15
The Storm- BELL _ 20
Mother- W. B. GREEN ~ 21
Possibilities- ELIZABETH AKIN ~ 22
Why I Teach &#183; _ 25
Practice Teaching 25
Success- FRANKIE MELSON 27
Editor's Page ..., 2f)
Beautiful Springtime...,... NELL HENDERSON 31
Glee Oub ....................................................&#8226;..................................... 32
Fun ..:. _ ~ 34
Literary Societies "'": 36
Chapel Talks _ 40
Faculty ............................................................................&#8226;................... 41
Locals 43
Alumni 45
A Lament _ 46
Y. W. C. A ~ 47
Athletics 49
Exchanges ~ ~ ~ 51
Hits, Runs and Errors _ 52
Advertisements ~ 55 .....
COMMENCEMENT PROGRAM
Tuesday, May 22.- Grades ( Evening).
Friday, May 25.- Essay Contest ( Evening).
Saturday, May 26- Athletics ( Afternoon).
Sunday, May 27.- Commencement Sermon 11 o'clock A.
M.
Sunday, May 27.- Glee Club, morning and afternoon.
Monday, May 28.- 0ratorical contest, afternoon.
Society debate, evening.
Tuesday, May 29.- Class Day Exercises, afternoon.
Alumni Banquet, evening.
Wednesday, May 30.- Graduation address, morning.
';;[ L;~'_
CLASS ROLL OF 1923
Liggett, Robert
Lowe, Jessie
Manier, David Loyd
McDaniel, Lela
Overton, Bruce
Rogers, Hester
Ray, Vera
Rowe, Mrs. Annie Lee
Smith, Hazel
Watson, Margaret
Secretary ' Windrow, J. Edwin
Woodson, Charles Joe
Arnold, Fred
Bass, Marvel
Bond, Gladys
Bray, Dessie
Brier, Henry Clay
Clark, T. E.
Clark, Mrs. T. E.
Cook, John
Dement, Cyrus, President
Flatt, Wesley P.
Grigsby, Elizabeth,
Lee, Ruth
THE NORMALITE 5
SIDELIGHTS , ON F~ MOUS MEMBERS OF
SENIORS SENIOR CLASS .
4 THE NORMALITE
Since the opening of the Spring Term our Senior class
ranks have been filled, and we now realize that we are on the
homeward stretch. Win or lose, pass or " bust" we are deter":
mined to have our sheepskins in June. With that determina-'
tion we have just about worked out our plans for Commence&#173;ment.
One of the most interesting and best meetings of the
year was held April 2. The principal topic for discussion was
our class day program.
The report of the class day committee was. quite inter&#173;esting.
They found first that we had a presIdent whose' spe&#173;cialty
is making speeches,. so they bestowed upon him the dis&#173;tinct
honor of making the address.
They found people in our class who could actually write
the history of our first days at M. T. N. Marvel and Bruce
ran a close race and both won. Marvel will have &#183; the privi&#173;lege
of delivering said history.
Our prophets will &#183; certainly have to use their imaginations
quite a bit to paint happy pictures for the future of the 1923
class. The prophets should work together well since they are
Windrow and Elizabeth.
Our class poet is; certainly a dreamer, she has never yet
failed to give us the best in school songs and we fe'el that she
will do equally well as a poet-,. none other than Margaret
Watson.
We have a big member in our class who loves to compli&#173;ment
the faculty, so Charlie Joe will be our Faculty Knock&#173;er
( 1 would strongly advise all faculty members to bring
smelling salts.)
The Class Will will be given by Ruth Lee and John Cooke.
The committee also found that we had a violinist and
some song birds, so we have provided for some interesti~ g mu~
sical numbers, incltiding our Class Song by alL
Come and hear our last farewell as students at M. T. N.
on May 29.
Dessie Bray- Mo$ t freque~~ ly ph. otograph~ d member of
1 f ' 23 Milliner of abIhty- pIpe her ma- ny chapeaux.
the c asS 0 &#8226; .
t
r actress; excellent hanger for clothes. .
AIDaHeauzel Smith-" Still water runs deep;" ghat ers capI. ta1
A's like snatching candy from an infant. Authority on &#183; Law
of Diminishing Returns. . . '...
Gladys Bond- Only girl during Mrs. Rutled~ e's a~ mmIs;
t
' on who could successfully engineer motor tnps WIth her
tra I . l'
suitor or use the sweetie line. Favorite Shakespearean me,
4' This above all, to thine own self be True( tt).
Ruth Lee, noted for her merry laugh and pretty curls.
Only girl here long enough to live in al~ sixty rooms of t~ e'
dormitory. Slow eater. ' Lives on yon SIde of the mountam.
Marvel Bass. Dean's favorite. Leader in the never- wear-your_
own_ clothe~,,,, W: hen- you- can- borrow- movement. Also
slow eater. Saturday is a gloomy day without soup.
W. Bruce Overton- Also slow eater; mighty speed de&#173;mon,
Mr. Belcher can almost beat him to town. &#183; Drinks water
soaked on a beer barrel stove. Runs sewing machine as a side
line. Has a de luxe twist to his bone rolling propensity.
John C. Cook- Great Latin enthusiast- Prefers maidens
fair with curly hair? Slow eater also. Great hunter, his gun
went off unexpectedly and scared a dove. Fishes in the rain
barrel and catches wiggletails. Has traveled widely- to Mc&#173;Kenzie.
Vera Ray- Most dignified member of the class. One of
the faculty favorites. Staunches. tadvocate of Einstein's The&#173;ory
of Relativity at M. T. N.
Elizabeth Grigsby, " Get Elizabeth to ask, she'll be sure
to get it." Craves winning as many medals as Windrow. Not
agraid of mice. Her interest in school activities never fags.
Cyrus Dement needs no introduction, for who has not
heard of his trip to Chattanooga and his sojourn in Porto Rico.
Prime mover in all interesting - dormitory activities.
Mrs. Rowe has the best mannered children we know. As-
pires to excel Jane Fale's noted work, " Dressmaking."
David Manier has an ambition to sell soap and candles.
( Good boot- Iegger. s never partake of their own products.)
Would wear red neck ties if he weren't so green. Has weak&#173;ness
for small white cubes with polka dots.
Hester Rogers- Her hobby is to dig deep and breeze in
with a beam of satisfaction on her face. Nobody will be sur&#173;prised
to hear of her in an artist's colony at Montmortre.
Fred Arnold loves Greek onions stewed with Dago pear
peels. Stands on one foot to keep from wearing both shoes
out. Frizzles his hair at night. Almost killed a June bug one
day while practicing on an Hibernian kettle- drum.
. Mrs. T. E. Clark- Wants to own her own home. Very
old- fashioned, has been seen walking across the campus with
her husband!
T. E. Clark holds the record for making announcem'ents.
No meal at the dining hall is really substantial or complete
without some of them.
Lela McDaniel- Her only sorrow is that M. T. N. doesn't
offer sufficient education for her to major. Yearns to dispel
ignbrance in Texas.
John Edwin Windrow: Loves cats. Cats are very fond &#183;
of him. Carries a feline suitcase. This catty occurrence won
him much popularity. Must win more medals than Elizabeth.
Writes salty water poems. Chews Battle Axe tobacco.
Margaret Watson- Educated, at last, begosh! Lives for
Tuesday afternoons and literary society. Be sure to read her
" Why Girls Wear Hair Nets that Do Not Match."
H. C. Brier- We really expect to find him in Who's Who
It was whispered once that he had great ego but it is known
now to be only an idle tale.
Robt. Liggett has a heart like an antique goose egg boil&#173;ed
in a solution of evaporated molasses. Buys hair and sells
patent whiskers. Has an ambition to out Pader- Paderewski.
Sings alto with a voice like a sick cat persecuted by an over&#173;grown
bull pup.
Jessie Lowe- Nothing, absolutely nothing, ruffles her
calm exterior. To see her, is to see her trusty Cremona too.
BE A BOOSTER .
7 THE NORMALITE
Boost your city, boost your friend
Boost the school that you attend
Boost the place where you are dwelling
Boost the goods the Y. W. is selling.
Boost your friends, boost your rieighbor
It will help to lighten labor.
Boost for every forward movement
Boost for every new improvement
Cease to be a progress blocker.
If you wish to make The NORMALITE better
Boost it to the final letter.
- MARVEL BASS.
FEATHERTOP'S BROTHER
come out ahead but she comes out in a Ford.
people may ' La f . J Woodson- Moffitt House mascot. ver 0 rhe oe .. d
doughnuts. Has seen two shootmg stars, one rna -
Pilot Knob, and Flat Rock.
Heard in the Hall
verna Eason- Say Geraldine, how do you like Walt Whit-
1 &#183; Geraldine Grigsby- Like him! 1 don't even know him.
en did he come?
( Continued from the March issue)
I was wasted in form; my spirit was bapdzed in the low&#173;er
current of despair; my folks and friends were alarmed at
my condition; but, I went to bed that night with a firm de&#173;termination
to make it known the next morning.
I arose early, dressed, and went into the dining room to
find that mother had sent for a doctor. That would not do
for I knew a doctor would ask me a thousand questions; and
I had resolved that no ot, her " outsider" should know anything
about it. I stole out at the back door; went to the station,
and took a train to Jackson, Tennessee where the minister,
THE NORMALITE 6
who wrote the letter, now lived. To my surprise, I met Mr.
Roscoe Layton who was formerly a resident of my homc5
town. I made known to him my business; namely, that I
wanted to see Rev. Thomas of the Baptist Church on E. Ches-'
ter. He told me that Mr. Thomas was away for the week&#173;end.
I ' accepted Mr. Laton's invitation to spend the night
with him and fill an engagement with ' so'ine young ladies with
whom he had already made arrangements for himself and any
friend of his young men friends whom he might choos~.
I had fully resolved that I keep all letters and recommen&#173;dations
out of this affair. But, as we all know a fellow can&#173;not
always do as he wishes. To hasten the conclusion, we
met the young ladies at the appointed hour. I had spent the
most care- free hour in forty days when suddenly there was a
rap on the door. Miss Horton, one of the young ladies, open&#173;ed
the door. She jumped back with a shudder, for there stood
her father with a shot gun. Besi~ e him stood a young man,
a lover of her's. They wished to speak to me. This young
man with Mr. Horton knew me in the army and all about my
misfortunes. He was the rascal who had betrayed' me. I
looked for a way of escape, but there was none; I must meet
my fate. I shrugged my shoulders, took a deep breath, mus&#173;tered
up all the courage possible, and tottered out of the
room. They conducted me into an adjoining room and talked
in an undertone a minute before Mr. Horton asked me for the
letter which I quickly gave him. While reading it, his face
which was usually as cold and as unchangeable as a marble
statue, softened somewwhat. Though he seemed bewildered,
his attitude had changed. He handed it to the young man
who read it, threw it down with an oath; and exclaimed, " He
is a liar, that is not the one." He twitched the container from
my hand, looked through it, withdrew another one, and read
it. Handing it to Mr. Horton, he said, ' This is the one, I told
you so." A glance at it was enough to convince me that I
had never seen it before. I saw through it all now. I - must
explain.
But I could not explain for a minute, no matter how hard
pressing were the circumstances. I felt too much release, I
8 THZ NORMALITE THE NORMALITE
h
I J'umped and shouted, " Hurrah! hurrah!"
tOO apPY' .
h d
me at last and the JOY of success was supreme.
ory lad Icohelp but s'hout- when such a load had vanished
CloU ' ped away like a mighty wave of the ocean would
"' WlIDf':. lOOefn ay, tWeaIr. It seemed that the bars of hell, were broken
,,"'~ t:~"' lUld'erand heaven and earth wer. e united to drown the sor-s
of a wreck. "'. , ..'
' I shouts aroused the family who rushed in ImmedIately
~ YJ. y I . . b
what was wrong. I gave the exp anatlOn, In su stance,
o see I .. d M
as follows: The night before. I left for cam~ VISlt~ r.
ThOJIlas' home. Through a ' I1llstake, I left thIS contaIner at
is home. It was one that my grandfather left in the pos&#173;session
of my father. It was made especially to keep import&#173;ant
documents in. It was made it} Germany 1812, and on the
bottom side, strange it seems, grandfather's initials were en&#173;gaved
in silver. The initials on the under side, gave the bot-om
side the appearance of the topside to a stranger. Sa it
as that a stranger would always look in the bottom part
which was quite natural because it looked to him to be the
Ope This explains why it was they forever got the wrong
letter, and why it was they would put it back where they got
it. I always kept my certificates, school warrants , and other
valuable papers in the top side and therefore never opened
the bottom part which I had no need of. When Mr. Thomas
sent me the letter of recommendation he put it in the top
where I found it. But he had also been using the bottom,
and in it he had placed a carbon copy of a letter that he had
written to a judge of a circuit court It was a short history
of a bank robber who had committed murder. It started out,
. c'To Whom This May Concern ~ this man, etc. It
used no names. This explanation was accepted by the people
present. The two gentlemen apologized for the way they had
done and I made haste to go home and explain.
The End
- ICHABOD IRVING.
Philip-" Thinking much about the term exams?"
Carl B;-" Oh, I take a passing interest in them."
' Twas a long time ago on a bright summer day,
I went out walking in a pretty field of hay.
The birds and the bees were humming a tune
And I began to drea'm ' twas the dear old month of June.
As I wandered onward by a brook
I saw ' most concealed a half- opened book
By' a quick glance that in August of 1923
Maye Leming would be Mrs. Dance of Normandy, Tenn.
I heard that Misses Daniels, Davidson, Demombrie and
Flegal
Had become very skilled in the use of the needle.
They owned a millinery - shop ona California street
And by a quick glance I saw that it was neat.
THE NORMALITE 11
I noticed in the paper where Gatis, Grigsby, Gilbert and
Gresham
Had become very famous in their beloved professions.
Each of them had always had sympathetic hearts
And as gentle nurses they were doing their part.
Ada Johnson had become a " Paris swell"
Because she had learned to design so well.
On I wandered through lane an~ dell
And I learned that Hortense was doing well.
She was planning meals by chance or fate
For the insane asylum of New York State.
Marjorie Oark- the little, but loud
I found addressing a very large crow. d;
The title, or subject I could not learn,
But she wanted a patent on her new style churn.
I
.,
&gt; 4 THE HOME EC. CLUB
Along educational lines we're doing our best,
Louise gave a talk on " The Psychology of Dress."
In the last number most of us learned our fate
For the Hom Ec. prophecy was something great.
If this prophecy you wish to hear
In the following lines it will appear:
THE NORMALITE
Prophecy of The Home Ec. Club
Our last program on April the fifth
Certainly did give the Club a lift.
The girls appeared without fright
And as a male quartet " they were a sight"
The music was rendered by the jolly four
Paul, Glyndon, Vera and no more.
Stop! Look I Listen I Proclamation,
The girls of the Home Ec. Club will lead the nation
The Home Ec. Club is still on the go,
The programs are anything but slow.
10
So plain could I see as if it was before my eyes
A little " Ford"- what a surprise I
And I learned that it belonged to Elizabeth Akin.
On a large building hung Lila Bostick's name,
By sewing so well she had won her fame.
Pearl Beasly had decided to sell wraps;
But most of all she preferred to sell " Capps."
Emma and Katie Byrom did not feel stranded
For Pharris and Lewis they had safely landed.
Miss Little had always thought it proper to primp
And after gaining public consent
She engaged helpers that called people shrimps
Who would not patronize her beauty parlor on 6th North
Flint.
As my mind wandered in another direction
I learned that Glyndon Waite had attained perfection
In teaching penmanship and art. .
The subjects which were always nearest her heart.
13 THE NORMALITE
. f h r were a tyrant unendurable, when he
a'S if th~ a~ e uptible in the sight of his children; a
b aking lncorr h " D" de. h h love and sincerity, that t e lvme r g WIt sue, .
ru tn . h ld be a part of the very hearts of hIS
t" of that kmg s ou
i ects. M ther is a party t~ this treason. She not only
Too often
f 0 bedience during the absence of the father,
s to en orce 0 . . se es disobedience, by her aSSIstance In
dually encourag .' f
a. h f t that the children have mdulged In or-nceabng
t e ac . h ld
And what is worse, she sometimes 0 s
en pleasures. h
b f re the children as a sort of bad man, w ose
her up eo. d
. means the redress of every wrong commItte
e- commg . . f f
. h d and making that home- commg a time 0 ear 109 t e ay,
aread. .
I thank God and my mother that she has never, for one
e, made my father's home- coming a thing of fea:. Instead
was an occasion joyous. And happy was the chtld whos. e
J{ J~~~= rivilege it was to bring him a drink of fresh water, or . to SIt
ext him at the table. For was this not the home- commg of
king' a king who had gone out to battle with the earth,
ture,' and the sky for the ' maintenance of his kindon:? Tru-y
it was a small kingdom; but he who rules a small k: ngdom
. e 1, is greater than he who rules a billion souls unWIsely.
But the most deplorable feature of this treason is the fact
that in the form of literature, art, and music, it is being pass&#173;ed
on into the hands of numberless generations, yet unborn.
e poet, the artist, and the musician are tireless in their
' se of mother- and justly so. For if every tongue, every
' paint brush, every pen, and every instrument of music should
ndeavor to tell all the wond'ers of mother- love, and if the
ifort should be carried on through endless eternity, too much
could never be said. Yet there is another love, which holds
the same claim: over the hearts of man, a love, which, though
may be a little different in its form of expression, and per&#173;ps
not so artistic or poetical, yet is just as broa~ and deep
: a8 the mother- love. This so great love is the love of a fath&#173;r
for his child. And high art is entirely indifferent to this
THE TREASON OF SOCIETY
The Home Ec. Club of M. T. N.
Was getting much praise from the author's pen
Not entirely by genius, although it had a part
" Cooking and sewing had become an art.
THE NORMALITE
Gracilee Templeton because of a stubborn will
Had never been able to decide " which Bill;"
Therefore she was living in turmoil and strife
But she said she would like "' Buttermilk" all of her life..
I was pleased in my wanderings far and wide
Of some old school friends to hear good tide,
Later I was aroused from my reveries and dreams,
And I found that life is not always what it seems.
- MARVEL BASS.
I learned in a very peculiar way
That Miss Williams had gone to Europe to stay;
She had married a millionaire of fame,
But I never was able to find out his name.
Since freeing itself from the clutches of paternal wor- &#173;ship,
society has swung to the opposite extreme, and is now
in open treason against the fathers. In all too many homes, &#173;father
is a fallen king; a king who must be tolerated for the
sake of paying the bills, but not a king to be obeyed and hon&#173;ored
and loved; a king who is- suppose" dly- attractive to the
office girls, but not one who has the confidence of his own
family. Instead he is looked upon with suspicion and dread
and fear only.
This fact is displayed most forcefully by the conversa&#173;tion
of the present generation. How often we hear some
youngster- important in his own estimation- speak in the
most sacrilegious terms of, " The Old Man," who has forbid&#173;den
some coveted pleasure, or of, " Putting it over on Dad,'"
ROUTINE OF A STUDENT AT M. T. N.
To get an- Education,
See the bursar- pay- Registration,
Visit the registrar- this is- Matriculation
There you'll use- Expostulation,
Or a little of your- Argumentation,
Nothing gained by your- Explanation,
There comes a period of- Exasperation,
After which follows- Rumination,
Better known as- Meditation,
No time left for- Recreation,
Then you begin- Procrastination.
But alas! we hear the- Proclamation,
Today we'll have an- Examination
After it you'll hear- Lamentation
Which is caused from- " Flunk- a- tion." "
love, or else devotes itself to the ridicule of this pOwerful
force.
Of course it is not for one moment to be supposed that
these three forms of art should be less profuse in their trib&#173;ute
to mothers, but why not use the energy, now being wast&#173;ed
on trivial and demoralizing subj ects in filling picture gal&#173;leries
and libraries with pictures and books in tribut~ to fath&#173;ers,
and in filling the earth with music in his vraise?
Would it not be better still to combine these two great
streams of love, so that, instead of two streams separate and
distinct, we should have one great river of paternal praise, as
broad as the earth, as deep as the ocean, and as high as the
heavens, flowing onward, ever onward, that generation after
generation might partake of its wholesome waters, aDd be
lifted to a higher, purer and nobler plane of life?
With the exception of my immortal soul and my priceless
life, gladly and with a shout of triumph, would I give any
possession I call my own, that I might be endowed with a gift
of poetical talent. Then I should spend that gift in a cease &#183;
less effort to fill the universe with praise of- not mother only
but of both father and mother. For are they not one in&#173;separable?
Thus I should be the happy instrument in aveng &#183;
ing this so great treason of society against father.
.. - oRA TODD.
PEPYS UP TO DATE
THE NO! WALITE 15
WORLD POLITY CLUB
Lay late ruminating on this and that until I've
remembered that the doors of our dining hall
would be verily locked in my face, did I not
haste.
To worship, where I had great difficulty to
keep my ' mind on the learned discourse, for ob-
World Polity Club which was organized at th. e be-e
of the sch00I year with a three- fold p. urpo. se; VIZ, an
. t study world affairs; a SOCial aim to meet
tual aim 0 d b
r and dI &#183; cuSss t. he results of that stu. dy; an a enev-
al. m. to render service wherever ne. ed . IS found, has prov-ost
helpful and successfur orgamzatlOn.
e members have drawn back the curtains of France,
oy, RUSS. la, th. e Balkan States., and'Greece and Romhe,
ve invited us to become acquamted with the geograp -
political, and educational conditions.; to listen to the mu&#173;and
literature; to ga: ze upon the FI~ e ~ rts; to learn of
development in the religious and sClenttfic fields; . and to
a social hour with the people of all these countnes.
When President Brackin, the dreamer and promoter of
Cub left we felt it as a great cala &#183; mity, but the Fates
wi; h us in securing Mr. C. C. Sims for President, who
brown himself into the work and kept the " old pep" from
iog. We feel that much of our success is due to these
I presidents.
1&#163; you weren't a club member this year you have missed
c of the best M. T. N. affords, but when you return next
r t~ y to make amends by making it your business to line
ith the folks who are enjoying not .; mly America but the
World as well and exclaiming in one voice:
" It is good to be here."
- EMMA BECTON, Secretary.
14 THE NORMALrrE
. l1 nt in Sam's face for talking so long to Glad- !! au .
ys at the dining hall steps after the evemng
repast . Must needs cut my hair and pluck my
brows again. They grow so fast.
Verily I did all but burst my sides today with
laughing when a lass lost a silken skirt of Lin&#173;coln
green hard by the Post Office door. I was
so filled with mirth, I could not assist the poor
child recover her fallen property, but scaped
hurriedly to Mr. Holmes' office to regain my
composure.
Domine Sims did this day in the library cre&#173;ate
a lively commotion. Some prankish youth
did put upon a chair a fair sized piece of ice.
Our domine sat thereon unbeknownst but quick,..
ly did get up- and all youths and maidens wer~
convulsed with laughter, at witnessing such a
treat; nor could all Dame Murfree's best frowns
quell the stir. . p..~
Again to the library at the fifth period. Did
purpose' to peruse parallels but Mi'stress Odie
Davidson at my right and Mistress Pearl Beas &#183; &#173;ley
at my left chewed gum so violently I was
force~ to find comfort in Life. There was none,
so I did stroll the halls, and most opportunely,
too, for I did rescue Sam from the wiles of that
creature, Gladys. In these times men seem so
easily vamped! I do marvel that Sa'm should
find her of interest! A plague of maesles in all
the dormitories. In truth it seems that many
do come to Normal on purpose to get the
plague!
To the village, it being Saturday, to purchase
hair nets and tooth paste. In a great rush to
finish in time to arrive for the screen perform&#173;ance.
Preceded George and Louise full two
hours. They came to see but for most part did
It'
March 26
Thursday,
March 29
THE NORMALITE
serving how Jiggs and Vashti do never rest
from making eyes and sweet speech.
Sam did come by at Vesper where we ShoUld
have passed . a pleasant hour but for Dame Rut.
ledge who nght sharply did chaperone us.
N. ot having food for supper, I did hail the boys
gomg to the Boulevard store. On their return
they brought sandwiches , and cake which I did
haul up , by a string I had first let down with my
Algebra attached thereto. Lord fend that the
Council did not discover me or I shall be vilely
campused. &#183; -
Up betimes and beset by washerwoman for
old clothes to sell. Did part with my favorite
blue sweater and two plaid skirts, hoping for
gain thereby. My poor rags are of no use once I
discard them. Bestirred myself with so much en&#173;ergy
that did arrive for the Amen of the Doxol&#173;ogy!
At great loss for my Algebra which that
Sam forgot to tie again to the string last night
and I did discover it this morning soaked with
dew. Fortunately I was not questioned at class
or I should have displ'ayed gr. eat ignorance
thereof.
All the teachers in their usual Monday humor
which is enough to drive one wild, were it not
for more pressing matters; Sam having " lately
developed a liking for that wench, Gladys.
A test in English in which I hope I did not
do so badly, though the Lord knows where
Mrs. Fertig got those questions- nor do I know
where I got the answers! To chapel where I
did yawn more than usual and groan aloud at
Mistress Saunders' exhortations. Verily I have
counted the seats in the three rows 365 times
for lack of something to think about. An epis&#173;tle
by special post from William which 1 did
~~ r ...-:.'
THE NORMALITE 17
speak angry words. Both carried divers b
dIes. Un~
April 10 Up and late to breakfast for reason th
h' h at tny w Ite ose put to dry last night by the d'
f 11 ra Iator
e down where I did find them- drip .
.. pmg Wet
at the last bell. Dressmg with all m
d ". y speed
da~ . pmnhm
l
g my mIddy as I ran did get me to the
m~ ng a I but to find the door locked. My
patIence was sore tried by reason of thO IS.
April 14 Abroad early. Did see many teachers tr th
locke. d doors of the dining hall, all right a: gr;
that It was locked full 12 minutes early M - . any
did laugh and giggle thereat. My own lock
out was too recent for me to be joyed.
In the library at the second period and read
with great speed " Gammer Gurton's Needle"
1-&#163;" --' played by strolling actors most admirably to a
crowded house in the afternoon.
At night to chapel early to see " The Imag&#173;inary
Invalid" made by Moliere and played by
the same actors. It is the most entire piece of
mirth, a complete farce from one end to the
other that certainly was ever writ. I never
, laughed so in all my life and at very good wit
there in, my fooling. The house full , and in all
things of mighty content to me.
April 16 News abroad of more plus and minus tests.
Verily I am nearly hectored out of my wits.
Also rumors of a print sale or a May Fair to be
held this coming month.
After study bell one of those nosy Council
Members appearing suddenly at my neighbor's
door did quickly scramble under the bed and to
the Closet without being found out. All ' up and
down the campus many people newly come out
after the measles.
April 17 To chapel and regaled for more than usual
at the most embodiment of precocity that ever
I did see. A wee damsel not yet seven, one
Dodo Reid, who knows all the capitals of all the
countries of all the earth and rivers and moun&#173;tains
thereof; even the twenty- nine presidents
and Ten Commandments and the Beatitudes!
The child's father did offer goodly pay for a
governess and we all are in a great ferment to
know who will be chosen; it being whispered
that Azilee Parks is thought of.
News of Hawaiian Troupe to be at chapel did
fill every seat. Profound silence then smother&#173;ed
laughter at seeing not, Hawaiians and musi~
cal instruments, but' an uncommonly small
brown man follow Mr. Lyon to the stage. Dis&#173;appointment
at no music gave way to surprise
that one of another race could talk so well.
./ To Grey Cottage ostensibly to delivevr a les&#173;son
plan but really to learn the cause of such
apparent merry making. Found the teachers
all engaged making candy and setting the house
on fire with canned heat and putting it out
again. Forgot to leave my lesson plan so had
to go again when the candy was just being pass &#183;
ed around. '
Did hear of a mighty stir in the boy's dormi&#173;tory
at one Paul Burton's being put full clad
from necktie to tennis shoes and even a racket,
into a tub of cold water!
Our dormitory alive with brooms and mops
and dusters and hair washings. Did ~ ot fare
forth to town, there being these Smyrna test
papers to grade, but sent by Grace for various
sundries which she did not get in her mad haste
to return ere five o'clock. Did hear that George
was seen with only one bundle, which he vainly
sought to cover up, during his weekly joint
shopping tour with Louise.
Lord's Day. Many to church. No hike. Ves-
18 THE NORMALITE THE NORMALITE 19
In the cold dark hours of mystic night
The great Ruler of Heaven came forth,
The wings of a raging storm He rode&#173;What
then of my fancied worth!
" The world is mine and the wealth thereof
To conquer or squander at will"
I said, vain thoughts possessing my soul
With ponderous power enraptured still.
My thoughts were haughty, and bold and vain,
As I viewed the achievements of men,
And my heart beat high with arrogant pride
Nor considered its burden of, sin.
21
Who is the best friend you have in this world?
Is it a woman or is it a girl?
In this world of grief and joy,
Is it a man or is it a boy?
' Tis Mother.
MOTHER
THE NORMALITE
When a boy leaves home his fortune to seek,
To whom does he write home every week?
Whether he meets with failure or success,
Is it not the one whom he loves the best?
Mother.
When a , man's reputation has been lost,
When men pass him by with looks cold as frost,
When he down to the dogs has been,
Has he not still one true friend?
Yes, Mother.
Do you not find this to be the case
In every people and every race?
To whom does your baby brother go,
With all his trouble and all his woe?
' Tis Mother.
THE STORM
THE NORMALITE
per on the green where m~ ny did live through
it to stroll about and eat ice cream afterwards.
Sages down from Peabody who do seek full
information regarding our school, even to the
ages of the faculty women, which I fear they
must live on in ignorance of. . Verily I do wish
they would give these fiendish intelligence tests
to all the faculty and publish their 1. Q's!
April 25
Fierce lightnings flashed through the tortured sky
And thunder rolled like the drums of war;
The great trees bowed their stately heads
And the wild things fled, the storm before.
Gone was conceit, my arrogant pride,
Trembling I fell to the lowly sod,
From out the wild storm a calm, sweet voice
Spoke-" Be still, and know that I am God."
- BELL.
Hatley says violators of law should be Gillentined.
So gentle readers heed these words well
For there's one thing certain you can never tell,
When from you this best friend must pass
So love her best until the last.
Your Mother!
- W. B. GREEN.
May every page before you
Give way to thoughts of nice things you may do,
And as you read this number of the Normalite through,
Bring a greeting glad and true,
From those who wish joy to you.- Ethel.
Last eV'ening after returning from the theatre I entered
the dining room and on the table I found ham sandwiches
piCkles, fruits, and caridy. After a bountiful repast I retired'
feeling very much refreshed, and while I was in this sleep:
came dreams, yes, wonderful dreams. I seemed to be on a
tour of Northern cities.
In walking down one of the most popular thoroughfares
in Washington, D. c., I had the misfortune of stepping upon
a banana peel, with the usual result.
As I was in this position, a rather undignified one, I fear,
a gentleman, wearing a tall silk hat, monocle, patent leather
pumps, and carrying a cane approached, and in a cultured
sweet voice, asked if he might assist me in getting back to
my former position. I thanked him, and after straightening
my hat and brushing from my suit some of the dust and dirt,
I took the second look at my most kind benefactor. There
in the middle of the street in Washington, D. c., I met Mr.
Belcher, of M. T. N. I was so surprised and shocked, I could
hardly regain my speaking ability; but finally, I returned with
renewed energy.
After a very formal greeting, any other kind except
strictly formal I asked him what he was doing and where he
was going.
He replied that he was an instructor of Physiology and
Sociology in Wsahington Seminary, and that he was on his
way to school at this time, and would be more than delighted
to have me accompany him. As I was in Washington for an
entire day en route to Boston and other points, I felt, I might
just as well see how things were with Prof. Belcher.
As we walked he told me of the whereabouts of several
members of the 1923 faculty of M. T. N. He asked me if I
remembered a man called Mr. Sims, the instructor of History,
" Whose mind to him, an Empire was?" It seemed that Pro&#173;fessor
Belcher in returning from abroad where he had be&#173;come
the proud possessor of the Ph. D. which he now carried
in a small leather satchel, had met Mr. Sims in New York,
THE NORMALITE 23
where he was preparing to become a foreign mlsslOnary to
Korea. He aiso told me of Mrs. Gillentine and Miss Little.
Mrs. Gillentine he had seen only a few days be.~ ore on her
way to Tampa, Florida, for her health. She only weighed
about ninety pounds and her health was very much impaired.
Miss Little, I learned, had gone into the movie" s and was play&#173;ing
opposite " Douglas Fairbanks." By. this time we had ar&#173;rived
at the famous Washington Seminary for girls. The first
class was in Physiology with perhaps fifty or sixty students.
They entered, took their. places and answered the roll call
without speaking a word. Could this be true, had Professor
Belcher forgotten his old proverb, " Too much talking in the
class?" Where had he l~ arned such discipline? But you see
by this time, he was quite a bit older, he even had a mustache,
but the permanent wave was still doing its duty. As I was
eaving on the four- twenty train for Boston I had to make
v departure.
As I entered the observation car in the depot some one
ooked at me over two celluloid rims of spectacles . This
proved to be Miss Fontaine, but no longer a Miss for she had
married one of her own rank and they were devoting their
lives to the developing of the young minds of the children in
lower New York. She insisted that I spend my first night in
Boston with her and her husband who were for the time be&#173;ing
staying there. I gladly accepted the invitation for I knew
no one in Boston and felt quite relieved at having m~ t some
one I ~ new. That evening we decided to attend the Ringling
Brothers Circus, and here came th surprise of my young life.
For, &#183; there all clad in pink skirts was Miss : Monohan, the most
accomplished of rope walkers. I could not believe my eyes
but facts had to be faced. I left Boston about noon the fol&#173;lowing
day for New York. Arriving there, I went straight
to the Waldorf where I was to meet some friends. Great ex&#173;citement
and music could be heard, as there was a debut
dance on hand. Just as I left the elevator, there standing
ready to descend was a dream girl, in white satin, pearls and
lace. At &#183; first, her face was not visible, hidden behind a tur&#173;quoise.
ostrich fan, but just then she turned and I stood face
THE NORMALITE
POSSIBILITIES
22
to face with Lila aostick. Lila had just returned from the
" CaStle on the Hudson."
While in New' York I had the pleasure of driving out to
. the convent of the Sacred Heart, for chapel. Here it was
that I found Miss Saunders. I was rather surprised but one
can never tell what time will bring. Later in the day I pick&#173;ed
up the New York Times and there in flaming letters this
announcement:
" W. T. Wynn, a second Caruso will sing tonight at the
Metropolitan Opera Home." I think this very nearly waked
me from my dream but the powers that were, had not willed
it so. I was still to dream.
Early the next morning, I went out far before the city
was astir, and in one of the parks met Mr. Frazier, out riding
on " Frier Charges." You can't imagine how natural he look&#173;ed.
He now occupied the chair of Engli~ h in Columbia Uni&#173;versity.
I had walked farther than I expected and it was getting
rather late in the morning when I returned.
As I walked along taking little note of what was happen&#173;ing
around me, suddenly I realized that I was in the midst of
a crowd around a platform. \ I knew, it was some advertise&#173;ment
for some patent medicine. I thought I would walk up
and see what the fellow had to say. They had such an amus&#173;ing
line; memorized and rendered so well. My first glance
showed me just the head and shoulders of a man- and such
shoulders. They seemed almost four feet wide. Such a phy&#173;sique
I had never seen. The man looked as if he might weigh
two hundred pounds. I thought his voice had a fa&#173;miliar
sound. I looked into the smiling countenance of our
friend, Mr. Lyon, selling Tanlac. This was too much for me,
I rolled out of bed, bumped my head on a rocking chair, awoke
and found I had only been dreaming.
- ELIZABETH AKIN 23'
PRACTICE TEACHING
WHY I TEACH
THE NORMALITE
Because I would be wise and wisdom find
From millions gone before whose torch I pass
Still burning bright to light the paths that wind
So steep and rugged, for each lad and lass
Slow- climbing to the unrevealed above,
I teach.
Because I know that when life's end I reach
And thence pass through the gate so wide and deep
To what I do not know, save what men TEACH,
That the remembrance of me men will keep
Is what I've done; and what I have is naught,
I teach.
Because in passing on the living flame
That ever brighter burns the ages through,
I have done service that is worth the name
Can I but say, " The flame of knowledge grew
A little brighter in the hands I taught,"
I teach.
By Louis Burton Woodward
( State Normal, Gorham, Me.
Because I would be young in soul and mind
Though years must pass and age my life constrain,
And I have found no way to lag behind
The fleeting years, save by the magic chain
That. binds me, youthful, to the youth I love,
I teach.
24 THE NORMALITE .-: ., ...... .. '" -" ;. ~ ... ."
Operator-" The party doesn't answer.'
Stewed-" Yesh, I know the party ish over, what, I want
ish the ambulance."
Several years ago when I came to the Middle Tennessee
Normal the bug- bear of the institution, the bone of conten&#173;tion
in every senior's eye, was practice teaching. This or&#173;deal,
I was told, was to be passed through by everyone, be-
- ONE WHO KNOWS.
fore receiving any kind of diploma. Of course hearing such
talk from those who had experienced it, I concluded that it
must be the most trying, nerve racking procedure that any
one had ever passed through.
Naturally, when I began teaching a few months ago, I
was frightened almost to death, and had no idea what kind of
tortures the critic teacher would inflict. Howev~ r, after teach&#173;ing
a few weeks I found that I had entirely the wrong con&#173;ception
of the critic teacher, and of student teaching in gen&#173;eral.
I had gained this false impression from the talk of for&#173;mer
students .
I think this department receives the most unjust criti&#173;cism
and abusement of any other department in the institu&#173;tion.
Instead of the horrible experiences I had imagined, I
found the most pleasant surroundings, - and discovered tEe
most delightful course of work possible.
The supervisor, or socalled critic teacher, does not put
herself upon a pedestal entirely out of the reC'. 1m of the stu&#173;dent
teachers, as' I had imagined, but makes herself one of
them. Her sympathy, patience, advice, and endurance is
something wonderful, and can be appreciated only by those
who have enjoyed Education VII or XIII.
Sometimes we may think her criticism' a bit harsh, but
we should remember all this is for our future good, and smile
and forget. This term of student teaching is not, and should
not be considered, a task, or three month's of torture, but
should be considered a pleasure, and an opportunity to put in
practice the wonderful methods learned at M. T. N. I hope
this article may help to eradicate the general false impression
of practice teaching that has been given by former students,
and cause the future students who are planning to do this
work to turn a deaf ear to those who tell them this course
is a drudgery.
Possibly many have received higher grades than I, but
surely no one has ever received more real enjoyment from
the course.
They love to sing and dance and play:
But what about their classes,
Just so their grade is high enough
To give them all their passes.
The girls do try to look so nice
With powder on their faces,
But listen, boys, take my advice,
And don't forget your places.
Of these two boats, thus guided
THE NORMAi. ITE
SUCCESS
The idle and indifferent,
Will, with the current ride,
But heroes in life's battle
Will pull against the tide.
I wonder if in future years
They'll still keep dancing on?
Or, will they reap in bitter tears
The tares which they have sown.
The school room is our training place,
In which we rise or fall
Though some regard it as a place
Of picnic or a ball.
Time is precious while it passes,
Waste it not in Folly's ways:
' Tis the boon of lads and lassies
Striving for still better days.
Do you want to be a sailor,
On the trobuled sea of Life?
Just launch your boat and venture
' Midst its terrors, storms and strife.
26 THE NORMALITE
Address all communications to Business Manager. Advertising rates
furnishen 11' 10n request.
Published Monthly by the students of Middle Tennessee Normal, Mur&#173;freesboro,
Tennessee
Appli~ ation ~ nade for entry as second- class matter at the Post~ ffice at
Murfreesboro, Tenn., under Act of Cong~ ess, March 3, 18/ 9
THE NORMALITE 29
Business Staff
CARL E. BRANDON . .__..__. . Business Manager
MILDRED RIDLEY . ..... ._._. Associate Business ~ 1anager
W. T. WYNN . ...__. . Faculty Adviser
Editorial Staff
CYRUS DEI\ 1ENT -..-._ _ _.. .__ ._..__ Editor- in- Chief
ELIZABETH GRIGSBY _ __._..__.__ Associate Editor- in- Chief
E. P . EAVES _. ._.._ . ._ _ __.. Athletics
ROBERT PARTIN .. . .._..__ _ _ Y. M. C. A.
MARGARET WATSON _. .._~ --..- - -.--.-.-.-- Faculty
HANNAH GRAHAM BELCHER .__..__.. _ _. Locals, Fun
T. E. CLARK . ~ ..__._ --..----- -- Societies, Lyceum
MARY HILL KING .__ ..__..__..__ _. .__._. ._ _ Exchange
LOUISE McKNIGHT _ __._. ._ __ __.__ _ __.__ A1umni
GERALDINE GRIGSBY _.. ._ Y. W. C. A., Glee Club
THE NORMAUTE
OPTIMISM
On which do you now sail?
Or, have you yet decided
To reap success, or fail?
But if we well have done our part
What care we for the weather?
We'll climb the -~ slopes and gain our hopes
And all succeed together.
- FRANKIE MELSON.
So let's enjoy our school days
Relieved of doubts and fears:
And make them happy rule daYJ
For future happy years.
Among the specimens of lettering done by the Art class
and included in the exhibit that won the prize at the State
Fair , is an artistic copy of Herrick's " Gather Ye Rosebuds
While Ye May," the last verse of which reads:
" Then be not coy, but use your time,
And while ye may, go marry,
For having lost but once your prime,
Ye may forever tarry."
Upon reading the above, a lady of the faculty, one of the
younger members who has not yet " given up the pursuit"
could not resist adding Tennyson's
" But while there's life, there's hope they say,
vVe may be happy yet."
";;*... :,. v
And now, my friends, my verses end,
But let us all remember
That summer's noon is passing soon
And then comes bleak December.
He-" Do you go to college?"
She-" No, I'm not that kind of a girl."- Lord Jeff.
As the last issue of The NORMALITE went to press the
edidtor- in- chief included in its contributions a very interest-
ing and needful article on the " Usefulness" of telling people
at M. T. N. how to turn in their contributions to the paper.
In this issue the associate- editor is going to turn the tables,
so to speak, and give you a short article on " Usefulness."
First may I call your attention to the way these words
are spelled . There is a big contrast between " less" and " ful"
of the two'words. So in meaning there is a big contrast. Let
us be of the " ful" type, rather than the " less" type. To do
this only requires being " Useful." Well- how can that be
done? Some one will ask. The answer is ever so easy. " Just
fit in where you are needed."
Granting that you will gladly receive suggestions, I am
going to offer a few. You are needed as a helper in the Stu&#173;dent
Activity Life of M. T. N.; this includes the classroom,
gymnasium, on the field and in chapel. While you are need&#173;ed
in all of these places, you are most needed in helping us to
put dear old M. T. N. on the map, as the best school paper on
the market. With this school backing us a 100 per cent and
sending in their contributions. as fast as we can read. them,
then our greatest wish and desire will be accomplished.
There are coming literary peaks within our walls, yet un&#173;discovered,
we are doing our best to help them discover them&#173;selves.
Can't you help also by your steady never failing en&#173;couragement?
That's usefuln~ ss of the best type.
let us adopt as our slogan " Usefulness." Then reap a harvest
of bountiful results.
I have said these things in this last issue principally to
encourage you not to waste precious m'oments during the
~ ummer months. There will be so many opportunities for you
i: O write " Useful" articles for the Normalite next year.
As we look over criticisms of our paper, during the past
year, we know that our efforts have been successful. The
contrihutions have been good and the student body at large
have supported the Norm'alite. But don't let us stop with
that, nothing short of the best paper on the market will bring
happiness to those interested in its welfare.
With the above admonition we submit for your conside!"-
ation and approval this, the last issue of the NORMALITE,
for the current year.
The staff desires to thank every member of the school,
both faculty and students, who has so loyally co- operated and
assisted in the work of the year. It is through such co- oper&#173;ation
that it has been possible for the Normalite to be what
it has been. Benefited by the mistakes of this year and prof&#173;iting
by experience you should have such a magazine next
year as you have never had before.
We cheerfully resign the work to the new staff in the
full assurance that its efforts will be such that the work of
this year will be improved upon and that in the future we
shall be proud that our humble labor was not expended in
vain.
30 THE NORMALITE TH &#183; E NORMALITE
BEAUTIFUL S1 &#187; RINGTIME
Beautiful Spring, at last you're here!
Since last we met, it is a year.
It wakes the music in my soul
When nature's breast I now behold.
The sun pours forth its golden rays
Reflecting on us golden days.
Each flower in the flower bed
In early morn doth raise its head,
And smiles, and tries, to me it seems
To steal the kisses of sunbeans.
Each bud that's trying to wake from sleep
Is trying its best to get a peep.
The oriole and mocking bird
And nightingale's sweet thrills are heard.
Their songs could ones own soul entrance
They, themselves , are a romance.
These things do my dead soul revive
And make me glad that I'm alive.
- NELL HENDERSON.
Overton says he is not specializing in soap.
31
I :
, ..!
ti &#8226;
.. ~~.
Friday evening, March 30, members of the Glee Culb
participated in the program given at Hume- Fogg High School
during the Teachers Association. The Lady of Shalott was
given by the following girls with Mrs. Murphy as soloist,
and Miss E. May Saunders as pianist: Misses Eulalia San&#173;ders,
Elizabeth and Geraldine Grigsby, Mary Hurt, Hannah
Graham Belcher, Elizabeth Brigham, Mildred Shippey, Gladys
Bowling, Gladys and Azilee Parks, Gladys Cole and Ruth
Whorley.
Faust Waltz was given by the Double Quartet made up
of the following boys and girls: Misses Gladys Bowling,
Gladys Cole, Geraldine and EI~ zabeth Grigsby, Eulalia San&#173;ders,
Azilee Parks, Hannah Graham Belcher and Mildred
Shippey; ~ t{ essrs. J. S. Holmes, Cyrus Dement, W. B. Green,
Jack Bennett, Bobbie Burns, Frank Huff'man, Garland Smith
and Elliott Ford.
On the following Sunday which was Easter, under the di&#173;rection
of Mr. Carlton, both of the Glee Clubs with Miss E.
May Saunders as soprano soloist, Mr. Bertram Smith, as ten&#173;or
soloist, and Mr. S. Milton Cook, supervisor of Music in
the City Schools of Nashville, as baritone soloist gave, HThe
Seven Last Words of Christ.
The Glee Club has ~ one excellent work this year and you
will readily believe this when you hear the program which
the Glee Clubs will give Friday night, May 4. Some of the
THE NORMALITE 33
Cason says there is no difference between a mole and a
human. We don't get the comparison except with those in
love.
Relationship
School" ~ 1arm- HLittle ' man, what is your name?"
Small Boy- HPete Peterson, ma'am."
School Marm- HAnd how old are you, Pe~ er?"
Pete- HAy not know how old I bane."
School Marm- HWell, where were you born?"
Pete- HAy not born at all; ay got step- mutter."
We heard of a girl who committed suicide because she
looked so awful with bobbed hair. Some of the girls we know
eVidently don't own mirrors.
Student Teacher-" When I mention Georgia, what are
you reminded of?"
Floyd Wynn- HDaddy."
Dyer~" Can you tell me the distance between my ears."
Fite- HYes, one block."
Frank Huffman- HHow do you like my voice in compar&#173;ison
with Caruso's?"
Mrs. Gracey-" His is good, but yours is better still."
Femin~ m
The hand that moves the lip- stick is the hand that rules
the world.- Sun Dial.
numbers to be given are, The Lady of Shalott, Faust Waltz,
The Chambered Nautilus, From the Land of the Sky- Blue
Water, There's Ever a Song Somewhere, and Zingarese Ser&#173;enade
with a Gypsy Dance afterward.
Gallia is to be one of the Commencement numbers and
there is a vast amount of enjoyment ahead for all in the pro&#173;gram
to be given Commencement.
THE NORMALITE
Geraldine , Grigsby, Editor.
32
James-" WeU, Father, then you go and get it."
3S
Ford-" My career at the Normal is like an opera book."
C. M. Clark-" I11ustrated with cuts; I suppose."
1st Stude-" Burton is the stingiest man I ever knew."
2nd Stude- HI didn't know that."
1st Stude- HYes, he wouldn't even spend his vacation."
Mr. Davis-" Does the moon affect the tide?"
Verna-" No. Only the untied."
Mr. Davis-" James, go and fetch the old horse."
James-" Why the old one, Father?"
Mr. Davis- HWear out the old one first; that's my mot-
George B.- HDo you believe that marriages are made In
Heaven?"
Louise T.-" If all men were as slow as you they would
have to be."
A Bank's a Bank
Still she hesitated.
" You are poor," she argued, " while I have a million."
Springing forward impetuously, he gathered her to his
bosom.
" I will marry you," he cried, " for all that.- Widow.
We would like to know what becomes of the goods when.
a hole appears in our socks.
Ezra-" I didn't know this guy Samson was a cannibaL"
Ezma-" He wurnt."
Ezra-" Then why does this here program say ' Samson et
Delilah' ?"
THE NORMALITE
1I1arry a girl who is my intellectual inferior?"
Seagraves-" More than foolish- impossible."
THE NORMALITE
Douglas-" Do you think it wouldd be foolish for tne to
" Shay, d'you know Sham Shmith?"
" Whatsh hish name?"
" Whatch hish name? Who?"
Hannah Graham Belcher, Editor
J udge-" You were present when the fight started?"
Mandy- HYass- ah."
Judge- HAnd you got cut in the fracas?"
Mandy- HNo, sah, ah got cut in the arm.- Orange Owl.
H. J. Jones, Jr., ( looking at a Bible)-" What are all these
red letters?"
Dorothy H.-" They are what Christ said."
D. G.- HMy! but He was a big talker."
Bill collecting is a cinch- we all have a fine collection
of ' em.
WANTED- Light work to oc~ upy time while waiting to
to reach marriageable age.- Margaret Sims.
Is chapel held in the main building or in the boys' dor&#173;mitory?
The programs of the last few weeks have shown a de&#173;cided
improvem: ent which seems to indicate that we are in
tune with Doc Coue's often- quoted aphorism. Some of the
numbers which have been of especial interest were a stirring
declamation, " Spartacus to the Gladiators," by Clarence Dar&#173;nell;
a talk on the great operas of the world, with opera rec&#173;ords,
by Hubert Overall; and two subjects dear to the heart
of every normal student, " Who's Who on Open Nights?" and
" Spring and the Campus Course," by Ben Chrisman and Paul
Burton respectively.
. ' We believe that it is fundamental to include interest and
variety in our programs. We believe it is requisite to study
and discuss subjects around which centers the culture of an
educated man. We believe that we are united for a purpose,
that it is our duty to offer our members material which will
both entertain and profit them so that they may &#183; be richly re&#173;paid
for the time invested.
We are now preparing to complete our year's work. Our
debaters against the Claxtons for commencement week are
Paul Eayes and C. M. Clark. The play selected to be given
in collaboration with the Murfrees is " A Pair of Sixes." This
THE NORMALITE 37
is a play of unusual merit permeated with genuine humor
and motivated by a well- knit plot.
Standing at the threshold of our departure from this
year's work, we may now look back in retr~ spect. It is. an
irony of life that all things must pass; but thIS very tranSIen&#173;cy
in itself lends the charm to objects ~ nd conditio~ s under
its influence. We, the Gradies of 1923, wIll soon be dIsbanded.
We trust that our influence has not been for naught. We trust
that our society and school may have been made better by
our presence and work. We trust that we hav~ lived uP. to
the true Grady ideals and that we have helped m advancmg
those ideals. We know that we have profited by being united
as Grady members, and we will always be in spirit with the
Gradies of the coming years.
I t is in your hands, you Gradies- to come, to carryon
our work. It is with you that in the future we leave our so&#173;ciety.
And may you always put forth the best efforts in the
endeavor to accord with the highest principles of Gradyism,
to advance those principles, and to be actuated by the resolve
to continue to make of the greatest value and brotherhood
the Grady Literary Society.
Claxton Society
The Claxton Literary Society has come to the close of an&#173;other
successful year. We have not reached the mark of per&#173;fection-
if that were true there would be no room for im&#173;provement.
New me~ bers hav~ been added to the list of
membership constantly . These as well as the old members
have show; n much interest in preparing their part when
placed on program.
The attendance during this month has necessarily been
lessened, due to the fact that several of the boys go out each
evening for baseball practice. The preparation of the annual
society debate, and the Claxton- Dromgoole play has taken
. considerable time; not only of those who participated but
those who have willingly given their assistance. As a society
we wish to express our sincere appreciation to Messrs. Fred
Arnold and David L. Manier, who have been so zealous in the
preparation of the affirmative side of this question: " Re-
THE NORMALITE
T. E. Clark, Editor.
Grady Literary Society
, ..........
36
\..~...
solved that the United States should adopt a cabinet system
of government similar to that of Great Britain." The debat&#173;ers
of the Grady Society are taking the negative stand.
Now, at the close of this year it is well to make some re&#173;mark
to the newstudents. We have four lively literary socie&#173;ties
in Middle' Tennessee Normal, two of which are for the
girls, and two for the boys. No newstudent can make a mis&#173;take
in joining one of these literary societies. The Claxton
Society extends a hearty welcome to the young men, and the
young ladies we wish to invite to visit our sister- society, the
Dromgoole. One of the things which these two societies
prize themselves for, is the congenial atmosphere which pre&#173;vails.
You are a stranger only once with us.
Murfree Society
The approach of spring has given to us new pep and zeal
to m'ake the many tasks which are before us a success.
Already a great deal of enthusiasm is being manifested
in the essay contest which will soon be here. Thpse who are
to represent us in the contest " try- out" have already been se&#173;lected
and are each trying to attain the high honor which is
sought.
The society broke the monotony of the chapel exercises
one day not long ago by presenting a very interesting pro&#173;gram
to the faculty and student body.
We are all very much interested in the Murfree- Grady
play, " A Pair of Sixes" which is to be given May II.
The Society is glad to welcome many new members this
term and are also glad to have many of its former members
back, and we wish to assure them that there is always a place
and a hearty welcome for them in Murfree Hall.
Dromgooles
The DrOnigooles came to a close of the year with a feel &#183; &#183;
ing that this has been a banner year for us. Its membership
has greatly increased and a number of interesting and inspir&#173;ing
programs have been features of the year's work.
Each member &#183; has worked diligently for the betterment
of the Society, but our work is not yet finished~ Our girls
are busy on their essays and every member must do all that
Windrow says M. T. N. has Peabody beat for pretty
girls. We wonder if he was thinking of the rest of the fel-lows.
she can to support them. Enthusiasm is now running high
and w'e expect a great victory.
Miss Will Allen Drom~ goole visited us in March and we
hope she can be with us again the night of the essay contest.
. Miss Dromgoole is writing an autobiography and will present
it to the society to preserve.
/
THE NORMALITE J9
Thus bees work from morn' till night
And then from night tm early morn.
But it doesn't really seem it's right,
Since by this their life is soon gone.
When night has come most creatures rest.
But night for bees is not that way,
While little birds sleep in their nest,
Bees preserve what they've made that day.
Thus' bees work the whole day through.
No drones in their home do abide;
For their queen is good and true,
And in her reign all drones have died.
TO THE HONEY- BEE
And so, here's to the honey bee!
The greatest worker. in our land&#173;Thou
dost not stop to think of thee,
But givest thy sweet life to feed man.
- ED GARR.
Oh! just to be a' honey- bee
And kiss the flowers in the spring,
Then fly with mates to our lone tree
And leave the nectar that we bring.
': 3 THE NORlVlALITE
Those who plan our chapel programs evidently believe
that " variety is the spice of, life," judging from the various
treats wehave enjoyed this term. We only hope that the fu&#173;ture
halds many more pleasures for us.
During " Clean- Up" Week Supt. J. C. NIitchell, of the
Murfreesboro City Schools, gave us a timely talk on Health.
Mr. Crichlow ' and ]\ 1r. Holloway also visited us that week.
Prof . and : Mrs. Frazier prepared us to enjoy the lyceum
numbers presented on the' afternoon and evening, of April 13,
by giving us briefly the necessary facts about the classic fea&#173;tures,
one of which was, " Gammer Gurton's Needle."
On l\ 1onday, April 16, 1\ 1r: Altman, manager of the Prin&#173;cess
Theatre, introduced : Mr. Curry, a motioll picture director,
and his charming little daughter whose screen name is Dodo
Reid. Baby Dodo, who is the niece of Wallace Reid, is only
seven years of age. She easily convinced her audience by an&#173;swering
numerous questions in history and geography, that
she is indeed a remarkable child.
Miss Cox of the Wesley House addressed us on Friday,
April 20. When Mr. Wynn introduced her he said she was a
real woman with a real message for us and we heartily agree
with him.
On Monday, April 23, Miss Lumpkin of Atlanta, Ga., ' who
is the National Secretary of the Student Y. W. C. ' A. spoke
to us on the subject of Prayer
THE NORMALITE 41
Margaret WilltSOn, Editor.
The members of the faculty who t'ook part on the pro&#173;gram'
of teachers' association in Nashville were: President
Lyon, Profs; \ i\ Tynn, Woodward, Frazier and Coach Miles;
Misses Mary Ellen Fontaine and E. May Saunders.
Prof. ' Thom1as Brackin, who was granted a leave of ab&#173;sence,
has gone to Alabama for the r'emainder of the spring
and summer.
Miss Mary Law, of Peabody, is filling the position in the
English and Latin departments, left vacant by Prof. Brackin.
Miss , EuJeen Brown, also of Peabody is assistant in the
mathematics department. , '
Miss E .1\ 1ay Saunders was one of the soloists for the Ea&#173;ster
service at the Presbyterian Church in Murfreesboro.
Miss Williams was hostess of a candy- making party re&#173;cently.
Those, enjoying this delightful affair were: Misses
Monohan, Fontaine, Laws and Brown, Mrs. Fralzier and Prof.
and Mrs. Sims. Mr. Sims ' being the only man present natu&#173;rally
felt his importance and " bossed" the ladies.
Mrs. Frazier served as substitute for Mrs. Gillentine dur&#173;ing
the latter's stay in Washington.
Mrs. Gillentine has returned from Washington, D. c.,
where she attended the National D . A. R. Conference. She
also acted as a judge in the oratorical and reading contests
40 THE NORMALITE
at Fayetteville during the recent Lincoln county school meet.
Mr. Holmes, who was away for several days at the be&#173;ginning
of the term on account of the illness and death of his
brother, is again at his post of duty.
President Lyon had a birthday recently and the other
members of the faculty found it out and remembered it ap&#173;propriately.
The senior members of the faculty said to him
" Cheer up Friend, we all have to have them" and the junior
members and the student body said " Friend, it was a good
day for this cold, gray world when you gave it a birthday."
At the beginning of the term some one saw Mrs. Ogden
and remarked, " Oh, what an attractive new student."
42 THE NORMALITE THE NORMALITE 4J
In a for: m'er issue of the NORMALITE the statement
was made that Miss Schardt and Miss Fontaine had made a
purchase of ear- rings at Woolworths. The ladies in ques&#173;tion
wish to explain that they wear the ear- rings not with
any idea of beautifying themselves, but only with the desire
of hearing Miss Monohan's free lecture on the " Age of Sav&#173;agery"
and " Relics of Barbarism."
When things grow dull at the teachers' table they don
their ear- rIngs and stir up a series of caustic remarks on
women of prehistoric ages and cave dwellers, etc, etc., etc.,
ad infintum.
Windrow-" There are no fools in our family!"
Manier-" Sir, you forgot yourself."
Harvill tells of a man who lost a tooth fiftten years ago
found it later, replaced it and has a good tooth today. Now
you tell one.
A puzzling question: " Will Ruth Lee be a teacher or a
Cook?"
Mr. Davis told of nine people on a, n island who were
starving on beans and water. Those who eat at the dining
hall should be thankful that they are not on an island for that
is the chief difference as we see it.
Hannah Graham Belcher, Editor
With the arrival of the Senior rings and pins everybody
very suddenly realized that Commencement was not far dis&#173;tant.
Plans for new white dresses and vacation trips are
being made rapidly.
A recent lyceum number was presented by the Peabody
Entertainment Com'mittee. It consisted of music by a mixed
quartette, readings by Miss Wilkes, and a scene from the
popular opera, " Martha."
On Friday, April the sixth, the campus' was the scene of
the County Athletic Meet. Representatives from all parts of
the county were present. It is said that the Normal had nev&#173;er
before witnessed such an array of blue, red, and white rib&#173;bons
' as was presented that day.
On the twenty- fourth of March the girls' physical edu&#173;cation
classes gave an exhibition in the gym. An interesting
feature was the series of reiays between the " peanuts" and
the " popcorns."
Dr. J. A. Sample, State Chemist, recently made a visit
to Mr. Belcher, and after an inspection of the laboratories,
pronounced them first class.
One of the interesting events, during April was the ap&#173;pearance
of the Coffer- Miller Players. They gave a matinee
and evening performance, presenting the two comedies,
(
A couple of old codgers got into a quarrel and landed be&#173;fore
the local magistrate. The loser, turning to his oppon&#173;ent
in a combative frame of mind, cried:
I'll law you to the circuit court."
" I'm willin'," said the other.
" An' I'll law you to the supreme court."
" I'll be thar."
" An' I'll law you to ' ell!"
" My attorney will be there," was the calm reply.
- Boston Transl ri1 t
THE NORMALITE 45
Louise McKnight, Editor.
Bladys Bond, ' 23, completed her work here in the winter
term. She is doing work this quarter at Peabody.
Frances Blevens, ' 22, is teaching in Chattanooga. She
visited Margaret Ward during the Easter Holidays and was
a welcome guest at M. T. N.
Laura Davis, ' 22, is teaching in Tyner School, Chatta&#173;nooga.
Hobart Massey, ' 22, who has taught in Chattanooga the
past year, recently married.
Pansy Brier, ' 22, a sister of our " Judge'" Brier, is teach&#173;ing
in Jamestown, her home town , this year.
Adina Golden, 22, is teaching in Walling, Tenn.
Rebecca Hill, 22, and her sister, Katherine Hill, ' 21, are
both teaching in their home town, Sparta.
Gladys Robinson, " 20, is teaching in Chattanooga.
Wayde H. Rucker, ' 20~ a graduate of the agriculture
Course is now studying at Vanderbilt.
Foster Swann, ' 20, is. teaching at Bethesda, Tenn.
L. R. Wheeler, ' 20, is teaching at Ashland City, Tenn.
J . E. Windrow, ' 23, completed his three years work here
last term and has gone to Peabody this quarter.
Lillian Beesley, ' 17, who has taught in the Public School
here for several years, is to be married to Mr. Thomas Hud-
THE NORMALITE
" Gam. mer Gurton's Needle," wand " The Imaginary Invalid,"
very creditably.
However the Middle Tennessee Normal is not dependent
on Moliere or professional players for its entertainment, for
it holds within its walls a master playwright and actors of
limitless ability. Proof - of thi" was riven on the evening of
April 20, when Mr. Mankin's . most recent production, " Wise&#173;acre's
Debut," was presented by a picked cast. It w2.~ a com&#173;plete
success as was evidenced by the insistent calls for
Uauthor."
: Miss Williams and eleven Y. W. C. A. girls spent the
week- end in Nashville attending a Y. W. conference at which
Peabody and Vanderbilt were joint hostesses. There were
representatives from several colleges, and the meeting was a
big success.
An unusual event occurred on April 30, when the faculty
forgot they were the faculty and enjoyed themselves huge&#173;ly
in giving a stunt program. We discovered many things
about our teachers that we had never even dreamed of.
Miss Lumpkin, a char &#183; ming and forceful Y. W. worker,
was here several days giving help and inspiration to the Y.
W. girls.
Mrs. Fertig entertained the Y. W. C. A. members at her
home April 24.
Mrs. E. L. Atwood entertained the Baptist girls at the
Normal on April 27.
44
A LAMENT
THE NORMALITE 47
Geraldine Grigsby, Editor
It is needless to mention the apparent zeal and action of
the new cabinet, ~ ho will serve the remainder of this year
and until March of the year following. It seems that each
one has grasped her work, and has already gone to work in
her field, with a ready and willing spirit, cumbined with a
complete comprehension of the task set before her. No one
would ever even dare to doubt that they had served as Y. W.
cabinet members for months past.
Already a Rummage sale is on foot, and at the present
time quite a number of articles, various in size, shape and
fashion have been collected for this purpose. We are ever
ready to receive any donation; nothing ever arrives too late,
as it is an easy task to store any article away until the next
opportunity for sale. Seems as though the boys might be in&#173;terested
in donating some of their perfectly good cast aside
apparel. Think this over boys, al1d let us hear from you.
Miss Lumpkin, active in Y. W. work, has been with us
for a few days and through her efforts any number of girls
ha. ve become interested in the Blue Ridge Conference. If pos&#173;sible
we want a delegation of at least ten for the Y W. C. A.
Blue Ridge Conference in June.
In our vast student body it seems that we have talent of
every imaginable description. The latest proof of this ! act
is a play of which Philip Mankin is the author. Friday mght
THE NORMALITE
J ohnny Jones and his sister Sue
Studied Psychology- I did too.
But Johnny and Susie got out light
They ate a peach and died one night!
Children up in the proper way.
That's what I lived and did- but say!
When my paper came back to me
The grade I got- O hully gee.
I had no peach, I did not die,
I merely lived to answer why
Knowledge of instincts was the thing
To use in a schoolroom, and to bring
Johnny Jones anc.; his sister Sue
Studied Psychology- I did too;
Now they're in heaven, cool and free,
And I am continuing Psychology.
Mr. Lyon ( in chapel)-" It m" ight be an interesting expet=" &#173;iment
for all the students, especially the boys, to quit smok&#173;ing
for a month."
dleston, a jeweler of Murfreesboro. The wedding has been
set for May twenty- fourth.
Mrs. W. W. Harmon, ' 23, one of our three year gradu&#173;ates
is working on her degree at Peabody this year.
Mattie Ida Hoover, ' 15, is now Mrs. Johnny O'Brien, and
lives at Christiana, Tenn.
Charlotte Forgey, ' 20, is teaching in Columbia.
Lennie]. Sanders, ' 20, is teaching in Richland City, Tenn.
Martha Moon, ' 20, is teaching at Christiana this year.
Nell D. Watkins, ' 20, is in Davidson county, teaching.
Elmer Dounum, ' 16, is now a resident of Kentucky. He
has made quite a financial success in the oil business.
46
The prospects for base ball at M. T. N. are exceedingly
bright this spring. Coach Miles has quite a number of fel&#173;lows
out, and he hopes within a few days to turn out a smooth.
working team.
We &#183; are very fortunate this time in having a number of
r(&gt; liable pitchers. In Duck and Phillips we have two veterans..
Last year they both pitched fine ball and they should win
some games this season. Gray and Kennedy look very good
and all the indications are that they are due to win. In Brat&#173;ten,
the Nashville boy, Coach thinks he has a real pitcher who
can deliver the goods.
There are many contenders for positions in the infield.
Delay seems able to take care of the catching, with Moffitt
an able assistant. Phillips IS playing a fine game at first. Joe
Davis has been shifted from second base to short stop. He
plays that position with the same old pep that he displayed
last season at second. At third we have a good man in Frank
Bryant, though at present he is out with a broken ankle.
Parks seems to be the man for the keystone position. He is
also out at present. Other likely contenders for positions on
E. P. Eaves, Editor.
THE NORMALITE
Advantages of Studying Poultry
Here's a concrete illustration of the advantages of study&#173;ing
poultry:
Angle who owns no poultry gets two eggs each day and
has one hen sitting. Can you beat it?
" What do you call it when a man has a number of wives?"
" Polygamy."
" Oh, yes! And what is it when he has only one wife?"
" Aw, that's monotony."
Prof. Davis insists that plain and plane spell ' plane, or
plain whether or not it is plain or plane.
Mr: Mankin staged his lat~ production with an all star cast,
consisting of M~ ssrs. Cyrus Dement, Paul Burton, Carl Bran&#173;dun,
Ernest Setc1iff and the. author himself; Miss Katie By-yom
was the heroine.
Of all the entertainments or features of the year, the
crowning one is yet in store. At some time in the near fu&#173;ture
we have succeeded in securing the promised services of
our faculty who will render a program very similar to our
annual stunt. night. Just for example: Mr. Davis will very
~ fficiently play the part of the city dude. With his' high top&#173;ped
hat, long tailed ~ oat, and walking cane he will announce
the various features of the evening. For a more detailed ac&#173;count
of the performance, you will have to be present to en&#173;joy
it all. Both this entertainment and the one last Friday
night have been given over to the Y. W. C. A.
THE NORMALITE
Correct this sentence: Prof. Woodward took me to town
in his Monroe.
Mr. Lyon says human nature is the same the world over,
but it is more so in chapel.
Shippey says the difference between land and the ocean
is the degree of moisture.
It took coach exactly three minutes to find that twenty&#173;five
thousand is one tenth of two hundred and fifty thousand.
the infield are Osteen and Price. They are both showing up
well.
In the outfield Harvill is the o~ ly regular of last year. The
" old man" is still able to hit the ball. Cy Miller is playing a
great game in center field. Charlie Joe Woodson is making
Coach take notice and , is trying to show him that a little fel&#173;low
can play ball. Other outfielders are Duck, Miles, Smith,
and Brumbaugh.
Nonn~~ Vand~ bilt3
The first game of the season was played with Vanderbilt
Freshmen on the local field. After a hard fought game the
Blue and White conquered the Vandy boys in the tenth inning. I
Final score was Norma' 1 4- Vandy 3. At the beginnig of the
ninth inning the score was 3- 1 with our boys holding the lit&#173;tle
end. It was in this inning that the boys did some work.
After Moffitt had walked, Delay hit a home run scoring Mof&#173;itt
ahead of himself. The score being tied, we were able to
win in the tenth by way of Phillip's three bagger. Gray and
Kennedy pitched fine ball. Gray struck out twelve batters ic
seven innings while Kennedy whipped three in three innings.
Kennedy allowed only two hits for the time he worked.
M. T. N. 3- Bryson 3
On April 20, our boys journeyed to Fayetteville to battle
the Bryson College nine. - The ga'm; e resulted in a 3- 3 tie af&#173;ter-
twelve innings of hard fighting. Bratten showed what he
could do by holding the Bryson boys to six scattered hits for
the twelve innings. Harvill hit a home run, and you can judge
for yourself how far the baH must have gone for the " o'ld
man" to make a home run.
We have a fine schedule which includes several games ~ t
home as well as on the road. The boys make their usual Ken&#173;tucky
trip, playing S. P. U., Bethel College and Kentucky
Normal on the trip.
The preps have - games scheduled, but as yet they have
not gone forth into battle.
THE NORMALITE 51
Mary Hill King, Editor.
As ~ his , is our last issue of the NORMALITE, we desire
to thank each of our exchanges and to compliment them on&#173;their
good work of the year. We have received exchange
publications from thirty different schools, which have been 1&#173;pleasure
and an insp. iration to us. We hope to have each of
these publications on our exchange list next year. One of
the best spurs, to real honest- to- goodness hard work and con&#173;sequent
success, in any line is constructive criticism and com&#173;mendation.
We have received both from our exchange list
and just to show our appreciation for what others have said
about us, we are pleased to print the following comments:
The Columns- Congratulations to Middle Tennessee Nor&#173;mal
on the NORMALITE- it's dandy.
The _ Echo- NORMALITE- One of the best exchanges
we have received.
Peabody Volunteer- The NORMALITE is certainly orig&#173;inal
and entertaining. Every organization and department of
your school is represented, which makes it an interesting pa&#173;per
to all.
The Hillbilly- The NORMALITE is one of the b. est rnJag&#173;azines
we have - received. Your literary department is good
and your jokes are very interesting. The cuts and cover de' &#173;signs
are fine.
so THE NOR' [ ALITE
WANTED- Another girl. See Roy Jakes.
A reward has been offered to the man who catches
Huffman not singing.
THE NORMALITE 53
MURFREESBORO, TENNESSEE
AT
BUTLER, HOOPER &amp; McCORD, Inc.
" The Good Clothes Store"
WEST SIDE SQUARE
HIGH CLASS CLOTHES, HATS AND
FURNISHINGS
KiT'
r
is
: J\ IIr. Sims-" In two hundred years, if we sho\, 1 '
to earth, we would find conditions much imp""'" ~ lL~
Pete Clark-" I would like to retu~- 68
Bob Partin-" I wouldn't; I woui! oioc. _
place where I was."
Louise McKnight-" Did the storm do any damage around
here ?"
Hannah Belcher- H Yes, it blew the daylight out of the
Moffitt House."
When a man taketh unto himself a wife he hath a bet&#173;ter
half. But ye bachelors have &#183; better quarters.
Thirty per cent of college students work their way
through college- the rest yell through.
Grey is ?- new shade, that King Tut is a by- word, that bacon
twelve times per week is appetizing, and that chapel is dull.
THE NORMALITE .. :,,: ~ \.'
HITS, RUNS AND ERRORS
Eddie B, urns says he is sure ( after figuring) that ten
times a hundred million equals a billion.
Paul Burton and Jack Bennett were seen smoking cigars
down town one Saturday afternoon recently.
Green announnces that he has learned a new chord In
q flat.
Verily I say unto thee, my son, when amongst women
let not thy " right" girl know what thy left girl is doing.
Some Normalites are so stupid that they think the blue
laws a new piece of jazz music, that a golf tea is for drink&#173;ing,
that home ties are a new style of neckwear, that Zane
The other day Lewis was moving' his Victrola cabinet
from the basement. " I'm glad to see that thing go," said Mr.
Ogden.
" Why so," inquired Lewis.
" That ~ ld i~ e box has been in the way long enough," Mr.
Ogden replIed, mnocent of his error.
52
Pharris ( to janitor)-" Do you know where I can get a
live house cat?"
J anitor-" What do you want with it?"
Pharris-" To dissect in the laboratory." .
Janitor-" YOl.~ can get the one over at the dining hall &#183; f
you will return it when you are through." 1
And Pharris went away wondering how many weiners
that would be.
54
. THE NORMALITE
put on the market. D
h &#183; h 0 you notice th
IS ead? '. e reSult On t
Craddock_" I thou h . .
H ff' g t Caesar was dead"
u mes-" He is, isn't he?" .
Craddock " N M' .
- 0, ISS Law is teach &#183; h.
. mg lIn."
Mr. Davis-" I told you to brin
Arnold-" I d ' . g a note- book t on t need one &#183; I use a
Mr. Davis-" I d'd ' ' my head."
I n t say a blank note- book."
Miss OrdwaY-" What is Swine?"
Clay Coe " S &#183; &#183; .
. - wme IS skim milk."
.' MaT~, Frances Bray has a new recipe for .
Venly I si(; ne seeds. makl
let not thy " right'; ! 5.
~ s examinations to shakin a
The other day Lewis+~ the top he says g
from the basement " I'm I d . . ga ' r--
Ogden. .
" " . . . rna and Christiana
Why so, mqUIred Lewis .
" That old ice box has bee~ in th
Ogden replied . . e way! .
, Innocent of hIS error. ' lIke an 0
Ph . ., this ap
. arns ( to janitor)-" Do ou k
live house cat?" y now where I ,
Janitor " Wh t d .
- a 0 you want with it?"
PharriS-" To d &#183; &#183; . .
] . Issect In the laboratory"
allItor-" YOt can get th .
you will retu . the one over at the dining hall .
rn I w en you are through"
And Pharris went a . .
that would be. way wonderIng how many weine
Some Normart
laws an &#183; I es are so stupid that they think the blu
ew pIece of ja . .
ing th ' t h ! zz musIC, that a golf tea is for drmk
, a orne tIes are a I
new stye of neckwear, that Zan
Truett Representing
' iih &amp; Fletche.. &#183; S
~ gger-~
OPPOSITE POST OFFICE
1- 1. BYRN &amp; SON
Authorized Buick Sales And Service
Goody~ ar And Kelly- Springfield Tires
COMPETENT MECHANICS
PHONES 8 AND 68
MURFREESBORO, TENNESSEE
HIGH CLASS CLOTHES, HATS AND
FURNISHINGS
AT
BUTLER, HOOPER &amp; McCORD, Inc.
" The Good Clothes Store"
'.
t &#183; WEST SIDE SQUARE
TELEPHONE 727
T A X I
SERVICE
" RED" HARVEY
Leave Leave
Murfreesboro Nashville
( J ordan Hotel) ( Maxwell House)
8: 00 A M. 8: 00 A. M.
11: 00 A. M. 11: 00 A. M.
1: 00 P. M. 1: 00 P. M.
3: 00 P. M. 3: 00 P. M.
5: 00 P M. 5: 00 P. M.
, BETWEEN MURFREES&#173;BORO
AND NASHVILLE
Eagleville, Tenn.
Both Phones 90
Murfreesboro and
Woodfin &amp; Moore
AMBULANCE SERVICE
Phone 439 Phone 458
Special Attention and Prices Given to School
Students and. Directors
J. T. Woodfin B. c. Moore, Jr.
We Wash Everything but the Baby, and Return
Everything but the Dirt
oaK'S LAUNDRY
. ]. E. cOOK &amp; SONS, PropS.
~ tJRFREESBORO - - TENNESSEE
4 per cent. Paid on Savm &#183; A . gs ccount.
QUAUIY Murfreesboro B
That's h HOll w at you eet when se
trade with you
BROWN BROS. Everything for
ICE CREAM CO S
Ice Cream Sh b &#8226; am Licker , . er eta, Ices 5 d
.. wu: hes, etc. ' an &#183; T
Brown Ice C B Carl Get th ream Pi.... &#8226; &#8226; ese from the Y W ~,-_-:- .... J1
at Normal' &#8226; C. A. I
Telephone U Y L H WEHRLE F I.: C::: mO rd... For &#8226;&#8226;
ree Delivery to th N p. GI Ev. rythin" h' ormal aInt, ass and V
sold with t': ou uy from us i.
isfaction or e guarantee of sat &#183; m &#183; shes your mo b " 100
M
ney aek.
,0 for M TN" A' '
Brown Bros. Ic~ C~~ C uto Painting A Spe-
PHONE 444 o. ~__ cialty.
MURFREESBORO BANK &amp; TRUST CO.
TOTAL RESOURCES OVER $ 1,800,000.00
LUNCHES
Wh.. SO
Itm~ Norris &amp; Hollinsworth
READ &amp; RIG
FORMERLY JACK'S G
CIGARS
PIUCEAND SE
SMART FOOTWEAR
AT ALL HOURS
SOUTH SIDE OF SQUARE
PHONE 77
IN BUSINESS FOR
YOUR HEALTH
D~ Y GOODS AND READY- TO- WEAR
Telephone 96. 103 Public Square
Groceries, Fruits And
Vegetables
TATUM &amp; SHACKLETT
LEADERS IN
W. E. CANTRELL &amp; CO. CITY RESTAURANT
, DEALERS - IN Meals and Lunches
Complete Line of School Supplies
Parker Fountain Pens
Ever Sharp Pencils
Magazines and Novels
Stickney Drug Company
Home Phone 13
Hot Chili in Winter T....
Ice C~ ealD in SUIDIDer
AnythlJlg good to eat ...
ALL THE TIME.
ELROD'S BOOTE
TfIE~ lXlll CO
. EVERYTIDNG TO WEAR FOR mE
ENTIRE FAMILY
OPPosite P. O.
Stones River Bank
&amp; Trust Co..
Murfreesboro, Tenn.
4 % Paid on Savings
SAVE
For the glorious privilege of
being independent
MURFREESBORO - TENNESSEE
Cumb. Phone J47
Phone 69
Misses E. and M.
Earthman
Exclusive Millinery
128 North Church St.
Cut Flowers For &#8226;
AU OCcaSIOns
" Where only the Best
&#65533;&#65533; IS goodenough"
ALSUP SHOE
COMPANY
WE DO HEMSTITCHING
c. B. LEATHERMAN &amp; COMPANY
Dry Goods And Ladies Ready- To- Wear
We Appreciate Your Patronage
- BONNET SHOP A. L. SMITH &amp; CO.
Druggists
If You Need A MAGAZINES, SCHOOL
SUPPLIES
NEW BONNET CHOCOLATES
GROCERIES
STORE OF FRIENDLY SERVICE
. PHONE 895
P
POSITE FIRE HALL
o H. M. TUTT, Propn &#183; etor.
FREE DELlVERY
'. N al Class at the Methodist Sunday School!!
JoU1 the orm
Murfreesboro- McMinnville- Tullahoma
HENRY KING &amp; COMPANY
Successor to Boulevard Store
WHOLESALE GROCERS
PHONE 515
Groceries, Cigars, Tobacco, Soft Drinks
High Grade Candies, Gasoline
Comer Normal Boulevard and East ~ ain Street
LEWIS BRINKLEY
Agents for
FISK RED TOP TIRES
Automobile Accessories, Oils and Gas
TIRE SERVICE
Free Air And Free Water
PROMPTNESS
PHONE 811 W. MAIN ST.
MURFREESBORO, TENN.
Allen Service
and'
o 0 0 0 04 0'..... 0 0 1
.....
1
e
I ~
I- &#183; 1
ICater to the Wants I
I of the Normal I
I Boys and Girls I
I COMPLETE LINES OF e IWearing Apparel I.
., and Accessories I
o I I EXCLUSIVE AGENTS OF 0
1Spaulding Sporting I
1 Goods and I
I . Bradley Sweaters I
o ..........() 0 0 0 () ( 0 .0 ( l-
TENNESSEE
Newspaper, Book
GARAGE
EVERYTHING FOR THE
AUTOMOBILE
Telephone 38 218 West Main Street
&#183; THE &#183; HOME JOURNAL
PUBLISHING CO.
MURFREESBORO,
Hirshrunner {;; Miles
Dodge Bros.' Motor Vehic1es
Authorized Dealers
Tennessee
746 East Main Street
Murfreesboro, Tenn.
The Favorite With
Up- To- Date Young
Men~
\ r l&gt; LEE A. UVELY STUDIO
CASON'S GARAGE
STUDEBAKER CARS REO CARS
All Kinds of Repairing And
Shop Work
f &#183;
(
Murfreesboro
STAR BARBER SHOP STAR PRESSING SHOP
Expert Pressing
And Cleaning
ALLEN BROS., Proprietors
P" hone 243
.. SPECIAL PRICES TO NORMAL STUDENTS
Horton Grocery Company CLAYTON &amp;
DRAPER &#183; Staple and Faney
Groceries SHOES
Walk Across the Square and Feed and Seed Save the Difference.
PHONES 260 AND 88 W. Side Square. Phone 184
H. H. WILLIAMS, Cas~ i
C. B. BELL, Ass't. Cashier
Tel. 800
GEORGE W. HOWSE, Pres.
JNO. M. BUTLER, Vice Pres.
Cars- Trucks And Fordson Tractors
First National Bank
CAPITAL $ 200,000 SURPLUS $ 40,000
fARTHMAN- WlLSON- UKIN MOTOR COMPANY
In. corporated
Murfreesboro
OLD RELIABLE TAXI SERVICE
PHONE 11
EPH HOOVER, Manager
MURfREESBORO HeHT &amp; POWER COMPANY
LEA VE YOUR I. JIGHTS ON, OR WE
CAN~ T PAY. FOR THIS AD
FERRELL
PHOTOGRAPHER
COOK'S SERVICE STATION
' AUBREY COOK, Mgr.
" You Can Find It There"
We Make Sick People Well At Little Cost
TELEPHONE 179 .
GAS, OIL, TIRES AND TUBES
FREE ROAD SERVICE
TELEPHONE 37 303 WEST COLLEGE ST.
FIRESTONE TIRES.
High Grade Wark At Very Reasonable Prices.
SPECIAL PRICES TO NORMAL STUDENTS
STORE
,
: .
t &#183; :
LEO
Telephone 361
North Side Public Square
, PHONE240
McKNIGHT AND
PARTEE
QuaGty Furniture
ART CHINA SHOP
Hand Painted China, Parch&#173;ment
Shades, Electroliers, Nov&#173;elties.
Carda for all Occasiona.
Orders Filled Promptly
MRS. D. E. LOGAN
MISS FANNIE NICHOL
We Guarantee Satisfaction.
Let Us Make You a Suit to Your Individual Measure.
E. L. ROGERS &amp; COMPANY
Gents' Outfitters, Clothing and Shoes' ;
SAMPLE SHOES A SPECIALTY
ELECTRIC SHOE
SHOP
Your Patronage
SoGcited
119 South Church St.
w. T. GERHARDT
Merchant Tailor
Phone 59
Cleaning Pressing
. Altering
SANITARY CAFE
FOR LADIES AND
GENTS
OPEN DAY AND NIGHT
VVHOLESALE GROCERS
RAGLAND, POTTER&amp; C
Next to Jordan Hot
MURFREESBORO WATERTO
TO ' TASTE OF NATURE'S SWEE
TRY
CONSUMER'S SUPPLY COMPANY'
ICE CREAM
CONSUMER'S SUPPLY COMPJ\ N
ARNOLD'S BARBER SHO
NORMAL BOYS INVITED
112 East Main Street,
'.
</dc:description>
<dc:subject>College publications; Middle Tennessee State Normal School</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Image; Text;</dc:type>
<dc:type>text; application/pdf</dc:type>
<dc:format>Periodical;</dc:format>
<dc:format>54 p.; 9.5 x 6.0 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright may or may not belong to MTSU; Reproduced with permission of the Albert Gore Research Center, MTSU</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>May be used freely by individuals for research, teaching, and personal use under the fair use provisions of the Copyright Act; Credit: Property of the Albert Gore Research Center, Middle Tennessee State University, Murfreesboro, TN 37132; For other uses contact The Albert Gore Research Center, P.O. Box 193, MTSU, Murfreesboro TN 37132</dc:rights>
<dc:relation>University Collections, MTSU Miscellaneous, Middle Tennessee Normal School, 1911-1925</dc:relation>
<dc:publisher>Albert Gore Research Center, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:description>Folder 5</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/mtsu1/id/1419</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>