<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Constitution revamp continues in ASB</dc:title>
<dc:relation>Sidelines, March 1, 1966</dc:relation>
<dc:creator>Call, Dick</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1966-03-01</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Call's article describes the proposed Associated Student Body constitutional changes (Replacing the word "college" with University, allowing women and juniors to run for A.S.B. president, and raising the GPA required to run) and the arguments that arose over some of the proposed changes.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Constitution Revamp Continues In ASB
BY Dick Call
It seems that things are not going according to 

schedule in the constitutional meetings that are 

being held in the House and Senate of our A.S.B. 

Congress. As you, the constituents of these 

congressional members, may or may not know, the 

constitution which limits and delegates power to 

our campus government is in the throes of being 

revised.
To bring you up to date, a constitutional 

committee was organized in the summer of 1965. 

The committee was composed of members of the 

House and Senate, and had for its main objective 

to strike from the constitution the word COLLEGE 

and replace it with the word UNIVERSITY. Of 

nearly equal importance was the striking, 

revision, and rewording of certain other sections 

of the constitution which will shape it into a 

document quite different from the one under which 

we now "operate."
The revised constitution came out of committee 

around the first week of February, with the 

following major changes:
1st. College was changed to University,
2nd. Individual clubs on campus are in effect 

under the jurisdiction of the A.S.B. government,
3rd. Females can now run for A.S.B. President,
4th. The President and two Vice Presidents have 

to have a 2.5 cumulative point average to run for 

office and maintain a 2.3 cumulative while in 

office,
5th. Either a junior or a senior can run for 

President or Vice-President.
Along with the above changes, much of the 

ambiguous and all but scholarly wording was 

changed.
The constitution went from joint committee into 

the House and Senate, where it is presently being 

debated. Of the five major changes, two in 

particular seem to be causing trouble, the raised 

cumulative grade point average and junior running 

for President and Vice President. Some of the 

arguments on the pro side of the 2.5 are: 1. 

There is a high correlation between point average 

and ability (this is denied by several on the 

negative  side, desiring 2.0-2.0). 2. A better 

point average will insure that the officials not 

flunk out. 3. Our leaders should have an average 

that is better than just above probation level. 

Arguments on the negative side are 1. Leadership 

does not manifest itself through high averages. 

2. More time could be devoted to government and 

less time to studying 3. By raising the point 

average to 2.5, only a small percent of the  

students on campus could run for office. Other 

less astute negative remarks were, "I'm posed to 

intellectualism and always have been," and "grade 

point average doesn't indicate anything, 

especially leadership; most of the intelligent  

people make low grades," finally, "anyone who 

could go through his junior year with a 2.5 

average or better should be worshiped as a Greek 

god or goddess." After all, what Christian wants 

to be led by a god, humm?
The House is not without problems in the 

constitutional debate. Because of its absolute 

size, the number of members needed for a quorum 

is high; thus there has been some problem getting 

enough of the House members present to do 

business. This obstacle has be bridged, however, 

by just having the speaker declare a new number 

for the quorum at each meeting, not really good 

parliamentary procedure but then one must make 

sacrifices for expediency's sake. If you are 

interested in your government and your 

constitution, why not corner your congressman and 

tell him what you would like to see for guide 

lines. Check the A.S.B. office for the names of 

your representatives.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Associated Student Body; Changes; Representatives</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Student government; Middle Tennessee State University;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Constitutions; Organizations;</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Text;</dc:type>
<dc:type>image/jpeg</dc:type>
<dc:format>Clipping;</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected. Reproduced with permission of the University</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Reproduction is permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only; Credit to Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:rights>
<dc:relation>Sidelines Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/mtsu1/id/753</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>