<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>W.L. Clement oral history. Transcript. Part 1</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Clement, William L.,interviewee; Hatch, Evan, Interviewer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2009-09-23</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009;</dc:coverage>
<dc:title>Photographs of W.L. Clement, U.S. Soil Conservation Service</dc:title>
<dc:description>Evan Hatch interview with William L. Clement Part 1: September 23, 2009
Interview conducted in anticipation of submitting photographs by Mr. Clement for digitization at the James E. Walker Library, MTSU.
HATCH: Hello, this is Evan Hatch. I work at the Arts Center of Cannon County, Woodbury TN. I am recording an interview with W.L. Clement at his home at 2927 Tower Dr., Murfreesboro TN, 37129. This interview is going to focus on Mr. Clement&#8217;s time spent at Soil Conservation Service as a government employee and we&#8217;ll talk about some photographs, in which, that he took while he was in the employ of the Soil Conservation Service. This interview will be known from this point on as W.L. Clement 09&#8208;09.23.09 taking place on September 23 of &#8217;09. So, this is Part 1 of the interview which will be a continuous play unless we stop the recorder. Mr. Clement, you do have a statement that you would like to read. You are welcome to read that. We may ask you some questions again that are referred to in the statement but if you&#8217;d like to read that please go ahead right now.
[The following portion of this transcript has been copied from a statement prepared by Mr. Clement and read as part of the interview]
"This is a series of photographs of soil and water conservation practices on farm land in the county which were planned by farmers and was carried out under the supervision of the Cannon County Soil Conservation District during the time period of 1950 through the mid&#8208;1970s. These photos shown are typical practices carried out on many farms in the county during this time period. The Soil
Conservation Service was an agency of the Department of Agriculture and was nationwide with districts in all counties in Tennessee. It was an agency which was established to address and work on projects to solve the erosion on farm land.
The overall programs for counties and states over the nation were varied in many ways because of the needs and requirements to solve the problems. The soils were mapped and classified by soil scientists to make the best use for the land and were used as a basis in planning and establishing practices to solve the problems of soil erosion. Individual plans were developed with landowners to be carried out using conservation practices.
All farm lands have a best use for cultivating crops, pasture, grassland, woodland, planting trees or just let nature take place on rock ,land. The use should be the most profitable use. Some of the practices included in soil and water on farm land were cover crops, contour cultivation, crop rotation to include grasses and clover, terracing to direct water to a suitable outlet, pasture to include grasses and legumes, "diversions" (structures) to prevent water from running down sloping land and causing erosion, strip cropping, grass waterways in natural drainage ways of fields to prevent erosion by water flowing in its natural drains, the planting of trees on land not suited for cultivation of hay and row crops, farm ponds for water for livestock, fish production for food and recreation, stream channels to improve sloping and vegetation of banks, drainage where needed on farm land, woodland "improvement" (elimination of undesirable growth considered not valuable to timber), wildlife borders planted with shrubs and seed&#8208;producing plants for quail and rabbits, control of erosion by seeding road banks on county roads on a limited basis, seeding, liming and mulch was provided by Soil Conservation Service as a special project, waterways were shaped and seeded to conduct water to a safe outlet, stream channel improvement by sloping and vegetating banks, some drainage where needed on farm land, diversions where needed, pine tree seedlings planted on land best suited for that use. A tree planter was purchased by a local bank for use. The tree seedlings were bought by the farmers from the Tennessee Forestry Service.
The structural practices on farms were designed and laid out and construction supervised to meet standards set by the programs and service. All the structural projects had to meet standards set by the Soil Conservation Service. The district personnel cooperated with all the other agricultural agencies serving landowners in the county.
Referrals from the agricultural program office which farmers had applied for the payment on construction practices were received and completed. The Soil Conservation Service did not make payments on completed conservation practices. We only furnished technical service on those practices. The relationship between those agencies was very cooperative in assisting farmers applying conservation practices. No till or minimum tillage practices were started on a few farms under
the guidance of the area agronomist. This practice was rapidly increasing in the early seventies. Special planters were required which were bought by the farmers. This new practice was great for preventing soil erosion.
The introduction and use of Kentucky 31 fescue was recommended and used for pastures and crop rotation. The Soil Conservation Service provided layout, design, and supervision of construction for Lake Anne. The landowner financed all work for the construction. This project was the focus for a whole new community.
Activities to Promote Soil Conservation:
1. Exhibits at county fair.
2. Pine seedlings planted by Boy Scouts on Short Mountain and by school children on school grounds or other land by three schools.
3. Display of practices pictures at office entrance.
4. Promote conservation at community meetings especially dairy meetings held by Armour Creamery personnel.
5. Newspaper articles.
6. District helped to establish county forest fire control.
7. District assisted in starting deer release. 8. Assisted town and county schools in assisting in project related to conservation.
9. A one time project to treat roadside erosion on county roads by liming, fertilizing and seeding and mulching. Crown vetch was seeded in this project on several miles of roadway. Cannon County Highway
Department provided the labor for this project.
10. Provided technical services for projects we were permitted to work with town of Woodbury and public service.
11. This same service was also provided to the county.
This is a brief overview of some of the work of the Soil Conservation District personnel during the time period of the fifties, sixties and first half of the seventies.
District Conservationist was William L. Clement.
Conservation Aid was Hiram Young.
The pictures displayed are examples of some of the conservation practices being carried out on many farms in the county during this time period."
[End of prepared statement read by W.L. Clement]
5:00
HATCH: Thank you sir for that concise statement you wrote out ahead of time. I would like to ask you some more questions. Some of these things may go over some material you talked about before but that is a great overview to some of the work the Soil Conservation Service did. Can you please give me your full name and your date of birth and your place of birth?
CLEMENT: William Lloyd Clement. March 24, 1918.
HATCH: So that makes you at this time?
CLEMENT: 91 years old.
HATCH: Also in the presence of this interview, Mrs. Clement. Can you give me your full name and, if you would like, your date of birth and your place of birth.
MC: Mildred Bowreen Clement, and my date of birth&#8230;January 21, 1926.
HATCH: Mr. Clement, when did you come to become employed by the Soil Conservation Service?
CLEMENT: In 19 and 49.
HATCH: Was that your first job?
CLEMENT: Uh, no. No. My first job after I got out of high school, I went to the service. HATCH: Army&#8230;Navy?
CLEMENT: Army. I went to the Army?
HATCH: And what did you do in the Army?
CLEMENT: I volunteered as a&#8230;at that particular time they had a compulsive military training that had just started in for everybody. And, uh, it was difficult to get a job even though I'd finished college and got a degree in agriculture. Jobs were hard to get. Jobs were scarce and for a short time I worked in Cleveland, Ohio in the Murray Manufacturing, uh, Company and they made bicycles and a lot of other different products, and, uh, they finally located here in Middle Tennessee, a plant down there, still Murray Ohio Manufacturing Company, and uh, they changed locations. I worked there for three months and when winter set in, my job was laid off, and I came back to Tennessee and was home for awhile, and uh, was called up to go to the service. My number was called. I volunteered and went to the service to serve my one year's time.
10:00
HATCH: Where did you serve?
CLEMENT: I served in the Army. I went to Fort Oglethorpe in Georgia. Then I went to Camp Wheeler in Georgia for infantry training. After infantry training, uh, I went to the, uh, Camp Shelby Mississippi. There I was assigned to Military Police Headquarters. I stayed there for a couple of years, and then I flew overseas and served over there where the war was close to an end.
HATCH: Where were you serving?
CLEMENT: I served in France, and uh&#8230;
MC: And Germany. He was in Germany.
CLEMENT: And Germany and through Luxembourg and, uh, the Port of Belgium.
HATCH: Wow. And you were infantry?
CLEMENT: Yes.
HATCH: You're first on the line?
CLEMENT: Yeah.
HATCH: Did you see a lot of&#8230;this is probably a subject of another interview in another time but did you see a lot of action? Was there any&#8230;did you see a lot of fights, combat?
CLEMENT: I was close. I was in the combat area. One combat battle. I was in the area but as the Military Police I had it, maybe, not as hard as somebody on the front line. After the war was over, uh, in Germany, they issued me all the equipment and gave me all of the vaccination shots that I needed to be in the war with Japan. I was ready to go, had all my equipment and everything when they dropped the atomic bomb. HATCH: And that was it.
CLEMENT: And that was it. In other words, the plans were changed drastically and, uh, my outfit didn't go and I was appointed to work with the, uh, as a, I suppose, say as a guard out in Antwerp, Belgium port &#8208; a big port where all supplies for Germany and Belgium and around there were shipped and coming through there, and uh, trains were made up there. We checked each train, each number, each box car and the contents of the car on the made up the full train when it was ready to leave.
HATCH: What were you checking for? What were you checking for?
CLEMENT: Well, just a routine check to account for the cars on the train. And they went all over Germany carrying supplies and things, and uh, I never knew for sure what was in all of them, but uh, they had some destination they were headed for.
HATCH: When did you return to the States? It doesn&#8217;t have to be specific &#8211; what year?
MC: '45. I can't remember.
HATCH: Long after the war ended? Okay.
CLEMENT: I spent four years in, uh, four years in the Army.
HATCH: Four times the minimum. You were going in for a year orginially.
CLEMENT: Yeah.
HATCH: Because of the job situation or was it war related?
CLEMENT: Well, I originally intended to serve my one year of compulsory military training but after I'd been in it about six months, Pearl Harbor happened and that was it. I was in for the duration.
HATCH: Yeah, that changes things.
15:00
CLEMENT: Yeah.
HATCH: If you came back in 1945, what did you do until 1949 when you started working for the Soil Conservation Service?
MC: He started working for the Soil Conservation Service before '49.
HATCH: Okay, so what brought you&#8230;you had mentioned a degree earlier. Where did you go to school?
CLEMENT: University of Tennessee.
HATCH: Okay, and you were born in Tennessee?
CLEMENT: Junior college, uh, first two years and at that time Martin just had a two year school down there. HATCH: UT Martin?
CLEMENT: Uh huh, and then I transferred to Knoxville and got the other two years out up there.
HATCH: That degree was&#8230;
CLEMENT: Agriculture.
HATCH: Okay. What were you planning on doing with that degree?
CLEMENT: I planned to be a teacher in agriculture. Agriculture was my plans&#8230;my overall plans. Uh, I never did teach any in school. Opportunity came up the examination to work for the Soil Conservation Service.
HATCH: So how did you find that job? How did you come into that job? Just an opportunity opened up?
CLEMENT: Took a civil service examination and, uh, my grade was good enough that they interviewed me and hired me and sent me to work in Hardeman County in West Tennessee.
HATCH: And what was your job there?
CLEMENT: Field work, just doing soil conservation work. Of course, I was hired on as a low grade &#8211; wanting Ashley the conservationists &#8211; I worked in Murphy Field laying out terraces and assisted in tree planting and, uh, all other functions that the service was providing there in West Tennessee.
HATCH: You were a government employee at that time?
CLEMENT: Yes.
HATCH: And was your work mostly labor? It sounds like you were doing manual labor at that point.
CLEMENT: Well, it wasn't all manual. It was laying out terraces with an instrument. Laying out terraces and ponds and things like that and drainage systems and running surveys for drainage systems. Drainage was a problem in West Tennessee in a lot of places. Soil erosion down there was much worse than it is here in Middle Tennessee. I worked down there until, uh&#8230;when I got out of the service, I signed up for reserves. I said, uh&#8230;about the time that they settled in Europe, they said "might as well stay over here and take care of Russia while you're here because you're going to have to be back over here". Well I was of the age that if they had another one, I would be called so I just signed up for reserves. I didn't hear but inactive reserves and working down there&#8230;then when the Korean War started, they recalled me. I served one year in the Air Force. When I because 27 years old, uh, I decided that I had the opportunity to get out. I just served one year during the Korean War and that was served here in the States.
HATCH: To go back to, uh&#8230;so that interrupted your Soil Conservation Service work?
CLEMENT: Yes. HATCH: Did you quit that job or did you just put it on hold?
CLEMENT: Leave of&#8230;they put me on leave of absence.
HATCH: Okay.
CLEMENT: And then when I came back after serving a year, they said "We've got a job for you. We've got a vacancy in Middle Tennessee, Cannon County and if you want to take that, then your job is up there."
HATCH: Can I ask you one question about your previous job? The one in West Tennessee? How did farmers receive aid? Did they actually request that or were you sent out by the Soil Conservation Service?
20:00
CLEMENT: Most instances, they already had a farm plan developed, uh, with the Soil Conservation Service. Maybe they decided, well I'm going to build this pond at a certain time. Or I'm going to build these terraces at a certain time. Now of course, terraces had to be laid out with an instrument man and a level, a tripod level.
HATCH: Well that makes sense, needs to be level.
CLEMENT: And I carried the rod. I'd done things like that as a conservation aid. Then they later promoted me to, uh, being at a higher level.
HATCH: That was the job in Cannon County?
CLEMENT: Yeah.
HATCH: And what was your position when you decided to take the job? Was there a problem with you taking the job in Cannon County? Did you know you wanted to be there?
CLEMENT: Well, I could have denied it of course. When I went in they said "The first opening we had in West Tennessee, we'll let you go. We'll assign that to you." Well that didn't happen and I didn&#8217;t&#8230;I thought Cannon County was a nice county to live in and, uh, there were nice people, a nice location, plenty of things to do, plenty of opportunities in my line of work, and that's were my assignment was, and uh, it's something that I enjoyed while I was there. That was my line of work and what I was&#8230;of course, my training was in agriculture education, teaching in high schools, and there wasn't a job and I left out because I started teaching veterans. The team that was discharged had loaded enroll and just training. I taught them agriculture topics and subjects. They came to school so many days out of the week and put in so many hours, and uh, we had discussed anything that was relevant to what they wanted to learn. They were farmers. They were getting ready to get established in farming. The Veteran's Farm Training Program is what it was.
HATCH: Did they have family land or were they being provided for? CLEMENT: Oh they were living on older land, land that their fathers had, or land that they had interest in before they went into the service.
HATCH: And you essentially taught them how to be successful farmers in the new era?
CLEMENT: Better farm practices and more or less general farming in that area.
HATCH: Your title at this point?
CLEMENT: I suppose you'd call it teacher for Metro's On the Farm training program. They had a program planned out on their farm that they wanted to carry out, a set of goals they wanted to achieve and I was more or less an instructor, an advisor for the group.
HATCH: Were you a conservationist up to this point?
CLEMENT: No, I wasn't, but by virtue of the authority and all the experience I had it was adequate to start in with the Soil Conservation Service.
HATCH: Can you tell me where you lived in Cannon County?
CLEMENT: Well, I lived in two or three different places. First few years, I rented&#8230;rented houses &#8211; mostly lived on Highway 70, east of Woodbury.
MC: Highway 53.
HATCH: Going towards Manchester?
MC: Yes.
CLEMENT: That's where we finally became established.
MC: We were there longer than anywhere.
HATCH: Okay. So were you in the county, in Cannon County?
CLEMENT: Yeah, lived in Cannon County.
HATCH: Okay, and that's where you finally staked your house, your claim out when you bought?
CLEMENT: Well after married, why of course we had one child, and then uh, we had one daughter. Later on, twins were born and I decided it was time to get out and get a place of our own instead of paying rent, why I bought ten acres of land four miles south of Woodbury city limits on Manchester Highway, and uh, I was fortunate to get it at that time, got a good price on it back then. Built a house and established a residence there.
25:00
HATCH: Did you farm yourself on your ten acres?
CLEMENT: Well, there wasn't enough of it to keep farmed and too much of it to keep mowed. So I had, uh, established the open land in front as grass and legumes and it was used for hay. I planted trees on a couple of acres in the back that was gulley. It was really full of gulleys. I planted some trees there and they grew up to be big. Now my driveway, which was about four hundred feet long, I planted white pines every so far apart. And some of them are still standing today, and uh, I don't know if any one has sold the other trees. I don't know if they've been sold or not. They were big enough to sell. A lot of the trees that the farmers planted up there and of course there wasn't a big number of them. But, uh, they have grown up and clear&#8208;cutted for logs. And that needs time. Of course, planting forests, planting pine trees in Hardeman County was one of the big items and so was terracing. They had some gulleys down there that you could set a house in. That soil was just bad to erode, gulley erosion. Lots of kudzu was planted down there. In other words, you used the practice or agriculture practice or conservation need, whatever will fit the need. Down there it was gulley erosion and kudzu was a good cover for it and kept the whole soil.
HATCH: Um, do you remember where your office was located in Cannon County?
CLEMENT: The office was there when I was there. It was located upstairs in a room on the second floor on the southeast corner of the building.
HATCH: Okay, was that on Adams Street, or what was near it at that point? Was there a school near there?
CLEMENT: County courthouse.
HATCH: It was in the county courthouse? Right downtown.
CLEMENT: Right downtown.
HATCH: Okay, southeast corner of the courthouse.
CLEMENT: Upstairs. That's where the office was when I went there and that's where it was when I retired.
HATCH: Okay, that's good to know, and you said you used the practice, whatever fits the need.
CLEMENT: Yeah.
HATCH: What were the needs in Cannon County?
CLEMENT: Well, some of the land in Cannon County...Cannon County is varied in types of soils. Of course, you have the flatland up on the Cumberland Plateau. In other words, the county is kind of on that slope. You had the hills and they were wooded. A lot of the open fields on the hills were plowed with teams. Mules and planted corn. And they would make good corn. It was good soil. And then, of course, you had a lot of good land in the Auburntown area. That was good for flatland, creekland. The land, the level land in the county, you got part near base that was good, the same in Rutherford County. It joins Rutherford, Coffee, Warren, Dekalb, and Wilson. That's all the way around it. They needed&#8230;most of the things that they needed, you couldn't do much to those hills that were being planted by mules&#8230;planted by plows. Some strip cropping, there was some strip cropping. 30:00
HATCH: What does that mean?
CLEMENT: That means a row around on the contour with corn, a space skipped and another down there. In other words, that prevented erosion.
HATCH: Did you introduce any crops to Cannon County or SCS?
CLEMENT: The SCS had some that they promoted. Of course, you've got to remember that there were certain requirements and, uh, specifications for these different practices, and uh, the crops were introduced, I don't suppose they were already being used.
HATCH: So what were some of the things you were introducing?
CLEMENT: Well, we'd recommend that they'd use fescue and clovers. I didn't introduce those, they were already in existence.
HATCH: And what was the purpose of the fescue and clovers?
CLEMENT: Pasture and hay for livestock.
HATCH: Anything else?
CLEMENT: And on the flat land out there, a lot of that was woods in those times, and uh, there was an old story that went around if you lived in the Barrens, which they called flat land up out there, you just couldn't make it anywhere else, and they said that farmers out there would buy corn from the hill farmers. It&#8217;s a changed situation later on. There was a gradual change because people cleared a lot of the land out there and some places drained it. It was thought to be good quality land. It isn&#8217;t the best quality land going, but if you manage it right, it's good land. That's where your good crop land fields are now, on the flatter land.
HATCH: Wasn't that up on Short Mountain, the Barrens?
CLEMENT: Short Mountain was a peculiar formation, I understand. It's not really connected with any mountains anywhere else, it's just up there. Beautiful.
MRS C: You introduced no till.
CLEMENT: Well, that comes later on.
HATCH: The Barrens were referred to the Barrens because of, would they not grow anything or&#8230;?
CLEMENT: They just weren't being used.
HATCH: Just weren't being used.
CLEMENT: Even in history, in the Civil War, when troops were trying to get from Nashville to Chattanooga, there's reference to that kind of land and they trouble they had trying to get through it with their guns and artillery and things. I mean, history records that, but it turned out that after they cleared the land it dried up more and they started using a lot of lime and fertilizers on it and growing crops on it, why it makes good&#8230;and put a lot of fertilizer to make that a good crop. Today's a different picture than it was in the '50s and '60s. A lot of open land there now that was in woods. And the quality of timber that was on it was poor, because, as the old saying goes, it was &#8220;blackjack land.&#8221; Now on the hills there was good timber. Good timber.
HATCH: The Barrens grew poor timber?
CLEMENT: Well, it was poor. There was a type of vegetation on it that it wasn't profitable.
HATCH: So, it was kind of hard to walk through, that's why the troops had a time 'cause it brambled up or&#8230;it wasn't timber.
35:00
CLEMENT: Yep, it wasn't timber. Now of course one the things I did. The Soil Conservation Service didn't do it but they pushed for a program of fire control. Now, a fire control unit that was recently established in that period of time, of course that came out of the forestry service, but that's part of conservation anyway and it was good to keep it from burning over because most of the forest land was hills. Hills burned as well as out there. Now that was a good thing that happened of course. The Soil Conservation Service didn't do it but we cooperated with them, and uh&#8230;
HATCH: I just find it odd that something that produced so many trees, that they would call it barren but that's the terms you got to use.
CLEMENT: Some of them call it barrens [bear&#8208;ins], some call it barrens [bar&#8208;ins]. Oh, I don't know. Whatever.
HATCH: Well, let's talk a little bit about the photographs if we can. How did you come to start documenting the work that you were doing out there? Were you still in the same position as educator at that point or had you moved up to conservator or&#8230;?
CLEMENT: No, I was the soil conservationist for the district.
HATCH: When was that? When did it happen?
CLEMENT: It happened when I went up there in '59.
MC: No, honey. In '51.
CLEMENT: '51. Yeah. '51.
HATCH: So you were soil conservationist and educator. You did all those jobs at the same time?
CLEMENT: Well, that's part of the whole thing &#8211; District conservationist. Work with the farmers in planning their farms and planning the conservation practices to be used on the farms. Of course it was the farmer's final decision, but we might make recommendations for this land use or that land use and he might go along with it and lots of times you'd suggest good conservation practices and recommend them and a lot of them were adopted. The making of the pictures were just to show some of the work, some of the pictures that are typical of that particular practice and not the only thing that was done. Far from that because the pictures that are shown on one place might be carried out at different places, other different farms. They encourage it, the farmers encourage it. And we use the pictures in exhibits for fairs. And we show them were there's different opportunities to show them. Show them at fairs and at schools. Sometimes we'd go to the schools and show some of those and maybe a film strip, a short film strip, on conservation. Cause that's where the 4H work and extension service. Of course, the extension service was more into agronomy and livestock and things like that. Of course, they would recommend, go along with, whatever program we were trying to get over so they could help us or we could encourage them or help them or if the needed a forester why we an area forester that served that county and he could work there. Also we put out a newsletter one year or maybe a couple of years. And used them there and in different places and of course it more or less kind of documented the work that was being done and carried out and it didn't cover everything but it covered what was being done by the farmers.
HATCH: So you were Soil Conservation District nineteen? Is that correct?
CLEMENT: Didn't have a number.
HATCH: Okay, what counties were covered?
40:00
CLEMENT: Just Cannon County.
HATCH: Just Cannon County?
CLEMENT: Mmhmm.
HATCH: Okay. So does that mean there were ninety eight Soil Conservation Districts in Tennessee? Or did they group some counties together?
CLEMENT: Really, I don't know. I don't know. Is that one of the pictures there?
HATCH: Yeah, I want to actually go through some of these things if you don't mind and figure out what some of these things are just for our purposes. If you could tell me&#8230; Let it be said that this is photograph T&#8208; 2523&#8208;5 of Joe Melton stream channel been improved by realigning and sloping the sides". So the first number we have is 10&#8208;21&#8208;64, the second number here has been covered up by a green marker. Is that a negative number?
CLEMENT: I don't know what that means cause I'm not familiar with that. But this is actually the date that it was made.
HATCH: Okay, and the subject is stream channel improvement.
CLEMENT: Mmhmm.
HATCH: The photographer, of course, is you.
CLEMENT: Mmhmm. HATCH: Location?
CLEMENT: One mile east of Woodbury, Tennessee. Joe Melton, Route 2, farm &#8211; Woodbury's the address.
HATCH: So that's Joe Melton's farm on Route 2 in Woodbury. So then it just says "Soil or Watershed. TN&#8208;SCD". Which I assume was Soil Conservation District nineteen. Now maybe they put that on there. You didn't have that.
CLEMENT: No I didn't put that on there. I can't tell you.
HATCH: Okay.
CLEMENT: A stream channel that had been improved by realigning and enlarging and sloping the sides was Joe Melton.
HATCH: Well, how did all that information get on the back? Did you log this information while you were doing this?
CLEMENT: Yes.
HATCH: And what did you log this information in? Was it a notebook that they provided?
CLEMENT: Yeah.
HATCH: So that was part of it?
CLEMENT: Mmhmm.
HATCH: How did they know, when they printed the pictures which occurred&#8230;how they correlated? How did they know to put this information on the back of that picture do you think?
CLEMENT: Oh I don't know. I don't know who done that or how it got on there.
HATCH: Okay.
CLEMENT: We sent the film into the Soil Conservation office in Nashville, and uh, from there on and what happened, I don't know the process.
HATCH: Did you send the log books as well?
CLEMENT: Well the information that's on there, yeah.
HATCH: Did you just send the whole book and they would send you the book back later or do you remember?
CLEMENT: Oh it went&#8230;it went in with the film.
HATCH: So what I think would be interesting to find out is how whoever printed this knew to tell the person to type this information on the back of it.
CLEMENT: Now I don't know how that happened. HATCH: Well maybe that's something I can see if I can find out from the SCS folks. I finally got in touch with them. They tell me they've got three warehouses they haven't opened up in years and years and years and that might be where the negatives are. When they told me that&#8230;he was also saying "Please don't make me". You could just hear in his voice that he did not want to deal with this particular problem but you never know.
CLEMENT: Well now they've changed. Soil Conservation Service has been changed to, uh, uh, got another title now, I don't know what it is.
HATCH: I think Clinton changed it&#8230;it&#8217;s like&#8230;it's not soil anymore. It's, like, National&#8230;
CLEMENT: National Conservation&#8230;
HATCH: NCCS I think.
CLEMENT: And they have a whole bunch of different objectives and different things, but it&#8217;s...
HATCH: Environmental now I suppose. Well, I know you don't believe this but I take pictures&#8230;oh, can you tell us about your camera? How did the camera come about? What was it and how did you come in contact&#8230;how did you come to have that camera? Not necessarily, the one you bought but the one you first started shooting on. Did that come with the office?
CLEMENT: This one?
HATCH: Well, which ever one you first started shooting on?
CLEMENT: Oh, the first one, the uh, the uh, Nashville office, uh, had, uh&#8230;we had an area office over so many counties that comes into this area office and they had one camera that was a Crown Graphic just like this one and they passed it around different places, different counties. And they're hard to come by and so I decided that I'd buy one. And I bought this camera, paid for it.
HATCH: Would word come from Nashville to move the camera, to give it to someone else? Or would someone just come over and pick it up?
45:00
CLEMENT: Well, I picked it up at a photograph store. I bought it at the store, and paid $150 for it.
MC: He&#8217;s talking about the camera in Nashville.
HATCH: The first one. How did you come to get&#8230;if someone needed it, would they just kind of borrow it from you? How did you come to get the first one from other people? You only had one to share.
CLEMENT: Oh, they passed it around one time and I got it and I made some pictures and I decided that, uh, I couldn&#8217;t get it off enough and I had to send it back, pass it around.
HATCH: Send it back to Nashville and someone else would get it there? CLEMENT: Yeah or from another county. I don&#8217;t remember just how it worked but that&#8217;s how it worked.
MC: You took it back to Nashville. You took it back to Nashville.
HATCH: Mrs. Clemons is saying that you took it back to Nashville and someone else would come and get it.
MC: I&#8217;m sure he did. Don&#8217;t you think you picked it up there and you took it back there when you went for a meeting.
CLEMENT: I don&#8217;t remember.
MC: I&#8217;m pretty sure.
HATCH: Okay. What I was going to say is that you may not think it but somebody took some pictures and you&#8217;ve got a good eye, uh, for taking photographs. Did you ever consider any artistic value to any of these photos?
CLEMENT: I was showing what was actually taking place on the ground.
HATCH: So you just saw yourself as a documentarian?
CLEMENT: And that&#8217;s the way it started.
HATCH: And where&#8217;d it go, if that&#8217;s the way it started? This is not an example of what I&#8217;m speaking of but this photo that we had talked about earlier of the stream channel improvement with Joe Melton, Route 2, Woodbury&#8230;sometimes you take your subjects and you put them in the corner of the photograph, sometimes you put them on the left hand side and it shows more of, um, it shows more of the landscape. That, to me, is an artistic statement because most people when they take a picture &#8211; don&#8217;t take photographs &#8211; they&#8217;ll put a subject right in the middle, centered in on everything and that&#8217;s what they have. But there are several images of yours that are, um, they seem to be more artistic, to be taken with an eye, you know what you&#8217;re doing, you&#8217;re not just focusing on one person but you&#8217;re focusing on the people and the area and you&#8217;re bringing in a lot of things. Was that a conscious decision?
CLEMENT: Yes, well, that&#8217;s not the way it happened. See the project and know it well and what would look good on a picture and I&#8217;d make it.
HATCH: So you did have an eye for it.
CLEMENT: Well, I don&#8217;t know.
MC: I think he does.
HATCH: I know he does.
CLEMENT: Now, I&#8217;m no artistic nothing. What I was trying to get was a good picture of a particular project so that it might mean something to somebody sometime. HATCH: Did you have limitless film? Did you have as much film as you needed or did they only give you a certain amount?
CLEMENT: Well, they didn&#8217;t have no&#8230;didn&#8217;t have no special amount but, um, every time I requested some film, why they provided it.
HATCH: Okay. I was looking here at this second photograph that we&#8217;ve got. It looks to be a little bit older because it&#8217;s faded some. &#8220;Gary Vinson and George Mayo cutting and spiking tobacco.&#8221; Which we have in the exhibits. It&#8217;s one of my favorite ones. Two things about this: First, that number that was at the top of the photo that we didn&#8217;t know what it was is repeated here. This one is T&#8208;2112&#8208;1 which corresponds with a number up here on the front and that&#8217;s why I was thinking maybe this was a negative number to be able to do that. Would that ring a bell to you, this number on the front, by any chance?
CLEMENT: No, I can&#8217;t tell you anything about that.
HATCH: Okay&#8230;let&#8217;s&#8230;I&#8217;m going to read you&#8230;
CLEMENT: That&#8217;s unusual. Of course, tobacco now you got to remember, years ago what every farmer that had tobacco, he counted on that as good income, and that&#8217;s one of the crops that they raised and that was an unusually good crop of tobacco on a good piece of ground and showed workers working which I don&#8217;t know if you&#8217;d get one like that there or not.
HATCH: No, it&#8217;s not a money crop anymore.
CLEMENT: Well, they&#8217;ve been restricted on the amount that they can grow, and uh, of course, every county that had been growing tobacco had an allotment, and uh, it was a valuable thing to have because it brought in a lot of money.
50:00
HATCH: Can you explain to someone who doesn&#8217;t know what you&#8217;re talking about what an allotment is?
CLEMENT: Restricted. The government says you can grow only so much tobacco and we&#8217;re going to check on it to see if you overplanted.
HATCH: Does that keep the cost up on it?
CLEMENT: I guess it has something to do with that. I don&#8217;t know. In other words, it was a particular situation because they could only have so much allotment for a county and whatever you had been growing, usually that&#8217;s what they gave in allotment. That wasn&#8217;t made by our office. That was made by the Agriculture State Reservation Conservation, which we worked closely with the Agriculture State Reservation Conservation because they paid us partial payments on some of these conservation projects that were carried out. I don&#8217;t know how they arrived at&#8230;used to they even had allotments on cotton. Out in East Tennessee they had allotments on cotton. I suppose that was an overall government program on supply and also keep something scarce, it makes it more valuable. HATCH: Exactly. Well let me read something on the back and you can help me explain this. &#8220;Gary Vinson and George Mayo&#8221;, these are young men in tobacco fields, &#8220;cutting and spiking tobacco. Burley 21 is being grown on Class III Mimosa soil.&#8221; Is Burley 21 a type of tobacco?
CLEMENT: That&#8217;s a variety.
HATCH: A variety of tobacco. &#8220;Being grown on Class III Mimosa soil.&#8221;
CLEMENT: Well, Mimosa soil is defined as having certain characteristics. It&#8217;s good growing soil and it&#8217;s good land use. In other words, they pitted the tobacco project. Pitted the ground. I mean by that red fertilize it and maybe put a one color crop on it and have pretty good soil to grow it on anyway. All the soil is classified into different classes depending on the different characteristics of it. That&#8217;s what soil signage did. And, uh, he would have a photograph, an aircraft photograph that, uh, ever so big, and he would go out there and draw lines on it and give you the name of the soil and the slope and erosion index on it. That was information we furnished the farmer along with his plan. And he had a&#8230;of course they probably didn&#8217;t know all the different names of the soil but they knew their soil. They knew what they were doing. They knew when this hill would do this and this one would do this. He knew the, uh, what he was doing. The uplands soils out there, the richest soil, the best are the river bottoms. That&#8217;s Class one soil. Flat, level terrain, and uh&#8230;
HATCH: F Full of nutrients from the rivers.
CLEMENT: Yeah, just naturally rich, just naturally fertile.
HATCH: How many classes of soil were there?
CLEMENT: Well the land classified seven different classes.
HATCH: So is seven like rock? Seven&#8217;s pretty bad then?
CLEMENT: Well, yeah, maybe rock land.
HATCH: County&#8217;s kind of got that do, doesn&#8217;t it?
CLEMENT: It&#8217;s got some. It&#8217;s got some rock land, and they had a lot of Class I in the Stones River bottoms and coming through there. So are creek bottoms. They had a Class one soil.
HATCH: Do they still classify it in the same way?
CLEMENT: Well, it don&#8217;t change. One classification to the other, it&#8217;s the same thing. If the soil signage saw it; it would be the same.
HATCH: Can you just pick it up and tell what kind it is?
CLEMENT: I couldn&#8217;t. The soils man could. He would have a soil auger that he would bore in there and see it and look at it and classify it as that, and a lot of the soil out there in the flat land is what they call Dickson soil. It&#8217;s got a hard pan on it. Otherwise it can be handled. Put lime to it and fertilize it and proper cultivation and make good crops. 55:00
HATCH: Okay.
CLEMENT: Farmers used to plant their corn maybe fifteen&#8230;twelve, fifteen, eighteen inches apart in rows 3 feet apart and then it looks like it&#8217;s been sowed, there planting so thick. But that&#8217;s another story. That came later on. The farming changed a lot over there.
HATCH: Maybe that would be a good place to pick up on the next interview. Is that something you would like? We could cut the interview here and pick up the rest of it the next time through. Do you want to do that?
CLEMENT: Well, you could, of course. There was a big change in farming during that period of time because in the 50s and 60s, there was a lot of horse drawn equipment and very few tractors. Then on the flat land out there, they got to having a few tractors out there. Then they got to having bigger tractors and bigger machinery and farming in a more efficient way, a more productive way.
HATCH: So that changes the role of the SCS at that point.
CLEMENT: Well, uh, some of the practices that they carried out was initially adopted from other places. In other words, when it&#8217;s slow about progress, it&#8217;s slow about going from one farm to another. Sometimes a good practice can&#8217;t get across a fence. But out there it&#8217;s changed so much that it&#8217;s hard to believe today. Even since &#8217;74, there&#8217;s been lots of changes that are taking place out there today, and uh, one of the practices that we stressed later on, in the &#8216;70s and late &#8216;60s, was no till or limited till cultivation. And who ever heard of that out there or anywhere else? But it was working other places and it finally got around to working out there where they can go out in a field and sage grass or color crop and poison it down and spray it and then go back over and plant it and got machinery to do it with. Back then, even before I quit, they had the knowledge to do this, but uh, farm machinery people hadn&#8217;t caught up with it; they didn&#8217;t have that kind of equipment, because uh, they had sprays and they had different nozzles on it. You could spray your field and if you wanted to spray a crop of corn, the nozzles wouldn&#8217;t work. You had to have the right kind of equipment and sprays and all to do the job right. Of course, now that&#8217;s sort of a process. I remember the first no till planter that was bought in Cannon County.
HATCH: Who bought it?
CLEMENT: Eric Cooper and his son still owns the land and he&#8217;s changed it to livestock, pasture and all.
HATCH: What does tilling do? Why would you go away from tilling? I&#8217;ve heard of this before but I&#8230;
CLEMENT: When you till&#8230;they used to think it was absolutely necessary to plant the corn and plow it. You had to plow it two or three times&#8230;maybe three times. They used to think that was necessary but now they&#8217;ve found out that you don&#8217;t have to plow at all. If you told someone that in the &#8216;60s, they wouldn&#8217;t believe you.
1:00:00 HATCH: Okay.
CLEMENT: They found out now that if you&#8217;ve got the equipment, you&#8217;ve got to have the equipment to do it with, but uh, and a lot of the farmers out there now are doing a good job. They know what they&#8217;re doing and they know how to do it. Of course, in the process, of course that flat land out there didn&#8217;t have the erosion problem but some of the heavier, sloping fields did. They didn&#8217;t have the erosion problem but they lacked a lot of other things. They lacked fertilizer and they lacked lime, and uh, one of the best rotations that I could recommend or we could recommend was grass based rotation. In other words, grass for two or three years then plow it up and grow corn on it. And at one time&#8230;at one time there, there was a lot of people that had a lot of pasture, a lot of livestock. That called for pastures. That called for water, ponds of water for livestock. Different fields. It&#8217;s changed. It&#8217;s a different things then. No till farming and uh&#8230;is one of the best things that ever happened to us for soil erosion because you leave the color on the ground and protect it through the winter. They have planters that drill, go right through the stubble and through the conifer and put the seed corn fertilizer in there and just drive on and come back when the corn&#8217;s ready together.
HATCH: So how do they get the seed in the ground?
CLEMENT: With a drill.
HATCH: They just drill a single hold, throw a thing in there? Okay.
CLEMENT: Maybe plant five rows at a time, six rows at a time, or four rows at a time depending on the equipment you have. But that&#8217;s one of the best practices for soil erosion that, uh, someone had made the statement that it would but Soil Conservation out of business because it had done such a good job and was that kind of practice. But the no till practice had started in the Great Plains States. They worked on it and worked on it and they of course found out what they could do with it. It just covered the whole country.
HATCH: Do you remember who discovered that? Did you believe in it when you first heard about no till? Did it seem like a good idea?
CLEMENT: Well, yeah. It was a good idea&#8230;it wasn&#8217;t my thinking. It wasn&#8217;t my discovery, it was up for the researchers. What we what we would recommend was in accordance with recommendation. It wasn&#8217;t something wild, some wild program or something like that. We did&#8230;Soil Conservation Service did get off on the wrong track on a few things I guess but that took care of itself. Kudzu&#8217;s one of them. Of course they say now that every part of a kudzu plant is edible. Cattle like it; goats like it; livestock like it. You can&#8217;t control it.
HATCH: Like bamboo.
CLEMENT: Well yeah. Of course, they didn&#8217;t have that problem in Cannon County. There were a few fields that had kudzu up there that were planted before I went up there. Some of it is still there. It&#8217;s not widely accepted here in Middle Tennessee. Of course go down into Mississippi and Georgia and Arkansas and there&#8217;s a place for it. HATCH: Can you tell me when you retired? Can you tell me when you retired?
CLEMENT: It was in &#8217;74.
HATCH: How long did you live in Cannon County after that?
CLEMENT: Until four years ago.
MC: 2004.
CLEMENT: Four years ago in the fall.
HATCH: What did you do in your retirement?
1:05:00
CLEMENT: Well, uh, I worked for a time with the Cannon County election commission. That helped me, gave me something to do&#8230;keep in contact with people. I had something going; I worked there just part time. I enjoyed that but my first love was the soil and conservation work. I tried to practice it on the little acreage that I had out there. I miss it today. Of course, when you get to a certain age you&#8217;ve got to do things different, you know.
HATCH: Did you take anymore photographs?
CLEMENT: No.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>United States. Soil Conservation Service; Oral history transcript;</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Rutherford County (Tenn.);</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro;</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text;</dc:type>
<dc:format>text;</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper;</dc:format>
<dc:format>20 p.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright Arts Center of Cannon County;</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>May be excerpted for educational and non-commercial uses with attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Arts Center of Cannon County</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/cannon/id/406</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>