<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>W.L. Clement oral history. Transcript. Part 2</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Clement, William L., interviewee; Vincent, Mickey, interviewer</dc:creator>
<dc:contributor>Hatch, Evan, recorder</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>2009-10-14</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009;</dc:coverage>
<dc:title>Photographs of W.L. Clement, U.S. Soil Conservation Service</dc:title>
<dc:description>Evan Hatch interview with William L. Clement Part 2: October 14, 2009
Interview conducted in anticipation of submitting photographs by Mr. Clement for digitization at the James E. Walker Library, MTSU.
HATCH: Okay, this is Evan Hatch and Mickey Vincent. We are recording an interview with W. L. Clement at his home, 2927 Tower Drive Murfreesboro, TN 37129. The date is October 14, 2009 and today Mickey and myself, mostly Mickey is the voice you'll be hearing as the interviewer, will be talking to Mr. Clement about his time in the Soil Conservation Service and some of the activities that you did. This interview will be known from hereon out as W. L. Clement 10.14.2009 Part 1. This will most likely be in one single part. Mickey, let it roll.
VINCENT: Okay. I thought we were going to let Mr. Clement read. So shall we go ahead and let him read and that will get me a little more familiar with what he's saying and go from there.
[The following section was read by Mr. Clement from a statement prepared in advance. The complete statement is included in Part 1 of the oral history]
CLEMENT: This is a series of photographs of soil water conservation practices on farmland in the county, which were planned by the farmers and carried out under the supervision of the Cannon County Soil Conservation District during the time period of 1950 through the mid&#8208;1970s. These photographs shown the typical practices carried out on many farms in the county during this time period. The Soil Conservation Service was an agency of the Department of Agriculture and was nationwide with districts in all counties in Tennessee. It was an agency which was established to address the work on projects to solve the erosion on farmland. The overall program for counties and states over the nation were varied in many ways because of the needs and requirements to solve erosion problems. The soils was mapped and classified by soil scientists to make the best use of the land or used as a basis in planting and establishing practices to solve problems of soil erosion. Individual plans were developed with land owners to be carried out using conservation practices. All farmlands have a best use either for cultivating crops, pastureland, grassland, woodland, or planting trees or just let nature take place, especially on farmland &#8208; rock land. Uh, the use should be the most profitable use. Some of the practices included sowing water on farmland and color crops, contour cultivation, crop rotation to include grasses and clovers, terracing to direct water to a suitable outlet, and pastures to include grasses and legumes. Diversions are structures to prevent water from running down sloping land and causing erosion. Strip cropping, grassed waterways, and natural drainage ways, fields to prevent water flowing in its natural drain. The planting of trees on land not suited for cultivation for hay or row crops, farm ponds for water for livestock, fish production for food and recreation. Stream channel improvement, sloping and vegetation banks, drainage where needed on farmland and woodland improvement. Wildlife border feed with shrubs and seed producing plants for quail and rabbits controlled erosion by seeding road banks on county roads on a limited basis. Seeding, liming, and mulch were provided by the Soil Conservation Service as a special project. Waterways were shaped and seeded to conduct water to a safe outlet. Stream channel improvement by sloping and vegetation banks and drains were needed on farmlands or where trees were planted where best for that use. A tree planter was purchased by the local bank for use. The tree seedlings were bought by the farmers from the Tennessee Forestry Department. The structural practices on farms were designed and laid out and constructed &#8208; supervised to meet standards by a program in the Service. All structure projects had to meet standards by the Soil Conservation Service.
5:00
CLEMENT: The District cooperated with all other agricultural agencies serving landowners in the county. Referrals from agricultural programs offices which farmers had applied for payment on construction practices were received and completed. The Soil Conservation Service did not make payments on completed conservation practices. We only furnished technical service on those practices. The relationship between those agencies was very cooperative in assisting farmers and applying conservation practices. No till or minimum till practices were started on a few farms under the guidance of (an area botanist?). This practice was rapidly increasing in the early 70s. Special planters were required which were bought by the farmers. This new practice was great for preventing soil erosion. The introduction of conductive fair water fescue (?) was recommended and used for pasture and hay crop rotation. Soil Conservation Service provided layout, design, and supervision of construction of Lake Ann. The landowners financed all the work for the construction. This project was the focus for a whole new community. Here are some of the activities to promote soil conservation: exhibits at the county fair, pine seedling planted by boy scouts on Short Mountain and by schoolchildren on some school grounds, display of practices and pictures at the offices, promote conservation at community meetings especially meetings held by farm personnel, newspaper articles, district helped to establish county forest control, the district assisted in starting the deer release, assisted town, county, and schools in projects related to conservation. A one time project to treat roadside erosion on county roads by liming, fertilizing, seeding, and mulching, crown vets(?) was seeded in this project on several miles of roadway, Cannon County Highway Department provided labor for this project. Provided technical service on projects we were permitted to work with town of Woodbury and Public Service, this same service was also provided to the county. This is a brief overview of some of the work on the Soil Conservation District personnel during the time period of the 50s, 60s, and the first half of the 70s. District Conservationist was William L. Clement. Conservation aide was Herman Young. The pictures displayed are some of the conservation practices being carried out by many farms in the county during this time period.
VINCENT: Well, that was pretty enlightening. Of course I remember the Lake Ann project from a different angle and that would be the legal angle. The people were Coco, uh, what, was it Frank Coco? What was his first name? I can't remember.
CLEMENT: Frank.
VINCENT: Was it Frank? Okay. That was a really big project and I just really didn't realize that it was part of the land&#8230;the Soil Conservation thing. I always thought it was something that he just did privately. So, could we talk a little bit about that and what all that entailed?
CLEMENT: Well, first of all he came into the county as a&#8230;from outsider and said that he wanted to establish residence there in the county and he was looking for a place for a lake. He had the intention of establishing a&#8230;probably a&#8230;he said that some of the people in the, uh, industry in which he worked would be, uh, interested in living there too.
VINCENT: And what was that industry?
CLEMENT: He was a blast&#8230;a designer and operator of blast&#8230;steel blast furnaces &#8211; in the steel industry.
VINCENT: Okay.
CLEMENT: And he was working in Mexico. This project, the reason we got involved in it&#8230;it involved considerable technique. If you recall the area that was there, uh, was owned by Eugene Reed and it was woodland. Well he cut them trees that were marketable, and uh&#8230;
VINCENT: Eugene Reed did?
CLEMENT: Yeah, and then sold it. And he had a side on it, on which he wanted to build a lake. And the Soil Conservation Program had what they called a watershed program, where the uh&#8230;that was organized and they made some big lakes&#8230;or dug some lakes to hold water, hold back erosion. And, uh, now there had been flooding downstream. And the pond or lake was designed that it would hold a lot of the water back and that what was done in that case there.
VINCENT: As I recall, there were a couple of creeks in that area, and they would just be running across the road, and if went down the road, you just went into the creek and on out the other side.
CLEMENT: Mmm hum.
VINCENT: And that would be water that collected in the lake?
CLEMENT: Yeah, and those watershed programs, uh, was the standard in which the engineers designed this. Of course, my job on it was, uh, was uh, the surveying work on the land and the engineers took the, uh, field work of the survey and designed the levy and outlet and all. And of course the landowner paid for, uh, he built it himself. In other words, the only assistance he got from us was technical assistance, and uh, it also those lakes that was built in watershed programs, and it might have been a program where they had several different locations for it to hold detention water, and uh, it fell into the category of legality of responsibility even though it probably was for his own use. As it turns out, all that land, or a lot of that land that he bought, he didn't know what to do with it. So, he thought he'd sell some lots off, and he did. And, uh, the lots that he sold around the lake had lake privileges, lake use privileges, fish in the water, and anything they wanted to use it for, and uh&#8230;
VINCENT: Now, did that have a time limit restriction on it? Do you remember?
CLEMENT: Yes, it was the owner's. The owner had a right to do it for 25 years, and there was a number of them built around a particular time. And then uh, after that, it became the property of&#8230;it became private property after 25 years.
VINCENT: Private property of the owner or private property of the owner of each individual lot?
CLEMENT: Of course, they had easements to do that. Of course the lake changed hands two or three times in ownership, but, uh, basically, it was started by that project, and other land around there, after he, uh, decided to sell lots off it. Why, they sold off some mid lots. All the land was sold around the lake, and other people had come in that joined it, and they just kind of&#8230;a community there, and uh, the uh&#8230;
VINCENT: And the road that goes back to the lake, uh, is named for his daughter, Ann. Lake Ann.
CLEMENT: That's right.
VINCENT: So from your perspective, it was the control of the watershed and the, uh, erosion purposes and everything. You helped with the design for that?
CLEMENT: Well I had an engineer and design the lake, and it was constructed for the specific requirements of the project, and uh&#8230;
VINCENT: And it would've been the requirements state, federal, and agricultural department?
CLEMENT: Yup, and of course it uh, recreation was one of the things that was permitted and public relations and uh, on that particular project and of course it's been built there for a long time.
VINCENT: Well, yes, I was in on that from a little bit different angle. Mr. Hort Bryson was the attorney that did all the deed work. So I wrote many, many, many of the deeds.
CLEMENT: I think Marshall Duggin worked for&#8230;was an agent for him. He built a home out there and, uh, he never did live in it, not one night.
VINCENT: He was still living in the trailer, or the mobile home, or whatever as I understand it when he passed away.
CLEMENT: He had, uh, well passed away.
VINCENT: But his wife continued the project.
CLEMENT: Well she was there until it was sold.
VINCENT: Do you remember his wife's name?
WOMAN: Ann.
VINCENT: Okay his daughter was Ann.
WOMAN: Well his daughter's name was Carol Ann.
VINCENT: Okay, Carol Ann? Okay. His wife is Ann. And his wife is Carol Ann, and that's the road name, Carol Ann Drive.
WOMAN: Carol Ann Drive.
CLEMENT: Of course, there's, uh, in Canon Country there's a hundred and seventy four thousand acres. At that time, back in the 50's, about half of it was in woodland, and, uh, about thirty&#8208;five percent of it was in crop production.
VINCENT: And the area out in Lake Ann around Woodland and all that, um, I remember it being called the Barn. When I grew up and saw the word and saw it "the barren." Do you remember it being kind of nonproductive?
CLEMENT: Well, I heard the story told that, uh, the people lived out there, the land wasn't suited. A lot of it was in woodland, and a lot of it was wet. They said that people out there had to buy corn from corn that was produced in the hills. Now, it's the probably other way around. Of course, uh, one of the earliest people out there I suppose that took a real hand in clearing a lot of that land and getting started in production was A.J. Atnip's daddy. He, uh, it wasn't him. It was where A.J. lives. It was another man that opened up some of that woodland and, uh, started liming and fertilizing, and some of it was grain.
MC: Found out it would grow something.
20:00
CLEMENT: Today it's the most productive areas of agriculture was out there in the bottoms &#8211; Stones River Bottom, the area around Bradyville &#8211; in that area there &#8211; and Auburntown and Short Mountain. Those were the main agriculture places. In the early days, they were still planting corn on those steep hills using a horse drawn turning plow. That soil was really good on the hill that would make good stuff if you could draw locust bushes and other problems that goes along with it, but it would certainly make good corn. Of course, when they started using fertilizer on it, it even made better corn. They prospered there and of course they used that hill land and level land that might be at the foothills, uh, for farming. It was really suited for that type of farming and that type of land really suited small farmers and uh, with dairy production in mind. You remember the Armor Creamery? VINCENT: Oh, absolutely.
CLEMENT: And you remember, oh I don't know, I think upwards of, probably uh, two thousand people worked there. And they kept expanding it two or three times, and uh, made shirts there.
VINCENT: So, you're thinking of the Colonial Shirt Factory that made shirts. Now the Armor Creamery was down there behind where Woodbury Funeral was.
CLEMENT: That's right.
VINCENT: My daddy hand milked just a few cows and put it into the milk cans and would haul it into the&#8230;well, maybe somebody would come pick it up. I don't remember, I was just a little girl.
HATCH: Is there any part of the building left?
VINCENT: No. It's all&#8230; Well, I don't know. Is that rounded thing down there part of it?
CLEMENT: It's part of it. Creamery. Armor Creamery.
VINCENT: We need to ask Al Harmon and Kenny Gilley about that to further something about that.
CLEMENT: Of course, with that kind of land and, uh, good pastureland and a few cows to milk and the women worked in the shirt factory and that gave them&#8230; and don't forget, remember when tobacco allotments where in that area there? In other words, it was very seldom that you found any on the upland in the county.
VINCENT: Very seldom that you found any tobacco on the what kind of land?
CLEMENT: Upland, flat land.
VINCENT: Well, you just kind of told the story of my life with the hill farmer and the woman, the wife working at the shirt factory. My daddy and my uncle farmed together, you know, out where I lived, and, which is kind of just backed up to where you used to live, you'd go over by the ridges. The mule&#8208;run hillside turning plow and the bull&#8208;tongue plow and the double shovel&#8230;
CLEMENT: Double shovel or "gee&#8208;whiz".
VINCENT: Daddy never had a "gee&#8208;whiz". Now, that's the thing with the many prongs?
CLEMENT: Mmm hmm.
VINCENT: I have in my yard, the old horse&#8208;drawn corn planter that probably belonged to my grandfather. But I remember by daddy and my uncle using it until probably I was seven or eight years old. So I certainly remember those days and the erosion and the, uh, locust bushes I remember. The only time I remember my daddy going to the doctor or being afflicted in anyway was he stuck a locust. Didn't the locust have a burr or something on it?
CLEMENT: Oh yeah. A sticker.
VINCENT: A needle, a sticker on it. And he got that stuck in his hand and it set up blood poisoning. I think he was in the hospital a few days. Seems like as a little girl I can remember being around the Good Samaritan Hospital. Being on the outside if he was on the inside and we couldn't go in. But the locusts made the good fence posts.
25:00
CLEMENT: Oh yeah. There's a lot of farmers out in that hill area sold a lot of locust posts, sold to people out of the county.
VINCENT: And that was kind of their harvest that went along with the industry of the making a living on the farm.
CLEMENT: Of course, some of them would gather corn on the ground slide. Of course, there was&#8230;and today most of those hills have gone back&#8230;growed up. Not much farm on that steep land. Very difficult, hard work plowing with a two&#8208;way&#8230;to turn all the soil down the hill. Have to reverse at each end.
VINCENT: Have to reverse the&#8230; And I've got the metal part for one of those plow and my brother has a couple of them in his yard, that's the whole plow and he's got them painted and everything. I can certainly remember that and the flipping of the&#8230;my younger brother and I used to run from one end of the field to another just to see the flipping of the plow. That was entertainment then for us.
CLEMENT: Well, there's one, I never did see it in my time, but before my time they had, uh, what was called paddling corn. Fellow had to walk along with the, uh, and put the paddle above the corn stalk to keep the plow from not really hurting it &#8211; running over it. I heard of that but I never did see it, but I've heard them talk about it.
VINCENT: Daddy and Unc. plowed with what they called a double shovel. One&#8230;
CLEMENT: One was in front of the other.
VINCENT: One was in front of the other and one was turned one way and one was turned the other. One to throw the dirt away from the corn and not to dig into it and one throw back over and just get the weeds from between.
CLEMENT: Help keep the filth; well I call it filth, out.
VINCENT: Filth. That's what they called it. It was just the weeds and the grass. I remember daddy saying, "Well, we've got to get the filth out of the corn."
CLEMENT: Well, that was necessary. The corn would be good production.
VINCENT: The corn, uh, the production of the corn, as I remember it, daddy would put it in the&#8230;and this was going somewhere else, we're supposed to be interviewing you but I want to tell you about daddy and the corn crib. He always&#8230;when he shucked the corn, he always took out the very best of the corn and he had a special place that he put that and then we would take it to the, um, to Charlie's Powell's, um&#8230;um, gris mill. I mean gristmill, and get corn meal made out of it. Were you in Cannon County during those days, when&#8230;?
CLEMENT: Oh yeah. Mr. Powell &#8208; O'Dell.
VINCENT: O'Dell. Charlie was O'Dell's father.
CLEMENT: O'Dell was very, uh, was very responsible as far as his land is concerned. He was one of the first farmers to use, uh, no&#8208;till planting. And of course his sons followed him, and they followed the practices that he followed. Of course, O'Dell in addition to farming, he ran a sawmill and preached. Fine fellow, and uh&#8230;that's something&#8230;
VINCENT: Describe no&#8208;till farming just a little bit.
30:00
CLEMENT: Well, no&#8208;till started out in uh, during the Depression. I mean during the thirties, when they were having dust storms in the west and &#8211; I don't know if you remember, a little bit of dust came across Tennessee somewhere that fall. Well, they uh, sometimes necessity causes you to do something else. They found out that leaving too much of that land plowed up and loose, they started using a lot of grass and stuff like that and, uh, they found out that residue on the land would keep water from eroding the soil.
VINCENT: Keep the wind from blowing it away also.
CLEMENT: Yeah. They decided&#8230;they went from that to planting crops that had residue, even on the good farm land, level farm land, leave a lot of mulch, red crop residue on the ground and that gonna cover it. In other words, you have to use chemicals, and uh, the chemicals that they had in the early stages wasn't that equipped to do the job, and uh, now, and uh, they can go in and take the sprays that are available and spray the stuff on the field that come up green and, uh, then they'll go in there with a no&#8208;till planter and&#8230;and plant, and then they don't plow it at all.
VINCENT: Right. So, they kill off the grass and stuff that was growing.
CLEMENT: Everything, and settles&#8230;settle down.
VINCENT: And it becomes a fertilizer type thing?
CLEMENT: Well, it helps enrich the soil.
VINCENT: Enriches it. When they go into plant, is there some sort of implement that goes down into the ground and makes a little row or tears up the ground a little bit?
CLEMENT: Well that's the most recent thing. They have a planter, a disc that will cut through anything that's there and drop the grain&#8230;the soil&#8230;the grain in the furrow and then have some&#8230;the little wheels behind that cover it up, and then uh&#8230;then uh, today's planters are designed for that, but in the early stages they didn't have that so they&#8230;
VINCENT: So, how did the seed get into the soil in the early stages of no&#8208;till? Did they just put it out there and whatever got down in there came up?
CLEMENT: No, they drop it uniformly now but back then you'd just take it and plow and the planter would just plant the corn&#8230;just plant the corn. Of course you'd have to have an open or something, a furrow. Then they'd put the&#8230;
VINCENT: But what I'm saying is that there was something on the machinery that did make a little furrow into the soil. It didn't plow it up but it did make a little furrow?
CLEMENT: Little furrow and then the wheels behind now pack it, and uh&#8230;the early&#8230;before they started doing that, they just&#8230;they wouldn't have as much mulch&#8230;as much crop residue as you do now. In the early stages, they didn't go&#8230;they took a field, in the early stages they took a field that was already maybe had soy beans on it last year and go in there and plant it.
VINCENT: Put corn on it today or something.
CLEMENT: Of course, this machinery that can go through this deep mulch is relatively new&#8230;is new. Of course, they started out early with just a small planter that would, uh, just plant, uh, a row at a time.
VINCENT: Now, I can remember, my daddy just saying it was just get in there and turn up, like, eight inches of soil and everything, and they thought that was the proper thing to do back in that time, but then the no&#8208;till came in.
35:00
CLEMENT: It's called so many different things: no&#8208;till and planting on land that has deep mulch on it, and of course no&#8208;till means they used to plow corn at least three times; they thought they had to.
VINCENT: Right. Exactly. That's what I was talking about with daddy that they always had to go in there and just really turn the soil up and turn it upside down and everything. That was his, from what I remember, that was the way everyone thought you needed to do then. But now it's just&#8230;So, now what about crop rotation?
CLEMENT: Well, if you have&#8230;some of the best crops out there&#8230;there was a period of time when people had more livestock and had more pasture. When you have grass a few years and then turn it up and plant corn or soy beans or whatever you're going to plant on it, and, is uh, something that they would do. Just rotate it, rotate crops and sometimes they double crop. A grain, harvest a grain and plant soy beans&#8230;plant corn now, and uh, back to the, uh, to the early stages there, it started in the early 50s from all that clearing. All land was cleared out there that was flat and became cultivated land. Of course they had to, uh, add lime and fertilizer to it, and uh, to get, uh, good results, and uh, it's good to&#8230;it made good crop&#8230;made your crop better to rotate. It ought not the same crops on the field all the time. Same till the same thing, same crop, it's better to rotate it&#8230;put in, uh, put in maybe corn this year and maybe next year something else.
VINCENT: So, if you kept doing the same crop all the time, it depleted certain minerals or whatever out of the soil and if you put another crop on, it restored.
CLEMENT: Um hum. Yeah, you have to keep&#8230;you still have to fertilize. You've got to fertilize every crop that isn't a legume. Now legumes, clovers put nitrogen in the soil. Yeah, clovers and vetch is the same thing.
VINCENT: Of course, vetch is just coming up in pitch rows around my place and, of course, no vetch has ever been planted around there&#8230;I mean as far as my daddy planted it or us planting it. So, seeds got blown and everything I guess.
CLEMENT: And of course, the tobacco patches, it's very essential you pick the very best ground you got and fertilize it and put your tobacco there because that's where your money come in.
HATCH: May I ask you a question, Mr. Clement?
CLEMENT: Yes.
HATCH: Uh, you had talked about crop rotation.
CLEMENT: Mh&#8208;hum.
HATCH: I was wondering if it was difficult to convince a farmer to rotate crops because would they not lose part of their&#8230;they would lose their crop for a year, and therefore lose some of their money? If you were putting vetch on or something that they couldn't actually sell or eat themselves, how would that&#8230;do I have that right? I mean, if you put soybeans on or something on, you could use the soybeans. But if you use something like vetch or clover&#8212;what would that be&#8230;would that not be&#8230;
CLEMENT: That's considered the cover crop. Every tobacco patch that people used would have a cover crop on it. You'd use clover or small grain, something like that. Of course now they found out that tobacco's bad for you.
40:00
VINCENT: Not much tobacco growing going on now, but would they plant the vetch in the fall and let it grow over the winter? I remember the burning of the tobacco beds and everything. Is that when they burned of that cover crop?
CLEMENT: No, you'd turn it under &#8208; use the plow and turn it under.
VINCENT: I remember&#8230;we never had tobacco, but I remember some of the kids that were in my class, they would even be out of school at tobacco planting and tobacco harvesting time, um, but I remember them talking about burning tobacco beds. Is that when they sowed the seeds to get their plant?
CLEMENT: They burn the tobacco bed and work up the soil and seed the beds.
VINCENT: So why did they burn it?
CLEMENT: To kill the weed seed and keep the weeds from coming up.
VINCENT: Okay. So, that was actually a purification type thing to get rid of the seeds of any weeds or grasses. Okay&#8230;all right. They actually grew their plants and then they took their plants up and went out and planted it in their field.
CLEMENT: You talk about the crop rotation. That's something that comes natural&#8212;It's just a natural thing to do, especially if you got a pasture, you got to renovate that pasture sometime and the best thing to do that is to plow it up and put a crop or two of corn or soy beans on it then if you want it back in the grass, seed it again.
HATCH: After you harvest your corn or your soy beans?
CLEMENT: Well, yeah.
HATCH: So there would be a time where they wouldn't be growing anything on there anyway, is that correct?
CLEMENT: Well there'd be something. It'd be either grass or something that they were growing on there. In other words, they wouldn't lose anything by it. They'd just pasture up and then they'd come back and seed it in the fall.
VINCENT: They'd maybe have cattle grazing on it for a couple of years.
CLEMENT: Mm hum.
VINCENT: Well, I remember daddy, um, always cleaning out the barn and taking the manure, and&#8230;in the wagon pulled by the mule then he'd take it over there and spread it all over the&#8230;the pastureland and the next year it may be&#8230;it might be pastureland for several heads of cattle, and then&#8230;So, it's just kind of the natural cycle of the industry. CLEMENT: Yeah. Of course, now then out there, they, uh, at one time, I knew a man that grew soy beans and he grew those soy beans, uh, to sell the seed to other farmers because it makes good hay to feed mules to plow, and now then, uh, and now then, uh, it's one of the main crops out there.
VINCENT: There was a time when pepper was a big&#8230;were you still with the conservation&#8230;soil conservation when&#8230;?
CLEMENT: Yes, I was there when they had a market&#8230;they had a market for pepper.
HATCH: What kind of pepper?
CLEMENT: Bell peppers&#8230;bell peppers.
VINCENT: Everybody was growing bell peppers and the Daniels had a marketplace where they took their peppers to.
CLEMENT: Yeah, they had a collection point there.
VINCENT: What do you think brought that on? It was just kind of, um, all of the sudden everyone was growing peppers, and uh&#8230;
CLEMENT: I think it's sponsored by people who make food out of peppers.
VINCENT: Okay.
CLEMENT: I think that was kind of pushed by them; it was profitable for the farmers too.
VINCENT: But it was kind of almost like a flash in the pan; it went on for maybe like seven to ten years then I don't know anybody that grows it.
CLEMENT: Well, somebody else&#8230;somebody else got the market.
VINCENT: Got the&#8230;.oh, I see. So, would it have been a bidding contest?
CLEMENT: So much per pound, I think.
45:00
VINCENT: I know, I'm thinking about the product, where it got to the place to be put into the food, uh, did somebody say "Okay, we'll grow this pepper cheaper than Tennessee is growing or Cannon County"?
CLEMENT: I guess that's probably what happened.
VINCENT: Oh. Hmm.
CLEMENT: Competition, you know.
VINCENT: Yeah. Do you remember&#8230;how much time do we have left?
HATCH: About fifteen, sixteen minutes.
VINCENT: Let me talk just very briefly about this. Do you remember when you helped my daddy build the little lake down behind my house?
CLEMENT: Very distinctly&#8230;very vividly.
VINCENT: Tell me a little bit about that.
CLEMENT: Well, your daddy said he wanted a pond there, and uh, even though there was a spring there, I think it got weak in the summertime, and uh, It was, uh&#8230;it fell under the eligibility for a pond.
VINCENT: See, I didn't know that. I just&#8230;
CLEMENT: Of course, there's more to it than what it looks like because really you got to select a site where to fill a pond up then you got to cut what they call a pour trench straight across, all the way across from one side to the other. And then you put the topsoil on the back. Of course, uh, people operating bulldozers one time &#8211; let me get this statement in &#8211; at one time there was a lot of bulldozers in the county, several, but that was back in the time where you could get a bulldozer for eight or ten dollars an hour.
VINCENT: Wow.
CLEMENT: Now then it's out of this world. Anyway, back to your pond, that's what happened to cut a trench across and then find some clay dirt and put in the bottom of that to keep it from seeping under it, and it wasn't&#8230;I remember the pond and I'm glad that it helped good. I don't know of any pond that we ever built that broke because, uh, they were built high enough and had spillway that went around when it filled up with surface water, and uh, we had several ponds there, most of them, well there's a few of them that put fish in there. The fish truck would come around and they'd buy fish, small ones and put in their pond, but they left more of that to the people in Mississippi and Louisiana and Georgia for fish farming, but these just put in there for more or less recreation.
VINCENT: When we&#8230;when Evan was doing the, uh, museum exhibit that is now there. I was helping them a little bit on a different project then I saw the pictures that he was using and saw your name on the back of those pictures and I said, "Oh I know him." Then I called you about the project. What&#8230;how did you feel, what did you think? Did you think, "Well, what are they doing dragging up that old stuff?" or did you have&#8230;
CLEMENT: Well, I thought that, uh&#8230;I never talked about it but I thought "well, I don't know if I remember that picture," but when I saw it, I remembered the picture and thought "well, that's something fifty years ago" and of course the pictures were saved, maybe the library or something held or for some historical purpose not&#8212;They don&#8217;t have any particular value other than it's something in the past. Of course, outside of what we've been talking about, the crops, we had other responsibilities. We had responsibilities that if we could help the city or help the school or help the county. We were there working with the Soil Conservation District who had supervisors for all of the districts that were elected by farmers. We had to work with them and the district supervisors were more or less instrumental in encouraging fire control and, uh&#8230;because that helps to conserve the woodland and all.
50:00
VINCENT: Right. So the Soil Conservation District was also instrumental in preventing forest fires and that kind of&#8230;
CLEMENT: Well, we didn't, uh, that came under State Forestry Department. In other words, Cannon County didn't have fire control. Dr. Evans and a lot of other people said we've got to have it. It was a long time before they could ever get it set up. Of course, we had responsibilities to any school or any organization that we could help. We had, uh, a farm level of course that, uh, we could lay out work; there's more to laying out diversions and ponds and stream channel improvement and things like that. Its got to be&#8230;there's a lot of surveying work and if it's thick, you got to go ahead and do it anyway.
VINCENT: Is that right, just had to go through the bushes and go on, huh?
CLEMENT: Or cut them. Cut them to get your measurements. Of course, at one time, you don't remember it but our organization was the only organization that was designated in the county when we were having trouble with Cuba and Russia intervening. It came close to being a shooting war, and uh, we had, at that time they had designated us to Geiger counters to test the level of radioactivity in case something did happen. I had to carry that thing home a lot of times at night. They said to take it home with you. In other words, it would only measure the level of the results if there was some kind of bomb, especially nuclear. But anyway, that soon passed over. Then another responsibility that come under, uh&#8230;I mean a lot of things happened other than that. They were having trouble down in Arkansas and Mississippi in the elections. Some of the service men that worked with the organization were sent down there to see that the election was carried out fair to everybody &#8211; just the responsibilities that we spoke of here and then to cover all that we actually were involved in. There was an effort at one time to establish a watershed in Smith Fork Creek in cooperation with DeKalb and Wilson Counties where the creek come, but it never did get approval and never worked out completely, but we done some work on that.
VINCENT: Well, uh, of course, Evan didn't know you and when I said that I know you here we are and all of the sudden we've sprung into a whole new avenue of getting some historical things going for the Historical Society I suppose and the museum and everything. We kind of just&#8230;you kind of appeared out from under a rock here and Evan said "Hey I think we want to do a story about him and just do a whole series about him." How do you feel about that?
CLEMENT: I'm just doing a job, doing my work. Of course, it was worthwhile and I enjoyed working. I got good cooperation with the landowners and I felt that I was doing the service for them and of course that's what they were paying me for, is trying to provide help on that and of course I had a whole booklet here that tells me what my responsibilities are and what's covered on it.
55:00
VINCENT: What about the reminiscing? Have you enjoyed that?
CLEMENT: Yes, I have. I remember a lot of instances that happened, and a lot of places that I went to. I guess I'd recognize any of those pictures, I could probably remember them. Of course, they were used&#8230;the pictures were&#8230;we had a working relationship with the paper and the radio station and of course we cooperated with the extension service and, uh, soil judgings. When they came around, the soil judgings first came around, why, I was called on to help organize, of course it's developed into something of real significance.
VINCENT: Right, I remember that with my children being in 4H and everything, and see that in the paper and hear my kids talking about it.
CLEMENT: Of course, the farming has changed there from what it was in the early&#8212;Farming section out there on the flatlands and the Short Mountain section and the Auburntown section and the Bradyville section. We had farmers cooperating all over the county and we had good relations with anything concerning the forest. You know, you've got a forester assigned to Cannon and Warren Counties. If they wanted to harvest some horse tracked timber and wanted some information about volume or something like that they were available. If we knew that farmer needed that help, we'd try to contact him and we would contact him and he would make an appointment to come down to cooperate and work with them.
VINCENT: That would be in the harvesting of timber?
CLEMENT: Yeah, that could be and also he helped out some when we were planting pines, when pines were being planted. Some of the pines that were planted back then have already been harvested for pulp wood and so.
VINCENT: Well, I think my daddy probably got some of those forty&#8208;six or seven years ago. They're still growing right along the roadside and right in front of my house. Huge. Huge.
CLEMENT: You'd be surprised. I found this out&#8212;I got some and planted them out over at my place and I figured out that you better figure out what that tree's going to do in future years. I planted them too close to the house.
VINCENT: So did I. My son and I had this discussion just a couple weeks ago. I said "Son, what you do today forty years from now is probably not going to be the right thing".
CLEMENT: Well, anyway I just made that remark and I found out from experience: they get big and boy you'd be surprised they grow that big in forty years time.
VINCENT: They are that big. Close to the road, it's kind of raised the ground up, the root system has raised the ground up and over here's my sidewalk to I've got a little whale in my front yard. I've got to figure out what to do with it. I might need to get you to come out there.
CLEMENT: Of course tree roots might be pushing up, breaking it. But in Tennessee, we'll never&#8212;With us on the border line of pine being used for commercial purposes. We're a little too cold for them. We'll never compete with Alabama and Georgia for crop purposes.
VINCENT: Well, we're coming right up on an hour and I think probably, we're going to run out of time in just a minute. Evan, is there anything else you want to add?
1:00:00
HATCH: I do have one question. I know fertilizer's been around for thousands of years, people have been using manure for growing their crops. You had mentioned using fertilizer for the Soil Conservation Service. Were the farmers in Cannon County aware of that? Were they using their own fertilizer before you all came in?
CLEMENT: I'm sure they were. They truly weren't using some fertilizer but they became an increased amount of fertilizer. Of course we had a pasture demonstration. Dr. Adams and the bank furnished some fertilizer and he wanted some plots planted, fertilized. Just some pasture that you had and asked that the farmers put a fence around a ten foot square place just to let them see what fertilizer would do for pasture. Of course, you know what happened when the pasture got short, they'd do their best to get over that fence and break in there to get to where that grass was.
VINCENT: The cattle.
CLEMENT: I think that was a very creative thing that he did. Of course, he'd charge that off to the expenses of the bank but nevertheless, he wanted that project done. The grade school kids at Iconium planted some on the land there by the road there. The students at the Woodland school&#8230;
VINCENT: Are you talking about the pine tree planting?
CLEMENT: Yeah. VINCENT: That was right near my house.
CLEMENT: Then the students down there at Woodland planted some at the back. Short Mountain planted some there on their schoolyard. Boy Scouts planted some. These were more or less demonstration projects. Boy Scouts planted some on Short Mountain up there at the use camp there. Of course, being a use camp, they built a pond up there. We laid it out for them and they built it. They built one on their own and it broke. It broke and water come down the holler there and they got someone to push it back up but it wasn't fixed right to start with. I forgot who lived down there now but they moved rocks, they didn't know what had happened. But there was a lot of things that happened there during that period of time that was of interest. If the project that you got will benefit anybody then I'm glad that it might be good. Not for my promotion, I was just there.
HATCH: You're humble.
CLEMENT: Just trying to do what I felt was right. And I used those pictures for (prayer?) and I kept a bulletin board outside the office and some of them were in the paper. One year we put out a newsletter that went out to all the people who were cooperating with us and kind of updating them on it. I don't know anything else that I could&#8230;
HATCH: That's good with me. I certainly appreciate it.
VINCENT: I can't think of anything else.
HATCH: This is no doubt.. Is it still doing anything?
VINCENT: It's still running little bars across.
HATCH: Okay. Just cut it off or you can just sign off or whatever you want to do.
VINCENT: This is the end of interview with Mr. Bill Clement. This is October the 14th, 2009 and it's about 1:30. We certainly have enjoyed talking with you Mr. Clement and it's just been delightful.
CLEMENT: Well, I'm glad to see the farmers that they're using, that they're doing out there now no&#8208;till farming and growing a lot of soy beans and corn on good land that they used to call Barrens. Of course, if you check history, you'll find out that during the Civil War they had trouble of getting from Nashville to Chattanooga and they had to travel through some of that land in Cannon County and Coffee County. They always had trouble getting through there because they couldn't get their cannons, pull the horses&#8230;</dc:description>
<dc:subject>United States. Soil Conservation Service; Oral history transcript;</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Rutherford County (Tenn.);</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro;</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text;</dc:type>
<dc:format>text;</dc:format>
<dc:format>Oral history;</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper;</dc:format>
<dc:format>14 p.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright Arts Center of Cannon County;</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>May be excerpted for educational and non-commercial uses with attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Arts Center of Cannon County</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/cannon/id/404</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>