<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:dltn="https://github.com/digitallibraryoftennessee" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Photograph of Anne Braden interviewing Rosa Parks</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/">Copyright Not Evaluated</accessCondition>
  <location>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/highlander/id/1587</url>
    <url access="preview">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/highlander/id/1587</url>
  </location>
  <abstract>Photograph of Anne Braden interviewing Rosa Parks at the Braden home in Louisville, Kentucky. Anne Braden was an activist and editor of "The Southern Patriot," the Southern Conference Educational Fund's monthly newspaper.</abstract>
  <abstract>Anne and Carl Braden were Civil Rights activists from Louisville, Kentucky. In 1954, they purchased a suburban home for acquaintances Andrew and Charlotte Wade, who were unable to because of the color of their skin. The Wades were subjected to cross burnings, broken windows, and dynamite, while the Bradens were condemned for their role. The Bradens' work in labor rights as well as Civil Rights saw them labeled as Communists amid McCarthyism and the Red Scare of the 1950s. They were convicted of sedition by the state but released after the Supreme Court overruled state sedition laws. The Bradens were unable to find work in Louisville so they joined the Southern Conference Educational Fund, a New Orleans civil rights organization, as field workers and newspaper editor. The two remained active in the civil rights movement until Carl's death in 1975. Following her husband's death, Anne continued her fight against racial inequality as well as an active member of environmental, women's, and anti-nuclear movements. Anne died in 2006.</abstract>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated>31 May 1960</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Tennessee State Library and Archives</recordContentSource>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
  </recordInfo>
  <subject>
    <topic>Highlander Folk School (Monteagle, Tenn.)</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Parks, Rosa (1913-2005)</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Civil rights workers</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic/>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <geographic>Louisville (Ky.)</geographic>
  </subject>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Highlander Folk School Manuscript Collection, 1932-1966</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>1811</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Tennessee State Library and Archives</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <physicalDescription>
    <form>Photographs</form>
  </physicalDescription>
  <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
</mods>
