<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Ryman Auditorium, view of Confederate Gallery</dc:title>
<dc:rights>While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law.  Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:subject>Auditoriums; Concert Halls; Historic buildings; Tabernacles (Buildings); Balconies; Columns; Benches</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Ryman Auditorium (Nashville, Tenn.); Grand ole opry (Radio program); Country music -- Tennessee -- Nashville; Country gospel music; Music-halls; Historic American Buildings Survey; Confederate States of America. Army -- Anniversaries, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:description>Interior of the Ryman Auditorium in Nashville, Tennessee, showing the main-level pews and the Confederate Gallery taken from the stage area.</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Nashville (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:date>1972 October 6</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Jack E. Boucher</dc:creator>
<dc:source>Library Photograph Collection</dc:source>
<dc:description>Sam Jones raised the money for a Tabernacle gallery to accommodate the 1897 Confederate Veterans Association Reunion. The three-day event in June 1897 (coinciding with the Tennessee Centennial Exposition) brought almost 100,000 people to Nashville. In honor of the legacy and donations brought about by the convention, the gallery was named "The Confederate Gallery."</dc:description>
<dc:relation>214</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>3494</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>Still Image</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jp2</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll12/id/44</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>