<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Edith Scott Coll  Memory Book_012 p. 4c</dc:title>
<dc:creator>unknown</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Photographs and captions from Miss Edith Scott's Memory Book, started July 1957.   Her ancestors included the Scott, Deaderick, Crozier, Ramsey, Anderson and Alexander families. Francis Alexander Ramsey Scott (1827-1909) married Margaretta Frances Deaderick (1833-1909) in 1857.  They were the parents of eleven children, including daughter Miss Edith Scott (1878-1971). Caption information appears below in the Full Text field.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Photographs; Scrapbooks; Families; History;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>mixed</dc:date>
<dc:type>photograph</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF; 400 dpi</dc:format>
<dc:source>Edith Scott Collection</dc:source>
<dc:rights>To use photographs or to order reproductions, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8808. Please refer to Image Number if available and provide a brief description of the photograph.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>
We have just read that a Baptist church
is the present owner of "Cedar Grove",
but they abandoned it, for what reason
I do not know, however, the vandals
soon found the place was open for their
destruction, and started in in dead
earnest to destroy it, knocking out
windows and doors and doing all the
damage they knew how to do. But fortunately Mr., and Mrs. Stevens were looking for a place for a funeral home and
saw the possibilities of "Cedar Grove"
for that purpose. How glad I am that
they bought it and on April 17, 1961
opened Stevens  Mortuary.
I am sure "Cedar Grove" was never
prettier than it is today - up on a
knoll in a grove of beautiful trees,
with the creek flowing quietly at the
foot of the knoll - accessible to Broadway, but far enough away to be very
quiet. The interior is beautifully and
tastefully furnished in every detail.
There is where I want to be buried from
not so very far away from where my
marker is already placed in our family
lot in "Old Gray Cemetery" - but of
course all this is just if the Lord
tarries.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2014-10-27</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll9/id/806</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>