<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Edith Scott Coll  Memory Book_004 p. 1c</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>Edith Scott Coll  Memory Book_004 p. 1c</dc:identifier>
<dc:creator>unknown</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Photographs and captions from Miss Edith Scott's Memory Book, started July 1957.   Her ancestors included the Scott, Deaderick, Crozier, Ramsey, Anderson and Alexander families. Francis Alexander Ramsey Scott (1827-1909) married Margaretta Frances Deaderick (1833-1909) in 1857.  They were the parents of eleven children, including daughter Miss Edith Scott (1878-1971). Caption information appears below in the Full Text field.  Roscoe C. d'Armand.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Photographs; Scrapbooks; Families; History; Portraits;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>mixed</dc:date>
<dc:type>photograph</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF; 400 dpi</dc:format>
<dc:source>Edith Scott Collection</dc:source>
<dc:rights>To use photographs or to order reproductions, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8808. Please refer to Image Number if available and provide a brief description of the photograph.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>We have just seen that my great-grandfather, James
Scott, Sr.., was with John Sevier in fighting the
Indians, and as he was a good age at the Battle of
Kings Mountain, he could have been in that engagement,
but  we   could  not   prove   that   he   fought   at   that   time.
My cousin, Roscoe C. d'Armand, a direct descendent of
James Scott, Sr., is a wonderful genealogist, and he
wrote me June 20, 1961 - "James Scott, Sr., served
with North Carolina troops during the Revolutionary
War from Captain Vail's Company, Second Regiment 1777;
and again in Captain Bailey's Company 10th Regiment,
for a period of 12 months from August 1, 1782. Apparently ancester James served first as a lad of 17
and again after he reached manhood and shortly before
he married. It has been a long trail and a long search,
done most of the time in darkness with no assurance
whatever save legends that survived. Apparently he
did serve with Sevier and Landon Carter, since their
names both appear  on his  voucher".
Again, August 10, 1961, he sent me all I need for a
supplemental DAR paper  on James  Scott  Sr..
JAMES SCOTT, Sr. served during the Revolutionary War,
as a private from August 1, 1782, for a period of 12
months; and again as a private in Vail's Company, 2nd
Regiment, from 1777 to November 1777, both in North
Carolina  troops.
He afterward served with John Sevier in his war against
the Indians and achieved the rank of Captain and then
Colonel. Department of Archives and History, North
Carolina Records,   page  1153:
2nd Regiment Muster and page 1165: 10th Regiment
Muster. Inid, Treasurer's Papers, Rev. Vochers No.
3344, June 12, 1783: The auditors for the counties of
Washington and Sullivan certify that James Scott is
allowed 9 pound specie as per voucher 12th of June
1783: By E. Williams - Landon Carter. John Sevier,
Sec."
My cousin writes "our Colonel Scott's military service
is without question and the proof is there". I am indeed most happy to know my great-grandfather was a
true patriot  and fought  for  his  country.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2014-10-27</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll9/id/802</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>