<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Edith Scott Coll  Memory Book_021 p. 9a</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>Edith Scott Coll  Memory Book_021 p. 9a</dc:identifier>
<dc:creator>unknown</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Photographs and captions from Miss Edith Scott's Memory Book, started July 1957.   Her ancestors included the Scott, Deaderick, Crozier, Ramsey, Anderson and Alexander families. Francis Alexander Ramsey Scott (1827-1909) married Margaretta Frances Deaderick (1833-1909) in 1857.  They were the parents of eleven children, including daughter Miss Edith Scott (1878-1971). Caption information appears below in the Full Text field.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Photographs; Scrapbooks; Families; History; Wallpapers;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>mixed</dc:date>
<dc:type>photograph</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF; 400 dpi</dc:format>
<dc:source>Edith Scott Collection</dc:source>
<dc:rights>To use photographs or to order reproductions, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8808. Please refer to Image Number if available and provide a brief description of the photograph.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>Here we come to a boat scene. The people in one of
the boats look placid, and all of them look happy,
but why that could be possible, when the water is so
choppy, is hard to understand. In fact, if I didn't
know better, I would take that water to be plowed
ground.
The process of papering the walls of this large room
was somewhat of a Herculean task for the paper did not
come in rolls, marked so the paper-hanger could follow
the markings, and so match the design. This paper
came in squares, and it was more like putting together
a jig-saw puzzle. The man who did this was Knoxville's
first town marshal!, a French pirate from the Gulf of
Mexico, named John Stacks. The story goes that he
helped Andrew Jackson with the British at New Orleans,
and hearing such tales of the beauties of Tennessee,
from the coon-capped riflemen of General Jackson, he
came with them from New Orleans to Knoxville and hung
up his shingle as a paper-hanger. Let us hope that
Knoxville was so law abiding that it induced him to
repent of his piracy and turn to enforcing the law in
the position of town marshall. However, my grandfather
trusted him enough to engage him to hang this lovely
paper. He evidently did an excellent job for in 1942
when Mrs. Ogle had these pictures taken, the paper had
been  on  the walls  one  hundred and nine  years.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2014-10-27</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll9/id/811</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>