<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>1865 4-part view with numbers_001 </dc:title>
<dc:identifier>Part 1 of 4</dc:identifier>
<dc:creator>T.M. Schleier</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Panoramic photograph (in 4 parts) taken of Knoxville, Tennessee in 1865 by T.M. Schleier.  Numbers were added and correspond with identifications provided by John S. Van Gilder in 1936.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Panoramic photographs; Historic buildings;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>1865</dc:date>
<dc:type>photograph </dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF; 400 dpi </dc:format>
<dc:source>Thompson Oversize Mounted Prints</dc:source>
<dc:rights>To use photographs or to order reproductions, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8808. Please refer to Image Number if available and provide a brief description of the photograph. </dc:rights>
<dc:description>Photograph was taken the year the War Between The States was over, 1865. 
Mr T.M. Schleier took it from a hill on the South Knoxville side of the river.
This photograph runs from Fort Sanders on the extreme left end,
acroes Knoxville, and up to Reservoir Hill on extreme right end.
The numbers below, explain the places beside same numbers on pictures:
1. Fort Sanders hill. Microscope reveals deadly network of trenches. 392
Confederate soldiers fell in action here in 20 minutes.
2. Probably the original cabin of Governor Blount, on Mead's Island, near
the big spring now used by the U. T. Power Plant.
3. A residence for University professors. Had a Greek temple columned front
facing present Cumberland Ave. Kappa Alpha Fraternity House at one time.
Today, the Administration Building is on this site.
4.  East Tennessee University: West College, Old College, East College.
Closed up like a clam during the war. Now the site of Ayres Hall.
5. Actual trenches of Union soldiers. "The Hill" was called Fort Byington
during the war.
6. The White House. Called the Prep Building. Used as a Preparatory
Department for East Tennessee University. Subsequently, the site of
President Ayres home.  Now the site of Ferris Hall.
7. Soldier tents pitched on present site of Library at University of Tennessee.
8. Janney House. Stood on site of present Humes Hall. Greek temple front
to balance 3. Likewise originally intended as a residence for University
professors. The present west end of Humes Hall may possibly consist of
this building, worked over. An architectural study of this photograph,
while standing beside Humes Hall, seems to indicate it. Sigma Alpha
Epsilon Fraternity was at one time on first floor of Humes Hall.
9. Stone piers of bridge for unfinished Knoxville and Charleston Railroad.
Now called the Maryvllle Bridge. River was in 1865 known as the Holston
River.
10. The Hugh A. M. White home. The Rodgers family lived here, Now the site
of the Home Economics Building of the University of Tennessee.
11. The William S. Mead residence. Note summerhouse. Now Terry Court Apts.
12. House where Admiral Farragut lived, northwest corner Poplar and Spring
Streets. Still standing.
13. The home of Mr. James H. Cowan. Subsequently owned by Mr. E. J. Sanford.
Latterly, the Kappa Sigma Fraternity House in Maplehurst Park.
</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-03-16</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll9/id/909</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>