<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Edith Scott Coll  Memory Book_055 p. 32a</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>Edith Scott Coll  Memory Book_055 p. 32a</dc:identifier>
<dc:creator>unknown</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Photographs and captions from Miss Edith Scott's Memory Book, started July 1957.   Her ancestors included the Scott, Deaderick, Crozier, Ramsey, Anderson and Alexander families. Francis Alexander Ramsey Scott (1827-1909) married Margaretta Frances Deaderick (1833-1909) in 1857.  They were the parents of eleven children, including daughter Miss Edith Scott (1878-1971). Caption information appears below in the Full Text field.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Photographs; Scrapbooks; Families; History; Silhouettes;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>mixed</dc:date>
<dc:type>photograph</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF; 400 dpi</dc:format>
<dc:source>Edith Scott Collection</dc:source>
<dc:rights>To use photographs or to order reproductions, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8808. Please refer to Image Number if available and provide a brief description of the photograph.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>Mrs. Margaretta A, Deaderick.  B. 1776-D. 1857.  Married Jan. 1st, 1795.                                                                                                                            Elsewhere in this memory book we have seen the pictures of "Poplar
Hill", the town house, and "The Cottage", the country house, at Jonesboro, Tennessee, and the site of the store at Cheek's Cross Roads, of
my great grandfather, David Deaderick II. From the pictures we learned
quite a good deal about him. Here we see how he looked.  I wish we
could see as well how my great grandmother, Margaretta looked. She was
born May 25, 1775 at White Clay Creek, Delaware, the daughter of William
and Elizabeth Inslee Adnerson. (Anderson).
She was quite young during the Revolutionary War. When the British
were marching to Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, there was nobody at home
but her mother and one of the soldiers asked her if she didn't have
four sons in the Rebel Army. She answered that she had four sons in
General Washington's Army. When the British were rumored approaching, a woman living near their home, who was panic stricken with the
news, exclaimed, "If the British come we will all go to the washtub",
and cried "what shall we do?" Margaretta's mother answered, "I don't
know what you will do, but I know what I will do - and my daughters -
if we come to the washtub, we will wash".
The Anderson family were patriots. William Anderson, Margaretta's
father, was too old to join the Army, but at the age of forty-six, he
joined anyway, but died the first year of the War. When great grandmother came to visit her brother, General Joseph Anderson, who had
married Only Patience Outlaw, she seemed to be a little homesick and
wanted to go back home, perhaps remembering the gay, happy time when
she was bridesmaid at the marriage of James Madison and the brilliant
Mrs. Todd in 1794. In those days you couldn't get on the train, or in
your car, or better still, fly where you wanted to go, but you had to
wait weeks, months sometimes, before a suitable escort could take you.
Her mother, Elizabeth Inslee Anderson, writes her she must be content
to "live retired" if she comes home now, and urges her to be patient.
But no, Margaretta meets the handsome David Deaderick - no more talk
of going to Delaware. The next wedding she attended was her own, on
January 1, 1795. It was a happy marriage for twenty-eight years, until October 20, 1823, when David Deaderick II passed away. She lived
a full life when left a widow.
She united with the church of Rev. Samuel Doak at Old Salem in East
Tennessee before any Presbyterian church was organized in Jonesboro -
then Dr. Charles Coffin preached in the Court House before the Presbyterian church was built. She was one of the five ladies who started
the ladies prayer meeting which met every week and was intimately connected with the prosperity of the church. October 21, 1857 she passed
away triumphantly in Christian faith.
</dc:description>
<dc:date>2014-10-27</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll9/id/829</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>