<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Edith Scott Coll  Memory Book_052 p. 31a</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>Edith Scott Coll  Memory Book_052 p. 31a</dc:identifier>
<dc:creator>unknown</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Photographs and captions from Miss Edith Scott's Memory Book, started July 1957.   Her ancestors included the Scott, Deaderick, Crozier, Ramsey, Anderson and Alexander families. Francis Alexander Ramsey Scott (1827-1909) married Margaretta Frances Deaderick (1833-1909) in 1857.  They were the parents of eleven children, including daughter Miss Edith Scott (1878-1971). Caption information appears below in the Full Text field.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Photographs; Scrapbooks; Families; History; Silhouettes;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>mixed</dc:date>
<dc:type>photograph</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF; 400 dpi</dc:format>
<dc:source>Edith Scott Collection</dc:source>
<dc:rights>To use photographs or to order reproductions, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8808. Please refer to Image Number if available and provide a brief description of the photograph.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>These two dear people, Reynolds and Naomi Alexander Ramsey, are my
great-great grandparents, both born in the same year - 1736 - so long
ago, yet I love and admire them as if I had really known them.
My great-great grandfather, son of William Ramsey of the Manor Maske,
York County, Pennsylvania, was born October 24, 1736 in New Castle
Delaware. In Philadelphia September 24 , 1761 he married Naomi Alexander
daughter of Francis Alexander of New Hopewell, N. J. She was born December 13, 1736 and can trace her ancestry to the kings and queens of
Scotland. They moved to York County Pennsylvania and settled on Marsh
Creek, owned and cultivated a farm, built a merchant mill, which supplied Washington's Army at Valley Forge, Trenton and Princeton with
flour. He refused British gold for the same flour, as he knew them to
be enemies of his country. He was as poor in 1781 as at the commencement of the war, and when he counted his Continental money, left on his
hands, it was just a scrap of paper. His sacrifices and self denial had
made him penniless but he was glad to pay that price for American
liberty and independence. He said what we had heard about how soldiers
crossed the Delaware River on ice, how frozen roads they traveled were
marked by blood from their naked feet, were no idle tales to excite
sympathy, but the real truth. He also served in the French and Indian
War, Muster Roll of Richard McWilliams Company, New Castle, Delaware,
December 28, 1757.
He sold his farm and mills and became a citizen of Gettysburg, Pa.,
where his half sister, Isabella Ramsey Gettys, lived. He resided there
several years, but still retained his membership in his old church at
Miller Town. Summer and winter, with my great-great grandmother,
Naomi, their daughter, Amelia King and her two children, he drove out
there every Sabbath, to hear his old minister, Mr. Paxton. He was
burgess of the town in February 1807 and on the second of that month,
inflicted a fine on Shem Greble for driving a team and wagon through
the town on Sunday. His two sons, F. A. Ramsey of Swan Pond, near the
forks of the Tennessee River and S. G. Ramsey, minister of the Presbyterian Church at Ebenezer, Tennessee, gave such glowing accounts of
East Tennessee - its towering mountains, its beautiful rivers, and mild
climate, with their urgent insistence to come and live in this heavenly
spot, they decided - each 71 years old - to leave Gettysburg on July 9
1807. With them were their daughter, Amelia King, her two children,
their son, S.G. Ramsey and family, who had been visiting them. They
arrived at Swan Pond, Tennessee on August 21, 1807. What a trip taking
six weeks!
The dear old people lived at Ebenezer until their son died, then they
came to Swan Pond, were happy there, members of the Old Lebanon Church
and are buried in its graveyard, where Ramsey generations followed
them. Naomi was 77 when she died in 1813 and Reynolds was 80 when he
died three years later in 1816. Two grand old people, who loved and
served God, and taught their children the Bible, who to the seventh
generation, rise up and call them blessed.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2014-10-27</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll9/id/827</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>