<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Edith Scott Coll  Memory Book_032 p. 14a</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>Edith Scott Coll  Memory Book_032 p. 14a</dc:identifier>
<dc:creator>unknown</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Photographs and captions from Miss Edith Scott's Memory Book, started July 1957.   Her ancestors included the Scott, Deaderick, Crozier, Ramsey, Anderson and Alexander families. Francis Alexander Ramsey Scott (1827-1909) married Margaretta Frances Deaderick (1833-1909) in 1857.  They were the parents of eleven children, including daughter Miss Edith Scott (1878-1971). Caption information appears below in the Full Text field.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Photographs; Scrapbooks; Families; History; Houses;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>mixed</dc:date>
<dc:type>photograph</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF; 400 dpi</dc:format>
<dc:source>Edith Scott Collection</dc:source>
<dc:rights>To use photographs or to order reproductions, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8808. Please refer to Image Number if available and provide a brief description of the photograph.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>This place we always called 96 Asylum Street, but the
street is now Western Avenue. The house at first was
only one story with dining room and kitchen in the
basement. The lot on which it stood was one hundred
and fifty feet square. The house must have been started
in 1859, 1860 or 1861. My sister, Margaretta Naomi, was
born July 31, 1861 at Fruit Hill, so I do not know if
we had moved to this house, or were still living in
the "Bride's Gift House". We can imagine what a turbu-
lant time that was with the War Between the States going on. Just when the second story with dining room
and kitchen upstairs, was added to the house, I do not
know, but it must have been pretty soon, for our children were coming right along, and during the Siege of
Knoxville, my grandmother and grandfather came there
when their home was burned in 1863; and other relatives
were coming and going frequently.
In the picture we were all there, except my oldest
brother, James Alexander. We will start at the left:
first is Frank Ramsey, born in this house May 6, 1865;
next comes Anne (we always called her Annie) born July
26, 1867. Then David Deaderick, born here April 27,
1863. Next Frederick William, sitting in his mother's
lap, born in this house January 6, 1876. My mother was
born at "The Cottage" in Jonesboro, Tennessee. Next is
my father, born in a brick house across the road from
Cedar Grove, October 12, 1827. Sitting on the step is
John Barton, born January 18, 1872. Sitting next to
him is Mary, born here December 27, 1869. Seated is
Elizabeth Crozier, born at Fruit Hill, the Deaderick
home, June 22, 1858. Curled up in the chair is Edith,
born here November 28, 1878. (Sister Lizzie is trying
to keep me still and from talking, which is the reason
she turned away and refused to respond to my calls of
"Sister Rizzie"). Next is Margaretta Naomi, born at
Fruit Hill, July 31:, 1861. At her feet is Clarence,
born here July 16, 1874.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2014-10-27</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll9/id/817</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>