<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>1865 4-part view with numbers ID_003</dc:title>
<dc:creator>T.M. Schleier</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Panoramic photograph (in 4 parts) taken of Knoxville, Tennessee in 1865 by T.M. Schleier.  Numbers were added and correspond with identifications provided by John S. Van Gilder in 1936.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Panoramic photographs; Historic buildings;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>1865</dc:date>
<dc:type>photograph </dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF; 400 dpi </dc:format>
<dc:source>Thompson Oversize Mounted Prints</dc:source>
<dc:rights>To use photographs or to order reproductions, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8808. Please refer to Image Number if available and provide a brief description of the photograph. </dc:rights>
<dc:description>31.  Mr. V. Burger's house. Built of brick taken from the original brick First
Presbyterian Church, when it vas torn down.
32. The J. A. Rayl house. Today standing at corner of Main Avenue and Walnut 
Street. It is on the southeast corner.
33.  Mr. Frank H. McClung's home at southwest corner Cumberland Avenue and Walnut
Street. , This lot is now a part of the Post Office site.
34.  Dr. James Park's residence First bricks laid for a John Sevier home. Now
standing at southeast corner of Cumberland Avenue and Walnut Street.
35. Summit House. Hotel on Summit Hill. Mr. John C. Ristine, Proprietor.
36. Catholic Church. Quaint stone edifice. Charming. Faced West.
37. Second Presbyterian Church on Clinch Avenue. Now Schriver Brothers site.
38. Church Street Methodist Episcopal Church. White. Brick. On Church Street.
39. South end of the Market House.
40. The Terry house. Knoxville's Mayor Joe King, who at one time ran Montvale
Springs, owned it before the Terrys. Now Mrs. Irwin's Dining Boom opposite
the Lawson MsGhee Library.
41.   The Court House. On site of present Car Barn on West Main Avenue. Clock
tower, western end, and one white column plainly visible.
42.  The Franklin House. On present Court House site. Back view. Formerly,
this hotel had been known as the Mansion House.  Solid silver tableware.
43.  Steamboat landing on Holston River. Warehouse on bank above river bank.
44.  Gay Street ending at Front Street. No bridge across river here in 1865.
45. The Judge Oliver Perry Temple home. Childhood residence of Miss Mary Boyce
Temple. Subsequently occupied by Mr. Matthew Nelson. Location is at
southwest corner of Gay Street and West Hill Avenue.
46. Chimney and white end of the Matthew Nelson and Miss Sally Jones double
house. It was on the site of the present Court House lot.
47. Roof of Lamar House, This hotel was formerly called the Coleman House.
Union General William P. Sanders, of Fort Sanders fame, died in the Lamar
House. It is now called the LeConte Hotel.
48. Probably the white tower of the First Baptist Church on Gay Street, the
steeple of which became unsafe and had to be taken down. One gentleman
was nearly killed by a falling timber, which hit him, during the process.
49. Cowan, Dickinson &amp; Co. building, and subsequently Perez Dickinson &amp; Co. building, at northeast corner of Main Avenue and Gay Street. Building still there.  Now occupied by Elgin Drug Store Inc. A commercial landmark.
50. Sam T. Atkin house. 51 Chisholm Tavern. 52 Bell House (hotel!) roof and
chimneys. 53 Blount Mansion in trees. 54 First Presbyterian Church side
view. 55 Monument in corner of First Presbyterian Church cemetery.

</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-03-16</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll9/id/915</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>