<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>1865 4-part view with numbers_004 </dc:title>
<dc:identifier>Part 4 of 4</dc:identifier>
<dc:creator>T.M. Schleier</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Panoramic photograph (in 4 parts) taken of Knoxville, Tennessee in 1865 by T.M. Schleier.  Numbers were added and correspond with identifications provided by John S. Van Gilder in 1936.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Panoramic photographs; Historic buildings;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>1865</dc:date>
<dc:type>photograph </dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF; 400 dpi </dc:format>
<dc:source>Thompson Oversize Mounted Prints</dc:source>
<dc:rights>To use photographs or to order reproductions, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8808. Please refer to Image Number if available and provide a brief description of the photograph. </dc:rights>
<dc:description>continued.
 56 Mrs. Jane Kennedy's house, an L of which was Central James White's original
log cabin and which was the first human habitation ever built on the site of
Knoxville. Built 1786.
57. Probably rows of soldier cabins. They are located on the hillside, across the
river, and opposite our present Court House, in South Knoxville. This hill,
during the war, was surmounted by Fort Stanley.
58. The "Military Bridge". It ran from State Street across the river. Note its
log crib piers. There was also a "Pontoon Bridge", during the war, which ran
from present Central Avenue across the river. In 1865, there was not any bridge
at Gay Street running across the river.
59. Site where Governor Blount signed the famous "Treaty of Holston" with 41 Cherokee
Indian chiefs and before 1200 Indians in 1791.
60. First Creek emptying into the Holston Biver. Central Avenue first called Water
Street is seen to the left.
61. John G. MsClannhan Flour and Grist Mill on First Creek and Main Street. Subsequently the Spot McClung Feed Mill. Now Dempster Ma.chine Shops.
62. Long white covered bridge over First Creek at Cumberland Street. 
63. David R. Richarduon's and E. J. Sanford's Saw Mill and Lumber Yard on First
Creek.
64. Little bridge at Clinch Street running over First Creek.
65. Scott and Dempster Flour Mill building in recent years.
66. The residence of Mr. John S. Van Gilder on East Clinch Street. 1861.
67. Home of Mr. William S. Kennedy. Now known as the "Hunter House."
68. Parson Brownlow's home. White western end peeping out from behind tree.
69. Knoxville Soap Factory.
70. Knoxville Pork House. Slaughter House.
71. Flint Hill with trail of East Hill Street running along the top of it.
72. The home, at one time, of Dr. Burnett and his wife Frances Hodgson Burnett,
who wrote the book "Little Lord Fauntleroy". Mr. William S. Mead, who it is
said was interested in her literary success, kindly opened his library to her.
Tradition reports that she picked blackberries to get postage stamps to mall
her manuscripts to publishers.
73. Temperance Hill. Fort Huntington Smith was up here during the war.
74. The John McKee house. McKee Street was named for Mr. John McKee.
75.  Temperance Hall. A Methodist Episcopal Mission on the corner of Clinch Street
and Temperance Street. During the war it was converted into a prison for holding captured soldiers. See the white stockade around it? Today, this building is called Gray Terrace.
By John S. Van Gilder    

December 2nd. 1936.
</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-03-16</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll9/id/912</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>