<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Thomas Legion</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>QSPC 2014.004</dc:identifier>
<dc:creator>unknown</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Cherokee Confederate veterans of Thomas's Legion at the New Orleans Confederate Convention in 1903.  Shown with Confederate flag and banner.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Veterans; Group portraits; Indigenous peoples; Flags;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>1903</dc:date>
<dc:type>photograph</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF; 400 dpi</dc:format>
<dc:source>Oversize Small Photograph Collections</dc:source>
<dc:rights>To use photographs or to order reproductions, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8808. Please refer to Image Number if available and provide a brief description of the photograph.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>The following caption was under the image: Above is shown the last photograph ever taken of the remaining members of the famous Thomas
Legion, composed of Cherokee Indians in the Confederate Army. The photograph was made in New
Orleans at the time of the New Orleans Reunion of Confederate Veterans. The inscription on
the banner, displayed in the photograph, is as follows: "Cherokee Veteran Indians of Thomas
Legion. 69 N. C. Regiment. Suo-Noo-Kee Camp U. C. V. 4th Brigade, N. C. Division." Reading
from left to right, those in the picture are: front row, 1 Young Deer; 2 unidentified;
3 Pheasant; 4 Chief David Reed; 5 Sevier Skitty; back row, 1 the Rev. Bird Saloneta; 2 Dickey
Driver; 3 Lieut. Col. W. W. Stringfield of Waynesville; 4 Lieutenant Suatie Owl; 5 Jim Keg;
6 Wesley Crow; 7 unidentified; 8 Lieutenant Calvin Cagle. All of these men are now dead with
the exception of Sevier Skitty, who lives one mile from Cherokee. Lieut. Col. Stringfield and
Lieut. Cagle were white officers of the legion. Names of the men in the photograph were furnished by James R. Thomas of Waynesville, son of the late Col. W. H. Thomas,who commanded the Thomas Legion. This band of Indians built the first road across the Great Smoky Mountains.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2014-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll9/id/739</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>