<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Edith Scott Coll  Memory Book_042 p. 21a</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>Edith Scott Coll  Memory Book_042 p. 21a</dc:identifier>
<dc:creator>unknown</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Photographs and captions from Miss Edith Scott's Memory Book, started July 1957.   Her ancestors included the Scott, Deaderick, Crozier, Ramsey, Anderson and Alexander families. Francis Alexander Ramsey Scott (1827-1909) married Margaretta Frances Deaderick (1833-1909) in 1857.  They were the parents of eleven children, including daughter Miss Edith Scott (1878-1971). Caption information appears below in the Full Text field.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Photographs; Scrapbooks; Families; History; Chairs; Tables; Silver;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>mixed</dc:date>
<dc:type>photograph</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF; 400 dpi</dc:format>
<dc:source>Edith Scott Collection</dc:source>
<dc:rights>To use photographs or to order reproductions, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8808. Please refer to Image Number if available and provide a brief description of the photograph.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>For many years these two Chippendale chairs were at
Swan Pond. They were made in London before 1773, and
were bought by my great grandfather, John McKnitt
Alexander in 1774, while a member of the provincial
legislature of North Carolina, and given by him to his
daughter, Margaret McKnitt Alexander. When she married
Francis Alexander Ramsey - that is how the chairs came
to Tennessee. They were in Swan Pond until after my
great grandfather's death, then they were in Uncle
Doctor's home, "Mecklenburg" where the French Broad
and Holston Rivers meet. Then during the War Between
the States they, with other valuables, were taken for
safe keeping across the Holston River to "Riverside",
the home of Uncle Doctor's daughter, Cousin Margaret
Jane Dickson. After the war when Uncle Doctor and aunt
Peggy came back from North Carolina, where they were
refugees, the chairs were taken to their home in Knoxville, which they called "Mecklenburg Place". When
Francis Alexander Ramsey died, his personal effects
were sold and his children bought almost all of the
things. My grandmother, Eliza Jane Naomi Bane Alexander Ramsey (Scott), bought the chairs and paid thirty-
one cents for them. It seems that before Uncle Doctor's
death he said the chairs should go to my grandmother,
Eliza Jane Scott's oldest son, my father, Frank Alexander Ramsey Scott. In 1888, when we moved to our new
home, "Oak Hill":, my mother sent for the chairs and
found them in the basement of "Mecklenburg Place" holding the wash tubs. When we left Knoxville to come to
Morristown, the chairs came with us, so here they are.
The sampler we see in the picture was made by my grandmother, Eliza Jane Ramsey.     The silver sugar bowl and
goblet were never in the Ramsey homes, but were in the
home of John  and Hannah Barton Crozier  - which was the
girlhood home of Aunt Peggy Ramsey.      This silver sugar bowl and goblet came from the home
of my great-grandparents, John Crozier and Hannah
Barton Crozier, on the corner of Gay Street and Clinch
Avenue, the present site of the Farragut Hotel, Knoxville, Tennessee. When returning from a trip East,
some time after 1799, my great-grandfather brought my
great-grandmother a beautiful silver service of four
pieces -a coffee pot, tea pot, cream pitcher and sugar
bowl. I have seen the coffee pot and the tea pot, both
very large, on a pedestal, with ebony handles, beautiful chasing as we see on the sugar bowl.
At my great-grandmother's death, October 11, 1838, her
daughter, Hannah Wells Crozier, wife of William Swan,
inherited the silver service. Before her death she
gave the coffee pot to her niece, Cornelia Crozier,
daughter of John Harvey Crozier and his wife, Mary
Williams Crozier. She sent the coffee pot to New York
City to be sold, and where it is now, I do not know.
The tea pot was next given to her niece, Mary Elizabeth Crozier, daughter of Dr. Carrick Crozier and his
wife, Elizabeth Baker Crozier, and she gave it to her
niece, Carrie Clinton as a wedding present, when she
married William D. Cleage. The cream pitcher was given
to her niece, Darthula Crozier, daughter of Arthur
Ramsey Crozier, and his wife, Nancy Henderson, and she
gave it to her niece.
The sugar bowl and goblet, Aunt Hannah Swan gave to
her favorite niece, my mother, daughter of Elizabeth
Jane Crozier Deaderick and David Anderson Deaderick.
The two pieces, the sugar bowl and goblet were never
in Swan Pond, but they came from the home of Margaret
Barton Crozier and were many times used by her, and
doubtless by Dr. J. G. M. Ramsey when he came to see
her at her home on Gay Street, Knoxville. When living
there, the Crozier family lived sumptuously and entertained lavishly.
</dc:description>
<dc:date>2014-10-27</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll9/id/822</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>