<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Edith Scott Coll  Memory Book_045 p. 22a</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>Edith Scott Coll  Memory Book_045 p. 22a</dc:identifier>
<dc:creator>unknown</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Photographs and captions from Miss Edith Scott's Memory Book, started July 1957.   Her ancestors included the Scott, Deaderick, Crozier, Ramsey, Anderson and Alexander families. Francis Alexander Ramsey Scott (1827-1909) married Margaretta Frances Deaderick (1833-1909) in 1857.  They were the parents of eleven children, including daughter Miss Edith Scott (1878-1971). Caption information appears below in the Full Text field.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Photographs; Scrapbooks; Families; History; Houses;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>mixed</dc:date>
<dc:type>photograph</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF; 400 dpi</dc:format>
<dc:source>Edith Scott Collection</dc:source>
<dc:rights>To use photographs or to order reproductions, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8808. Please refer to Image Number if available and provide a brief description of the photograph.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>This is our home my mother named "Oak Hill":, which was
well named for it was on the highest point in Knoxville,
and our yard was full of a variety of oak trees. As
it was up so high we had a wonderful view from the observatory on top of the house, you just can see in the
picture. The Smokies, the Cumberlands stretched out
before us to the south; House Mountain to the east, and
Sharp's Ridge at the north. We see a little glimpse
of Sharp's Ridge in the picture. The walls of the
house are of solid brick, made on our property. We
used to drive out here from town to see the brick kiln,
red hot, burning bricks for our house.
Cedar Grove, the home built by my grandfather Scott,
was also built with brick made on the place, but the
difference was that our bricks were not made by slave
labor. There were sixteen rooms in our house and servants' room and laundry in the yard, we were obliged
to have a large house for we had a large family. We
also had a large brick stable and carriage room. At
the end of the porch you see a conservatory, but Sister
Lizzie was such a flower lover that soon it was too
small, and my father built her a green house.
The group seated on the porch is my mother whom you
just can see, David standing, Frank seated, Annie seated
and I have on a white apron. Sister Ret is taking the
picture.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2014-10-27</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll9/id/823</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>