<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Edith Scott Coll  Memory Book_059 p. 33b</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>Edith Scott Coll  Memory Book_059 p. 33b</dc:identifier>
<dc:creator>unknown</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Photographs and captions from Miss Edith Scott's Memory Book, started July 1957.   Her ancestors included the Scott, Deaderick, Crozier, Ramsey, Anderson and Alexander families. Francis Alexander Ramsey Scott (1827-1909) married Margaretta Frances Deaderick (1833-1909) in 1857.  They were the parents of eleven children, including daughter Miss Edith Scott (1878-1971). Caption information appears below in the Full Text field.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Photographs; Scrapbooks; Families; History; Portraits;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>mixed</dc:date>
<dc:type>photograph</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF; 400 dpi</dc:format>
<dc:source>Edith Scott Collection</dc:source>
<dc:rights>To use photographs or to order reproductions, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8808. Please refer to Image Number if available and provide a brief description of the photograph.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>Here is another David Deaderick, son of the one we have just seen,
born March 23, 1797 in Jonesboro, Tennessee, and his wife, Elizabeth
Jane Crozier Deaderick, daughter of John and Hannah Barton Crozier.
My grandfather was the third of the name David - only he was David
Anderson Deaderick, adding his mother's maiden name. He died before I
was born by several years, but I feel as if I knew him well, for his
high principles and standards were instilled into his children, and my
mother almost daily would speak of him - what he had said, and what
would he say to the present-day way of living?
There is so much to say about this just and devout man - his sweet
loving nature that drew his grandchildren to his knee Immediately, his
love of nature, his delight in mountain scenery. Even in later years,
he made trips to the Smoky Mountains and walked twenty miles through
the mountains in one day. His physical endurance was remarkable.
About the year 1832 he, with other men of East Tennessee, was appointed
by the State Legislature Commissioners to supervise improvements in
the Tennessee River at "The Suck", and it was during this service my
grandfather performed the wonderful and perilous feat never done, perhaps, before or since by any man, of swimming through that terrible
whirlpool of waters, called the "Boiling Pot". He was a man absolutely
without fear, but this incident he never wanted to allude to, for a
man from Pennsylvania, standing by said that he "could do anything a
Tennesseean could" but attempting to do the same thing, was drowned,
which distressed my grandfather that he, himself, had been so rash.
He loved to travel and joined the Forty Nlners on their trip to California, arriving a year and ten days after leaving Knoxville. The
trip back home was quite different - his money gave out, and he did
not return by overland, but came by steerage around the Cape of Good
Hope, by New Orleans, and on arriving, so great and general was the
joy felt at his return, that a large crowd of the population of the
city met him at the wharf and escorted him to his home, where his
family were hoping and wishing they could hear from him and better
still, welcome him home. My mother said never was there such joy and
happiness in any family. Another trip unusual for the times was to
England and Scotland, taking six weeks to cross the Atlantic. He spent
the winter of 1819-1820 in London, and there it was this miniature we
see was made when he was 22 years old. Do you know anybody any finer
looking?
Elizabeth Jane Crozier Deaderick keeps pace with him. She and her
sisters were noted for their beauty and brains. Much more I could tell
about these two fine people. David Anderson Deaderick in 1825 was instrumental in introducing the cast iron plough in place of the old
wooden mould-board article, which did more to stimulate the farmer in
the improvements of the soil than any other one thing for agricultural
interest in East Tennessee. He predicted we would be a manufacturing
people for we had water power without end, and we would be celebrated.
Hasn't the TVA proved that prediction? He was an elder, and with his
wife, were members of the Presbyterian church and are buried in Old
Gray Cemetery in Knoxville, Tennessee.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2014-10-27</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll9/id/832</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>