<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Edith Scott Coll  Memory Book_030 p. 13a</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>Edith Scott Coll  Memory Book_030 p. 13a</dc:identifier>
<dc:creator>unknown</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Photographs and captions from Miss Edith Scott's Memory Book, started July 1957.   Her ancestors included the Scott, Deaderick, Crozier, Ramsey, Anderson and Alexander families. Francis Alexander Ramsey Scott (1827-1909) married Margaretta Frances Deaderick (1833-1909) in 1857.  They were the parents of eleven children, including daughter Miss Edith Scott (1878-1971). Caption information appears below in the Full Text field.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Photographs; Scrapbooks; Families; History;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>mixed</dc:date>
<dc:type>photograph</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF; 400 dpi</dc:format>
<dc:source>Edith Scott Collection</dc:source>
<dc:rights>To use photographs or to order reproductions, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8808. Please refer to Image Number if available and provide a brief description of the photograph.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>LANDMARK&#8212;This  historic  dwelling,   more  than a century old,  is  expected  to
be moved from Church Avenue on the proposed department store site, to a new loca-
tion for preservation.    Onetime home of the city founder's granddaughter, it is one of
Knoxville's most aged structures, after Chisholm Tavern, Blount Mansion and the ____
____ across State Street from the mansion.
This little house is where my mother and father went
to housekeeping. I do not know if it was in 1858 or
1859. My oldest sister, Elizabeth Crozier., was born
June 22, 1858 at Fruit Hill, my mother's home - where
she and my father were married September 24, 1857. Our
next child, James Alexander., was born December 15,
1859 in this little house - so sometime in these two
years my parents made the move from Cedar Grove. And
in 1859 or 1860, I think it must have been, then decided to build a home and bought a lot opposite to what
was then, the Deaf and Dumb Asylum, now the City Hall.
This house is known as "The Bride's Gift House" and
the early history is that it belonged to James White,
the founder of Knoxville. His son, Hugh Lawson White,
gave it to his daughter, Isabella White, as a bridal
gift when she married William B. French in 1843 at the
home of her aunt Mrs. Overton in Nashville. She lived
in the house some time, I do not know how long, but
she or somebody, rented it to my parents when they
lived there in 1859.
Her sons sold it to James. G. Mitchell in 1873. W. P.
Toms owned it when Rich's Atlanta store bought it in
the block between Clinch, Church, Henley and Locust
Streets for the Rich's Knoxville store. They announced
they would without charge, turn this landmark building
over to any one interested in transferring it to another
location for preservation. Now is my chance to live
in one of the many houses I have a great interest in.
IF (that great, big, awful IF) I had the money to buy
a lot suitable for its location, and if I had the money
to put the building material together- then wouldn't I
have a darling little house! and wouldn't I love it!
</dc:description>
<dc:date>2014-10-27</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll9/id/816</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>