<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Edith Scott Coll  Memory Book_038 p. 17a</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>Edith Scott Coll  Memory Book_038 p. 17a</dc:identifier>
<dc:creator>unknown</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Photographs and captions from Miss Edith Scott's Memory Book, started July 1957.   Her ancestors included the Scott, Deaderick, Crozier, Ramsey, Anderson and Alexander families. Francis Alexander Ramsey Scott (1827-1909) married Margaretta Frances Deaderick (1833-1909) in 1857.  They were the parents of eleven children, including daughter Miss Edith Scott (1878-1971). Caption information appears below in the Full Text field.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Photographs; Scrapbooks; Families; History; Houses; Fences; Trees;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>mixed</dc:date>
<dc:type>photograph</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF; 400 dpi</dc:format>
<dc:source>Edith Scott Collection</dc:source>
<dc:rights>To use photographs or to order reproductions, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8808. Please refer to Image Number if available and provide a brief description of the photograph.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>Here is Fruit Hill, the home of my grandmother and
grandfather Deaderick.    The original Fruit Hill was the
home of my great-grandparents,  John and Hannah Barton
Crozier,    I wish very much I had a picture of it, but
my mother  said James Park, the father of Rev.  James
Park,  admired it  so much, he wanted to build his house
just like it.    I do not know how closely he carried out
that desire.    The Park home is still standing on the corner of Cumberland Avenue and Walnut Street. My grandmother
Deaderick inherited Fruit Hill and many of her children
were born there. My mother was not born there, but was
married there,  September 24th,  1857,  her sister Anne,  and
two    first cousins, were bridesmaids.    One was Mary Elizabeth (daughter of Dr.  Carrick Crozier) and Darthula (daughter of Arthur Ramsey Crozier).    My mother's two sisters
were also married there.    Two of our children were born
there,-Elizabeth Crozier and Margaretta Naomi.    November
20th,  1863,  Fruit Hill was burned by the Federal soldiers.
When it was just about night,  they gave warning to get out
before they started burning the  house.    My grandmother,
carrying a candle, tried to get as many blankets,  and
necessary things,  as she knew would be needed at our Asylum Street house, where so many were coming in.    The soldiers called to her,   if she didn't put the candle out,
"the Rebels" would fire on the house.    She tried to conceal the lighted candle with the shawl around her shoul-
ders, which made  it almost impossible to get anything.
My grandfather and Uncle Todie (Crozier),  carried away
some things in a wagon, but of course there was a great
lost.    All of them,  including Grannie (Maria) and Elvira,
two faithful slaves,  slept at our house that night.    The
immense oak tree was injured on the side by the burning
house,,  as we can see in the picture.    I do not know when
the house was rebuilt, but certainly must not have been
started until    the war was over.     I have sweet memories of
this place, when my grandmother and Aunt Alice McClung
were living there.    Aunt Alice is sitting on the ground
by the tree,  and Charlie Irly,  a little cousin of ours,
is in the swing.    I remember the yard extended on down
the    hill to the spring,  and I was outdone one day,
when my mother and I went out there,  and a road had been cut
between the house and the spring,   and a fence built all
around the place.     I didn't like it at all,- neither did
I like it, a short time ago, when a street was cut right
through the house,   and it    is no more.    So, that ever-
moving progress must go on, whether we like  it or not.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2014-10-27</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll9/id/820</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>