<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>1865 4-part view with numbers_002  </dc:title>
<dc:identifier>Part 2 of 4</dc:identifier>
<dc:creator>T.M. Schleier</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Panoramic photograph (in 4 parts) taken of Knoxville, Tennessee in 1865 by T.M. Schleier.  Numbers were added and correspond with identifications provided by John S. Van Gilder in 1936.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Panoramic photographs; Historic buildings;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>1865</dc:date>
<dc:type>photograph </dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF; 400 dpi </dc:format>
<dc:source>Thompson Oversize Mounted Prints</dc:source>
<dc:rights>To use photographs or to order reproductions, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8808. Please refer to Image Number if available and provide a brief description of the photograph. </dc:rights>
<dc:description>14. The old Ramsey house. Situated on Loudon Hill. Subsequently, the home of
Mrs. Eliza J. McClung. Latterly known as the major R. C Jackson residence.
Located at the present corner of Forest Avenue and 11th Street.
15. Mystery! An unknown building!!  Possibly a barracks or factory.
16. Home of the dentist Dr. John Fouche on West Hill Avenue in 1859. Probably
built by him. Successively occupied by Mr. Michael Gordy, then by Mr. James
D. Cowan, and subsequently became a Catholic Convent with large golden cross
on top. Afterwards was owned by Mr. Alex. A. Arthur. Latterly the home of Mr.
Dan M. Rose. How the property of the United Daughters of the Confederacy.
17.  The present site of the Sigma Nu Fraternity House. In 1865, it was the garden
of Mr. Charles J. McClung. Note: The gigantic hackberry tree, now prominent
at this corner, was not there 71 years ago.
18. The home of Mr. Charles J. McClung. Subsequently Mr. R. P. Gettys's residence.
Today, a part of the Church Street M. E. Church lot.
19. The original Judge Sam T. Logan home. Afterwards torn down and another Judge
T. Logan residence was built on corner, Just to right.
20. The famous East Tennessee Female Institute, surrounded by fragrant white locust
trees, and where many of Khoxville 's present prominent matrons learned readin',
'ritin', and 'rithmetic. Over the roof of the Institute they gaily played the
ball game "Anthony Over". A Knoxville girl found 600 four leaf clovers in the
Institute yard one year. Now the location of the Church Street M. E. Church
entrance on Henley Street.
21. Probably the old Tan Yard building and the Rolling Mill. Just to the left
can be seen the little Asylum Street bridge crossing over Second Creek.
22. Rev. Robert Burns McMullen's home. Located Just above northwest corner of
present Western Avenue and Broadway. He was the pastor of the First
Presbyterian Church for the 18 years previous to Dr. Park.
23. Judge Robert J. McKinney's home with garden in rear. Present location of the
McKinney Terrace Apartments and the Valencia Apartments.
24. The Gas Works. Demolished roof is said to be the result of cannon ball fired
during war. Trellis, to left, is metal framework for gas tank.
25. Evidently, this photograph was made on a Monday. See the washing?
26. Tree's shadow indicates sun in West and photograph made in afternoon.
27. Probably the tragic tree on which Confederate Abner Baker was hanged.
28. Col. Perez  Dickinson's house. Rear view. Now, Mrs. C. B. Atkin's home.
29. Roof of Deaf and Dumb School. Rev. Robert Burns McMullen was first
President. Organized 1844. Now Knoxville's Civic Center.
30. The Jail! Stood on the site of the First Baptist Church on West Main Avenue!
Jail was in English castle style. Huge white stockade ran around the edifice.
Subsequently, Mr. Charles J. McClung built his home on  this site. Latterly
it was Mrs. Jacob L. Thomas's residence.
</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-03-16</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll9/id/910</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>