<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Sirenius M. Mort tintype_003</dc:title>
<dc:description>Civil War tintype of Sirenius M. Mort, 1st Lt., Co. F, 9th Tennessee Cavalry Volunteers, U.S.A.  A newspaper obituary for Lt. Mort was found  folded in the case.  He died on July 15, 1869.  Newspaper obituary from Dandridge, TN, July 16, 1869.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Funeral rites &amp; ceremonies;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>tintype / photograph</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF; 720 dpi</dc:format>
<dc:source>Daguerreotype Box 2</dc:source>
<dc:rights>To use photographs or to order reproductions, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8808. Please refer to Image Number if available and provide a brief description of the photograph.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>Tribute  of Respects.
Dandridge, July 16, 1869.
On the morning of yesterday, Lieut. S.
Mort, late of Co. F, 9th Tennessee
Cavalry Volunteers, went to his work in
ordinary health, at 2 o'clock of that day he
was a corpse. Lt. M. was dangerously sick
but about two hours&#8212;during which time
he was insensible. His death was caused by
sun-stroke.
The ex-soldiers of this place and vicinity
attended the funeral to-day in a body, and
immediately after the burial services gathered at the court house where the following
proceedings were had.
On motion, D. R. N. Blackburn, Esq.,
was called to the chair, and W. M. Hill
elected secretary.
The chairman, in obedience to the instructions of the meeting, appointed a committee of five to draft resolutions expressive of our feelings of respect and regard towards the deceased.
The committee reported the following
which were unanimously adopted:
Whereas, It pleased the Good Father
and Great Captain to call from time to eternity, suddenly, and in a most unexpected
manner, on yesterday, the 15th inst., our
soldier-brother and comrade, 1st. Lieut.
Sirenius M. Mort, therefore be it resolved,
1 st. That the deceased Lieut. Mort, was
a brave, patriotic and model soldier, that
he justly had the esteem and warm friendship of all his associates in the army, and
that in consequence of his uniform kindness to those whom he commanded, he was
throughout his entire term of service one of
the most popular of officers.
2d. As a citizen the deceased was industrious, generous, and an honor to his country.
3d. As a husband, brother, and son, Lt.
Mort was faithful, affectionate, and "the
light of the household.''
4th. That we commend the character and
conduct of our departed brother, and pledge
ourselves to ever keep his memory green;
and we tender to the greatly afflicted family
and relatives of Lt. Mort, the ardent sympathy of old soldiers and true friends.
5th. That the officers of this meeting
furnish to the widow of Lt. Mort, a copy
of our proceedings, and also that they furnish copies for publication to the Knovville (sic.)
Whig, and Press and Herald.
Upon motion the meeting adjourned
without day,
D. R. N. Blackburn, Ch'n.
W. M. Hill, Sec'y.
</dc:description>
<dc:date>2012-04-17</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll9/id/444</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>