<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Edith Scott Coll  Memory Book_063 p. 35a</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>Edith Scott Coll  Memory Book_063 p. 35a</dc:identifier>
<dc:creator>unknown</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Photographs and captions from Miss Edith Scott's Memory Book, started July 1957.   Her ancestors included the Scott, Deaderick, Crozier, Ramsey, Anderson and Alexander families. Francis Alexander Ramsey Scott (1827-1909) married Margaretta Frances Deaderick (1833-1909) in 1857.  They were the parents of eleven children, including daughter Miss Edith Scott (1878-1971). Caption information appears below in the Full Text field.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Photographs; Scrapbooks; Families; History; Portraits;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>mixed</dc:date>
<dc:type>photograph</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF; 400 dpi</dc:format>
<dc:source>Edith Scott Collection</dc:source>
<dc:rights>To use photographs or to order reproductions, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8808. Please refer to Image Number if available and provide a brief description of the photograph.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>This is Dr. William Haney Deaderick, son of David Deaderick II and his
first wife, Ann Knight. As I am descended from David Deaderick II and
his second wife, Margaretta Anderson, this makes Dr. William Haney
Deaderick my half-great uncle.
He was born in Winchester, Virginia November 30, 1785, and after his
mother's death when a small boy, he came with his father to Jonesboro,
Tennessee. When he was ten years old his father married Margaretta
Anderson, who was twenty-three years old. Though a young stepmother
for a boy ten years old, she had a wonderful influence for good over
him, and taught him to be a devout Christian as she reared her own
children, David, Franklin, Joseph, James, Eliza Rosa and Amanda Frances.
William Haney had the best of educational advantages the country afforded, and also a first-class medical education. He practiced medicine in Greeneville, Rogersville and in Jefferson County, (then in
North Carolina), and later in Athens, Tennessee, where he died October
30, 1857. March 26, 1807, when he was twenty-three years old, he
married Penelope Smith Hamilton, daughter of Joseph Hamilton, Sr. and
Penelope Outlaw Hamilton. Eleven children were born to this union.
In his second marriage he married a widow, Mrs. Lois Ashworth. One
daughter was born to this union. He, like his half brothers, David
and James, were at different times living at Cheek's Cross Roads, where
his father had a store.
At this time, 1810, when he was twenty-five years old, he performed an
operation that gave him lasting fame. The medical journals gave him
credit for being the first to remove the lower jaw, where an abscess
had formed, and to save life, he cut the jaw bone in two at the chin,
removed the trouble, replaced the bone, and saved the patient's life
(who lived many years afterward). It was stated the operation was no
haphazard case, but was directed by reason and judgment. Of course
there was no hospital at Cheek's Cross Roads, no operating room with
electric lights, no assisting surgeons nor trained nurses nor anesthetists to give an anesthetic, for there were no such things heard of.
Where else could this operation have been performed but on a counter
in his father's store, by a lamp and flickering candles? Above his
reputation as an esteemed physician of East Tennessee and a surgeon of
no mean degree, he was a man of high moral character, a high-toned and
sensitive nature of deep spirituality. His death was not sudden. For
many weeks he knew he would soon leave this earth and often spoke of it
and said he was ready and eager to go. Just nine days before he passed
away his beloved stepmother, who taught him the way to live and the
way to die, passed over Jordan in Jonesboro, Tennessee. When asked
was she supported in Christian faith, answered, "wonderfully, wonderfully" - and again her words were repeated in Athens, Tennessee by her
stepson, when asked was he supported by Christian faith. Surely the
price of a good woman, whether she is mother or stepmother, is above
rubies.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2014-10-27</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll9/id/834</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>