<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Looking towards Tennessee from Clingman&#8217;s Dome (stereograph)</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>SV 2012.001 b</dc:identifier>
<dc:creator>unknown</dc:creator>
<dc:description>SV 2012.001b (back):   37570 Looking towards Tennessee from Clingman&#8217;s Dome, Great Smoky National Park, North Carolina. 31*  Keystone View Company Manufacturers Copyrighted Made in U.S.A.  Publishers.  Meadville, Pa., New York, N.Y., Chicago, Ill., London</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Great Smoky Mountains; Views; Stereographs;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>unknown</dc:date>
<dc:type>stereograph</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF; 400 dpi</dc:format>
<dc:source>SV 2012.001</dc:source>
<dc:rights>To use photographs or to order reproductions, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8808. Please refer to Image Number and provide a brief description of the photograph.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>37570
LOOKING TOWARD TENNESSEE
FROM THE TOP OF CLINGMAN'S
DOME, GREAT SMOKY MOUNTAINS
Clingman's Dome is the topmost peak in the
park. From this elevation of 6,642 feet there
is an unobstructed view of timbered ridges,
shared equally by North Carolina and Tennessee. Their axes run almost east and west for
fifty-four miles and at no point does the area
exceed nineteen miles in width.
Great honor is due the naturalists who returned to untold hardships year after year in
order to explore this fastness and reveal its
true import to our nation. In some 700 square
miles more varieties of plants have been found
than in any other equal area in the temperate
zone. Included in the list are all of those growing along the Atlantic from Canada to
Georgia. To better comprehend the botanical
wealth of the region a few figures may help.
There are 129 species of trees alone.   This is
significant when one recalls that in all of Europe there are only eighty-five. Flowering
plants contribute 1,200 varieties while fungi,
mosses, lichens and liverworts add 1,600 more
to the grand total. Even with all of these, the
possibilities are still far from exhausted. Two
hundred thousand of the 428,000 acres are
covered with virgin spruce and hardwoods, the
only stand of their kind left in this country.
Trails or paths, spelling certain disaster to
the uninitiated, are the sole means of access
to this hinterland where matted luxuriant undergrowth bridges many of the streams, hiding them so completely that their presence
would be undetected except for the gurgling,
bubbling sounds of the water. Yes, adventure
still abounds, even for those hardy individ-
ualists who mutter objections as civilization
makes inroads and establishes its footholds.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2012-11-26</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll9/id/481</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>