<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Edith Scott Coll  Memory Book_061 p. 34a</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>Edith Scott Coll  Memory Book_061 p. 34a</dc:identifier>
<dc:creator>unknown</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Photographs and captions from Miss Edith Scott's Memory Book, started July 1957.   Her ancestors included the Scott, Deaderick, Crozier, Ramsey, Anderson and Alexander families. Francis Alexander Ramsey Scott (1827-1909) married Margaretta Frances Deaderick (1833-1909) in 1857.  They were the parents of eleven children, including daughter Miss Edith Scott (1878-1971). Caption information appears below in the Full Text field.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Photographs; Scrapbooks; Families; History; Portraits;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>mixed</dc:date>
<dc:type>photograph</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF; 400 dpi</dc:format>
<dc:source>Edith Scott Collection</dc:source>
<dc:rights>To use photographs or to order reproductions, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8808. Please refer to Image Number if available and provide a brief description of the photograph.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>Inslee Deaderick in Confederate uniform.                                                                                                                                                                                     This is my uncle, Ins lee Deaderick, a gallant, brave Confederate soldier,
son of David Anderson and Elizabeth Jane Deaderick - the handsome couple we
have just seen.
My mother told us how during the siege of Knoxville Uncle Inslee was in
camp near by, and he was so overcome with the desire to go home and see his
mother he took the chance of being seen and caught. Alas, somebody saw him
either going or coming and reported him. He was taken prisoner, and for
two years suffered untold hardships at Fort Delaware. She told us the descendants of the man who reported him were then living in Knoxville, and we
begged her to tell us who they were but she said no - it was all over now,
and we must forgive and forget all that the soldiers and the people at home
had suffered, that Uncle Inslee had no hatred or bitterness in his heart
for the treatment he had received at Fort Delaware. When writing home he
would leave a space in the letter where he wrote in milk or onion juice,
the truth of his prison experience. The loved ones at home knew to put
heat at that part of the letter, and the writing would come out plain. He
made out my paper for me when I joined the UDC in 1913. He belonged to
Company I, 2nd Regiment, Tennessee Cavalry, Ashby's Brigade, and added a
little bit of interesting history. He stated "At the breaking up of the
Army in North Carolina, General Wheeler called for volunteers to join Gen.
E. K. Smith, commanding the Trans-Mississippi Department. When we got
across the Mississippi River, Gen. Smith's army had surrendered and gone home
no one to discharge us, so I was never parolled, nor discharged, nor surrendered." Just how was this, that he was never parolled nor discharged
nor had the humiliation of surrendering? He gives the answer himself in
The Confederate Veteran, May 1926, but in his extreme modesty, he leaves
out the high point of the story - his swimming the Mississippi River near
Memphis, Tennessee in the spring of 1865, when it was a mile or more wide,
and more than a 100 feet deep, and had a current of five or six miles an
hour.    Just turn the page and read about it yourself.
</dc:description>
<dc:date>2014-10-27</dc:date>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p265301coll9/id/833</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>