<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Green Street Baptist Church: interior sanctuary windows, west wall</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2012-09</dc:date>
<dc:description>Green Street Baptist Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>1220 Green Street Selma, AL 36701</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Selma, Dallas County, AL</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>32.416946, -87.019854</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of stained glass windows on the west wall of Green Street Baptist Church, photographer facing north of west. Image includes five stained glass windows, with four grouped further from the photographer and one separate nearest the photographer. The windows themselves are divided into three panes, and each window is nearly identical. The lowest panel is geometric, composed of rectangles and squares. The middle and top sections include an abstracted, art nouveau-style flower motif in the extending up the center of both panes. A pattern of rectangles, diamonds and triangles frames the entire window. The dominant colors are a light blue green, a rose pink, and a deeper blue violet. The lower portion of each window includes an amber-colored dedication panel, which is only readable in the first image, and states Mr &amp; Mrs G.H. Hall. The top of the windows are partially obscured by white-painted duct work. The windows have plain frames and the lower portion of the wall is covered in beadboard wainscoting with a chair rail, all painted white. The top right corner of the image includes the partially collapsed underside of the balcony.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The congregation of Green Street Baptist Church formed in 1881, primarily from the congregation of First Baptist Church (Colored), which was then known as the St. Phillip Street Baptist Church (due to their location). The church was led by Reverend John Blevins, who had been pastor at St. Phillip Street, thus the church was originally known as &#8220;The John Blevins Church.&#8221; He remained there for two or three years. On December 31, 1881, church trustees Jefferson Richardson, Joseph Baylock, Adam Clayton, and Henry Lamar purchased a lot on the corner of Green Street and McCreary Avenue (now Griffin Avenue) for $150. The first worship services were held in a store on the corner.  The first church the congregation built was a small frame building on a lot adjacent to where the brick church now stands. The frame church was small and uncomfortable, unable to accommodate the congregation of 200 souls (with 300 attending Sunday School). The interior of the original structure was lit by three lanterns hanging from the ceiling and a tin lamp on each side wall. The minister had a small platform to stand on, and the children sat on the edge. The original frame building was replaced once by a larger frame church, and again by a brick church, which was dedicated in 1892. The current building was dedicated in 1922. The plan for the building came to Pastor James A. Martin in a dream, and it was designed and built by contractor A.J. Farley. It is a Romanesque Revival church with Italianate influences. Between 1937 and 1946, the church building was renovated and restrooms added. Between 1946 and 1958, the church was renovated again, including the purchase of new pews and floor coverings, and a paved sidewalk was added around the church. In 1946, the church opened a kindergarten, which operated for 14 years. In 1962, the church added an education wing. The late 1980s saw another interior renovation, accompanied by a new roof and renovated restrooms. In the late 1990s, a truss in the church&#8217;s roof failed, which has led to significant damage to the structure, including the bowing of the sanctuary wall on Griffin Avenue, the holes in the roof, and extensive interior damage from exposure to the elements. The remaining congregation currently worships in the education wing.  Green Street&#8217;s current state belies its historical significance. During the 1960s, the church enjoyed a thriving congregation, and its kitchen was used to prepare meals for marchers in the Selma to Montgomery March in 1965. The considerable space in both the education wing and the main sanctuary were also used to provide temporary housing for civil rights workers. On June 5, 1964, the church hosted a mass meeting featuring Ralph Abernathy of the Southern Christian Leadership Conference. Following the meeting, someone threw a rock at some of the deputized possemen who had surrounded the church during the meeting. The possemen responded by attacking the crowd as it tried to exit the church, using night sticks and tear gas. The riot continued in the neighborhood, injuring many of the black residents and putting some in the hospital. Homes up to a block and a half away from the church were damaged, with broken windows and porch lights. Two white journalists were targeted and their cameras destroyed by possemen.  
</dc:description>
<dc:subject>African American Churches -- Tennessee; Baptist church buildings; Brick churches; Church buildings; Church buildings -- Alabama; Churches; Civil rights -- United States; Historic buildings; Houses of prayer; Interior architecture; Stained glass windows; Windows</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>IMG_5630</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/6284</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>