<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Centennial Park: Thomas Monument</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Yandell, Enid, sculptor</dc:creator>
<dc:contributor>West, Carroll Van, photographer</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1907</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1900-1909</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Centennial Park</dc:description>
<dc:description>Park</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>08000689 listed July 15, 2008</dc:identifier>
<dc:description>2500 West End Ave, Nashville, Davidson County, TN</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Nashville, Davidson County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>36.149438,-86.812935</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of the Thomas Monument, constructed 1907. The monument structure includes eight benches, two on each side to form a balustrade around the focal point of the monument, a bronze statue of John W. Thomas, president of the Centennial Exposition. A tall concrete base that supports the statue features elaborate bas relief panels on three sides and a plaque with text on the fourth.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Centennial Park in Nashville is a designed landscape park that was first created as a site for the Tennessee Centennial Exposition of 1897, celebrating Tennessee's admission to the Union. In 1902 the Exposition grounds were given to Park Board of the city of Nashville by the Nashville Railway and Light Company. The 2008 listing of the park on the National Register of Historic places covered 91 of the 132 acres now included in the park, along with 29 contributing features, including numerous buildings, sculptures and memorials. The most notable architectural element in the park is the full-scale replica of the Parthenon, which was originally constructed for the Centennial Exposition and then reconstructed as a permanent concrete structure between 1920 and 1931. The park's evolution over time mirrored new ideas and trends for public recreation. The park grounds, buildings and features have been maintained for more than one hundred years, resulting in a large urban park that continues to be central to life in present-day Nashville.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Monuments &amp; memorials</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Monuments</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>Centennial004</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/2646</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>