<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Mt. Olivet Cemetery: residential area border</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2001</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009;</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Mt. Olivet Cemetery;</dc:description>
<dc:description>Cemetery;</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>02000237 listed March 20, 2002</dc:identifier>
<dc:description>E. Forest Ave, Jackson, Madison County, Tennessee</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Jackson, Madison County, TN;</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>35.634979,-88.814332</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of cemetery next to a residential neighborhood. Chain-link fence separates the cemetery from a highway. Cemetery driveway is visible. Maud Smith's marker, depicting a lamb at the base of a tree stump, and Abie Gilmore's obelisk, featuring a closed Book of Life on an angled shelf, are located next to the fence.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Established in 1885, Mt. Olivet Cemetery is the largest, private African American cemetery in Jackson, and is still in use today. It was especially popular with the growing upper middle class and professional segment of the local black community from 1890 to 1930. Based on a 1995 survey of extant cemetery grave markers, the earliest marked burial is from 1885. Prominent burials include doctors, ministers, businessmen, a lawyer, veterans, and many educators. The grave markers also indicate membership in specific clubs, and fraternal and civic organizations, especially those grave markers between 1917 and 1988. The markers indicate particular importance on the graves of children, or "innocents." The cemetery is a symbol of local artisanship, and the success of Jackson's postbellum black community.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>African American cemeteries; Graveposts;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>tombstones; roads; driveways;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Tombs &amp; sepulchral monuments;</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image;</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000;</dc:format>
<dc:format>Slide;</dc:format>
<dc:format>35 mm</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission;</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only;</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>MtOlivetCemetery106.tif</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/3631</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>