<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>St. Peter Primitive Baptist Church: church annex</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2003</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>St. Peter Primitive Baptist Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>2115 Fourth Ave North, Bessemer, AL</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Bessemer, Jefferson County, AL</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>33.405833,-86.952034</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of a two-story white cement building with blue stone work on corners; double metal doors on ground floor under a blue cross; metal stairs going up to a second floor blue door. The building was constructed as a commercial warehouse but was acquired and renovated by the church to serve as an annex.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The congregation of St. Peter Primitive Baptist Church formed in 1903 and constructed its first building in 1911 at the same location as the present church. By 1943 the congregation had outgrown the original building, which was demolished to allow construction of a brick church of mid-twentieth century Gothic Revival design, creating one of the largest gathering places for African Americans in Bessemer. The expansive new sanctuary allowed the church to have an important role in the development of a capella gospel singing in the Birmingham-Bessemer area. Most notably, the Sterling Jubilee Singers are closely associated with the church.&lt;br&gt;
Rev. William A. Clark, who served as pastor until 1962, led the effort to construct a new church, encouraged the use of the church for gospel programs, and was a supporter of the Alabama Christian Movement for Human Rights (ACMHR).  The church was among the first to host critical meetings of ACMHR in the years 1956-58.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>African American Churches -- Tennessee; Church buildings -- Alabama</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Churches</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:format>4 x 6 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>stpeterpb00008</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/718</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>