<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Cairo Rosenwald School: group gathering</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2004</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Cairo Rosenwald School</dc:description>
<dc:description>School</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Gallatin, Sumner County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>36.363359,-86.363587</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of group gathered inside Cairo Rosenwald School in May 2004, before the restoration of the school. Alice Rosenwald, the granddaughter of Julius Rosenwald, is sitting in the front center.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Located on historic Zieglers Fort Road, the Cairo School was created in part through the Julius Rosenwald Fund. Of the total cost, the Julius Rosenwald Fund provided five hundred dollars and the local African American community raised seven hundred dollars, a sum that was matched by the Tennessee public school fund. Following the standardized Rosenwald School design for a one-teacher facility, the one-story building contains a gable roof, continuous stone foundation, and weatherboard siding. The Cairo School, constructed between 1922 and 1923, has underwent architectural changes to increase access and to accommodate modern conveniences. During the 1940s, electricity was installed. In 1951, a pump house was constructed behind the school to provide running water. At the time of its National Register nomination, the building lacked indoor restrooms and a heating system. It was however made handicap accessible in 1995 when a ramp replaced the original stoop stairs. Eventually, by 2008, the ramp had been relocated to the rear and the front steps were rebuilt. The Cairo School bears significance for its role in the education and social history of the local African American community. From 1923 to May 1959, the school provided elementary education, grades one through eight, for African American children. A consolidation movement forced the school to close in 1959. In Sumner County, it is just one of three extant Rosenwald schools. Although no longer functioning as a school, the building serves as a social center for the Cairo community. The Cairo Improvement Club has played an active role in the school's adaptive reuse. In 1996, the club nominated their school to the National Register of Historic Places. In 2008, the Tennessee Preservation Trust and Middle Tennessee State University's Center for Historic Preservation worked together to rehabilitate the school using a grant from the National Trust for Historic Preservation and Lowe's.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Alice Rosenwald (sitting, front center); Dr. Mary Hoffschwelle (standing, front center).</dc:description>
<dc:subject>African American schools -- Tennessee; Julius Rosenwald Fund -- Buildings</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:format>Computer disk</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>Cairo School and Alice Rosenwald 3.tif</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/5820</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>