<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>E.T. Wickham roadside park and Wickham Cemetery: headless statue on bull</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Wickham, Enoch Tanner</dc:creator>
<dc:contributor>West, Carroll Van, photographer</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>2002</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>E.T. Wickham roadside park and Wickham Cemetery</dc:description>
<dc:description>Cemetery</dc:description>
<dc:description>Buck Smith Road, Palmyra-Shiloh,  TN</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Palmyra-Shiloh, Montgomery County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>36.399838,-87.473411</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph statue of a figure, now headless, riding a running bull. It is mounted on a pyramid base with graffiti. Inscribed lettering reads "Do not touch or swing on statues"</dc:description>
<dc:description>Enoch Tanner Wickham (1883-1970) created a roadside park across from his own concrete and log home that was full of concrete sculpture devoted to famous events and people in American history.  He also created sculptures with powerful religious imagery at his family cemetery in rural Montgomery County. Statues include likenesses of Daniel Boone, Andrew Jackson, Alvin York, and wing-spread angels. Wickham was not discovered as an artist until after his death, but some of his work was featured in the 1982 World's Fair in Knoxville. Some installments were then removed to Austin Peay University. In 2000, the National Endowment of the Arts awarded a grant for a combined effort from Austin Peay Professors and the Custom House Museum in Clarksville to document and interpret Wickham's contributions to Tennessee's self-taught art traditions. This resulted in a major exhibit and catalog about Wickham's sculptures at the Custom House Museum in 2001.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Statues</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Sculpture</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:format>35 mm slide</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator; Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>WickhamParkCemetery020</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/1613</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>