<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>St. Marks Presbyterian Church: side view</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2006-11-05</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>St. Marks Presbyterian Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>Church</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>06000132 listed 2006/03/10</dc:identifier>
<dc:description>St. Marks Presbyterian Church, Kyle and Hasson Streets, Rogersville, Hawkins Co., TN</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Rogersville, Hawkins County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>36.407574,-83.008274</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of a historic landmark sign in front of a church; side view; the sign reads "1B 66; St. Marks Presbyterian Church, 1875-2002; Originated in 1875, St. Marks was the first black Presbyterian Church in Rogersville. Formerly located in the Tenth Civil District, now McKinney Avenue, the church moved to the corner of Kyle and Hasson Street in 1912. The Reverend William H. Franklin, founder and pastor, served St. Marks and Swift Memorial College. Buried on the Swift campus, in 1898, Dr. Franklin received an honorary doctorate from Maryville College. The church ministered to the Swift's faculty, students, and community. On July 21, 2002, the church dissolved. Its facility now serves the youth and community through the arts."; the church is two stories; the lower portion is red brick with four rectangular windows on the side and one white door obscured by a hill; red brick stairs on the left; upper portion is white panel with two visible arched windows (one stained glass) on the side; on the left (front of the church) are pointed arched doorways; gable roof.</dc:description>
<dc:description>St. Marks Presbyterian church was founded c. 1875 by Reverend William H. Franklin, also pastor. It is significantly associated with Swift College, an African American institution in Upper East Tennessee from 1883 to the mid-1960s. The church ministered to the faculty, students, and community of Swift. The church dissolved on July 21, 2002.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>African American Churches -- Tennessee; Church buildings -- Tennessee; African American universities and colleges</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Churches; Historical markers</dc:subject>
<dc:language>Eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>Ducktown R'ville G'ville 2006 040</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/484</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>