<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Northern Heights Presbyterian Church: view of facade</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Gautreau, Abigail R., photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2013-12-12</dc:date>
<dc:description>Northern Heights Presbyterian Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>Northside Baptist Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>1575 Marie Foster Street Selma, Alabama 36703</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Selma, Dallas County, AL</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>32.421009, -87.014312</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of Northern Heights Presbyterian Church, located at the corner of Marie Foster Street and Philpot Avenue, photograph taken from southwest of the building. The east-facing, gable-end facade features buff brick, contrasting with the red brick used on other elevations. A steeple sits atop the peak of the gable end. A set of white double doors serves as the main entrance, and is flanked on either side by two tall, fixed-pane, four-panel windows. an asphalt-shingle awning wraps from the side elevations across the front of the facade, bisecting it horizontally. The awning's roof is supported by two square brick columns on either side of the double doors, and the base of the columns is built into brick planters that extend away from the doors to either side of the facade. There are boxwoods planted in front of the planters. The top half of the facade is dominated by a cross made from glass bricks. The church faces Marie Foster Street, and the main doors open onto a concrete path connected with the sidewalk in front of the church. The lawn area on the corner between Philpot and Marie Foster is protected by a set of steel posts with a chain running across them to discourage people from cutting the corner. The north elevation is partly visible and includes a single-leaf door where the porch wraps around, supported by two round columns. Two windows are visible on the west elevation beside the door, approximating one on each story. Another boxwood decorates the corner behind the chain at Philpot and Marie Foster. The church sign is partly visible in front of a large evergreen shrub obscuring the rest of the west elevation. A white clapboard house is visible to the south of the church.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The congregation of Northern Heights Presbyterian Church formed in 1900 at the Sylvan Street Presbyterian Church under the Reverend Lucius Deyampert. Deyampert left the church to become a missionary to the Congo under William H. Sheppard, an African American missionary who would later become known for his activism opposing to the treatment of the Congolese by rubber companies. The Sylvan Street Presbyterian Church was the second black Presbyterian Church established in Alabama. The congregation grew through the first half of the twentieth century, and moved to the Northern Heights building in June 1960. This building was originally the Northside Baptist Church. The Sylvan Street Church, located at Sylvan Street (now Martin Luther King Street) and Philpot Avenue, is still extant, though in very poor condition. Like many churches at that time, Northern Heights had an active congregation and hosted many volunteer activities for women and children. The church also operated a kindergarten and low-level elementary school, as did many other black churches. Later, starting in the 1970s, the church operated a daycare center for low-income families for fourteen years. Northern Heights is affiliated with the Presbyterian Church (USA). </dc:description>
<dc:subject>African American Churches -- Tennessee; Brick churches; Church buildings -- Alabama; Church buildings; Civil rights -- United States; Historic buildings; African American neighborhoods; Baptist church buildings</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Missionary</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only;</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>IMG_0464</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/6195</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>