<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Brainerd Mission Cemetery: commemorative marker</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van</dc:creator>
<dc:date>c. 2006</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Brainerd Mission Cemetery</dc:description>
<dc:description>Cemetery</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>79002435 listed 1979/12/06</dc:identifier>
<dc:description>5700 Eastgate Loop, Chattanooga, Hamilton Co., TN</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Chattanooga, Hamilton County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>35.009407,-85.212949</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of an engraved stone marker with the text: "Site of Brainerd Mission to the Cherokee Indians. Established by the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions in 1817. First called Chickamaugah. Changed to Brainerd in 1818. Maintained with aid of the United States government until the removal of the Indians in 1838. Here forty buildings were erected and hundreds of Indians were Christianized and educated. Erected by the Chickamauga Chapter of the Daughters of the American Revolution, 1924"</dc:description>
<dc:description>Founded in 1817 by representatives of the American Board of Commissioners of Foreign Missions (ABCFM), Brainerd Mission remained open until Cherokee removal 21 years later. Brainerd Mission was responsible for the basic education and religious education of many Cherokee, and was recognized as a national model for the boarding school approach that dominated white attempts to educate Native Americans for most of the nineteenth century.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Cemeteries -- Tennessee; Brainerd Mission; Cherokee Indians -- Missions</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Cemeteries; Historical markers</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:format>35 mm slide</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>brainerd004</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/1051</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>