<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Green Street Baptist Church: facade</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Humphreys, Elizabeth Moore, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2013-08-08</dc:date>
<dc:description>Green Street Baptist Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>1220 Green Street Selma, AL 36701</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Selma, Dallas County, AL</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>32.416946, -87.019854</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of the west-facing fa&#231;ade, photographer facing the northwest. The fa&#231;ade extends along Green Street. Part of a telephone pole is visible in the upper right corner of the image. A silver sedan is parked parallel to the facade. The church has a cross-gable shape, with one gable end facing the facade and another gable end facing south, with a one story addition filling in the inside corner between the gabled projections. The northwest corner of the building features a tall square bell tower with a steeply-pitched pyramid bonnet roof topped by a large cross. Just below the roof, two narrow, arched openings are visible on each of the elevations. The top section of the tower is supported by split brick pilasters on each corner, each divided into three sections with a solid connection between. The top of the bell tower section is supported by a row of brick corbels. The bottom half of the tower includes a pair of arched, stained-glass windows on the west elevation, with a concrete keystone and two concrete imposts separated by a triple-row of brick. The lowest level of the tower includes wood double doors with a stained glass fanlight beneath a matching arch. A single metal light fixture on an arm projects out from the keystone of the arch, providing light for the main entrance. The doors are accessed via a set of concrete steps with plain, wrought-iron railings on either side. The stairs are flanked by a low concrete wall on either side. The enclosed foundation of the church is white-painted concrete. The fa&#231;ade is asymmetrical, as the northwest corner bell tower intrudes on the gable-end central section. A smaller bell tower is situated at the south end of the fa&#231;ade. The central part of the fa&#231;ade has a gable front roof with a small square brick pediment at its apex to which a decoy or statue of an owl has been affixed. The roofline of the gable end is cement, and the south end has a small flat section at its end. The brickwork below the roofline includes a series of brick corbels like those on the bell tower, though as they move down at an angle they give the effect of brick bargeboard. Roughly two thirds from the apex, two of the corbels extend down to the foundation to form split pilasters like those on the bell tower. There are two circular openings beneath the apex of the roof, one small, open, and edged in cement, the other a stained glass rosette window with a clear glass storm window over it. Between the pilaster and the northwest bell tower are two rows of windows. The top row is four arched stained glass window, each with its own cement keystone sharing imposts with its partners, like those on the northwest bell tower, though each one here has its own cement sill. The row below includes four vertical rectangular stained glass windows, each with a cement lintel and sill. The windows are arranged so that they appear to be four very tall windows interrupted by brick and cement. Another such window, with one arched on top and other rectangular below, sits between the brick pilaster and the southwest tower. The southwest tower is very similar to the northwest bell tower, though it is roughly one story shorter. It has no bell, and its pyramid bonnet roof is peaked by a sharp spike and it has no set of open arches. It also includes a pair of arched, stained-glass windows and matching double doors. An arm for a light fixture protrudes over the doors, but the light fixture itself is missing. The upper section of the south elevation of the tower matches the facade, however, the lower portion has been obscured by a one-story addition filling in the southwest corner of the building. The addition houses a children's choir room and is likely from the 1937-46 renovations. The addition is partially set back from the facade, and obscures the south elevation of the bell tower, so a window matching those on the upper portion of the tower has been replaced with white painted wood. The addition's roof has partially collapsed so that the north end obscures the very top of the addition's west wall. The addition is red brick, but is stretcher bond rather than common bond like the original brickwork. Each corner of the addition includes a double brick pilaster with white wood moulding-topped caps supporting the white painted wood eave. the base of the west elevation matches the white-painted foundation on the rest of the facade. The west elevation is dominated by a large arched wood triple stained glass window. The west elevation of the original church building above the addition includes a pair of arched stained glass windows matching those on the facade. A gutter system is visible where the roof meets the wall, and obscures the tops of the keystones over the windows. A security camera sits on the corner of the addition facing north along the facade. A gutter pipe extends from the gutter system along the roof down to the roof of the addition, and there are two PVC pipes sticking up from the roof of the addition nearest the original building on the west elevation A brick chimney with a cement cap extends up along the west elevation of the south-facing gable end. Three wooden crosses, one set in front of the other two, are on the lawn facing the Green Street behind the sedan. There are trimmed boxwoods in front of the foundation along the fa&#231;ade. The A cement sidewalk runs along Green Street, sloping down to street level. The south corner of the building includes two sections of chainlink fence extending from the sidewalk to the building. Another section of chainlink extends south from the one story addition. The west elevation is barely visible due to the angle of the photograph. </dc:description>
<dc:description>The congregation of Green Street Baptist Church formed in 1881, primarily from the congregation of First Baptist Church (Colored), which was then known as the St. Phillip Street Baptist Church (due to their location). The church was led by Reverend John Blevins, who had been pastor at St. Phillip Street, thus the church was originally known as &#8220;The John Blevins Church.&#8221; He remained there for two or three years. On December 31, 1881, church trustees Jefferson Richardson, Joseph Baylock, Adam Clayton, and Henry Lamar purchased a lot on the corner of Green Street and McCreary Avenue (now Griffin Avenue) for $150. The first worship services were held in a store on the corner.  The first church the congregation built was a small frame building on a lot adjacent to wear the brick church now stands. The frame church was small and uncomfortable, unable to accommodate the congregation of 200 souls (with 300 attending Sunday School). The interior of the original structure was lit by three lanterns hanging from the ceiling and a tin lamp on each side wall. The minister had a small platform to stand on, and the children sat on the edge. The original frame building was replaced once by a larger frame church, and again by a brick church, which was dedicated in 1892. The current building was dedicated in 1922. The plan for the building came to Pastor James A. Martin in a dream, and it was designed and built by contractor A.J. Farley, which accounts for the church&#8217;s unusual architectural features. Between 1937 and 1946, the church building was renovated and restrooms added. Between 1946 and 1958, the church was renovated again, including the purchase of new pews and floor coverings, and a paved sidewalk was added around the church. In 1946, the church opened a kindergarten, which operated for 14 years. In 1962, the church added an education wing. The late 1980s saw another interior renovation, accompanied by a new roof and renovated restrooms. In the late 1990s, a truss in the church&#8217;s roof failed, which has led to significant damage to the structure, including the bowing of the sanctuary wall on Griffin Avenue, the holes in the roof, and extensive interior damage from exposure to the elements. The remaining congregation currently worships in the education wing.  Green Street&#8217;s current state belies its historical significance. During the 1960s, the church enjoyed a thriving congregation, and its kitchen was used to prepare meals for marchers in the Selma to Montgomery March in 1965. The considerable space in both the education wing and the main sanctuary were also used to provide temporary housing for civil rights workers. On June 5, 1964, the church hosted a mass meeting featuring Ralph Abernathy of the Southern Christian Leadership Conference. Following the meeting, someone threw a rock at some of the deputized possemen who had surrounded the church during the meeting. The possemen responded by attacking the crowd as it tried to exit the church, using night sticks and tear gas. The riot continued in the neighborhood, injuring many of the black residents and putting some in the hospital. Homes up to a block and a half away from the church were damaged, with broken windows and porch lights. Two white journalists were targeted and their cameras destroyed by possemen.  </dc:description>
<dc:subject>African American Churches -- Tennessee; Baptist church buildings; Bell towers; Brick churches; Church buildings; Church buildings -- Alabama; Churches; Civil rights -- United States; Stained glass windows</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>IMG_0178</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/6319</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>