<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Pikeville Chapel AME Zion Church: front view and sign</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2006?</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Pikeville Chapel African Methodist Episcopal Zion Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>School</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>99001444  listed Nov. 30, 1999</dc:identifier>
<dc:description>Upper East Valley Road, Pikeville, Bledsoe Co., TN</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Pikeville, Bledsoe County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>35.605403,-85.185385</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of a small white church building. The view is of the front (north) and side (east) facades. The single-story building of frame construction has a steep metal roof with gable end at its front and a small tower to the left side that includes the double entry doors. Two short flights of steps lead to the doors, which open under a small porch. At the rear of the sanctuary a small shed-roofed unit forms an el with the main building. In the foreground is a sign reading "Pikeville Chapel A.M.E. Zion Church. Sunday School 10 AM. Morning worship 11 AM. Rev. Charles Clark-pastor."</dc:description>
<dc:description>Pikeville African Methodist Episcopal Church was built ca. 1870 and is believed to be the oldest rural African American Church building in Tennessee. At times during its long history it served multiple congregations. The church building also served as a public school, known as Lincoln Academy, that served the Black population of the Pikeville area until the new Lincoln School opened in 1925 with support of the Rosenwald Fund. From its founding throughout the Jim Crow era, the setting and location of the church
 was significant to its association with African-American ethnic heritage. Laying on the east bank of the Sequatchie River, the church was physically segregated from the remainder of Pikeville. It was next -to-town, but clearly not part of town. The church was still in use at the time of its nomination to the National Register.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>African American Churches -- Tennessee ; Rural churches -- Tennessee</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Churches</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>4 x 6 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University ; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>SP_AMEZion_019.tif</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/277</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>