<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Cedar Hill Rosenwald School: close-up front view</dc:title>
<dc:date>1995-2005</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Cedar Hill Rosenwald School</dc:description>
<dc:description>Coopertown Cedar Hill Rosenwald School</dc:description>
<dc:description>School</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>19731002</dc:identifier>
<dc:coverage>Coopertown, Robertson County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>36.448146, -87.009827</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of the one-story white frame school building with a side red gable roof. It features three chimneys and a bell tower in the center of the roof. It resembles the traditional two-teacher floor plan. The central front gable extension would have been the industrial room and on either side were classrooms. All three rooms feature a chimney.  The classrooms feature two one over one light double hung windows. The two classroom entrances are located on either side of the industrial room on the facade. The industrial room is characterized by four twelve over twelve light double hung windows with transoms above for additional light. </dc:description>
<dc:description>The Cedar Hill School was built with support of the Julius Rosenwald fund with funds allocated for budget year 1929-30. Total cost of construction was $5750.00 with funds contributed by African American community, the public, and Rosenwald. The school was a three teacher design plan built on four acres of land.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>African American schools -- Tennessee;Julius Rosenwald Fund -- Buildings</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:format>4 x 6 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/6345</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>