<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>St. Mark United Primitive Baptist Church: history</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Fearnback, Heather; Besser, Susan; West, Carroll Van</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1998</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1990-1999</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>St. Mark United Primitive Baptist Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>Church</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>00000811 listed 2000/07/14</dc:identifier>
<dc:description>518 Maury Hill St, Spring Hill, Maury Co., TN</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Spring Hill, Maury County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>35.751301,-86.934607</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Church history and property survey; includes history of the building, congregation, ministers, and activities</dc:description>
<dc:description>St. Mark United Primitive Baptist Church was originially named Spring Hill Primitive Baptist. Spring Hill Primitive was part of the Big Harpeth United Primitive Baptist Association of Tennessee. On August 31, 1872, the Association convened at Spring Hill Primitive. This means the congregation dates back to between 1866 and 1872. The construction of the church is suspected to have been around 1900. It served as a local school for African-American children until Spring Hill Rosenwald School opened in 1920-21.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>African American Churches -- Tennessee; Church buildings -- Tennessee</dc:subject>
<dc:language>Eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>History</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>3 p., 8.5 x 11 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>StMark00002</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/228</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>