<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Macedonia Baptist Church: view of church front, marquee sign, and bell</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:coverage>1990-1999</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Macedonia Baptist Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>303 White Oak Avenue, Newport, TN 37821</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Newport, Cocke County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>35.963468,-83.191548</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of marquee sign and bell in front of church. The marquee sign, located inside a brick enclosure, reads "Macedonia SS 945; Church 1050; Pastor James Billings." A bell is mounted to the top of the brick enclosure. Another sign is located on the front of the church's portico. This sign's lettering reads, "Macedonia Baptist Church; Pastor James C. Billings."</dc:description>
<dc:description>Established in 1898, Macedonia Baptist Church resides in Newport, Tennessee. In 1978, the current building on White Oak Avenue was built under the pastorate of Reverend C. J. Mize. At the time of fieldwork, James C. Billings served as pastor.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>African American Churches -- Tennessee; Baptist church buildings; </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Churches ; Gable roofs ; Signs ; Bells ; Steeples ; Sidewalks ; Cornerstones ; Brick</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Churches</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>4 x 6 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>SP_MacedoniaBaptistChurch_002.tif</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/4226</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>