<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>New Pilgrim Baptist Church: history and property description</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van</dc:creator>
<dc:contributor>Nelson, Linda; White, Marjorie</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>2003</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>New Pilgrim Baptist Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>Church</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>05000306  Listed August 24, 2007</dc:identifier>
<dc:description>903 6th Ave. S., Birmingham, AL</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Birmingham, Jefferson County, AL</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>33.499592,-86.815283</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>The narrative document developed for nomination of the property to the National Register. It provides both a physical description of the property and a summary of the history and significance of the church.</dc:description>
<dc:description>New Pilgrim Baptist Church was built in 1945-46 in response to an increasing number of African-American laborers in the southside neighborhoods near downtown Birmingham.  The congregation expanded the building in 1958-59 under the leadership of Rev. Nelson H. Smith, a young pastor who considered himself a "loyal lieutenant" to Rev. Fred Shuttlesworth, co-founder of the Alabama Christian Movement for Civil Rights and key participant in the 1963 Birmingham campaign.   The New Pilgrim congregation was the largest in the ACMHR in the early years, and frequently hosted meetings. The most significant event associated with the church is the May 5, 1963 March on the Birmingham Jail.  Activists  who spoke at the church included Rev. Ralph Abernathy, Dr. Martin Luther King Jr., Freedom Rider Clyde Carter, Rev. E.S. Blackstone; Rev. Andrew Young; Wyatt Tee Walker; Rev. J.W. Hayes; Rev. James Bevel; Bernard Lee; and comedian Dick Gregory.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>African American Churches -- Tennessee; Alabama Christian Movement for Human Rights; Civil rights -- United States</dc:subject>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>History</dc:format>
<dc:format>electronic</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>New Pilgrim Baptist Church</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/1757</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>