<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Hackney Chapel AME Zion Church: side view</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1998</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1990-1999</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Hackney Chapel African Methodist Episcopal Zion Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>Cemetery</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>00000729 listed July 10, 2000</dc:identifier>
<dc:description>Hackney Chapel Rd, Lenoir City, Tennessee</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Unitia, Loudon County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>35.744699,-84.197019</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of a church building with gable roof and bell cupola on the right; left elevation is shorter than the main building; three boarded rectangular windows; one open rectangle window next to a covered door; tall stove pipe midway down wall; gravel road in foreground and trees in background</dc:description>
<dc:description>Hackney Chapel AME Zion Church was built by the African American members of the Unitia community (unincorporated) in October of 1899. The land had been owned by F.R. and M.J. Hackney, African American land owners who donated the land for a church and cemetery. During the early twentieth century life in Unitia centered around the church and the Unitia School, which closed in 1948 due to lack of students. The church added a rear addition in the 1930s, which provided a raised space tor the minister's pulpit and choir; electricity and paneling followed c. 1970, and a picnic shelter with attached restrooms c. 1980. The church remained in business until 1988 when its only two members passed away. The cemetery contains approximately 100 markers, dating to the 1880's prior to the church's construction in 1899.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>African American Churches -- Tennessee;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Churches;</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>4 x 6 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>HackneyChapel008</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/1192</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>