<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>First Baptist Church Alamo: side</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1998-06-11</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1990-1999</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>First Baptist Church Alamo</dc:description>
<dc:description>Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>290 W. Lincoln St, Alamo, TN 38001</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Alamo, Crockett County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>35.777986,-89.120552</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of brick church's side. The building features three distinct sections: a gable-fronted vestibule, a gable-roofed main section with three bays of windows, and a rear section with two doors and two sash windows. A gravel lot sits next to the building.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The First Baptist Church of Alamo, Tennessee is a rural African American church. The historic building was remodeled in 1976 under the pastorate of Reverend E. L. Mabins. On November 4, 1984, the church cornerstone was laid by Celestial Lodge No. 80 of Humboldt, Tennessee. Reverend John Cole served as pastor at that time. The Central High School once stood behind the building. At the time of fieldwork, a park had replaced the former high school.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>African American Churches -- Tennessee; Baptist church buildings</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Churches</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Churches</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>4 x 6 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>SP_FirstBaptistAlamo_003.tif</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/4234</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>