<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Wells Rosenwald School: exterior of school</dc:title>
<dc:date>1995</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1920-1929</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Wells Rosenwald School</dc:description>
<dc:description>School</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>95000292 listed 1995/3/31</dc:identifier>
<dc:coverage>Eads, Shelby County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>35.238705, -89.649652</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of a side gable one-story wooden building with chimneys on either end. It has a central, recessed entrance in the middle of three bays. The north bay of the facade has a ribbon of five nine-over-nine light double hung sash windows. The south bay has four of the same windows set as two pairs. The original foundation for this building consisted of concrete piers. The foundation has since been filled in with brick and small vents for circulation.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The Wells Rosenwald School was built by Samuel L. Smith with support of the Julius Rosenwald fund. According to the National Register nomination, it was originally built in 1924-25 as a four room, rectangular plan. The Rosenwald Fund donated $900, the African American community raised $600, and the county and state provided the remaining $2,850. The 1924 Community Plans stated that the schoolhouse should also serve the larger community. Wells had a designated community room with a stage where a variety of lecturers spoke to both adults and children alike. The attendees came from both the Eads and Collierville areas. As a school, Wells' enrollment included around 100 students annually. Over time, partitions have been added to expand the number of rooms. In the 1950s, other minor renovations were made that include adding a concrete block building in the rear attached by a covered walkway to the main building.  It served as an African American school until desegregation occurred in 1966. It then became a private residence. </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Julius Rosenwald Fund -- Buildings; African American schools -- Tennessee </dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:format>4 x 6 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/6291</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>