<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Republican Primitive Baptist Church: south facade</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1998?</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1990-1999;</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Republican Primitive Baptist Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>Brownsville, Haywood County, TN</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>00000769 listed July 5, 2000</dc:identifier>
<dc:description>350 Raymond Taylor Rd., Brownsville, TN</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Brownsville, Haywood County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>35.630113,-89.432955</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Black and white photo of the back (south) facade of a small, white, wood-framed church. The church rests on concrete piers. Three windows line the wall and a stovepipe emerges between two of the windows, reaching above the eave of the gable-on-hip roof. The angled view shows a small addition on the east side of the building, and an entrance door.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The Republican Primitive Baptist Church began in the late 1800s, formered by the Florence and Payton families of Haywood Count, TN. These families were staunch Republicans, reflected in the 1880 election of the Governor, who the African American vote helped to elect. After its establishment, Republic Primitive Baptist Church joined the Big Creek Association, a regional organization of black Primitive Baptists. The church served as both a schoolhouse and church until the late 1920s when a neighborhood school for black children was built. By the mid-1970s, the congregation dwindled and by 1989 only five or six members and a minister remained. These numbers prompted them to merge with a neighboring community's Primitive Baptist Church. In the early 1990s, some of the congregation reinstituted some activities like the annual homecoming and in 1998 during the annual homecoming, funds were donated to help support and restore the church.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>African American Churches -- Tennessee; Rural churches</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Churches</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>Republican012.tif</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/3570</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>