<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Waco Rosenwald School: view from road of red paneled buildings</dc:title>
<dc:date>2004</dc:date>
<dc:description>Waco School</dc:description>
<dc:description>School</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Lynnville, Giles County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>35.3731323, -87.0355625</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of roadside view of Waco Rosenwald School. The one-story structure features two buildings with red paneling. There are no visible windows on the building in the foreground. The perpendicular building in the background has red paneling on either ends with off-white paneling in the center. The main view of this building is obstructed by the enclosed building in the foreground. One entrance is visible from this view as well as two small clearstory windows. </dc:description>
<dc:description>The Waco Rosenwald School was built with support of the Julius Rosenwald Fund. According to the Tennessee Humanities Council&#8217;s History of Black Education in Giles County, the construction on the Waco School began in 1917 and it was completed in 1921. It was 720 square feet and valued at $3,050. The 1921-22 term began in July 1921 and ended four months later. It resumed in February 1922 and closed in April. This was due to the irregular attendance caused by many of the children working during the fall harvest season. The cold winter months also affected attendance because the school lacked a stove for heat. The Council&#8217;s analysis of the teachers&#8217; registers reveals that the teachers worked to professionalize education and improve the level of instruction. The classes included writing, music, drawing, reading, U.S. History, arithmetic, civics, geography, spelling, language, grammar, and hygiene.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Julius Rosenwald Fund -- Buildings; African American schools -- Tennessee</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:format>4 x 6 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission.</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/6151</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>