<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Willilam Cannon Houston House history and property description</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van</dc:creator>
<dc:contributor>Shell, Mary Mason</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1988</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1980-1989</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>William Cannon Houston House</dc:description>
<dc:description>House</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>89000503 listed 1989/06/16</dc:identifier>
<dc:description>107 Houston Ln., Woodbury, Cannon Co., TN</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Woodbury, Cannon County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>35.823084,-86.059565</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>William Cannon Houston House history, its historical significance and property description</dc:description>
<dc:description>The William Cannon Houston House, "Beaver Dam," is associated with Indian and military activities in early Cannon County history. Its owner was the most important Cannon County politician of the turn-of-the-century, serving six terms in the U.S. Congress, besides stints in the state legislature and as a judge.  A cabin was originally built by Sam McFerrin  on an old Indian trail and the historic Old Stage Road used by fur traders and travellers in the early 1800s.  Tradition dates the cabin to c. 1810. Cherokee Indians, on the Trail of Tears, camped near the house in 1838. Nathan Bedford Forrest's troops headquartered at the house briefly in July 1862. By the time ownership passed to William Cannon Houston in 1873, the house had transformed into a classic two-story I-house dwelling.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Houses and homes; Historic buildings -- Tennessee</dc:subject>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>History</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>11 pg, 8.5 x 11 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>wmcanhou00007</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/761</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>