<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Montgomery High School: entrance to the auditorium</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2006-11-09</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Montgomery High School</dc:description>
<dc:description>Montgomery-Bond-Robinson Community Center</dc:description>
<dc:description>School</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>07000662 Listed July, 3, 2007</dc:identifier>
<dc:description>125 Montgomery Way, Lexington, TN 38351</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Lexington, Henderson County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>35.650967,-88.400431</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>A color photograph to the entrance of the auditorium. The trophy cases between the doors are visible.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Montgomery High School, in Lexington, Tennessee, was built from 1948-1950 and opened in 1950. It served African-American students in rural Middle and West Tennessee counties, including Henderson, Wayne, Perry, Benton, Decatur, and Madison. The gymnasium was built in 1953. The current school building was built on the site of the Montgomery School, a Rosenwald Fund school, built in 1923 to replace the Lexington Colored School which was in another location. The Montgomery School became Montgomery High School in 1927. Montgomery High School was in operation until 1967 when all county schools were desegregated. The school building remained a part of the community and served as a community center run by the Alumni Association. In 1997, the gymnasium was renovated and renamed Montgomery-Bond-Robinson Community Center. Montgomery Head Start uses a portion of the original school building.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>African American schools -- Tennessee; National Register of Historic Places</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Awards; Cabinets (Case furniture)</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>MontgomerySchool_interiorentrancetoauditorium(25)</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/1324</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>