<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Major Ridge Home: excavation of building site</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van</dc:creator>
<dc:date>c. 2011</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2010-2019</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Major Ridge Home</dc:description>
<dc:description>Chieftains Museum</dc:description>
<dc:description>House</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>71000273 Listed April 7, 1971</dc:identifier>
<dc:description>501 Riverside Parkway, Rome, GA</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Rome, Floyd County, GA</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>34.270289,-85.169419</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of excavation site that appears to be an old building foundation; stonework visible in ground; wood fence and brick buildings in background</dc:description>
<dc:description>Major Ridge was an important Cherokee leader who is most remembered as a signer of the Treaty of New Echota that sold Cherokee land to the U. S. Government in exchange for land in Oklahoma, leading to the removal of most Cherokee from Georgia via the Trail of Tears. Originally from the Hiwassee River area of Tennessee, Ridge moved his family to a site along the Oostanaula River, where he operated a ferry, trading post and farm. The original dogtrot cabin built by Major Ridge circa 1800 is incorporated in the modern Major Ridge Home. Conversion of the cabin to a clapboard plantation home was done by Ridge, with significant modernization done since. The house is now part of the Chieftains Museum.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Ridge, Major, ca. 1771-1839 -- Homes and haunts</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Archaeological sites</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:format>Electronic</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>IMG_0434</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/1005</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>