<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Lynchburg Historic District: nominated area map</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Moore County government</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Lynchburg Historic District</dc:description>
<dc:description>District</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>96000771 listed July 19, 1996</dc:identifier>
<dc:description>Bounded by majors, Main, Elm, and Wall Streets, Lynchburg, Moore County, TN</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Lynchburg, Moore County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>35.283136,-86.374159</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Parcel map of downtown Lynchburg with a highlighted area which denotes the Historic District</dc:description>
<dc:description>The Lynchburg Historic District is comprised of eighty-two properties which make up the central part of the community, located in Moore County, TN. Lynchburg was designated as the county seat of the newly established Moore County in 1871. It is also the commercial and industrial center for the county. The area contains buildings that represent the development of Lynchburg from a crossroads community into the political and commercial center of Moore County. The integrity of the district is evident not only in the historic buildings, but in the layout of the town, which reflects the impact of the county seat designation. The focus of the historic district is a downtown core which surrounds the courthouse block and is known as the Public Square.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Historic districts</dc:subject>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Map</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>1 pg, 11" x 17"</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>Lynchburg090</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/2278</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>