<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Good Samaritan Hospital: southwest view</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Humphreys, Elizabeth Moore, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2012-08-21</dc:date>
<dc:description>Good Samaritan Hospital</dc:description>
<dc:description>Hospital</dc:description>
<dc:description>1107 Voeglin Avenue Selma, Alabama </dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Selma, Dallas County, AL</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>32.417154, -87.023232</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of the southwest corner of Good Samaritan Hospital, photographer facing northeast. The hospital is a four-story, modern, brutalism-influenced building in brick in and concrete. Its overall shape is rectangular, with the west and east elevations making up the long sides and the fa&#231;ade on the south side. Two sections project out of their respective elevations. On the west elevation, the short side of an L-shaped section that is half a story higher than the rest of the building projects slightly from the rest of the elevation. The fa&#231;ade features a section a half story taller than the rest of the building and projecting slightly. It is also L-shaped with the longer side facing the fa&#231;ade. The projecting section of the fa&#231;ade is clad in concrete panels and dominated by a stylized cross made of peaked, greenish concrete sections that slope into the fa&#231;ade. The entry is protected by three flat-topped, box-style, open-front, three-sided concrete awnings. The awnings are supported by four flat, rectangular columns with the short sides facing the fa&#231;ade. The west end of the fa&#231;ade is brick with a wide concrete belt between the first floor and the upper three. Just below the concrete belt, metal letters read GOOD SAMARITAN HOSPITAL CENTER 1107 VOEGLIN AVENUE. The letters after the R in &#8220;Samaritan&#8221; are obscured by a telephone pole in the foreground. The concrete belt wraps around the west elevation as well. The ground floor is brick with three openings. The upper floors are divided into nine bays. Moving from the fa&#231;ade north, the first five bays are identical. Each floor includes a pair of single-pane windows in metal frames topped with a three-sided, box-style concrete awning. The sides of the awning extend down half the height of the windows. The vertical column of bays containing the windows are clad in concrete panels with vents centered between the pair of concrete panels. The areas between the bays are brick. The sixth bay is the projecting section. The upper levels include the same windows on the end, but without the awnings and only one vent between the second and third story windows. The other side of the projecting section is brick. The final three bays match the first five. The first level of the west elevation is brick. It includes a pair of metal doors below a concrete panel transom lined up below the second bay. Large metal letters reading Good Samaritan Center are mounted near the concrete belt between the metal doors and the projecting section. Ten utility boxes are situated below the name of the building. The projecting section includes a pair of boarded-up doors beneath the windows, with a single three-sided concrete awning matching the ones on the fa&#231;ade, with the same style of supports. The north end of the west elevation includes a large, boarded over section with a concrete transom spanning the space between the last two windowed bays. The seamed ends of the metal roof are visible at the roofline. The grassy yard in the foreground is surrounded by a single metal rail fence. A sidewalk with a median between it and the curb runs along Voeglin Avenue. Low steps provide access from the sidewalk to the entry on the fa&#231;ade. Two large boxwoods flank the entry. Two more trimmed shrubs grow in the median in the foreground, and a short but very full tree is in the enclosed yard. Two telephone poles, one with a streetlight, sit in the foreground. The metal-fenced parking lot on the east side of the hospital is just visible.	
</dc:description>
<dc:description>The extant modernist Good Samaritan Hospital in Selma, Alabama was built in 1964 by the Sisters of St. Joseph and the Edmundites (Fathers of St. Edmund), two Catholic missions. Originally built in 1922, Good Samaritan (or Good Sam, as it is known locally) was the second black hospital in the city, after the Burwell Infirmary. The hospital was originally run by the Alabama Baptist Convention under the administration of Mamie Norris, a nurse from the Tuskegee Institute. The Catholics purchased the hospital in 1944, built a new facility in 1947, which was replaced by the modern facility that could house 111 patients in 1964. Good Samaritan was the only hospital in the six surrounding counties open to African Americans. Sister Louis Bertrand established Alabama&#8217;s first School of Practical Nursing at Good Samaritan to deal with the critical nursing shortage. This was an important source of employment and training to black women (though a handful of black men also completed the program), who had few other such opportunities under Jim Crow. The hospital was also an important source of employment for Selma&#8217;s black community. The Sisters of St. Joseph took part in the civil rights movement in Selma in a variety of ways, including boycotting grocery stores that only catered to whites, attending mass meetings at nearby Tabernacle Baptist Church, and attempting to visit black youth who were arrested for protesting. This did little to endear them to Selma&#8217;s white community, who referred to them as the &#8220;black sisters,&#8221; and earned the attention of the local chapter of the Ku Klux Klan (KKK). The building was It also functioned as a center of community, hosting the Selma Literacy Project, an effort of the Dallas County Voters League and the Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (SNCC) to prepare potential black voters for the literacy test required in order to register to vote. Good Samaritan was where victims of racially motivated violence and police shootings went for care. Jimmie Lee Jackson, a civil rights activist in nearby Marion (Perry County), Alabama was brought to Good Sam for treatment after being beaten by troopers and shot by Alabama State Trooper James Bonard Fowler. Jackson&#8217;s death from his injuries inspired James Bevel of the Southern Christian Leadership Conference to plan the Selma to Montgomery Marches that included both Bloody Sunday and the successful March to Montgomery in March 1965. Marchers injured in Bloody Sunday were also brought to Good Sam for treatment. Though the sisters could not march by order of the bishop, they opened the hospital and convent as meeting and rest places for the demonstrators who poured into Selma from across the country. After 1965, Good Samaritan began to struggle as white hospitals were forced to open their doors to black patients, and white doctors and black patients began seeking out care at the better-equipped (and better paying) formerly white facilities. In 1972, the Sisters of St. Joseph withdrew from Good Samaritan Hospital, citing worsening conditions, poor finances, and a lack of sufficient staff. African American leaders took over, with John Crear as administrator and Dr. Charles Lett as medical chief. They won a grant for research on rural health, which led to the establishment of the Rural Health Medical Program, which allowed Good Samaritan to play a key role in providing education and health care to the rural communities of Dallas, Perry, Wilcox, and Lowndes Counties. By 1983, however, the poverty of the surrounding areas overwhelmed the hospital&#8217;s precarious finances, and Good Samaritan was forced to close its doors. In 2016, Mayor George Evans announced an effort to reopen the hospital as a medical center with space for a museum to acknowledge the facility&#8217;s key role in the voting rights movement.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Civil rights -- United States; Clergy; Historic buildings; Women</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>hospital; catholic; nursing; nuns; black history; voting rights</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>IMG_0162</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/6333</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>