<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Spring Hill United Methodist Church: northwest elevation</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Eatherly, Brad, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2015</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2010-2019</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Spring Hill United Methodist Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>Church</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Spring Hill, Maury County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>35.752415, -86.928560</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of a historic brick church viewed from the southwest.  The church has a stone foundation with a gabled roof with two cross gables.  Two sets of steps lead from Main Street up to the front entryway.  The double-leafed wooden doors are flanked by two stained glass windows.  A small awning is located above the doorway with a large stained glass window directly above the doorway.  A stained glass arched transom light sits above the stained glass windows.  A large steeple with a cross dominates the front facade.  The south elevation of the original building features three stained glass windows.  An addition at the rear of the building has two doors and  seven windows.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The Spring Hill United Methodist Church has existed as a congregation perhaps since 1816.  The current building was constructed in 1886.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Church buildings -- Tennessee</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Methodist churches; Signs (Notices)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Church signs</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/6259</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>