<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Cumberland Gap: The Church of the Living God</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van</dc:creator>
<dc:date>c. 1989</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1980-1989</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Cumberland Gap Historic District</dc:description>
<dc:description>District</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>90000321 listed Feb. 23, 1990</dc:identifier>
<dc:description>217 Pennlyn Avenue, Cumberland Gap, TN</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Cumberland Gap, Claiborne County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>36.599527,-83.668525</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Black and white photograph of The Church of the Living God (formerly Cumberland Gap Methodist Church), circa 1905, Gothic Revivial influence one-story frame structure; gable roof; flanking square tower with double leaf entrance with multi-light arched transom, arched ventilation openings with wooden slats, multi-light stained glass windows in Gothic arches; cement stairs lead up to doors from a side walk</dc:description>
<dc:description>The Cumberland Gap Historic District is significant for the patterns of Claiborne County's history as a a late nineteenth and early twentieth century mining town, fueled by English capitalists, and an example of late nineteenth town architecture in Claiborne County. For over two hundred years, Cumberland Gap has served as a significant passageway to the lands west of the Appalachian mountains.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Historic districts; Churches -- Tennessee; Cumberland Gap (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Churches</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>6 x 4 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>cumberlandgap020</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/1002</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>