<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Mt. Pleasant AME Zion: fieldnotes</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1998</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1990-1999</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Mt. Pleasant African Methodist Episcopal Zion Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>Cemetery</dc:description>
<dc:description>3664 Mt. Pleasant Church Rd, Rockford, TN 37853</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Rockford, Blount County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>35.821354, -83.955308</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Fieldnotes of Mt. Pleasant AME Zion Church. Notes document the location of the church. At the time of fieldwork, the church's address was listed as 3664 Grade Road. Rough sketch shows the 1948 and 1982 sections of the church in relation to Grade Road and the railroad.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The Zion Methodist Church of Rockford has roots in the late nineteenth century when Reverend Jim Rogers served as pastor. At that time, church members regularly congregated in a log building until a fire destroyed it. The land upon which the present-day church sits was purchased for thirty-nine dollars on September 5, 1887. Although the church had acquired land, they were financially unable to afford the construction of a new church building. In order to have a place of worship, the congregation entered into an agreement with Blount County Quarterly Court. In exchange for allowing an elementary school to be erected on the land, the church gained access to the facility for services.  By May 1912, a new building was in use. This building was improved in 1941 with the addition of electric lighting, choir areas, kitchen, and dining hall. Further renovations, including restrooms and brick veneering, occurred in the 1960s and 1970s. According to the fieldnotes, the current building includes</dc:description>
<dc:subject>African American Churches -- Tennessee</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Field notes</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Fieldnotes</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>1 p.; 8.5 x 11 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>SP_MtPleasantAMEZion_001.tif</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/3917</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>