<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Fisk University: Douglas mural detail of man with torch</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Douglas, Aaron</dc:creator>
<dc:contributor>West, Carroll Van, photographer</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1930?</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Fisk University</dc:description>
<dc:description>School</dc:description>
<dc:description>District</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>78002579 listed February 8, 1978</dc:identifier>
<dc:description>1000 17th Ave. N., Nashville, Davidson County, TN</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Nashville, Davidson County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>36.167574,-86.804103</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of a green and black mural featuring a figure kneeling next to a column and holding a torch, planets in the background</dc:description>
<dc:description>Fisk University was established six months after the end of the Civil War by John Ogden, the Reverend Erastus Milo Cravath, and the Reverend Edward P. Smith. They named the school in honor of General Clinton B. Fisk of the Tennessee Freedmen's Bureau, who provided the new institution with facilities in former Union Army barracks near the present site of Nashville's Union Station. The first classes convened on January 9, 1866. Students ranged from ages seven to seventy, and shared common experiences of slavery and poverty. Strongly affiliated with the United Church of Christ, the institution was dreamed to be  open to all, regardless of race, and that it would be measured by "the highest standards, not of Negro education, but of American education at its best." The educational institution was incorporated into Fisk University on August 22, 1867.  From its earliest days, it played a leadership role in the education of African Americans, producing such traditions as the Fisk Jubilee Singers.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>African American universities and colleges; Mural painting and decoration</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Colleges; Universities; Mural paintings</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Universities &amp; colleges; Murals</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>Fisk047</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/3253</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>