<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Pikeville Chapel AME Zion Church: historic photograph of students standing at church entrance</dc:title>
<dc:date>189?</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1890-1899</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Pikeville Chapel African Methodist Episcopal Zion Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>Lincoln Academy</dc:description>
<dc:description>Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>School</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>99001444    Listed November 1999</dc:identifier>
<dc:description>East Valley Road, Pikeville, Bledsoe Co., TN</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Pikeville, Bledsoe County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>35.605403,-85.185385</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Black and white photograph of adults and students outside of the church building. Approximately fifty individuals are pictured, the majority of them children. Several adults stand to the left.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Pikeville African Methodist Episcopal Church was built c. 1870 and is believed to be the oldest rural African American Church building in Tennessee. The church building also served as a school, known as Lincoln Academy, that served the Black population of the Pikeville area until the Lincoln School opened in 1925 with support of the Rosenwald Fund. The church is still in use.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>African American Churches -- Tennessee; African Methodist Episcopal Church</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Churches; Group portraits</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>4 x 6 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>SP_AMEZion_005.tif</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/28</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>