<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>United Sons and Daughters of Charity Lodge Hall: front view</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2005</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>United Sons and Daughters of Charity Lodge Hall</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>listed 2005/11/09</dc:identifier>
<dc:description>322 E. McNeal Street, Bolivar, Hardeman County, Tennessee</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Bolivar, Hardeman County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>35.254361,-88.985655</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of a one-story white wood panel building with red gable roof; front facade has two white doors. 

The Lodge Hall's architectural significance is as largely extant example of the type of 
vernacular design and craftsmanship that would be found in African American 
community buildings constructed in small southern towns during the era of Jim Crow 
segregation. The building's original paneled doors, its dual entrances, and its 
unadorned facade speak to the building's dual function as religious and secular space within the larger white-dominated built environment of Bolivar. The dual entrance of the 
facade reflects a strong vernacular found in rural and small-town church architecture 
from the nineteenth and early twentieth centuries, one that typically found women using 
one entrance and men using the other entrance. Thus the vernacular design conveyed 
to local residents the sacred use of the building. 
</dc:description>
<dc:description>The United Sons and Daughters of Charity was a local self-help and benevolent organization that assisted African Americans in the wake of the end of the Freedmen's Bureau and Reconstruction in Bolivar and Hardeman County. Established by a group of African American free men in 1873, it was one of several like groups to form  in Tennessee during the Reconstruction Era. In 1909, the organization expanded its level of community service by purchasing a lot and building a lodge hall on E. McNeal Street in Bolivar, in a part of town which emerged in the years of reconstruction and Jim Crow as the cultural heart of the local African American community.  The building burnt down in the 1920s and was rebuilt and simultaneously served as a church building for several congregations, and as a school.  From 1950-1970, the Lodge Hall's significance within the landscape became even more pronounced as it became the only remaining African American cultural institution on E. McNeal Street when the other churches relocated their sanctuaries and built new edifices on the west side of town.  Today it is the oldest African American building in Bolivar.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Historic buildings -- Tennessee</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Historic buildings; Lodges</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>35 mm slide</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator; Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>UnitedSonsDaughters004</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/1720</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>