<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Charleston United Methodist Cemetery: Woodmen of the World grave marker</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2002</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Charleston United Methodist Church and Cemetery</dc:description>
<dc:description>Church</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>02000811 listed 2002/07/17</dc:identifier>
<dc:description>Covington-Stanton Road, Charleston, TN</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Charleston, Tipton County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>35.495268,-89.509864</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of a stone grave marker carved to resemble the trunk of a tree. Near the top is the round seal of the Woodmen of the World. In the center is the name Byars, which can also be read on a simple slab behind the gravepost. Below the large carved name are two smaller plaques with the name P.N. Byars and birth and death dates.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Built in 1917, Charleston United Methodist Church was constructed to serve an expanding Methodist community in Tipton County and replace a previous church in poor condition. James McFerrin, an early circuit rider, established the church in Charleston in 1833. The 
first multi-denominational meetinghouse was probably a log cabin built at about the same time . The second church was built in 1849 and the third around 1876. The associated cemetery may predate the oldest religious building known for the site. It includes approximately 300 gravesites, with the earliest identifiable date of 1836.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Cemeteries -- Tennessee; Woodmen of the World</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Tombs &amp; sepulchral monuments; Cemeteries</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:format>35 mm slide</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>charlestonum005</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/1565</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>