<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Shiloh National Military Park: Indiana Cavalry monument and graves</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Staff at MTSU Center for Historic Preservation</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1984</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1980-1989</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Shiloh National Military Park</dc:description>
<dc:description>Shiloh National Cemetery</dc:description>
<dc:description>Park</dc:description>
<dc:description>Cemetery</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>66000074 listed October 15, 1966</dc:identifier>
<dc:description>1115 Hwy 22, Shiloh, TN 38376</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Shiloh, Hardin County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>35.142987, -88.338726</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Black and white photograph of monument and grave markers for the Indiana Cavalry, located at Shiloh National Battlefield.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The Battle of Shiloh occurred from April 6 to 7, 1862. The War Department established a cemetery on Shiloh Battlefield in 1866 to bury dead Civil War soldiers and those who perished from Tennessee River operations. Initially called Pittsburg Landing National Cemetery, the cemetery was renamed Shiloh National Cemetery in 1889. A total of 3,584 Civil War soldiers are buried within the confines of the cemetery. Granite stones denote the location of the dead and replaced the original wooden headboards. In Spring 1984, the Center for Historic Preservation surveyed the monuments at the battlefield. The purpose of this survey was to record the battlefield monuments, document their condition, and make recommendations to the National Park Service concerning the rehabilitation and/or preservation of the monuments.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Shiloh National Military Park (Tenn. and Miss.) ; Cemeteries ; Monuments</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Cemeteries ; Monuments</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Cemeteries ; Tombs &amp; sepulchral monuments</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>3.5 x 5 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>SP_ShilohNBP_486.tif</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/6107</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>