<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>LeFlore County, MS: church and city officials at Wesley Methodist</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2005</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>LeFlore County, MS</dc:description>
<dc:description>District</dc:description>
<dc:description>Church; Cemetery</dc:description>
<dc:description>Greenwood, LeFlore County, MS</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Greenwood, LeFlore County, MS</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>33.516232,-90.179528</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of church and city officials, two men and two women, inside Wesley Methodist church in Greenwood.</dc:description>
<dc:description>In 2005 and later in 2009, the Main Street program of Greenwood, Mississippi worked to identify possible landmarks associated with both the civil rights movement and with blues music. The Wesley United Methodist Church was the most important building since it was largely the headquarters for the local movement there for decades. The church built the city&#8217;s first gym for African American students and also maintained a community library for African Americans. Finally, the building in the Money community that once housed Bryant Grocery and Meat Market serves as a reminder of the gruesome murder of Emmett Till in 1955, an event that invigorated the civil rights movement.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>African American Churches -- Tennessee</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Churches</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>LeFloreCo001</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/3484</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>