<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Dyersburg MPS: National Register of Historic Places form</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Staff at MTSU Center for Historic Preservation</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1992-03-20</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1990-1999</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Dyersburg Multiple Property Survey</dc:description>
<dc:description>District</dc:description>
<dc:description>Dyersburg, TN 38024</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Dyersburg, Dyer County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>36.032373, -89.386266</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>National Register of Historic Places multiple property documentation form for Dyersburg, Tennessee.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Established on October 16, 1803, Dyer County, Tennessee was named in honor of Colonel Robert H. Dyer. On January 10, 1850, the town of Dyersburg was incorporated. The town's early growth stemmed from the town's proximity to the North Forked Deer River and the development of steamboat transportation. By 1884, the railroad had arrived in Dyersburg and further boosted the town's economic development. The presence of the new railroad link encouraged the establishment of additional industries and commercial services. Dyersburg Oil Company, a cottonseed oil plant, was established in 1884 and remained a major industry at the time of fieldwork. The architectural styles in Dyersburg reflect the sustained period of commercial, industrial, and population growth from 1880 to 1940. Partial architectural surveys of Dyersburg were conducted for the City of Dyersburg and the Dyersburg Chamber of Commerce in the spring of 1990 and 1991 by historic preservation graduate students under the direction of Dr. Carroll Van West of the MTSU Center for Historic Preservation.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>National Register of Historic Places</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Historic districts</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Forms (Documents)</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>18 p.; 8.5 x 11 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>SP_DyersburgMPS_001.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/5120</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>