<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Good Samaritan Hospital: north elevation</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Humphreys, Elizabeth Moore, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2012-08-21</dc:date>
<dc:description>Good Samaritan Hospital</dc:description>
<dc:description>Hospital </dc:description>
<dc:description>1107 Voeglin Avenue Selma, Alabama </dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Selma, Dallas County, AL</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>32.417154, -87.023232</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of the north elevation of the hospital, photographer facing southwest. The north end, as would be expected, shows the most wear and weather-related damage. The majority of this elevation is solid brick with a concrete belt dividing the first level from the upper three floors. There are (or were) four openings. A flat, possibly concrete panel covers the corner, and is partially protected by a flat-roof concrete awning that projects from the building with no supports. Some graffiti covers the panel, reading FLAG and I S99 U with a pair of eyes. To the right, another panel covers a long, narrow, horizontal open situated close to the concrete belt. A boarded up door sits to the immediate right of this former window, and it appears to have been a glass door with a transom and sidelights like the front door on the facade. Another covered opening sits directly above this door above the belt course. Three sets of pipes enter the building near the ground floor door, and a utility box sits at the northwest corner of the building. A tall brick chimney is visible above the roofline, where the seamed ridges of the metal roof are visible. Moss or other growths have taken hold near the street level and just above the concrete belt, along with other areas marking where the floors are on the rest of the building. A concrete sidewalk with a curb runs in front of the graffiti-covered section. The east elevation is partly visible, with the metal fence surrounding the parking area attached to the north end of the building. Sullivan&#8217;s Alley runs along the north elevation.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The extant modernist Good Samaritan Hospital in Selma, Alabama was built in 1964 by the Sisters of St. Joseph and the Edmundites (Fathers of St. Edmund), two Catholic missions. Originally built in 1922, Good Samaritan (or Good Sam, as it is known locally) was the second black hospital in the city, after the Burwell Infirmary. The hospital was originally run by the Alabama Baptist Convention under the administration of Mamie Norris, a nurse from the Tuskegee Institute. The Catholics purchased the hospital in 1944, built a new facility in 1947, which was replaced by the modern facility that could house 111 patients in 1964. Good Samaritan was the only hospital in the six surrounding counties open to African Americans. Sister Louis Bertrand established Alabama&#8217;s first School of Practical Nursing at Good Samaritan to deal with the critical nursing shortage. This was an important source of employment and training to black women (though a handful of black men also completed the program), who</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Civil rights -- United States; Clergy; Historic buildings; Women</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>hospital; catholic; nursing; nuns; black history; voting rights</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>IMG_0171</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/6335</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>