<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Waco Rosenwald School: close-up of exposed wall </dc:title>
<dc:description>Waco School</dc:description>
<dc:description>School</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Lynnville, Giles County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>35.3731323, -87.0355625</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of a two-building complex featuring two adjoining wooden structures. The red side gable roof building on the left appears to be an original Rosenwald school. It is characterized by two banks of five windows (now boarded up) and is sitting on pier blocks. The other building, which appears to join the north end of the original school building at a ninety degree angle, is a long low building featuring a red side gable shed roof over an open porch. In this photograph, two windows are visible.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The Waco Rosenwald School was built with support of the Julius Rosenwald Fund. According to the Tennessee Humanities Council&#8217;s History of Black Education in Giles County, the construction on the Waco School began in 1917 and it was completed in 1921. It was 720 square feet and valued at $3,050. The 1921-22 term began in July 1921 and ended four months later.  It resumed in February 1922 and closed in April. This was due to the irregular attendance caused by many of the children working during the fall harvest season. The cold winter months also affected attendance because the school lacked a stove for heat. The Council&#8217;s analysis of the teachers&#8217; registers reveals that the teachers worked to professionalize education and improve the level of instruction. The classes included writing, music, drawing, reading, U.S. History, arithmetic, civics, geography, spelling, language, grammar, and hygiene. 
</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Julius Rosenwald Fund -- Buildings; African American schools -- Tennessee</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:format>4 x 6 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission.</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/6149</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>