<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Durham's Chapel School: well and water pump</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2004</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Durham's Chapel Baptist Church, Cemetery, and School</dc:description>
<dc:description>School</dc:description>
<dc:description>Cemetery ; Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>5055 Old Highway 31 E, Bethpage, TN 37022</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Bethpage, Sumner County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>36.472333,-86.330093</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of well and water pump in a wooded area. The historic resource, dating to 1923, is located to the rear and east of the schoolhouse. The iron water pump consists of a manually operated pump, spigot, and piping that lead from the concrete trough and well.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Durham's Chapel Baptist Church, located in rural Sumner County, Tennessee, dates back to 1866. Throughout the years, the church building has been updated and remodeled at least twice. A cemetery, dating to 1870, accompanies the church. Durham's Chapel is perhaps best known for the Rosenwald school that still stands in the vicinity of the church. Durham's Chapel School was funded partially through the Julius Rosenwald Fund's School Building Program. The local black community raised $1,525, the Rosenwald Fund granted $700, and Sumner County supplemented the balance using public funds. The building, dating to 1923, was constructed according to the standardized plans for a two-teacher school with industrial room. Sitting on a limestone block foundation, the one-story building features weatherboard siding and a shingle cross-gable roof. The building serves as an example of a Rosenwald school with Craftsman-inspired decorative elements, including exposed rafter tails and wide-overhanging eaves. In addition to two classrooms, the school contained an industrial room used originally for home economics training. The industrial room currently functions as a kitchen and storage area. Historic resources associated with the school can also be found in the schoolyard. These resources, all dating to the 1923 construction date, include the Girls' Privy, the Boys' Privy, a well and water pump, and an original concrete sidewalk. According to the 2008 historic structure report, "the Durham's Chapel School documents the development and evolution of a rural African American enclave of settlement, education, and religion during the Jim Crow era (1890-1955) of segregation in Sumner County, Tennessee."</dc:description>
<dc:subject>African American schools -- Tennessee ; Julius Rosenwald Fund -- Buildings ; Feed-water pumps; Wells</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Wells ; Pumps</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Water pumps</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>4 x 6 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>SP_DurhamsChapelBaptist_033.tif</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/4373</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>