<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Cumberland Gap: two story house with gable roof front porch</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van</dc:creator>
<dc:date>c. 1989</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1980-1989</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Cumberland Gap Historic District</dc:description>
<dc:description>District</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>90000321 listed Feb. 23, 1990</dc:identifier>
<dc:description>Cumberland Gap, Claiborne County, TN</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Cumberland Gap, Claiborne County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>36.599527,-83.668525</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Black and white photograph of two story, raised foundation house with a gable roof and interior brick chimney. Single story gable roof front porch with 6 posts. L-shaped layout. Mobile home with carport in foreground.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The Cumberland Gap Historic District is significant for the patterns of Claiborne County's history as a a late nineteenth and early twentieth century mining town, fueled by English capitalists, and an example of late nineteenth town architecture in Claiborne County. For over two hundred years, Cumberland Gap has served as a significant passageway to the lands west of the Appalachian mountains.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Historic districts</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Houses; Porches</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:format>4 x 6 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>cumberlandgap011</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/1016</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>