<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Worship Among the Warioto</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Williams, Eleanor S.</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1995</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1990-1999</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Guildfield Missionary Baptist Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>Church</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>03000151 listed 2003/03/14</dc:identifier>
<dc:description>Guildfield Church Rd., South Guthrie, Montgomery County, Tennessee</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>South Guthrie, Montgomery County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>36.640216,-87.17154</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Williams provides a brief history of Guildfield Baptist Church.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The congregation that became Guildfield Missionary Baptist Church dates to meetings in 1868 held at the South Guthrie home of Isaac Saile.  It formerly organized in 1869 under the auspices of the Consolidated American Missionary Baptist Convention. Reverend C.W. Ware servas the the first pastor until 1882. The Guildfield name came from a suggestion by a deacon's wife, Mr.s William Saile.  There are no other Guildfield African American churches in Tennessee. A new frame building was built in the 1890s. The frame building served as meeting please until the present church was constructed in 1922. A small middle-class of black professionals developed in South Guthrie , but the black community was still small and in general poor.  The money raised for the new building is largely credited to the work of Rev. Paul D. Dennis, and Edward B. Warfield. Warfield was also responsible for the construction of a two-story Rosenwald school , also built in 1922.  It was nicknamed the "Warfield School". Rev. T.E. Winston, minister of the church 1934-1977, made many improvements on the building, including finishing the ground floor of the builidng and large open room for community gatherings, installation of modern restrooms and a kitchen, and the installation of new stained glass windows in the facade (1967). He also installed storm doors and central heat and air system in 1970. Rev. William Barker Kirby took the leadership in 1985 and remains its present minister.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>African American Churches -- Tennessee</dc:subject>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>History</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>4 pg, 11 x 8.5 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>GuildfieldMB027</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/2620</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>