<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Pearl High School: map and floor plan</dc:title>
<dc:description>Pearl High School</dc:description>
<dc:description>School</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>02000828 listed 2002/08/02</dc:identifier>
<dc:description>613 17th Ave. N, Nashville, Davidson County, TN</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Nashville, Davidson County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>36.161668,-86.800462</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Map of the school grounds and building floor plans.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Pearl School began in 1883 as a grammar school on present day Fifth Ave South. It remained in that area, known as "Black Bottom," until 1917 when the student population outgrew the building. Pearl High School was the second public African-American high school in Nashville. It became an educational center for the fine arts, music, and sports after some architecture additions in the late 1930s. Its first graduating class was in 1898.  Pearl High also was one of two major black schools in Nashville built with Public Works Administration funds during the New Deal of the 1930s. In late 2001, the school changed its name to Martin Luther King Magnet at Pearl High School.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>School buildings -- Tennessee; African American schools -- Tennessee; Pearl High School (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Schools</dc:subject>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Map</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>3 p., 8.5" x 13"</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>pearlhs00031</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/624</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>