<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Riverwood: Murphy bed</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Staff at MTSU Center for Historic Preservation</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1983</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1980-1989</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Riverwood Mansion</dc:description>
<dc:description>House</dc:description>
<dc:description>1833 Welcome Lane, Nashville, TN 37216</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Nashville, Davidson County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>36.200357, -86.710075</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Black and white photograph of a Murphy (fold-down, wall) bed in the parlor at Riverwood.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Located in northeastern Nashville, Tennessee, historic Riverwood Mansion dates back to the late 1790s when Alexander Porter purchased 2,500 acres on the north bank of the Cumberland River for a farm. A native of Ireland, Porter settled first in Philadelphia sometime before 1793. Eventually, Porter settled in Nashville and started a successful linen business. As early as 1799, construction began on a Porter family residence overlooking the Cumberland River. Tammany Wood, as the structure came to be known, was styled after Tamna Wood, the ancestral home in Ireland. The home remained in the Porter family until December 9, 1859 when William Frierson Cooper purchased the property for $87,933.40. Cooper, who eventually gained distinction as the Chief Justice of the Supreme Court of Tennessee, renamed the stately residence Riverwood. The Cooper family retained ownership of Riverwood until the 1970s. It then passed through the hands of several owners, including Dr. James M. High, over the next several years. At time of fieldwork in the spring of 1983, Dr. C. Michael Currie and his wife, Vickie L. Currie, owned the property. Since 1994, Joe and Jackie Glynn have owned Riverwood, currently a wedding venue in the Nashville area. Indicative of the Greek Revival style, Riverwood reflects three construction phases: a first phase from 1790 to 1820, a second phase in the 1820s, and a final phase from 1820 to 1850. Remodeling started in 1875 and continued throughout the early twentieth century to modernize the home. Legend holds that William Strickland, a discipline of Benjamin Henry Latrobe, served as architect; however, according to other sources, his son, Francis Strickland, is attributed with the house's design.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Historic buildings ; Beds</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Murphy beds</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Beds</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>4 x 6 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>SP_Riverwood_263.tif</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/5155</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>