<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>United Sons and Daughters of Charity Lodge Hall: front and side facades.</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2005?</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>United Sons and Daughters of Charity Lodge Hall</dc:description>
<dc:description>Community building</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>listed Nov. 11, 2009</dc:identifier>
<dc:description>322 E. McNeal Street, Bolivar, Hardeman County, Tennessee</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Bolivar, Hardeman County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>35.254361,-88.985655</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Black and white photograph of the lodge hall, showing a front with two entrance doors and a side wall that includes four large windows that are shuttered. The building sits on brick piers. It has a metal hipped roof. A brick chimney extends from the roof.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The United Sons and Daughters of Charity was a local self-help and benevolent organization that assisted African Americans in the wake of the end of the Freedmen's Bureau and Reconstruction in Bolivar and Hardeman County. Established by a group of African American free men in 1873, it was one of several like groups to form  in Tennessee during the Reconstruction Era. In 1909, the organization expanded its level of community service by purchasing a lot and building a lodge hall on E. McNeal Street in Bolivar, in a part of town which emerged in the years of reconstruction and Jim Crow as the cultural heart of the local African American community.  The building burned down in the 1920s.  and was rebuilt in 1928. It simultaneously served as a school and as a church building for several congregationsFrom 1950-1970, the Lodge Hall's significance within the landscape became even more pronounced as it became the only remaining African American cultural institution on E. McNeal Street when the other churches relocated their sanctuaries and built new edifices on the west side of town.  Today it is the oldest African American building in Bolivar.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Fraternal organizations; Historic buildings -- Tennessee</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>4 x 6 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/3639</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>