<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Woodlawn Baptist Church: correspondence about nomination to the National Register</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1996-01-30</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1990-1999</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Woodlawn Baptist Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>Church</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>96001358 listed Dec. 2, 1996</dc:identifier>
<dc:description>Woodlawn Rd. at TN Highway 19, Brownsville, TN 38012</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Nutbush, Haywood County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>35.658905,-89.364771</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Correspondence from Carroll Van West, National Register Coordinator to the Pastor of Woodlawn Baptist church with a copy of the draft nomination for the National and Tennessee Registers of Historic Places</dc:description>
<dc:description>Woodlawn Baptist Church's congregation dates back to at least the early 1850s. It began under the leadership of slave carpenter Harden Smith (1829-1929). The first sanctuary was built in June 1865. Harden was ordained in 1868, after which he held a revival that brought 400 members to the church. Construction began on the initial brick structure in 1870. By 1891, the growing congregation added 2.5 acres to the property. The new addition later served as the location for the present church building. A larger brick building was built 1927-28 across the rod from the cemetery. The ministry of J.A. Caldwell who served 1942-1954 marked a campaign to pay off debts and build a new Sunday School annex. Other ministers include R.W. McClendon (1961-1964), Virgil J. Caldwell (1964-1968), and William Kelly, Jr. (1969-1973).</dc:description>
<dc:subject>African American Churches -- Tennessee;</dc:subject>
<dc:language>Eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>4 p., 8.5 x 11 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>Woodlawn00003</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/379</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>