<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Montezuma CME: church</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2001-7-31</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Montezuma Colored Methodist Episcopal Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>2610 Old Montezuma RD, Henderson, TN 38340</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Henderson, Chester County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>35.399195,-88.692022</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of gable-front, concrete-block church. A vestibule with double doors and board siding provides an entrance to the church. Four windows adorn the side of the building. A cemetery sits behind the church and a driveway runs in front of the church.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Montezuma Colored Methodist Episcopal Church is a small church located in Chester County, Tennessee. The church's concrete-block building dates to 1951 and is characteristic of rural, African American churches in the mid-twentieth century South. According to the cornerstone, P.B. Peague Masonic Lodge No. 4 played an active role in the church's early history. A cemetery, located behind the church, serves as the burial area for Montezuma CME. At the time of fieldwork, Reverend Jeremiah Hill was the church's pastor.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>African American Churches -- Tennessee</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Churches ; Gable roofs ; Vestibules ; Concrete</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Churches</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>4 x 6 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>SP_MontezumaCMEChurch_001.tif</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/4258</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>