<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Trenton Rosenwald School: site of old football field</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2014</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2010-2019</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Trenton Rosenwald School</dc:description>
<dc:description>School</dc:description>
<dc:description>421 East 2nd Street, Trenton, TN 38382</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Trenton, Gibson County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>35.978995, -88.935485</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of the site of the old football field at Trenton Rosenwald School. The space was occupied by a basketball court at the time of fieldwork.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Constructed in 1928, the Trenton Rosenwald School (TRS) was originally a one-story, seven-classroom school funded partially through the Rosenwald Fund. The local African American community contributed $1,500, the Rosenwald fund contributed $2,100, and the remaining $11,000 came from public sources. For over two decades TRS functioned as part of the segregated public education system that was separate but not equal. TRS offered grades 1st through 8th and served as a feeder school to the only Gibson County high school for blacks located twelve miles away in Milan. Students could pay $1.00 to $2.00 a month for bus transportation to attend high school. In early 1953, TRS was destroyed by fire. Local newspapers indicate that the officials quickly approved funding for a new seven-classroom building. Immediately following the completion of the new school, it is likely that the Gibson County School System added more classrooms, laboratories and other amenities to TRS in order to match the facilities available at the local white schools. The last graduating class of seniors was 1968. After this year, grades 9th through 12th were transferred to Trenton&#8217;s white school, Peabody High School. It is probable that the elementary grades were also transferred, because TRS once again became a middle school, however this time both white and black students attended. The local school board changed the name from Trenton Rosenwald School to Trenton Middle School.  The name change was fiercely opposed by the African American community. In 1996, Trenton Rosenwald Middle School was moved to a new building located at 2065 Highway 25 Bypass. The Rosenwald name was kept and the current school&#8217;s pedigree links back to the original 1928 Rosenwald School. Trenton Rosenwald Middle School currently serves approximately 430 students in grades 5th through 8th. Since the new school opened, the old facility on East Second Street has been largely vacant with the exception of a Head Start daycare and some local business rental. Owned by Trenton Special School District, TRS is now known as the Trenton Community Resource Center.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Julius Rosenwald Fund -- Buildings; Basketball courts</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Courts</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:format>Computer disk</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>TRS site of old football field.JPG</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/5883</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>