<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>New Rising Star Baptist Church: history and property description</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van</dc:creator>
<dc:contributor>Nelson, Linda; White, Marjorie</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>2005?</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>New Rising Star Baptist Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>Church</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>05000305 listed April 19, 2005</dc:identifier>
<dc:description>3104 33rd Place N, Collegeville, Birmingham County, AL</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Birmingham, Jefferson County, AL</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>33.554389,-86.799741</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>A history and property description of New Rising Star Baptist Church that was developed as part of its nomination to the National Register of Historic Places</dc:description>
<dc:description>New Rising Star Baptist Church is a small church in the working-class neighborhood of Collegeville in Birmingham. It was established by Rev. George E. Pruitt, who oversaw construction of the church building in 1958 and served as pastor until 1986. The church is significant for its association with African American ethnic identity in the Collegeville neighborhood of Birmingham, and its relationship with Alabama Christian Movement for Human Rights (ACMHR). Rev. Pruitt was one of the founders and an executive committee member of ACMHR, and his church hosted strategy meetings for the organization.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>African American Churches -- Tennessee; Alabama Christian Movement for Human Rights; Civil rights -- United States</dc:subject>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>History</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>3 pg, 8.5 x 11 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>NewRising001</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/3452</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>