<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Pruitt Hill United Methodist Church and Cemetery</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:contributor>Bowers, Norma, church historian</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>2001</dc:date>
<dc:description>Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>Cemetery</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Greeneville, Greene County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>One story concrete block front gable structure, painted white, with square white wooden steeple and metal roof. Projecting gable front entrance bay, with slightly lower roof line, opens onto raised platform with black metal railing. A ramp leads up from the left to centered double wood panel doors, also painted white, and steps descend from the platform on the right side. Setting is rural, tree-lined lot.  </dc:description>
<dc:description>According to the church history, Pruitt Hill School (no longer extant, closed due to integration) was located nearby. A historic cemetery, with approximately fifty graves, is located on the same property, the oldest inscription visible on a grave marker is 1917.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>African American cemeteries; African American Churches -- Tennessee; Sepulchral monuments; Church buildings -- Tennessee</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission.</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/6306</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>