<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>King Chapel at Union Ridge COGIC: front and side view</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:coverage>1990-1999;</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>King Chapel at Union Ridge Church of God in Christ</dc:description>
<dc:description>Church;</dc:description>
<dc:description>510 Union Ridge RD, Wartrace, TN 37183</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Wartrace, Bedford County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>35.514867,-86.262054</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of church front and side view. Church vestibule and main building are gable-roofed. Vinyl siding covers the building. Entrance steps contain two handrails. Rock foundation of vestibule varies from that of the main building. Double glass doors provide entrance to the vestibule. Light fixtures flank the entranceway and a cross appears above the doors. Three windows are located on the side of the main building. The back portion of the main building contains a four-over-four sash window and a side door. Another section of the building runs perpendicular to the back of the main building. Parking lot is located to the side and front of the church.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The current Kings Chapel building dates from the 1960s. Vinyl siding was added to the frame and additional work was completed in the 1980s. At the time of fieldwork (July 23, 1998), W. L. Rippy served as pastor and the church was thought to have once been the largest in the village.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>African American Churches -- Tennessee;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>vestibules; sash windows; steps;</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image;</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000;</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph;</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper;</dc:format>
<dc:format>4 x 6 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission;</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only;</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>SP_KingsChapel_002.tif</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/3849</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>