<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Blythe Ferry: Trail of Tears historic marker</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2006</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Blythe Ferry</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>07001046 listed October 3, 2007</dc:identifier>
<dc:description>Shadden Rd. at Tennessee River, Birchwood, Meigs County, TN</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Birchwood, Meigs County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>35.4094,  -85.00856666</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of the historic marker at Blythe Ferry. Text reads: "One of the worst acts of &#8220;man&#8217;s inhumanity to man&#8221; took place when an entire race of peoples were driven from their lands in 1838. It was here at Blythe Ferry that approx. 9000 Cherokees and Creeks camped while waiting to cross the Tennessee River on their forced removal. They had been held captive in stockades a few miles back. Many books have been written on the heart-wrenching description of what is now called &#8220;The Trail of Tears&#8221;. Butrick&#8217;s journal describes their condition in the camps as &#8220;very much like brute animals &#8211; lieing down on the naked ground exposed to wind and rain &#8211; like droves of hogs. Butrick also states &#8220;But not only the Cherokees &#8211; the dear Creeks and Seminoles have fallen by the same means &#8211; fictitious treaties:. He speaks of &#8220;Nanny as a slave&#8221; so this shows the diversity among the detachments. A mental picture of what happened here at Blythe Ferry can be drawn from these excerpts.  Oct. 16th 1838 &#8211; 10 O&#8217;Clock AM &#8220;we have only succeeded in getting some twenty wagons across the river &#8211; proprietors of the Ferry are determined to retard all exertions&#8221; J. Powell. The last detachment crossed Nov. 12th, 1838. &#8220;I reached Blythe&#8217;s Ferry on Saturday Nov. 10 &#8211; found the great body of Mr. (Peter) Hildebrand&#8217;s detachment of emigrating Cherokees quietly encamped &#8211; about twelve wagons had crossed &#8211; at dawn four boats were put in requisition and continued &#8211; until dusk &#8211; close of the day about sixty one wagons &#8211; across &#8211; this morning before 12 O&#8217;Clock  eighteen wagons and all the people were over&#8221; to Winfield Scott. This park is dedicated in memory to these peoples. May it serve as a touchstone for future generations."</dc:description>
<dc:description>Blythe Ferry, one of Tennessee's most important Trail of Tears landmarks, is located on the Tennessee River between Meigs and Rhea Counties. William Blythe, a mixed-ancestry Native American, began operating the ferry on the Federal Road in 1809. Following Blythe&#8217;s death in 1856, the ferry passed through several hands  before being replaced by a bridge in 1994. The historical ferry landings now lie under the waters of the Chickamauga impoundment. The Cherokee Removal Memorial Park has been constructed at the site.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Ferries; Cherokee Indians -- 1830-1840; Trail of Tears, 1838-1839</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Historical markers; Rivers</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>BlytheFerry002</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/2791</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>