<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>McKenzie Depot: history and property description</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van</dc:creator>
<dc:contributor>Dobbs, Megan</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>c. 1995</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1990-1999</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>McKenzie Depot</dc:description>
<dc:description>Railroad station</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>96000336 listed 1996/03/28</dc:identifier>
<dc:description>85 E. Bruce St., McKenzie, Carroll Co., TN</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>McKenzie, Carroll County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>36.130866,-88.519061</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>A history and description of the McKenzie Depot, its historical significance, and property description. Document is titled "Nashville, Chattanooga, and St. Louis Railway Passenger Station, Carroll Co., TN" and is an excerpt from a longer document.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The McKenzie Depot is a passenger station of the Nashville, Chattanooga, and St. Louis Railway (NC&amp;St.L). It is an example of the "combination depot," combining two passenger waiting rooms, freight area, and ticket office within one building.  The town of McKenzie,  organized and platted in 1865, formed because of the intersection between two railroad lines. These lines  were the NC&amp;St.L and the Louisville and Nashville Railway.  The McKenzie Depot dates to 1926, and the last passenger train stopped in McKenzie in 1970.  After the demolition of a NC&amp;St.L depot in Milan in 1993, the McKenzie Depot became the only extant Renaissance Revival styled passenger station in West Tennessee.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Railroad stations -- Tennessee</dc:subject>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>History</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>9 pg, 8.5 x 11 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>mckenziedepot00002</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/650</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>