<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Neblett Place Farm: portrait</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1994</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1990-1999;</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Neblett Place Farm;</dc:description>
<dc:description>Farm;</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>95000267 listed March 30, 1995</dc:identifier>
<dc:coverage>Charlotte, Dickson County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>36.192609,-87.31883</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Black and white photograph of a lady's portrait on the interior wall next to a staircase.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Neblett Place Farm is a Tennessee Century Farm in Dickson County, Tennessee. James R. Neblett and Martha Grimes Neblett established the farm on November 13, 1893, when they acquired an earlier established farm of 111 acres, complete with a dwelling and log outbuildings which dated to the early nineteenth century. John B. Neblett, the son of James, continued the farm's expansion. The farm produced traditional mixed agricultural products such as horses, cows, chickens, corn, hay, and potatoes. James R. Neblett was a civil engineer. During his absences on various railroad and road assignments, Martha operated the farm with her sons Herschel W. and John B. and two resident tenant families. Marthan also bartered butter and eggs, and collected black walnuts from local timber areas. Son John B. and wife Augusta assumed ownership of the farm in 1935, which had expanded to 198 acres. During the late 1930s, the landscape was modernized by terracing fields to guard against erosion, building a pond for livestock, and constructing natural wind breaks. By 1940, the farm had been designated as an experimental farm by the Agricultural Extension Service. John B. died in 1951, but Augusta continued to manage and operate the property. As late as 1994, she and daughter Rhoba Neblett-Harvey continued to live in the family dwelling.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Houses and homes; Historic buildings;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>portraits; interior walls;</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image;</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000;</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph;</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper;</dc:format>
<dc:format>3.5 x 5 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission;</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only;</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>Neblett032.tif</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/3557</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>