<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>St. Paul Chapel Missionary Baptist Church: grave marker 3</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2005-12-13</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>St. Paul Chapel Missionary Baptist Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>Cemetery</dc:description>
<dc:description>St. Paul Chapel Missionary Baptist Church, near Richardson's Landing, Dummonds Road, St. Paul, Tipton Co., TN</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>St. Paul, Tipton County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>35.49381,-89.94134</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of two grave markers; one marker is surrounded by an elaborate black wrought-iron fence reading "RCJ Sr.", has a stone flower holder and floral design and reads "Ronald Curtis Jones Sr.; Feb 20 1962 - Nov. 12 1992; Beloved Husband, Father, Brother &amp; Son"; second marker reads "Morgan McDaniel Dec 28 1927 - Jun 18 1994" and has prayer hands as a design</dc:description>
<dc:description>St. Paul Chapel Missionary Baptist Church is an early Reconstruction era black settlement along the Mississippi River.  The late 20th century property has an adjacent Rosenwald School building  and a historic cemetery that contains at least one grave of a U.S. Colored Troops veteran. The cemetery also contains examples of folk art grave markers.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>African American Churches -- Tennessee; Cemeteries -- Tennessee</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Tombs &amp; sepulchral monuments</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:format>Electronic</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>MS River Corridor Day 3 023</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/467</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>