<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Blythe Ferry: Trail of Tears map at Cherokee Removal Memorial Park</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2006</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Blythe Ferry</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>07001046 listed October 3, 2007</dc:identifier>
<dc:description>Shadden Rd. at Tennessee River, Birchwood, Meigs County, TN</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Birchwood, Meigs County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>35.4094,  -85.00856666</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of a map on the ground at the Cherokee Removal Memorial Park and visitor center that is located at the site of Blythe Ferry on the eastern shore of the Tennessee River.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Blythe Ferry, one of Tennessee's most important Trail of Tears landmarks, is located on the Tennessee River between Meigs and Rhea Counties. William Blythe, a mixed-ancestry Native American, began operating the ferry on the Federal Road in 1809. Following Blythe&#8217;s death in 1856, the ferry passed through several hands  before being replaced by a bridge in 1994. The historical ferry landings now lie under the waters of the Chickamauga impoundment. The Cherokee Removal Memorial Park has been constructed at the site.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Cherokee Indians -- Relocation; Cherokee Indians -- 1830-1840;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Ferries; Historic sites; Trading posts; Transportation; Commerce</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>BlytheFerry005</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/2802</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>