<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Frierson-Voorhies Cemetery: Unmarked headstone</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Eatherly, Brad, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2015</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2010-2019</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Frierson-Voorhies Cemetery</dc:description>
<dc:description>Cemetery</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Brentwood, Williamson County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>36.034132, -86.782309</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of a small unmarked headstone.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The Frierson-Voorhies Cemetery is located in a section of Brentwood, Tennessee that was once known as the Hardscuffle Community.  The African-American community of Hardscuffle extended along what is now Church Street East from Wilson Pike to Edmondson Road.  Hardscuffle was formed a couple of years after the Civil War ended when freed slaves began purchasing property along what was then known as Hardscuffle Road.  About fifty African-American families ultimately lived in the community.  The community also supported three churches, two schools, and a baseball field.  The property where the cemetery is located used to be owned by Hardscuffle community members Wilbur and Katherine Hayes.  The community's property owners were offered about $150,000 in the 1960s when Interstate 65 was being constructed.  Mt. Lebanon Missionary Baptist Church and Brooks Memorial Methodist Church were two of the churches that served Hardscuffle.  </dc:description>
<dc:subject>African American cemeteries; Cemeteries; Sepulchral monuments</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Tombs &amp; sepulchral monuments</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/6162</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>