<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Clement Museum: pressed metal ceiling</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Staff at MTSU Center for Historic Preservation</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1988-10</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1980-1989</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Frank G. Clement Birthplace</dc:description>
<dc:description>Clement Railroad Hotel Museum</dc:description>
<dc:description>Museum</dc:description>
<dc:description>100 Frank Clement Place, Dickson, TN 37055</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Dickson, Dickson County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>36.075333, -87.389002</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of the pressed metal ceiling in the Hotel Halbrook's main lobby area.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Frank Goad Clement was born on June 2, 1920 in the Halbrook Hotel in the railroad town of Dickson, Tennessee. His parents, Robert and Maybelle Goad Clement, resided at the hotel, just off the railroad tracks, operated by Clement's maternal grandmother, Belle S. Goad. Robert and Maybelle Clement eventually took over the daily operation of the hotel. Frank Clement went on to earn recognition as the governor of Tennessee from 1953 to 1959 and then again from 1963 to 1967. The historical significance of the Frank G. Clement Birthplace, however, concerns more than the exceptional significance of Frank Clement to Tennessee history. It also involves the local significance of the building in which Clement was born. Built in 1912 by Dickson businessman J. T. Halbrook, the Halbrook Hotel is one of the few remaining examples of a 'railroad hotel' in small town Middle Tennessee. The building was used commercially until 1972 when the Clement family purchased the building to be used as a memorial to the former governor. At the time of fieldwork in 1988, the hotel was operated by the Frank G. Clement Memorial Foundation and served as a depository for Clement's personal papers and memorabilia associated with his political career. On June 2, 2009, the Clement Railroad Hotel Museum opened in the space to interpret railroading, the Clement family, and local history. Listed on the National Register of Historic Places, the site is now state-owned.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Museums ; Hotels ; Ceilings</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Hotels ; Museums ; Ceilings</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Hotels ; Galleries &amp; museums ; Ceilings</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:format>Slide</dc:format>
<dc:format>35 mm</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>SP_ClementMuseumPlan_048.tif</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/5781</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>