<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Maple Dean farm: correspondence concerning sale of the farm</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Crigler, Marjorie H.</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1994</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1990-1999</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Maple Dean Farm</dc:description>
<dc:description>Farm</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>95000269 listed 1995-03-30</dc:identifier>
<dc:description>400 New Herman Road, Shelbyville, Bedford County, TN</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Shelbyville, Bedford County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>35.370468,-86.423875</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Correspondence from Marjorie H. Crigler to Dr. Carroll Van West discussing an impending auction and the sale of the farm itself</dc:description>
<dc:description>Maple Dean Farm was established in 1819 by Thomas Dean. It began agricultural operations within the first generations of settlement in Bedford Co., established 1807. Thomas Dean was a prominent Democrat in Tennessee politics during the Second Party System.  By the time of his death in 1881, he owned 209 acres. His son Peyton Dean inherited the farm and later gave it to sister Elizabeth  Dean upon her marriage to teacher Walter Crigler  in 1885. The new Victorian farmhouse was constructed in 1886. It passed to Elizabeth's son John Peyton Crigler in 1911. John Peyton spent nearly a decade turning it into a model progressive operation, including the installation of electricity via a generator. In 1948, the farm was acquired by Mr. and Mrs. Jacob Crigler. And in 1976, Maple Dean Farm was certified as a Tennessee Century Farm by the Tennessee Department of Agriculture.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Century Farms; Historic farms -- Tennessee</dc:subject>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Correspondence</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>2 p., 6" x 8"</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>mapledeanf00005</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/768</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>