<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Columbia Union Station Depot:  Front (north) facade view</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Eatherly, Brad, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2015</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2010-2019</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Columbia Union Station Depot</dc:description>
<dc:description>Railroad station</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>86002908 listed October 23, 1986</dc:identifier>
<dc:coverage>Columbia, Maury County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>35.608080, -87.037371</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of a train station viewed from the north.  The foundation is a brick and stone material.  The front facade is asymmetrical  with two double-leaf entries with wood-and-glass doors.  Above the two sets of doors are semi-circular hood molds with three-light transoms and traceried muntins.  Geometrical bas-relief decorations dominate the entryways.  Two one-over-one double-hung sash windows are located to the east of the doorways and three one-over-one double-hung windows are located to the west of the doorways.  Corbeling surround each set of windows.   The second floor is separated by a raised stone cornice.  Eight one-over-one double-hung sash windows are located on the second story.  Eight small rectangular fixed single light attic windows cap the second story windows.  A tin cornice with dentils tops the entire facade.  A hipped corrugated tin roof sits atop the structure.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The Columbia Union Station train depot was built from 1902-1905 by the Nashville, Chattanooga, and St. Louis Railway and the Louisville and Nashville Railroad.  It operated as a passenger service depot until 1954 when airline travel became more popular and as a freight depot until 1961, at which time it became unused as a station.  It was used as cheap apartments in the 1970s and 1980s until it fell into disrepair.  It was restored in the early 2010s.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Railroad stations</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Railroad stations</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/6115</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>