<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Shakertown at Pleasant Hill:  open room</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2000-2009?</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Shakertown at Pleasant Hill</dc:description>
<dc:description>District</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>71000353 listed Nov. 11, 1971</dc:identifier>
<dc:description>3501 Lexington Rd, Harrodsburg, Mercer County, KY</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Shakertown, Mercer County, KY;</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>37.81618,-84.740266</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of a large open room with an arched ceiling and two entry doors. The room is white with deep blue wainscotting and trim. A broom and chair hang from pegs along the far wall.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Pleasant Hill was a founded in 1805 as a community of the Society of Shakers. Many of the buildings that now comprise the historic district were planned and designed c. 1815 by Micajah Burnett and built by community members over the following decades. The community continued to grow until 1860 and then declined, which resulted in the communally-held Society properties gradually passing into private ownership. Beginning in the early 1960s a preservation effort was begun. By the time of the 1971 National Register listing, Shakertown at Pleasant Hill held 2200 acres of the previous lands and had restored many of the surviving buildings. The properties are open to the public.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Pleasant Hill (Ky.); Shakers -- Buildings.;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Historic sites; Religious dwellings</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>PleasantHill011</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/2756</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>