<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Alexandria Cemeteries Historic District: Baird tombstone base</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2002?</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Alexandria Cemeteries Historic District</dc:description>
<dc:description>Cemetery</dc:description>
<dc:description>Church; District</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>02000584 listed May 30, 2002</dc:identifier>
<dc:description>Cemetery St., Alexandria, Dekalb County, TN</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Alexandria, Dekalb County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>36.077559,-86.033322</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Black and white photograph of Baird tombstone base, which includes two quotes. Location is the East View cemetery.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The Alexandria Cemeteries Historic District is located at the end of Cemetery Street in Alexandria, TN. The district includes the Seay Chapel African-American United Methodist Church, the East View (White) cemetery and the African-American cemetery. Of these, the East View Cemetery is oldest, dating to 1836 or earlier. It contains the remains of both Federal and Confederate veterans of the Civil War.  Seay Chapel was established in 1869 on land deeded by the city of Alexandria for construction of an African-American church, school and cemetery. The original Seay Chapel building was replaced in 1931 with a new building that features rock-faced masonry. W.E.B. Dubois attended the church while serving as a teacher at the nearby Wheeler School during his undergraduate years at Fisk University. His experience there was described in his book, Souls of Black Folk.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>African American cemeteries -- Tennessee;  Sepulchral monuments -- Tennessee</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Cemeteries; Tombstones</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Cemeteries; Tombs &amp; sepulchral monuments</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>5 x 7 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>Alexandria011</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/2975</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>