<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Cleburne Jersey Farm: Davis Swing Churn</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2000</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Cleburne Jersey Farm</dc:description>
<dc:description>Farm</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>00001430 listed Nov. 22, 2000</dc:identifier>
<dc:description>2319 Sugar Ridge Rd, Spring Hill,  TN</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Spring Hill, Maury County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>35.776253,-86.93863</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of a large oval wood container with the words "Davis Swing Churn; No. 7; Vermont Farm Machinery, Bellows Factory". Metal buckets are resting on top and small  metal tanks are visible in the background.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The Cleburne Jersey Farm dates to the 1870s.  Its dairy industry dates to 1878, when Mack Capbell began the state's first Jersey herd, though the farm contributed to the Tennessee agrarian culture before that. In the 1880s, the property began to be called the Cleburne Jersey Farm, and in 1885 the dairy herd was significantly expanded.  In 1892, the farm expanded into general stock breeding, especially horses.  Mack's partner McCoy Clemson Campbell died in 1906 at which point McCoy's sons Allen and George  managed the farm.  George died in 1948 and his sons George Jr. and John McCoy Campbell took over the management of the  farm. The  electrification of the farm and the dwelling that same year. In 1964, the Tenness Jersey Cattle Club formally declared the Jersy heerd at Cleburne Jersey Farm to be the oldest Jersey herd in the United States.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Dairy farms; Historic farms -- Tennessee</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Agricultural machinery &amp; implements</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>4 x 6 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>CleburneFarm008</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/1573</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>