<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Green Street Baptist Church: partial north elevation</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Humphreys, Elizabeth Moore, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2013-08-08</dc:date>
<dc:description>Green Street Baptist Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>1220 Green Street Selma, AL 36701</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Selma, Dallas County, AL</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>32.416946, -87.019854</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of a partial view of the north elevation (along Griffin Avenue), photographer facing southeast. A telephone pole and wires are situated in the foreground, with the pole on the left side of the image. A portion of an octagonal white cupola with louvered, arched windows on each side and a domed roof is visible above the asphalt shingle roof. A portion of the northwest tower is visible on the right side of the image. This elevation includes a symmetrical gable-end section that projects slightly from the main body of the church, and the northeastern corner includes a small tower. A 1962 addition is visible at the east of the small tower. A circular drainpipe sits in the corner where the gable end projection meets the wall of the building. The north-facing gable has a sharply-pitched cement roofline, with a small brick and cement pediment. The roofline ends in short horizontal sections supported by brick corbels extending from a split pilaster on the west end. The north gable end features the same brick corbels/split pilasters as the fa&#231;ade. The corbels below the apex of the gable end include three vertical setback sections, and below it is a small narrow section of corbels like the ones on the northwest bell tower. A triple-arched louvered window sits below the apex, with no keystone or imposts, divided by brick with a shared cement sill. The window pattern below follows the same pattern as the fa&#231;ade, only symmetrical; a set of four arched, stained glass windows in the center with vertical rectangular ones below, and a single arched stained glass window with a rectangular one below on either side past the split pilasters. These windows all have cement keystones and imposts. In the white foundation at the base of the gable end, small openings are visible to allow the foundation to breathe. The tower at the northeast corner follows the same basic pattern as the other two towers. Its roof is identical to the southwest tower, and it has the same pattern of corbels and split pilasters with two rows of arched stained glass windows on the bottom half. This tower, however, is brick all the way to the base, and includes a pair of arched louvered windows like those below the apex of the north gable end. A white cornerstone is visible on the lower section of the northeast corner of the tower. The 1962 education wing is just visible, with a three-bay symmetrical fa&#231;ade and low-pitched or flat roof. The bays are divided by solid brick pilasters. The central bay includes a four-pane window on the top section, with the horizontal muntin set low. Below the window is a painted sign reading GREEN STREET BAPTIST EDUCATION WING. Below the sign is an asphalt roof slightly pyramid-shaped awning with wood brackets over a white painted double door. The left bay includes a four-pane window at top and bottom, identical to the one in the central bay. The right bay includes a matching window on the top story with a five-by-two fixed vertical window below it. All of the windows have cement sills. A sidewalk runs along the north elevation, extending all the way to the street in front of the northwest bell tower, but with a grass median on the east sections.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The congregation of Green Street Baptist Church formed in 1881, primarily from the congregation of First Baptist Church (Colored), which was then known as the St. Phillip Street Baptist Church (due to their location). The church was led by Reverend John Blevins, who had been pastor at St. Phillip Street, thus the church was originally known as &#8220;The John Blevins Church.&#8221; He remained there for two or three years. On December 31, 1881, church trustees Jefferson Richardson, Joseph Baylock, Adam Clayton, and Henry Lamar purchased a lot on the corner of Green Street and McCreary Avenue (now Griffin Avenue) for $150. The first worship services were held in a store on the corner.  The first church the congregation built was a small frame building on a lot adjacent to wear the brick church now stands. The frame church was small and uncomfortable, unable to accommodate the congregation of 200 souls (with 300 attending Sunday School). The interior of the original structure was lit by three lanterns hanging from the ceiling and a tin lamp on each side wall. The minister had a small platform to stand on, and the children sat on the edge. The original frame building was replaced once by a larger frame church, and again by a brick church, which was dedicated in 1892. The current building was dedicated in 1922. The plan for the building came to Pastor James A. Martin in a dream, and it was designed and built by contractor A.J. Farley, which accounts for the church&#8217;s unusual architectural features. Between 1937 and 1946, the church building was renovated and restrooms added. Between 1946 and 1958, the church was renovated again, including the purchase of new pews and floor coverings, and a paved sidewalk was added around the church. In 1946, the church opened a kindergarten, which operated for 14 years. In 1962, the church added an education wing. The late 1980s saw another interior renovation, accompanied by a new roof and renovated restrooms. In the late 1990s, a truss in the church&#8217;s roof failed, which has led to significant damage to the structure, including the bowing of the sanctuary wall on Griffin Avenue, the holes in the roof, and extensive interior damage from exposure to the elements. The remaining congregation currently worships in the education wing.  Green Street&#8217;s current state belies its historical significance. During the 1960s, the church enjoyed a thriving congregation, and its kitchen was used to prepare meals for marchers in the Selma to Montgomery March in 1965. The considerable space in both the education wing and the main sanctuary were also used to provide temporary housing for civil rights workers. On June 5, 1964, the church hosted a mass meeting featuring Ralph Abernathy of the Southern Christian Leadership Conference. Following the meeting, someone threw a rock at some of the deputized possemen who had surrounded the church during the meeting. The possemen responded by attacking the crowd as it tried to exit the church, using night sticks and tear gas. The riot continued in the neighborhood, injuring many of the black residents and putting some in the hospital. Homes up to a block and a half away from the church were damaged, with broken windows and porch lights. Two white journalists were targeted and their cameras destroyed by possemen.  </dc:description>
<dc:subject>African American Churches -- Tennessee; Baptist church buildings; Bell towers; Brick churches; Church buildings; Church buildings -- Alabama; Churches; Civil rights -- United States; Stained glass windows</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>IMG_0176</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/6318</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>