<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Lannie's Bar-B-Q Spot: sign</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Humphreys, Elizabeth Moore (photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2012-08-21</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2010-2019</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Lannie's Bar-B-Q Spot</dc:description>
<dc:description>Commercial building; Restaurant </dc:description>
<dc:description>2115 Minter Ave Selma, AL 36703</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Selma, Dallas County, AL</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>32.418991, -87.010358</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of the sign for Lannie&#8217;s Bar-B-Q Spot. The sign hangs from a metal rod that extends from the creosote-treated pole that the power and telephone lines are mounted to. The sign itself is metal frame with a white plastic face. It hangs from the pole with a looped metal chain on one end and a flat metal hood with a screw on the end nearest the creosote pole. The top of the sign includes the Pepsi logo with PEPSI beside it in blue. The lower portion reads LANNIE&#8217;S BAR-B-Q SPOT on the left in blue and has a cartoon pig with a chef&#8217;s hat serving a ham in red on the right. Based on the Pepsi logo design, this sign dates to the mid-1990s.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Lannie&#8217;s Bar-B-Q Spot has been in business since the 1940s. Named after the original owner, Lannie Travis, and has remained in the (now Hatcher) family. Located in East Selma, it served both black and white patrons throughout its tenure, including during the civil rights activities of the 1960s, when it was neutral ground. Lannie Travis provided sandwiches for the Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (SNCC) workers. The current building is from about 1950, but the restaurant has operated on the site since it first opened. </dc:description>
<dc:description>PEPSI
LANNIE&#8217;S
BAR-B-Q
SPOT
</dc:description>
<dc:subject>African American business enterprises; Civil rights -- United States; Signs and signboards</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>barbecue</dc:subject>
<dc:language>Eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>IMG_0247</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/6296</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>