<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Northern Heights Presbyterian Church: sanctuary facing altar</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Gautreau, Abigail R., photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2012-09-20</dc:date>
<dc:description>Northern Heights Presbyterian Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>Northside Baptist Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>1575 Marie Foster Street Selma, Alabama 36703</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Selma, Dallas County, AL</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>32.421009, -87.014312</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of the interior of the sanctuary at Northern Heights Presbyterian Church. Photographer is in the mezzanine looking down, facing west. Ten rows lacquered pine, light wood pews are visible leading to the altar, divided by a center aisle. The floor is covered in a grey composite work carpet. The walls are painted cream with pine paneled wainscoting. A stained glass window is visible on either side of the church. Moving toward the altar, each wall includes three single-leaf white doors. The west end of the church is dominated by the elevated chancel. The chancel projects from the west wall in a broad rectangle with the front corners clipped. Two single-leaf doors provide access to the space behind the west wall, one on either side of the chancel. The chancel is carpeted on top (matching the carpet on the floor of the sanctuary) with pine panel skirting. The north side of the chancel includes a paneled half wall demarcating the area where the pianist sits. The southeast corner of the chancel includes a step up to the chancel set at an angle in the clipped corner. The pulpit is centered at the front of the chancel, and a communion table sits below it on the main floor of the church. A green linen runner covers the table, which features a flower arrangement at the center flanked by two tall candles in brass candlesticks. A set of chairs for the choir sit directly behind the pulpit, with another row on a more elevated section behind a paneled half-wall. The higher section features an organ facing the west wall with three chairs for choir members on either side. Two dark wood flower pedestals with flower arrangements are situated on either end of the chancel on the main floor. A rostrum sits on the main floor southeast of the chancel. A c1980 mansard drop ceiling obscures a low-pitch vaulted ceiling. The building is illuminated by fluorescent lighting panels set into the drop ceiling, and a brass chandelier hangs over the chancel. A set of three track lights on either side of the church are directed at the pulpit. </dc:description>
<dc:description>The congregation of Northern Heights Presbyterian Church formed in 1900 at the Sylvan Street Presbyterian Church under the Reverend Lucius Deyampert. Deyampert left the church to become a missionary to the Congo under William H. Sheppard, an African American missionary who would later become known for his activism opposing to the treatment of the Congolese by rubber companies. The Sylvan Street Presbyterian Church was the second black Presbyterian Church established in Alabama. The congregation grew through the first half of the twentieth century, and moved to the Northern Heights building in June 1960. This building was originally the Northside Baptist Church. The Sylvan Street Church, located at Sylvan Street (now Martin Luther King Street) and Philpot Avenue, is still extant, though in very poor condition. Like many churches at that time, Northern Heights had an active congregation and hosted many volunteer activities for women and children. The church also operated a kindergarten and low-level elementary school, as did many other black churches. Later, starting in the 1970s, the church operated a daycare center for low-income families for fourteen years. Northern Heights is affiliated with the Presbyterian Church (USA). 


</dc:description>
<dc:subject>African American Churches -- Tennessee; Balconies; Baptist church buildings; Brick churches; Ceilings; Chandeliers; Church buildings; Church buildings -- Alabama; Churches; Historic buildings; Interior architecture; Presbyterian church buildings; Stained glass windows </dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University </dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>IMG_5796</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/6315</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>