<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Cumberland Gap: town hall</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van</dc:creator>
<dc:date>c. 1989</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1980-1989</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Cumberland Gap Historic District</dc:description>
<dc:description>District</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>90000321 listed Feb. 23, 1990</dc:identifier>
<dc:description>330 Colwyn Street, Cumberland Gap, TN</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Cumberland Gap, Claiborne County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>36.599527,-83.668525</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Black and white photograph of a two-story brick building on a small hill; six rectangular windows and double glass doors on front facade; three windows and air conditioning unit on left facade; brick chimney and gable shingle roof; stone stairs in hill leading up to front door; car parked on left side of building; sign over door reads "City Hall"</dc:description>
<dc:description>For over two hundred years, Cumberland Gap has served as a significant passageway to the lands west of the Appalachian mountains. The Cumberland Gap Historic District is significant as evidence to the patterns of Claiborne County's history as a late nineteenth and early twentieth century mining town funded by foreign capitalists as well as its associations with Wilderness Road.  American Association, Limited had its headquarters in Cumberland Gap.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Historic districts; Historic buildings; Cumberland Gap (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>City &amp; town halls</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>4 x 6 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>cumberlandgap019</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/998</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>