<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Gordon-Oak Streets: National Register nomination form</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Staff at MTSU Center for Historic Preservation</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1991-11</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1990-1999</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Gordon-Oak Streets Historic District</dc:description>
<dc:description>District</dc:description>
<dc:description>Gordon Street, Dyersburg, TN 38024</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Dyersburg, Dyer County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>36.039717, -89.383044</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>National Register of Historic Places nomination form for the Gordon-Oak Streets Historic District in Dyersburg, Tennessee.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Located in Dyersburg, Tennessee, the Gordon-Oak Streets Historic District consists of a portion of the odd numbered side of the 700 block of Sampson Avenue; the 100 through 300 blocks of Oak Street; and the 100 through 300 blocks of Gordon Street. The development of Gordon and Oak Streets began in the 1910s and 1920s as a residential neighborhood for professionals and business owners. It is believed that a local contractor/builder named Gordon platted the area as a new neighborhood. Most of the buildings in the district were constructed from 1910 to 1940. The Gordon-Oak Streets neighborhood gained recognition as a historic district in 1992 for its early twentieth century domestic architecture.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Historic districts</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Historic districts</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Forms (Documents)</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>18 p.; 8.5 x 11 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>SP_Gordon-OakStreets_008.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/4496</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>