<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Mt. Ararat MB: side view</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1998-6-10</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1990-1999</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Mount Ararat Missionary Baptist Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>5125 Main St. W, Trezevant, TN 38258</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Trezevant, Carroll County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>36.013507,-88.628622</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of church side. The church is a gable-fronted, brick building. A sided portico is visible at the front of the church. A side addition intersects the main section at the rear. A parking lot is located to the side of the building.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Mount Ararat Missionary Baptist Church is located in Trezevant, Tennessee. The church has occupied its current building since the mid-twentieth century. The brick building reflects two major building periods: 1952 when the building was constructed under the pastorate of Reverend E.G. Carroll and the 1980s when a sided portico was added. A large cemetery sits to the side of the church.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>African American Churches -- Tennessee; Church buildings</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Churches; Steeples; Porticoes; Gable roofs; Brick; Parking lots</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Churches; Brickwork</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>4 x 6 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>SP_MtAraratMB_004.tif</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/4160</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>