<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Peace Baptist Church: view of north side facade</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2003-2005?</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Peace Baptist Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>Church</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>05000293 listed April 22, 2005</dc:identifier>
<dc:description>302 Sixth St. N, Birmingham, Jefferson County, AL</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Birmingham, Jefferson County, AL</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>33.507174,-86.826999</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of the side of the church building, showing two levels of the main building and a third level in the tower visible at left. Five pilasters divide six bays, each of which features large windows of painted glass on the upper floor and standard windows on the lower floor.. A metal staircase leads to a door at the back of the second story. Decorative wrought ironwork protects three visible doors.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Peace Baptist Church was built in 1948 under the guidance of Reverend Dr. J.H. Stenson, who oversaw construction of a large twin-tower brick church.   Its location near downtown Birmingham and its large size contributed to the prominent role played by Peace Baptist during the formative years of the Alabama Christian Movement for Human Rights (ACMHR) during 1956-1958, when the church was an important strategy center for the ACMHR. Members of the congregation played an active role in the early mass meetings of the ACMHR and participated in the Selective Buying Campaign of 1962, and the Project C demonstrations of 1963. Dr. Stenson was minister of the church until 1969.&lt;br&gt; The original church building now serves as a fellowship hall for the adjacent  Sixth Street Peace Baptist Church building that was constructed in 1990.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>African American Churches -- Tennessee</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Churches</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>4 x 6 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>PeaceBaptist005</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/3236</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>