<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Brainerd Mission Cemetery: view of tombstones</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van</dc:creator>
<dc:date>c. 2006</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Brainerd Mission Cemetery</dc:description>
<dc:description>Cemetery</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>79002435 listed 1979/12/06</dc:identifier>
<dc:description>5700 Eastgate Loop, Chattanooga, Hamilton Co., TN</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Chattanooga, Hamilton County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>35.009407,-85.212949</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of cemetery with brown leaves on the ground and scattered green trees; low stone grave markers in foreground and larger markers in background. Approximately 20 tombstones</dc:description>
<dc:description>Founded in 1817 by representatives of the American Board of Commissioners of Foreign Missions (ABCFM), Brainerd Mission remained open until Cherokee removal 21 years later. Brainerd Mission was responsible for the basic education and religious education of many Cherokee, and was recognized as a national model for the boarding school approach that dominated white attempts to educate Native Americans for most of the nineteenth century.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Cemeteries -- Tennessee; Brainerd Mission; Cherokee Indians -- Missions</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Cemeteries</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:format>35 mm slide</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>brainerd002</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/1045</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>