<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Columbia Union Station Depot: east view of rear of building</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Eatherly, Brad, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2015</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2010-2019</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Columbia Union Station Depot</dc:description>
<dc:description>Railroad station</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>86002908 listed October 23, 1986</dc:identifier>
<dc:coverage>Columbia, Maury County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>35.608080, -87.037371</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of the rear of a train station viewed from the east.  The rail (south) elevation of the west wing includes a double-leaf doorway with wood-and-glass doors.  A two-light transom caps the doorway.  Three one-over-one double hung sash windows are located on the west wing.  The first floor of the main structure's south elevation includes a double-leaf wood-and-glass doorway, a single-leaf wood doorway, and a second double-leaf wood-and-glass doorway.  Each doorway is capped with a three light semi-circular transom window with traceried muntins.  The second floor of the main structure includes seven one-over-one double-hung sash windows topped by eight small fixed single light attic windows.  The main structure's east elevation includes a single one-over one double-hung sash window, three small fixed single light attic windows, and a tall stone chimney with four flues and a corbeled top.  The east wing's (foreground) south elevation has three one-over-one double hung sash windows.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The Columbia Union Station train depot was built from 1902-1905 by the Nashville, Chattanooga, and St. Louis Railway and the Louisville and Nashville Railroad.  It operated as a passenger service depot until 1954 when airline travel became more popular and as a freight depot until 1961, at which time it became unused as a station.  The building served as an apartment complex in the 1970s and 1980s until it fell into disrepair.  It was restored in the early 2010s.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Railroad stations</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Railroad stations</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/6295</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>