<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Good Samaritan Hospital: west elevation</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Humphreys, Elizabeth Moore, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2012-08-21</dc:date>
<dc:description>Good Samaritan Hospital</dc:description>
<dc:description>Hospital</dc:description>
<dc:description>1107 Voeglin Avenue Selma, Alabama </dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Selma, Dallas County, AL</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>32.417154, -87.023232</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of the west elevation of Good Samaritan Hospital, photographer facing slightly south of east. This elevation faces Broad Street but it set back from the road by a yard and partial parking area. Two brick planters are visible in the foreground; the one on the left includes several shrubs and the one on the right is mostly grass. A flowering tree is partly visible beyond the planter on the right. A metal railing sits in front of the building, dividing the yard area from the hospital itself. This elevation of the hospital shows the overall rectangular shape of the building, with the inside of an L that projects out of the elevation and rises a half story above it and the outside of the L that projects slightly from the fa&#231;ade to the south and rises a half-story above the rest of the building. The ground floor is brick with three openings. On the north end, a wide concrete transom sits over a wide covered opening. Moving south, the next opening is on the projecting section. It is a glass and metal door, likely matching the one on the fa&#231;ade, that has been boarded up. A concrete porch roof or open-front awning protects the door. It is supported on either side by a flat rectangular column. A wider section sits just top the column, with a narrow flat section that runs up to meet in a flat roof over the doorway. The third opening is a covered door or window of some type directly below the eighth bay above it. The area between the second and third openings has metal letters reading GOOD SAMARITAN CENTER. Six utility boxes sit below these words. The upper three floors are divided into nine bays separated by brick sections. Each bay includes a pair of single-pane metal-frame windows protected by an open-front, box-style concrete awning, except for the fourth bay on the projecting section, which has no awnings. The first two bays have vents between the second and third level windows. The fourth bay, on the projecting section, has vents below the third and second story windows. The last five bays feature vents below each window. The raised seams of the metal roof are visible along the roofline. A brick chimney sits at the north end. The inside of the L projection on the west elevation is brick with metal covering part of it. The side of the back of the L projection facing the fa&#231;ade is brick and concrete, with the arched handles of a ladder just visible allowing access to the roof of the projection. </dc:description>
<dc:description>The extant modernist Good Samaritan Hospital in Selma, Alabama was built in 1964 by the Sisters of St. Joseph and the Edmundites (Fathers of St. Edmund), two Catholic missions. Originally built in 1922, Good Samaritan (or Good Sam, as it is known locally) was the second black hospital in the city, after the Burwell Infirmary. The hospital was originally run by the Alabama Baptist Convention under the administration of Mamie Norris, a nurse from the Tuskegee Institute. The Catholics purchased the hospital in 1944, built a new facility in 1947, which was replaced by the modern facility that could house 111 patients in 1964. Good Samaritan was the only hospital in the six surrounding counties open to African Americans. Sister Louis Bertrand established Alabama&#8217;s first School of Practical Nursing at Good Samaritan to deal with the critical nursing shortage. This was an important source of employment and training to black women (though a handful of black men also completed the program), who had few other such opportunities under Jim Crow. The hospital was also an important source of employment for Selma&#8217;s black community. The Sisters of St. Joseph took part in the civil rights movement in Selma in a variety of ways, including boycotting grocery stores that only catered to whites, attending mass meetings at nearby Tabernacle Baptist Church, and attempting to visit black youth who were arrested for protesting. This did little to endear them to Selma&#8217;s white community, who referred to them as the &#8220;black sisters,&#8221; and earned the attention of the local chapter of the Ku Klux Klan (KKK). The building was It also functioned as a center of community, hosting the Selma Literacy Project, an effort of the Dallas County Voters League and the Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (SNCC) to prepare potential black voters for the literacy test required in order to register to vote. Good Samaritan was where victims of racially motivated violence and police shootings went for care. Jimmie Lee Jackson, a civil rights activist in nearby Marion (Perry County), Alabama was brought to Good Sam for treatment after being beaten by troopers and shot by Alabama State Trooper James Bonard Fowler. Jackson&#8217;s death from his injuries inspired James Bevel of the Southern Christian Leadership Conference to plan the Selma to Montgomery Marches that included both Bloody Sunday and the successful March to Montgomery in March 1965. Marchers injured in Bloody Sunday were also brought to Good Sam for treatment. Though the sisters could not march by order of the bishop, they opened the hospital and convent as meeting and rest places for the demonstrators who poured into Selma from across the country. After 1965, Good Samaritan began to struggle as white hospitals were forced to open their doors to black patients, and white doctors and black patients began seeking out care at the better-equipped (and better paying) formerly white facilities. In 1972, the Sisters of St. Joseph withdrew from Good Samaritan Hospital, citing worsening conditions, poor finances, and a lack of sufficient staff. African American leaders took over, with John Crear as administrator and Dr. Charles Lett as medical chief. They won a grant for research on rural health, which led to the establishment of the Rural Health Medical Program, which allowed Good Samaritan to play a key role in providing education and health care to the rural communities of Dallas, Perry, Wilcox, and Lowndes Counties. By 1983, however, the poverty of the surrounding areas overwhelmed the hospital&#8217;s precarious finances, and Good Samaritan was forced to close its doors. In 2016, Mayor George Evans announced an effort to reopen the hospital as a medical center with space for a museum to acknowledge the facility&#8217;s key role in the voting rights movement.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Civil rights -- United States; Clergy; Historic buildings; Women</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>hospital; catholic; nursing; nuns; black history; voting rights</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>IMG_0173</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/6337</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>