<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Good Samaritan Hospital: east elevation</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Humphreys, Elizabeth Moore, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2012-08-21</dc:date>
<dc:description>Good Samaritan Hospital</dc:description>
<dc:description>Hospital</dc:description>
<dc:description>1107 Voeglin Avenue Selma, Alabama </dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Selma, Dallas County, AL</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>32.417154, -87.023232</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of Good Samaritan Hospital, east elevation, photographer facing west. The hospital is a four-story, modern, brutalism-influenced building in brick in and concrete. Its overall shape is rectangular, with the west and east elevations making up the long sides and the fa&#231;ade on the south side. Two sections project out of their respective elevations. On the west elevation, the short side of an L-shaped section that is half a story higher than the rest of the building projects slightly from the rest of the elevation. The fa&#231;ade features a section a half story taller than the rest of the building and projecting slightly. It is also L-shaped with the longer side facing the fa&#231;ade. The shapes of these projecting sections are visible above the roofline from the east elevation. The first story of the hospital is brick and divided from the rest of the building by a concrete belt. The sections above it are divided into eleven bays of vertical rectangular concrete panels with brick sections between them. The brick section between the sixth and seventh concrete panels is slightly more than twice as wide as the brick sections between the other paneled sections. The first floor features eleven openings. The first is a boarded-up door protected by a concrete, shed-roof portico with wide columns. A painted inset with two utility boxes sits directly to the right of the door. The next four openings are metal-frame single light pairs of windows. Two pairs of utility boxes are fixed to the brick between the second and third windows, and a fifth box sits between the third and fourth. The sixth opening is another boarded-up door inside a shed-roof, concrete portico. The last five openings are boarded up window pairs. Three utility boxes sit below and between the ninth and tenth windows. Each pair of windows has a brick sill. The first four bays of the upper three floors are identical, with a pair of single-pane metal windows on each floor topped by a three-sided open front concrete awning. The second story window on the first bay is boarded up. The fifth, tenth, and eleventh bays include the same windows on the first and second floors only, and on the tenth and eleventh bays, the second floor windows are boarded up. The sixth, seventh, and eighth bays include the same window but only on the third floor. The ninth bay is slightly different, with a large square of white painted material covering the space where the window would be and overlapping the brick sections on either side. Another rectangle of this same material covers the top edge of the ground floor window. The concrete belt divides this section. Metal vents sit below each window on the third floor and in the center of the wider brick section. The same vents sit below the windows on the first five bays. The seamed edges of the metal roof are visible at the top of the building. On the south end, the east elevation of the projecting portion of the fa&#231;ade is just visible, with four one-over-one metal frame windows and a square, single-light window on the half-story above the roofline. On the inside of the L, a section of metal is just visible, disrupting the brickwork that makes up this elevation. Further to the north, the backside of the brick half story is partly visible, with the arched top of a ladder on the south elevation. A brick chimney sits to the north of this projection. The foreground of the image includes the metal fence surrounding the concrete parking lot. This image includes a brick column used to anchor the rolling gate that provides access. </dc:description>
<dc:description>The extant modernist Good Samaritan Hospital in Selma, Alabama was built in 1964 by the Sisters of St. Joseph and the Edmundites (Fathers of St. Edmund), two Catholic missions. Originally built in 1922, Good Samaritan (or Good Sam, as it is known locally) was the second black hospital in the city, after the Burwell Infirmary. The hospital was originally run by the Alabama Baptist Convention under the administration of Mamie Norris, a nurse from the Tuskegee Institute. The Catholics purchased the hospital in 1944, built a new facility in 1947, which was replaced by the modern facility that could house 111 patients in 1964. Good Samaritan was the only hospital in the six surrounding counties open to African Americans. Sister Louis Bertrand established Alabama&#8217;s first School of Practical Nursing at Good Samaritan to deal with the critical nursing shortage. This was an important source of employment and training to black women (though a handful of black men also completed the program), who had few other such opportunities under Jim Crow. The hospital was also an important source of employment for Selma&#8217;s black community. The Sisters of St. Joseph took part in the civil rights movement in Selma in a variety of ways, including boycotting grocery stores that only catered to whites, attending mass meetings at nearby Tabernacle Baptist Church, and attempting to visit black youth who were arrested for protesting. This did little to endear them to Selma&#8217;s white community, who referred to them as the &#8220;black sisters,&#8221; and earned the attention of the local chapter of the Ku Klux Klan (KKK). The building was It also functioned as a center of community, hosting the Selma Literacy Project, an effort of the Dallas County Voters League and the Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (SNCC) to prepare potential black voters for the literacy test required in order to register to vote. Good Samaritan was where victims of racially motivated violence and police shootings went for care. Jimmie Lee Jackson, a civil rights activist in nearby Marion (Perry County), Alabama was brought to Good Sam for treatment after being beaten by troopers and shot by Alabama State Trooper James Bonard Fowler. Jackson&#8217;s death from his injuries inspired James Bevel of the Southern Christian Leadership Conference to plan the Selma to Montgomery Marches that included both Bloody Sunday and the successful March to Montgomery in March 1965. Marchers injured in Bloody Sunday were also brought to Good Sam for treatment. Though the sisters could not march by order of the bishop, they opened the hospital and convent as meeting and rest places for the demonstrators who poured into Selma from across the country. After 1965, Good Samaritan began to struggle as white hospitals were forced to open their doors to black patients, and white doctors and black patients began seeking out care at the better-equipped (and better paying) formerly white facilities. In 1972, the Sisters of St. Joseph withdrew from Good Samaritan Hospital, citing worsening conditions, poor finances, and a lack of sufficient staff. African American leaders took over, with John Crear as administrator and Dr. Charles Lett as medical chief. They won a grant for research on rural health, which led to the establishment of the Rural Health Medical Program, which allowed Good Samaritan to play a key role in providing education and health care to the rural communities of Dallas, Perry, Wilcox, and Lowndes Counties. By 1983, however, the poverty of the surrounding areas overwhelmed the hospital&#8217;s precarious finances, and Good Samaritan was forced to close its doors. In 2016, Mayor George Evans announced an effort to reopen the hospital as a medical center with space for a museum to acknowledge the facility&#8217;s key role in the voting rights movement.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Civil rights -- United States; Clergy; Historic buildings; Women</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>hospital; catholic; nursing; nuns; black history; voting rights</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>IMG_0167</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/6336</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>