<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Green Street Bapist Church: corner of facade and south elevation</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Humphreys, Elizabeth Moore, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2013-08-08</dc:date>
<dc:description>Green Street Baptist Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>1220 Green Street Selma, AL 36701</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Selma, Dallas County, AL</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>32.416946, -87.019854</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of the southwest corner of the brick building, photographer facing northeast. A telephone wire extends across the shot in the foreground, part of a transformer box is visible in the upper left corner of the image, with five wires extending to the building. The main church is cross-gabled. The west-facing gable forms the facade, and other gable end faces south. The facade gable has a bell tower on the northwest end and a shorter tower on the southwest end. A single story addition fills in the southeast corner of the building, and a flat-roofed 1962 addition (the education annex) extends to the east, flush with the face of the south gable end. The peak of the west-facing gable roof is higher than the peak of the south-facing gable, and the point where they meet is capped by a hexagonal cupola. Each side of the cupola features an arched, louvered window, and the body of the cupola is light gray. The cupola's domed roof is metal, and each face of the cupola meets the roof with a projecting wooden eave. The northwest belltower features a pyramid-shaped bonnet roof covered in asphalt shingles with a large cross at the peak. Each elevation of the tower includes a pair of arched openings just below the roof, though the one on the east side of the south elevation is obscured by the gabled facade. Continuing down the west elevation of the bell tower, the face of the tower features pilasters and corbelling that make the face of the tower appear to be slightly recessed. Two arched window openings with cement keystones, imposts, and sills are visible on the lower part of the tower. The base of the tower features an arched opening with a cement keystone. A metal light fixture on an arm extends out over the arched opening. Continuing south the facade, the gable end is rendered asymmetrical by the northwest tower, which cuts off the north section of the gable end. The top of the gable end section is cement, with a pedestal at the peak housing an owl decoy. Moving down, a set of corbels create a decorative bargeboard-esque brick detail which becomes double brick pilasters descending to the foundation. There are two circular openings in the upper portion of the gable end, the top one is empty and surrounded by a cement sill. The one below is larger and houses a stained-glass rosette window surrounded by two rows of headers. Directly below, there are two rows of four windows. The top row are arched with cement keystones and imposts. The lower ones feature cement lintels. All of the windows have cement sills and are trimmed in white-painted wood. The brickwork on the facade is common bond. The foundation is solid concrete, painted white. Moving south, the shorter tower has a pyramid-shaped bonnet roof covered in asphalt shingles with a four-sided spike at the apex. The shorter tower lacks the arched openings of the bell tower, but is otherwise very similar, with the same corbels/pilasters/recessed effect. Each of the visible elevations includes a pair of arched stained glass windows with cement keystones and a imposts, sharing the central impost, and cement sills. The west elevation of the ground level includes a double door with an arched transom with a concrete keystone and imposts and headers between. The white-painted wood door frame is visible, as is part of the plain wrought iron railing and low white-painted concrete wall. The south elevation is partly obscured by the one-story addition, but an arched opening for a stained glass window is partly visible, though it has been boarded up. A small section of the church's south elevation is visible above the one-story addition and includes a pair of arched stained-glass windows sharing a concrete impost with concrete keystones. The tops of the keystones are obscured by a white painted eave housing a gutter system, and two gutter pipes are visible descending from the eave to the roof of the addition. The addition has a flat or very low sloping shed roof with white painted wood eaves. Some flashing is visible where the addition roof meets the main structure. Both elevations of the addition are the same. The lower portion of the south elevation is common bond, the lower portion of the west elevation is painted white and appears to be concrete to match the rest of the facade. The upper portion of the addition is stretcher bond with brick pilaster extending up to the roof. Each elevation features a large arched opening with concrete imposts and keystones, four rows of headers, and a concrete sill. The opening houses a stained glass window divided into three vertical sections with white wood trim. The foundation section of the west elevation includes header openings for ventilation, while the center of the foundation area on the south elevation includes a white-trimmed boarded up access point for getting beneath the building. The south-facing gable end extends slightly past where the south elevation of the one-story addition, and a brick chimney runs from the addition up the of the gable end behind the flared section of table end. The west elevation of the south-facing gable includes a pair of arched stained glass windows like those on the south elevation of the west-facing gable end. The asphalt shingle roof is visibly damaged. The south elevation's gable end matches the gable end of the north elevation. The gable end roofline is concrete with a pedestal at the peak, and it flares out flat on either end. Below the roofline, a series of corbels give the effect of brick bargeboard, and double pilasters extend down to the foundation, compressing into a single pilaster around the imposts of the arched stained glass windows before becoming double pilasters again on the rest of the facade. Double brick pilasters also sit on either end of the gable end, though the one on the west end is partly obscured by vegetation. Just below the peak of the roof sit a set of three arched, louvered windows with a shared concrete sill. The arches are three rows of headers. Moving down, four arched stained glass windows with concrete keystones, imposts, and sills are situated between the pilasters, with a row of four three-pane stained glass windows with concrete lintels and sills directly below them. One either side of the pilaster, there is an arched stained glass window with a concrete keystone, imposts, and sill above a three-pane stained glass window with a concrete lintel and sill. The brickwork below the windows is common bond. Moving east, the south elevation of two-story the education wing is visible. It is stretcher bond brick in a slightly different shade from the original church, and features a flat roof with white-painted eaves. It is divided into three bays by plain brick pilasters. The west bay features a six light wood window with a concrete sill beside a smaller two-light window with a concrete sill. Directly below the larger window is a metal louvered vent. Metal conduits and piping extend from the roof to the ground on the westernmost edge. Below the larger window is a ten light window with the bottom four panes painted white. Beside it is a two-light window identical to the one on the second floor. The central bay includes a six light window on the western side of the second level, a six light window on the west side of the lower level, and a solid, white-painted metal door on the east end of the central bay. A flat roof carport supported by square columns extends from the top of the six light window on the lower floor into the parking lot that occupies the length of the south elevation. The eastern bay is slightly wider than the other two bays. It features a matching six light window on the western end with a matching two- light window on the eastern end. A metal pipe extends from the area between the first and second stories, between the two widows, out below the eave, and opens upward. A metal fire escape extends from the larger window across the south elevation down to the ground, though the lowest portion lacks steps. The first floor includes a six-light window on the western end like the one above. Another six light window with the two lower panes painted white occupies the eastern end of the ground floor. Most of the south elevation is paved in concrete with grass growing between the sections. The area in front of the south-facing gable is protected by a chainlink fence surrounding outdoor air conditioning units, some discarded boxes, and a traffic cone. Another chain link fence sits in front of the western bay of the education wing, also housing air conditioning units and some refuse. A concrete sidewalk extends along the facade, with a grassy median visible between the sidewalk and the road. The area in front of the facade includes grass lawn with decorative boxwoods along the foundation level. Three wooden crosses are situated in front of the facade's central gable, and the back of the church sign is visible from this angle. A chainlink fence extends from the west elevation of the one-story addition to the sidewalk.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The congregation of Green Street Baptist Church formed in 1881, primarily from the congregation of First Baptist Church (Colored), which was then known as the St. Phillip Street Baptist Church (due to their location). The church was led by Reverend John Blevins, who had been pastor at St. Phillip Street, thus the church was originally known as &#8220;The John Blevins Church.&#8221; He remained there for two or three years. On December 31, 1881, church trustees Jefferson Richardson, Joseph Baylock, Adam Clayton, and Henry Lamar purchased a lot on the corner of Green Street and McCreary Avenue (now Griffin Avenue) for $150. The first worship services were held in a store on the corner.  The first church the congregation built was a small frame building on a lot adjacent to wear the brick church now stands. The frame church was small and uncomfortable, unable to accommodate the congregation of 200 souls (with 300 attending Sunday School). The interior of the original structure was lit by three lanterns hanging from the ceiling and a tin lamp on each side wall. The minister had a small platform to stand on, and the children sat on the edge. The original frame building was replaced once by a larger frame church, and again by a brick church, which was dedicated in 1892. The current building was dedicated in 1922. The plan for the building came to Pastor James A. Martin in a dream, and it was designed and built by contractor A.J. Farley. It is a Romanesque Revival church with Italianate influences. Between 1937 and 1946, the church building was renovated and restrooms added. Between 1946 and 1958, the church was renovated again, including the purchase of new pews and floor coverings, and a paved sidewalk was added around the church. In 1946, the church opened a kindergarten, which operated for 14 years. In 1962, the church added an education wing. The late 1980s saw another interior renovation, accompanied by a new roof and renovated restrooms. In the late 1990s, a truss in the church&#8217;s roof failed, which has led to significant damage to the structure, including the bowing of the sanctuary wall on Griffin Avenue, the holes in the roof, and extensive interior damage from exposure to the elements. The remaining congregation currently worships in the education wing.  Green Street&#8217;s current state belies its historical significance. During the 1960s, the church enjoyed a thriving congregation, and its kitchen was used to prepare meals for marchers in the Selma to Montgomery March in 1965. The considerable space in both the education wing and the main sanctuary were also used to provide temporary housing for civil rights workers. On June 5, 1964, the church hosted a mass meeting featuring Ralph Abernathy of the Southern Christian Leadership Conference. Following the meeting, someone threw a rock at some of the deputized possemen who had surrounded the church during the meeting. The possemen responded by attacking the crowd as it tried to exit the church, using night sticks and tear gas. The riot continued in the neighborhood, injuring many of the black residents and putting some in the hospital. Homes up to a block and a half away from the church were damaged, with broken windows and porch lights. Two white journalists were targeted and their cameras destroyed by possemen.  </dc:description>
<dc:subject>African American Churches -- Tennessee; Baptist church buildings; Bell towers; Brick churches; Church buildings; Church buildings -- Alabama; Churches; Civil rights -- United States; Stained glass windows</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>IMG_0179</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/6320</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>