<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Dockery Plantation: historic marker sign</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2000?</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Dockery Plantation</dc:description>
<dc:description>Farm</dc:description>
<dc:description>Cemetery</dc:description>
<dc:description>229 Highway 8, Cleveland, Bolivar County, MS</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Cleveland, Bolivar County, MS</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>33.74777,-90.7238</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of a historic marker sign for Dockery Plantation issued by the State of Mississippi that reads " Dockery Plantation. Established by Will Dockery in 1895 and operated 1937-1982 by Joe Rice Dockery. Included a post office, commissary, and cotton gin. The plantation once employed Charley Patton, a legendary blues musician, who inspired such greats as Muddy Waters, Robert Johnson, B.B. King and Elvis Presley."</dc:description>
<dc:description>Dockery Plantation, part of the Mississippi Blues Trail, is considered by many blues music historians as a birthplace of the Delta Blues genre. Dockery Farms was created in 1895 by the clearing and draining of thousands of acres along the Sunflower River in the Mississippi delta region. By the early 20th century it had grown into a self-sufficient community composed of hundreds of tenant farm families, primarily African-Americans. Notable among musicians who worked at Dockery Farms are Charley Patton, Howling Wolf, Tommy Johnson and Roebuck "Pops" Staples.  The site is now managed by a non-profit foundation as public site. A key component is the Dockery Plantation cemetery, where many of the farm's African American workers are buried.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Historic farms; Plantations</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Farms; Plantations</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Farms; Plantations; Cemeteries; Historical markers</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>Dockery001</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/2679</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>