<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Morton Funeral Home: front (south) facade</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Eatherly, Brad, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2015</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2010-2019</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>A. J. Morton Funeral Home</dc:description>
<dc:description>Funeral Home</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Columbia, Maury County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>35.613640, -87.033101</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of a commercial building viewed from the south.  A concrete foundation supports the structure.  The front facade of this funeral home has six bays.  To the far left is a former garage door, used in the beginning by horse and carriage, and later by automobile.  Three windows of unknown specifics are located on the facade.  A front entry doorway and another doorway to the side are also located on the facade.  A single transom window is visible above the side entry way. All bays are now covered with plywood.  The structure is made of cement blocks with a brick front.  A driveway leads to the garage with a sidewalk in front of the structure.  A sign sits in the yard in front of the structure.  A rock stonewall borders the property and the street.  Overgrowth of ivy has overtaken much of the facade.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The A. J. Morton Funeral Home opened in 1891 by J. M. Morton and his wife, Clara B. Morton.  This was the first African-American owned undertaking business in the state of Tennessee.  When J. M. died in 1899, his wife and his son, Andrew J. continued to operate the business.  The funeral home received national attention during the Columbia race riots in 1946.  The funeral home was broken into and one of the caskets was defaced with the letters "KKK."  The funeral home remained in operation until the year 2000.  It ended up being one of the longest operated African-American owned businesses in the United States.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Funeral homes; Abandoned buildings; Historic buildings -- Tennessee</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Morgues &amp; mortuaries</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/6128</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>