<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Mt. Zion School: south facade</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2014</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2010-2019</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Mt. Zion School</dc:description>
<dc:description>Mt. Zion CME Church; Mt. Zion Worship Center</dc:description>
<dc:description>School</dc:description>
<dc:description>Mt. Zion Rd., Bradford, TN</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Bradford, Gibson County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>36.093562, -88.887325</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of Mt. Zion's south facade. The one-room, one-story building contains weatherboard covering and a metal gable roof.</dc:description>
<dc:description>In 1855, David P. Hamilton deeded one acre of land to A.P Foster, T.S Freeman and G. B Rust for the sum of five dollars. The deed dictated that the land was for the establishment of &#8220;Mount Zion meeting house.&#8221; Tradition states that a rural school called Mt. Zion School was built in 1870 by &#8220;freed slaves.&#8221; In 1915, Mt. Zion had one teacher and hosted Grades 1-6. Mt. Zion was one of seventy-two separate schools in the county at that time. This leaves a possible construction date ranging between 1870 (as the community suggests) and 1915 (when the school is known to exist). Though the school is listed in 1915 as hosting Grades 1-6, children beyond the age of elementary school children attended Mt. Zion. Photographic evidence from 1925 suggests that possible ages could range from four or five to teenagers. The last class to leave Mt. Zion was the class of 1962. Its legacy lives on in the stories of Gibson County community members and has a rich history still yet untapped.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>School buildings </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Schoolhouses ; Clapboard siding</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Schools ; Clapboard siding</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:format>Computer disk</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>Mt Zion school S facade.JPG</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/5852</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>