<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Toles Chapel CME: fieldnotes</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1998-05-15</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1990-1999</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Toles Chapel Christian Methodist Episcopal Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>497 Wren Ave., Camden, TN 38320</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Camden, Benton County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>36.071907,-88.088487</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Fieldnotes of Toles Chapel CME Church. Notes document the location of the church on Wren Avenue and provide a basic description of the building.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Toles Chapel's first meetinghouse originally sat on the grounds presently occupied by the cemetery on Flatwoods Road. The land was purchased for six dollars in February 1907 by Oliver Toles, George Wyly, and Richard McAuley. The congregation eventually relocated to its current building, a former schoolhouse. Built as a Rosenwald-plan school between 1930 and 1940, Toles Chapel CME is a concrete-block building that sits in a well landscaped lot. Sometime after its construction, a small addition with a gable and shed roof, exterior door, and chimney was attached. The historic cemetery at the rear was a principal burial ground for local African Americans and reportedly contains hundreds of unmarked graves. The cemetery landscape has been altered by the movement and rearrangement of tombstones. At the time of fieldwork, Jerry Howard served as pastor and the property was considered eligible for the National Register.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>African American Churches -- Tennessee; Julius Rosenwald Fund -- Buildings</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Churches</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Fieldnotes</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>1 p.; 8.5 x 11 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>SP_TolesChapelCME_001.tif</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/3865</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>