<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Old Jailer's House: distance view from Courthouse Square</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Gavin, Michael, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2004</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Old Jailer's House</dc:description>
<dc:description>House</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>77001266 listed 1977</dc:identifier>
<dc:description>Robertson St., Charlotte, TN 37036</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Charlotte, Dickson County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>36.178178,-87.338586</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of Old Jailer's House viewed from the Courthouse Square. The two-story brick structure contains a plain Colonial Revival porch.</dc:description>
<dc:description>In 1806, Dickson County erected a log jail. On May 30, 1830, a tornado destroyed the jail. In its place, a new jail was constructed using materials from the former courthouse. Finished in 1831, the Old Jailer's House originally served as the county jailor's residence. The two-story, gable-roofed brick building witnessed several periods of construction. In 1920, a single-story, one-room brick addition was added to the side. The Colonial Revival porch and cornice details were also added at that time. Around 1940, a single-story, concrete-block jail facility was annexed to the rear of the building. As part of Charlotte's Courthouse Square Historic District, the building (Lot #39, Public Square) is owned by the Dickson County Historical Society. At the time of fieldwork, the society hoped to "utilize the building as a local history museum, to house its archives and collections, and to host special events and exhibitions."</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Historic buildings ; Houses and homes ; Jails</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Porches ; Sash windows ; Columns ; Chimneys ; Gable roofs ; Hip roofs ; Brick</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Jails</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>4 x 6 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>SP_OldJailer'sHouse_025.tif</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/4189</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>