<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Craigs Chapel AME Zion Church: sketch of site plan</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2000</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Craigs Chapel African Methodist Episcopal Zion Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>Church</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>01000256 listed March 12, 2001</dc:identifier>
<dc:description>Craigs Chapel Rd.,  Greenback, Loudon County, TN</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Greenback, Loudon County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>35.649559,-84.172706</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Hand drawn map of the Craigs Chapel property with property details noted.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The Craigs Chapel AME Zion Church is an example of Jim Crow era communities in which churches had different but related buildings, structures, and sites existing on either the church lot or on immediately adjacent lots. Craigs Chapel has included three critical elements of African American communities, church, cemetery and school. The church was constructed in 1896 and the original school three years later. The church expanded its service to the African American community with the incorporation of the cemetery in 1903. An original school building was physically connected to the church after construction of WPA schools for both whites and blacks in Loudon County c. 1940.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>African American Churches -- Tennessee</dc:subject>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Map</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>8.5 x 11 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>CraigsChapel002</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/1020</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>