<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Oaklawn: southeast elevation</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Eatherly, Brad, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2015</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2010-2019</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Oaklawn</dc:description>
<dc:description>Absalom Thompson House</dc:description>
<dc:description>House</dc:description>
<dc:description>Farm</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>79002449 listed Sept. 11, 1979</dc:identifier>
<dc:coverage>Spring Hill, Maury County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>35.721465, -86.929815</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of a historic home viewed from the southeast.  The Greek Revival home was originally constructed in the Federal style.  The east elevation features a small portico with a side doorway and a six-over-six double-hung window.  The rest of the first floor has four six-over-six double-hung windows and another small side door.  The second floor features four six-over-six double-hung windows and a small four-over-four double hung window.   Two brick chimneys rise above the roof line.  The hipped roof is made of corrugated tin.  The south elevation features a large portico with four large columns.  The columns are topped off with Doric capitals.  The central doorway is flanked by two six-over-six double-hung windows with four light side lights in the Palladian style without the fan light.  The central doorway has a fanned transom window over the door.  A balcony with a wrought iron railway extends beyond the second floor doorway.  The second floor doorway has a three light transom light.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Oaklawn was built in 1835 for Absalom Thompson.  The original structure was built in a Federal style, ell-shaped and one-and-a-half stories high.  The home was rebuilt in 1860 in the Greek Revival style and enlarged to two full stories.  The home served as headquarters for Confederate General John Bell Hood during the Battle of Spring Hill in November of 1864.  This is the infamous location where General Hood slept while Union forces marched past his troops toward Franklin, TN.  The house stayed in the Thompson family until 1911.  The interior was renovated to become a tenant house and suffered from decay.  In the 1940s, the building was returned to its original condition.  The rear portico was enclosed in the 1950s. The exterior remains much the same as it did when it was remodeled in 1860.  The building served as the home for country and western performers George Jones and Tammy Wynette during the early 1970s.  The building is now privately owned.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Brick houses -- Tennessee; Family farms -- Tennessee; Tennessee -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Greek Revival</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Dwellings</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission.</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/6301</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>