<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Christian Valley Baptist Church: history and property description</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van</dc:creator>
<dc:contributor>Nelson, Linda; White, Marjorie</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>2005?</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Christian Valley Baptist Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>3104 33rd Ter N, Birmingham, Jefferson County, Alabama</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Birmingham, Jefferson County, AL</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>33.557179,-86.805545</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>History and property description of Christian Valley Baptist Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>Christian Valley Baptist Church, originated in 1914, is locally significant for its association with the Alabama Christian Movement for Human Rights and the Civil Rights Movement in Birmingham from 1956 to 1963.  The church is an example of the smaller, working class based North Birmingham Baptist congregations that supported the ACMHR.  Its pastor during the Civil Rights era was Rev. A. Lawrence Lawson, who was an active voice in the ACMHR and was a part of the Collegeville Baptist ministers who strongly supported Rev. Fred Shuttlesworth and the activism carried out by the nearby Bethel Baptist Church.  The church itself never hosted a mass meeting of the entire ACMHR due to its small size, but congregation members held planning sessions at the church and later conducted Voter Registration information sessions and registration drives.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>African American Churches -- Tennessee; Baptist church buildings; Alabama Christian Movement for Human Rights</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Church history</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Churches</dc:subject>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>History</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>3 pg, 8.5 x 11 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>ChristianValley001</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/3377</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>