<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>St. John Baptist Church: history and property description</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van</dc:creator>
<dc:contributor>Nelson, Linda; White, Marjorie</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>2005?</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>St. John Baptist Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>2401 Carlos Ave SW, Birmingham, Jefferson County, AL</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Birmingham, Jefferson County, AL</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>33.46474,-86.874398</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>History and property description of St. John Baptist Church developed as part of a multi-property nomination to the National Register for Historic Places.</dc:description>
<dc:description>St. John Baptist is a large church in the Powderly neighborhood of southwest Birmingham. The first church building was constructed in 1910 and elements of the original building are included in the large expansion built in 1966. An educational building was added in 1973. The church was active during the civil rights era in Birmingham and two of its pastors, Rev. Joseph Crosby and Rev. Ambus Hill, were leaders in the Alabama Christian Movement for Human Rights (ACMHR).  Mass meetings of the ACMHR were held in the church during 1961 to discuss issues such as the closing of city parks after segregation in the parks was ruled unconstitutional. The activism of the church in the early 1960s is credited in part with the growth of the congregation and the need for a larger sanctuary.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>African American Churches -- Tennessee; Alabama Christian Movement for Human Rights; Civil rights -- United States</dc:subject>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>History</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>3 pg, 8.5 x 11 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>StJohnBap001</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/3475</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>