<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Columbia Hydroelectric Station: west view</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Eatherly, Brad, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2015</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2010-2019</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Columbia Hydroelectric Station</dc:description>
<dc:description>Dam</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>89002364 listed February 2, 1990</dc:identifier>
<dc:coverage>Columbia, Maury County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>35.620543, -87.021469</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of a hydroelectric station viewed from the west.  A concrete walkway with steel handrails leads to a brick building sitting atop a concrete foundation.  The walkway ends at a large white door which has three sets of sixteen small window panels.  To the right of the walkway is a large window panel composed of thirty-six small windows.  A ventilation chamber sits  on the roof.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The Columbia Hydroelectric Station was built in 1925, prior to the founding of the Tennessee Valley Authority.  The dam is an early example of an hydroelectric site that crosses the Duck River in Columbia, Maury County, Tennessee.  It was designed by the engineering firm of Freeland, Roberts, and Co. and constructed by Foster and Crighton of Nashville.  It was built for the Southern Cities Electrical Corporation, with two sister sites built in the same manner in Marshall and Bedford Counties.  The site includes a walkway, a concrete foundation, the brick superstructure, a fish ladder, and a dam spillway. The structure has been dormant for nearly fifty years.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Dams</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Dams; Hydroelectric power</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/6118</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>