<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>RCA Studio A: front facade (west)view</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Eatherly, Brad, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2015</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2010-2019</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>RCA Studio A</dc:description>
<dc:description>RCA Victor Studios Building</dc:description>
<dc:description>Studio</dc:description>
<dc:description>Office</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Nashville, Davidson County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>36.149638, -86.793049</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph a  historic building built in the International Style of architecture viewed from the west.  The three-story building is made of concrete, brick, stone, and metal.  It combines recording studios and offices.  The foundation is of poured concrete and it has a flat asphalt roof.  Metal double-glass doors  are flanked by large fixed picture windows.  The windows and the doors all have single-light transoms.  Two concrete pillars sit on either side of the entrance way and extend from ground to ceiling.  Three fixed windows are located on each floor separated by metal cantilevers that run from the central entryway to the south end of the building.  </dc:description>
<dc:description>The RCA Victor Studios Building was built in 1964-65 along Nashville's Music Row by W.B. Cambron and Company at the urging of Chet Atkins and brothers Owen and Harold Bradley.  Studio A, inside the building, is a large rectangle that is virtually in tact from it's original construction date.  The room measures 75' x 45' x 25' and is three stories high.  A control room abuts the studio.  Several musicians, including The Monkees, Joe Cocker, Leon Russell, Waylon Jennings, Dolly Parton, Tony Bennett, George Strait, The Beach Boys, William Shatner, George Jones, Jewel, and Willie Nelson, have recorded at the studio.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Sound studios</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>recording studios</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Office buildings; Studios</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Music</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/6255</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>