<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Rippavilla: courtyard view</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Eatherly, Brad, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2015</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2010-2019</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Rippavilla</dc:description>
<dc:description>Nathaniel Cheairs Home</dc:description>
<dc:description>House</dc:description>
<dc:description>Farm</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>96000773 listed on July 19, 1996</dc:identifier>
<dc:coverage>Spring Hill, Maury County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>35.732012, -86.953957</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of a courtyard of a historic home viewed from the east.  The kitchen and smokehouse are visible on the left of the photo.  The rear of the main house is seen in the middle of the photo.  Part of the garage is visible on the right.  The rear of the main house has Flemish-bond brickwork and wide denticulated wood cornice with projecting roof. This section contains a double veranda with three brick pillars and one wood column, all of which extend to the full height of the building. The first story is composed of a half veranda with open newel staircase which provides access to both the second floor veranda and the basement. To the east of the staircase is the fully enclosed portion of the veranda, containing only one six-over-six double hung sash window with flat wood lintel and wood shutters directly next to the intersection with the connecting building. An identical window is located south of the staircase, facing north.  The second story veranda runs from the southwest corner of the main house to the junction of the north wing of the main building. The veranda has a plank wood flooring, beaded board ceiling, and brick exterior walls and contains five bays. From southwest to northwest, this section is composed of a single, five panel wood door with wood framed screen door, one six-over six double hung sash window with flat wood lintel and wooden shutters, and a paired six-over-six double hung sash window flanked by single six-over-six double hung sash windows, all with flat wood lintels but without shutters.  A wooden Chippendale style railing runs the length of the front view of the veranda on both the first and second floors.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Rippavilla was built by Nathaniel Cheairs IV.  Construction began in 1852 and commenced in 1855.  Rippavilla and its farmland was the location where General John Bell Hood's Confederate troops set up camp in late November of 1864.  The Union Army marched past the Confederates while they were asleep through the night along the Columbia-Franklin Turnpike, what is now known as U.S. Highway 31.  The house remained in the Cheairs family until 1920.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Historic buildings -- Tennessee; Historic farms -- Tennessee; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>courtyards; fountains</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Courtyards</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/6167</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>