<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Free Hills Church of Christ: newspaper article</dc:title>
<dc:date>2006-10-5</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Free Hills Church of Christ</dc:description>
<dc:description>Church</dc:description>
<dc:description>2070 Free Hill River Rd, Celina, TN 38551</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Celina, Clay County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Tennessean newspaper article about Free Hill, a historic black settlement.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Free Hills, a historic black community in Clay County, Tennessee, was established in the antebellum period by former slaves. Virginia Hill, a slaveholder from North Carolina, moved with her slaves to the area prior to the Civil War. Settling on 2,000 areas, Hill freed her slaves and gave each land. Taking the surname of Hill, the slaves formed a community known as Free Hills. In the wake of the Civil War, other newly freed African Americans moved to the area. By the early twentieth century, Free Hill was home to about 300 residents. In 1929, a local school opened for blacks through the assistance of the Julius Rosenwald Fund. The school closed in 1966 at the time of desegregation and now serves as a community center. Long before the school's construction, Free Hills boasted a church. Established in 1816 (according to church officials), the first Church of Christ was built of logs on the Brady Plumlee farm. Eventually, by 1938, a new church was built using a combination of logs from the former building and new materials. In the 1940s, the church building was moved closer to the road.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>African American Churches -- Tennessee</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Articles</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Churches</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>3 p.; 8.5 x 11 in.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Access restricted</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Reproduction not permitted</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>SP_FreeHillsChurchofChrist_002-0.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/4273</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>