<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Rippavilla: slave house</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Eatherly, Brad, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>2015</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2010-2019</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Rippavilla</dc:description>
<dc:description>Nathaniel Chearis House</dc:description>
<dc:description>House</dc:description>
<dc:description>Farm</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>96000773 listed on July 19, 1996</dc:identifier>
<dc:coverage>Spring Hill, Maury County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>35.732012, -86.953957</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of a house for enslaved African-Americans on the property of a historic home.  The house has several wooden slats that are falling or have fallen off.  A brick chimney is prominent on the side of the house.  A small four-light fixed window with a pane knocked out sits to the right of the chimney.  The rear elevation has a central four-over-four double hung window with several panes knocked out.  The gabled roof is made out of corrugated tin.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Rippavilla was built by Nathaniel Cheairs IV.  Construction began in 1852 and commenced in 1855.  Rippavilla and its farmland was the location where General John Bell Hood's Confederate troops set up camp in late November of 1864.  The Union Army marched past the Confederates while they were asleep through the night along the Columbia-Franklin Turnpike, what is now known as U.S. Highway 31.  The house remained in the Cheairs family until 1920.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Historic buildings -- Tennessee; African Americans -- Dwellings -- Tennessee; Slaves -- Dwellings</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Slave quarters</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/6169</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>