<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Tennssee State University Historic District: Harned Science Hall east facade</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1996?</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1990-1999</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Tennessee State University Historic District</dc:description>
<dc:description>School</dc:description>
<dc:description>District</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>96000677 listed June 14, 1996</dc:identifier>
<dc:description>3500 John A. Merritt Blvd, Nashville, Davidson County, Nashville</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Nashville, Davidson County, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>36.165787,-86.831614</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>View of the Harned Building from the east, showing its placement on the street with the Industrial Arts building in the background. The three-story building is constructed of red  brick with a flat roof with parapet. The eleven-bay facade is divided by a second story string course. The second and third stories are marked by seven central bays with a limestone veneer. The first story facade is highlighted by three centrally placed and slightly recessed entrances. A limestone belt-course divides the first story from the second and third stories. The seven centrally located bays of the second and third stories are identical in appearance.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Tennessee State University was established in 1912 as the Tennessee Agricultural and Industrial State Normal School, the first African-American public institution of higher education in Tennessee.  The land-grant school was built on thirty-five acres with an additional ninety-five acres dedicated for a demonstration farm. It was established by the Tennessee Legislature in the same period that normal schools were established for white students in each region of the state. It's creation also reflects a response to Booker T. Washington's "Tuskegee Idea" for Negro industrial education. A particular emphasis was placed on education of public school teachers.
The three original campus buildings have been demolished. The seven buildings included in the TSU Historic District were  constructed between 1915 and 1949 along Centennial Blvd: Goodwill Manor (1915); Learning Resource Center (1927); Harned Science Hall (c.1927); Jane E. Elliot Building (1932); Administrative and Health Building (1933); Industrial Arts Building (1933); and Engineering Building (1943-1949). Several of the buildings were designed by McKissack and McKissack, a prominent African-American architectural firm in Nashville. All of the buildings were constructed of red brick with limestone elements.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Tennessee State University; Historic districts</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Historic buildings; Schools; Universities &amp; colleges</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>35 mm slide</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Credit Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University; Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>TSU002</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll4/id/3077</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>