<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Alvin C. York Agricultural Institute</dc:title>
<dc:rights>While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law.  Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:subject>Educational facilities; Schools; Education</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Education - Tennessee; Education - History - Tennessee; School buildings - Tennessee; Alvin C. York Agricultural Institute</dc:subject>
<dc:description>Front view of York Institute in Fentress County.  It is a large brick or stone building set amid pines, and has multiple windows and a low sloped roof.  The words "York Institute" are laid out on the grass in the foreground.</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Jamestown (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:date>undated</dc:date>
<dc:source>State Board of Education Records, 1815-1958</dc:source>
<dc:source>Photographs</dc:source>
<dc:description>Famed World War I hero Alvin Cullum York (1887-1964) raised funds in order to provide impoverished Fentress County boys and girls the education that had been denied him.  The result was a private agricultural school that operated from 1926 to 1937.  In 1937, the General Assembly transferred operations to the State Board of Education.</dc:description>
<dc:relation>RG 91</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>33319</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>IMAGE</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:relation>http://www.tennessee.gov/tsla/history/state/recordgroups/findingaids/rg91.pdf</dc:relation>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/schoolhouses/id/32</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>