<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Highlander Folk School: Communist Training School</dc:title>
<dc:description>Newspaper from Georgia Commission on Education referring to Highlander Folk School as a "communist training school." The centerfold shows pictures of training workshops, musical sessions, and dancing at Highlander. This piece of segregationist propaganda enraged white supremacist groups which led to the investigation of Highlander by the Tennessee General Assembly.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The Georgia Commission on Education was an arm of the Georgia state legislature established to preserve segregation. Many segregationists labeled desegregation attempts as communist, a popular attack of the era.</dc:description>
<dc:source>GP 48: Governor Buford Ellington Papers, 1959-1963</dc:source>
<dc:source>GP 48</dc:source>
<dcterms:references>https://sos-tn-gov-files.tnsosfiles.com/forms/GOVERNOR_BUFORD_ELLINGTON_PAPERS_1959-1963.pdf?JrsB2frhYm4xik026QTwP0jUxO3G5JY4</dcterms:references>
<dc:subject>Highlander Folk School (Monteagle, Tenn.); Communism; Civil rights; Governmental investigations; Education; Leadership; Koinonia Community; Race relations; United States. Congress. House. Committee on Un-American Activities; Southern Regional Council; Southern Conference for Human Welfare; Subversive activities; American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born; American Youth Congress; Civil rights--Congresses; International Labor Defense; National Federation for Constitutional Liberties; League of Struggle for Negro Rights (U.S.); Methodist Federation for Social Action (U.S.); National Negro Congress (U.S.); National Negro Labor Council (U.S.); Segregation; Segregation--Law and legislation; Race discrimination; School integration; Civil disobedience; Boycotts; Boycotts--Alabama; Civil rights workers; National Association for the Advancement of Colored People; Southern Conference for Human Welfare; Communism and education</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>46132</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Box 72, Folder 8</dc:source>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Highlander Folk School</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dcterms:medium>Newspaper</dcterms:medium>
<dc:rights>Copyright not evaluated: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/highlander/id/1270</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>