<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Champions of Democracy</dc:title>
<dc:description>Pamphlet on citizenship activities at Highlander by Septima Clark.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Septima Poinsette Clark, educator and civil rights leader, was born in Charleston, South Carolina in 1898. Her father was born enslaved, and even by the time Septima was born, the city was strictly segregated. Clark grew up poor, having to babysit to afford primary school. After graduating from high school, she taught school on John's Island as black teachers were barred from teaching in Charleston's public schools. She first joined the NAACP in 1919 and fought for equal pay for black teachers in South Carolina for many years, finally securing a court victory in 1945. She obtained her Bachelors and Masters degrees and studied under W. E. B. Du Bois during the summers. She was hired as director of workshops at Highlander in 1954 and continued until she was arrested and the school padlocked in 1959. Afterwards she continued teaching citizenship schools across the South with both Highlander and the Southern Christian Leadership Conference. She retired from the SCLC in 1970. Septima Clark died in 1987. Highlander Research and Education Center's new education center is named in honor of Clark.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Clark, Septima Poinsette, 1898-1987</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Highlander Folk School (Monteagle, Tenn.)</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>Highlander Folk School Manuscript Collection, 1932-1966</dc:source>
<dc:source>1811</dc:source>
<dcterms:references>https://sos-tn-gov-files.tnsosfiles.com/forms/HIGHLANDER_FOLK_SCHOOL_MANUSCRIPT_COLLECTION_1932-1966.pdf</dcterms:references>
<dc:subject>Highlander Folk School (Monteagle, Tenn.); Literacy tests (Election law); Civil rights; Citizenship--Study and teaching; Clark, Septima Poinsette, 1898-1987; White Citizens councils; National Association for the Advancement of Colored People; Johns Island (S.C.); Voting; Jenkins, Esau, 1910-1972; Civil rights workers; Civil rights movements</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>46190</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>VI-D-1, Box 12, Folder 2</dc:source>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Highlander Folk School</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dcterms:medium>Pamphlets</dcterms:medium>
<dc:rights>Copyright not evaluated: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/highlander/id/1718</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>