<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Porter Linder Part 1</dc:title>
<dc:description>Audio files of Fentress County resident Porter Linder recorded as part of the Tennessee State Parks Folklife Project. Tales of Stearns Logging illustrate the commercial logging that came to the Big South Fork area between 1900 and 1920. The logging camps, logging trains, and large-scale operations of Michigan-based Stearns Coal and Lumber Company are conveyed.  Linder speaks of the tragic 1933 lumber camp shooting sparked by Jerome Boyatt that rocked the Big South Fork area and resulted in five deaths.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Linder's contribution illustrates the impact commercial lumber and coal ventures of northern investors had on areas like Scott, Pickett, and Fentress Counties.  The Tennessee State Parks Folklife Project began in 1979 under the direction of Park Ranger Bobby Fulcher and continued until 1983.  Each summer during those years, three folklorists were stationed in Tennessee's state parks.  From those bases, they conducted interviews, took photographs, and recorded music with local tradition-bearers.</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Fentress County (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:date>1979 June 9</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>Division of Parks and Recreation</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Parks Folklife Project Collection, 1979-1984</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Logging; Personal narratives</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Bootlegging; Photographs; Lynchings</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Allen, Ray</dc:creator>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>39629</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>Sound</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/wav</dc:format>
<dc:rights>While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll21/id/193</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>