<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:dltn="https://github.com/digitallibraryoftennessee" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Political cartoon depicting the election of 1844</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/">No Copyright - United States</accessCondition>
  <location>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll43/id/6</url>
    <url access="preview">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p15138coll43/id/6</url>
    <url note="iiif-manifest">https://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/iiif/info/p15138coll43/6/manifest.json</url>
  </location>
  <abstract>A colored lithograph and pro-Whig political cartoon which depicts the nominees in the presidential election of 1844 in a footrace to the White House on Pennsylvania Avenue. The cartoon shows Whig nominee Henry Clay leading the race, with James K. Polk lagging behind and stumbling in a pothole. Incumbent president John Tyler lags behind Polk. Tyler subsequently withdrew in August, from the race. In the foreground offering comments are vice presidential candidate Theodore Frelinghuysen, and Whig senator Daniel Webster. The cartoon identifies the "Stakes" at $25,000.</abstract>
  <abstract>During the presidential election of 1844, the annexation of Texas and the expansion of slavery was a major issue. The Whig Party nominee, Henry Clay, adopted an anti-annexation platform on the principle of preserving the North-South sectional unity and to avoid war by respecting Mexico's claims to Texas. The Democrats nominated James K. Polk, who ran on a platform that embraced America's popular commitment to territorial expansion which was referred to as Manifest Destiny. During the presidential campaign, Polk successfully linked the United States-British boundary dispute over the partition of Oregon Territory with the Texas annexation debate. By doing so, Polk united the anti-slavery Northern expansionists, who demanded Oregon as free from slavery with pro-slavery Southern expansionists, who insisted on acquiring Texas as a slave state. After a hard fought campaign, James K. Polk was elected as the eleventh president of the United States.</abstract>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated>1844</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Tennessee State Library and Archives</recordContentSource>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
  </recordInfo>
  <subject>
    <topic>Polk, James Knox, --1795 - 1849</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Presidents</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Presidents--Election</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Political cartoons</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Political Cartoons</topic>
  </subject>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Library Photograph Collection, Oversize</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Tennessee State Library and Archives</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <physicalDescription>
    <form>Political cartoons</form>
    <form>Cartoons</form>
  </physicalDescription>
  <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
</mods>
