<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Concrete pipes manufactured by the Civilian Conservation Corps for use in forest road construction</dc:title>
<dc:rights>While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law.  Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:subject>Pipes (Conduits); Forests</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Civilian Conservation Corps (U.S.); New Deal, 1933-1939; Pipe -- Hydrodynamics; Roads -- Design and construction</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Pickett State Forest (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>A man inspecting a concrete pipe manufactured by the Civilian Conservation Corps for use in constructing forest roads.  Five rows of pipes are visible, the second of which has planks of wood, presumably for rolling the heavy concrete pipes in order to stack them.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1940 September 11</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Tennessee -- Dept. of Conservation</dc:creator>
<dc:source>RG 82, Department of Conservation Photograph Collection</dc:source>
<dc:description>With the purpose of relieving unemployment, the Civilian Conservation Corps was created in 1933, and was expanded by Congress in 1937.  During this expansion, the Civilian Conservation Corps added vocation training and remedial education programs.  The Corps employed young men to perform structural improvements to bridges and roads; erosion and flood control; and various conservation work projects.  The Corps was instrumental in the infrastructure of the Tennessee State Parks System and National Parks in Tennessee.</dc:description>
<dc:relation>CV2569</dc:relation>
<dc:relation>RG 82</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>17414</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>IMAGE</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:relation>http://www.tn.gov/tsla/history/state/recordgroups/findingaids/rg82.pdf</dc:relation>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll7/id/89</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>