<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Mt. Zion AME Church</dc:title>
<dc:date>1880</dc:date>
<dc:date>2011</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Finding Community</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Religious Institutions</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African American churches</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Centerville</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Hickman County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of a single story white clapboard building, with a low white concrete block ell extending from the back right side. The church has a front gable roof, with an entrance tower on the right side, and concrete block foundation. Four concrete steps lead to a pair of gray paneled doors on the lower level of the tower. Over the entry porch is a shallow, shed roof with a metal eave a few feet above.  The tower is topped by a quadrilateral metal roof. The front fa&#231;ade has two double-hung, eight-over-eight light windows. A cement sidewalk leads through the lawn to the entrance.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Mt. Zion AME Church in Centerville, Tennessee is a good example of the small, historic African American churches that still dot the rural landscape in Tennessee.  The church has been a vibrant part of the community, hosting both religious services and allowing African American fraternal groups to use the building. In the 1880s, the church started a high school for African Americans. Classes met at the church, and the school was known as the Centreville Male and Female Academy.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator. Reproduced with permission</dc:rights>
<dc:relation>Photograph by Leigh Ann Gardner</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/138</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>