<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Baseball Team, Tennessee State Technical &amp; Agricultural School for Colored Boys, Pikeville</dc:title>
<dc:date>n.d.</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Finding Community; Performing Identity</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Athletes; Schools</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African American baseball players; African American schools; African American students</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Pikeville</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Bledsoe County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Sixteen young men, standing in two rows outside of a plaster-covered building. Fifteen are wearing baseball caps and uniforms  with the letters S.T.A.S. across the front; one wears a plain uniform. There is a man with a plain uniform and no cap at front center, holding a bat atop a pile of baseball gloves. An older man wearing a plain uniform and a hat with brim stands between the rows at far left.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The State of Tennessee created several "state training schools" or reform schools for teenaged offenders.  Originally called the school for "negro boys," this school on the Cumberland Plateau, just up the mountain from Pikeville, was later renamed the Tennessee State Technical &amp; Agricultural  School for Colored Boys. This image of a baseball team, posed against the wall of a modern-looking building, probably dates from after 1945, as facilities at the school were remodeled and upgraded about that time. The posed photograph seems designed to give the impression that recreational activities were a regular part of life for the young inmates.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation>Courtesy of Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact the Tennessee State Library and Archives.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/247</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>