<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Tennessee General Assembly, composite photograph of the 42nd legislature</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Schleier</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1881</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Embracing Citizenship</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Civic Engagement</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African American legislators; Legislators</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Nashville</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Davidson County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Head and shoulders photographs arranged to form a group portrait in the shape of a flat oval placed against a rectangular background. Images are numbered and names keyed to a list below the group portrait.</dc:description>
<dc:description>This composite portrait represents Tennessee's 42nd General Assembly, which served from 1881-1882. Four of Tennessee's earliest African American state representatives can be found grouped together at far left in this image. Not pictured here is Sampson Wesley Keeble (1833-1857), the first African American elected to the Tennessee General Assembly. Keeble served one term only, in the 38th legislature, from 1873-1874. There were no African American legislators elected to three subsequent General Assemblies, the 39th, 40th, and 41st. The African American members of the 42nd General Assembly can be located by number written on the image in white lettering:  59, Thomas A. Sykes (1838-ca.1895), Davidson County; 61, Thomas Frank Cassels (ca. 1845-1903), Shelby County; 62, Isham Franklin Norris (1851-1928), Shelby County; and 63, John William Boyd (ca. 1850-1932), Tipton County.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation>Courtesy of Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact the Tennessee State Library and Archives.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/262</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>