<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Blount Mansion</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Delaney, Joseph</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1930s</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Performing Identity</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Artists</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Knoxville</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Knox County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>This black and white drawing shows a white woman holding the hand of a child walking on the sidewalk in front of a two-story frame house towards a flag pole and American flag flying out front. The house has brick chimneys on either end, a side addition with brick chimney, and is surrounded by a picket fence.  Scribbled lines depict utility wires, trees in the front yard, clouds in the sky, and with a 1930s-era automobile parked on the street in front. Partially visible at lower left is a car parked on the side street and a white man wearing a hat.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Artist Joseph Delaney 1904-1991) moved to New York in 1930 and lived and worked there for many years. He may have made this drawing on a visit home to Knoxville, Tennessee.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:format>Art original</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Beck Cultural Exchange Center</dc:publisher>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects, contact the Beck Cultural Exchange Center.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/163</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>