<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Community School Plan</dc:title>
<dc:title>Rosenwald School Plan</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Samuel L. Smith and Fletcher B. Dressler</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1921</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Finding Community</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Schools</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African American schools; Julius Rosenwald Fund -- Buildings; School buildings</dc:subject>
<dc:description>A floor plan for a five teacher school as part of the Community School Plans developed by Samuel L. Smith and Fletcher B. Dressler for the Rosenwald Fund.</dc:description>
<dc:description>In 1921, Samuel L. Smith and Fletcher B. Dressler published the first official Community School Plans bulletin for use by the Rosenwald Fund.  These plans derived from earlier plans Smith had developed in the 1910s and that had already been used in some Rosenwald Schools.  The plans show Smith and Dressler's belief in the importance of simplicity of design, the use of natural lighting, and the importance of sanitation.  The plans oriented buildings as to maximize natural light, using banks of tall, narrow windows to provide adequate lighting for students.  In addition to providing lighting, the windows also provided ventilation for the classroom and allowed for the circulation of air. The plans were designed for simplicity to make them affordable for local school boards to implement.  The plans were offered without cost to both white and African American schools across the South, leading to the construction of many rural schools using these plans.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/245</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>