<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Waiting for the bus at the Memphis terminal</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Bubley, Esther, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1943</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Claiming Space</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Transportation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African Americans; Segregation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Bus terminals; Buses</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Memphis</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Shelby County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Black and white photograph taken from a high vantage point of a mixed crowd of black and white passengers in the outdoor area of a bus terminal. In bay number 3 is a bus with a placard for Chattanooga. Visible above the heads of passengers is a sign for "White Waiting Room."</dc:description>
<dc:description>This image shows a crowd in the Memphis terminal, September 1943, during a Greyhound bus trip from Louisville, Kentucky, to Memphis, Tennessee. It was taken by Esther Bubley (1921-1998), a young photographer who had been hired by Roy Stryker, formerly at the Farm Security Administration, who had just been appointed to direct photography for the Office of War Information. Bubley spent four weeks riding buses on a route that include Pittsburgh, Indianapolis, Chicago, Columbus, Cincinnati, Louisville, Memphis, Nashville and Chattanooga before heading back to Washington. One of the reasons for the series was to document the increase in bus travel due to wartime rationing of gasoline and tires.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Library of Congress</dc:publisher>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/101</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>