<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Flagg Grove School</dc:title>
<dc:date>2014</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Finding Community</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Schools</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African American schools</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Haywood County</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Haywood County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Photograph of the Flagg Grove School, a front-gable, unpainted, frame building, now relocated to the grounds of the West Tennessee Delta Heritage Center, Brownsville,Tennessee</dc:description>
<dc:description>The Flagg Grove School was an African American school formerly located in Nutbush, iThe Flagg Grove School was an African American school formerly located in Nutbush, in Haywood County.  It was moved to Brownsville, Tennessee in 2012 and restored with help from the owners of the farm on which it stood for over one hundred years. This school was the childhood school of Tina Turner (born Anna Mae Bullock).  Flagg Grove School was built on land purchased in 1889 from former slave Benjamin Flagg, who was Bullock's great uncle. The school was closed in 1968, and is a good example of the one-room schoolhouses used by African American children across the state well into the late 1960s. The building is now located at the West Tennessee Delta Heritage Center in Brownsville, Haywood County.n Haywood County.  It was moved to Brownsville, Tennessee in 2012.  This school was the childhood school of Tina Turner.  Flagg Grove School was originally built on land purchased from former slave Benjamin Flagg in 1899.  Flagg was a great uncle of Tina Turner. The school was closed in 1968, and is a good example of the one-room schoolhouses used by African American children across the state well into the late 1960s. The building is now located at the West Tennessee Delta Heritage Center in Brownsville, Haywood County.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/148</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>