<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Lincoln Rosenwald School</dc:title>
<dc:date>1930</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Finding Community</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Schools</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African American schools; African American students; African American school principals</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Pikeville</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Bledsoe County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Historic photograph of the Lincoln School, which has been inscribed with name and date, and listing of students and principal E. Angel (back row).</dc:description>
<dc:description>Beginning in 1912, the Rosenwald Fund contributed matching funds for the construction of thousands of schools for African Americans across the South. Built in 1925, the Lincoln School is an excellent example of the standardized architecture of the schools that were specified in the Community School Plans. The Rosenwald Fund provided $900 for the construction of the Lincoln School, Pikeville's African American community provided $1,200, Bledsoe County and the State of Tennessee provided $3236 for its construction.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/152</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>