<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Knoxville College Hospital</dc:title>
<dc:date>1915</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Achieving Recognition</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Medical Profession</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African Americans -- Hospitals</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Knoxville</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Knox County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Two-story brick building with a pyramid roof, central dormer window, double hung windows with slightly arched sashes, two brick chimneys, and central entry through a front porch supported by four classical order columns. The building appears to have a side addition of similar brick construction, with front porches on both levels across the width of the building. A utility pole stands on the street out front and wires are visible running to the buildings.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Knoxville College established a medical school in 1895 to train physicians and also to provide medical care for African Americans. The school struggled with inadequate staffing and facilities and closed in 1900 after graduating only two students: N.B. Crenshaw and J.G. King. Recognizing the ongoing need for professional medical education, Dr. Henry Morgan Green, a graduate of Knoxville College with a degree from Northwestern University, was one of the founders of the Knoxville Medical College that same year. In its ten years of operation, the school prepared twenty-one doctors for the profession. However the need for a hospital continued--the Knoxville General Hospital opened in 1902 provided only two basement wards for African Americans and prohibited black physicians from attending patients. Eliza B. Wallace left money to Knoxville College to build a hospital on the campus as a facility to train nurses. The modern two-story building that opened in 1907 was built by Knoxville College students and constructed using student-made bricks. The wing for contagious diseases was added in 1915. Not only did it provide a well-equipped training facility for nurses, the hospital attracted more African American physicians to Knoxville. When the hospital closed in 1926, there were twenty black doctors in Knoxville.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Beck Cultural Exchange Center</dc:publisher>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects, contact the Beck Cultural Exchange Center.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/125</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>