<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Evidences of the Progress of a Race</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Green, Henry Morgan</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1929</dc:date>
<dc:source>Wilson, Bartow G., Charles W. Cansler, and Henry Morgan Green. The Knoxville Negro: Emphasizing the Great Era of Progress Prevalent in Negro Knoxville Today. Knoxville [Tenn.]: Trent Printing Co., 1929.</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Achieving Recognition</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>National Leaders</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African Americans</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Knoxville</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Knox County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Essay by Dr. Henry Morgan Green in The Knoxville Negro, published by Trent Printing Co. 2104 Magnolia Ave. Knoxville, Tenn. U.S.A., June 1929 </dc:description>
<dc:description>In the opening essay for this promotional booklet, Dr. Henry Morgan Green, a pioneering Knoxville physician and esteemed community leader, assessed the social and material growth of Knoxville's African American population. Green was well-qualified to analyze the city's progress, having graduated from Knoxville College, helped found a short-lived medical college there, and been successful in his own medical practice. He also chaired the Negro Department at the Appalachian Exposition of 1910, at which a handsome separate building, designed and built by African Americans, was erected to house exhibits related to African American accomplishments. In this essay, Green lays out what he sees as four important measures of progress that would place Knoxville in the forefront of American cities of the period: moral worth (the number of churches and congregations); intellectual achievement (notable educational institutions); material growth (home and business ownership); and industrial application. Of the latter, he wrote "Knoxville through its multitudinous industrial activities, furnishes an abundance of opportunities for gainful occupation . . . because of the cordial race relations existing, he [the Knoxville Negro] has access to all kinds of classes of labor..."</dc:description>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:format>Essay</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/263</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>