<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>National Conservation Exposition at Chilhowee Park, 1913. Knoxville, TN. September 25, 1913. Negro Building.</dc:title>
<dc:title>Negro Building, Chilhowee Park, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Thompson Brothers Photographers</dc:creator>
<dc:contributor>Green, Dr. Henry; Knoxville College</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1913</dc:date>
<dc:date>1910</dc:date>
<dc:date>1913-09-25</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Claiming Space</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Leisure</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African American architects; African Americans; Fairs; Parks</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States - Tennessee -- Knoxville</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Knox County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>White building on a wooded site facing a lake, with "Negro Building" placard over the doorway and two United States flags flying from rooftop. Women in long white dresses, men in dark suits and hats, and children are walking about.
</dc:description>
<dc:description>The National Conservation Exposition, held in Knoxville's Chilhowee Park in 1913, was the third and grandest of the three early twentieth century expositions held in Knoxville. The other two, titled Appalachian Expositions (1910 and 1911), had had a more regional focus, while this one attracted a larger number of business, industry, and early conservation-minded citizens to the increasingly prosperous city that was promoting itself as not only a business and railroad center but as an attractive destination for recreation and leisure in the mountains of East Tennessee. The "Negro Building" was was designed by the head of the mechanical department at Knoxville College and constructed by students in that department. Dr. Henry Green directed the exhibits and the "Negro Department" of the 1910 exposition. </dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation>Thompson Photograph Collection, McClung Historical Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects, contact the McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/287</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>