<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Group of African Americans being transferred to jail in Nashville</dc:title>
<dc:date>1946</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Embracing Citizenship</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Military Service</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African Americans; Riots</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Firearms; Jails; Men; Police</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Nashville</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Davidson County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>A group of African Americans being transferred to Nashville for safety during the Columbia Race Riot of 1946. Armed police line the outside of the jail with weapons drawn.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The Columbia Race Riot took place in Columbia, Tennessee on the night of February 25-26, 1946. An African American U.S. Navy veteran became involved in an altercation with a white store clerk. Arrested and charged initially with disturbing the peace, James Stephenson, was later charged with intent to commit murder. Released on bond, Stephenson returned home and a white mob gathered at the Maury County Courthouse. By the end of the night, two African American men were killed while in police custody, the entire African American business district had been ransacked by whites, weapons had been confiscated from African Americans, and African Americans were arrested without warrants. More than 100 African Americans were arrested, and none were granted bail or allowed legal counsel.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Nashville Public Library, Special Collections</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects, contact the Nashville Public Library.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/195</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>