<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Swimming pool at Lincoln Park</dc:title>
<dc:date>1940s</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Claiming Space</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Leisure</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African Americans; Swimming pools</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Chattanooga</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Hamilton County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>The swimming pool at Lincoln Park, the African American park in Chattanooga.</dc:description>
<dc:description>In 1918, Chattanooga opened its first public park for African Americans, a ten acre park with a center fountain. In 1938, a swimming pool was opened at the park. The park grew to include a mini-zoo, a Ferris Wheel, a dance hall, and a baseball field. The park had the first lighted softball fields for African Americans in the South. The Chattanooga Choo-Choos, an African American baseball team, played many games at Lincoln Park. The pool was closed in 1996, and the city gave the park to Erlanger Hospital in 1979. During the height of its popularity, Lincoln Park drew African Americans from as far away as Birmingham and Atlanta.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Bessie Smith Cultural Center</dc:publisher>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects, contact the Bessie Smith Cultural Center.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/206</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>