<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Certificate of Appointment, Governor W.G. Brownlow to J.C. Napier</dc:title>
<dc:date>1868</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Achieving Recognition</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>National Leaders</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Davidson County</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Davidson County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Stamped with the Great Seal of Tennessee on certificate bearing the legend "State of Tennessee" with an engraving of the Tennessee State Capitol at top center, this document, dated 25 April 1868, appoints J.C. Napier as County Claim Commissioner for Davidson County.
</dc:description>
<dc:description>James C. Napier was born to free parents in Nashville in 1845. Young James attended a free black school in Nashville until the disruption caused by the Civil War. With the children of several other free black families, he went to Ohio to continue his education.
On his return to Nashville, he heard an Emancipation Day speech by John Mercer Langston, a prominent Ohio free black and a friend of Napier's father, who visited Nashville on December 30, 1864. The young Napier became involved in local Republican politics, as this certificate of appointment to a post in the Reconstruction administration of  Tennessee's Republican Governor, William Gannaway Brownlow, attests. At Langston's invitation, Napier left Nashville a year or so later to attend Howard Law School in Washington, D.C., from which he graduated in 1872.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Ephemera</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Fisk University, John Hope and Aurelia E. Franklin Library, Special Collections</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation>Fisk University, John Hope and Aurelia E. Franklin Library, Special Collections, James C. Napier Collection, Box 2, folder 7</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing organization. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact the Fisk University Franklin Library, Special Collections, Nashville, Tennessee.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/55</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>