<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Aaron Douglas mural above the door, Cravath Hall</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Douglas, Aaron </dc:creator>
<dc:date>1930s</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Performing Identity</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Artists</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Mural painting and decoration</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Nashville</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Davidson County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>A photograph of a long mural over a doorway and bookshelves, with an image of Jubilee Hall at far left, and a procession of silhouetted figures growing larger in stature, from left to right, including the profile of a graduate in mortar board and robe, as well as a woman with hand on a large globe, a male figure looking through a microscope and others. The mural is in one of the reading rooms of Cravath Hall, which formerly housed the library at Fisk University.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Aaron Douglas, born in Topeka, Kansas, in 1898, was one of the leading visual artists of the Harlem Renaissance. He was commissioned in 1930 to paint a series of murals in Cravath Hall at Fisk University. These murals depict African American contributions to American history and society. He returned to Fisk University as a professor in the late 1930s and founded the Art Department. Douglas died in Nashville in 1979.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>Art original</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Nashville Public Library, Special Collections</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation>Nashville Public Library, Special Collections</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact the Nashville Public Library.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/141</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>