<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Helen Mae Lennon Hospital record book</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Lennon, Edgar F.</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1923</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Achieving Recognition</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Medical Profession</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African Americans -- Hospitals; Medical records</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Knoxville</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Knox County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Handwritten entries on patient admissions and care from day one, January 6, 1923.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Dr. Edgar F. Lennon was the owner and operator of the Helen Mae Lennon Hospital on Clinch Street, which had twenty-five beds and also a training facility for nurses. This ledger contains notes on various patients signed by Lennon, as well as S(amuel) M. Clark, another prominent early physician in Knoxville.Lennon practiced medicine from 1917 to 1966. Clark was one of the founders of the East Tennessee Hospital Association in 1929, the group largely responsible for beginning a movement to found a separate "Negro Unit" at Knoxville General Hospital. The wing was completed in 1933, with funding from the Rosenwald Fund, the City of Knoxville, Knox County, and the East Tennessee Hospital Association.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>University of Tennessee, Knoxville -- Libraries</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation>University of Tennessee, Knoxville -- Libraries</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only.  All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact the University of Tennessee, Knoxville - Libraries.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/137</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>