<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Zinc Company Negro Baseball League</dc:title>
<dc:date>1930s</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Performing Identity; Claiming Space</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Athletes; Work</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African American baseball players</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Jefferson City</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Jefferson County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Twelve middle-aged African American men in plain baseball uniforms with baseball caps, posed in two rows (5 men standing, 7 men seated) out of doors.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The Zinc Company Baseball League, from Jefferson City, Tennessee, played in the old Negro League. According to the Tennessee Encyclopedia of History &amp; Culture &lt;http://tennesseeencyclopedia.net&gt;,the first zinc mining in Tennessee occurred at Mossy Creek, near Jefferson City, in 1854. After the early surface mines were exhausted, the zinc industry developed large underground operations in Knox, Jefferson, Hawkins, Hancock, and Grainger Counties. The industry was one of the highest producers nationally in the 1960s, and its modern production depends on a small number of large operators around Mascot, in the Jefferson City area. The American Zinc Company came to Mascot in 1915. The East Tennessee Zinc Company is still producing in Jefferson City.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation>Courtesy of the Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects, contact the Tennessee State Library and Archives.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/112</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>