<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>People sitting on a bus</dc:title>
<dc:subject>Claiming Space</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Transportation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Segregation in transportation; African Americans</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Buses; Men; Women</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Chattanooga</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Hamilton County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Interior of a bus with white persons sitting in the first three rows and African Americans seated behind and on the bench seat back of the bus. A sign stenciled in black lettering on the back wall above bench seat reads "This part of bus for Colored Race 416." Several of the African American passengers, including the front-most woman, a man two rows behind her, and the man seated in the center of the bench seat, look directly at the photographer, the white woman and man in first rows are not in focus, and another white woman looks away and out of the window.</dc:description>
<dc:description>"Jim Crow" public bus in Chattanooga, Tennessee, showing segregation of passengers: whites in front, blacks in back, and stenciled sign stating that the back of the bus was for the "Colored Race."</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Chattanooga Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation>Picture File, Local History Room. From the Chattanooga Publishing Co. Collection, Chattanooga Public Library</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects, contact the</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/167</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>