<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Chesapeake, Ohio &amp; Southwestern Railroad Company v Ida B. Wells</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Greer &amp; Adams</dc:creator>
<dc:contributor>Cassels, T.F.</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1885</dc:date>
<dc:source>Tennessee Supreme Court</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Claiming Space</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Transportation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Segregation in transportation -- United States -- Cases; Wells-Barnett, Ida B., -- 1862-1931; African American women civil rights workers</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Memphis</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Shelby County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Cover of a published legal brief filed by Greer &amp; Adams and T.F. Cassels, and sections 19-23 of transcribed testimony regarding a case before the Tennessee Supreme Court in April 1885.</dc:description>
<dc:description>On September 15th 1883, twenty-year old, Fisk University-educated, school teacher Ida B. Wells purchased a  ticket for a trip by train from Memphis to Woodstock (ten miles north of Memphis), where she was teaching at a public school. She chose a seat in the rear car with white ladies and gentlemen but was forcibly removed and told to move to the forward car, where smoking and drinking were allowed and where black and white passengers rode together. She refused and sought damages in a challenge to Tennessee's 1882 statute, which ordered common carriers to provide "accomodations equal in all respects in comfort and convenience to the first-class cars on the train..." for non-white passengers. The case, in which she was represented by prominent Memphis attorney, Thomas Frank Cassels, a free black who had served in the 42nd Tennessee General Assembly (1881-1883), was appealed to the Tennessee Supreme Court in April 1885. The Court found for the Railroad Company, reversing the earlier decision by the Circuit Court of Shelby County.</dc:description>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Legal case and case notes</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation>Tennessee Supreme Court, RG 170, Courtesy Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact the Tennessee State Library and Archives.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/283</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>