<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Facts Every Negro Should Know about Roosevelt</dc:title>
<dc:date>1940</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Embracing Citizenship</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Voting Rights</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945; Voting</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Memphis</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Shelby County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Four-sheet broadside announcing a Victory Meeting at Church Park Auditorium on Monday Night, Nov. 4, 1940, 8 pm, issued by the Colored Democratic Club, Memphis, Tennessee, Dr. J.E. Walker, Chairman; T.J. Johnson, Director of Publicity</dc:description>
<dc:description>This informational pamphlet, Facts Every Negro Should Know about Roosevelt and the Democratic Administration, has a head shot of Franklin D. Roosevelt on the cover page, with the slogan "Keep Him in Office and Keep the Negro Moving Forward" just below.  The broadside announcing the "victory meeting" has the names of those on the ticket with Roosevelt on the voting date of Tuesday November 5th, including Tennessee candidates K.D. McKellar (U.S. Senate); Governor Prentice Cooper, and Congressman Clifford Davis, as well as Utilities Commissioner Porter Dunlap. Also announced is the promotion of Benjamin Davis to Brigadier General in the U.S. Army, which was touted as an accomplishment of the adminstration. The other pages contain facts and figures about government agency accomplishments that had particularly benefited African Americans, as well as African American appointed officials in various departments.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:format>Broadside</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Memphis and Shelby County Room, Memphis Public Library and Information Center</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation>Courtesy Memphis and Shelby County Room, Memphis Public Library and Information Center http://memphislibrary.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p13039coll5/id/578</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects, contact the Memphis and Shelby County Room, Memphis Public Library and Information Center.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/261</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>