<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Group of African American men in front of the County Clerk's office</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Morgan, John</dc:creator>
<dc:subject>Embracing Citizenship</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Military Service</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African Americans; Trials</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Lawrenceburg</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Lawrence County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>The defendants in the Columbia Race Riot trial standing in front of the County Clerk's office after the verdict in the case was reached.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Future Supreme Court Justice Thurgood Marshall came to Tennessee and headed the defense of the African Americans charged in connection with the Columbia Race Riot. He was assisted in his efforts by Z. Alexander Looby of Nashville and Maurice Weaver of Chattanooga. Marshall and his team were successful in having the judge move the trial from Columbia to Lawrenceburg, and the jury there acquitted 23 of the men and found two of the men guilty on October 4, 1946. On November 18, 1946, one of the two found guilty was acquitted; the other man received a commuted sentence.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Nashville Public Library, Special Collections</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation>Nashville Public Library, Special Collections</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects, contact the Nashville Public Library.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/175</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>