<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>York Institute</dc:title>
<dc:date>1926</dc:date>
<dc:date>2006</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Finding Community</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Schools</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Jamestown</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Fentress County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>This 2006 photograph shows the substantial two story brick school building, with its steep gable roof, central bay entrance door, and flat-roofed addition, in disrepair.  The building has since been stablized and renovated.</dc:description>
<dc:description>World War I hero Alvin Cullum York founded the York Institute in 1926. He went on speaking tours to raise funds to provide the education he had never had, growing up in rural Fentress County, Tennessee, for the boys and girls of coming generations. The school was transferred to the state of Tennessee in 1937. The future of the York Institute was in peril for several years until a successful fund-raising campaign and the efforts of historians and preservationists made it possible to restore the building to use. Today it serves as a public K-12 school in the region.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/157</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>