<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>St. Mark's Presbyterian Church</dc:title>
<dc:date>1912</dc:date>
<dc:date>2013</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Finding Community</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Religious Institutions</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African American churches</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Rogersville</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Hawkins County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>The lower portion of this two-story, front-gable building is red brick, the upper story and the tall square tower with pointed cap on the left side of the building are white clapboard.The building sits on a hill. The steep-pitched front-gable forms a triangular pediment on the facade that is echoed by two small triangular gables over entrance doors located on either side of the facade.  A split stair, which begins as four concrete steps located at street level, leads diagonally away from the central axis to the doors on either side. A square white panel emphasizes the central bay of the facade. It is topped by a bank of four twelve-pane windows, with a pair of two-over-two double hung windows below.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The congregation of St. Mark's Presbyterian Church in Rogersville was established circa 1875. The church was closely associated with Swift Memorial Junior College, founded in 1883 by The Reverend Dr. William H. Franklin. The property for the church was purchased circa 1885 by the Board of Missions for Freedmen to add to the campus.  Reverend Franklin, who was also pastor of St. Mark's Presbyterian, was a native of Knoxville and the first African American graduate of Maryville College. This building was erected circa 1912, the same year that St. Mark's Presbyterian received its charter from the State of Tennessee. It stands today, at the corner of Kyle and N. Hasson Streets, just one block north of West Main Street in downtown Rogersville. The congregation disbanded in 2002.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation>Photograph by Carroll Van West, courtesy of the Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University.</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/145</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>