<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Trenton Rosenwald School</dc:title>
<dc:date>1928</dc:date>
<dc:date>1939</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Finding Community</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Schools</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African American schools; African American students; African American teachers</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Boys; Girls; Men; Students; Teachers; Women</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Trenton</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Gibson County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Black and white photograph of almost two hundred students and faculty standing in front of a single story brick building with a side gable roof. A narrow brick chimney projects through the roofline on the right side. A Spanish Revival style parapet crowns the central bay entry and brick coping extends along the top of the parapet wall extending across the building fa&#231;ade.  A series of narrow windows is partially visible above this roofline. Above the recessed entrance, which leads to double multi-paned doors, is an arched pediment reading: &#8220;Trenton Rosenwald School 1928.&#8221; Bays of three, double-hung, six-over-six light windows flank the entrance bay, with an additional bay containing a single, double-hung, six-over-six light window, on either side. Front projecting wings can be found at both ends of the building, each with a door covered by a shed roof.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The original Trenton Rosenwald School (no longer extant) was built in 1928-1929 as an eight-teacher school at the cost of $14,600.  The Rosenwald Fund provided $2,100 for construction while the rest of the funds came from the African American community and public funds.  This school design was one used for the construction of larger schools.  In 1951, Carrie Booker Seats noted in her thesis about African American schools in Gibson County that the school had become overcrowded and was in the process of being renovated.  At that time, the school had twelve grades and fifteen teachers. The school building was lost to fire in early 1953 and a replacement building, which is currently at this location was built later that same year. The last high school class graduated in 1968 and the building continued in use as an integrated middle school until 1996. Now owned by the Trenton Special School District, the building is now known as the Trenton Community Resource Center. </dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation>Courtesy of the Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact the Tennessee State Library and Archives.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/244</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>