<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Main Street School, Chattanooga</dc:title>
<dc:title>Montgomery Avenue School</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Stokes, David or W. H.</dc:creator>
<dc:subject>Finding Community</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Schools</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African American schools</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Chattanooga</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Hamilton County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Two-story brick building with triple stone arched entry, steep pitched roof with two front gable dormers, side gable dormer also visible on left side, and center steeple with gothic cupola. A low stone wall marks the boundary of the property and utility poles and wires are visible in front of the building. Photograph shows small bare trees out front, and a low modern-looking horizontal structure behind, with a square brick smokestack behind it.  Written at lower left on the photograph "Main Street Colored School" and at lower right "Stokes." David Stokes opened his photography studio, located on Market Street, in 1881. He became known for his visual documentation of landscapes, downtown buildings, battlegrounds, and his work with the railroad. His son, William Henry Stokes, learned the craft in his father&#8217;s studio and shared many commercial assignments in downtown Chattanooga. W.H. Stokes would later open his own studio in East Lake around 1901.  Many historic photographs of Chattanooga bear the Stokes name.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Originally named Montgomery Avenue School, this photograph shows what became known as the Main Street School after Montgomery Avenue became Main Street.  In 1881, this public school, originally housed in a church building, became the first in Chattanooga to have an African American teacher assigned to teach African American students. The circa 1890s building shown here was built to accomodate Chattanooga's growing African American population, as were East Fifth Street  and East Eighth Street Schools.  </dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Chattanooga History Center</dc:publisher>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing organization. For research inquiries about specific objects, contact the Chattanooga History Center.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/67</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>