<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>John and Calvin and Barlow Roberts</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Free Hill Community Center</dc:creator>
<dc:contributor>Tennessee Folklore Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:subject>Finding Community; Performing Identity</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Musicians; Schools</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African American musicians; African American men</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Free Hill</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Clay County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>African American three-piece string band, two older men with fiddles, a younger man in center with banjo, seated outside in straight back wooden chairs against an unpainted frame structure.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Free Hill, a neighborhood containing homes, a church and cemetery, and a former Rosenwald School, located on a hill near Celina, Tennessee, is a historically African American-owned community. There is an intact legacy of old-time string band musicians as well as sacred music associated with Free Hill. The Tennessee Folklore Society, in conjunction with the Tennessee State Parks Folklife Project at the Department of Conservation, recorded an album entitled "Free Hill: A Sound Portrait of a Rural Afro-American Community (TFS 107) in 1983. It included not only musical selections but also historical remembrances and local lore. This photograph of members of the Barlow family is on display in the Free Hill Community Center, a well-preserved example of a two-room Rosenwald School.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/238</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>