<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Knoxville College Chemistry Building</dc:title>
<dc:date>1940s</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Embracing Citizenship</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Public Education</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African American college students; African American universities and colleges; African American men; African American women</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Knoxville</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Knox County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Coeducational class of African American students standing at laboratory benches in a brick walled room, with a shelf holding clear glass bottles at rear, and a white man in a suit to the left of blackboard.</dc:description>
<dc:description>In the 1890s, when Knoxville College had a medical department, chemistry had been part of the medical curriculum. This modern laboratory, providing instruction in chemistry for students of the 1940s, may have been under the auspices of the University of Tennessee's faculty, per the continuing agreement to provide state-funded equal educational opportunity on separate campuses for African American Tennesseans. It was likely housed in the Mechanical and Industrial Building, or in the Agriculture Building, both of which were brick structures.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Beck Cultural Exchange Center</dc:publisher>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects, contact the Beck Cultural Exchange Center.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/182</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>