<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Hubbard Hospital and Meharry Medical College</dc:title>
<dc:date>1940s</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Achieving Recognition</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Medical profession</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African Americans -- Hospitals; Meharry Medical College</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Nashville</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Davidson County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Meharry Medical College began in 1876 as the medical school of Central Tennessee College, established by the Freedmen's Aid Society. The founder and first president was George W. Hubbard, a former Union soldier. In 1915, Meharry Medical College was granted a charter separate from Central Tennessee College. The college moved to north Nashville, one block from Fisk University, in the late 1920s, and its new buildings adopted the collegiate gothic style of architecture found on the neighboring Fisk campus. Meharry Medical College grew to include a School of Dentistry, a School of Medicine, and a School of Nursing, as well as other departments. Meharry Medical College continues to educate health care professionals.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Nashville Public Library, Special Collections</dc:publisher>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects, contact the Nashville Public Library.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/270</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>