<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>LeMoyne College Library, Steele Hall</dc:title>
<dc:title>Library Interior, LeMoyne College</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hooks Brothers Photographers</dc:creator>
<dc:subject>Finding Community</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Schools</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African American college students; African American universities and colleges; College buildings</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Memphis</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Shelby County</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>35.1194098,-90.0356423</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Scene of male and female students seated at rectangular library tables inside a large open room with a bookshelves lining the walls and a central circulation desk under an archway. Double-hung twelve over twelve pane windows are visible on two sides of the room.  Printed on image at bottom right: Hooks Bros. Photographers, 228 Linden Avenue, Memphis, Tenn.</dc:description>
<dc:description>In 1914, the school was moved from Orleans Street to its present site on Walker Avenue. Steele Hall, completed circa 1908, is the oldest building on campus. It originally housed the college library, which now occupies a modern building nearby.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the creator</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>LeMoyne-Owen College</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation>Courtesy LeMoyne-Owen College Library Special Collections</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects, contact LeMoyne-Owen College.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/293</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>