<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>First Baptist Church Lauderdale</dc:title>
<dc:title>First Colored Baptist Church</dc:title>
<dc:date>1939</dc:date>
<dc:date>2000</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Finding Community</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Religious Institutions</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African American churches</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Memphis</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Shelby County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of corner view of two-story red brick, Greek Revival style church. The entrance portico is a white pediment supported by four Doric columns. The pediment has a central circular window. Stone steps lead to a three-bay fa&#231;ade with two white doors and a double-hung window on the lower level and three double-hung windows above. The front lawn and a stone wall at street level are visible in foreground.</dc:description>
<dc:description>First Baptist Church, Lauderdale, is considered one of the most significant African American churches in Memphis and in West Tennessee.  The congregation was begun in 1854 by Morris Henderson.  This congregation built the First Baptist Beale church building.   The congregation split in 1894, and the First Colored Baptist Church, as it was known, moved out of their church building on Beale Street to Zion Hall, also located on Beale Street.  In 1906, the congregation moved to a site on St. Paul Avenue.  In the 1930s, the area was condemned and the neighborhood demolished.  At that time, the congregation moved to South Lauderdale Street, building the church building depicted here.  The church enjoyed a long association with Booker T. Washington High School, an African American high school located across the street. This congregation is considered the "mother church" for many of the African American Baptist congregations in Memphis and West Tennessee.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects, contact the Center for Historic Preservation.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/190</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>