<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Uncle Sam's Helping Hand Quilt</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Bond, Ruth Clement, designer; Cooper, Rose Lee, quiltmaker</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1934</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Claiming Space</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Work</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Quilts</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Knoxville</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Knox County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>This image was scanned from an 18 x 12 inch poster reproducing a quilt in the collection of the Tennessee Valley Authority. The text under the image is as follows: ''Uncle Sam's Helping Hand'
This quilt was one of several made by African American women whose husbands worked on Wheeler Dam in Alabama in the 1930's. Many of these quilts conveyed appreciation for the improved living standard TVA brought to the region. 'Uncle Sam's Helping Hand' is on permanent display in TVA's Historical Collection in Knoxville, Tennessee."</dc:description>
<dc:description>This quilt was made by Rose Lee Cooper. It is one of several of the same design crafted by the wives of men employed at TVA's Wheeler, Pickwick, and other dam sites in northern Alabama. The design, which bears a striking resemblance to the silhouetted figurative style of Harlem Renaissance muralist Aaron Douglas, was suggested by Ruth Clement Bond, whose husband, Max J. Bond was Personnel Officer at the Tennessee Valley Authority, 1934-38. A period photograph of a similar quilt, which was used to illustrate an October 1935 article in The Crisis (NAACP journal) by John P. Davis about TVA's treatment of African American workers, captioned the image "Rugs made by wives of TVA workers in Muscle Shoals area. Motif from Aaron Douglas." Ruth Clement Bond, originally from Louisville, KY, was an educator and civic leader who had been Head of the English department at Kentucky State College prior to coming to Wheeler Dam Village with her husband. After 1944, she taught at universities in Haiti, Liberia and Malawi and worked with women's and youth groups in Afghanistan, Tunisia and Sierra Leone. Her husband had earned a PhD in sociology and economics from USC in 1934. Following his tenure at TVA, Max J. Bond served as Dean at Dillard University in New Orleans from 1938-1940 and Administrator at Tuskegee Institute from 1940-1944, when he joined the foreign service. He was President of the University of Liberia in the early 1950s. This information was excerpted from the essay, &#8220;The TVA Quilts,&#8221; in Soft Covers For Hard Times: Quiltmaking &amp; the Great Depression, by Merikay Waldvogel (Nashville:Rutledge Hill Press,1990): 78-82.  Bond, in an interview with Waldvogel, did not recall specifically modeling the work on that of Aaron Douglas, and also mentioned Henri Matisse as an influence.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>Artifact</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:publisher>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/226</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>