<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Leading themes used in Singing Negro Folk Rhymes</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Talley, Thomas</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1920s</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Peforming Identity</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Musicians</dc:subject>
<dc:description>Handwritten musical notation and lyrics beginning with "Oh the Old Hen Cackled She."
</dc:description>
<dc:description>Thomas W. Talley, who chaired the Chemistry Department at Fisk University for 25 years, was also a singer and a musician. In 1922, he published Negro Folk Rhymes, based on the stories, rhymes, and songs he learned in his youth, with his own scholarly analysis and an introduction by Vanderbilt literature professor Walter Clyde Curry. According to scholar Lucinda Poole Cockrell, Talley's volume was "the first serious collection of folksongs from Tennessee . . . and the first to be assembled by a black scholar." &lt;http://tennesseeencyclopedia.net/entry.php?rec=1683&gt; 
</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Fisk University, John Hope and Aurelia E. Franklin Library, Special Collections</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation>Fisk University, John Hope and Aurelia E. Franklin Library, Special Collections, Thomas Talley Collection, Box 7, Folder 3</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects or to request high resolution images, contact Special Collections, John Hope and Aurelia E. Franklin Library, Fisk University, Nashville, TN.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/14</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>