<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Carnegie Hall invitation card</dc:title>
<dc:date>1929</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Performing Identity</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Musicians</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African American singers</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- New York (State) -- New York</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Cream colored engraved card with text: Thursday January 26th 8:30 o'clock in Carnegie Hall The Fisk University Choir of Sixty Voices will give its first public concert in New York City.
</dc:description>
<dc:description>The music department of Fisk University trained both large and small choral groups in addition to the Jubilee Singers. Groups regularly traveled to perform and the Fisk University Choir was featured over the Columbia Broadcasting network in the 1940s.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Ephemera</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Fisk University, John Hope and Aurelia E. Franklin Library, Special Collections</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation>Fisk University, John Hope and Aurelia E. Franklin Library, Special Collections, Thomas E. Jones Collection, Box 51, folder 7</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing organization. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact the Fisk University Franklin Library, Special Collections, Nashville, Tennessee. </dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/59</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>