<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Souvenir program, Cotton Makers Jubilee, inside cover</dc:title>
<dc:source>C&amp;T Press Service, Memphis, Tennessee</dc:source>
<dc:date>1937</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Claiming Space</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Leisure</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African American business enterprises; Parades</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Memphis</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Shelby County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Inside front cover and introductory page of the 1937 souvenir program for the Cotton Makers Jubilee. The inside cover contains two advertisements: the top 1/4 page was taken by A. Schwab, 163 Beale, "better goods at better prices" and the lower 3/4 page by Mid-South Refrigerator &amp; Appliance Co. 206 Hernando Street, billing itself as "Memphis' Only Colored Appliance Store."</dc:description>
<dc:description>The introduction to the 1937 program recounts the history of the Cotton Makers Jubilee, which was founded by Dr. R.Q. Venson as the "Cotton-Makers Fiesta" in 1936, featuring a parade, a play about African American accomplishments, and a grand ball at which W.C. Handy performed as guest of honor. The name was changed to Cotton Makers Jubilee in 1937, and it became the African American counterpart to Memphis's Cotton Carnival. The objective of the "Memphis Cotton-Makers (sic) Jubilee as set out here" is to symbolize the great and important part which the colored people of this area have played in the history of cotton . . . it marks one of the first times in the history of this area . . . that colored and white Memphians and Delta citizens have been united in a common program for the advancement and development of their common home community--the Deep South--the cotton belt."</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Memphis and Shelby County Room, Memphis Public Library and Information Center</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation>Rhodes College and Memphis Public Library &amp; Information Center, http://www.crossroadstofreedom.org</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects, contact the Memphis and Shelby County Room, Memphis Public Library and Information Center.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/158</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>