<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Church Park</dc:title>
<dc:date>n.d.</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Claiming Space</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Leisure</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Parks; Historic buildings; African American philanthropists</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Memphis</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Shelby County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>A two story structure stands at the center of what appears to be a rectangular park, with pathways leading to the building from several directions. Medium sized trees are spaced evenly and two streetlamps are visible in this photo, which is captioned "View of the Church Park from entrance gate."</dc:description>
<dc:description>Robert R. Church purchased six acres of land on Beale Street at Fourth Avenue on which to build a park in 1899. On it he erected an a modern auditorium, which could accomodate over two thousand persons, complete with a banquet hall and soda fountain. Church's Park was the center of urban African American entertainment and political activity in Memphis. Although the auditorium is no longer extant, the park was placed on the National Register of Historic Places in 1993.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Memphis and Shelby County Room, Memphis Public Library and Information Center</dc:publisher>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects, contact the Memphis and Shelby County Room, Memphis Public Library and Information Center.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/269</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>