<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Handbill for an integrated performance</dc:title>
<dc:date>1942</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Performing Identity</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Musicians</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Advertising fliers; African American musicians</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Alabama -- Eureka</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Handbill for an integrated performance in 1942 in Eureka, Alabama.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Billed as "first time in history that white and colored render a joint program," handbill advertises  an event at Eureka School, in Eureka, Alabama in 1942. The performers were the Daniel Quartet, a white gospel group featured on the Grand Ole Opry, and the Fairfield Four, an African American gospel group from Nashville. Sharing the bill, apparently, was boxer Joe Louis's mother. According to the Encyclopedia of American Gospel Music John Daniel (1903-1961), the leader of the quartet, was from the Sand Mountain area of Alabama. He moved the singing group to Nashville in the 1940s, which allowed broadcasts over WLAC and WSM radio. Joining John Daniel and his brother Troy over the years were a number of aspiring young singers, including Gordon Stoker (1924-2013), who joined the group as a pianist right out of high school. Stoker is best-known as a member of The Jordanaires, for whom he played piano beginning in 1950, assuming the role of first tenor in 1953 and continuing with the group until his retirement in 2000.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Advertisement</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Private collection, Family of Gordon Stoker</dc:publisher>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/65</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>