<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Free Hill School</dc:title>
<dc:date>1929</dc:date>
<dc:date>1996</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Finding Community</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Schools</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African American schools; Julius Rosenwald Fund -- Buildings</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Free Hill</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Clay County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Black and white photograph of one-story side-gable wooden schoolhouse viewed from driveway as approached from rear. This side of the building features two banks of double-hung eight-over-eight light windows arranged as a group of three and a pair on either side of a brick chimney. The building rests on a block and brick foundation. A basketball hoop is near the building. A sign reading Free Hills Community Center is in the foreground.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The Free Hill Rosenwald School was built circa 1929-1930 with assistance from the Julius Rosenwald Foundation. The only Rosenwald school built in Clay County, it operated as a school until 1966. It currently serves as a community center.  The community of Free Hill is located five miles northeast of Celina, Tennessee, and was organized by former slaves.  Virginia Hill, a slaveholder originally from North Carolina, freed her slaves and gave them 2,000 acres of land.  The former slaves named their community Free Hill.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/151</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>