<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>TVA or "Lazy Man" Quilt</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Bond, Ruth Clement, Designer; Thomas, Rose Marie Phillips, Quiltmaker</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1934</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Claiming Space</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Work</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Knoxville</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Knox County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Silhouetted figure of a man, cut from black cloth, with his face turned in profile to his right, holds a silhouette of a guitar cut from red cloth in his left hand while his right hand stretches below towards a silhouette of the rays of a sun cut from orange cloth. He is surrounded by silhouettes of vegetation, cut from green and bluish green clothon three sides. A wide blue sleeve with a yellow star and band and what appears to be a white gloved hand touches his right shoulder. The central design block described here is surrounded by a plain wide light brown border, and the whole has been quilted in small squares.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The maker of this quilt was Rose Marie Phillips Thomas, whose husband, Wesley Marion Thomas, was in charge of education for African American workers employed by the Tennessee Valley Authority. This is one of at least four known examples of the same design made by the wives of African Americans employed by TVA on the construction of dams in northern Alabama. The design, which bears a striking resemblance to the silhouetted figurative style of Harlem Renaissance muralist Aaron Douglas, was suggested by Ruth Clement Bond, whose husband, Max J. Bond, was Personnel Officer at the Tennessee Valley Authority, 1934-38. Ruth Clement Bond, originally from Louisville, KY, was an educator and civic leader with a B.A. and M.A. in English from Northwestern University. She  had been Head of the English department at Kentucky State College prior to coming to Wheeler Dam Village with her husband. After 1944, she taught at universities in Haiti, Liberia and Malawi and worked with women's and youth groups in Afghanistan, Tunisia and Sierra Leone. Her husband had earned a PhD in sociology and economics from USC in 1934. After his tenure at TVA, he served as Dean at Dillard University in New Orleans from 1938-1940 and Administrator at Tuskegee Institute from 1940-1944, when he joined the foreign service. He was President of the University of Liberia in the early 1950s. This information was excerpted from the essay, &#8220;The TVA Quilts,&#8221; in Soft Covers For Hard Times: Quiltmaking &amp; the Great Depression, by Merikay Waldvogel (Nashville:Rutledge Hill Press,1990): 78-82.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>Artifact</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Michigan State University Museum</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation>Photograph by Pearl Yee Wong</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects, contact the Michigan State University Museum.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/205</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>