<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Peiser the tailor, Klinke the ice cream maker, the delivery man, the Italian restaurant owner, O'Nearn the Irish policeman</dc:title>
<dc:subject>Claiming Space</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Business Districts</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Policemen; Restaurateurs; Tailors</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Memphis</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Shelby County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Five white men seated on a long bench in front of a brick wall. The man on far left is the only one not wearing a hat, and all are in shirtsleeves except for the man at far right who wears a policeman's uniformand holds a stick across his lap. Painted letters from advertisements on the wall are visible behind the men.</dc:description>
<dc:description>This image represents business owners in "the Pinch," a business district of mixed ethnicity in downtown Memphis. The area was first settled in tthe 1830s, primarily by Irish immigrants. By the turn of the twentieth century, it included Jewish, Italian, and other ethnic groups, who built businesses and raised their families in nearby neighborhoods.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Center for Southern Folklore</dc:publisher>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects, contact the Center for Southern Folklore.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/250</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>