<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Lansky Brothers Men's Shop on Famous Beale Street</dc:title>
<dc:subject>Claiming Space</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Business Districts</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Beale Street (Memphis, Tenn.); Business enterprises; Men's clothing industry; Storefronts</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Memphis</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Shelby County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Black and white photograph of the exterior of two story brick commercial building with plate glass storefont below, neon sign for  "Lansky Bros Men's Shop on famous Beale Street" out front, and the number 126 and the words "shoes, uniforms, formal wear for rent, jewelry, luggage, hats" painted in block letters on second level. Next door is a sign for Miss River Cafe.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Lansky's was a menswear store located at 126 Beale Street, near the corner of south Second Street, in Memphis, from 1946 until the 1980s, when it moved into new spaces in the lobby of the Peabody Hotel at 149 Union.  Samuel Lansky put up the money to purchase a store on Beale Street for his sons just after World War II.  Bernard (1927-2012)  built the business from a dry goods store, to an army surplus store, to a fashion center. Through his personal relationship with Elvis Presley, he turned it into an internationally-acclaimed celebrity outfitter and tourist mecca. As Lansky related it in a 2005 interview, Elvis rented a tuxedo when he was in high school and bought his first suit there, continuing to buy tailored jackets, pants, and coats from Bernard Lansky throughout his career.  Lansky's descendants still own and operate the Lansky stores at the Peabody Hotel.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Center for Southern Folklore</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation>Courtesy of the Center for Southern Folklore</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects, contact the Center for Southern Folklore.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/271</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>