<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>James &amp; Allen Drug Company</dc:title>
<dc:date>1900s</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Claiming Space</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Business Districts</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African American business enterprises</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Chattanooga</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Interior of a drug store with soda fountain at front right and glass cased pharmacy counter at left. Four persons are inside the store. A boy sits on a chair at back left and a man in a three-piece suit stands in front of him next to the glass cases. Seated on one of several wooden stools with cane seats at the soda fountain counter is a  man in bowler hat, while a uniformed attendant leans on one elbow behind the counter. Electric light fixtures hang from the ceiling and the back wall has a wallpaper patterned border at top.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The East Side Pharmacy, James &amp; Allen, proprietors was on East 9th Street in the James Building. The three-story brick building was erected by Dr. O.W. James. Above the street-level store front were office and lodge rooms, according to J. Bliss White's 1904 Biography and Achievements of the Colored Citizens of Chattanooga. </dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Bessie Smith Cultural Center</dc:publisher>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects, contact the Bessie Smith Cultural Center.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/264</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>