<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Ida B. Wells</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Garrity, Mary, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1890s</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Claiming Space</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Transportation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Wells-Barnett, Ida B., -- 1862-1931; African American women civil rights workers</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Memphis</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Shelby County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Bust-length image of a young African American woman posed looking to her right, hair pulled up into a a bun with a visible hair ornament, wearing a sheer dark dress with appliqued bodice and layered lace collar held together with white bar pin.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Ida B. Wells (1862-1931) was born in Holly Springs, Mississippi, the daughter of former slaves. While  teaching in a public school, just outside of the city of Memphis, she mounted an unsuccessful challenge to the segregation of public railroad cars in Memphis. Although she was at first awarded damages in her lawsuit challenging the Chesapeake, Ohio and Southwestern Railroad Company, the victory was overturned by the Tennessee Supreme Court in 1887. Wells became an outspoken advocate for African American rights and began publishing articles in African American newspapers, first in Memphis and later nationally. She moved to Chicago where she was active in anti-lynching campaigns and civil rights advocacy and also integrated the Women's Suffrage Movement. The National Portrait Gallery, Smithsonian Institution, owns a card mounted with this albumen silver print photograph, with the imprint of Miss Garrity. Photographer. Chicago. in the bottom margin. Chicago city directories from the period list the Misses Garrity on North Clark Street in 1885, Miss Mary Garrity on North Clark in 1886, and Miss S.E. Garrity on Wabash in 1891 and 1893.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>National Portrait Gallery, Smithsonian Institution</dc:publisher>
<dc:rights>The National Portrait Gallery's Flickr page for this image provides rights information: https://www.flickr.com/photos/20942641@N07/8489606999/in/pool-2155245@N20</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/265</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>