<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Roosevelt Election Headquarters</dc:title>
<dc:date>1944</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Embracing Citizenship</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Voting Rights</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African Americans; Political campaigns</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Automobiles; Buses; Men; Women</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Knoxville</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Knox County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>A group of five African American men and two women standing with a car and trailer parked in front of a two story brick building. The top story has been painted with the words "Roosevelt Headquarters."</dc:description>
<dc:description>In this photograph, a Democratic Party campaign trailer hitched to a late model automobile is parked in front of the Presnell building on Vine Street. Dr. James H. Presnell, who began practicing medicine in Knoxville in 1913, constructed this large brick building in 1922, at 503 Vine, the heart of Knoxville's African American business district. Dr. Presnell was an influential figure politically; when the Knoxville Flashlight Herald (a weekly African American paper) sponsored what historian Robert Booker calls a "bronze mayor" contest in 1937, Presnell was chosen to represent the community. Here, a marquee for the Atlanta Life Insurance Company hangs over the entry porch. There is a smaller marquee for Artcraft Studio below, and a sign for the Service Beauty School in the window at left. Two of the five men in the photograph wear military uniforms.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Beck Cultural Exchange Center</dc:publisher>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects, contact the Beck Cultural Exchange Center.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/209</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>