<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Soldier with children in yard in North Memphis</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Taylor, Reverend L.O., photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1940s</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Embracing Citizenship</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Military Service</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African Americans in military service; African American soldiers; African American children</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Memphis</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Shelby County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Black and white image of a smiling young African American soldier in uniform seated in a wooden lawn chair below a raised wooden porch and the corner of a frame house holds two tiny children in white dresses, with a seated boy about two years of age wearing shorts and holding a bottle leaning against the chair at his feet.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The Reverend Lonzie Odie Taylor (circa 1899-1977) was pastor of Olivet Baptist Church in Memphis in the 1930s, 1940s, and early 1950s. He was also a photographer who recorded the daily life of the community in which he lived. This informal family portrait of a smiling young soldier in uniform, seated in a lawn chair with three young children, in  a neatly kept, middle class neighborhood with established trees and vegetation, has a friendly informality that suggests not only a moment of tranquility, stability, and prosperity, but also that the photographer was known and liked by the subject.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Center for Southern Folklore</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation>Courtesy of Center for Southern Folklore</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects, contact the Center for Southern Folklore.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/104</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>