<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Fredonia Baptist Church</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1957</dc:date>
<dc:date>1998</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Finding Community</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Religious Institutions</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African American churches</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Stanton</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Haywood County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color photograph of a one story red brick building with a front gable roof. A centrally located entrance portico, supported by two pairs of pillars, covers a concrete porch at the top of four steps leading to a pair of glass doors. Two over two double hung colored glass windows flank the portico and four similar windows are visible on the left side of the building. A low brick ell extends from the left rear and paved asphalt parking places are visible in front and on the left side of the building.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Although the current building for the Fredonia Baptist Church dates to 1957, this congregation dates to 1867, and has been an active church since its inception.  Two Baptist ministers, Reverend Hardin Smith and Reverend Henry Owen, officially began this congregation in 1869 when they began organizing men and women to build a sanctuary at this location. The congregation met in a brush arbor until a frame structure could be built. The frame church was destroyed in a fire in 1899.  The next building, built in 1900, was demolished in 1957 to make room for the current building.  The Fredonia Baptist Church also served as a school, known as the Fredonia School.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects, contact the Center for Historic Preservation.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/192</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>