<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Group of people seated in the cafeteria of Booker T. Washington High School</dc:title>
<dc:date>1944</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Embracing Citizenship</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Civic Engagement</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African American men; African American women; African American schools</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Memphis</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Shelby County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Group of African American adults, some seated at banquet table, some turned to form a front row facing the camera. Inscribed: Made for Lt. G.W. Lee, Jr., Atlantic Life Ins. Co. on Beale</dc:description>
<dc:description>This group of nicely dressed men and women may have been gathered for a public or professional meeting in the cafeteria of Booker T. Washington High School, a public school for African Americans in Memphis. The inscription indicates that the photograph was ordered by George W. Lee, Jr., a World War I veteran and insurance executive active in Memphis politics. Lee, who earned the rank of 1st Lieutenant, continued to use the title professionally. The George W. Lee postal station at 826 Mississippi, was the first in Memphis to be named for an African American.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Memphis and Shelby County Room, Memphis Public Library and Information Center</dc:publisher>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects, contact the Memphis and Shelby County Room, Memphis Public Library and Information Center.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/168</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>