<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Young Men's Social Club</dc:title>
<dc:date>1930s</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Performing Identity</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Photographers</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African American men -- Societies and clubs</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Knoxville</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Knox County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Photograph of the Young Men's Social Club. Note the tinting of the hats and ties of the gentlemen.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Knoxville's African American social life was lively and varied in the 1920s. According to historian Robert J. Booker, there were six dance halls in the black community by 1924. In the 1910s, several movie theaters opened in the Vine Street business district: the Gem and the Iola on Vine Street, and the Lincoln and Lyric theaters nearby. With the initiation of the East Tennessee Negro Fair at Chilhowee Park in 1925 came traveling acrobats, tap dancers, blues singers and minstrels, and boxing, and a dance band each evening. This photograph of dapper young men taken includes: seated, left to right, unidentified, Langley Tucker, Maynard James, Edgar Blair, Fred Miller; standing, left to right, Edward Ramsey, Robert Martin, Henry Jefferson, unidentified, unidentified, Hadyn Williams, Harvey Allen.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Beck Cultural Exchange Center</dc:publisher>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects, contact the Beck Cultural Exchange Center.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/207</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>