<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Group of people on the courthouse square</dc:title>
<dc:date>1946</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Embracing Citizenship</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Military Service</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Automobiles; Courthouses; Men; Women</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Athens</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>McMinn County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>A group of people standing amidst the scene of violence on the courthouse square in Athens, Tennessee.</dc:description>
<dc:description>On August 1, 1946, a group of veterans in Athens took up arms to stop a local group, led by State Senator Paul Cantrell and linked to Memphis mayor Edward Crump from stealing the election. The veterans broke into the courthouse and demanded the return of the ballot boxes. The deputies refused and the veterans opened fire. This "Battle of Athens" lasted several hours and only ended after the front of the jail was dynamited. The mob also turned cars over on the Square and burned them, as seen in this picture. The Battle of Athens was a victory for the veterans as the Election Commission swore in the veteran candidates as duly elected.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Nashville Public Library, Special Collections</dc:publisher>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects, contact the</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/178</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>