<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Matt Gardner Homestead</dc:title>
<dc:date>1896</dc:date>
<dc:date>2000</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Claiming Space</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Towns, Neighborhoods</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African Americans -- Dwellings; Historic buildings</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Elkton</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Giles County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Two story frame building on stone foundation, with standing seam metal roof. A central doorway is flanked by two double hung windows and covered with a 3/4 width shed roof porch on stone pier blocks. Above the porch, an upper story features two 4/4 smaller, double hung windows.  </dc:description>
<dc:description>Matt Gardner was born into slavery in 1847, and freed in 1865.  A frugal man, Mr. Gardner saved his money until he was able to purchase a 300 acre farm on the Elk River in Giles County.  In addition to his farm, he served as a pastor for two separate Baptist churches in the community, funded the community-built school, and led fundraising efforts in 1926 to build a Rosenwald School in his community.  Mr. Gardner lived until the age of 95, a respected leader in his community.  His homestead is listed on the National Register of Historic Places, and the site is also home of the Matt Gardner Homestead Museum that interprets African American life. The house
pictured here was built as a two-story saddlebag house in 1896.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation>Carroll Van West, photographer</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing organization.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/68</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>