<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Promise Land School</dc:title>
<dc:creator>West, Carroll Van, photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1899</dc:date>
<dc:date>2009</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Claiming Space</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Towns, Neighborhoods; Schools</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Promise Land</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Dickson County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>White frame, front gable one-story building on stone foundation, with side gable ell. Handlettered sign over door.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Promise Land community was first settled by freedmen during Reconstruction.The African American Bowen, Redden, and Vanleer families purchased one thousand acres in what would become Promise Land circa 1870. In 1881, the Nesbitt brothers purchased land for a school and a church, forming the nucleus of the community.  By 1900, there were three churches in the community as well as several stores.  The building pictured here was partially constructed in 1899, replacing an earlier school which had been destroyed by fire.  Promise Land may have been Dickson County's largest African American community during the first half of the twentieth century.  The school, closed in 1957, is now used as a community center.</dc:description>
<dc:type>still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>photograph</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects, contact the Center for Historic Preservation.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/274</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>