<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Blair T. Hunt</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hooks Brothers</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1917-1918</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Embracing Citizenship</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Military Service</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African American soldiers; African Americans in military service; World War, 1914-1918</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Memphis</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Shelby County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Formal studio portrait of Lt. Blair T. Hunt in WW I uniform, with Chaplain's Corps insignia on collar.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Hunt served in France during WWI with the Chaplain's Corps. The college educated Hunt served as Principal of Booker T. Washington High School and as Pastor of the Mississippi Boulevard Christian Church, all the while working for opportunity for African Americans. He was a founder of the Memphis Urban League and the "Negro" YMCA.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Memphis and Shelby County Room, Memphis Public Library and Information Center</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation>Courtesy Memphis and Shelby County Room, Memphis Public Library and Information Center</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects, contact the Memphis and Shelby County Room, Memphis Public Library and Information Center.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/185</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>