<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Benjamin "Pap" Singleton and S.A. McClure</dc:title>
<dc:date>1876</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Claiming Space</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Towns, Neighborhoods</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African Americans -- Migrations</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Exodusters</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Nashville</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Davidson County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>A photograph of Benjamin Singleton and S.A. McClure superimposed over an image, apparently taken in Nashville, Tennessee, of a steamboat with passengers.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Benjamin Singleton was born into slavery in 1809. He eventually escaped his owners and fled to Canada. Following the Civil War, Singleton returned to Nashville and organized a homestead assocation around 1869 with Columbus N. Johnson to promote the resettlement of African Americans to lands in the western United States. This movement was known as the "Exoduster" movement, and several thousand African Americans in Nashville and Middle Tennessee joined the movement, settling in townships in Kansas.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Kansas Historical Society</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation>kansasmemory.org, Kansas State Historical Society, Copy and Reuse Restrictions Apply</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects, contact the Kansas Historical Society.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/237</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>