<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>First Baptist Church East Nashville</dc:title>
<dc:date>1928</dc:date>
<dc:date>2005</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Finding Community</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Religious Institutions</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African American churches</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Nashville</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Davidson County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Black and white photograph of a two-story, Greek Revival style church facade viewed from Main Street. The front portico has three white entry doors and four Ionic columns supporting a brick pediment with a circular window. Both pediment and roofline are trimmed in white. Side stairs lead to a raised entrance level. The church has a limestone foundation and matching decorative stone facing at street level.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Former slave Rev. Randall B. Vandavall founded the First Baptist Church East Nashville in 1866. The church was known as Vandavall's Baptist Church for many years, becoming officially chartered as First Baptist Church East Nashville in 1882. The current building, seen here, was built in 1928.  The congregation played a role in the Civil Rights Movement, with members and leaders taking part in meetings and activities.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Center for Historic Preservation, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects, contact the Center for Historic Preservation.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/189</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>