<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Robert R. Church, Jr., W.C. Handy, and Lt. George Lee</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hooks Brothers</dc:creator>
<dc:subject>Achieving Recognition</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>National Leaders</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African Americans; African American men; African American businesspeople; African American musicians;</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Memphis</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Shelby County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Three African American gentlemen, all wearing suits and hats, standing in front of a plate glass window, 392 Beale Avenue.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Businessman and civic leader  Robert R. Church, Jr. stands in front of his offices at 392 Beale Street, with musician W.C. Handy, and Lieutenant George Washington Lee, a World War I veteran who was also active in local politics. Handy's publishing company, Handy &amp; Pace, was in business at this address until moving to New York City in 1918.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Memphis and Shelby County Room, Memphis Public Library and Information Center</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation>DIG Memphis &#8211; Bob Church Jr WC Handy and Lt George Lee http://memphislibrary.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p13039coll5/id/35</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects, contact the Memphis and Shelby County Room, Memphis Public Library and Information Center.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/230</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>