<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Voting District 29-2, Memphis</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Taylor, Reverend L.O.</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1940s</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Embracing Citizenship</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Voting Rights</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Suffrage; African Americans; African American men; African American women; African American children</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Memphis</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Shelby County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Color film footage showing African American women standing in line, two African American men assisting a small boy walking on a porch, a sign reading 29-2 "Vote Here," African American men standing in line leading to tents with placards, and an African American man in a suit and zig-zag striped tie standing next to an automobile.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The Reverend Lonzie Odie Taylor (circa 1899-1977) became pastor of Olivet Baptist Church, 270 East Calhoun, Memphis, in 1931, serving the church until the 1950s. He was also a prolific photographer, whose black and white images of Memphis's African American community, both posed in a studio setting and in the busy business district of Beale Street and neighboring areas, captured a dynamic period of middle class prosperity and achievement from the 1920s to the 1960s. Taylor also made 16mm films, including this excerpt showing voters at a temporary neighborhood polling place. Blanche Taylor donated her husband's invaluable archive, which consists of thousands of negatives, five hundred still images, approximately 15 hours of color and black-and-white film, sound recordings, and manuscripts, to the Center for Southern Folklore.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Moving image</dc:type>
<dc:format>video/mp4</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Center for Southern Folklore</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation>Courtesy of Center for Southern Folklore</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects, contact the Center for Southern Folklore.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/233</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>