<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>"Aunt Jemima" Publicity Photograph</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Kaufman-Fabry</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1933</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Claiming Space</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Leisure</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African American women; African American women in advertising</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Illinois -- Chicago</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>"Official Photograph" of the Aunt Jemima pancake booth at the "Century of Progress" World's Fair, Chicago, 1933</dc:description>
<dc:description>The "Aunt Jemima" brand, which was based on a minstrel show character, originated in St. Louis in 1889. Quaker Oats, which had purchased the brand in 1926, hired several women to represent the popular brand, including Maude Woodfork McElroy, who was living in Chicago. However, this newspaper photograph does not appear to be of Maude Woodfork McElroy who may not have taken the position until sometime after the Chicago fair. The New York Age (29 March 1947) reported that McElroy had been hired to play the radio part of "Aunt Jemima" for a five-figure salary, that she had trained in the dramatic arts at Tennessee State University, and that she had originally come to Chicago to teach dramatics for the Works Progress Administration and that her husband, Charles McElroy, was a federal postal clerk in Chicago.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Wilson County Archives</dc:publisher>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects, contact the Wilson County Archives.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/212</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>