<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Pastoral: Fulani &amp; Infant</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Baldridge, Cyrus</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1920s</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Performing Identity</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Artists</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Blacks in art; Infants in art; Women in art</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Nashville</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Davidson County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Woman in colorful woven wrap garment, with ornamental hair braids, metal hoop earrings, and jewelry including cowrie shell necklace,  holding an infant, signed Baldridge at lower right.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Artist and illustrator Cyrus Leroy Baldridge (1889-1977) attended the Chicago School of Illustration as a boy. He worked as an illustrator after graduation from the University of Chicago and served as a war correspondent during World War I. While in the American infantry, he contributed to the Stars and Stripes, Leslie's Weekly and Scribners. His first book "I Was There with the Yanks in France" was a collection of his wartime sketches. After his marriage to Caroline Singer, the two traveled in Africa, mostly along the west coast, during the mid to late 1920s, staying in native villages in order to glean an understanding of the homelands and customs of the ancestors of contemporary African Americans. W.W. Norton published their book, entitled "White Africans and Black," written by Singer and illustrated by Baldridge, in 1929. During his career, Baldridge illustrated books for African American authors and worked for Opportunity, the magazine of the Urban League. Chicago businessman Samuel Insull purchased the collection of sketches from Baldridge's African sojourn and donated them to Fisk University in 1931.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Art original</dc:format>
<dc:format>Charcoal and gouache on paper</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Fisk University Galleries, Nashville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects, contact the Fisk University Galleries.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/255</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>