<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Advertisement for Sam Leftwick's quarry in McMinnville, Tennessee</dc:title>
<dc:date>1890-09-20</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Transforming the Economy</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Industry</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African American business enterprises; African Americans -- Employment; Quarries and quarrying; Stonemasons</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Masonry</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- McMinnville</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Sam Leftwick (1853-1935), a former slave, opened a stone quarry in McMinnville in 1888. In 1891, he was contracted to build the foundation for the Colored School House in Egypt Alley, an African American community in McMinnville. For additional information about Leftwick and the quarry site see Leigh Ann Gardner and Torren Gaston, Heritage Development Plan for the Town Spring / Quarry Site, McMinnville, Tennessee (Murfreesboro, Tenn.: Tennessee Civil War National Heritage Area, 2014).</dc:description>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:format>Advertisement</dc:format>
<dc:rights>This item is in the public domain and may be used freely.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation>Southern Standard, September 20, 1890, p. 3.</dc:relation>
<dc:description>Lime and Rock. Leftwick &amp; Marbury will keep a full supply of fine Lime on hand at their quarry on the Town Spring Bluff, and will also furnish building stone in any quantities. Orders for Rock Work of all kinds solicited, and satisfaction guaranteed on every contract. </dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/309</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>