<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Letter to Thomas Elsa Jones, President of Fisk University from Werthan Bag Company President Joe Werthan</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Werthan, Joe</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1945</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Claiming Space</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Business Districts</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Correspondence; Donations</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Nashville</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Davidson County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Typed letter on Werthan Bag Company letterhead, signed by Joe Werthan.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Joe Werthan was a member of a prominent Jewish family that owned a large burlap bag manufacturing plant near the Fisk University campus. This letter accompanied a substantial monetary donation to Fisk University for a national summer project sponsored by the Society of Friends to outfit and renovate a school for African Americans in Whiteville, a town located in one of the most heavily populated post-slavery sections of southwest Tennessee during the height of Jim Crow segregation with its pronounced inequality of public educational facilities.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Text; Image</dc:type>
<dc:format>Correspondence</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Fisk University, John Hope and Aurelia E. Franklin Library, Special Collections</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation>Fisk University, John Hope and Aurelia E. Franklin Library, Special Collections, Thomas E. Jones Collection, Box 14 Folder 10</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects, contact the</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/161</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>