<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Science</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Douglas, Aaron</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1930</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Performing Identity</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Artists</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Mural painting and decoration</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Nashville</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>Davidson County</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>A silhouetted figure kneels on a platform with a microscope at his feet and a flashlight pointed at the heavens in his left hand. His right hand rests against a classical column, and planets and stars are visible in the sky behind him.</dc:description>
<dc:description>This section of the Cravath Library mural cycle, depicting the achievements of African Americans in scientific endeavors, is in the card catalog room. In 1930, popular Harlem Renaissance artist Aaron Douglas, was commissioned to create a cycle of murals depicting African American progress. The series of images he created for the library's two large reading rooms depict the transition from Africa to America and the building of America into a modern nation. He also painted vignettes, such as this one, in the niches over the card catalog and designs for the vaulted ceilings overhead.</dc:description>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>jpeg2000</dc:format>
<dc:format>Art original</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Fisk University Galleries, Nashville, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
<dc:relation>Aaron Douglas, Science, 1930. Fisk University Galleries, Nashville, Tennessee</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>Reproduction permitted for non-profit educational and research purposes only. All reproductions require acknowledgement of the contributing institution. For research inquiries about specific objects, contact the Fisk University Galleries.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15838coll7/id/147</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>