<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Book I of the Park Commission Minute Books</dc:title>
<dc:subject>Memphis Park Commission; parks; municipal government;</dc:subject>
<dc:description>The Park Commission's first minute book, beginning September 13, 1900, and contiuing on through December 13, 1910. Page 122 was blank and omitted.  Please see transcript for introduction by John T. Dulaney.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Introduction by John T. Dulaney - The newly appointed Memphis Park Commission of September 1900 consists of Judge Louis B. McFarland as Chairman, Robert Galloway and John R. Godwin; later in the decade John T. Willingham and Dr. Benjamin F. Turner will replace McFarland and Godwin respectively. Each is required to post a bond of $5,000, equivalent to about $135,000 in 2012, &#8220;conditioned for the faithful discharge of their duties.&#8221; The original Commissioners waste no time getting down to business. At their second meeting they begin discussing the purchase of land to create two major parks, one to the south and one east of the city, and not long afterward the acquisition of land to connect the two with a parkway. For such large projects, funds will be raised by bond sales, limited by statute at the time to no greater than $250,000 each. By their second year the Commission acquires Overton Park, and shortly thereafter hires landscape architect George E. Kessler (designer of Kansas City&#8217;s much-emulated park and boulevard system) to design something similar for Memphis. -- As the minutes begin, they are written in a fine legible hand (with occasional exceptions) and continue thus for more than seven years. Typed copies of first letters, then bills, then resolutions, cut-out newspaper notices of bids, etc. begin to be pasted (or glued?) into the minutes beginning as early as September 29, 1903. The first location where the complete minutes of a meeting are typed throughout appears to be March 27, 1907. However, these minutes are not typed onto the pages of the minute book, but are pasted onto its pages in the same manner as bills are. Handwritten minutes resume for several months, but as of April 15, 1908 typed pasted-in minutes become the norm. Near the end of the book, headings appear in red and the text in blue. -- Lists of bills incurred by the Commission begin to appear regularly in the minutes by the end of 1901, sometimes as often as once a month, and continue through Books 1 and 2 and into the early years of Book 3. By about July 10, 1905, the lists of bills are typed and pasted onto the pages. The format for payment approval is along these lines: &#8220;On motion the following claims were allowed and the Secretary instructed to draw checks for same,&#8221; or the even simpler &#8220;The following bills were approved and ordered paid.&#8221; This form also continues throughout Minute Books 1 and 2 and part of Book 3. As indicated, bills are paid with checks, which are listed in the minutes with the payee&#8217;s name and the amount of the check; thus on November 8, 1901, the minutes record the check to Overton Lea for $110,000. -- Few references are seen to salaries and fewer, if any, to payrolls, a practice that continues for years. The first audit of Park Commission financial records appears in the minutes of December 7, 1904, but audits are not prominent features of Book 1. On November 7, 1906, Chairman Godwin reports on receipts and expenditures during his term of office and includes a rudimentary budget, and Chairman Galloway gives a similar report on October 2, 1907. An audit for 1908 appears on February 12, 1909 and one for 1909 on December 22, 1909; it may be noted that in the former, in a section on Park Commission Disbursements, there are references to salaries and maintenance costs for parks. -- It is clear that the Commission has a bidding process, in which bids are invited for products, services, concessions, construction and the like, although the methodology may not be clear. A bid &#8220;for Overton Pavillion stand privileges was submitted by H.S. Hughey&#8221; and &#8220;Under advertisement the following bids [for paving] were submitted&#8221; on August 10, 1903. Some of the early bid notices are cut out of newspapers and pasted into the minutes, for example one inviting bids for &#8220;furnishing Music for the Memphis Parks for the season of 1905&#8221; (April 11, 1905) or for &#8220;furnishing drain pipe under Parkway between Riverside &amp; Overton Parks&#8221; (May 17, 1906). A special called meeting is held June 19, 1908 &#8220;for the purpose of opening and awarding bids for the erection of a pavilion at Riverside Park.&#8221; On January 18, 1910, &#8220;The matter of awarding bids for the construction of the comfort station in Court Square was taken up . . . Inasmuch as there was only one bid offered for this work . . . this bid was declined.&#8221; -- As mentioned above, Chairman Godwin submits a budget in November 1906. Commission properties named there are Auction Square, Bickford Park, Confederate Park, Gaston Park, Market Square, Overton Park, Riverside Park, and the Speedway (part of North Parkway). Two years later another audit adds to this list Brinkley Square (the re-named Market Square), Forrest Park and Overton Park Zoo. -- In addition to acquiring land, the Commission finds itself providing construction, caretaking and police services, as well as entertainment. As its component parks and parkways are cleared and planted, buildings are constructed and custodians hired by the Commission. Soon after Kessler designs Overton Park, a superintendent is overseeing its landscaping. Bridges must be built, as well as houses for the &#8220;Keepers&#8221; of Overton and Riverside Parks. Minutes refer to &#8220;park policemen&#8221; in gray uniforms and helmets. During the summer, music is provided from Riverside and Overton Park pavilions, and at other locations, by a band numbering up to two dozen musicians. -- There are problems to be addressed where park meets city. Telephone and telegraph poles and their wires along the edges of parks and parkways are &#8220;inexpedient,&#8221; the Commission believes, and it forces companies to remove these eyesores, or tries to. The topic of railroad crossings on the eastern parkway comes up repeatedly. The Commission also works to provide or improve public access to the parks, viz. through encouraging the construction of streetcar lines and stations, and indeed the building of streets themselves to poorly-accessible Riverside Park. The acquisition of land for the Parkways becomes a long-drawn-out process, giving one Commissioner what he calls &#8220;considerable worry.&#8221; Not all park land is used as parks; Astor Park is for years leased to a coal company (which later also causes Commissioners considerable worry). -- Once the zoo is established it becomes one of the Commission&#8217;s dominant enterprises. Animals are donated by the public or purchased with Commission funds or with monies raised by benefit events, and improved housing is provided from time to time for both inhabitants and their Keeper. -- Toward the end of the Commission&#8217;s first decade, representatives of the tax-paying African-American community begin to petition for equal provision of park services, such as children&#8217;s playgrounds and equipment, band concerts, and indeed a park of their own, which the Commissioners go on record as favoring. These requests, sometimes backed by members of the white establishment, are taken under advisement, sometimes with the explanation that sufficient funds are not available at the time but that when they are, the requests will be reconsidered. -- In late 1910 comes a letter that clearly takes the Commissioners by surprise. Newly elected Mayor E.H. Crump writes to them that, just then, Memphis had enough parks, and that funds are needed for furthering construction of other facilities rather than expanding the park system.</dc:description>
<dc:contributor>Collection processed by John T. Dulaney</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Frierson, S.</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1900 - 1910</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>ledger book, 357 pages, 12 x 18 in.</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Box 1</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>Minute Book Edited</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Memphis Parks</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Memphis Park Commission Minute Books</dc:source>
<dc:source>Memphis &amp; Shelby County Room, MPLIC</dc:source>
<dc:rights>Digital Image &#169;2014, Memphis Public Library &amp; Information Center.  All rights reserved.  While the Memphis Public Library &amp; Information Center may house an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use. Any image from the library's collection published in any form must cite as the source: Memphis and Shelby County Room, Memphis Public Library &amp; Information Center.  For all requests, please contact the History Department at 901.415.2742 or hisref@memphistn.gov.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16108.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p13039coll3/id/1344</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>