<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Video - Historically Speaking: The "Hallelujah!" Collection at the Memphis Room</dc:title>
<dc:subject>African Americans; Campbell, Lucy; Carter, Rubye; entertainment; film; "Hallelujah!"; Jessye, Eva; Johnson, James R.; music; Woodruff, Georgia;</dc:subject>
<dc:description>A television program from the library channel in which Dr. Jim Johnson (History Department) interviews Rubye Carter.  Rubye Carter was the donor of the Hallelujah! Collection and the daughter of performer Georgia Woodruff.</dc:description>
<dc:publisher>Memphis/Shelby County Public Library and Information Center</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Justin Thompson; Sarah Frierson</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1986-02</dc:date>
<dc:type>Moving Image</dc:type>
<dc:format>VHS, 35:55</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>HALL DISC 02</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Hallelujah!</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Hallelujah! Collection</dc:source>
<dc:source>Memphis &amp; Shelby County Room, MPLIC</dc:source>
<dc:rights>Digital Image &#169;2013, Memphis Public Library &amp; Information Center. All rights reserved.  While the Memphis Public Library &amp; Information Center may house an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use. Any image from the library's collection, published in any form, must cite as the source: Memphis and Shelby County Room, Memphis Public Library &amp; Information Center. For all requests, please contact the History Department at 901.415.2742 or hisref@memphistn.gov.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16108.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p16108coll9/id/6</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>