<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>WSM &#8211; America&#8217;s Tallest Radio Tower, Nashville, Tennessee </dc:title>
<dc:description>Color postcard of WSM Radio tower south of Nashville, Tennessee. It stands at 878 feet tall, which is 323 feet higher than the Washington Monument. Postcard is addressed to Mr. John S. Evins of Gerlach, Nevada.
</dc:description>
<dc:description>WSM is credited with shaping Nashville into a recording industry capital. WSM (National Life and Accident Insurance&#8217;s radio call letters for &#8220;We Shield Millions&#8221;) debuted on October 5, 2925 and less than two months later would broadcast its most famous show, the Grand Ole Opry. The Opry was the first of WSM&#8217;s shows to develop fans who would visit live studio broadcasts. In 1928, WSM was given the frequency of 650 kilohertz and admission to Class 1-A-clear-channel broadcasters. The station&#8217;s 50,000-watt transmitter, built in 1932, made it a nation-spanning station. The 878-foot tower was reduced in size in 1939, though at its construction, the antenna was the tallest in North America. In 1941, National Life and Accident Insurance became the first commercial broadcaster in the U.S., and received a commercial FM license from the Federal Communications Commission. WSM-TV, created in 1950, was Nashville&#8217;s first television station and the only the second in Tennessee. In 2008, WSM received the NAB Marconi Award, the radio industry&#8217;s highest honor. Today, 650 AM WSM is a broadcasting giant.
</dc:description>
<dc:description>Mr. John S. Evins, Gerlach, Nevada.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1940 January 2</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>Nashville (Tenn.) </dc:coverage>
<dc:publisher>Capitol News Co. </dc:publisher>
<dc:coverage>Chicago (Ill.) </dc:coverage>
<dc:source>Tennessee Postcard Collection </dc:source>
<dc:subject>Radio and television towers; Broadcasting; Postcards</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives </dc:source>
<dc:identifier>32826</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>Still Image</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:format>Postcards</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright not evaluated: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/tpc/id/128</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>