<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:dltn="https://github.com/digitallibraryoftennessee" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Letter from Rachel Jackson to John Donelson, August 25, 1821</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/">No Copyright - United States</accessCondition>
  <location>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll33/id/182</url>
    <url access="preview">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p15138coll33/id/182</url>
  </location>
  <name>
    <namePart>Jackson, Rachel, 1767-1828</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cre">Creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <abstract>Rachel Jackson wrote to her brother, John Donelson, from Pensacola, Florida, complaining of Spaniards, Seminoles and the bad climate and discussing her husband's experience as Florida's military governor. She missed home, and felt that her health was "delicate." The concluding paragraph is filled with rambling scriptural quotations from the Book of Isaiah and communications for family members.</abstract>
  <abstract>Rachel Donelson Jackson was the youngest child of John Donelson and Rachel Stockley Donelson. At the age of 12, Rachel accompanied her family down the Cumberland River to Fort Nashborough. She married Captain Lewis Robards, but the unhappy couple soon separated. Rachel believed her husband filed for divorce during this tumultuous time. A young attorney named Andrew Jackson boarded at the Donelson home, where he first met Rachel. The two married in Natchez, Mississippi in 1791. This marriage was considered invalid because she was never officially divorced from Robards. This unfortunate circumstance troubled the couple for the remainder of their lives. After an official divorce was granted in 1794, Rachel and Andrew were officially married in Davidson County. They adopted the son of Rachel's brother Severn Donelson, in 1806 and named him Andrew Jackson, Jr. Rachel died in 1828, shortly before Andrew took office as president</abstract>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated>1821 August 25</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Tennessee State Library and Archives</recordContentSource>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
  </recordInfo>
  <subject>
    <topic>Jackson, Rachel, 1767-1828</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Donelson, John, 1755-1830</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Seminole Indians</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic/>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Correspondence</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <geographic>Pensacola (Fla.)</geographic>
  </subject>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>THS T-100</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Tennessee Historical Society</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <physicalDescription>
    <form>Correspondence</form>
  </physicalDescription>
  <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
</mods>
