<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:dltn="https://github.com/digitallibraryoftennessee" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Letter from John Coffee to his wife, Mary, April 2, 1814, following the Battle of Horseshoe Bend</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/">No Copyright - United States</accessCondition>
  <location>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll33/id/60</url>
    <url access="preview">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p15138coll33/id/60</url>
  </location>
  <name>
    <namePart>Coffee, John, 1772-1833</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cre">Creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <abstract>Coffee wrote this letter to his wife the day after his first, in case it would reach her more quickly. Again he mentioned the Battle of Horseshoe Bend, reporting that they "killed from eight to nine hundred of the enemy, and took about 500 prisoners- this is the greatest defeat we have ever given them." Coffee claimed that they killed three of their prophets including their "principal one," probably a reference to Monahee. He told her they were heading to the hickory ground and would arrive in "3 or 4 days." He guessed they may have one more battle with the Creeks before they surrender, as they were starving. He expected to be home in about a month. The letter ended with personal remarks and updates about mutual friends.</abstract>
  <abstract>The Battle of Horseshoe Bend was fought on March 27, 1814, between the war faction (Red Stick) Creek and a coalition of American and Native American troops. The decisive battle proved to be the climax of the Creek War, a conflict between warring factions of Creek and their allies as a part of the War of 1812. Major General Andrew Jackson led a force of just over 2,700 soldiers composed of US Regulars, Tennessee militia and volunteers, as well as 500 Cherokee and 100 allied Creek warriors to a Red Stick fortification at a bend on the Tallapoosa River in present-day Alabama. Jackson estimated that the defending Red Sticks numbered about a thousand. Jackson sent General John Coffee, the cavalry, and almost all of their Indian allies to encircle the encampment and prevent any escape. A two hour artillery barrage preceded a covert attack on the fortification led by Captain Russell, Colonel Richard Brown [Cherokee], and Colonel Morgan, who was in overall command of the Cherokee. This small force set fire to a few of the buildings in an attempt to force the Red Sticks out. The 39th US Infantry, raised almost exclusively in Tennessee and led by Colonel John Williams and Major Lemuel Montgomery, mounted a simultaneous frontal assault of the fortification. Third lieutenant Sam Houston participated in this assault and was wounded, while Montgomery was killed. In his official report, Jackson recorded, "The enemy, altho[ugh] many of them fought to the last with that kind of bravery which desperation inspires, were at length entirely routed and cut to pieces." Many escaping Red Sticks were killed by Coffee's troops. Jackson estimated 800 enemy were killed, including their prophet, Monahee, who was shot in the mouth. Jackson commented, "as if heaven designed to chastise his impostures by an appropriate punishment." He reported that 26 white men were killed along with 18 Cherokee, with 107 and 36 wounded, respectively.</abstract>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated>1814 April 2</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Tennessee State Library and Archives</recordContentSource>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
  </recordInfo>
  <subject>
    <topic>Coffee, John, 1772-1833</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Creek War, 1813-1814</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Horseshoe Bend, Battle of, Ala., 1814</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Correspondence</topic>
  </subject>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Dyas Collection of John Coffee Papers</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Tennessee Historical Society</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <physicalDescription>
    <form>Correspondence</form>
  </physicalDescription>
  <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
</mods>
