<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:dltn="https://github.com/digitallibraryoftennessee" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>The Proclamation of Andrew Jackson, President, to the people of the United States of America</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/">No Copyright - United States</accessCondition>
  <location>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll33/id/288</url>
    <url access="preview">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p15138coll33/id/288</url>
    <url note="iiif-manifest">https://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/iiif/info/p15138coll33/288/manifest.json</url>
  </location>
  <abstract>Printed copy on silk of President Andrew Jackson's speech given on December 10, 1832, in opposition to South Carolina's actions in an attempt to nullify Federal tariffs. Taking his case directly to the American people, Jackson gave constitutional defenses for his actions as president. Dispute over the tariff, which came to a head in the Nullification Crisis, was very much a sectional issue between the industrial North and slaveholding South. It presaged the growing antagonism that would lead eventually to secession and Civil War. South Carolina's challenge to Federal authority in 1832 was beaten back by the strong Unionism of Jackson and other Southern moderates. Such unionists would become a dying breed in the South during the ensuing 30 years.</abstract>
  <abstract>The Nullification Crisis was a confrontation between the federal government and South Carolina over tariffs, South Carolina's perceived rights, and the threat of secession. It began with the passage of the Tariff of 1828, referred to by the South Carolinians as the "Tariff of Abominations." They argued that the tariff protected manufacturing rather than agriculture. Jackson's election as president was expected to ease the tensions, but Jackson refused to lower the tariff until national debts were repaid. After the passage of the Tariff of 1832, Jackson issued the Proclamation to the People of South Carolina denouncing the nullification doctrine. In the following session, the Force Bill was introduced to Congress, which authorized the use of force to ensure that South Carolina would comply with federal tariffs. This led to the introduction of the Compromise Tariff of 1833. The passage of these two bills eased the rising tensions and ultimately ended the crisis.</abstract>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated>1832</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Tennessee State Library and Archives</recordContentSource>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
  </recordInfo>
  <subject>
    <topic>Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Nullification (States' rights)</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>United States. President (1829-1837 : Jackson)</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Proclamations</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Tariffs</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <geographic>New York (N.Y.)</geographic>
  </subject>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Andrew Jackson Collection, 1788-1942</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>3, 79-048</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Tennessee State Library and Archives</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <physicalDescription>
    <form>Documents</form>
    <form>Proclamations</form>
  </physicalDescription>
  <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
</mods>
