<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:dltn="https://github.com/digitallibraryoftennessee" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Letter about the Battle of Horseshoe Bend from John Coffee to Sam Houston April 25, 1828</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/">No Copyright - United States</accessCondition>
  <location>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll33/id/25</url>
    <url access="preview">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p15138coll33/id/25</url>
  </location>
  <name>
    <namePart>Coffee, John, 1772-1833</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cre">Creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <abstract>A four-page letter written from Florence, Alabama, on April 25, 1828. Coffee answers Sam Houston's inquiry regarding the accusation (no doubt connected with the 1828 presidential election) that the Battle of Horseshoe Bend was a "cold blooded massacre." Coffee defends General Andrew Jackson's conduct there and throughout the war. He states that "It was most certainly [Jackson's] object and his orders to kill in battle as many of the enemy as possible, but I never know him to treat a prisoner with cruelty or inhumanity." Coffee continues, "on the contrary, I have seen him uniformly...take them into safe keeping and have them guarded and protected from his friendly Indians...who would put them to torture and to death." He explains that Jackson ordered an end to the pursuit of escapees after the battle and had interpreters offer them terms, but the enemy fired upon them Coffee mentions "Lincoyer" the infant Creek whom Jackson later adopted, and he states that the child's mother had been unavoidably killed at Tallushatchee.</abstract>
  <abstract>The Battle of Horseshoe Bend was fought on March 27, 1814, between the war faction (Red Stick) Creek and a coalition of American and Native American troops. The decisive battle proved to be the climax of the Creek War, a conflict between warring factions of Creek and their allies as a part of the War of 1812. Major General Andrew Jackson led a force of just over 2,700 soldiers composed of US Regulars, Tennessee militia and volunteers, as well as 500 Cherokee and 100 allied Creek warriors to a Red Stick fortification at a bend on the Tallapoosa River in present-day Alabama. Jackson estimated that the defending Red Sticks numbered about a thousand. Jackson sent General John Coffee, the cavalry, and almost all of their Indian allies to encircle the encampment and prevent any escape. A two hour artillery barrage preceded a covert attack on the fortification led by Captain Russell, Colonel Richard Brown [Cherokee], and Colonel Morgan, who was in overall command of the Cherokee. This small force set fire to a few of the buildings in an attempt to force the Red Sticks out. The 39th US Infantry, raised almost exclusively in Tennessee and led by Colonel John Williams and Major Lemuel Montgomery, mounted a simultaneous frontal assault of the fortification. Third lieutenant Sam Houston participated in this assault and was wounded, while Montgomery was killed. In his official report, Jackson recorded, "The enemy, altho[ugh] many of them fought to the last with that kind of bravery which desperation inspires, were at length entirely routed and cut to pieces." Many escaping Red Sticks were killed by Coffee's troops. Jackson estimated 800 enemy were killed, including their prophet, Monahee, who was shot in the mouth. Jackson commented, "as if heaven designed to chastise his impostures by an appropriate punishment." He reported that 26 white men were killed along with 18 Cherokee, with 107 and 36 wounded, respectively. David Crockett, in his autobiography, recounted of the Battle of Tallushatchee that they "shot them like dogs, "set the house on fire, and burned it up with the forty-six warriors in it."</abstract>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated>1828 April 25</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Tennessee State Library and Archives</recordContentSource>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
  </recordInfo>
  <subject>
    <topic>Coffee, John, 1772-1833</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Creek War, 1813-1814</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Horseshoe Bend, Battle of, Ala., 1814</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Houston, Sam, 1793-1863</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <geographic>Florence (Ala.)</geographic>
  </subject>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Dyas Collection of John Coffee Papers</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>THS 38, 211</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Tennessee Historical Society</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <physicalDescription>
    <form>Correspondence</form>
  </physicalDescription>
  <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
</mods>
