<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:dltn="https://github.com/digitallibraryoftennessee" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Letter from Amos Kendall to Andrew Jackson, August 22, 1827</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/">No Copyright - United States</accessCondition>
  <location>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll33/id/113</url>
    <url access="preview">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p15138coll33/id/113</url>
  </location>
  <name>
    <namePart>Kendall, Amos, 1789-1869</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cre">Creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <abstract>Amos Kendall, writing from Frankfort, Kentucky, confidentially disclosed to Jackson his experience during the 1824 election. He told Jackson that "Mr. Clay never treated me confidentially in relation to his arrangement with Adams." He claimed the he would have disclosed this information if Clay had informed him He went on to say that one of Clay's friends told him of the arrangement on about January 20, 1825, and that he "was solicited three times to write to Mr. White, our representative, to vote for Adams on that account." Kendall believed so fervently that the suggestion of the arrangement came from Clay rather than Adams that he would "risk [his] honor and [his] life on the result of a thorough investigation." On the final page of the letter, Kendall attempted to curry favor with Jackson by praising his character and military exploits.</abstract>
  <abstract>The 1824 presidential election was a fierce contest. Four frontrunners, Henry Clay, William Crawford, John Quincy Adams, and Andrew Jackson, were identified as early as a year before the election. The results were highly regional, each candidate won his home state. Jackson received the most popular votes but failed to win a majority of electoral votes so the choice fell to the House of Representatives. Clay threw his support behind Adams, who ultimately won. Adams then appointed Clay as Secretary of State which infuriated Jackson and his supports who deemed it the "corrupt bargain.</abstract>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated>1827 August 22</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Tennessee State Library and Archives</recordContentSource>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
  </recordInfo>
  <subject>
    <topic>Presidential elections--1820-1830</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Election campaigns</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <geographic>Frankfort (Ky.)</geographic>
  </subject>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Andrew Jackson Collection, 1788-1942</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>3, 79-048</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Tennessee State Library and Archives</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <physicalDescription>
    <form>Correspondence</form>
  </physicalDescription>
  <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
</mods>
