<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:dltn="https://github.com/digitallibraryoftennessee" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Handwritten transcript of letters among Andrew Jackson, Charles Dickinson, Thomas Overton, and Hanson Catlet regarding the 1806 Jackson-Dickinson duel</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/">No Copyright - United States</accessCondition>
  <location>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll33/id/214</url>
    <url access="preview">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p15138coll33/id/214</url>
  </location>
  <abstract>This document is a handwritten copy of a series of letters between Andrew Jackson, Charles Dickinson, Thomas Overton, and Hanson Catlet regarding the duel that ultimately resulted in Dickinson's death. The sequence of these exchanges begins with Charles Dickinson publishing an article on Andrew Jackson insulting Jackson "with blackguards abuse." Jackson sent Dickinson a letter inviting him to satisfy the insults by means of a duel. Dickinson accepted and the terms of the duel were settled by Thomas Overton and Hanson Catlet, acting as 'seconds' on behalf of Jackson and Dickinson, respectively. Thomas Overton requested that the duel happen as soon as possible and offered to provide pistols if Dickinson could not obtain one. They agreed upon a date and time for the "affair of honor," which was given as seven in the morning on May 30, 1806 across the state line at Harrison's Mill in Logan County, Kentucky. They also agreed that Jackson and Dickinson would stand 24 feet apart, facing each other with their pistols drawn until someone called "Fire."</abstract>
  <abstract>In early 1806, Andrew Jackson and Charles Dickinson engaged in a disagreement over a horserace involving Jackson and Dickinson's father-in-law, Joseph Erwin. In the midst of this disagreement, Dickinson publicly insulted Jackson's wife, Rachel. Insults were made back and forth until Jackson ultimately challenged Dickinson to a duel on May 23, 1806. On May 30, 1806, the two men and their seconds met at Harrison's Mill, Kentucky, to settle their dispute. Knowing Dickinson's reputation as a marksman, Jackson planned to hold his fire and hope that Dickinson missed in his rush to fire. The two men formally paced until they were 20 feet apart when one of the seconds shouted, "Fire!" Dickinson shot first hitting Jackson in the chest; the ball broke ribs and lodged close to the heart. Though injured, Jackson slowly aimed and hit Dickinson in the abdomen. Dickinson died later that evening. Jackson carried the ball from the duel the rest of his life</abstract>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated>1806 May 23</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Tennessee State Library and Archives</recordContentSource>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
  </recordInfo>
  <subject>
    <topic>Dueling--Kentucky--History</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Correspondence Dueling</topic>
  </subject>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Andrew Jackson Collection, 1788-1942</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>3, 79-048</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Tennessee State Library and Archives</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <physicalDescription>
    <form>Correspondence</form>
  </physicalDescription>
  <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
</mods>
