<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Government Building</dc:title>
<dc:rights>While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law.  Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:subject>Centennial celebrations; Exhibition buildings; Exhibitions; Anniversaries; Events; Fairs; Commemorations; Flags; Domes</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Tennessee Centennial and International Exposition (1897 : Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:description>Angled view of the U.S. Government Building at the Tennessee Centennial Exposition. The building stood close to the main entrance of the grounds near Lake Katherine. The building, with classical style architecture, had the form of a cross. The center was intended to resemble in general appearance the dome of the newly constructed Library of Congress in Washington. Flags were mounted on each corner of the building.</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Nashville (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:date>1897</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Calvert Bros. &amp; Taylor</dc:creator>
<dc:source>Tennessee Historical Society Picture Collection</dc:source>
<dc:description>The purpose of the Government Building was to exemplify the workings of the United States Government. Ten different departments, such as the War and Treasury Departments, displayed exhibits which were brought to the building by railroad cars of the Nashville, Chattanooga, and St. Louis Railway Company. The Railway Company had to extend its tracks up to the east end of the building for unloading purposes.</dc:description>
<dc:relation>THS 193</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Tennessee Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>27167</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>IMAGE</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:format>4.5" x 3"</dc:format>
<dc:format>5.75" x 4.25"</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/Centennial/id/194</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>