<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Business card advertising Forrest, Jones &amp; Co. as "Dealers in Slaves"</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <identifier>41940</identifier>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated encoding="edtf" keyDate="yes">1859/1860</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <physicalDescription>
    <internetMediaType>image/jp2</internetMediaType>
  </physicalDescription>
  <location>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll18/id/1072</url>
    <url access="preview">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p15138coll18/id/1072</url>
    <url note="iiif-manifest">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/iiif/info/p15138coll18/1072/manifest.json</url>
    <physicalLocation>Tennessee State Library and Archives</physicalLocation>
  </location>
  <subject>
    <topic>Slavery</topic>
  </subject>
  <abstract>Located at No. 89 Adams Street, Memphis, Tennessee, the owners of this slave-dealing business included Nathan Bedford Forrest, later a famous Confederate general during the Civil War, and his brother William. The bottom of the business card reads, "They will Board and Sell on Commission, and keep constantly on hand, a good assortment of Virginia, Georgia, and Carolina Negroes for sale." On the reverse of the card is written in pencil, "Sold Madison to Forrest," possibly referring to an enslaved person sold to Forrest by the owner of Belle Meade plantation near Nashville. Four enslaved individuals were killed in this brick building on Jan. 13, 1860 when it collapsed following heavy rains; Forrest, one of Memphis' largest slave dealers and wealthiest men, closed the business soon afterwards.</abstract>
  <accessCondition type="local rights statement">While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees, that may be necessary for the intended use.</accessCondition>
  <subject>
    <geographic>Memphis (Tenn.)</geographic>
  </subject>
  <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Collection">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>William Hicks Jackson (1834-1903) Papers, 1766-1978</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Project">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Education Outreach</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <abstract>We're here to help you bring Tennessee history alive in the classroom! The Tennessee State Library and Archives (TSLA) is a great resource for educators and students seeking primary sources for use in the classroom. With extensive holdings in Tennessee, Southern, and regional history, TSLA is also the official repository for the permanent records of the State of Tennessee...</abstract>
    <location>
      <url>http://www.tn.gov/tsla/educationoutreach/index.htm</url>
    </location>
  </relatedItem>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Tennessee State Library and Archives</recordContentSource>
    <recordChangeDate>2023-05-12-04:00</recordChangeDate>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
    <recordOrigin>Record has been transformed into MODS 3.5 from a qualified Dublin Core record by the Digital Library of Tennessee, a service hub of the Digital Public Library of America, using a stylesheet available at https://github.com/utkdigitalinitiatives/DLTN. Metadata originally created in a locally modified version of qualified Dublin Core using ContentDM (data dictionary available: https://wiki.lib.utk.edu/display/DPLA.)</recordOrigin>
  </recordInfo>
</mods>
