<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Letter from Lewis Ross to John Ross regarding the options for Cherokee removal</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <identifier>42426</identifier>
  <name>
    <namePart>Ross, Lewis, 1796-1890</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cre">Creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated>1838 January 4th</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <physicalDescription>
    <note>Application/pdf</note>
  </physicalDescription>
  <location>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll18/id/2044</url>
    <url access="preview">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p15138coll18/id/2044</url>
    <physicalLocation>Tennessee State Library and Archives</physicalLocation>
  </location>
  <subject>
    <topic>Indian Removal, 1813-1903</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Cherokee Indians--Treaties</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Cherokee Indians--Relocation</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Ross, John, 1790-1866</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Indians of North America</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Indigenous peoples</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Tribal chiefs--Cherokee</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Treaties</topic>
  </subject>
  <abstract>In this 2-page letter, Lewis Ross writes his brother, Cherokee Chief John Ross, about the options for the removal of the Cherokee Tribe. He states that given the circumstances, he fears there is nothing his brother will be able to do in Washington but to negotiate the terms of removal. He states that there are only two options presented to the people - either to stay and be forced off their lands under the terms of the false treaty or to negotiate their own terms that could be more satisfactory to the Nation. He suggests that they should negotiate for more time to remove, their own control of the money, and to be allowed to remove to where they choose. He goes on to say they will likely receive nothing more from the United States Government than more oppression as long as they are within the limits of the country and perhaps they could find a different country in which to settle. He knows the people place high expectations and pressure on his brother and they are all waiting in suspense for the news from him.</abstract>
  <accessCondition type="local rights statement">While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees, that may be necessary for the intended use.</accessCondition>
  <subject>
    <geographic>Calhoun (Tenn.)</geographic>
  </subject>
  <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
  <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Collection">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Penelope Johnson Allen Cherokee Collection, 1775-1878</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Project">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Education Outreach</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <abstract>We're here to help you bring Tennessee history alive in the classroom! The Tennessee State Library and Archives (TSLA) is a great resource for educators and students seeking primary sources for use in the classroom. With extensive holdings in Tennessee, Southern, and regional history, TSLA is also the official repository for the permanent records of the State of Tennessee...</abstract>
    <location>
      <url>http://www.tn.gov/tsla/educationoutreach/index.htm</url>
    </location>
  </relatedItem>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Tennessee State Library and Archives</recordContentSource>
    <recordChangeDate>2023-05-12-04:00</recordChangeDate>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
    <recordOrigin>Record has been transformed into MODS 3.5 from a qualified Dublin Core record by the Digital Library of Tennessee, a service hub of the Digital Public Library of America, using a stylesheet available at https://github.com/utkdigitalinitiatives/DLTN. Metadata originally created in a locally modified version of qualified Dublin Core using ContentDM (data dictionary available: https://wiki.lib.utk.edu/display/DPLA.)</recordOrigin>
  </recordInfo>
</mods>
