<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Broadside displaying instructions to be observed by pickets and patrols on duty around Memphis</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <identifier>42668</identifier>
  <name>
    <namePart>State Board of Health of the State of Tennessee</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cre">Creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated encoding="edtf" keyDate="yes">1879-09-30</dateCreated>
    <publisher>State Board of Health of the State of Tennessee</publisher>
  </originInfo>
  <physicalDescription>
    <internetMediaType>image/jpeg</internetMediaType>
  </physicalDescription>
  <location>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll18/id/1576</url>
    <url access="preview">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p15138coll18/id/1576</url>
    <url note="iiif-manifest">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/iiif/info/p15138coll18/1576/manifest.json</url>
    <physicalLocation>Tennessee State Library and Archives</physicalLocation>
  </location>
  <subject>
    <topic>Yellow Fever</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Epidemics</topic>
  </subject>
  <abstract>This boadside warns those outside of the picket lines surrounding Memphis of the dangers of entering the city and further spreading the yellow fever. No one from outside of the city is allowed to come in and no one from inside is allowed to leave, unless they have a permit. No household items are allowed to cross the city limits, but provisions and supplies can. Cotton and bales and cotton seed are allowed to cross the border. Anyone who violates these rules put in place by the Superintendent of Quarantine John Johnson will have to pay a fine between fifty or five hundred dollars or serve up to three months in jail.</abstract>
  <accessCondition type="local rights statement">While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees, that may be necessary for the intended use.</accessCondition>
  <subject>
    <geographic>Memphis (Tenn.)</geographic>
  </subject>
  <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Collection">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Tennessee Department of Public Health Records, 1874-1975</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Collection">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Series 14</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Project">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Education Outreach</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <abstract>We're here to help you bring Tennessee history alive in the classroom! The Tennessee State Library and Archives (TSLA) is a great resource for educators and students seeking primary sources for use in the classroom. With extensive holdings in Tennessee, Southern, and regional history, TSLA is also the official repository for the permanent records of the State of Tennessee...</abstract>
    <location>
      <url>http://www.tn.gov/tsla/educationoutreach/index.htm</url>
    </location>
  </relatedItem>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Tennessee State Library and Archives</recordContentSource>
    <recordChangeDate>2023-05-12-04:00</recordChangeDate>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
    <recordOrigin>Record has been transformed into MODS 3.5 from a qualified Dublin Core record by the Digital Library of Tennessee, a service hub of the Digital Public Library of America, using a stylesheet available at https://github.com/utkdigitalinitiatives/DLTN. Metadata originally created in a locally modified version of qualified Dublin Core using ContentDM (data dictionary available: https://wiki.lib.utk.edu/display/DPLA.)</recordOrigin>
  </recordInfo>
</mods>
