<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Photomontage of a graduation at Cumberland University, babies and children of Tennessee families, and five ads. Nashville Banner, 1932 November 6.</dc:title>
<dc:subject>Stockton, Mrs. Ernest L.; Clark, Elmer T.; Crawford, Leonidas W.; Lyon, P. A.; Stockton, Ernest L.; Guerry, Alexander; Eubanks, Weaver K.; Mayfield, George R.; Jones, Thomas Elsa; Anderson, Charles A.; Faw, W. W.; Bones, W. P.; Stine, Charles M. A.; Kelly, Robert L.; Snavely, Guy E.; Hoskins, James D.; Poe, Floyd; Munro, Hugh; Caruthers, John; Wilson, Violet; Turner, Margaret; Doherty, Helen; McAdoo, Madeline; Singer, Ann; Elkins, Helen; Loudon, Dorothy; Edgerton, Harriet; Tucker, Mary; Smith, Samuel Boyd; Harris, Betty Jo; Gibson Jr., Hickman J.; McNatt, Martha Jane; Flanagin Jr., Elmer; Moore Jr., Lewis Edward; Harris, James Clyde</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Banner</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Graduation ceremonies; Infants; Children; Portraits; Dogs</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:description>Photomontage of a graduation at Cumberland University, a group of freshman girls at the same school, babies and children of Tennessee families, and five ads, one of which features a local child. 16 x 21.5 in. Forms part of the Nashville Newspaper Rotogravure Digital Images Collection.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Easter; Stark; Calvert's</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1932 November 6</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text; Newspapers</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Newspaper Rotogravure Digital Images Collection.</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll19/id/249</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>