<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Photomontage of Tennessee babies and children, and two ads. Nashville Banner, 1927 November 13.</dc:title>
<dc:subject>Mogan, Joseph John; Mogan, Catherine Agnes; Mogan, Edward Nenon; Thomas, Dorothy Evelyn; Connor, August Gerst; Stephens, Patty Lu; Parker, Estelle Colleen; Parker, Millard Raymond; Whitehead, Edyth; Mayfield, Mary Frances; Chaney, Mary Frances; Chaney, John Charles, Jr.; Ballentine, Jetora Novarese; Eakes, James Edward; Carlton, Dorothy; Carlton, Billie Wayne; King, Jacquelyn; Hammond, Jean; Williams, Doris Dixon; Williams, Bobby Ruth; Coombs, Margaret Ella; Coombs, Betty Jean; Mitchell, Hoyte Campbell, Mitchell, Charlie Hatton; Atkinson, Frances Lois; Whitefield, Sarah Helen; Morrissey, Loftin A., Jr.; Morrissey, Dorothy Jean; Duckworth, Alice Ewin; Pappas, Victor G.; Barnes, Howard S.; Barnes, Eva Miller; Austin, James Monroe, Jr.; Watson, Orndoff; Stephens, Juanita; Huddleston, Edna Earl; Huddleston, Edith Marie; Cross, Janice; Cross, Virginia; Brown, Mary Ann; Bateman, Frances Kathleen; Ghea, Dorris Elmer; Cobb, Nancy Carolyn</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Banner</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Infants; Children; Portraits</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:description>Photomontage of Tennessee babies and children, and two ads. 16 x 21.5 in. Forms part of the Nashville Newspaper Rotogravure Digital Images Collection.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Thuss, A. J.; Calvert Bros.; Thuss, W. G.; Stark, E. M.; Harding Studio; Dickerson; Cook's Studio</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1927 November 13</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text; Newspapers</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Newspaper Rotogravure Digital Images Collection.</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1920-1929</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll19/id/1145</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>