<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Photomontage of a National Guard Squadron, a Jewish retirement home in Memphis, a horse, and two women swimming with balloons. Nashville Banner, 1931 November 22.</dc:title>
<dc:subject>Gleaves, Richard; Outlaw, John; Hibbitts Jr., Josiah; Fox, Herbert F.; McCall, John; Williams, Walter; Reed Jr., James; Sloan, Paul; Conway, Lee; Horkins, Maxwell; Gardner, John; Covington, Claude; Zellner, Jesse; Catron, William B.; Noland, George W.; Hurt Jr., James W.; Edwards, Lewis; Lindsay, Robert; Farrar, R. S.; Orr III, Robert; Dyer, Harry B.; Ingalls, Elliot; Sneed Jr., William B.; Oman III, John; Farrar Sr., J. M.; Norman Jr., Haywood; Orr, John; Flanary, Paul</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Banner</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Militia; Retirement communities; Judaism; Horses; Swimming</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:description>Photomontage of Officers of the 105th Observation Squadron of the National Guard, a Jewish retirement home in Memphis, a horse raised at Travellers Rest Farm, and two women swimming with balloons in California.  16 x 21.5 in. Forms part of the Nashville Newspaper Rotogravure Digital Images Collection.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>International Newsreel</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1931 November 22</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text; Newspapers</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Newspaper Rotogravure Digital Images Collection.</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll19/id/241</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>