<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Photomontage of babies and children of Tennessee families and six ads. Nashville Banner, 1931 July 19. </dc:title>
<dc:subject>Just Jr., Frank; Simmons, Zolon Lee; Griffin, Walter Brown; Walker, Joe Tom; Tomlin, Mildred; Tomlin, Sue; Parham, Imogene; Holt, Lily Mai; Medford, Edsel; Jared, Wanda Katherine; Moore, Dorothy Ann; Coppinger, Jesse William; Burrow, Anne Marie; Wisner, William K. M.; Nix, Elizabeth; Nix, Joy; Ellington, Thomas Howard; Ellington, Grace Cornelia; Shaffer, Rose Mary; Smith Jr., Charles E.; Baxter, Gertrude Nebetha; Aydelatt Jr., Clyde D.; Hilles, Charles Edwin; Dillard, Frank Thomas; Coffee, Billie Marie; Tubbs, Donald T.</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Banner</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Infants; Children; Portraits</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:description>Photomontage of babies and children of Tennessee families and six ads. 16 x 21.5 in. Forms part of the Nashville Newspaper Rotogravure Digital Images Collection.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Ferrell, Leo; Thuss, W. G.; Anderson's Studio; Hughes' Studio; Elbrick; Seat Studio</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1931 July 19</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text; Newspapers</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Newspaper Rotogravure Digital Images Collection.</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll19/id/309</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>