<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Photomontage of libraries, the Calvary Cemetery entrance, composing staff of The Banner newspaper, and a group of football players with a church group. Nashville Banner, 1932 November 13.</dc:title>
<dc:subject>Graham, Claire; Miller, Suzanna; Fleming, Lillian D.</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Banner</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Libraries; Group portraits; athletes; Religion; Children</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:description>Photomontage of libraries, the Calvary Cemetery entrance on Murfreesboro Road, composing staff of The Banner newspaper, and a group of high school football players with the Edgefield Cumberland Presbyterian Church. The athletes are from Central, Hume-Fogg, and Isaac Litton High Schools. Libraries pictured are at Bailey Junior High, Buena Vista Junior High, the Brown Opportunity School, Washington Junior High School, and the East and West branches of the Nashville Carnegie Library. 16 x 21.5 in. Forms part of the Nashville Newspaper Rotogravure Digital Images Collection.</dc:description>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1932 November 13</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text; Newspapers</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Newspaper Rotogravure Digital Images Collection.</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll19/id/245</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>