<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Photomontage of Tennessee babies and children. Nashville Banner, 1928 December 30. </dc:title>
<dc:subject>Williams, Bettie Irene; Hummer, June Wilson; Hummer, Irby H., Jr.; Pittard, Joe Doyle; Grimes, John Walter; Peterman, Marion; Caruthers, Frances Dent; Goodrich, Angela Celia; Neely, Wendell Louis; Menefee, Albert, Jr.; Hill, Harry Dale; Ballard, Robert Harmon; Ballard, Thomas Stanford; Gleaves, Alice Joy; Davenport, Bethel; Anderson, Betty Jane; Gier, Hugh Edward; Bass, Leslie; Bass, Wesley; Holt, Geneva Dean; Stubblefield, Charles Henry; Fyke, James Manlove; Evans, James David; Clay, Paul; Clay, Donna Mae; Bates, Dorothy Laura; Thoman, Alice Marie; Thoman, Alfred H.; Eakes, Mildred; Davis, Geraldine; Sneed, Roy Phillip; Grimes, Bobby; Hogan, Charles Bill; Neal, Herman Katherine; Neal, Larry Gray; Kane, Wilton R.; Pettigrew, Richard Raine; Jacobs, Carl Douglas</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Banner</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Infants; Children; Portraits</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:description>Photomontage of Tennessee babies and children. 16 x 21.5 in. Forms part of the Nashville Newspaper Rotogravure Digital Images Collection.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Thuss, A. J.; Adkisson Studio; Elbrick; Schumacher Studio; Lively, L. A.; Trail, Anson; Curtis, Ben T.; Vantrease; M. &amp; R. Studio; Staley's Studio; Harding Studio; Meyer &amp; Holt; Jenkins Studio</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1928 December 30</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text; Newspapers</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Newspaper Rotogravure Digital Images Collection.</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1920-1929</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll19/id/988</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>