<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Photomontage of a scene from a play, a church gathering, church leaders, a football game, law students, the Statue of Liberty, and masonic leaders. Nashville Banner, 1931 November 8.</dc:title>
<dc:subject>Dalton, Sydney; Hume, Mrs. Mayes; Dalton, May Herbert; Criddle, Virginia; Rosenblum, Anna; Guerry, Emily; Blackman, Barbara; Haggard, Eleanor; Rowan, Virginia; Roth, Helen; Schnitker, Clarence; Pearson; Poage; Craig, Robert J.; Collier, William J.; Woodward, James E.; Stewart, John R.; Polk, Greenfield Q.; Ballin, David; Hudson, Charles; Tisdale, Wade Hampton; Morse Jr., Joe; Rowell, Alex H.; Lewis, Gordon; Levy, H.; Bowen, A. Oscar; Caldwell, Sam Y.; Cohn, Maurice; Pierotti, Harry; Crouch, Joe; Connor; John; Rosenblatt, William; Young, B.; Ramson, Fletcher; Krugley, William; Pritchard, Howard; Beckham, Ben; Dodson, William; Miller, Katherine; Hearn, C. A.; Kunkle, George; Crownover, A.; Coffey, Shelby; Thompson, George W.; Yater, W. H.; Donnan, B. H.; Cain, H. B.; Cain, G. W.; Steel, H. C.; Rowan, B. H.; Minton, O. F.; Darr, W. W.; Smith, W. T.; Taylor, E. B.; Rutland, Neale M.; Handley, C. C.; Maddux, S. T.; Wiles, E. A.; Hamilton, J. P.; Lassiter, Neill H.; Hood, John E.; Smith, F. M.</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Banner</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Actors; Theatrical productions; Picnics; Churches; Football; Group portraits; students; Sculpture; Fraternal organizations</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:description>Photomontage of a scene from a play performed by the Nashville Conservatory of Music, the Goodlettsville Methodist church and leaders at the church's 100th anniversary, church leaders, a high school football game, Vanderbilt University law students, the Statue of Liberty, and masonic leaders. 16 x 21.5 in. Forms part of the Nashville Newspaper Rotogravure Digital Images Collection.</dc:description>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1931 November 8</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text; Newspapers</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Newspaper Rotogravure Digital Images Collection.</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll19/id/237</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>