<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Photomontage of Tennessee babies and children, and three ads. Nashville Banner, 1928 September 2. </dc:title>
<dc:subject>Caruthers, Wendell Wilson; Caruthers, Mildred Daun; Young, Hycinth; Gilliland, James Irvin, Jr.; Hall, Betty Doris; Hall, Anderton, Jr.; Jones, Horton A., Jr.; McCord, Delores; McCord, Dorothy; Moore, Phyllis Irene; Mingle, Willard Maron; Tomlin, Dorothy Ann; Lancaster, Ruth Evelyn; Swift, Sara Emagene; Maynord, Anna; Maynord, Janie Sue; Bradley, Vance Grayson; Bradley, Russell Edward; Jernigan, Mary Gladys; Swack, Edna Mae; Swack, Elba Elizabeth; Stewart, George William; Stewart, Eva Ethel; Gunn, June; Gunn, Nancy; Lee, Juanita; Taylor, William; Bailey, Laura Agnes; Bailey, Mildred Florence; Bailey, Stanley Merrell; Bearden, Hayes Elizabeth; Nichol, Bettie Jean; Miller, Bradford; Miller, Edward, Jr.; Halley, Edward Gailon; Henry, Doy Nesby; Campbell, Vanise Oleta; Hale, Dorothy Lee; Griffith, James Elbert; Waynick, Dewey Averette, Jr.; Sims, Marvin; Sims, Melvin; Sims, Ruth; Jones, Pauline Gwendolyn</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Banner</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Infants; Children; Portraits</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:description>Photomontage of Tennessee babies and children, and three ads.  16 x 21.5 in. Forms part of the Nashville Newspaper Rotogravure Digital Images Collection.  </dc:description>
<dc:creator>Schumacher Studio; M. &amp; R. Studios; Easter's Studio; Anderson Studio; Ferrell, Leo; Calvert Bros; Harding Studio; Elbrick; Stark, E. M.</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1928 September 2</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text; Newspapers</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Newspaper Rotogravure Digital Images Collection.</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1920-1929</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll19/id/1007</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>