<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Photomontage of a Massachusetts athlete with a baby, Elliott Jr. High School students, the engaged daughter of a Virginia governor, a document thanking a donor for his collection which is displayed at the War Memorial building, and an ad.  Nashville Banner, 1930 October 19.</dc:title>
<dc:subject>Mar, Clarence De; Pollard, Sue; Beerworth, C. W. Simpson, Eva; Dean, Gertrude; Woodside, Martha; Andrews, D'Moore; Turner, Vera; Stewart, Enice; Summers, Lucile; Johnson, Bertha; Binkley, Delores; Womack, Elizabeth; Sweeney, Maydelle; Hankey, Cecilia; Reeder, Lillian; Lannius; Annyce; Morgan, Ruby; Whitworth, Estelle; Tyler, Bessie; Setters, Mildred; White, Kathryn; Rollins, Hazel; Thomason, Elizabeth; Patton, Mary; Thomas, Aileen; Binkley, Carrie; Wills, Billie; Richards, Vera; McMurry, Howard; Hadley, Melvin; Demonbreum; Robinson, James; Moskovitz, Sara; Green, Perry; Bauman, Kenneth; Deep, Sam; Spelta, Peter; Travis, J. B.; Morris, Burton; Zink, Edward; Byrd, Mildred; Page, Frank; Sadler, Elma; Bull, Eldred</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Banner</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Athletes; Infants; Students; Portraits; Documents</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:description>Photomontage of a Massachusetts athlete holding his newborn daughter, students of Elliott Jr. High School, the engaged daughter of a Virginia governor and  a document thanking a donor for his collection which is displayed at the War Memorial building, and an ad. 16 x 21.5 in. Forms part of the Nashville Newspaper Rotogravure Digital Images Collection.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>West, J. Frank; P. &amp; A. Photo</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1930 October 19</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text; Newspapers</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BN Rotogravure 1930 October 19 004.jpg</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Newspaper Rotogravure Digital Images Collection.</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll19/id/430</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>