<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Photomontage showing US Navy aircraft and carrier, President Hoover's fishing retreat, competitive golfer and supporters, and Nashville resident at boat pageant. Nashville Tennessean, 1929 September 1. </dc:title>
<dc:subject>Jones, R. H.; Hurt, Sherwood; Black Jr., Charlie; Black, Mrs.; Jones, Bobby; Jones, Mrs. Bobby; Keeler, O. B.; Keeler, Mrs. O. B.; Compton, Mrs. Carl </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Tennessean</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Boats; Airplanes; Camps; Group portraits </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:description>Photomontage showing President Hoover's fishing retreat in western Virginia, Navy aircraft carrier and aircraft, a group of golfers and their supporters leaving for the National Amateur Golf Tournament and one photo showing Nashville resident Mrs. Carl Compton in a boat pageant at Lake Junaluska. 16 x 21.5 in Forms part of the Nashville Newspaper Rotogravure Digital Images Collection.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Associated Press</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1929 September 1</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text; Newspapers</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TN Rotogravure 1929 September 1 001.jpg</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Newspaper Rotogravure Digital Images Collection.</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1920-1929</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll19/id/318</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>