<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Photomontage of football players, a church nursery school class, a polar bear, two celebrity explorers, a library, and a club meeting space. Nashville, Banner, 1931 November 1.</dc:title>
<dc:subject>Roberts, H.; Roberts, David Dixie; Jones, Carolyn; Eden, Thomas; Bowers, Joan; Milton, Almira; Lamasters, Robert; Oman, Ann; Brush, Mae; Koty, Betty; Senter, James; Casey, Celeste Hale; Fergerson, William Paul; Williams, Gladys; Cooper, Benson; Warner, Mrs. L. A.; Poppelman, Ray; Wilkins, Hubert; Wilkins, Lady; Cohn, Corinne Leiberman; Cohn, Charles </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Banner</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Football; Children; Bears; Celebrities; Explorers; Libraries; Schools; Clubs</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:description>Photomontage of Central High School, Vanderbilt University, and Hume-Fogg High School football players, Immanuel Baptist Church nursery school class, a polar bear at the New York Zoo, two celebrity explorers, The Cohn School Library, and the Nashville Women's Club Home at 217 Louise Avenue. 16 x 21.5 in. Forms part of the Nashville Newspaper Rotogravure Digital Images Collection.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>International Newsreel</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1931 November 1</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text; Newspapers</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Newspaper Rotogravure Digital Images Collection.</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll19/id/234</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>