<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Photomontage of Egyptian scenes, a boat, a sculpture, a parade, and graduates of the West Tennessee Teachers College. Nashville Tennessean, 1929 June 16. </dc:title>
<dc:subject>Yost, Ross; Wood, Dorothy; Bright, Howard; Crosthwaite, Melda; Gerard, Josephine; Latting, Ellen; Smith, J. M.; Utz, Isabelle; Dowdy, C. H.; Moody, Mary Sue; Moore, Irene; Walker, Odus</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Tennessean</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Rivers; Dams; Pyramids; Boats; Sculpture; Portraits; Students; Universities &amp; colleges; Parades &amp; processions</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:description>Photomontage of a dam on the Nile, the Egyptian pyramids, an ocean liner docked in England, a sand sculpture of the Last Supper in California, a Memorial Day parade in Manhattan, and graduates of the West Tennessee Teachers College. 16 x 21.5 in. Forms part of the Nashville Newspaper Rotogravure Digital Images Collection. </dc:description>
<dc:creator>Cassaday; A. P. Photo; Herbert Photo</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1929 June 16</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text; Newspapers</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Newspaper Rotogravure Digital Images Collection.</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1920-1929</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll19/id/1029</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>