<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Photomontage of a balloon ascension, football players, a saloon, and Church Street. Nashville Banner, 1929 May 19. </dc:title>
<dc:subject>King; Fisher, Billy; Davis, Charles; Warren, George; Lindsey, Dick; Litton, Cooper; Whitworth James; Williams, Percy; Power, Bob; Compton, Thomas; Brown, Sam; Brown, J. P. W.; Goodpasture, Dillard; Hardcastle, Kendrick; French, Horace; DeMoss, Skelt; Cave, Robert L.; Geer, Charles; Cleveland, Grover</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Banner</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Balloons (Aircraft); Football; Bars; Streets</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:description>Photomontage of an 1892 balloon ascension in downtown Nashville, football players at Wharton Academic School, a saloon decorated for a presidential visit, and Church Street. 16 x 21.5 in. Forms part of the Nashville Newspaper Rotogravure Digital Images Collection.</dc:description>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1929 May 19</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text; Newspapers</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Newspaper Rotogravure Digital Images Collection.</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1920-1929</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll19/id/887</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>