<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Photomontage of children and babies of Tennessee families, and three ads. Nashville Banner, 1932 November 20.</dc:title>
<dc:subject>Connings, Dorothy Helen; Robinson, William Howard; Fowler, Marion; Grant, Burton Paine; Nelson, Marjorie; Medlin, Vernon Leon; Mizell, Lucy Merrill; Green, James Clyde; Lee, Jane; Lee, John Moore; Newby, Billy Roy; Lish, William Burten; Camp, Harry Ward; Murphree, Slaydon Hudson; Farris, Carter Miller; Melton, Ruby Laverne; Wilson, Eva Francis; Hatler, Jo Ann; Fleming, Robert; McKee, James Thomas; Hicks, Charles C.; McAlister, John Hill; Sanders, Mary Virginia; Stovall, Kenneth W.; Reale, Regina; Baker Jr., Thomas; Greene, Robert Moore; Hendricks, James S.; Dinwiddie, Robert; Butts, Thomas; Butts, Lloyd Francis; Cox, Margie Louise; Davis, Laurel Dorina; York Jr., Master James Marvin; Hicks, Gladys Aline; Jordan, Robert Norman; Ledbetter, Harold Thomas; Yates, Margaret Daphyne</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Banner</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Infants; Children; Portraits</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:description>Photomontage of children and babies of Tennessee families, and three ads, one of which features a local child. 16 x 21.5 in. Forms part of the Nashville Newspaper Rotogravure Digital Images Collection.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Hitt Studio; Thuss, A. J.</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1932 November 20</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text; Newspapers</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Newspaper Rotogravure Digital Images Collection.</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll19/id/255</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>