<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Photomontage of a circus performer, a natural bridge, a kindergarten class, and three landscapes. Nashville Banner, 1928 July 1. </dc:title>
<dc:subject>Parks, Homer H.; Moore, Lucy Holt; Hayes, J. R., Jr.; Morrow, Lista Lee; Bezzill, W. B., Jr.; O'Neal, Louise; Sullivan, Christine; Frensley, Houston; Walker, William; O'Neal, Rosie; Boone, Daisy; Colbert, Katherine; Dunn, Lois; Morphis, Garland; Hartley, Louella; Hayes, Ruth; Purdom, Aubrey</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Banner</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Circus performers; Bridges; Children; Landscapes (representations); Bears</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:description>Photomontage of a tall circus performer from Spring Hill, Tennessee, a natural bridge in Bermuda, a graduating kindergarten class from Wesley House, a broken treetop in the Pacific Northwest, bears in Glacier National Park, and a landscape in the Canadian rockies. 16 x 21.5 in. Forms part of the Nashville Newspaper Rotogravure Digital Images Collection.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Thuss, W. G.; Union Pacific Photo; Canadian Pacific Photo</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1928 July 1</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text; Newspapers</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Newspaper Rotogravure Digital Images Collection.</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1920-1929</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15769coll19/id/968</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>