<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Department of Energy Photograph Collection</dc:title>
<dc:title>General Groves holds his first press conference</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>VIP 0050</dc:identifier>
<dc:contributor>Edward Westcott</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1945-08-30</dc:date>
<dc:description>A group of men and two women sit or stand around a table. Three men and one woman wear military uniforms.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Interiors; Military uniforms; Press conferences; Soldiers; Uniforms</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Adams, Virgil; Dobbs, George; Fell, Philip; Filippi, Catherine; Gates, Frances S.; Gehman, Richard B.; Groves, Leslie R., 1896-1970; Howard, Lafitte; Marsden, Earl H.; Miller, Loye; Smith, Edward B.; Stern, Daniel K.; Wells, Horace V.; Yarbrough, Willard</dc:subject>
<dc:description>Oak Ridge, Tennessee</dc:description>
<dc:description>See Oak Ridge Journal article of September 6, 1945. Left to right, around the table, Horace V. Wells, Clinton Courier News; Virgil Adams, Lenoir City News; General Groves; Lt. Philip Fell; Col. Earl H. Marsden; George Dobbs, TEC Bulletin; Frances S. Gates, Oak Ridge Journal; Edward B. Smith, Knoxville News-Sentinel; Lafitte Howard, AP; Loye Miller, and (back to camera) Willard Yarbrough, News-Sentinel. In background, Lt. Catherine Filippi; Richard B. Gehman, Oak Ridge Journal and Daniel K. Stern, Knoxville Journal.</dc:description>
<dc:description>PRO 979-3; 8-30-1945</dc:description>
<dc:publisher>Oak Ridge Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:type>Photograph</dc:type>
<dc:format>Black and White</dc:format>
<dc:description>8 x 10</dc:description>
<dc:format>JPEG image</dc:format>
<dc:description>435 KB</dc:description>
<dc:description>Oak Ridge Public Library</dc:description>
<dc:contributor>United States Department of Energy</dc:contributor>
<dc:rights>Physical rights are retained by the institution. Copyright is retained in accordance with U. S. Copyright laws.</dc:rights>
<dc:source>Oak Ridge Public Library, 1401 Oak Ridge Trpke, Oak Ridge, TN 37830 reference@oakridgetn.gov</dc:source>
<dc:date>2012-11</dc:date>
<dc:contributor>Thompson Photo Products, Knoxville, TN</dc:contributor>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16107.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15388cdi/id/717</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>