<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Department of Energy Photograph Collection</dc:title>
<dc:title>Oak Ridge Hospital medical staff 1943-1945</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>MED 0140</dc:identifier>
<dc:contributor>Edward Westcott</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1946-03</dc:date>
<dc:description>Portraits of men arranged around a caduceus.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Directories; Physicians; Oak Ridge Hospital (Oak Ridge, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Bansmer, Gustav; Beller, Cleve; Bernstein, William; Blum, Bernard; Bryant, Frank; Cartnick, Joseph; Clark, Dwight; Clarke, Eric; Clarkson, William; Dahleen, Henry; Dale, Peter; Dean, Donald; DePersio, John; Donoghue, Francis; Eneboe, John; Fannin, Thomas; Fleeson, William; Frank, Edward; Friedell, Hymer; Gilbert, John; Goldring, David; Hamblin, Leonard; Hays, Albert; Hummel, Fred; Ibsen, Maxwell; Inda, Frank; Johnson, Robert; Kallestad, Leonard; Kearns, Barry; Keettel, William; Kimberly, Lester; Knutson, Gerhard; Koltoff, Leon; LaFond, Robert; Latona, Salvatore; Law, Stanley; Lindberg, Vernon; Loue, Selby; Mears, Burtis; Moody, Frank; Murphy, Francis; O'Connor, Kenneth; Olsen, Edward; Phillipsborn, Herbert; Preston, Lewis; Prosser, Charles; Pugh, William; Ragan, Julian; Rea, Charles; Ridley, James; Riley, William; Rogers, Joseph; Royer, Clark; Ryan, Joseph; Salisbury, Earl; Seegar, King; Stoltz, Rodney; Stout, Joseph; Tasher, Dean; Thompson, Albert; Wake, Douglas; Warkentin, John; Warren Stafford; Whitaker, Carl; White, Asher</dc:subject>
<dc:description>Oak Ridge, Tennessee</dc:description>
<dc:description>Top row, Left to right: William Bernstein, Frank Bryant,William Keettel, Leonard Kallestad, Albert Hays, Hymer Friedell, Stafford Warren, Charles Rea, Gerhard Knutson, Burtis Mears, Edward Olsen, Joseph Ryan, Asher White. Left section, top row to bottom, left to right: Gustav Bansmer, Cleve Beller, Bernard Blum, Joseph Cartnick, Dwight Clark, Eric Clarke, William Clarkson, Henry Dahleen, Peter Dale, Donald Dean, John DePersio, Francis Donoghue, John Eneboe, Thomas Fannin, William Fleeson, Edward Frank, John Gilbert, David Goldring, Leonard Hamblin, Fred Hummel, Maxwell Ibsen, Frank Inda, Robert Johnson, Barry Kearns, Lester Kimberly, Leon Koltoff. Right section, top row to bottom, left to right: Robert LaFond, Salvatore Latona, Stanley Law, Vernon Lindberg, Selby Loue, Frank Moody, Francis Murphy, Kenneth O'Connor, Herbert Phillipsborn, Lewis Preston, Charles Prosser, William Pugh, Julian Ragan, James Ridley, William Riley, Joseph Rogers, Clark Royer, Earl Salisbury, King Seegar, Rodney Stoltz, Joseph Stout, Dean Tasher, Albert Thompson, Douglas Wake, John Warkentin, Carl Whitaker.</dc:description>
<dc:description>1553; 3-1946; Medical Staff-Oak Ridge Hospital</dc:description>
<dc:publisher>Oak Ridge Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:type>Photograph</dc:type>
<dc:format>Black and White</dc:format>
<dc:description>8 x 10</dc:description>
<dc:format>JPEG image</dc:format>
<dc:description>107 KB</dc:description>
<dc:description>Oak Ridge Public Library</dc:description>
<dc:contributor>United States Department of Energy</dc:contributor>
<dc:rights>Physical rights are retained by the institution. Copyright is retained in accordance with U. S. Copyright laws.</dc:rights>
<dc:source>Oak Ridge Public Library, 1401 Oak Ridge Trpke, Oak Ridge, TN 37830 reference@oakridgetn.gov</dc:source>
<dc:date>2012-02</dc:date>
<dc:contributor>Thompson Photo Products, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:contributor>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16107.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15388cdi/id/418</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>