<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Department of Energy Photograph Collection</dc:title>
<dc:title>First meeting of southeastern universities representatives to form Oak Ridge Institute of Nuclear Studies</dc:title>
<dc:identifier>MTG 0010</dc:identifier>
<dc:contributor>Edward Westcott</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1946-10</dc:date>
<dc:description>Fifteen men are seated around a conference table.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Interiors; Meetings; Oak Ridge Institute of Nuclear Studies</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Branscomb, Harvie; Brehm, C. E.; Funkhouser, W. D.; Graham, Frank P.; Herzfeld; Carl F.; Hoxton, L. G.; McDaniel, Paul W.; Morris, J. C.; Neilson, W. M.; Parks, J. H.; Paty, Raymond; Pollard, W. G.; Poor, Russell S.; Rosselot, G. A.; Sarbacker, Robert I.; Slack, Frances G.</dc:subject>
<dc:description>Oak Ridge, Tennessee</dc:description>
<dc:description>Date is taken from Oak Ridge Journal article of October 17, 1946. This article does not have a photograph, but it does list the representatives as Frank P. Graham, President, University of North Carolina; C. E. Brehm,President, University of Tennessee; Raymond Paty, President, University of Alabama; Harvie Branscomb, Chancellor, Vanderbilt Univeristy; W. D. Funkhouser, Dean, University of Kentucky; Russell S. Poor, Dean, Alabama Polytechnic Institute; Paul W. McDaniel, Acting Chief of Technical Branch of Research Division, Manhattan District and professors Frances G. Slack, Vanderbilt; W. M. Neilson, Duke; J. C. Morris, Tulane; J. H. Parks, Emory; Robert I. Sarbacker, Georgia Institute of Technology; G. A. Rosselot, Georgia Institute of Technology; Carl F. Herzfeld, Catholic University of America; L. G. Hoxton, University of Virginia; W. G. Pollard, University of Tennessee. William G. Pollard is on the right, with pipe in hand.</dc:description>
<dc:description>3045-5; 1945; First Meeting of Representatives From South Eastern Universities For Forming ORINS</dc:description>
<dc:publisher>Oak Ridge Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:type>Photograph</dc:type>
<dc:format>Black and White</dc:format>
<dc:description>8 x 10</dc:description>
<dc:format>JPEG image</dc:format>
<dc:description>110 KB</dc:description>
<dc:description>Oak Ridge Public Library</dc:description>
<dc:contributor>United States Department of Energy</dc:contributor>
<dc:rights>Physical rights are retained by the institution. Copyright is retained in accordance with U. S. Copyright laws.</dc:rights>
<dc:source>Oak Ridge Public Library, 1401 Oak Ridge Trpke, Oak Ridge, TN 37830 reference@oakridgetn.gov</dc:source>
<dc:date>2012-02</dc:date>
<dc:contributor>Thompson Photo Products, Knoxville, Tennessee</dc:contributor>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16107.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15388cdi/id/426</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>