<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>James M. Buchanan on Keynesian economics</dc:title>
<dc:relation>Sidelines, February 8, 1977. p. 5</dc:relation>
<dc:creator>Daley, Pat, photographer;</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1977-02-08</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1970-1977</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Article from Sidelines, student publication of Middle Tennessee State University. Describes a talk given by James M. Buchanan on campus on Feb. 7, 1977. His talk covered the impacts of Keynesian economic policy in the wake of the depression of the 1930s and the prospects for a constitutional amendment to address deficits of the U.S. government. A photograph of the speaker is included.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Buchanan graduated from MTSU in 1940 before moving to the University of Chicago for his graduate work.</dc:description>
<dc:description>James McGill Buchanan</dc:description>
<dc:description>Tuesday, February 8, 1977

Sidelines

Page 5

Misapplication of Keynesian theories faulted

Objections have been raised to using Keynesian tools in democracy because Keynes was not a democrat, national economist James Buchanan said last night.
Speaking to over 100 persons, Buchanan said the "political democracy may not be able to survive the Keynesian test."
The Keynesian idea aimed at the 1930's was concerned with unemployment and demand, Buchanan said. The policy followed was to create a deficit to create more spending.

' 'We did not apply the Keynesian principles properly, the MTSU graduate said. The Keynesian teachings were a "gross intellectual oversight by persons in these ivory towers because they overlooked democracy, "Buchanan maintained. The Keynesian principles may "yet be judged a curse."
The Post-Keynesian thinking is not the answer to the nation's economic problems. It just doesn't work anymore.
Instead, the economist proposed that a set of constitutional rules be established. The constitutional rule "would put us on the record as saying that's what we want."Presently, there is not much hope of a constitutional rule but Buchanan would not rule out the possibility.

Buchanan predicted the nation's deficit would reach $85 billion during the 1978 fiscal year. For persons who believe the budget may be balanced in 1981, Buchana is skeptical. "It is just the never, never land of politics."Voters want reduced taxes and more federal spendings so that the politicians respond.
"The politicians create the deficits and the economists five excuses," he commented. In the five-year period between 1971-1975, the federal budget exceeded revenue by $110 billion, Buchanan said. During the period of 1975-76, the deficit was more than the five-year increase.Over the next five years, the deficit will reach between $250 to $500 billion, the economist predicted.

"My charge is that the Keynesian economy is incompatible with the political economy," he said. "Must we allow ourselves to destroy our institution?"
The popular notion that the "trade-off" of inflation and unemplo3Tnent would balance each James Buchanan other doesn't  work  anymore,  he added.
Balancing the budget over the business cycle and allowing the revenue to build up to a surplus is irrelevant, Buchanan said. 
As a means to curb unemployment, Buchanan said the repeal of a minimum wage law for teen-agers would cause the unemployment rate to decrease two percent overnight.

MTSU photo by Pat Daley</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Economic policy; Buchanan, James M.</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Rutherford County (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright held by Middle Tennessee State University;</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>May be reproduced for educational and research purposes. Credit image to Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, MTSU</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/buchanan/id/13</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>