<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>A short genealogy of the Ridley, Buchanan, Gooch, Kimbro &amp; McEwan families</dc:title>
<dc:title>Frow Chips</dc:title>
<dc:date>2006</dc:date>
<dc:description>A narrative genealogy of the Ridley, Buchanan and related families. Includes some anecdotal recollections of family history. Documents births into the late 19th century. Published in Frow Chips, newsletter of the Rutherford County Historical Society.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Excerpt from the newsletter of the Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:description>
<dc:description>Volume 35, Issue 3 5 January/February 2006
A short genealogy of the Ridley, Buchanan, Gooch, Kimbro &amp;
McEwen families Captain George Thomas Ridley h. Jan 11,
1737 probably in Guilford Couthouse, NC and d. Dec 2, 1835 at
Ridley Station Mill Creek, Davidson Co., TN. He m. (1)
Eliza~ethMaria "Betsy" Weatherford, b. 1744 in VAand d. Nov
24, 1776 at Watauga Settlemen4 TN Territory; m. (2) Sarah
"Sally" Vincent b. May 1, 1754 an~ d. Mar 20, '1836 Ridley
Station, Mill Creek, Davidson Co., TN. Capt. George Ridley was
a famous early settler of; Tennessee, a Revolutionary War
Veteran; designated '''Defender of the Frontier" by Congress; a
Veteran of the French and Indian War (at Braddocks Defeat
with George Washington in 1755); came to the Watauga TN
Territory in 1772; came to 'Nashville with family in 1779; one of
the builders and occupants of Ft. Nashhoro from 1779-1784;
Signer ofthe Cumberland Compact 1784; owner ofthousands of
acres in souther Davidson Co. (now part of Rutherford Co.) by
1790; build Ridley Station on Mill Creek, 2 miles from Buchanan
Station (site of the Mill Creek Cemetery) in 1784; and a national
historical marker is at the site.
Children of George and Betsy Ridley:
1. Beverly Ridley (1762-1844) m. (1) Annie Williams (2)
Elizabeth Gooch, daughter of David Gooch
2. George Ridley (1764-1793) m. Thankful Doak
3. John Ridley (1765 - ? in GA)
4. William Ridley (1767-1787) killed by Indians
. 5. Patsey Ridley (1770-1792) m. James Wright
6. Elizaheth "Betsy" Ridley (1772-1854) m. (1) Robert
McMinn; (2) William H. Smith
7. Sarah "Sallie" Ridley (1773-1835) m. Maj. John Buchanan
(1759 in PA - 1832 Buchanan Station, TN) [SEE
FURTHER]. Sallie Ridley Buchanan was called "'&#163;rrst lady
of the frontier" by eastern papers throughout her life;
possibly the tIrst female born in Tennessee Territory; lived
as a young girl in Ridley Station; famous in the Battle of
Buchanan Station (1792); said to be large, tough, rough,
kind, crude, gentle.
8. Lettie Ridley (1776-?) m (1) James Roberts; (2) James
Everett
Children of Georae and Sallie Ridley:
9. Vincent Marr Ridley (1778-1853) m. Lydia Everett
10. Thomas E. Ridley (1780-1854 in Miss.) m. Peggy Harwood
11. Col. Moses Ridley (1782-1854 Stewarts Creek, Rutherford
Co., TN) m. Catherine Carroll Harwood (1793~1841) Moses
Ridley built Buchanan's Mill at Stewarts Creek. Children~
John Clark Ridley; George Vincent Ridley., Louisa Abigail
Ridley, Sarah Buchanon Ridley; Susan Margaret Ridley;
William Henry Ridley, Washington Green Ridley; Narcissa
"Vicksburg" on it, given to my father by one of his men; and his
fine watch, which he gave to one of his men not so badly
wounded and told him to "take it to my wife."
Uncle James had returned to his regiment, and mother had
gone back to Mississippi, so I spent my time on the plantation
and at school in Monticello, but I finally went to my aunt's (Mrs.
Ridley) after I left school. This aunt lived ten miles away and I
had to make the trip in an ox cart, as all our horses had been 
taken. A Negro man drove the cart in which I rode with a Negro
woman and my Saratoga trunk, which contained all of my
earthly possessions.
My aunt had a young daughter, and we three women were
the only white people on the hig plantation. While I was there,
a merchant from Nashville, a kinsman, John B. Everett, stopped
over on his way to Macon, Ga., and to him I gave a hundred
dollars with which to huy me ten yards of calico and another
hundred for a pair of store shoes. He got them for me, and I felt.
very well-fixed indeed with my new calico and a silk dress that
my mother had left me when she went hack to Mississippi,also
a green plaid delaine made from an old dress of my aunt's. All
these had been made up for Christmas, which was not far off,
and hung away in the closet upstairs.
After Stoneman left that section there was a great deal of
suffering, and all the mills and factories had heen burned and
the poor people were out of work. One night, two boys, about
ten and twelve years old, came to my aunt's asking for something
to eat and a place to sleep. We took them in and put them
upstairs to sleep. We thought nothing of their leaving so early
the next morning, but in a about a week, when I went upstairs to
look at my dresses, I found them gone. You can imagine how
heartsick I was over having my pretty frocks stolen.
Aunt and I would talk often about the war and what we had
to eat. Our coffee was made of parched meal, dried sweet
potatoes, peanuts, okra, and such things; our sweetening was
sugar cane and molasses; our drink was a persimmon beer, made.
in a tub. Our main thought was, when will this cruel war he
over?
It was soon to end. Many of the soldiers from Tennessee
came to Forsyth, for there was a large Ridley family living
around there, and they took care of all the kin and friends until .
they were able to get money from Tennessee to go home on. Old
Dr. Charles Ridley and his wife, a remarkable woman, had been
pioneers in that section, and their three sons had married and
lived near them. They were all kindness itself in giving what
they had to the stranded soldiers. Many of these soldiers had
been paroled in that section, and among them were Gen. A. P.
Stewart and his two sons; Judge Bromfield Ridley, his two sons
and a daughter, who marri.ed later on and was the mother of
Admiral Ridley McLean, of the present U. S. Navy, and there
was Capt. James Ridley. Mter conditions had improved, my
uncle, Mr. Camillus Huggins, came down to Ga. to get the four
thousand dollars in gold which we had been keeping for him
(burying it for safety), and he took me back to Tennessee to my
people, who supplied me with everything I needed.
When we left Mississippi, there were five hundred bales of
cotton on the plantation, hut when uncle went back after the
war, only five hales could he found. Mter going hack to
Mississippi from Georgia, my mother had her beautiful china
and our family silverware buried, and I thought the silverware
had he~n stolen, as I never saw it again; hut I learned some years
ago that in settling up my father's estate after the war everything
had been sold, and a cousin had bought the silver. So that was
one time the Yankees missed a trick.
written 1929 by Margaret Ridley Gooch (Mrs. Nathaniel)
.******************************
Volume 35") Issue 3 6 January/February.2006
Frances Ridley; Samuellen Jones Ridley; Mary Josephine
Ridley; Amanda C. Ridley.
12. James M. "Jimmy" Ridley (1784-1847) m. Amy Anne
Hamilton, da~terorCol. Hance Hamilton. Jimmy Ridley
was in the War of 1812 and a close personal friend of Pres.
Andrew Jackson.
13. Abbagil "'Abby" Ridley (1786-1836) m. Charles Mulherrin
14. Sarah Winneford "Winny'" Ridley (1789-?) m. Col. James,
Mitchell
15. Samuel Jones Ridley (1791-1827) m. Sally Hay
16. Henry Ridley (1794-1835 in Smyrna, TN) m. Elizabeth
Allison (1797-1873). Henry was "a man of considerable
note and great agricultural worth; was a member of the
convention to amend the State constitution." Children:
James Derrick Ridley; George Granville Ridley (m. Rebecca
B. McEwen); William A. Ridley; Samuel Jones Ridley [SEE
FURTHER]; James Allison Ridley (m. Almira Pauline
Russworm); Mary Jane Ridley; Sallie Elizabeth Ridley (m.
Camillus B. Huggins); Henry Ridley; Nancy Allison Ridley
(m. #1 John Clark Ridley, son of Col. Mose&#183;s Ridley &amp; #2
Valentine S. Allen)
Capt. Samuel Jones Ridley (1821-1863 Baker's Creek, MS)
[FATHER OF 1929 LETTER WRITER] m. (1) Sarah Caroline
McEwen (1822-1848), daughter of Christopher Ervin McEwen
and Rebecca Brown; (2) Hannah McMahon (1837-?). Child of
Samuel Jones and Sarah Caroline: Sarah Margaret Ridley
(1847-June 6.. 1932 in Murfrees~oro)m, 1870 NathanielGooch
(ea 1838-ea 1910) [SEE FURTHER]. Children: John Claiborne
Gooch h. 1871; Jones Ridley Gooch h. 1874; Robert Nathaniel
Gooch b. 1877.
Maj. John Buchanan, Jr. (1759 in PA-1832 in TN) m. Sarah
"Sallie" Ridley (1773-1835), daughter of Capt. George Thomas
Ridley &amp; Betsy Weatherford (see ahove). [from Memoirs in the
possession of Mrs. Harlow Chandler]"MAJOR JOHN
BUCHANAN was born at Harrisburg, Pennsylvania, January
12, 1759, and was the oldest son of James and Jane Trimble
Buchanan (of Scotch Irish descent). He was a brave old man
with a liberal, generous disposition, endowed with the faculty of
precaution and prudence, a well balanced mind, of sound
judgment, a noble soul and a spirit of keen susceptibility, having
accompanied his father through all his meanderings over
mountain and vale, sharing with him in all his trials, labors,
dangers, and hardships incident to the first settlers ofthe middle
states of America, greatly qualified him as a leader, protector
and benefactor. The father, through age and infIrmity caused by
trial, exposure and hardship that the pioneers of the American
continent had to undergo, became unable to maintain and
defend his family. This duty devolved upon the son, he being the
moving spirit and nucleus around which the hope of future
support protection and happiness of the mother and sisters
clung. He necessarily assumed the care and responsibility ofthe
family. The spirit of adventure so inherent in the father had its
potent influence on the 80n. The wonderful accounts made of
him through exploring, enterprising settlers of the beauties and
fertility of the Cumberland Valley country, with its abundance
of wild game that nature had seemingly turned loose to graze
upon the luxuriant cane brakes and tangled pea vine that grew
so profusely throughout this beautiful country; his ambitious
spirit and love for adventure could be held in subjection no longer..
MAJOR JOHN BUCHANAN, with his father's family, left
Danville, Kentucky, for the Cumberland country with the fond
hope of finding a permanent home. They arrived where
Nashville is now located December 14, 1778, and crossed the
Cumberland River on the ice at the mouth of Sulphur Spring
branch. On his arrival he found General James Robertson and
one other man living in log cabins on the bluff of the
Cumberland River where the county jail now stands. The third
house erected was built by Buchanan andd his comrades. These
pioneers, as a means ofbetter protection and defense against the
attacks ofthe various bands ofIndians frequently maraudingthe
settlement, built a fort on the bluff over the Cumberland River
on what is now Front Street, near to where the county prison
stands. In 1781 the Indians invaded the settlement and
Alexander Buchanan, brother of Major John Buchanan, was
killed by the Indians near the crossing of Market and Broad
streets. After staying at the Nashville fort four years, MAJOR
BUCHANAN moved six miles east of the Nashville fort and
erected his rude cabin on astream now called Mill Creek from
the fact that he afterward built the first mill that was ever
erected in the county on it. As a necessity, he soon built a fort in
simplicity of style but formidable in strength to guard against the attacks of the Indians in their savage mode ofwarfare in the time ofthe early settlers ofTennessee. On the night of September 30, 1792 the combined force of three tribes of Indians, numbering 900 warriors, made an attack upon Buchanan station thinking from the simplicity of its structure and weakness of its defense to over-ride that "cow pen fort" so styled by the Indians. With true gallantry these brave men, like Spartans, stood to their posts, and with unerring aim with their flint rock rifles held the fort and defeated the enemy with the slight wounding of one man in the fort. 

One Indian chief was killed, and left near the fort, in
the act of setting the fort on fire. From the blood and other signs&#183;
left by the Indians there were many others killed or wounded. In
the heat of the hattIe, the ammunition in the fort began to get
scarce and Nancy Mulheron, sister of Major Buchanan, melted
the pewter plates and dishes used by the early settlers and
moulded them into bullets, and carried them while hot in her
apron around to the men fighting. The men engaged in this battle
were: Major John Buchanan., James Bryant, Thomas Wilcox,
James O'Conner, Robin Castleman, James Mulheron, Thomas
McCrary, Morris Shane, William Kennedy, Samuel Blair, Robin
Kennedy, Thomas Durat, George Finalson, Charles Herd,
Sampson Williams, John Castleman, Samuel McMurray, Robin
Turnbull, Thomas Latimer, Robin Hood, and James Thompson,
JAMES BUCHANAN, father of this branch of the Buchanan
family in Tennessee, was killed by an Indian in his cahin near
the fort two or three months before the battle of September 30, 1792.
Children of Maj. John &amp; Sallie Ridley Buchanan:
1. George Buchanan (1792-1816)
2. Alexander "Alex" Buchanan (1794-~836) m. Mary T"
Ridley, daughter of John Ridley

3. Elizabeth "Betsy" Buchanan (1795-1875) m. Thomas
Hardeman "Tom" Everett (parents of John Buchanan
Everett mentioned in the story by Mrs. Gooch)
4. Samuel Buchanan (1797-1836)
5. William Buchanan (1800-1849) m. Jane E. Hogan
6. Jane T. Buchanan (1802-1837)m. George Moses Goodwin, Jr.
7. James Bryant Buchanan (1804-1862) m. Lettie Roberts
8. Moses Ridley Buchanan (1806-1887) m. Sarah Elizabeth
"Sallie" V~centRidley, daughter ofJames M. "Jimmy" and
Amy Anne Hamilton Ridley
9. Sarah Vincent "Sallie" Buchanan (1807-1866) m. James
Blanton Williams
10. Charles Bingley Buchanan (1809-1856)
11. Richard Gregory "Dick" Buchanan (1811-d. in Memphis)
m. Martha A. Murphey
12. Senator Henry Ridley Buchanan (1814-1898) never
married, was scalped by Indians but survived, elected TN
State Senator from Davidson &amp; Wilson districts 1875
13. Nancy Mulherrin Buchanan (1818-1881) m. #1 Henry
Bridges ~2 Jackson Smith.
William Gooch of Hanover Co., VA and later Caswell Co.,
NC was a Revolutionary War veteran, m. Frances Rice. Seven
ofWilliam &amp; Frances' 12 children came to TN: Nathaniel Gooch
(1768-1841) [SEE FURTHER]); Thomas Gooch (d. in
Williamson Co., TN); James Gooch; David Gooch, Ann "Nancy"
Gooch (m. Jesse Benton, parents of Thomas' Hart Benton);
Elizabeth Gooch (m. William Kimbro, Sen.); Mary "Polly"
Gooch (m. ? Williams).
Nathaniel Gooch (1768-1841 near old Jefferson, Rutherford
Co., TN) m. Martha ""Patsy" Taterrait (1777-1827) and had four
known children:
1. Sarah W. Gooch
2. John Claiborne Gooch (1800-1853) m. Eliza Ann Saunders
(1814-1877) and had 10 children:
. a. Col. John "Jack" Saunders Gooch [MENTIONED IN
1929 LETTER]
h. Robert Saunders Gooch
c. Dr. Nathaniel Gooch [HUSBAND OF 1929LETTER BY
MARGARET RIDLEY GOOCH]
d..John Claiborne Gooch
e. Martha Tait Gooch
f. Eliza Gooch
g. William Gooch
h. James Gooch
i. Pinkney Gooch
j. Claiborne Alexander Gooch
3. Lucinda Tait Gooch (1803-1867) m. Joseph A. Kimbro!
Kimbrough (1790-1860) son of William Kimbro, Sen. &amp;
Elizabeth Gooch. Lucinda &amp; Joseph Kimbro had at least 12
children:
NELMEADE by Lawson B. Nelson
The Nelson home, Nelmeade, was owned by Mr. &amp; Mrs.
Lawson B. Nelson of the Lavergne Community until it was sold
to the McDowell Development Corporation in 1970. Their two
sons became the fifth generation ofthis family to live there. The
7 JanuarylFebruary 2006
a. Martha L. Tait Kimbro m. 1842 Priged Mike Mire
Alexander (his 18t wife)
b. Sarah W. Gooch m. William Scruggs
c. Mary Elizabeth Kimbro m. 1849 Priged Mike Mire
Alexander (his 2nd wife)
d. Narcissus Sophronia Kimbro
e. John Claiborne Gooch Kimbro
f. Joseph A. Kimbro
g. Frances Cornelia Kimbro
h. Nathaniel Gooch Kimbro
i. William W. Kimbro
j. Nancy Ann Kimbro
k. Ellen Cone Kimbro
I. James W. Kimbro. .
4. Allen Tait Gooch (1806-1883) m. Elizabeth Venable Morton.
David McEwen (1756 in PA - 1821 in Williamson Co., TN)
m. in NC Margaret Ervin (1761-1822). Children of David &amp;
Margaret McEwen:
a. James McEwen m. Elizabeth "Betsy" Goff
b. Jane McEwen died young
c. Isabella Miller McEwen m. John Goff
d. Mary McEwen died young
e. Christopher Ervin McEwen (1790-1868) m. (1) Rebecca
Brown; (2) Narcissa Newson.
Children of Christopher &amp; Rebecca McEwen:
(1) Johnnie McEwen
(2) Elizabeth Brown McEwen died }Toung
(3) David McEwen died young
(4) John Brown McEwen m. Cynthia Graham
(5) Sarah Caroline McEwen [MOTHER OF 1929
LETTER BY MARGARET RIDLEY GOOCH]
(6) Rebecca Brown McEwen b.1822, m. #1 George
Granville Ridley, son of Henry &amp; Elizabeth Allison
Ridley and had son Christopher Henry "Kit" Ridley
(1842-1864 in Atlanta) [MENTIONED IN 1929
LEYrER]. Rebecca m. #2 John Campbell.
Children of Christopher &amp; Narcissa McEwen:
(7) Isabella Goff McEwen
(8) Margaret McEwen
(9) Ann P. "Annie" McEwen
(10) Mary Harwood McEwen
(11) James Knox Polk McEwen
(12) Suse McKinney McEwen.
f. Sallie B. McEwen m. Simon Glenn
g. John Lapsley McEwen m. Tabitha H. Barfield
h. Margaret Dickson McEwen m. #1 Mr. Brandon, #2
Martin Lane
i. Matilda McEwen died young
j. Cyrus J. McEwen
k. Eleanor Caroline McEwen m. Henry C. Stephens.
house on old Rock Springs Road, now Waldron Road, built
about 1835, or before, by John Hill, was designed in the style of the prosperous farmer with office and kitchen detached. At one time the place had a cotton gin and grist mill. Construction of the house was of hand hewn walnut, poplar and cedar, dressed

</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Buchanan family; Ridley family; Genealogy</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Rutherford County (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Periodical</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>3 p.</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright of the author</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>May be reproduced for personal or educational purposes with attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/buchanan/id/18</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>