<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Exploits of Major John Buchanan, the founder of Buchanan's Station</dc:title>
<dc:title>Old times in Tennessee: with historical, political and personal scraps and sketches</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Guild, Jo Conn</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1878</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1760-1769; 1770-1779; 1789-1789; 1790-1799</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Chapter 13 of the book, Old Times in Tennessee, describes the life of Major John Buchanan. The chapter emphasizes battles with Indians during the early days of Nashville but also notes family lineage and later experiences.</dc:description>
<dc:description>SCRAPS AND SKETCHES.
Some said, Jo, print it
Others said, not so 
Some said it might do good
Others said, no
- John Bunyan
By JO. C. GUILD,
JUDGE OF THE LAW COURT OF NASHVILLE
Nashville
TAVEL, EASTMAN &amp; HOWELL,
1898.

300 OLD TIMES IN TENNESSEE
XIII.
EXPLOITS OF MAJ. BUCHANAN, FOUNDER OF
BUCHANAN'S STATION.
MAJ. JOHN BUCHANAN was born at Harrisburg, Pa., January 12, 1759. 
His father was of Scotch-Irish descent. His
mother's maiden name was Jane Trindle. The family consisted
of three sons, John, Samuel and Alexander; and two daughters,
Sally, who married James Todd, and Nancy, who married James
Mullherrin. This family removed from Harrisburg to North
Carolina, but remained only a few years in that State. Thence
they went to Kentucky, and settled where the town of Danville
now stands. After remaining there four years, they, in company
with friends, came to Tennessee, making the trip through
the wilderness to the Cumberland river opposite the mouth of
Lick Branch. It was in the early part of December, during a
very cold season, and they found the river frozen over, but were
compelled to wait until the ice was sufficiently hard to bear their
weight before they could cross, which was finally effected on 14th of 
December, 1778. They found Gen. James Robertson and family 
and one other family living in humble log cabins on the bluff near 
where the county jail now stands, then called the
Spout Spring. from which Spring ( Church) street took its name.
Gen. Robertson and Maj. Buchanan found in each other the
elements for a confidence that ripened into a lasting friendship.
The third log cabin was soon erected for Maj. Buchanan, while
accommodations were provided for the other members of the new
accession to the settlement. Maj. Buchanan was a surveyor and
hunter, and these pursuits constantly called him into the woods,
thus enabling him to gain a thorough knowledge of the Indian
character- their sagacity, their treachery. and their blood- thirsty
purposes against the white settlers.
Robertson and Buchanan immediately set about erecting a fort
for protection and defense against the depredations and at&#172;tacks
of the Indians, and shortly after its completion, Indian &#8220;signs&#8221;
were reported to have seen seen near the fort. On the

301	Old Times in Tennessee

2d day of April, 1781, a desperate effort was made by the Indians
to take this fort. A numerous body of Cherokee warriors came
in the night and lay around in ambush. In the morning three
of them came in sight, and fired at the fort and immediately re &#8226;
treated. Nineteen horsemen in the fort at once mounted their
horses, and, under the lead of Maj. Buchanan, followed them in
a southerly direction. When they reached the steep and abrupt
banks of the branch emptying into the river above the present
city wharf ( now known as Wilson's Spring branch), a few In&#172;dians
were seen on the opposite side of that stream hiding behind
trees and making demonstrations as if preparing to give battle.
It appears that this was only a ruse to decoy the men from the
fort, for a considerable body arose from their concealment and
fired upon the horsemen. The latter dismounted and gave them
battle, and returned their fire with great alacrity. Another party
of Indians lay concealed in the cedars ready when the fighting
should commence at the branch to rush into the fort in the rear
of the combatants. The horses ran back toward the fort, leaving
 their riders on foot to fight their way out as best they could.
To guard against the expected assault from the Indians against 
those in the fort, its gates were closed, and preparations made for
defense. Meantime the battle raged without. Retreat was cut
off by the party concealed in the cedars, and the position of Maj.
Buchanan and his men was extremely critical. The Indians
were advancing upon them rapidly on either side, and there was
no time for consultation and concert of action in whatever course
it might have been thought best to pursue. It was a crisis when
each man had to act upon his own judgment. Emptying the
contents of his rifle in the breast of an advancing Indian, Maj.
Buchanan rushed to the bluff at the river for the purpose of gain&#172;ing
shelter while reloading his gun. An Indian having discov&#172;ered
his place of retreat, approached very cautiously to the edge
of the bluff, and began peer about in the hope of discovering
the Major's hiding place. While thus engaged, Buchanan sent
a ball crashing through his brain. Loading his gun again quickly,
he started for the fort, but before reaching the brow of the
bluff he discovered an Indian coming bounding like a frightened
antelope in the direction where he stood, but apparently having
his attention fixed in an opposite direction. The trusty rifle was
again leveled 

302 OLD TIMES IN TENNESSEE

and another redskin fell before Buchanan&#8217;s unerring aim.
While the Major was thus engaged, his companions were fighting with 
equal desperation and quite a number of Indians fell before their deadly aim. 
In this engagement five of Buchanan&#8217;s men were killed, his brother Alexander being of the number, and two badly wounded. One of them (Isaac Lucas) had his thigh broken by a ball. 

His comrades had gotten within the fort and the Indians rushed on him to take his scalp. One of them running toward him and being but a short distance from the supposed victim of 

this barbarous revenge, was fired upon and shot through the body by Lucas, who, with rifle well charge, was lying unable to rise from the ground. The Indian died instantly. Those in the 

fort, in order to save Lucas, kept up a brisk fire upon the pursuing Indians, and finally drove them off, when Lucas was brought into the fort. &#8220;Among those who escaped toward the fort&#8221; 

says Ramsay, &#8220;was Edward Swanson, who 
was so closely pursued by an Indian warrior as to be overtaken
by him. The Indian punched him with the muzzle of his gun,
and pulled trigger, when the gun snapped. Swanson laid hold
of the muzzle, and wringing the lock one side, spilled the
priming from the pan. The Indian looked into the pan, and
finding no powder in it, struck him with the gun-barrel, the muzzle foremost; the stroke not bringing him to the ground, the In&#172;dian
clubbed his gun, and striking Swanson with it near the look,
knocked him down. At this moment Maj. Buchanan, seeing the
certain death that impended his comrade, gallantly rushed from
the fort to the rescue of Swanson. Coming near enough to fire,
he discharged his rifle at the Indian, who gritting his teeth on
receiving its contents, retired to a stump near at hand. Buch&#172;anan
brought Swanson off, and they both got into the fort with&#172;out
further injury. From the stump to which the wounded warrior
retired, was found after the Indian forces had withdrawn, a
trail made by the body dragged along the ground much marked
with blood. When the Indians fired upon the horsemen at the
branch, the party of them lying in ambush in the cedars, rose
and marched toward the river, forming a line between the com&#172;batants
and the fort. Meantime, when the firing between the
dismounted horsemen and the enemy had commenced, the horses
took fright, and ran in full speed on the South side of the Indian

303	  OLD TIMES IN TENNESSEE.

Line toward the French Lick, passing by the fort on the bluff. Seeing this, a number of the Indians in the line, eager to get possession of the horses, left their ranks and went in pursuit of 

them. At this instant the dogs in the fort, seeing the confusion and hearing the firing, ran toward the branch and came to that part of the Indian line that remained yet unbroken, and 

having been trained to hostilities against the Indians, made a most furious onset upon them and disabled them from doing anything more than defending themselves.
 Whilst thus engaged the whites
passed near them, through the interval in the Indian line made
by those who had gone in pursuit of the horses. Had it not been
for these fortunate circumstances, the white men could never have
succeeded in reaching the fort through the Indian line which had
taken post between it and them." The Indians finally retired,
and although their loss could never be ascertained, it must have
been considerable.
Shortly after this incident, Maj. Buchanan went out hunting"
on Richland creek, several miles west of Nashville. Having
the luck to kill a young doe, after skinning and selecting the
choice pieces take home with him, he converted the hide into ,
a knap- sack in which he placed his venison. Throwing this
knap- sack over his neck and shoulders, he commenced to retrace
his steps toward home. The country was covered with a heavy
growth of cane and pea- vine, through which the buffalo had
beaten a track from Richland creek to the French Lick, now
called the Sulphur Spring. Maj. Buchanan was returning by
this path, and at a point some distance out, he came to where a
tree had fallen across the path, and the buffalo had made a path
around the top as well as the root of this tree. As he approached
the spot, he turned to the left, and just at that moment he heard
the voices of Indians coming around by the right. To his aston&#172;ishment
there were seven Indian warriors within twenty feet of
him, who had that day stolen two boys from the fort, and had
these boys with them. Before the Indians discovered him, Maj.
Buchanan shot the leader dead, which so frightened the others
that they took to their heels in a wild scamper through the bush,
cane, and pea- vines, the two boys running with their Indian cap&#172;tors,
fearing that they would be killed if they attempted to escape.
The Major retreated in a different direction. On his arrival at

304	  OLD TIMES IN TENNESSEE.

home the next morning, a company of men started out in pursuit
of the Indians to recover the hays if possible. They found Maj.
Buchanan's venison where he had thrown it off at the fallen tree,
the camp where the Indians had spent the night, and a new made
grave where they had buried their companion who had been
killed by Maj. Buchanan, but they did not succeed in recovering
the boys. Several years afterward the younger of the boys came
home and reported that the night after Buchanan had killed the
Indian, his brother made his escape and ran down Richland
creek. One of the Indians followed him, and returned about
daybreak bringing his brother's scalp with him, which he showed.
to the younger brother, and told him that if he attempted to run
off, he would kill and scalp him. The boy remained with the
Indians a long time before he succeeded in getting away. They
treated him very kindly, but made him stay with the squaws and
children and work. These boys were named Clayton.
After his return from captivity, young Clayton and another
young man, named Gee, were out on a scouting tour in the direc&#172;tion
of the Big BlackFox camp, a noted Indian camping ground,
near where Murfreesboro now stands, and as they were riding
through a dense cedar forest about two miles East of the present
site of Lavergne, they were fired on by a party of Indians and
killed. They were not found until several days afterward, and
then by attention having been attracted by the hovering of buzzards about the spot where their bodies were lying.
Maj. Buchanan was married twice- first, in 1786, to Miss Mar&#172;garet
Kennedy, who bore him one son and the second time in
1791, to Miss Sally Ridley, daughter of Capt. George Ridley,
who bore him nine sons and four daughters. After remaining
four years in Nashville, he located on Mill Creek, where the
Tennessee and Pacific Railroad crosses that stream, four miles
from the city. The place is known in tradition and history as
Buchanan's Station, and is memorable on account of having been
attacked about midnight on the 30th of September, 1792, by
about nine hundred Cherokee, Creek, and Choctaw warriors, who
were held at bay and finally repulsed by twenty- one in the fort.
This repulse has been pronounced a feat of bravery which has
scarcely been surpassed in all the annals of border warfare."
The following are the names of the men who were in the fort,

305	  OLD TIMES IN TENNESSEE

and who acted with such conspicuous bravery on that occasion:
Maj. John Buchanan, James Bryant. Thomas Wilcox, James
O'Connor, Robin Castleman, James Mulherrin, Thos. McCrory,
Morris Shane, William Kennedy, Robin Kennedy, Samuel Blair,
Jo. DuRat, George Finalson, Charles Herd, Sampson Williams,
John Castleman, Samuel McMurry, Robin Turnbull, Thomas
Latimore, Robin Hood, and Rohin Thompson.
Some three or four months before this battle, George Finalson,
a Frenchman, and Jo. DuRat, a half- breed, who were on terms
of intimacy with the Indians as well as the white settlers, and en&#172;tertaining
the warmest sympathies for Maj. Buchanan, deter&#172;mined
to communicate to him the purpose of the Cherokee, Creek,
and Choctaw Indians to unite their forces, attack and destroy
his fort, and after murdering those who had taken refuge in that
place, march on to Nashville and capture the town, and then di&#172;vide
the plunder they might secure. On learning the purpose of
the Indians, Maj. Buchanan set about repairing and strengthen&#172;ing
his feeble fortification. About five hundred State troops had
been ordered to Buchanan's Fort to meet and repel the Indians.
The  time at which the Indians were to have attacked the fort
having passed, and no sign of their coming, the matter was looked
upon as a ruse on the part of Finalson and DuRat to get up a
little excitement, or that they were themselves unduly excited,
if not frightened, the troops were disbanded the Friday previous
to the attack on Sunday night. Maj. Buchanan, however, pre&#172;vailed on 
a number of his friends to remain with him, having
the fullest confidence in the information given him by Finalson
and DuRat touching the purpose of thc Indians, which was fully
verified within three days.
The moon was full the night of September 30, and
unobscured by even the smallest cloud. As the clock struck the
hour of twelve, two faithful sentinels at the entrance gates descried in the distance the approach of the Indians. The sentinels
awaited their coming until they were within easy range, when
the sharp report of two rifles rung out upon the still air of that
bright moonlight night, the one killing the Cherokee chief and
the other severely wounding the celebrated Choctaw chief John
Watts, who was shot through one thigh while the ball lodged in
The other. The Indians returned the fire, and continued a constant

306	 OLD TlMES IN TENNESSEE.

stant and very heavy fire upon the fort for an hour. A few yards
from the fort a cellar had been dug out over which a house was
soon to be built. The Indians took refuge in this as a safe re&#172;treat,
from which ' they hoped to he able to pick off the men in
the fort as opportunity should present. The block- houses were
so constructed as to give the whites a decided advantage, which
was improved with telling effect by some expert riflemen from
the upper portholes. Whenever an Indian raised his head above
the ground sufficiently high to be seen, he was sure to be picked
off by one of the expert shots in the fort. Many were the bloody
traces made by hurriedly dragging the bodies of dead Indiams
down the rough, rocky declivity from that fatal spot. The prin&#172;cipal
burying ground of the Indians was at the lower extremity
of Todd's Knob, near the mouth of Stone's river, on the farm
now owned by Maj. David H. McGavock, and numerous are the
graves yet to be seen containing the bones of red men who fell
in the sanguinary attempt to take. the fort on that memorable
night of Sept. 30, 1792.  Prior this attack, Maj. Buchanan&#8217;s
sagacity and apprehension of the purpose of overriding and de&#172;stroying
him, put him actively on his guard against surprise, and
he was at all times fully prepared to meet any emergency. The
fort was repaired and strengthened, blockhouses built, guns
cleaned up and placed in position for use at a moment's warning,
powder- horns filled, bullets moulded and stored in convenient.
places; and although the spring was but a few yards distant from
the fort, to guard against a siege, all vessels for holding water
were carefully filled and conveniently arranged for use should
necessity require. So that when the Indians came he was fully
prepared for them. The attack being made at midnight, the in &#8226;
mates were all in bed and asleep, except the two sentinels on
guard at the outer gate, and when these faithful sentinels dis &#8226;
charged their guns at the advancing Indians, every man and
woman in the fort was soon at the post of duty. The attack was
so sudden and the emergency so great that no time was lost by the inmates of the fort in dressing, and they commenced the
fight with only the clothes on- many in only their under gar&#172;ments-
in which they had retired for the night. One lady fear &#8226;
ing capture, and believing the women and children would not be
killed but carried off, dressed herself and children So as to be 

307	OLD TIMES IN TENNESSEE

ready for the fate that awaited them. James O'Conner, who was
one of the inmates of the fort, was a gallant son of the Emerald
Isle, as his Irish brogue clearly indicated, but was much addicted
to strong drink. He had that day been to Nashville, and had
imbibed just enough make him quite lively. He had returned
to the fort only about an hour before the attack by the Indians.
While the battle was at its hottest, Jimmy O'Conner appeared
before Maj. Buchanan and asked permission to use an old long
pistol owned by the mother of the Major, and usually kept loaded
and laid away under the old lady's pillow. His request was
granted and Jimmy was soon at an upper port. hole, which was
reached by means of a ladder, and thrusting his blunderbuss,
which was known as " My Grandmammy's Pocket Piece,"
through the port- hole, pulled trigger, and supposing that he had
fired, and that at least one Indian had been made to &#8220;bite the
dust," returned to the Major for another load. This" pocket
piece" required just four times the quantity of powder that an
ordinary rifle did. Jimmy repeated his visit to the Major for
&#8220;another load" for the fourth time, thinking he had fired each
time. At the fifth trial his blunderbuss went off, with a report ,
akin to that made by a six- pounder, and &#8220;sending poor Jimmy
backward from the top of the ladder to the floor, a distance of
eight feet, and inflicting a severe bruise on his shoulder. No
sooner had he reached the floor than he was up and on his feet
again, and going the Major, he exclaimed with all the enthu&#172;siasm
of his nature, " Be jabbers, I give it to ' em; but she give
me a tremendous pounce!"
The night was quite cool, especially to those who were dressed
only in their night clothes. Mrs. Sally Buchanan was kept busy
in furnishing the men with powder and bullets, and occasionally
she warmed up their spirits with a " dhrop" of Jimmy O'Conner's favorite beverage. Mrs. Buchanan was large, active, cheer&#172;ful,
brave, and daring, knowing no fear and shunning no respon&#172;sibility;
with a strong mind, generous impulses, and sensitive to
the wants of the suffering. She was well calculated to encourage
the little band then defending the fort deeds of great bravery.
During the fight Mrs. Buchanan observed one man shirking
duty. She approached him and asked resolutely, "What are you
doing there, Tom? Why are you not fighting?" And then she

308 OLD TIMES IN TENNESSEE

Added with emphasis, &#8220;I would rather be killed fighting like a man, than be crouching in a corner like a coward. Go to your gun this instant, for your own credit&#8217;s sake&#8221; Of course such a 

speech had its desired effect. 

The lady who had dressed herself and children, was so completely the victim of fear that she left her room and advanced toward the gate of the fort. Mrs. Buchanan seeing her leading 

her children along, hastened to her side and inquired, &#8220;What in the world are you going to do, Phoebe?&#8221; &#8220;To surrender&#8221; was her reply. &#8220;Never&#8221; exclaimed Murs Buchanan, &#8220;as long as 

there is life in this body. Go back to your room and keep out f the way; we will whip the Indians? And back Phoebe went with her children.

Mrs. Buchanan was frequently by the Major's side during the engagement, to see that his orders were promptly executed, while she occasionally visited every part of the fort to 

encourage the brave men upon whose coolness and intrepidity so much depended. Never were husband and wife better suited to each other, or possessed in a greater degree the 

traits which lead to heroic daring&#8212;even in those days when these traits were so conspicuously developed in men and women&#8212;than were John and Sally Buchanan. It is a memorable 

incident that eleven days after this engagement Mrs. Buchanan gave birth to her first child.
In an account of the attack on Buchanan&#8217;s Station in a letter to the Secretary of War, Gov. Blount says: &#8220;Their (the Indians&#8217;) approach was suspected by the running in of cattle that had 

taken fright at them, and upon examination, they were found rapidly advancing within ten yards of the gate; from this place and and distance they received the first fire from the man 

who discovered them (John McRoy). They immediately returned the fire, and continued a very heavy and constant firing upon the station (block-houses surrounded with a stockade) for 

an hour, and were repulsed with considerable loss, without injuring man, woman, or child in the station. During the whole time of the attack the Indians were not more distant than ten 

yards from the blockhouse and often in large numbers around the lower walls, attempting to put fire to it. One ascended the roof with a torch, where he was shot, and falling to the 

ground renewed his attempts to fire the bottom logs, and was killed. The Indians

308	OLD TIMES IN TENNESSEE

Fired thirty balls through a port-hole of the overjutting, which lodged in the roof in the circumference of a hat, and those sticking in the walls on the side were very numerous. Upon 

viewing the ground next morning, it appeared that the fellow who was shot from the roof was a Cherokee half-breed, and there was much blood and signs that many dead had been 

dragged off, and litters having been made to carry their wounded to their horses, which they had left a mile from the station.&#8221;
The loud report of &#8220;My Grandmammy&#8217;s Pocket Piece&#8221; in the hands of Jimmy O&#8217;Conner impressed the Indians with the belief that the whites had a cannon in the fort, and caused them 

to retreat sooner perhaps than they otherwise would have done. So much for the part the Pocket Piece played in this memorable engagement.
For sixteen years after his settlement on Mill creek, Maj. Buchanan was compelled to keep a guard constantly on watch for the protection of those who cultivated his farm. His brother 

Samuel was cut off from the guard whilst plowing and wounded. His old father was shot down in his own house by a band of Indians while the men were out at work. Mrs. Sally 

Buchanan died Nov. 23, 1831 and Maj. John Buchanan, Nov. 7, 1832 and both were buried in the family graveyard near the site of the old fort.
</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Buchanan, Major John</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Buchanan family</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Nashville (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Text;</dc:type>
<dc:format>Biography;</dc:format>
<dc:format>Book;</dc:format>
<dc:format>10 p.</dc:format>
<dc:relation>Old times in Tennessee: with historical, political and personal scraps and sketches</dc:relation>
<dc:identifier>Guild, Jo Conn. Old times in Tennessee: with historical, political and personal scraps and sketches. Nashville, TN: Tavel, Eastman &amp; Howell, 1878.</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>976.8 G94, 1971</dc:identifier>
<dc:rights>Out of copyright</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>May be freely reproduced; May be freely reproduced. Please provide proper attribution of digital image;</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/buchanan/id/14</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>