<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>1940 Sigma Club</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Middle Tennessee State Teacher's College</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1940</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Posed photograph of the Sigma Club, a student  organization of the Middle Tennessee State Teacher's College.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The photograph was part of the 1940 Midlander yearbook. The club is described as: "an honorary organization composed of serious-minded men interested in intellectual and cultural development and actuated by worthy aims. It was founded in 1925 by Mr. Neal Frazier, and now has a total membership of one hundred ninety-three." The club was the only extra-curricular activity listed for Mr. Buchanan with his senior photograph.</dc:description>
<dc:description>James McGill Buchanan and others.</dc:description>
<dc:description>SIGMA  CLUB
OFFICERS
HALL HARRIS-_______________..____________________________President
JAMES BAXTER_____._____________.____________________Vice-President
DAVID ALDERMAN_________________________________Secretary
MR. NEAL FRAZIER______________________________Sponsor

The Sigma Club is an honorary organization composed of serious-minded men interested in intellectual and cultural development and actuated by worthy aims. It was founded in 1925 by Mr. Neal Frazier, and now has a total membership of one hundred ninety-three.

OTHER    MEMBERS

DENVER BAXTER, LEON BIBB, JAMES BUCHANAN, CHARLES BROWN,
MORTIMER COHEN, WILLIAM DEUBERRY, HUGH DELZELL, JULIAN GOBELET,
B. B. GRACY, III ROBERT L. MCCARTNEY,
ALDERSON MILLER, DABNEY PHILLIPS,
ROBERT ABERNATHY,       J. M. EDNEY,

Graduate Faculty Members

W. B. JUDD, ROY SIMPSON, WILLIAM SHACKLETT,
 EDWIN SPILMAN, RAY THOMAS, JESSE WALLER,
T. B. WOODMORE</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Buchanan, James M.;</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Rutherford County (Tenn.);</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Still image;</dc:type>
<dc:format>Still image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph;</dc:format>
<dc:format>6.8" x 9.4"</dc:format>
<dc:relation>Midlander 1940 (yearbook of the Middle Tennessee State Teacher's College</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>Copyright held by Middle Tennessee State University</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>May be reproduced for educational and research purposes. Credit image to Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, MTSU</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/buchanan/id/12</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>