<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>James M. Buchanan, Commencement Speaker</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Middle Tennessee State University</dc:creator>
<dc:source>Middle Tennessee State University</dc:source>
<dc:date>2000-05</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009;</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Excerpt from the program of the May 2000 commencement at MTSU. Dr. James Buchanan received the President's Award and was the commencement speaker</dc:description>
<dc:description>SPRING COMMENCEMENT
89th Academic Year
Murphy Athletic Center
Saturday, May 13, 2000, 10:00 a.m.
Program
Processional: Crown Imperial March - William Walton
Moment of Silence
Presiding Dr. James E. Walker
, President, Middle Tennessee State Uniuersity
The President's Award' Presentation President James E. Walker
Address Dr. James M. Buchanan
Nobel laureate in Economic Sciences and Advisory General Director,
Center for Study of Public Choice, George Mason University
Presentation of Candidates for Degrees Dr. Barbara S. Haskew
Prouost and Vice President for Academic Affairs
Conferring of Degrees President James E. Walker
Alumni Association Welcome Mr. David Cullum
President, MTSU Alumni Association
Alma Mater Mr. Stephen Smith
Assistant Professor, Department of Music
Recessional: "Rigaudon" - Andre
Organist Dr. Polly Brecht
Associate Professor, Department of Music
Brass Ensemble
Trumpets: Leonard Foy, Jamie Koester; Horn: Terry Jolley;
Trombone: Donn Schaefer; Tuba: Mark McMahon
(Audience please remain until procession has marched out.)
Names of Students Receiving Diplomas
Will Be Read by Dr. Bertha S. Clark, Professor, Department of Speech and
Theatre, and Deborah K. Anderson, Professor, Department of Speech and Theatre
Assisting with Diplomas Ms. Cande Oliverius,
Assistant Director of Admissions
Commencement Marshal: Dr. Sherian Huddleston
Heralds: Dr. Deborah Gentry and Dr. Thomas Burke
Although graduates are listed in this program according to the academic degree
they haue earned, their names are called alphabetically by colleges.
PLATFORM PARTY
Dr. James E. Walker
President
Dr. James M. Buchanan
Nobel Laureate in
Economic Sciences
Mr. David Cullum
President, MTSU Alumni
Association
Dr. Barbara S. Haskew
Prouost and Vice President for
Academic Affairs
Dr. Linda P. Hare
Vice President for Deuelopment
and Uniuersity Relations
Dr. Duane Stucky
Vice President for Finance and
Administration
Dr. Robert K. Glenn
Vice President for Student Affairs
Dr. Robert B. Jones
Associate Vice President,
Academic Affairs
Dr. E. Ray Phillips
Interim Dean, College of Basic
and Applied Sciences
Dr. E. James Burton
Dean, College of Business
Dr. Gloria Bonner
Dean, College of Education
and Behauioral Science
Dr. John N. McDaniel
Dean, College of Liberal Arts
Dr. Deryl learning
Dean, College of Mass
Communication
Dr. Donald l. Curry
Dean, College of Graduate Studies
Dr. John P. Montgomery
Dean, College of Uniuersity Honors
THE PRESIDENT'S AWARD
The President's Award at Middle Tennessee State University provides special
recognition to individuals or organizations who have distinguished themselves
through their exemplary service to MTSU; their extraordinary contributions to
education, the community, or society; or their remarkable professional achievement.
Asilver medallion, designed by Chris Brady and crafted by Klaus Kallenberger, with
the phrase semper aspirare (always aspire) is presented as tangible evidence of this
recognition.
Today, Nobel laureate James M. Buchanan returns to his alma mater to become
the third recipient of this award. MTSU proudly salutes this outstanding individual!
2
COMMENCEMENT SPEAKER
Dr. James M. Buchanan, Nobel laureate
Dr. James M. Buchanan, (B.S. '40), who grew up in rural middle Tennessee&#173;the
Gum community in Rutherford County. Despite his obvious brilliance and
prodigious achievements, he seems never to have lost his independent spirit and the
simple goodness of his roots. Buchanan the farm boy, the scholar, the man...ar.e still
one and the same.
He attended Buchanan School, so named because it was built on land once
part of the Buchanan family farm. He came from a poor but distinguished family.
His grandfather, John P. Buchanan, was elected governor of Tennessee in 1891. It
was, however, his family's poverty, Dr. Buchanan has said, that provided him a
strong family foundation and created a sense of determination, purpose, and
frugality.
Early on, it was determined that the young Buchanan would follow in his
grandfather's steps and become a lawyer-politician. When the Great Depression put
Vanderbilt University out of reach financially, he decided he could live at home, earn
money for books and fees by milking cows, and attend the small college down the
road.
Dr. Buchanan studied at Middle Tennessee State Teachers College from 1936
to 1940. He graduated with majors in mathematics, English literature, and social,
science. later that year, he was awarded a graduate fellowship in economics at UT&#173;Knoxville
and earned his master's degree in 194 I. He then won a fellowship in
statistics at Columbia University for the 1941-42 academic year. However, military
service intervened, and he was in the U.S. Navy by August 1941. After officer
training and duty at Pearl Harbor and Guam, he was discharged in 1945. He went
to the University of Chicago in 1946 and left with a Ph.D. degree in 1948. He
received a Fulbright grant for the 1955-56 year and studied in Italy.
In his book Better Than Plowing and Other Personal Essays (I 992, University
of Chicago Press), he said of his undergraduate years, "Up until about my second
year, I was not really sure about my own competence or ability. At the end of that
year, however, the academic rankings were published, and, with all As that year, my
name led all the rest. This result made me forget all about the first year C that
Nooby Freeman had given me in mechanical drawing, the only C that I got during
the whole of my academic career."
cont. on next page
3
When Dr. Buchanan visited MTSU in 1997 to address the first Buchanan
Scholars, he summed up his personal journey by sbaring words of advice. "I would
emphasize the fact that students from Middle Tennessee can make it. In other
words, they shouldn't stand in awe of the eastern establishment elite."
"The mixed curriculum, bbth self-selected and imposed, served me well," Dr.
Buchanan wrote of his college experience. "Economics, the discipline that was to
become my scientific home, requires expository writing skills, logical structures of
analysis, and a grounding in ultimate reality. And political economy, the branch of
moral philosophy from which economics springs, requires philosophical coherence. I
came away from Middle Tennessee with all of these... "
In 1986, Dr. Buchanan was awarded the Nobel Memorial Prize in Economic
Sciences, of which he wrote, "If Jim Buchanan can get a Nobel Prize, anyone can.
Recognition and acceptance of this simple truth are very importanL.Here was Jim
Buchanan, a country boy from middle Tennessee, educated in rural public schools .
and a local public teachers college, who is with an establishment university. who has
never shared the academically fashionable soft left ideology, who has worked in
totally unorthodox subject matter with very old-fashioned tools of analysis, chosen
by a distinguished and respected Swedish committee."
By describing Frank Knight. who was his mentor at the University of Chicago.
Dr. Buchanan reveals who he is. "The qualities of mind that Knight exhibited were,
and remain, those that I seek to emulate: the willingness to question anything. and
anybody, on any subject anytime; the categorical refusal to accept anything as
sacred; the genuine openness to all ideas; and finally, the basic conviction that most
ideas peddled about are nonsense or worse when examined critically."
Today, Dr. Buchanan, the author of several books and essays. serves as
advisory general director of the Center for Study of Public Choice at George Mason
University. in Fairfax, Virginia.
Since 1911
Middle Tennessee State University has graduated 75,293 students since its incep&#173;tion
in I9 I I. These students have received associate, bachelor, masters, educational
specialist. and doctoral degrees. Our first doctoral degrees were conferred on Decem&#173;ber
22, 1972, and the first educational specialist degrees on December 20, 1974.
There have been 31 Idoctoral degrees and 870 educational specialist degrees awarded
since that time.
4</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Commencement ceremonies; Buchanan family;</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Program</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>4 p</dc:format>
<dc:rights>Copyright held by Middle Tennessee State University</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>May be reproduced for personal or educational purposes with attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/buchanan/id/19</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>