<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Buchanan Dramatic Club, 1960</dc:title>
<dc:creator>[Yearbook staff, Midlander]</dc:creator>
<dc:date>1960</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>A group photograph of the members of the Buchanan Dramatic Club that was included in the Midlander yearbook for the 1959-1960 academic year. In 1958 Dorothe Tucker became the sponsor and director of the club named for Rebecca Jane Buchanan, who had founded the Dramatic Club in 1925. Tucker would continue her leadership of campus dramatic activities into the 1980s.</dc:description>
<dc:description>L. to R: First row, Margaret Cantrell, Dorethe Tucker, (faculty sponsor),Jo Faye Moorehead, Beverly Sadler, Bonnie Hudgens, Sarah Jane Croft, Jerry Dooley, Marguerite Batey, Cecil Davidson, Betty Holten. Second Row: Thelma Holman, Geddis Noble, Lou Ezell, Carolyn Duke, Nancy Johnson, Joyce Eaton, Kay Aiken, Bebe Drumwright, June Vickory, Agnas Carlson. Third Row: Roy Landrum, Tommy Mason, Holland Bratten, Mary Whitaker, Barbara Whitley, Janette Rexton, Barbara Tucker, Virginia Woodall, Lynette Daughetry, David Gannons, Jerry Newman. Fourth Row: Larry Robinson, Don Rieder, Dicky Barnes, Burton Barrett, John Spining, Bob Clark, Bruce Hancock, Larry Payne.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>College and student drama</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:format>Photograph</dc:format>
<dc:relation>Midlander (yearbook of Middle Tennessee State College). 1960</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>Copyright held by Middle Tennessee State University</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>May be reproduced for educational and research purposes. Credit image to Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, MTSU</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/buchanan/id/9</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>