<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Buchanan's Station</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Washington, Thomas</dc:creator>
<dc:contributor>Drake, Edwin L., ed.</dc:contributor>
<dc:coverage>1790-1799</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>An account of the raid on Buchanan's station provided by Thomas Washington, who was a boy of 15 at the nearby Hardeman's Station at the time of the attack. He recalls events leading up to the raid and the response of the community.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Reprinted in the newsletter of the Rutherford County Historical Society as an excerpt from The Annals of the Army of Tennessee and Early Western History, c1878, republished by Jackson, Tenn. : Guild Bindery Press,1998.</dc:description>
<dc:description>FROW CHIPS, Volume 32, Issue No. 4 Page 3 March/ April2003
BUCHANAN'S STATION The following was found in a compilation
produced and published by J. J. Fox, Fox Books, 9 Precipice Road,
Camden, SC 29020 and E. F. Williams, EFW Commercial Ventures, Inc.,
P. O. Box 241813, Memphis, TN 38124. The compilation includes
articles printed in " The Annals of the Army of Tennessee and Early
Western History", which seems to have been edited and published
regularly circa 1878 for at least ayear, by Dr. Edwin L. Drake, Lieutenant&#173;Colonel,
C. S. A. It primarily contains descriptions of battles and personal
experiences of the Civil War, much of which pertains to areas not of
Rutherford County or Middle Tennessee. However, there were also
articles concerning the recollections of early pioneers in Tennessee. The
following, written by Thos. Washington, is about Buchanan's Station,
located on Mill Creek in Davidson County, which was formed in 1783.
Many of the participants in this article resided in what later became
Rutherford County.
" The attack upon Buchanan's Station, as Mr. Tannehill [ of the
Tennessee Historical Society at that time] informs me was made in
September, 1792. Since I heard that this subject was under investigation
by this Society- that i~, within thr~ . or}~ ur Y'eeks past-: I wrote to
Constantine Hardeman, of Rutherford County, requesting him to'inforni
me of the date of said attack. Constantine Hardeman is ason of the late
Thomas Hardeman, who was the owner of the place at which
Hardeman's Station was established ( it being the place owned by the
later Robert C. Foster), and situated within one mile of Buchanan's
Station. Mr. Hardeman did not answer my letter, but he called upon me
in afew days after its reception and stated that he could not undertake
to give the exact date of the said attack on Buchanan's Station; that he
remembers the event perfectly well; was in Hardeman's Station at the
time; heard the firing of arms when it commenced and throughout its
continuance; thinks that he was then about fifteen years old, and says
that he was bom in the year 1778- which, if correct, would place the date
of the attack in the year 1793. Mr. Hardeman says, further, that although
he was then old enough to be capable of shooting arifle at squirrels, etc.,
he was considered too small to be of any service in defending
Buchanan's Station, and was left at Hardeman's Station, while he
mentions anumber of others who went from the latter station to the relief
of the former, all of whom are now dead. He refers me to Benjamin
Bashan, of this county, as being a man who can probably assist me in
ascertaining the date of the attack upon Buchanan's Station; and, also
the widow of the late Thomas Buchanan, a sister of the said Benjamin
Bashan, whom he describes as being awoman of remarkable memory....
" Thos. Washington continues- NOTE: Since the above was written,
I have seen and conversed with Colonel Moses Ridley, of Rutherford
County, on the subject of the attack upon Buchanan's Station. He is a
son of the late George Ridley, of this neighborhood, and a brother- in-law
of Major John Buchanan, afterwhom and at whose residence the station
was called and situated. Colonel Ridley says that he was between ten
and eleven years old when the attack was made, having been born in
June, 1782. That he remembers the event perfectly well, and grew up
among those who were in the station at the time; that it was aprominent
event in the history of the country, and that he has heard its incidents so
often narrated, that they have almost become identified with his own
existence. Colonel Ridley says that his impression is that his sister's son,
George Buchanan ( his sister being in the station at the time of the
attack), was born from ten to fourteen days after the attack; that,
recollecting that fact, he made search for the family Bible of Major John
Buchanan, in order to ascertain his son George's age, and found a copy
of that part of the bible where the ages of the children are recorded in the
possession of Henry Buchanan, another son of the said Major John
Buchanan. According to that copy, which I have seen, George Buchanan
was bom on the 11iii day of October 1792. And in the same copy the
exact date of the attack on Buchanan's Station is given, as being set
down among the ages of Major Buchanan's children; and according to
that record, it was the 30th of September 1792. Colonel Ridley also
produced to me a copy, as taken from a copy of said family record kept
by Thomas Everett, ason- in- law of Major Buchanan, in which the birth of
George Buchanan is set down as having occurred on the 11th day of
October, 1782. Colonel Ridley also says that he recollects that the attack
was made on a Sunday night, and during the full of the moon, it being a
very bright, beautiful moonlight night. Colonel Ridley also states that the
original family Bible of Major John Buchanan, after his death, went into
the possession of his daughter, Mrs. Jane Goodwin, the mother of the
present keeper of ! be Nashville jail, from whom it can probably be
obtained. Colonel Ridley also states that some time in August preceding
the date ofthe attack, Findleston, ahalf- breed Cherokee, and one Joseph
Durat, a Frenchman, brought information to Nashville- being, as they
state, direct from the Indian Nation- that the Indians were preparing an
expedition against Nashville and the settlements in the neighborhood,
and intended to make their attack at the next full moon. Findleston had
been about Nashville before as a trader, and was acquainted with ~
number of the inhabitants; and, in the course of his visits, had conceived
an attachment for a white woman named, as he thinks, Black. So the
story went; but, at all events, he afterward married her. He left the Indian
Nation, ashe stated, in company with Durat, under pretense of acting as
a spy, in finding out the situation and strength of the defenses about
Nashville, and of returning and giving information. Upon the faith of this
information, Abraham Castleman ( more familiarly called Abe Castleman),
aman of great daring of much experience in Indian warfare and strategy,
was sent out as aspy, to discover whether the Indians were approaching.
He returned, after having gone as far as some place between the Black
Fox's camp and Duck River, and reported that he had seen the trail of a
large body of Indians advancing in the direction of Nashville. Ameeting
of the heads of families in the settlement was called by General
Robertson, immediately after the receipt of the above- mentioned
information from Findleston and Durat; and the meeting was disinclined
to believe the story, and dispersed. Findleston then offered to General
Robertson that he might put him in the Nashville jail, and there keep him
until after the next full moon, and if the Indians should not have arrived,
he was willing to be shot The earnestness of Findleston, as thus
evinced, was the occasion ofAbraham Castleman's being despatched by
General Robertson as a spy, as aforesaid. About two hundred men,
however, were assembled and encamped at Rain's Spring, and the
families had generally moved in from their residences to stations.
" One full moon intervened, and the Indians did not arrive. The men
FROW CHIPS, Voome 32, Issue No. 4 Page 4 MarchlApril2003
found dead; but that, from the quantity of blood that was effused round
about, there was much more mortality than that. Colonel Ridley
presented me with arough draft of the fort at the time and the approach
to it, which is here present; and says that John McCrory was the man
who fired the first gun into the midst of a group of Indians gathered
together just at the fort- gate from the block- house situated nearest the
creek; and that Thomas Kennedy fired the next gun into the same group
from the house situated opposite while under a cross- fire. That the
Indians- then retreated to an open cellar of an unfinished house, the
foundation of which was just digged out and walled up, situated outside
of the station, and scattered about around the station, and took
advantage of the localities afforded by the place. In this situation, the two
contending parties- the men in the station and the Indians without- kept
up afiring, and also aparley; one asking the other who commanded, and
Thomas Kennedy telling them that they were a set of damned squaws,
and to put more powder in their guns. There were anumber of women
in the station at the time, and among them Mrs. Sarah Buchanan, who
was occupied during the attack in carrying around to the men posted in
the different parts of the station ammunition and brandy, giving to each,
as she supplied him, a word of encouragement. In eleven days
afterward, this same Sarah Buchanan was delivered of her first child, the
said George Buchanan. Colonel Ridley states that he never heard of
Tecumseh's being present at said attack until since the last war [ 1812]
with England." [ Ed: This entire artide concerned whether Tecumseh,
very famous in later years, had been present at the " Attack on
Buchanan's Stationl.
in camp and the families in the stations then began to lose confidence in
the truth of the information given by Findleston, and also in that of
Castleman's report, and they became very anxious to be disbanded, and
to return to their homes. General Robertson, for the sake of greater
caution, sent out John Rains and Abraham Kennedy ( commonly called
Abe Kennedy) in the direction in which Castleman said he had been, for
the purpose of seeing what discoveries they could make. Rains and
Kennedy were gone afew days and returned, and Rains reported that he
had seen plenty of " bear signs," but no " Indian signs," and swore to it, and
that he believed Castleman was mistaken. Kennedy refused to be sworn,
and therefore the men encamped at Rain's Spring were discharged.
Rains returned, as aforesaid, on Thursday, and the next moming- being
the Friday next before the attack- the men were discharged. On Sunday
morning, the inhabitants being still unsatisfied as to whether Findleston's
story might not be substantially true, sent out from Hardeman's Station,
after early breakfast, two spies ( Gee and Clayton) upon Taylor's old trace,
and they advanced as far as a tract of land then owned by Major
Buchanan, but now occupied by his son, James B. Buchanan, which is
situated on the Jefferson Road and extends across to the present
Murfreesboro Turnpike Road, and beyond it; and on said tract of land,
near Neill's Spring, where Beverly Nelson now lives, not far from the old
Jefferson Road, it being then Taylor's trace, the said spies were met by
the advance guard of the Indians, and one of them killed on the spot.
The other fled, and was likely to make his escape, when he was called
to by the said advance party of Indians, and told that they were friendly,
and that his comrade had been killed by the accidental discharge of one
of their guns. He was thus induced to stop, and when the Indians came
up with him, he also was killed. That night the attack on Buchanan's RODERICK Also, from " Annals of the Army of Tennessee and
Statio~ was made. The circumstances relative to. the deaths of the said Early Westem Hi, story" edited and published by Dr. Edwin L. Drake:
two spies were afterwards learned from George FI~ lds~ a Cher, okee ha~ f- In March 1863 In aperiod of relative inactivity following the Battle
breed, and others, after peace wa~ restor~, the sal. d Fields bemQ o~~ ald ._ of Stones River, a- reinforced_ Union . infantry~ bdgade, under Col. John
advance party. And the d~ ad b~ les . of said ~ o spies w~ re found by th~ Coburn, left Franklin to reconnoiter south toward Columbia. Four miles
party sent ~ om Buchanan. s Station In pUrsUIt of the Indians, ~ fter their from Spring Hill, Coburn attacked with his right wing, aConfederate force
repulse, Iym~ at some dlsta. nce from ~ ach other. The Indian force composed of two regiments; he was repelled. Then, Maj. Gen. Van Dom
~~ e~ en~ f~ said att~ ck was estrmated at mne hundred men. The number seized the initiative. Brig. Gen. W. H. " Red" Jackson's dismounted 2nd
e the statron, at the commencement of the attack, was about Division made afrontal attack while Brig. Gen. Nathan Bedford Forrest's
twenty, some of whose names are appended by Henry Buchanan to the . , . ' , ..
copy herewith presented, taken from Major Buchanan's family Bible' in diVISion swept aro~ nd Coburn s le~ flank, and mto ~ IS rear. A~ er ~ hree
addition to which Colonel R'dle states th tM' B h h' If' attempts, charactenzed by hard fighting, Jackson camed the Umon hilltop
, I Y a aJor uc anan Imse was position as Forrest captured Coburn's wagon train and blocked the road
also present, and John Gowen, Thomas Kennedy, Wm. Turnbull, Joseph to Columbia in his rear, Out of ammunition and surrounded Coburn
Crabtree, Moore Cotton, Henry Gleeson and James Matthews. These ... , .' ,
names do not quite make up the twenty' but Colonel Ridley at the surrendered. Umon Influence 10 Middle Tennessee subs. lded for awhile.
.. . . ' .' " The Death of General Forrest's War Horse, Rodenck - The strong
mtervlew that I had With him, could not recollect the reSidue, He says attachment which the horse sometimes exhibits for his master is
that, after the commencement of the attack, a runner was sent to .. ... .
Nashville, and that Anthony Foster, from Nashville, was the first man that touchingly. Illustrated 10 ! he m~ dent which follows.. Gener~ 1 Forrest rarely
entered the fort he having arrived just as the Indians ere refrin d allud~ to It, and the~ With e~ ld~ nces of deep emotion, wh~ ch oft~ n fou~ d
while et the ~ r in ' . Wig, an vent In tears, belong109, as It did, to that class of memones whiCh, With
, Y Y e e Sight. That John Rams was ne~, and close after men of his strong and passionate nature became more sacred with the
him; but that a number of others went forward, but did not reach the . . ..' .
station until after the firing had ceased. He says that the attack lapse of years. Dunng hiS bnlllant and memorable movement ~ gamst. the
commenced about eleven o'clock at night and that the assault conf d flank and rear of Colonel Coburn, at the ba~ le of T. hompson s Stab. on,
about an hour ' .. . mue General Forrest was mounted that day on hiS favonte horse, Rodenck,
. and a half. There ~ ere no men killed 10 th~ station, and and desiring to press the enemy from a strong position across an open
but . one slightly wounded by a spllnter. from some. of the bm~ rs of the field he appeared upon the flank of one of his regiments as it lay taking
station. There was a blunderbuss 10 the station, of which James ' .. . , .""
O'Connor an Irishman took charge and in the hurry and confusi that the fire, and, 10 hIS charactenstlc ~ ords, ordere~ It to move up. At the
.' '," . on command the men leaped to their feet, and, With loud cheers, dashed
prevailed, th. ought he had. discharged the ~ Iunderbuss several ! Imes, but forward under a hot fire. The General, attended by his son, Lieutenant
had not until he had pu~ 10 three successive I. oads; that the piece then William Forrest, accompanied the charge, as was his wont when the point
went off, and knocked 0 Connor ~ o the b~ ck Side. of ~ e house, who was to be gained was of importance. In the brief conflict, which resulted in the
thus very much hurt. Colonel. Ridley's ImpreSSion IS ~ at ther~ was a overthrow of the enemy, Roderick was wounded in three places. This
small p~ rt of Creeks present With the Cherokees on saId oeca, slon, and even gave the General so much concern that he immediately dismounted,
one chief, ~ ose nam. e he d~ s not recollect, but h~ wa~ killed. He and charged his son to lead Roderick to the rear and have his wants well
heard of the dlffe. ren~ 10 council between Watts and sald. chlef, and says attended to by the hostlers in charge of his extra horses. He then
there was an extingUished firebrand found the n~ xt d. ay Iymg so~ e ten or mounted his son's horse, which had also been wounded, and pressed
~ fteen fe~ t from the fo~, an~ ~ ear where. the said chief lay dead, but that forward in pursuit of the enemy. On reaching the hostlers, Lieutenant
It was Major Buc~ anan s opmlon that, said. brand had not been on fire so Forrest had the wounded animal stripped of saddle and bridle for his
recently as the night before. That said chief was the only man that was
</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Buchanan family; Nashville (Tenn.)--History;</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Nashville (Tenn.);</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Text;</dc:type>
<dc:format>Memoir;</dc:format>
<dc:format>Booklet;</dc:format>
<dc:format>2 p.</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Buchanan's Station. Frow Chips, Rutherford County Historical Society, Murfreesboro TN. Vol. 32 No. 4, March/April 2003, p. 3</dc:identifier>
<dc:rights>Out of copyright;</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>May be freely reproduced. Please provide proper attribution of digital image</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Albert Gore Research Center, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/buchanan/id/15</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>