<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Morgan's Wedding</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Jones, Shirley Farris</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 34</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1994</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869; 19th Century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>MORGAN'S WEDDING
by Shirley Farris Jones
The Civil War was a time of uncertainty, especially
for those living in the recently established Confederate
States of America. Happiness was a brief interlude from
the reality of the horrors and deprivations inflicted
upon a people trying to protect their homeland. For
some it was a bittersweet time of both joy and sorrow.
Such is the story of Martha Ready of Murf reesboro,
Tennessee and John Hunt Morgan of Lexington, Kentucky.
John Hunt Morgan was born in Huntsville, Alabama on
June 1, 1825. The first of ten children of Henrietta
Hunt and Calvin Morgan, John was named for his
millionaire maternal grandfather, John Wesley Hunt of
Lexington, Kentucky. Although Calvin Morgan tried
various ways to become a successful businessman and
provide adequately for his family, failing business
ventures finally forced him to relocate to Lexington
when John was six, thus becoming dependent upon the
Hunt's for their livelihood and affluent lifestyle.
John Morgan had inherited by birth the status of
aristocracy. Very handsome, he was tall (6 feet) with a
strong and attractive athletic body and exhibited
excellent horsemanship. As a young man, he was very
bashful and did not feel comfortable speaking before a
group. His college career at Translyvania University
proved quite disappointing and he was suspended for
dueling in 1844. John entered the military in 1846,
after two frustrating years of trying to "find himself",
and was elected second lieutenant of Company K of the
Kentucky Volunteers in the war against Mexico. He was
then promptly promoted to first lieutenant of Kentucky's
Mounted Volunteers 1st Regiment. He distinguished
himself as a hero in the battle at Buena Vista, and
although his enlistment was up, the war over, he wanted
desperately to continue his military career. He had
gained self confidence through his experiences of war,
and enjoyed being welcomed home as the conquering hero.
More importantly, he had distinguished himself as a
Morgan of Honor 1 He had acquired one year of military
experience, although discipline was lax and contempt for
authority prevalent. This would shape his future
military actions.
Morgan settled down in Lexington and entered into
business with his friend, Sanders Bruce. The Bruce
family lived across the street from Hopemont, Morgan's
ancestoral home, and were considered an established
manufacturing family, wealthy, successful, and
respected. Perhaps it was only natural that John Morgan
should then marry Sanders' sister, Rebecca Bruce. He
was 23 and she was 18 years old, on their wedding day,
November 21, 1848. In 1853, after five years of
marriage, she gave birth to their first and only child,
a son, who was stillborn. From that point on, for the
duration of her life, Becky would remain a victim of
poor health, despite trips to various doctors and places
in a fruitless attempt to find a cure for her
afflictions. Becky, suffering from both the pain and
humiliation of not fulfilling her role as wife and
mother, turned to her mother for emotional support and
to religion for comfort. After existing several years
as an invalid, confined to bed for many months, she
finally died on July 21, 1861. During this time,
Morgan's behavior was typical of so many Southern
gentlemen of his time &#8212; with Becky and his relatives,
he was always respectful, yet Morgan never denied
himself any of the wordly pleasures. He was known as a
favorite among women, as well as a gambler and
libertine. Morgan's brother-in-law and best friend,
Basil Duke, expounded the Southern code of ethics when
he pointed out that Morgan never attempted to be
secretive or hypocritical about his diversions, and he
never did anything "which touched his integrity as a man
and his honor as a gentleman." Duke later wrote: "Like
the great majority of the men of his class &#8212; the
gentlemen of the South &#8212; he lived freely, and the
amusements he permitted himself would, doubtless, have
shocked a New Englander almost as much as the money he
spent in obtaining them. ... General Morgan, with the
virtues, had some of the faults of his Southern blood
and country."
Meanwhile, John's busines ventures, many of which
were dependent upon the institution of slavery,
flourished. By the late 1850' s, the Southern system of
honor was wholly identifiable in the character of John
Morgan, and he had established his identity and
respectability as Captain of the Lexington Rifles, and
entered into the romantic social life of antebellum
Lexington. VThen all of this was threatened, John was
more than ready to go to warl
Kentucky found herself a state divided, unable to
choose between North and South, and therefore took the
position of peace and neutrality. Morgan, however,
aligned himself with other Southern sympathizers in the
state and the Lexington Rifles were among the first
volunteer companies to join the State Guard, a newly
created pro-Southern state militia organization, in
1860. In September of 1861, the Lexington Rifles left
to join Confederate forces and shorthy thereafter Morgan
began his own type of warfare against the enemy that had
driven him from his home. He entered into it with both
intensity and enjoyment, which is apparent from his
raids along the Green River. After General Albert
Sidney Johnston's defensive line in Kentucky collapsed
early in 1862, Morgan's command became part of the thin
screen thrown out to protect Johnston's army from Union
divisions under General Buell in Nashville, Tennessee.
On February 27, 1862 Morgan moved his headquarters to
near Murf reesboro.
Martha Ready Morgan was born near Murf reesboro,
Tennessee on June 21, 1840. She was the sixth of eight
children, and the second of four girls, born to Colonel
Charles Ready, Jr. and Martha Strong Ready. Mattie was
known to be a "very attractive young woman of medium
height, with a shapely figure, a fair, creamy
complexion, large blue eyes, and dark hair." She
attended Soule College in Murf reesboro and the Nashville
Female Academy during the 1850 's. Col. Ready was a
Murfreesboro attorney, who served Tennessee as a United
States representative before the Civil War and a judge
afterwards. While in Washington with her family, Mattie
was known to be a favorite among society. She was "the
first girl in Washington to wear a curl on her forehead,
which was soon imitated by a hundred others."
The Ready family was among the earliest and most
prominent Rutherford County families. They were known
to be strong supporters of the Confederacy, and offered
hospitality to the officers encamped in the area,
including the dashing cavalryman from Kentucky, General
John Hunt Morgan, who arrived in Murfreesboro in late
February of 1862. One day when Colonel Ready was
visiting the army camp, he met General Morgan and
invited him to dinner. He sent a slave home with word
that "the famous Captain Morgan was coming. Tell Mattie
that Captain Morgan is a widower and a little sad. I
want her to sing for him." In a diary entry of March 3,
1862, sister Alice describes a visit by General Morgan
to the Ready home the previous evening: "... Morgan is
an extremely modest man, but very pleasant and
agreeable, though one to see him would scarcely imagine
him to be the daring reckless man he is. An immense
crowd collected at the front door to see him, two or
three actually came in and stood before the parlor door
... ." Although his stay in Murfreesboro was brief.
Captain Morgan made quite an impression on the 21 year
old beauty. Following an expedition to Gallatin, Morgan
returned to Murfreesboro to find a Union cavalry
regiment conducting a reconnaissance outside the town.
He sent Mattie a note asking whether the town was clear
of Federals. She hurriedly penned a reply: "They are
eight miles from here. Come in haste," and handed it to
a courier who returned to Morgan, ten miles to the
north. A few hours later, in the early morning, Morgan
appeared. He and Mattie talked until daylight and
family tradition holds that they became engaged on that
March nineteenth. At dawn John bade good-bye to Mattie
by forming the soldiers on the square and leading in the
singing of "Cheer, Boys, Cheer."
Mattie was known for her spirit. One day, in the
late spring of 1862 while Murfreesboro was under Federal
occupation, she overheard some Union soldiers making
unkind remarks about Morgan. She stepped in and gave
the Yankees a royal scolding. When one of the soldiers
asked her name she replied, "It's Mattie Ready nowl But
by the grace of God, one day I hope to call myself the
wife of John Morgan I"
After a brief courtship, John Morgan presented
Mattie with one of the most unusual wedding presents in
history. Following a battle with Union forces in
Hartsville, Tennessee more than 1,800 Federal soldiers
were captured. General Morgan then had them marched to
the Ready home in Murfreesboro where they were presented
to Mattie on her front porch. That army of discomfited
"boys in blue" came to be known as "Gen. Morgan's
wedding present to his bride."
The wedding of Mattie Ready and John Hunt Morgan
was held a.t the Ready home near the Court House in
Murfreesboro on Sunday evening, December 14, 1862. The
Ready House was described as having been built in the
1350 's, and being a two-storied wooden structure facing
East Main Street along the whole block where Nations
Bank is currently located. The house actually occupied
the second lot along East Main Street; the first lot was
an ornamental garden with twin magnolia trees right
across from the Court House. Inside the house was a
large hall with flanking parlors. One of these parlors
served as the scene of the wedding. According to family
records Mattie wrote in later years, "Mama and Papa's
room was downstairs and the children's upstairs."
Windows from the upstairs rooms opened onto Main Street.
Colonel Ready's law office was in the east room on the
ground floor. This grand home was the scene of much
gaiety and hospitality &#8212; and headquarters for both
armies during the war.
The wedding was one of the great social occasions
of the Confederacy. Groomsmen were Mattie' s brother,
Horace Ready, an officer on General William J. Hardee's
staff, and Col. George St. Leger Grenfell, an English
soldier of fortune. General Leonidis Polk performed the
ceremony, while Generals Bragg, Hardee, Cheatham, and
Breckinridge looked on with the headquarters staff.
President Jefferson Davis, in Murfreesboro the day
before the wedding, had promoted Morgan to brigadier
general
.
In an Augus^ 31, 1912 issue. General Basil Duke of
Louisville recalled to a News-Banner reporter his
memories of that great celebration. "...All the
officers of high rank who could reach Murfreesboro had
assembled for the wedding &#8212; General Bragg among them.
Distinguished civilians were present in great numbers.
The house was packed with people to its full capacity
. . .and decorated with holly and winter berries&#8212;the
lights from lamps and candles flashed on the uniforms
and the trappings of the officers, and were reflected in
the bright eyes of the pretty Tennessee girls who had
gathered. ...The raven-haired, black-mustached Morgan,
in his general's uniform, looking like a hero of
chivalry, the bride, a girl of rare beauty, tall,
dark-haired, and blue eyes, with a creamy complexion and
perfect features, and standing before them, to perform
the ceremony, in his full military uniform. Bishop Polk,
himself a general of the Confederate Army, and Bishop of
the Episcopal Church. ...Miss Ready's bridal dress was
one of her best ante-bellum frocks, for it was not
possible at that time to purchase material for a
trousseau. . . . General Duke was certain that the bride
could not have worn anything more becoming. He
remembers that she wore a bridal veil. ... General
10
Morgan' s att-endants were as dashing a set of young
soldiers as any bride could wish ah her wedding. ...Two
or three regimental bands had been provided for the
occasion. They were stationed in the house and on the
porch, and there was plenty of music. Outside in the
streets thousands of soldiers were assembled, who by the
lighted bonfires, celebrated the wedding proper style,
cheering Morgan and his bride."
After the wedding there was a great supper served
in the Ready mansion where the wedding party and invited
guests feasted ... turkeys, hams, chickens, ducks, game,
and all the delicacies and good dishes a Southern
kitchen could produce were on the board, while Colonel
Ready's cellar still had a sufficient stock of wine to
provide for the many toasts proposed to the happy
couple. After the wedding supper, the bands were called
in and the gallant soldiers and Tennessee belles danced
to their heart's content.
Eight days after the wedding, on December 22, 1862,
the newlyweds were separated when General Morgan and his
command left for a raid into Kentucky. The second day
of the raid, on December 23, 1862, he wrote Mattie that
he hoped it would be finished within six days.
"and then my precious one I shall try and get back
to you as fast as possible and then my pretty one
11
nothing shall induce me to again leave you this
winter. How anxiously I am looking forward to the
moment when I shall again clasp you to a heart that
beats for you alone. Do not forget me my own
Darling and you may rest assured that my whole
thoughts are of you. Farewell my pretty wife, my
command is leaving I must be off."
The raid was a great success, and John and Mattie
hoped that it would help to dispel speculations that
marriage came first, career second. Colonel Grenfell
had participated in the wedding but said later that he
had attempted to prevent it, as he felt that marriage
would cause John to become cautious and less
enterprising. And Mattie' s family had instructed her,
"You must remember your promises, not to restrain the
General in his career of glory, but encourage him to go
forward." She promised, but she did not know what a
profound influence she would have on his life and
career. He was her hero; her knight in shinning armor.
Following the raid he wrote, "The greatest pleasure my
expedition has afforded is the knowledge that our great
success will gratify and delight you." After the war
Basil Duke stated that Mattie "certainly deserved to
exercise over him the great influence she was thought to
have possessed." There were hints that Mattie slowed
Morgan down, took away his strength and courage, and
sent his career on a downward spiral. The wedding came
at the peak of his career, one day after his promotion
to brigadier general. But instead of encouraging him to
12
set'ile down to regular cavalry service, the relationship
with Mattie seems to have added to the psychological
pressure to continue independent raids, even to the
point of recklessness and insubordination.
Mattie loved her husband deeply, and despite the
hardships of the war, tried to be with him whenever and
wherever she could. Three weeks after the wedding,
following the Battle of Stones River and Bragg' s retreat
from Middle Tennessee, Mattie, accompanied by her lovely
sister Alice, was forced to take flight from home. (They
did not see their parents again until after the war.
The Ready house was used by Union General Rosecrans for
his headquarters in Murf reesboro. ) Under escort by
members of General Hardee's staff, they reached the army
at Winchester, Tennessee. Three weeks after the
wedding, on January 6, 1863, Mattie wrote:
"... Come to me my own Darling quickly. I was
wretched but now I am almost happy and will be
quite when my precious husband is again with me. I
can bear anything Darling when you are with me, and
so long as I have your love&#8212;but when separated
from you and I know that you are surrounded by so
many dangers and hardships as you have been on your
last expedition I become a weak nervous child.
Have I not lived a great deal, love, in the last
three weeks? When I look back now at the time, it
seems three years. But in each hour I have passed
through, there has always been one dear face ever
before me. ... I have so much to tell you, and so
very much to hear from you. Although I have heard
nothing from you since you left Glasgow, I knew you
had accomplished what you had in view&#8212;but oh I was
so anxious for your safety. I had some dark days,
dearest, and when the battle was raging around me
13
in such fury, and everybody from the
commander-in-chief to the privates were praying for
Morgan to come, I thanked God in the anguish of my
heart that it was not for me to say where you
should be. ... I love to write to you. Dearest, and
your sweet letters always make me happy. It
grieved me that I could send you no word of love
from my pen while in Kty. Both-because it would
have been a relief to pour out my heart to you, and
then. Darling, I feared you would forget me. You
left me so soon. ... Good night, my Hero. My
dreams are of you."
One of General Morgan's first priorities was to
bring Mattie to his new headquarters in McMinnville. He
wrote, "Am determined to have you near me. Cannot bear
the thought of your being away from home and ray not
being with you." Once she came, Mattie declared: "My
life is all a joyous dream now, from which I fear to
awaken, and awake I must when my Hero is called to leave
me again. My husband wants me to remain with him, and
of course I much prefer it. They say we are a love sick
couple." This devotion to each other was reflected in
John Morgan's military leadership. After long and
strenuous marches, when even the strongest men were
exhausted, he would ride another fifty miles to be with
her. Mattie diverted his attention, and he lost his
single-minded devotion to the Cause. One night,
anticipating attack from the enemy, he wrote, "Altho I
fully expected to be attacked today, still my thoughts
were of you and not of war." Twenty-five miles from the
hardships at the front of battle, John and Mattie
1^
ext:ended their honeymoon into the spring. Nearly every
afternoon they made an elegant appearance, riding
horseback into the country&#8212;she in a beautiful black
riding habit, hat, and veil, he in a blue roundabout
jacket with brass buttons, blue pants tucked into shiny
cavalry boots with spurs, and black felt hat fastened up
at the side. A correspondent for the Richmond Enquirer
observed that Mattie's "full-blown figure was certainly
"apropos to the sterling manhood of Morgan. She loves
him very ardently, and I doubt not that the affair was
entirely one of the affections. They take long strolls
every afternoon, and the evidences of attachment . . . are
delicate and dignified upon both sides."
With Middle Tennessee under Federal occupation, and
Mattie choosing to remain with John behind Confederate
lines, arrangements for Mattie's escape in case of enemy
attack were always first and foremost in his mind. John
provided an ambulance and wagon and kept her informed on
the most feasible escape route. She kept her bags
packed for immediate evacuation. On April 19, 1863,
Colonel Robert Minty's Michigan cavalry burst through
picket lines and into Morgan's headquarters at
McMinnville. Two officers were seriously wounded while
creating a diversion to give Morgan time to put Mattie
in the ambulance and send her racing out of town. John
and his headquarters escort escaped on horseback across
15
the fields. Mattie was captured but immediately
released.
This was a foretaste of what was to become habitual
for Mattie &#8212; flights before the enemy, lonely vigils,
brief intervals with her husband. In the summer of
1863, during the Confederacy's "farthest north" raid.
General Morgan was captured and imprisoned in Columbus,
Ohio. He wrote to her two or three times a week in
terms of cheer and confidence, but his concern for her
steadily increased. During this time the "happy" days
were over for Mattie. She and Alice became war-time
refugees &#8212; in Knoxville, in Augusta, Georgia, in
Knoxville again, and finally in Danville, Virginia.
Mattie wanted to be as near Richmond as possible in
order to do everything she could to speed up the parole
of her beloved husband. When they heard that their
brother Horace was wounded at Chickamauga, Alice hurried
off to take care of him. Alone and desperately anxious,
Mattie grew seriously ill. Her baby daughter was born
prematurely and lived only a short time.
General Morgan made his miraculous escape from the
Ohio prison on November 27, 1863 (the day his daughter
was born) and managed to reach Mattie in time for
Christmas. It was later felt that John's overwhelming
desire to be with her inspired this reckless plan. After
the couple was reunited, they were more devoted than
16
ever. And more determined than ever to be together.
They even made a covenant to this effect. Mattie
accompanied him to Richmond in early January of 1864 for
a nearly three month ovation in the capitol. They were
wined, dined, and extensively made over. He was
celebrated as the South' s great hero; Mattie enjoyed it
all and continued to gain strength.
At the end of March 1864, General Morgan was given
command of the Confederacy's Southwestern Virginia
Department (which included part of east Tennessee) and
they moved to the headquarters in Abingdon, Virginia.
This was Morgan's first and only departmental command
and one of the most undesirable in the entire army. The
next few months brought a different picture into focus.
At this time in his career, Morgan was a very
disenchanted man. There were clouds of suspicion and
disgrace from previous unauthorized military actions
hovering around him and a court of inquiry threatening
to ruin his career. His intense love for Mattie was the
only bright spot in his life during this dark time. On
his way back to Abingdon from the Last Kentucky Raid, he
wrote: "How very anxious I am to see you &amp; to hold you
in my arms. Do not think I shall permit myself to be
separated from you again." His appearance indicated
that he was a tired, sick man who had aged considerably,
and Basil Duke, who had just been released from the Ohio
17
prison, was appalled at the change in Morgan. The new
command was a mixed group, with many untrustworthy
elements among them, while most of his former command
was still in prison in Ohio. During the summer while
operating in Greenville, Tennessee he revoked the parole
of a Union officer whom a townswoman by the name of Lucy
Williams had "befriended" and it was always believed by
Morgan's family and friends that it was she who sought
revenge.
On August 28/29, 1864, General Morgan and his men
once again rode off from Abingdon, Virginia to
Greenville, Tennessee. Even though Tennessee was a
Confederate state, it was widely divided, and this part
of east Tennessee was very pro-Union. Though strongly
advised to the contrary on separating himself from his
men, Morgan selected the largest and most comfortable
house in the area for his headquarters, that of Mrs.
Catherine Williams, a friend of Mattie's family. Mrs.
Williams had three sons, two of whom fought for the
Confederacy and one for the Union. The Union
soldier-son was married to Lucy, a woman of questionable
character. Although there was no evidence to actually
prove Lucy's betrayal as to informing the Federals of
Morgan's whereabouts, it was generally accepted that
this was indeed the case. She herself never denied the
accusations and Joe Williams began divorce proceedings
18
almost immediately. He later visited the Ready family
in Murfreesboro.
Four days after leaving Mattie in Abingdon, a Union
cavalry force, commanded by Military Governor of
Tennessee Andrew Johnson's adjutant general, Alvan C.
Gillera, surprised the Confederates and John Hunt Morgan
was shot and killed by Union private, Andrew J.
Campbell. (it was believed that Johnson, himself a
native of Greenville, felt it his duty to promote the
Union cause in the area and was particularly offended by
Morgan being recognized as a hero by Southern
sympathizers.) Morgan was the only headquarters
officer killed, and many believe that he was murdered
after surrender and his body desecrated. Others feel
that he chose death over surrender and indefinite
separation from Mattie. Perhaps the covenant he and
Mattie had agreed upon previously entered into his
decision to gamble on life, rather than death. This was
on September 4, 1864 &#8212; the same day that Atlanta fell.
Mattie learned of her husband's death and claimed
his body under a flag of truce. Grief stricken and
pregnant, she returned to Augusta, Georgia to stay with
relatives. Seven months after the death of General
John Hunt Morgan, Mattie gave birth to their daughter,
and named her Johnnie. (Johnnie Hunt Morgan was born on
19
April 7, 1865, just two days before General Lee's
surrender.) The child was a great comfort to Mattie in
her grief. During the summer of 1865, Mattie and
little Johnnie returned to her parents' home in
Murf reesboro, where she devoted most of her time and
energy to raising her young child and representing her
late husband as the widow of a Lost Cause hero. Her
home, her family, and the Southern way of life she had
previously known were gone forever. The period
following the war years was a difficult time for
everyone, and the Ready family was no exception. In
1870, in order to help alleviate the shortage of family
funds, the "New Ready House" opened as a boarding house,
with Mattie' s brother, Ex-Colonel Horace Ready, as its
proprietor, "keeping a ledger of those who came to
dinner and to spend the night." This was after the
"Great Fire" in Murf reesboro in 1868, when perhaps the
old house was either burned or badly damaged.
Mattie remarried on January 30, 1873 after about
eight years of widowhood. Her second husband was Judge
William H. Williamson of Lebanon and they were the
parents of five children. In the early 1880 's, Mattie
was described in Prominent Tennesseans as "noted for her
fine address, intellectual vigor and cultivation, her
strength of character and devotion to her children.
Handsome in person, and clothed with the graces of the
20
highest order of womanhood, she is naturally of great
influence in the community." Martha Ready Morgan
Williamson died on November 16, 1887 at the age of 47.
Her love for Morgan was apparent even after death. On
her tombstone is the following inscription, "Our Mother
- First the wife of Gen'l John H. Morgan - And then of
Judge Wm. H. Williamson."
Six months after her mother's death, Johnnie
married the Rev. Joseph W. Caldwell. On June 28, 1888,
shortly after her honeymoon, Johnnie died of typhoid
fever, thereby leaving no direct descendants of John
Hunt and Martha Ready Morgan.
21
SOURCES:
Article from the FREE PRESS , Murf reesboro, Tennessee,
Sunday, February 28, 1988.
Arnette, C.B. From Mink Slide to Main Street . Williams
Printing Company, Nashville, TN, 1991.
Jones, Katharine M., Ed. Heroines of Dix ie; Spring of
High Hopes , Bobbs-Merrill , 1955. ~
Memoirs of General Basil W. Duke, interview with " NEWS -BANNER " reporter, Louisville, Kentucky, August 31,
1912.
Neff, Robert 0. Unpublished manuscript based on
interview and information obtained from Mrs. Samuel B. Gilreath of Lebanon, Tennessee in 1985. Mrs. Gilreath is
the granddaughter of Mattie and Judge Williamson.
Pittard, Mabel. History of Rutherford County , Memphis
State University Press, 1984.
Ramage, James A. Rebel Raider; The Life of General
John Hunt Morgan , The University Press of Kentucky
&#8212;
Lexington, KY, 1986.
"Tennessee Historical Quarterly", Spring, 1991, vol. L.
No . 1
.
'
22
Shirley Farris Jones is a staff member at Middle
Tennessee State University, Mur f reesboro, Tennessee. She
is currently serving her fourth term as President of the
Rutherford County Historical Society. she also serves
as Vice President of Friends of Stones River National
Battlefield and 1st Vice President of the Martha Ready
Morgan Chapter of the United Daughters of the
Confederacy. A direct descentant of three Confederate
grandfathers, she is a member of the Real
Great-grandaughter' s Club of the UDC. "Civil War history
is more than just a hobby, it has been a "passion" since
childhood," according to Ms. Jones, who has had several
articles published previously in "Civil War Regiments,"
"The Journal of Confederate History," and the United
Daughters of the Confederacy monthly magazine. This
research was done in conjunction with Newmark Publishing
U.S.A., Louisville, KY, for the "Orphan Brigade:
Journey Through the Civil War" limited edition prints
series by artist John Paul Strain. "Morgan's Wedding"
was the sixth of this series to be released.
</dc:description>
<dc:description>The author briefly describes the early lives of General John Hunt and Martha Ready Morgan, detailing more specifically their courtship and marriage during the Civil War.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.); Ready, Charles, 1802-1878; Morgan, John Hunt, 1825-1864; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Morgan, Martha Ready; Civil War Stories</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>22 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-01-26</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication34ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/75</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>