<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Rutherford County Historical Society publication no. 24: The history of medicine in Rutherford County, Tennessee</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Ransom, Robert G.</dc:creator>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1984</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>19th century; 20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>n T S U LIBRARr
F^ IIIIMIIIIIIIII RD COUNTY
3 3082 00527 6919
wwwi-.
HISTORICAL SOCIETY
Publication No. 24
WINTER 1985
Murfreesboro, Tennessee 37133-0906
Digitized by the Internet Archive
in 2010 with funding from
Lyrasis IVIembers and Sloan Foundation
http://www.archive.org/details/publication24ruth
RUTHERFORD COUNTY HISTORICAL SOCIETY
PUBLICATION NO. 24
Published by the
RUTHERFORD COUNTY HISTORICAL SOCIETY
OFFICERS
President Mrs. Homer Pittard
Vice President Mr. Steve Brown
Recording Secretary Mrs. Cathy Goode
Corresponding Secretary Mrs. Susan Daniel
Publication Secretary Mr. Walter Hoover
Treasurer Mrs. Kelly Ray
DIRECTORS: Mrs. Lalia Lester
Mr. Jerry Gaither
Mrs. Judy Lee Green
Publication No. 24 (Limited Edition - 650 copies) is distributed
to members of the Society. The annual membership dues is $10.00.
(Family $11.00) which includes the regular publications and the monthly
NEWSLETTER to all members. Additional copies of Publication 24 may be
obtained at $6.00 per copy.
All correspondence concerning additional copies, contributions to
future issues, and membership should be addressed to:
Rutherford County Historical Society
P.O. Box 906
Murfreesboro, Tennessee 37133-0906
Library
Middle Tennessee State Uni&gt;&#171;rs,x&gt;
&#8226;^'"^"^
Urfreesboro. Tennessee
^ '^^'/^ FOR SALE
V , 7 ^:
THE FOLLOWING PUBLICATIONS ARE FOR SALE BY:
The Rutherford County Historical Society
P.O. Box 906
Murfreesboro, Tennessee 37130
PUBLICATIONS 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 8, and 9 are out of print.
PUBLICATION 7: Hopewell Church, Petition by Cornelius Sanders'
for Rev. War Pension - - $3.50 + $1.00 postage
PUBLICATION 10: 1864 Diary, Peter Jennings, Henderson Yoakum, Early
Methodist Church, and Overall
family $3.50 + $1.00 postage
PUBLICATION 11: State Capitol, Ben Mc Culloch, Petition of Michael
Lorance, Country Store, and Soule College
$3.50 + $1.00 postage
PUBLICATION 12: Out of Print
PUBLICATION 13: Tennessee College, Coleman Scouts, New Monument in Old
City Cemetery and James Boles' Revolutionary War
Pension $3.50 + $1.00 postage
PUBLICATION 14: Murfreesboro Presbyterian Church, Kirks and Montgomerys,
Russell Home, John Lytle and John M. Leak's Revolution-ary
War Pension $3.50 + $1.00 postage
PUBLICATION 15: John W. Childress' home (1847), Whigs in Rutherford
County, 1835-1845 $3.50 + $1.00 postage
PUBLICATION 16: Hart, Childress, Miles, Fosterville, Cherry Shade,
William Cocke $3.50 + $1.00 postage
PUBLICATION 17: Jefferson 1803-1813, Will Abstracts (1803-1814),
Old City Cemetery $3.50 + $1.00 postage
PUBLICATION 18: Railroad Stations in Rutherford County, Rion Family
Stones River ---------- $3.50 + $1.00 postage
PUBLICATION 19: Footprints ... at Smyrna, V.A. Medical Center, Manson
Family, Jenkins' Homes, Will Abstracts (Record Books 3 &amp;
4), Rutherford Co. Hist. Society, Early News, Bio. Sketch
from Macon Co., 111., 1981 in Rutherford County - - -
$3.50 + $1.00 postage
PUBLICATION 20: Roads and Turnpikes of Rutherford Co. (includes many
Rutherford Co. names) ------ $5.00 + $1.00 postage
89-09192
FOR SALE
PUBLICATION 21: Jefferson Springs Resort, Lascassas Baptist Church,
John Price Buchanan, Will Abstracts, 1836 Tax Records
of 25th District $5.00 + $1.00 postage
PUBLICATION 22: Ft. Rosecrans, Big Springs, East Main Church of Christ
Tax Record District 23 &amp; 24, for 1836, 1837, and 1849
Mathias Hoover $5.00 + $1.00 postage
PUBLICATION 23: Harding House, Milton Country Stores in Jefferson area.
Will Abstracts book 7, Tax Record of District 15 &amp; 16
for 1836, 1837, and 1849 $5.00 + $1.00 postage
PUBLICATION 24: History of Medicine in Rutherford Co.. .$6.00 + $1.00 postage
History of Westbrook - Williams and Smotherman of Rutherford Co. with
fustories of Midland, Oak Grove School and Old Leb Church
$12.00 + $2.00 postage
History of Versailles (southwestern Rutherford Co.) in hard cover, (some
families included are: Adcock, Brown, Burns, Carlton, Covington,
Crick, Dyer, Farris, Garrett, Gillespie, Hendrix, Ivey, Jackson,
Jones, Lamb, Lawrence, Leathers, Lowe, Manier, Maxwell, Mc Gee,
Morris, Nance, Pinkerton, Opoe, Powers, Puckett, Ray, Ralston, Rice,
Rutledge, Sharver, Smotherman, Tabor, Taylor, Whitehead, Williams
Windrow, Winsett) $9.00 + $2.00 postage
History of Rutherford County by C.C. Sims (pub. 1947) Reprint - -
$12.00 + $2.00 postage
1840 Rutherford County Census with Index $5.00 + $1.00 postage
Deed Abstracts of Rutherford County 1803-1810 $10.00 + $1.00 postage
GRIFFITH : Illustrated by-centennial publication .... $2.00 + $1.00 postAGE
CEMETERY RECORDS OF RUTHERFORD COUNTY :
Vol. 1 Northwestern third of county and part of Wilson and Davidson
counties, 256 cemeteries with index and maps $10.00 + $1.00 postage
Vol. 2 Eastern third of Rutherford and the western part of Cannon Co.,
241 cemeteries with index maps $10.00 + $1.00 postage
Vol. 3 Southwestern third of Rutherford Co., 193 cemeteries with
index and maps $10.00 + $1.00 postage
Available from: William W. Walkup, 202 Ridley Street, Smyrna, TN 37167
1878 Rutherford County Map, shows land owners $3.50 + $1.00 postage
Available from : Mrs. R.A. Ragland, P.O. Box 544, Murfreesboro, TN 37130
Marriage Record of Rutherford Co. 1851-1872 $10.00 + $1.00 postage
Note Cards : Box of twelve with six different designs of covers for our
publications by Jim Matheny $3.00 + 50?; postage
THE HISTORY OF MEDICINE
IN RUTHERFORD COUNTY,
TENNESSEE
PART I
by
ROBERT G. RANSOM, M.D,
Dedicated to all the physicians
who have lived these scenes, and
to those of the future who will
create theirs
CONTENTS
PREFACE iv
ACKNOWLEDGMENTS vi
INTRODUCTION 1
Chapter Page
I. STATE OF THE MEDICAL ART 1803-1860 5
II. MEDICAL PRACTICE IN RUTHERFORD COUNTY
1803-1860 21
III, THE STATE OF THE MEDICAL ART 1860-1920 .... 71
IV. MEDICAL PRACTICE IN RUTHERFORD COUNTY
1860-1920 87
V. STATE OF THE MEDICAL ART 1920-1980 172
VI . MEDICAL PRACTICE IN RUTHERFORD COUNTY
1920-1980 189
VII. BLACK PROFESSIONAL PRESENCE IN RUTHERFORD
COUNTY 245
VIII. CONTEMPORARY MEDICAL PRACTICE IN RUTHERFORD
COUNTY 267
BIBLIOGRAPHY 277
INDEX 288
PREFACE
In the course of the research on this historical
project, I have drawn certain conclusions and made certain
assumptions which I deem to be logical and plausible
explanations of the data at hand. The information has
been gathered from multiple sources. Prominent in the
research have been the material obtained at the Tennessee
State Library and Archives, Nashville, Tennessee; Vander-bilt
University School of Medicine library, Nashville,
Tennessee; Meharry Medical School library and archives,
Nashville, Tennessee; Middle Tennessee State University
library, Murf reesboro, Tennessee; Linebaugh library,
Murf reesboro, Tennessee; and the Filson Club library,
Louisville, Kentucky. Additionally, much valuable
information has been obtained from members of physicians'
families through correspondence, telephone conversations,
and personal interviews. The assimilation of this material
has not been an easy task; I consider the conclusions to
be reasonable based upon the extensive analysis of the
data obtained, although occasional errors may be discerned
in the findings.
The history will be presented in five parts. Part I
will be an introduction and overview of the history of
medicine in the county; Part II is a collection of
biographies of nineteenth century physicians who practiced
here; Part III is a collection of biographies of twentieth
century physicians who practiced or are practicing here;
Part IV is a history of Rutherford Hospital (now the Middle
Tennessee Medical Center); and Part V is a history of the
Rutherford County Health Department.
The subject of medical history is intensely interesting
and stimulating. Like all research projects it seems a
continuous and never ending task and can frequently be a
lifetime involvement. I recognize that my effort on this
subject is at best an imperfect outline of the medical
history of Rutherford County. However, I present this
research to all those interested in history with the hope
that it will prove interesting to the present and future
generations, and especially to those who have direct or
indirect involvement in the medical history of this area
that it may help to preserve to their posterity information
regarding that involvement.
Robert G. Ransom, M. D.
Murf reesboro, Tennessee
October, 1984
ACKNOWLEDGMENTS
To list individually all who have helped or encouraged
me in this research would require pages. Many have been of
invaluable assistance, but some are preeminent.
I am grateful to Dr. Robert Jones of the history
department at Middle Tennessee State University for his
helpful suggestions and encouragement.
Mrs. Kelly Ray and Mr. Ernest Johns have encouraged
the publication of this material from the outset.
Many physicians' family members have given their time
unselfishly in correspondence, telephone conversations
and personal interviews.
Many busy physicians were interviewed to "tap their
memory bank." They granted time unhurriedly for this
project and encouraged me along the way.
I have received many photographs through the courtesy
of physicians and descendants of physicians which were
earmarked for use in the final manuscripts. I thank each
of them.
The libraries used in the research were very generous
with their help and suggestions. Those with restricted
archival and historical sections welcomed my project and
granted me unhindered access to their priceless and
irreplaceable material.
vi
My thanks to each publisher or copyright holder who
gave me permission to quote or reproduce their copyrighted
material
.
Mrs. John Q. Wade offered many helpful suggestions
during the organization of the manuscript, and typed the
final manuscript with her usual professional skill. A
special acknowledgment and thanks is extended to her.
Throughout all the traveling, interviewing, corre-sponding,
and researching among the various "medical folk,"
I have only encountered cooperation, interest, encourage-ment,
and kindness. Their enthusiasm made this work much
easier.
Finally, I would like to thank my wife, Margaret.
Her hours of assistance in reading microfilm, typing, and
proofreading, as well as her understanding and
encouragement, were invaluable.
INTRODUCTION
The physicians who figure historically in the practice
of medicine in Rutherford County include not only those
who practiced in Murf reesboro, but also those who practiced
in the outlying rural communities. Such a list must also
include the physicians in the neighboring communities of
our sister counties; Cannon, Coffee, Bedford, Marshall,
Williamson, Davidson, and Wilson. The physicians who
practiced in such neighboring communities to Rutherford
County maintained practices which encompassed both
counties. Such communities include Cainsville, Norene
,
Vine, and Vesta of Wilson County; Unionville, Rover,
Deason, Bellbuckle, Wartrace, and Fairfield of Bedford
County; Beech Grove, Gossburg, and Noah of Coffee County;
Allisona, College Grove, Kirkland, Triune, and Nolensville
of Williamson County; Chapel Hill and Holtland of Marshall
County; Auburntown, Bradyville, Woodbury, Curlee, Porter-field,
and Readyville in Cannon County; Oneyville,
Treppardsville, Kimbro, and Antioch in Davidson County
(Figure 1 ) .
At the inception of Rutherford County in 1803, few
doctors were in the area. And the few who were resident
did not depend on medicine for their living. Few, if any,
could make a living practicing medicine alone. Too, the
1
&#8226;r
3W3ilo/v,
o**-
area was pioneer and primitive, sparsely settled, hardly an
area for a flourishing medical practice. Medical practice
was usually combined with another occupation such as
farming, storekeeping, preaching, teaching, and other forms
of endeavor. The economy was agrarian; as the century
progressed more physicians were found in small country
communities. During the late nineteenth century, virtually
every rural community in Rutherford County had one or more
doctors. With the advent of industry and improved
transportation, the economy became less agrarian and more
concentrated in the towns and cities with the resulting
migration of physicians away from the rural communities to
the more urban. With these gradual changes, the physician's
medical practice increased and he became a man of medicine
full time. Too, the improvements in medical knowledge
improved medical practice. X-rays, laboratory testing
became available, hospitals built, all concentrating
medical practice in the town or city. The horse and buggy
passed into oblivion in favor of the automobile. Home
calls faded away in favor of medical office or medical
center care. Let us not yearn for the old, but appreciate
the new. But let us not forget the old. Much of that
which is learned today, in its broad aspects, is under-standable
only when superimposed upon a historical
background. "The longer you look back, the further you can
look forward," said Mr. Winston Churchill, when addressing
the Royal College of Physicians in March, 1944.
CHAPTER I
STATE OF THE MEDICAL ART 1803-1860
There was no such thing as a "licensed physician" in
Rutherford County in 1803. There was no law in Tennessee
which required a practitioner of medicine to be licensed.
Anyone, regardless of training, could profess to be a healer
and practice unhindered if he so desired. Those who were
legitimate practitioners of medicine possessed a knowledge
of the medical arts. Most were trained by apprenticeship,
usually two to four years, to a physician who most often
was himself apprentice-trained.
Under this arrangement the preceptor provided his
student with practical experience and such theo-retical
knowledge as he possessed, and in return
the student assisted his preceptor in practice,
performed various chores, and paid him a fee.
Whether the student was well or poorly trained
depended on the ability, knowledge, and conscien-tiousness
of his preceptor .
'&#8226;
Apprenticeship, then, was the traditional mode of medical
education that carried over to the frontier.
At the time of the American Revolution it was esti-mated
that only 400 of approximately 3500 colonial
practitioners held the M. D. degree. 2 Prior to the
Ijohn H. Ellis, Medicine in Kentucky (Lexington, Ky.
:
The University Press of Kentucky, 1977), p. 3.
^Highlights of 200 Years of American Medicine&#8212;No. 1,
prepared by the American Medical Association, Journal of
the Tennessee Medical Association , V. 69, No. 3 (1976), 210,
Revolution a few sons of wealthy parents went abroad for
formal medical education in the European centers of London
and Edinburgh. After the Revolution the political climate
with England was hardly receptive for our students to train
in their universities, even if students from this new, poor
and struggling nation could afford a foreign education. So
apprenticeship was virtually all that was available to a
young aspiring student of medicine.
Most of the few physicians, prior to the Revolution,
who possessed their M. D. were trained at the University of
Edinburgh. Benjamin Rush and John Morgan were both Edin-burgh
trained physicians under the great William Cullen.
In 1765 John Morgan established the first American medical
school, as an adjunct to the College of Philadelphia.
By requiring preliminary education for admission to
what became known as the Medical Department of the
University of Pennsylvania, Morgan intended to
elevate the social and professional standing of the
physician. His overall plan for the school was
almost immediately successful, and within a-.few
years, he assembled a full medical faculty.
Benjamin Rush (famous as a patriot and signer of the Decla-ration
of Independence) joined the faculty. The influence
of the University of Pennsylvania and its eminent and
forceful teachers was profound and of long duration.
^Ellis, p. 6.
King's College was founded in New York in 1768,
Harvard in 1783, Dartmouth in 1797, and the University of
Maryland in 1807, but the University of Pennsylvania was
far ahead of these in training new physicians.
There was no university west of the mountains in 1803.
Transylvania University Medical School was founded in
Lexington, Kentucky in 1817. The University of Louisville
Medical Department was founded in 1837. The University of
Nashville Medical Department did not open until 1851. Many
of the apprentice trained physicians, at least those who
were aspiring, hoped to obtain formal medical education and
an M. D. degree. Many of them were eventually able to save
the necessary money to travel to the University of Pennsyl-vania,
University of Maryland, Transylvania University, or
the University of Louisville. With two years apprentice-ship
the physician could enroll at a medical college and
take two years of course work of from four to seven months
per year, depending on the school curriculum, and after two
years of such work, obtain an M. D. degree.
The preeminent medical school at that time certainly
was the University of Pennsylvania and the preeminent
professor and force at the University of Pennsylvania was
Dr. Benjamin Rush. Therefore, American medical practice in
the late eighteenth and early nineteenth centuries was
dominated by the precepts and teachings of Benjamin Rush.
This man was intelligent, he was active in politics, he was
a signer of the Declaration of Independence, an ardent
patriot, activQ in public affairs. His energy seemed
boundless. He was a prolific medical writer and some of
his treatises are classics today. His monograph on insanity
was ahead of its time. Fielding Garrison, the medical
historian, characterized Rush as
a man of highly original mind, well read, well
trained in his profession, an attractive, straight
forward teacher--sometimes wrong-headed as well as
strong-headed .
^
Rush taught that
disease, particularly disease manifested by fever,
was due to the accumulation of a bodily poison that
exerted its harmful effect by causing a nervous
constriction of the vessels and to bring about a
relaxation of the nervous excitement. Elimination
was promoted by bleeding, administering drugs to
induce vomiting, purging, sweating, and salivation,
by drawing the poison to the surface by cupping
(applying suction cups) and by blistering the skin.
Calomel was sometimes given in such large doses that
it caused the hair and the teeth to fall out. Rush
cautioned his students that in blood-letting nothing
could be worse than timidity, saying that it was
frequently desirable to bleed a patient to the
point of unconsciousness. Even in his obstetrical
practice. Rush bled his patients, 30 ounces at the
^Fielding Garrison, History of Medicine (Philadelphia,
Pa.: W. B. Saunders Co., 1929), p. 379.
beginning of labor, and at the same time, administering
purgatives .^
Bleeding was produced by an operation which consisted
in making an opening into a vessel to draw blood from it.
When practiced on an artery, it was called arteriotomy.
When practiced on a vein, it was termed phlebotomy or
venesection. The process of bleeding is referred to some-times
as blood-letting, venesection, arteriotomy, or wet-cupping.
Blood-letting was used in the nineteenth century,
both during the existence of a disease and in the prevention
of disease. It was employed to fulfill various indications
among which were (1) to diminish the actual mass of blood,
(2) to diminish the consistence of the blood. The immedi-ate
effects of blood-letting were diminution of the mass of
blood and of heat, retardation of the pulse and sometimes
syncope. Blood-letting from the veins (venesection or
phlebotomy) was practiced on the subcutaneous veins of the
neck, the face, the forearm, the leg, sometimes on those of
the hand or foot. The necessary apparatus consisted of a
bandage or riband, a compress of rag, and a lancet. The
operation of phlebotomy in the limbs was performed by tying
a circular bandage around the limb, acting as a tourniquet.
A puncture was then made into the vein and the desired
^James Bordley III, M. D., and A. McGehee Harvey, M. D. ,
Two Centuries of American Medicine 1776-1976 (Philadelphia,
Pa.: W. B. Saunders Co., 1976), pp. 34-35.
10
quantity allowed to flow. The ligature was then removed
and a compress and retaining bandage applied. Capillary
or local blood-letting was also practiced on the skin or
mucous membranes by means of leeches, the lancet or cupping.
Cupping is a type of blood letting performed by a scarifi-cator
and a glass called a cupping glass. The lancets are
placed in such a manner in the scarificator that when it is
applied upon the affected part, the whole are by means of
a spring, pushed suddenly into it. After scarification
the cupping glass which has been previously exhausted by
heat or by an exhausting syringe is then applied. The
pressure of the air within the glass, being thus diminished,
allows the necessary quantity of blood to be drawn. The
latter procedure is referred to as wet-cupping. Dry-cupping
is the application of the glasses without previous scarifi-cation.
Dry-cupping was used to prevent the activity of
absorption from any wounded part. Occasionally it was used
to excite suppuration in abscesses and to remove pus when
an abscess was opened. Cupping, taken without any epithet
means the abstraction of blood by means of the scarificator
and cups
.
Blisters were often used as a counter-irritant. The
physicians felt that by exciting a disease artificially on
the surface, he could often remove the effect of a disease
11
which might be, at the time, existing internally. The
blisters were accomplished by applying irritants to the
skin such as cantharides, mustard, euphorbium, garlic and
ammonia. It was simply raising a blister on the skin by
applying irritating chemicals. The physicians thought the
fluid in the vesicles was drawing out the various "poisons"
within.
Emetics were felt to be valuable agents in disease.
They were substances capable of producing vomiting. The
physicians felt that there was a "sympathy" between the
stomach and other parts of the body which was very
extensive; therefore they used emetics to "help" other organs
in disease. The chief emetics used were antimony and
potassium tartrate, copper acetate, copper sulfate, ipecac,
lobelia, and zinc sulfate. Purgatives were used to keep
the bowels opened, from mild purgation to intense purgation,
depending on the opinion of the physician as to how
vigorous he must expel the "poison." Calomel was a
standard item. This is mercuric chloride and was used as a
cathartic and diuretic. They liked to use calomel because
it kept the kidneys opened as well as the bowels and they
would frequently use it to the point of toxicity which
would be measured by the degree of ptyalism (salivation).
When the patient receiving calomel starting salivating a
12
great deal, the dosage was usually reduced. The calomel
also produced swelling of the gums and frequently looseness
of the teeth. Other purgatives frequently used were senna,
castor oil, aloe, jalap, magnesia. The specific agent or
purgation was chosen relative to the desired amount of
purgation, some being mild, others intermediate, others
strong.
A sinapism was a type of poultice or cataplasm of
which mustard formed the basis which was used for exciting
redness and acting as a counter irritant. It was prepared
by mixing flour 6f mustard and vinegar together to the due
consistency. It was applied to the soles of the feet of
patients in coma or on any patient who was exceptionally
sick or delirious and it was also used on the painful
parts in rheumatism.
Some of Rush's contemporaries did not agree with his
system of medicine and believed that his bleeding and
purging were excessive but he was such a reknown patriot,
such a forceful and energetic person, such a prolific
writer, such a dogmatist, and he had such a large following
among those who had attended his lectures at the Medical
College and elsewhere, that his influence was widespread
and long lasting. Rush's methods continued to be practiced
with some modifications for several decades after his
13
death. The erosion of his system, which came about slowly,
was attributable to several factors. More students were
beginning to study in European centers and were learning to
distrust dogmatism. They brought back fresh new ideas
about how one disease could be distinguished from another.
A spirit of critical inquiry was beginning to replace blind
reliance on authority. Many physicians began to realize
that some diseases were self-limiting and would run their
course and subside without the benefit of a physician.
Also, public antagonism toward the harsh therapy of the
Rush School made many people reject orthodox physicians and
turn to quacks and cultists who employed gentler remedies.
This competition from irregular practitioners forced the
profession to examine more critically the rationale of its
therapeutic measures.
Independent minds were beginning to doubt the efficacy
of bleeding as it was practiced and to collect statistical
evidence to determine the question. Skoda in Vienna gave
a series of pneumonia cases no treatment at all and got
results as good or better than those who were treated with
bleeding. Louis in Paris claimed that the influence of
bleeding in pneumonia was much less than was supposed.
He studied about 2000 cases and had many post-mortems. He
applied statistical analysis to his patients comparing the
14
effects of treatment by venesection and treatment without
venesection. He found that there was no statistical
difference in morbidity or mortality. He made a similar
extensive study in typhoid fever and he proved the value
of statistics in medical work.
We wonder today how people had the fortitude to call
a doctor knowing that they would have to submit to the
harsh treatment employed by Rush and his many followers.
They did so because of the high mortality rate of the
diseases then prevalent, because the practices were
advocated by Rush, and because it was commonly believed
that without medical intervention the natural outcome of
disease was death.
The medical problems which physicians faced in 1803
were much different from those of today.
Infectious diseases were paramount. The death rate
among children was appalling. To be convinced of
this, one has only to walk through a cemetery of the
mid-nineteenth century and note the graves of those
who died before reaching their tenth year.&#176;
Cholera, yellow fever, influenza, pneumonia, diphtheria,
measles, scarlet fever, typhoid, typhus, diarrheal
diseases, tuberculosis accounted for many of the deaths of
all age groups.
^Bordley and Harvey, p. 31.
15
Some of these infectious diseases occurred in epi-demics,
notably cholera, diphtheria, typhus, typhoid fever,
yellow fever, and small pox. The great epidemics of the
nineteenth century were,
to the people of those days, as mysterious as they
were terrifying. They came stealthily, spread
relentlessly, and killed without respect for age or
rank. It must have been obvious to intelligent
people that the doctors knew neither how to prevent
disease nor how to cure it. The best medical advice
was to flee the affected area with all possible
haste, and this practice was followed by most of
those possessing the means to do so. The sense of
helplessness was of course due to ignorance about
the cause of the disease and about how it was spread;
the terror of confronting a remorseless, invisible
enemy . 7
'
Syphilis was not uncommon, but the mortality
from this disease is obscure, since the more serious
late manifestations were not then recognized.
Streptococcal infections in the form of erysipelas,
scarlet fever and childbed fever were common.
Though nothing is known about the incidence of
streptococcal and pneumococcal infections of the
respiratory tract, it may be presumed that it was
high. Malaria was prevalent in the southern states
and frequently had serious consequences in spite of
the availability of quinine.
Since the causes of infectious diseases were not
known and since it was difficult to distinguish one
from another, these diseases were treated in a more
or less similar manner. There is little doubt that
in many cases the treatment did more harm than good.^
In spite of the limitations, the nineteenth century
saw the profession gradually improving its knowledge in
'Bordley and Harvey, p. 31.
^Bordley and Harvey, p. 34.
16
breadth. Certain objective features of disease were known,
the art of careful observation has been cultivated, many
empirical remedies had been discovered, the courser
structure of man's body had been well worked out, and a
good beginning had been made in the knowledge of how the
machinery worked. But what disease really was, where it
was, how it was caused, had not even begun to be discussed
intelligently.
Empirical discoveries of helpful medications included
quinine for fever and malaria, digitalis for heart failure,
colchicine for gout, and opiates for pain. Smallpox
vaccine became available about 1800.
Most of the major medical discoveries in the nineteenth
century were being made in Europe but outstanding dis-coveries
were made in this country as well. John C. Otto
of Philadelphia in 1803 wrote the first account of hemo-philia
in which he described an investigation of a family
of "bleeders." In 1807 John Starns, of Saratoga County,
New York was the first to publish an account of the
physiological effects of ergot in which he reported both
its ability to stimulate and strengthen uterine contrac-tions
and its power to constrict small blood vessels. He
explained how ergot could be utilized to speed up child-birth
and to control postpartum hemorrhage. His
17
observations were soon confirmed by others, and, within a
short time, ergot was recognized as a valuable drug avail-able
to obstetricians. Ephraim McDowell, a frontier
physician of Danville, Kentucky, was the first in the world
to succeed in removing a diseased ovary in 1809, a remark-able
achievement in the early days of the nineteenth
century. In 1811 Elisha North of New London, Connecticut,
wrote a treatise on a malignant epidemic, commonly called
spotted fever. This work, based on personal observations
of more than two hundred patients in a single epidemic,
gave the first adequate description of cerebral spinal
fever (meningitis). North was among the first to emphasize
the importance of the clinical thermometer for the study
of fever. Laennec laid the foundation of modern clinical
medicine with his discovery of auscultation and the
publication of his work on auscultation in 1819. His
development of the stethoscope ushered in the era of
physical diagnosis. Laennec ' s book^ is among the eight or
ten greatest contributions to the science of medicine. In
1831 chloroform was discovered by Samuel Guthrie, a chemist,
It was not until 1847 that its anesthetic qualities were
^R. T. H. Laennec, M. D., A Treatise on the Diseases
of the Chest (London: T. and G. Underwood, 1821).
18
recognized and put to use by James Simpson, Professor of
obstetrics at Edinburgh. William Beaumont made a great
contribution by his experiments on the physiology of
digestion. He .published his classical work in 1833.
Richard Bright in 1836 opened a new chapter on the relation
of disease of the kidney to dropsy, Daniel Drake in 1840
was the first to write a clinical description of "milk
sickness." During the first half of the eighteenth century
this disease caused many deaths and much serious illness
among the frontiersmen of the middle west and actually
delayed the settlement of that area. A discovery of supreme
importance occurred at Massachusetts General Hospital,
October 16, 1846. On that day, William T. Morton, in a
public operating room, rendered a patient insensible with
ether and demonstrated the utility of surgical anesthesia.
The occasion was one of the most memorable in the history
of medicine. In 1850 Henry Bowditch of Boston introduced
thoracentesis, drawing off accumulation of fluid in the
chest. William Reid of Rochester, New York, in a series of
observations and experiments reported in 1851 and 1855,
laid down the principals for the reduction of dislocation
by simple manipulation. His methods were quickly accepted
and won for him an international reputation. The publica-tion
in 1858 of the research of Virchow on cellular
19
pathology removed the seats of disease from the tissues to
the individual elements, the cells.
Although the American discoveries and innovations
cited contributed to the progress of medicine, these were
not a part of a broad plan and did not result in the
creation of a foundation upon which a scientific structure
could be erected.
Therefore, this was in sharp contrast with the con-sistent
and progressive development of clinical diagnosis
and physiology in France, and of cellular pathology,
biochemistry, and physiology in Germany. The Europeans
were creating a firm base for modern medical science,
while the American contributions (anesthesia excepted) did
no more than fill in largely by chance, a few gaps in the
rising structure.
We must remember that the physicians of earlier times
were practicing within the framework of medical knowledge
as it was known at that time.
When we reflect that physicians of earlier
times saw the same diseases as we see, were
possessed of the same five senses, were equally
earnest and conscientious, and that about the same
proportion then as now were endowed with common
sense, it does not seem reasonable to look upon
them as being so incompetent and impractical as
often we are disposed to do.
We have the advantage of living in a period
when research into the material world has made trite
for us knowledge which was hidden from them. For
20
making our observations we have numerous instruments
of precision whereas they had to depend on judgment
alone.
Then, as now, speculation and hypothesis
supplemented exact knowledge.
Hypotheses are useful but it is important not
to accept them as demonstrated facts. There is little
doubt that some of the hypotheses accepted today
will seem very absurd to the science of the future.
The fact that a man has adhered to an erroneous
hypothesis by no means convicts him of being
incompetent
.
^
^
^^B. M. Randolph, M. D., '*rhe Blood Letting Controversy
in the Nineteenth Century," Annals of Medical History ,
V. 7 (1935), 177.
CHAPTER II
MEDICAL PRACTICE IN RUTHERFORD COUNTY 1803-1860
When Rutherford County was founded in 1803, appropri-ately
educated physicians were a rarity, but the stock of
people who moved into this area were a pioneer breed and
perfectly willing to take their chances by acting as their
own physician. They exchanged medical recipes just as they
exchanged kitchen recipes. They had a recipe for virtually
every symptom one can imagine. Some were helpful, some
were not. When one v\7as found to give beneficial results,
it was shared with neighbors all around, for the pioneer
spirit dictated that each must help the other.
Most of the families, who were moving west at the
turn of the nineteenth century, possessed a medical book
which gave advice on almost every medical problem. As
they pushed farther west into the wilderness, medical care
simply was not available. They acted as their own
practitioners using such books as a guide. These books
occasionally were written by physicians and occasionally
they were written by quacks. One of the v/ell known books
used in this area was Gunn ' s Domestic Medicine . The book
discussed in plain language the diseases of men, women and
children and it contained descriptions of the medical
21
22
roots and herbs of the western and southern country and how
they were to be used in the cure of diseases. The latter
book was one of the better written books for this purpose.
Much superstition pervaded the populace about medical
illnesses. Many carried a buckeye in their pocket to
ward off rheumatism. Many would wear a bag of asafetida
attached to a string about the neck. The asafetida
supposedly protected against infectious diseases. They
would frequently use asafetida hung around a baby's neck
to protect the baby from infectious disease. A bag
supposedly protected the baby for six months. A man was
hanged in Murfreesboro in 1813. The rope used for the
execution was cut up and the small pieces passed out to
the spectators as talismans against human ills.-'- More
logically, the people kept on hand a variety of medications
and herbs with which they would prepare various teas,
salves, and poultices according to medical recipes col-lected
by the family over the years. The people frequently
depended more on their medical recipes than on trained
doctors. There were also people roaming all over the area
with absolutely no training in science, pushing themselves
'Carlton C. Sims, Editor, A History of Rutherford
County (Murfreesboro, TN. : Reprinted by Rutherford County
Historical Society, 1981), p. 130.
23
upon the public as cancer doctors, arthritis doctors, and
herb doctors, all sorts of quackery. There was no legal
regulation of any kind to prevent the business of
charlatans and quacks.
Surgery was limited to opening abscesses, removing
foreign bodies, setting fractures, closing cuts. Surgery
was still in a primitive state. They knew nothing about
the necessity for cleanliness in surgery. Infections
were devastating. It was not unusual for the surgeon with
unwashed hands to suture while he held the scalpel in his
teeth, frequently keeping the needles and thread fastened
to his coat lapel. The germ theory was not to be dis-covered
until the late nineteenth century.
The earliest physicians in this county were Doctors
T. Vernon about 1803, James Loudon Armstrong 1809,
William Ward 1811, Swepson Sims 1811, John Nash Reid 1810,
James Roane about 1812, Wilson Yandell, W. E. Butler,
W. T. Henderson, and Elisha B. Clark 1816-17. The dates
are approximate. These doctors were all trained under
the apprenticeship. Dr. Wilson Yandell was particularly
well trained and had three sons who became physicians.
Then, in the 1820s and early 1830s, included Dr. James
Maney, Frederick Edward Becton, Isaac C. Brown, Alfred
Hartwell, P. H. Mitchell, Patrick D. Neilson, George
24
Thompson, Henry Holmes Treadway, Samuel Watkins, John
Robertson Wilson, Lunsford Pitts Yandell, and Benjamin
Avent. Doctors Armstrong, Sims, and Wilson Yandell were
still practicing also.
The early medical practice in Rutherford County could
be typified by a letter Dr. James Roane wrote to a friend
who was caring for his cousin in Virginia. The letter
was written in 1817 and he stated that from the descrip-tion
the friend had given, his cousin's complaint was
probably "rheumatic" and he recommended that the friend
take about a half pint of blood and use a purgative in
preparation for the following: dissolve one ounce of soda
in a pint of strong decoction of seneka snake root and
take two tablespoons, evening and morning in water or in
some pleasant tea. He also advised wearing a warm plaster
between the shoulders.^ A part of every therapy for
virtually every disease was blood letting and purgatives
and emetics to rid the body of "poisons."
Dr. Lunsford Pitts Yandell, who started practicing
in Murfreesboro in 1826, wrote several papers which were
published in the Transylvania Journal of Medicine . A
^Letter from Dr. James Roane to David Campbell,
Abdingdon, VA. , Journal of the Tennessee Medical Associa -
tion, V. 75 (March, 1982), 225.
25
paper entitled "A Case of Purpura Haemorrhagica" was
published in 1828. The patient had pleurisy and pneumonia
symptoms. Dr. Yandell used venesection (blood-letting),
cathartics, and nauseating doses of antimony. It was
found necessary to repeat the bleeding more than once and
calomel in 10 grain doses was given for several nights in
succession followed by saline purgatives the next day.
He also used blisters and diaphoretic drugs. In due time
the patient developed severe diarrhea and opium was
resorted to. Later the patient began to show signs of
capillary hemorrhage from the mouth, ears and nostrils.
At that time they administered sulphuric acid and a gargle
made of borax. In a few days the patient rallied and
convalesced. Dr. Yandell attributed the bleeding to the
use of calomel. Dr. Yandell referred in his paper to
Laennec--ref erring to Laennec ' s observation in pneumonia
with the cylinder (early stethoscope) and the percussion
findings in the chest. Dr. Yandell also wrote a paper on
milk sickness which was published in the Transylvania
Journal of Medicine in 1828. He described the symptoms
Lunsford P. Yandell, M. D. , "A Case of Purpura
Hemorrhagica with Observations," Transylvania Journal of
Medicine and the Associate Sciences , V. 1 (1828), 237.
Lunsford P. Yandell, M. D. , "An Essay on Milk-sickness,"
Transylvania Journal of Medicine and Associate
Sciences , V. 1 (1828), 309.
26
very clearly and stated that venesection was not a valuable
remedy for this particular entity, that cathartics were
deemed to be the most practical, calomel to be preferred.
He stated that the bowels must be kept soluble with castor
oil, salts or senna until complete health is restored. He
also advised blisters to the abdomen, especially if the
bleeding and the calomel had not allayed the vomiting. He
emphasized that it was frequently necessary to cover the
abdomen with blisters. On the whole, he stated that he
would rely mainly on venesection, mercury, epispastics
and effusions of cold water upon the extremities. In the
last part of the paper, he described the post mortum
examination of several cases, giving the pathological
findings
.
The doctors believed that the decomposition of plant
and animal matter poisoned the air with "marsh miasmata"
giving rise to disease. The plant decomposition was
always best effected during the presence of warmth and
moisture which the physicians felt created rotted vegetable
matter which in turn contaminated people with various forms
of bilious disease, and they felt it was especially true
of areas which were frequently flooded by creeks, streams,
and rivers which laid down further deposits of decomposing
matter. Of course, their observations of topography were
27
at least partially correct, because in flooding these
areas, sewage contaminated the marshy areas and the water
supply was contaminated, therefore resulting in disease.
But these people did not know of the relationship of
sanitation to disease.
Dr. Samuel Hogg, who practiced mostly in Wilson
County, but who later bought a farm near Smyrna and
practiced in Rutherford County, wrote a letter to Dr. Samuel
Brown in which he discussed the history of the autumnal
fever of the year 1822 as it appeared in Wilson County,
which undoubtedly appeared in Rutherford County as well.
An epidemic prevailed that year, during the summer and
fall. The disease commenced in most cases with a chill,
pains in the extremities, soreness of all the muscles,
nausea, diarrhea, and pain in the area of the liver. He
stated that the skin was sometimes yellow. He described
the symptoms in minute detail. The patients were
treated with bleeding, cathartics, emetics, and the "bark"
(refers to the cinchona bark or similar quinine con-taining
bark). He used blisters to the region of the
stomach or liver, calomel was used freely, and opium to
induce rest. His letter was published by Dr. Samuel
28
Brown in the Western Journal of Medical and Physical
Sciences .
Murfreesboro was the capital of Tennessee from 1819
to 1826, a fact which undoubtedly influenced the influx
of talented and educated people. We were fortunate to
have in that period of our history a group of physicians
who were intelligent, honest and well-educated for their
day. It was they who began a movement to organize a
state medical society to improve the practice of medicine
in the state. It was their purpose to federate and
bring into one compact organization the entire medical
profession in the state of Tennessee and to unite with
similar associations in other states with a view to the
extension of medical knowledge and to the advancement of
medical science. The movement started in this county
by a meeting of interested physicians in 1829. We're
not sure who these physicians were but it stands to
reason that included in the group were the charter
members from Rutherford County in the state medical
association: Doctors James Maney, William R. Rucker,
Lunsford Pitts Yandell, Frederick E. Becton, and Samuel
Watkins . There were also undoubtedly other interested
Samuel Hogg, "A History of the Autumnal Fever of
the Year 1822," Western Journal of the Medical and
Physical Sciences , V, 2 (February, 1828),
29
physicians, probably from Davidson County and Wilson
County. It was entirely possible, although we do not
know, that this meeting was 'held at Oaklands, since
Dr. James Maney was one of the charter members of the
Tennessee State Medical Association. As a result of
this meeting, these doctors petitioned the legislature
to incorporate a medical society and it passed both
houses to become law on January 9, 1830, The act empow-ered
the society to elect a board of censors to issue or
to refuse a license to practice medicine in the state.
These board members would examine any prospective
applicant and decide whether or not he was sufficiently
trained to practice medicine. The act did not require,
however, that no one could practice medicine in the state
of Tennessee without a license. That was a fatal omission
and was not to be rectified until almost sixty years later
in 1889. So, even though the organization of a society
was a step in the right direction, there was no teeth
in the legislation to control the practice of medicine in
the state and during that period of time, the state con-tinued
to be a haven for all manner of quacks and charlatans.
The society repeatedly petitioned the legislature, unsuc-cessfully
over many years, to amend the act of incorporation
30
to require practitioners to be licensed. The society was
accused, on the other hand, of being self-serving in its
desire to control the practice of medicine. The public's
level of sophistication in such matters was such that it
mattered little to them whether a doctor was licensed or
not. Therefore, only a handful of Tennessee doctors
traveled the necessary horseback miles to be examined by
the society censors and become licensed. The society
persisted in its efforts and finally won the legislature's
cooperation. In 1889, the legislature passed a law which
required all practitioners of medicine to be licensed.
At the organizational meeting of the new state
medical association. Dr. James Roane, son of Governor
Archibald Roane, was chosen the first president of the
Medical Society of Tennessee and this gentleman practiced
in Murfreesboro for four years before he moved to
Nashville. Dr. Lunsford Pitts Yandell was elected the
first corresponding secretary of the state medical
association and he was a practitioner in Murfreesboro from
1826 to 1831. On the first board of censors was Dr. James
Maney. Doctors Frederick Becton and Lunsford Pitts
Yandell were on the committee charged to prepare and
present a code of medical ethics for the government of
the members of the society. At the first meeting of the
31
society, Dr. Roane, the president, appointed three
individuals of the society to read essays at the next
annual meeting in 1831. Of these three. Dr. Becton of
Murfreesboro was appointed to read an essay on medical
topography of disease in Rutherford County. The new
members from Rutherford County elected at the first
meeting were Doctors Alfred Hartwell, George Thompson,
John R. Wilson, Henry Holmes Treadway, William D. Gowen,
Henry Holmes, P. H. Mitchell, William M. Yandell, John
Claiborne Gooch, William L. Thompson, Thomas H, Read,
and Lafayette Ezell. Our physicians contributed admirably
to the development and organization of medicine in this
state from the outset and to medical education.
Dr. Lunsford Pitts Yandell was present at the 1831
meeting of the medical society in Tennessee to which he
had been elected corresponding secretary. His brother-in-law
from Murfreesboro, Dr. Frederick Becton, read a paper
on the medical topography of Rutherford County. There
were several points in the paper on which the two dis-agreed
rather pointedly and apparently some unpleasantness
was exchanged between the two doctors. &#176; Dr. Becton '
s
^Phillip M. Hamer, Editor, The Centennial History of
the Tennessee State Medical Association 1830-1930 ,
(Nashville, TN. : Tennessee State Medical Association,
1930), p. 37.
32
paper which he read at that meeting was published in the
Transylvania Journal of Medicine and the Associated
Sciences in 1832. He discussed in the paper the effect
of the marsh miasmata in causing diseases and expounded
several theories of his ov/n about how disease was
produced. He alluded to his observation that inhabitants
residing near the rivers on the low bank side are usually
more sickly than those who reside on the bluff side of
the stream. He referred to greater sickness among people
who were exposed to vicinities where stagnant water was
present in ponds or creeks. He referred to the type
buildings erected by the settlers of the county with
foundations or bottom logs on or near the ground. Chip
shavings and debris were left under the floors. The
sleepers upon which the flooring planks were laid were
close to the ground and, therefore, the rooms of these
homes were exposed to the decomposing matter. Additionally,
garbage was frequently decaying in the yard. He felt the
buildings should be raised with the dwelling houses and
kitchens some distance above the ground, removing all
vegetable substances from beneath the floors and out of
^Frederick E. Becton, M. D. , "An Essay on the Topo-graphy
and Diseases of Rutherford County, Tennessee,"
Transylvania Journal of Medicine and the Associate
Sciences , V. 5 (1832), 20.
33
the neighborhood of the yard, and leaving a free space for
ventilation under the houses. He alluded also to the
dietetic habits of the people, stating "we in Rutherford
County generally eat as if for a wager against time,
swallowing our food mashed, but not masticated, and of
course, scantily supplied saliva. Instead of applying
this useful adjuvant in digestion to its proper and
natural uses, it is spit up with tobacco juice, and the
food in the stomach must find its way to the coats of
that viscus floating in strong hot coffee." He treated
most of the diseases similarly, bleeding freely at the
beginning and subsequently by giving such doses of tarter
emetic as would produce free vomiting, and cathartics to
keep the bowels open. He also freely used cupping and
leeching as well as applying blisters.
The cholera epidemic visited Murfreesboro and the
Middle Tennessee area in 1833. The disease made its
appearance in June. The weather which had proceeded it
was intensely hot accompanied by frequent showers of rain.
The heat continued uninterruptedly for several weeks.
During this period, the epidemic raged with more or less
violence throughout the neighboring country. Dr. Henry
Yandell, a brother to Lunsford Pitts Yandell, wrote an
account of the epidemic as it appeared in Shelbyville.
34
The epidemic covered much of Middle Tennessee and would
probably typify the conditions of the epidemic in
Murfreesboro as well.
At once the whole population seemed to be invaded
by disease, scarcely an individual being found in
the place a day or two afterwards who was not more
or less indisposed. The premonitory diarrhea
generally preceded the more formidable symptoms but
its duration usually was brief, if not promptly
checked. The disease advanced after a few hours to
its more malignant stage. No class was exempt.
The wealthy and the poor, the temperant, the
intemperant, each furnished their share of victims.
Of the usual symptoms of the disease, vomiting was
uniformly present. When diarrhea came on simulta-neously
with this symptom, it rarely failed to
hurry the patient off in from two to eight hours.
For the first two days of its prevalence, few who
died lived beyond eight hours after their attack.
Out of a population of about 800, we lost thirty
the first day after its eruption. Its malignancy
was unabated on the second day, but, as many of
the citizens had fled, the number of deaths was
only about 15 or 20. In all, during its continuence,
one hundred and nine of our citizens perished. It
lingered in the town for about fourteen days when
the population returned to their homes, and since
that time uninterrupted health has prevailed. As
already remarked, the pestilence spread itself
throughout the surrounding country, several localities
being severely afflicted. In some families ten or
twelve died, and in Bedford County, it is supposed
that the number of deaths exceeded two hundred and
twenty.
&#176;
Dr. Yandell treated the disease with reliance chiefly
upon calomel. He was governed only by the effects
^Henry Yandell, M. D. , "An Account of Spasmodic
Colera, As It Appeared in Shelbyville, Tennessee, in the
Summer of 1833," Transylvania Journal of Medicine , V. 7
(1834), 5.
35
produced. He stated that the calomel alone seemed
competent to allay the gastric irritability and check the
watery passages. The description of the epidemic in
Shelbyville would certainly correlate with the descrip-tion
of the epidemic in Murf reesboro. Dr. James Roane
lost his life in Nashville of cholera in the 1833 epidemic.
The cholera epidemic visited again in 1835 with similar
results. Dr. Alfred Hartwell lost his life in that
epidemic
.
A majority of the physicians in Rutherford County
joined the Tennessee Medical Society. Dr. George Thompson
was made one of its censors in 1838. Dr. John Wilson
participated in the 1838 meeting. Professor Yandell
returned from Lexington regularly to participate in the
meetings. Dr. Treadway was appointed to read a medical
essay.
Dr. John W. Richardson was elected president of the
Tennessee Medical Society in 1849. Dr. Richardson was a
prominant physician in Rutherford County. He wrote a
paper which was published in 1842 on the diseases of
Rutherford County. 9 In his paper he mentioned first
9john W. Richardson, M. D., "Remarks on the Diseases
That Appeared in Rutherford County, Tennessee, During the
Year 1841, and the Winter of 1841-2," Western Journal of
Medicine and Surgery , V. 6 (1842), 426.
36
Dr. John W. Richardson
President
Tennessee Medical Association
1848-1850
37
intermittent fever, stating that it existed almost continu-ally.
Measles prevailed extensively during the early part
of 1841. Whooping cough had prevailed for twelve months.
Parotitis (mumps) had been in the neighborhood for a year
and was still prevailing. He stated that it progressed
remarkably slow, remaining in some families for four and
even six months. He stated that it was attended with
more fever and more cerebral disturbance (encephalitis).
The summer and autumnal diseases were of the usual charac-ter
with intermitting and remitting fevers. In November,
an epidemic of influenza commenced. Many cases were
alarming, so extensive and severe were the bronchial
inflamation and pain. During the winter there were some
cases of pleurisy, a good many cases of pneumonia and
combinations of the two. Tonsillitis visited during the
winter. He commented that in January an epidemic visited
which was more unmanageable than any of the former and
more fatal than all of the whole of them combined. The
cases he described were those of meningitis. Of those
who survived, some were left deaf or blind.
The physicians practicing in the area in the 1840s
were J. J. Abernathy, Martin W. Armstrong (Milton),
Benjamin Ward Avent , William T. Baskette, Thomas Crutcher
Black (Walter Hill), Jonathan Bostick (Triune), James
Area Physicians During the 1840s
38
J. J. Abernathy
Martin W. Armstrong
(Milton)
Benjamin Ward Avent
(Murf reesboro)
Wm. T. Baskette
(Murfreesboro
)
Thomas Crutcher Black
(Walter Hill)
Jonathan Bostick
(Triune
)
James Hamilton Charlton
(La Vergne area)
George D. Crosthwait
(Florence)
John Claiborne Gooch
( Smyrna
Samuel R. Gooch
James W. Gowen
(Cannon County)
William D. Gowen
Samuel Hogg
( Smyrna)
Reuben D. Hubbard
Daniel H. Johnson
James Maney
(Murf reesboro)
Francis J. Manning
(Fox Camp)
Robert C. Price
John W. Richardson
(Murf reesboro)
T. L. Rives
(Eagleville)
Samuel B. Robison
Dr. Rogers
William R. Rucker
Swepson Sims
George W. Thompson
Nimrod Whitefield Thompson
James Wade
John M. Watson
James Wendel
(Murf reesboro)
39
Hamilton Charlton, Nimrod W. Thompson, Jonathan C- Gooch,
George Thompson, James Wade, William R. Rucker, George D.
Crosthwaite, John M. Watson, James Maney, John W.
Richardson, Robert C. Price, R. D. Hubbard, Daniel H.
Johnson, Swepson Sims, F. J. Manning, Samuel B. Robison.
By virtue, undoubtedly, of Dr. Richardson's position
in the Tennessee Medical Society, the society convened in
Murfreesboro for three consecutive years, 1850, 1851, and
1852. The proceedings of the 1850 meeting follow:
Murfreesborough, Ten., Wednesday, April 3, 1850.
The Medical Society of Tennessee convened this
day, in Odd Fellow's Hall, according tb adjournment,
being its 21st annual session&#8212;the following members
present
:
John W. Richardson, Rutherford County, Ten.
L. P. Yandell, Louisville, Ky.
F. H. Gordon, Lebanon, Ten.
B. W. Avent, Murfreesborough, Ten.
R. S. Wendell, Murfreesborough, Ten.
Thos. C. Black, Murfreesborough, Ten.
W. R. Rucker, Murfreesborough, Ten.
The President, Dr. Richardson, called the Society
to order, and requested the members present to
re-sign the Constitution.
The Secretary being absent, on motion. Dr. R. S.
Wendel was appointed Secretary pro tem.
On motion of Dr. Yandell the rule requiring
the nomination of members to lie over one day, was
suspended, and thereupon the following gentlemen were
proposed and duly elected members of the Society,
Dr. J. Abernathy, Dr. G. W. Burton, Dr. P. D.
McCulloch, of Murfreesborough; Dr. S. H. Woods,
Dr. L. W. Knight, Dr. D. H. Johnson, Dr. J. B.
Armstrong, Dr. G. M. Alsup, Dr. W. A. Smith, Dr. L. V.
40
Young, of Rutherford Co.; Dr. T. F. Waters, of Smith
Co.; Dr. Caldwell, of Shelbyville; Dr. C. T. New, of
Woodbury; Dr. G. L. Robertson, Dr. J. H. Li Hard, of
Wilson Co.; and Dr. Smith Bowlin, of Bedford Co.
On motion of Dr. Avent , the following gentlemen
were appointed a Committee to arrange the order of
business for to-morrow--Dr . B. W. Avent, Dr. F. H.
Gordon, Dr. J. J. Abernathy.
Dr. Gordon offered the following . resolutions
,
which were read, and on motion adopted:
Resolved, That the long established custom of
writing medical prescriptions in the Latin Language
should be abolished;
Resolved, That Natural Philosophy and Chemistry
have an intimate connection with Medicine, throwing
much light upon it, and ought therefore to be
included among the preliminary studies of Medical
Students
;
Resolved, That the chief cause of the common
complaint of the disrepute and degradation of the
Medical Profession is to be found in the faulty
elementary, or office medical education, and that
the desired elevation of the standards, the qualifi-cations
and exaltation of the Profession will never
be accomplished until suitable measures shall be
adopted to correct the cause;
On motion, the Society adjourned until 9 o'clock,
to-morrow morning.
Thursday Morning, 9 o'clock.
The Society met pursuant to adjournment.
Proceedings of last meeting read.
The Committee appointed at last meeting to
arrange the order of business for this day, reported
the following, which on motion, was received and
adopted:
1. Reading of Essays.
2. Report of Cases.
41
3. Orator's Address.
4. Election of Officers.
5. Motions and Unfinished Business.
6. Appointments for next Annual Meeting.
7. Select Place for next Annual Meeting of
Society.
8. President's Address.
Your Committee would suggest the propriety of
appointing a reporter to take down the remarks of
members on such medical subjects as may be discussed.
B. W. Avent,
F. H. Gordon,
J. J. Abernathy,
On motion, Dr. G. Burton was appointed Reporter.
The appointments of Delegates to the next
meeting of the American Medical Association to be
held in Cincinnati, in May next, being in order, the
following were duly elected:
Dr. Kelley and Dr. J. Lindsley, of Nashville;
Dr. F. H. Gordon, of Lebanon; Dr. J. W. Richardson
and Dr. L. P. Yandell, of Rutherford Co.; Dr. G. W.
Burton, Dr. B. W. Avent, and Dr. J. J. Abernathy, of
Murfreesborough; Dr. Thos . Lipscomb of Shelbyville;
Dr. R. G. White, of Pulaski; Dr. H. R. Robards , of
Memphis
.
The Society then proceeded to the regular order
of business. Dr. J. B. Lindsley appointed at last
annual meeting to read an Essay on the Medical
Topography of Davidson County, being absent, was on
motion fined $10, for delinquency.
The following gentlemen appointed at last
meeting to report Cases, were also fined the sum of
$5 each for delinquency, viz: Dr. J. W. Percy,
Dr. R. M. Porter, Dr. S. H. Stout, Dr. W. P. Jones,
Dr. J. G. Barksdale, Dr. George Thompson, Dr. G. A.
J. Mayfield, Dr. S. S. Mayfield, and Dr. J. S. Parks.
Dr. Thomas Lipscomb also appointed to report
cases, excused his absense by letter, but presented
through the Corresponding Secretary, a paper on
Apoplexy, which on motion was received and read.
42
Dr. Avent read a paper on Traumatic Tetanus,
which was on motion received.
On motion the Society adjourned until l|
o'clock, P. M.
Thursday, l\ o'clock, P. M.
Society met pursuant to adjournment. On motion
the contribution fee was fixed at $2 the present
session.
The accounts of H. M. Watterson, B, R. McKennie
&amp; Co. and Dr. W. Taylor amounting to $15, for
advertising the meeting of the Society, were pre-sented,
and on motion allowed and ordered to be
paid by the Treasurer.
Dr. R. S. Wendell read a case of Intermittent
Fever, complicated with convulsions, which on motion
was received.
Dr. Avent, Corresponding Secretary, read a
communication from Dr. J. King, declaring his inability
to attend and deliver the Oration assigned him at the
last meeting of the Society. On motion a fine of $10
was imposed.
Dr. Gordon read a paper on Tetanus caused by
puncturing a Sarcomatus Tumor, which on motion was
received.
The President announced as next in order the
election of Recording Secretary, the other officers
being elected for the term of two years from last
meeting; when Dr. R. S. Wendel was on ballot duly
and constitutionally elected to fill said office.
Dr. Gordon offered the following which was
adopted:
Whereas, The painful intelligence has reached
this Society of death of our distinguished friend and
associate. Dr. Benjamin R. Owen, of Lebanon, by
whose decease, our Society and the Medical Profes-sion,
have lost one of their brightest ornaments,
therefore
43
Resolved, That a committee of two be appointed
to present at our next meeting, suitable testimonials
of the worth of our friend and the loss sustained by
his decease.
The President appointed Drs. Gordon and Lillard
as committee.
The President narrated some interesting cases
showing the value of Enemata of solution of nitrate
of silver in dysentery.
On motion of Dr. Burton, it was resolved that
the President write out a report of the same to be
published as part of the proceedings.
The appointments for the next annual meeting
being in order, the President made the follov/ing
&#8212;
Dr. F. H. Gordon, Orator; Dr. J. J. Abernathy, of
Murf reesborough and Dr. Tho ' s Lipscomb, of
Shelbyville, to read Essays; and Drs. Avent,
McCulloch, R. S. Wendel, and Burton, of Murf reesborough,
Drs. Alsup, Young, Knight, G. Thompson, Crosthwaite,
W. A. Smith, and Armstrong, of Rutherford Co.,
Dr. Waters of Smith Co., Dr. Robertson of Wilson Co.,
Drs. Barksdale and Caldwell of Shelbyville, Drs. S. S.
Mayfield and J. S. Park of Franklin, Drs. Percy,
Buchanan, Cheatham, Kelley, R. Martin, R. C. K.
Martin, Porter, King, Ford and Winston of Nashville
to Report Cases.
Dr. Avent offered the following resolution,
which was adopted:
Resolved, That Prof. L. P. Yandell, of the
University of Louisville, be requested to address
this Society at its next annual meeting.
Dr. Avent also offered the following resolution,
which was adopted--
Resolved, That the thanks of this Society be
tendered to Stranger's Refuge Lodge, No. 14, I.O.O.F.,
for the use of their Hall during the session of this
society.
Dr. Avent moved that a Committee of three by
appointed to prepare the proceedings of this Society
44
for publication, which was adopted, and Drs. Avent
,
R. S. Wendel and Burton appointed. On motion,
the President was added.
On motion, the President was requested to deliver
his address in the Methodist E. Church this evening,
at 7 1-2 .o'clock, and that the public be invited.
On motion, the Society adjourned until 1st
Wednesday in April, 1851, to meet at that time in
Murf reesborough
.
JOHN W. RICHARDSON, President.
R. S. Wendel, Cor. Secretary. 10
Dr. Avent ' s presentation on traumatic tetanus
indicated that physicians recognized that these symptoms
occurred as a result of a wound. This particular case was
preceeded by a wound to the foot in which a portion of
splinter had remained. Dr. Avent described the symptoms
of tetanus admirably, describing the severe spasms of the
muscles and stated that when the patient was laid on his
back, the heels and posterior skull were the only part of
the patient that would touch the bed. He stated that the
jaws were not completely locked but were very rigid, and
swallowing was very difficult so that they were frequently
prevented from administering either food or medicine. It
was difficult for the patient to speak. The treatment
IQ proceedings of the Twenty-First Annual Meeting of
the Tennessee Medical Society, Held at Murf reesborough ,
April, 1850 (Published by the Tennessee Medical Society,
1850) .
45
agreed upon was calomel in small doses, morphine, enemas
composed of brandy and well prepared gruel to be adminis-tered
every six hours. The spine should be rubbed with a
strong volatile linament. Spirits of turpentine and
castor oil were to be employed as purgatives. The wound
was opened and the splinter extracted. The morphine was
the main medication that helped relieve the symptoms of
spasms. The patient did recover although it required
several weeks. &#8226;'&#8226;-'
Dr. Wendell reported a case of fever accompanied by
gastroenteritis and convulsions in a man of age 35.
Dr. Wendell bled him freely from the arm which reduced
his pulse from an initial 120 per minute to nearly 90.
He then applied a cup to each temple but as their drawing
seemed to excite a great deal of pain, they were removed
without obtaining much blood. He gave the patient 15
grains of calomel and 2 grains of ipecac. He poured cold
water over his head for some several minutes and he
sponged the entire surface of the body with cold water
and directed the family to repeat the calomel and ipecac
in six hours and continue to use the cold water at
intervals. On the evening of the same day, Dr. Wendell
^^- Proceedings , April, 1850 , p. 11
46
returned and found the patient to have a pulse of about
100. He repeated the bleeding until the pulse indicated
some change. He gave him a stimulating enema and
repeated the enema in one hour. He then administered a
dose of castor oil. The next morning he continued the use
of cold water. The patient was given a purgative of
castor oil and calomel combined which was used twice
during the day. Later in the day, he was given calomel,
opium, and ipecac, to be given every three hours until
ptyalism (salivation) was manifested. Cups were applied
to the whole length of the spine, both wet and dry, and
this was followed by a blister on the nape of the neck
extending up and over the occiput (lower part of the
posterior skull). The sublingual glands (salivary glands)
were rubbed with an unguent and a teaspoon of a mixture
of strichnine and alcohol was ordered three times a day.
The following day. Dr. Wendell discovered that ptyalism
had taken place. He then gave him a cathartic of equal
quantities of castor oil and turpentine. He found the
pulse to be very weak and the extremities cold. He then
placed a large blister over the stomach and one on each
wrist and he dry cupped the whole length of the spine.
When Dr. Wendell returned in the evening, the patient
had a severe convulsion following which another enema was
47
given. The next day, the patient began to rally and
improve slowly and in a few weeks, he entirely recovered. -^"^
In Dr. Richardson's paper on injections of nitrate of
silver in dysentery, he advised the use of nitrate of
silver in an enema to be administered for the relief of
the diarrhea. He had found that this was especially
useful in the various dysenteries .
'-^
It was customary for the president of the society to
deliver his address to the society as the last item of
the meeting. In Dr. Richardson's address to the society,
he admonished the physicians to read and study. He stated
that the science of medicine had grown wonderfully since
the apprenticeship and studies of most of the physicians
practicing at that time and he further stated that the
intelligent and industrious students have great advantages
over those who studied medicine twenty, thirty and forty
years ago. He emphasized that medicine v/as a progressive
science and by the very nature of things must continue to
be progressive. I quote from his address:
If those who studied medicine and commenced
the practice some thirty or forty years since have
not read a great deal, they are far behind in the
^^ Proceedings, April, 1850 , p. 15
^-^ Proceedings, April, 1850 , p. 19
48
profession. Their old musty books have gone out of
print, and out of date. ^
He further counseled.
The advantages, then, to the older and younger
physicians in theii associations are much more
reciprocal than many, upon first view, will allow;
for a while the young are benefited by the counsel,
and practical experience of the old, the latter
in turn receive much that is new and important
from the former. '^
Undoubtedly the meeting in Murfreesboro was a very
stimulating educational experience for the local physicians.
Other physicians in the community became interested in the
work of the Medical Society of Tennessee and joined the
society, among whom were Doctors Benjamin Avent, James
Wendell, Thomas C. Black, J, J. Abernathy, G. W. Burton,
P. D. McCullough, S. H. Woods, L. W. Knight, D. H. Johnson,
J. B. Armstrong, G. M. Alsup, W. A. Smith, L. V. Young.
Many of the physicians were probably stimulated to keep
better records of cases in anticipation of reporting or
publishing papers on their particular cases. Dr. Richard-son
admonished the physicians to keep a diary of
interesting cases to present to their colleagues. Com-municating
interesting cases in Dr. Richardson's mind was
^'^Proceedings, April, 1850, p. 23,
^^Proceedings, April, 1850, p. 24,
49
essential for educational progress. He found medical
associations to be fine opportunities for doctors to
present interesting cases to the profession where they
could be examined, closely criticized and published.
At the 1850 meeting in Murf reesboro. Dr. J. W.
Richardson, Dr. Yandell, Dr. G. W. Burton, Dr. B. W.
Avent, Dr. J. J. Abernathy were all appointed as
delegates from the Tennessee Medical Association to the
next meeting of the American Medical Association which
was to be held in Cincinnati the following May. The
American Medical Association had been formed in 1847; so,
early in the history of the national organization, Ruther-ford
County physicians were active in its proceedings.
In 1851 the state society again met in Murfreesboro
at which other Rutherford County physicians became
members: Doctors Crosthwaite, W. T. Baskette, L. V.
Young, W. A. Smith, E. D. Wheeler, J. M. Watson, S. B.
Robinson. Dr. Richardson was still president of the
society. Dr. Avent presented a paper to the society.
Doctors McCul lough, Crosthwaite, Young, Knight, Thompson,
Smith, and Armstrong all read essays. It was observed
in that meeting that efforts were under way to establish
a medical school in Tennessee and it was indeed in that
year that the Medical Department at the University of
50
Nashville was established. The society adopted the code
of ethics established by the American Medical Association.
That motion was made by Dr. Wendell of Murf reesboro, and
it was unanimously passed. At the 1851 meeting, Dr. J. M.
Watson was elected president for the next two years. He
was a practicing physician in Marf reesboro. Dr. B. W.
Avent of Murfreesboro was elected vice-president. Dr. R. S.
Wendell, recording secretary. Dr. E. D. Wneeler, corre-sponding
secretary, and Dr. J. J. Abarnathy, treasurer.
That year a clean sweep of the officers of the state
society was made by Rutherford County physicians. Doctors
Richardson, Avent, Wheeler, McCullough, Baskette, Wendell,
Robertson, Knight, Smith, Young, and Black of Rutherford
County were appointed to report cases for the next
meeting of 1852 which was also to be held in Murf reesboro. '^"
At the 1851 meeting Dr. Avent read a case of fungus
cerebri to which he appended the notes of the case treated
by Dr. J, W. Richardson. ^^ Dr. McCullough reported a case
of Cupture of the intestines caused by a fall from a horse
^^"Proceedings of the Medical Society of the State of
Tennessee," Nashville Journal of Medicine and Surgery ,
V. 1 (1851), 73.
-"-^B. W. Avent, M. D. , "Fungus Cerebri," Nashville
Journal of Medicine and Surgery , V. 1 (1851), 65.
51
Dr. John M. Watson
President
Tennessee Medical Association
1851- 1853
52
and also a case of traumatic tetanus. Dr. Crosthwaite
reported a case of prolapsus vesicae. Dr. Armstrong
presented to the museum of the society a rare specimen of
lumbrici obtained from the liver of a dog. Dr. Young
read a case of rupture of the uterus on which Dr. Watson
made some remarks. Dr. Knight read a case of acute mania
following an attack of bilious fever which elicited some
remarks from Doctors Baskette and Watson. Dr. Thompson
reported a case of puerperal convulsions. Dr. Smith
reported a case of stricture of the bowels. Dr. Armstrong
reported a case of indigestion accompanied with extreme
emaciation.
The delegates appointed to the next meeting of the
American Medical Association included Dr. B. W. Avent of
Murfreesboro. The society resolved to instruct the dele-gates
to use their best influence to induce the American
Medical Association to urge the Congress of the United
States to appoint a Board of Health for the United States.
The duty of said board should be to publish the analysis of
all secret compounds proposed as remedies together with
the effects which said compounds are calculated to produce
upon the human system in health and disease. It was
further resolved that the delegates be instructed to use
their endeavors to procure from the American Medical
53
Association a memorial to the Congress of the United States
"praying that body not to grant patents for secret
compounds intended to be used as medicines."
The society noted with pleasure, not only the efforts
to organize a medical school in Nashville but also efforts
to start the publication of the Nashville Journal of
Medicine and Surgery on a regular basis. They recognized
the educational value of a journal to the local physicians.
When the Medical Society of Tennessee met in
Murfreesboro on May 5, 1852, the meeting was held in Odd
Fellows Hall and Dr. J. M. Watson of Murfreesboro pre-sided
as president. At that meeting it was resolved that
in the future a rule of the society would be to open for
discussion by the members any paper which was read to the
society, and, after each member had had an opportunity
to speak, the writer of the paper should have the liberty
to close the discussion. This represented an excellent
medium for the exchange of ideas and advancement of educa-tion.
This same format is used at most medical meetings
today. Attending the meeting from Rutherford County were
Doctors W. A. Smith, J. W. Richardson, S. B. Robi son.,
L. W. Knight, B. W. Avent, R. S. Wendell, E. D. Wheeler,
J. J. Abernathy, W. D. Baskette, and J. M. Watson, W. A.
Smith, P. D. McCul lough, and Thomas C. Black.
54
Dr. Medicus Ransom was admitted as a new member.
Dr. Richardson read a case of hour glass contraction
of the uterus. IS Dr. Abernathy read an essay on tetanus. &#8226;'-^
Dr. Avent read a paper on three cases of urinary calculi
with the operation of lithotomy on each. 20 Dr. Robison
reported a case of ovarian inflammation. ^1 Dr. Smith
reported a case of labor attended with laceration of the
perineum. 22 The next meeting of the State Medical Society
was scheduled for Nashville in 1853 and the meeting
adjourned. The meeting was written up in the Nashville
Journal of Medicine and Surgery and was described as
unusually interesting in that a much greater interest was
manifested by the members than from many years past.
They also said that the meeting was more numerously
ISjohn W. Richardson, M. D., "Hour Glass Contraction
of the Uterus," Nashville Journal of Medicine and Surgery ,
V. 3 (1852), 66.
l^J. J. Abernathy, M. D. , "Essay on Tetanus,"
Nashville Journal of Medicine and Surgery , V. 3 (1852), 22,
20
B. W. Avent, M. D., "Three Cases of Stone in the
Bladder," Nashville Journal of Medicine and Surgery ,
V. 3 (1852), 72.
21s. B. Robison, M. D., "Case of Inflammation of
Ovaria," Nashville Journal of Medicine and Surgery , V. 3
(1852), 77.
22w. A. Smith, M. D., "Case of Labor Attended with
Laceration of Perineum," Nashville Journal of Medicine and
Surgery , V. 3 (1852), 65.
55
attended and that the discussions were considerably more
animated. -&#8226;
The Nashville Journal of Medicine and Surgery was in
its second year of publication. It started its first
year the same year the medical school was established. It
should be also noted that Dr. J. M. Watson of Murfreesboro
had been elected as the head of the Department of
Obstetrics at the new medical school.
The Rutherford County Medical Society was organized
in Murfreesboro on June 1, 1852. Undoubtedly this was due
to the stimulation of the three consecutive meetings in
Murfreesboro by the Tennessee State Medical Association
and the very active participation in the State Medical
Society of Rutherford County physicians. Doctors B. W.
Avent, S. B. Robison, J. W. Richardson, Medicus Ransom,
B. H. Bilbro, R. S. Wendell, J. J. Abernathy, W. T.
Baskette, L. W. Knight, T. C. Black, W. C. Martin, R. J.
Powell, G. W. Burke, and H. H. Clayton were the founding
members. Dr. J. W. Richardson was elected president,
Dr. J. E. Wendell, vice-president. Dr. E. D. Wheeler,
recording secretary. Dr. S. B. Robison, corresponding
23"proceedings of the Twenty-third Annual Session of
the Medical Society of Tennessee, held at Murf reesborough,
May, 1852," Nashville Journal of Medicine and Surgery, V. 3
(1852).
56
secretary, and Dr. B. W. Avent , treasurer. The objects of
the society were stated to be "the discussion of the theory
and practice of medicine and the collateral sciences." The
code of ethics, of the recently organized American Medical
Association was adopted. The meetings were held in May
and November of each year. Cases were reported and dis-cussed
and essays read. Many of the essays and case
reports were published in the Nashville Journal of Medicine
and Surgery and in other medical periodicals . ^4
At the November 4, 1852, meeting of the Rutherford
County Medical Society, Dr. William T. Baskette read a
paper on cholera infantum. His treatment of the disease
was the usual emetics, purgatives, and the ubiquitous
calomel. He advised
If there be any evidences of cerebral irrita-tion,
such as delirium, photophobia, heat about
the head, redness of the eyes, etc., a few leeches
should be applied to the temples, or a cup or two
behind the ears, and warm stimulating embrocations
to the extremities. A towel wrung out of cold
water may be applied to the head at the same time.
When there is sufficient subduction of the
arterial excitement, and no abatement of the head
symptoms, the whole head ought to be shaved and a
large blister drawn over it.25
24 Hamer, p. 486.
^^william T. Baskette, M. D., "Cholera Infantum,"
The Southern Journal of the Medical and Physical Sciences ,
V. 1 (1853), 82.
57
Dr. John W. Richardson was invited to give the com-mencement
address to the graduates of the University of
Nashville Medical Department February 24, 1853. He
expounded on the difficulties in the practice of medicine,
the great variety of diseases, the necessity for correct
interpretation of signs and symptoms, the proper choice
of treatment. He discoursed on many areas of problematical
practice.
. . . it requires immense labor. You had better
not engage in the practice of medicine at all if
you do not intend to worship at her altar. You
must study--read--think--observe closely, or the
science will suffer in your hands, and the sick
will suffer more. . . .
Gentlemen--the science of medicine, properly
studied, and the practice of medicine, faithfully
pursued, will give a man more knowledge--do more
to refine his morals and manners, and secure for
him more friends and better friends, than any
other human profession. No other science opens
such a field for reading and reflection, where a
man can do so much good, and make so much character.
Here are cases that challenge the skill of the most
gifted, objects for his charity, subjects for his
benevolence, and every inducement that can be
offered to make a man intelligent, virtuous, and
happy. ^"
When the Tennessee Medical Society met in Nashville on
May 4, 1853, Dr. J. M. Watson presided as president.
26john W. Richardson, M. D., "The Difficulties and
Responsibilities of the Physician," Nashville Journal of
Medicine and Surgery , V. 4 (1853), 129.
58
Doctors Wendel , Ransom, Abernathy, Avent , Wheeler, Knight
were present. Dr. Wheeler offered a tribute to the memory
of Dr. W. A. Smith of Rutherford County who had died since
the last meeting. The resolution was published with the
proceedings of the society and a copy transmitted to the
family of the deceased. ^^ Dr. Medicus Ransom reported a
case of paralysis.^" Dr. John M. Watson's presidential
address to the society was an eloquent review of the
advances in medicine, though perhaps he was a bit complacent
with the state of the art at that time.
. . . the chances of new and valuable discoveries
in the different departments of medicine are far,
very far, greater than in former ages. And though
there are many things which will live and perish
only with the world, yet other important means will
be discovered. The lancet, the leech, the cupping
glass, calomel, quinine, tartar emetic cannot be
superceded. Other medicines may rise and fall, and
be finally dispensed with, but these cannot.
But he did, nevertheless, attempt some visionary projections
into the future.
. . . more attention will, in all probability, here-after
be given to the means of preventing (diseases)
^'^ Transactions of the Tennessee State Medical Society
at their Twenty-Fourth Annual Session, Convened at
Nashville, May 4, 1853 (Nashville: J. F. Morgan, 'l853).
2oM. Ransom, M. D., "Case of Cerebral Disease," The
Southern Journal of the Medical and Physical Sciences ,
V. 1 (1853), 236.
59
than of curing them. . . . Hence we may soon look
out beyond occulists, dentists, lithotomists , for
pneumatologists , gastrologists , hepatologists
,
spermatologists , and, in short, a name and a doctor
for every part of the system, whose case and duty
it shall be to treat the diseases of one particular
organ in .an open, scientific way. 29
The professional and educational stimulus of the
Tennessee Medical Society and the Rutherford County
Medical Society on the physicians of the county was evident.
Many papers were reported and published during the decade of
the 1850s.
Dr. J. 0. Sharber, who practiced in Versailles,
reported a case of fatal uterine hemorrhage in a thirty-five
year old woman. An autopsy was performed and the hemorrhage
found to be the result of erosion of an artery from cancer
of the uterus. ^0
Dr. Taswell S. Smith reported a case of gun shot
wound of the head. Three wounds were noted by Dr. Smith
and treated in consultation with Dr. G. W. Burk. The
wounds were debrided, the integument drawn together and
retained with adhesive strips. A "nervous stimulant" was
administered initially, then one grain of calomel was
^^Transactions, 1853 , pp. 27-28.
^^J. O. Sharber, M. D. , "Death from Exterior Uterine
Hemorrhage," Nashville Jounral of Medicine and Surgery ,
V. 4 (1853), 259.
60
ordered every hour for six hours followed by saline
cathartics. On the second day the calomel doses were
ordered again and pushed to ptyalism, with "the view if
possible to prevent inflammation and promote absorption."
The patient recovered. ^'-
Dr . Medicus Ransom, at that time practicing in the
Salem area, reported two cases of trismus nascentium
(tetanus of the newborn). Such cases were so uniformly
fatal that frequently a doctor was not even called to
attend the infant. Dr. Ransom reported these two cases
because they both recovered. He had used internal
chloroform in the treatment of both cases which helped
relieve the muscle spasms. He also scarified the umbilicus
(almost always the portal of infection entry) and applied
poultices to it. He was impressed with the effects of
chloroform in treatment and encouraged the profession to
try it. 32
3lTaswell S. Smith, M. D., "Case of Sun Shot Wound
of the Brain," Nashville Journal of Medicine and Surgery ,
V. 8 (1855), 495.
32iyi. Ransom, M. D. , "Cases of Trismus Nascentium,"
The Southern Journal of the Medical and Physical Sciences ,
V. 3 (1855), 21.
61
Dr. William T. Baskette reported a case of congenital
absence of the uterus. 33
At the Rutherford County Medical Society meeting in
June, 1856, the society requested Dr. Samuel B. Robison
to take an account of the births, deaths, and marriages
in the county for the preceding year. He was the property
assessor for the county and could, therefore, gather the
medical statistics when assessing the properties. His
report covered the year from May 1, 1855, to May 1, 1856.
He reported to the society at a later meeting. The most
frequent causes of death were phthisis (tuberculosis),
scarlatina, cholera infantum, flux, pneumonia, croup, and
dropsy. The largest number of deaths was from flux, the
second largest from "unknown causes." Other fatal
illnesses included meningitis, tetanus, measles, pleurisy,
child-bed fever, congestive chills, stomatitis, whooping
cough, fits, old age, cancer, fever, and scrofula. He
was impressed with the large incidence of flux and
correlated the disease with the "miasma" emanating from
the water courses. 34
33william T. Baskette, M. D. , "A Case of Absence of the
Uterus in an Adult Female," The Southern Journal of the
Medical and Physical Sciences , V. 3 (1855), 157.
34s, B. Robison, M. D., "Statement of the Births and
Deaths of Rutherford County for One Year," Nashville
Journal of Medicine and Surgery , V. 13 (1857), 2.
62
An interesting case was reported by Dr. Benjamin W.
Avent describing an operation for tumor in which half the
lower jaw was removed. Dr. J. J. Abernathy had originally
removed part of the tumor, but it recurred. At the second
operation. Dr. Avent listed the doctors present who
assisted in the operation: Professor Buchanan (of the
University of Nashville Medical Department), Doctors
Baskette, Clayton, Robison, Wasson, Richardson, Keyes,
and Mr. Buchanan, a medical student. Dr. Baskette admin-istered
cholorform anesthesia. The surgery was described
in some detail. Cautery and ligation were used to control
bleeding. The patient recovered at the end of nine weeks.
I would suggest that the cautery used may have prevented
some of the inevitable post-operative infection . -^^
In 1858 the Rutherford County Medical Society wrote
the editors of the Nashville Journal of Medicine and
Surgery as follows:
RUTHERFORD COUNTY MEDICAL SOCIETY
Murf reesboro. May, 1858
Editors Nashville Medical Journal:
Dear Sirs: At the regular meeting of the
Rutherford County Medical Society, held in this
^^B. W. Avent, M. D. , "Resection, With the Disarticu-lation
of One Half the Inferior Maxilla," Nashville Journal
of Medicine and Surgery , V. 13 (1857), 27.
63
place on yesterday, 6th of May, the following
resolution was unanimously adopted :--
Resolved, That this Society adopt the Nashville
Journal of Medicine and Surgery as its organ, and
that the Editors of that journal be requested to
acknowledge the same, and to publish its proceedings,
with such other matter as the committee may deem
worthy of publication.
The undersigned. Committee of Publication, have
been directed to transmit a copy of the above
resolution to you, and to request your approval.
The Society holds its meeting semi-annually.
Respectfully,
B. W. Avent
T. S. Smith
L. M. Wasson
It certainly was a credit to the doctors in the
Rutherford County Medical Society that the letter was
published in the Nashville Journal of Medicine and Surgery
with an editorial comment which followed the letter:
We have already privately expressed our willing-ness
to publish the proceedings of this Society, and
promise our readers a series of interesting practical
articles from its members, among others, "On Croup,"
"On Intussusception," "On Veratrium Viride," &amp;c,
S(C , &amp;c
.
No city in our State possesses an abler Faculty
than our sister city of Murf reesboro, nor any
county an abler one than Rutherford, which we think,
accounts for the fact of the large number of our
subscribers there. -^^
^^ Nashville Journal of Medicine and Surgery , V. 15
(1858), 86-87,
64
The meeting of the Rutherford County Medical Society
in May, 1858, must have been an all day affair, for
several papers were reported and later published. Dr. H. H,
Clayton reported some cases of trismus nascentium in which
he used topical applications of chloroform. He used three
parts of chloroform and nine of whiskey or diluted
alcohol, sprinkled on a poultice every 20 or 30 minutes
as long as the spasms lasted. The poultice covered the
entire abdomen. 37 qj^ , Avent read a paper on the use of
chloroform in mania. He reported the prompt relief of the
mania state from the inhalation of chloroform. 38 q^ . T. S.
Smith reported three cases of pneumonia treated with
veratrum veride (an alkaloid which reduces blood pressure).
He also used the usual procedures of bleeding, purging,
catharsis, and vomiting. He reasoned that the veratrum
reduced the frequency of the pulse, which was associated
with a lessening of the heat of the skin, thirst and pain,
and induction of free perspiration, all of which, he
37h. H. Clayton, M. D., "The Topical Application of
Chloroform in Trismus Nascentium," Nashville Journal of
Medicine and Surgery , V. 15 (1858).
38 B. W. Avent, M.D., "Chloroform in Mania," Nashville
Journal of Medicine and Surgery , V. 15 (1858), 188.
65
3 Q
assumed, reduced the inflammation. ^ Dr. H. W. Winstead,
of Beech Grove, presented a case of epistaxis (nose bleed)
which was so profuse the patient, a male child of five,
almost exsanguinated. He used cold applications to the
head, face, and back of the neck, gave astringent injections
blew powdered alum into the nostrils, gave lead and opium,
resorted to plugging, all to no avail. The patient was
sinking from the loss of blood when the thought struck
Dr. Winstead that he had heard (whether from a brother of
the profession or some old woman he could not recall) that
bathing the scrotum in cold water would stop hemorrhage of
the nose. He then obtained a cloth wrung out in cold
water, completely enveloped the genitals in the cloth, and
the hemorrhage ceased. Dr. R. S. Wendell reported a
case of fatal intussusception. The diagnosis was made at
autopsy. Dr. L. M. Wasson read a paper on pseudo-membranous
croup. He advised against venesection in this
^^T. S. Smith, M. D., "Veratrum Veride as an Arterial
Sedative," Nashville Journal of Medicine and Surgery ,
V. 15 (1858), 195.
"^Oh. W. Winstead, M. D., "Case of Profuse Epistaxis,"
Nashville Journal of Medicine and Surgery , V. 15 (1858),
358.
^&#8226;'R. S. Wendell, M. D., "Case of Intussusception,"
Nashville Journal of Medicine and Surgery , V. 15 (1858),
193.
66
form of croup and relied chiefly on calomel, tartar emetic,
and nitrate of silver as a local remedy. '^^
Dr. Wasson gave an essay on syphilis at the meeting
of the county . society May 3, 1860.^-^
In 1860, by invitation. Dr. Benjamin W. Avent deliv-ered
the commencement address to the graduating class of
the Medical Department of the University of Nashville.
Dr. Avent was very active in state and county societies,
had written and published several medical papers, and was
generally respected as an outstanding physician of that
day.
The doctors obviously relied much on their mutual
sharing of cases at the medical meetings to arrive at
more successful and efficient means of treating various
disorders. The Rutherford County Medical Society had
regular meetings from its inception in 1852 through 1860.
It should be noted that an attempt at organizing a medical
society in Rutherford County occurred in 1848 and Dr. J. J.
^^L. M. Wasson, M. D., "Pseudo-Membranous Croup,"
Nashville Journal of Medicine and Surgery , V. 15 (1858),
184.
43l. M. Wasson, M. D., "An Essay on Syphilis as a
Cause of Scrofula," Nashville Journal of Medicine and
Surgery , V. 19 (1860), 101.
67
Abernathy was elected its president.'*'^ However, this
effort apparently failed. The records (minutes) of these
early years of the society have been lost.
^^Hamer, p. 136,
68
Area Physicians During the 1850s
J. J. Abernathy
(Murf reesboro
)
C. C. Abernathy
Gideon M. Alsup
(Falls Creek)
J. B. Armstrong
(Cannon County)
Benjamin Ward Avent
(Murf reesboro)
John Baird
(Wilson County)
E. T. Barnett (ca. 1855)
(Millersburg)
Wm. T. Baskette
(Murf reesboro)
Robert Parker Bateman
(Nolensville)
James M. Bell
(Versailles 1855)
John Bella
(Fox Camp)
Berryman H. Bilbro
(Milton)
Samuel P. Black
Thos. C. Black
(Walter Hill)
Robert Blair
(Falls Creek)
Jonathan Bostick
(Triune)
Smith Bowl in
(Bell Buckle)
Alexander B. Buchanan
(La Vergne)
George W. Burk
(Falls Creek)
George W. Burton
Thomas R, Butler
Andrew Jackson Charlton
(La Vergne area 1855)
Ephraim Charlton
(Davidson County)
George Washington Charlton,
(Davidson Co.
)
James Hamilton Charlton
(La Vergne area)
Joseph Charlton
(La Vergne area)
Edwin Childress
(Millersburg)
Wm. J. Clark
(Nolensville)
H. H. Clayton
(Murfreesboro)
George D. Crosthwaite
(Florence)
Joseph W. Davis
(Smyrna--La Vergne)
Preston K. Davis
(Fox Camp)
James H. Dickens
(Readyville)
Edward Donoho
(Milton)
Dabney Ewe 11
(Coffee County)
Lafayette Ezell
(Davidson County)
Uberdwell Ezell
(Fosterville)
Wm. W. Frazar
John Wesley Gaines
(Antioch)
John Gannaway
(Fairfield)
Joseph S, Gentry
(Chapel Hill)
John Claiborne Gooch
( Smyrna
)
James W. Gowan
(Cannon County)
William D. Gowen
(Cannon County)
Thomas Graves
(Marshall County)
Isaac H. Gray
(Nolensvil le
)
Addison P. Grinstead
Sr. (Treppardsville)
Allen Hall
(Fairfield)
69
Area Physicians During the 1850s (continued)
John W. Hall
(Hall's Hill)
Reuben D. Hubbard
(Wilson County)
Wiley Huff
(Barfield)
William M. Hutton
(Middleton)
John H. Ivie
M. H. Jackson
(Versailles
)
Daniel H. Johnson
Clement Jordan
(Triune)
James E. Kendle
(Versailles
)
George Currin Kinnard
(Eagleville area)
John C. Kirkpatrick
(Jefferson)
Lewis W. Knight
(Marfreesboro)
P. G- Leech
(Cannon County)
William H. Lytle
James Maney
(Murfreesboro)
Francis J. Manning
( Fox Camp
)
James Edward Manson
(Blackman)
Robert W. Martin
(Milton)
William C. Martin
Phillip D. McCullough
John L. McKnight
Samuel A. McKnight
Samuel N. McMinn
(Wilson County)
Samuel Caldwell McWhirter
(Milton)
Jennings Moore
(Bedford County)
William N. Moore
John H. Morgan
(Fairfield)
Solomon G. Morton
(Davidson County)
George W. Mullins
(Jefferson)
Abner W. Nelson
Joseph H. Nelson
(La Vergne)
Charles T. New
(Woodbury)
James K. Norton
(Bedford County)
James B. Owen
(Williamson County)
Benjamin H. Paschall
(Williamson County)
D. Pate
(Williamson County)
Alex R. Pinkston
(Triune)
Green L. Poplin
(Bedford County)
Robert C. Price
(Brown's Mill)
Medicus Ransom
(Salem)
John W. Richardson
(Murfreesboro)
John H. Robinson
(Chapel Hill)
George Whitfield Robertson
(Big Spring)
Samuel B. Robison
William R. Rucker
Absalom W. Scales
(Triune)
James Turner Scales
(Triune)
J. W. Scales
(Triune)
Mark Hardin Scales
(Marshall County)
James Searcy
(Beech Grove)
J. Sharber
(Versailles)
70
Area Physicians During the 1850s (continued)
Jason B. Sheffield
(Marshall County)
D. Shegog
(Nolensville)
Walter Sims
(Wartrace
)
Robert L. Singleton
(Fairfield)
Wm. A. Smith
Stephen Spain
John W. Steele
William D. Stone
(Bedford County)
George W. Thompson
(Jefferson)
Nimrod Whitefield Thompson
Samuel Wade
L. M. Wasson
John M. Watson
(Murf reesboro)
Sam Webb
(Williamson County)
James E. Wendel
(Murfreesboro)
Robert S. Wendel
(Murf reesboro)
E. D, Wheeler
Augustus H. White
William H. Wilson
John A. Wood
(Cannon County)
Stephen Henry Woods
William C. Work
( Fosterville
)
Hillary H. Yeargan
(Barfield)
John S. Young
(Davidson County)
Lewis V. Young
(Fosterville)
CHAPTER III
THE STATE OF THE MEDICAL ART 1860-1920
During the first half of the nineteenth century, there
had been rapid progress in physiology, in pathology, in
histology and the sum of the progress led to a new clinical
medicine which was the beginning of medicine of the present
day. With the advent of knowledge in the basic sciences,
the laboratory became an essential tool of discovery and
instruction. Germany played a leading role in the new
development since it was only in Germany that there had
grown-up a large body of full time scientists. There were
professional physiologists and professional institutes of
physiology in Germany.
Such professional and professional institutes were
poised to create new vistas in the future of medicine.
These researchers were rejecting the vain speculation,
theorizing and dogmatism of the past. Their researches
were demonstrating that diseases and disorders of human
function were a logical progression of a pathological
process. The new emphasis, then, was on pathological
physiology rather than a purely anatomical approach. The
efforts in the area of pathological physiology created an
era of laboratory medicine. Researchers began concen-trating
on specific areas of medical science such as the
71
72
study of liver disease, experimentally investigating
pneumonia and kidney and heart diseases. A systematic
study of temperature change in disease was developed by
Carl Wunderlich in the 1860s. This study was one of
pathological physiology at its best. There were many
other specific studies on other disease states such as
diabetes, the mobility, secretion, and digestive abilities
of the stomach, the secretions of the glands, the heart in
various diseased states. Mickowski made the decisive
experiment in 1889 which proved that diabetes was due to
pancreatic disease. Much research was proceeding in
neurology. Laboratory studies were being developed such
as tests for blood urea, blood biliruben, blood sugar. The
use of such laboratory studies in physiology, experimental
pathology, and pharmacology certainly had a great contri-bution
to the increase of clinical knowledge, especially
diagnostic ability. The results, however, were gradual
rather than dramatic.
Even though all of this research was opening new doors
and creating new light and was certainly provoking the
enthusiasm of scientifically minded physicians, it still
did not kindle the imagination of the average practitioner
and the layman. To them, it was not improving their
knowledge as to the cause of disease and their experience
73
in the treatment of disease; so far the pragmatist,
something of immediate usefulness was desperately needed.
That dramatic event occurred with the discovery that
infectious diseases are caused by microorganisms . '
It was in August 1857 that Pasteur sent his famous
paper on lactic acid fermentation to the Lille Scientific
Society and in December of the same year, he presented to
the Academy of Sciences, a paper on alcoholic fermentation
in which he concluded that the conversion of sugar into
alcohol and carbonic acid is correlavent to a phenomenon
of life.
2
Pasteur was early impressed with the analogies
between fermentation and putrefaction in the
infectious diseases, and, in 1863 he assured the
French emperor that his ambition was "to arrive
at the knowledge of the causes of putrid and
contagious diseases."^
The microscope had revealed a new world. The analogy
between disease and fermentation urged the suggestion:
what would be most desirable would be to push these studies
^Erwin H. Ackernecht, M. D. , A Short History of
Medicine (Baltimore, Md.: Johns Hopkins University Press,
1982), pp. 170-174.
^Rene Vallery-Radot , The Life of Pasteur (New York:
Doubleday, Page &amp; Company, 1924), p. vii.
^Vallery-Radot, p. ix.
74
far enough to prepare the road for a serious research into
the origin of various diseases. If the tiny living
organisms can produce changes in lactic and alcohol
fermentation, why should not the same tiny creatures make
the changes which occur in the body in the putrid and
suppurative diseases.
The first outcome of the researches of Pasteur upon
fermentation and spontaneous generation represented a trans-formation
in the practice of surgery which has probably
been one of the greatest boons ever conferred upon
humanity. It had long been recognized that occasionally a
wound would heal without the formation of pus but almost
invariably both spontaneous and operative wounds were
associated with the development of pus, frequently becoming
putrid, which we now term an infected wound. With the
infection the general system became involved and the
patient frequently died of blood poisoning. This was so
common, particularly in the old ill-equipped hospitals, in
the absence of knowledge of sepsis, that many surgeons
feared to operate.^ The general mortality in all surgical
'*Sir William Osier, Bart., M. D. , F. R. S., The
Evolution of Modern Medicine (New Haven, Conn.: Yale
University Press, 1929), pp. 208-209.
^Osler, p. 212.
75
cases was extremely high. A Young surgeon in Glasgow,
Dr. Joseph Lister, recognized the value of Pasteur's
experiments. Lister had done researches on inflammation
and had been led to suspect that putrefaction was the
cause of infection of wounds and that the primary cause
was not merely the gases of the air but something carried
by the air. Pasteur's work came as a revelation, and he
deduced that infection in wounds must be analogous to
putrefaction in wine. Lister then sought for means of
destroying the organism. He selected carbolic acid as a
disinfectant, using the antiseptic on wounds, dressings
and most especially washing hands in antiseptic solution
prior to surgery. Later, he developed a carbolic acid
spray to be used in the operating area. At first it
worked by hand, then by a pump and later by a steam
apparatus. He first used his antiseptic system in 1865
in a case of compound fracture of the leg. He published
his results in 1867, describing eleven cases, nine recov-eries
of life and limb, one amputation, and one death.
This was a milestone in the history of surgery. He laid
the foundation for aseptic surgery. At his death in 1912
^Douglas Guthrie, M. D., F. R. C. S. Ed., F. R. S. E.,
A History of Medicine (Philadelphia, Pa.: J. B. Lippincott
Company, 1946), pp. 323-325.
76
a eulogy appeared in the Royal College of Surgeons Report:
His gentle nature, imperturbable temper,
resolute will, indifference to ridicule, and
tolerance to hostile criticism combined to make
him one of the noblest of men. His work will last
for all time; humanity will bless him evermore and
his fame will be immortal.'
Inseparably linked with Pasteur in the creation of the
science of bacteriology is the work of Robert Koch. Koch's
first great discovery was his discovery of the anthrax
bacillus. Koch further developed media to culture bacteria
and new methods of fixing and staining bacteria that they
may be studied and identified under the microscope. These
great improvements in technique enabled Koch in 1879 to
identify the bacteria causing wound infection. He was
every inch a pure scientist. He developed scientific
postulates on the genesis of contagion. These postulates
were ( 1 ) the organism should be found in each case of the
disease, (2) it should not be found in other diseases,
(3) it should be isolated, (4) it should be cultured,
(5) it should, when inoculated, produce the same disease,
and (6) it should be recovered from the inoculated animal.
With the pioneering work of Pasteur, followed by Koch,
growth of the field of bacteriology exploded. The advances
in the 1870s and 1880s were breath-taking. A partial list
^Guthrie, p. 327.
77
of diseases whose causative agents were discovered during
the last decades of the nineteenth century and beginning
twentieth century illustrates the rapid rate of progress:
1875 Amoebic Dysentery (Loesch)
1879 Gonorrhea (Neisser)
1880 Typhoid Fever (Eberth, Gaffky)
Leprosy (Hansen)
Malaria (Laveran)
1882 Tuberculosis (Koch)
Glanders (Loeffler)
1883 Erysipelas (Fehleisen)
Cholera (Koch)
1884 Diphtheria (Klebs, Loeffler)
Tetanus (Nikolaier, Kitasato)
Pneumonia (Fraenkel)
1887 Epidemic Meningitis ( Weichselbaum)
Malta Fever (Bruce)
1892 Gas Gangrene (Welch)
1894 Plague (Yersin, Kitasato)
Botulism (van Ermengem)
1898 Bacillary Dysentery (Shiga)
1905 Syphilis (Schaudinn)
1906 Whooping Cough (Bordet)^
^Ackernecht, pp. 178-180
78
In the 1890s, it was realized by investigators,
especially Loeffler and Roux, that a number of diseases
were caused by organisms so small that they would pass
through the filters which would retain bacteria. The
filterable organisms were referred to by the investigators
as viruses. They were so small they could not be seen
under the ordinary microscope. A third group of organisms
occupying a position between the virus and the bacteria
was identified in the twentieth century and called
rickettsia.
^
With the advent of the research in the field of
bacteriology, means of prevention of the diseases caused
by the bacteria was of pressing importance. Research
efforts were directed toward this, giving rise to the
new fields of serology and immunology. In 1890 Behring
developed an effective diphtheria antitoxin which when
injected neutralized the toxin elaborated by the diphtheria
organism. Behring was the first to open the door to the
field of serum therapy, and his discovery considerably
reduced the mortality from one of the most murderous
children's diseases. ^^ In 1885 Pasteur devised a rabies
vaccine
.
^Ackernecht, pp. 180-181
lOAckernecht, p. 181.
79
Although the new knowledge in bacteriology produced
enormous strides in medicine there was still no effective
means of preventing many epidemics and the mechanism of
contagion in these epidemics continued to be a mystery
until the demonstration of the part played by vectors or
intermediaries in the transmission of disease. It was
learned that human carriers were possible. It was also
recognized that animals could be carriers of parasitic
organisms and insects were also recognized as vectors.
Human carriers were recognized as being largely responsible
for the spread of diphtheria, cholera, meningitis, typhoid
fever, polimyelitis , and dysentery. It was known that
dogs carried rabies and certain worms. It was recognized
that the fly very often transported an infectious organism
from excrement to food. In 1897 Sir Ronald Ross discov-ered
that the malaria parasite was carried by the mosquito.
In 1897 Simond and Ogata showed that fleas carried plaaue.
In 1901 Walter Reed, Carroll, and Lazear demonstrated that
yellow fever was carried by the mosquito. In 1909
Charles Nicolle showed that typhus was transmitted by lice
which also carried trench fever and relapsing fever. The
discovery of the carrier opened the way for prevention of
&#8226;
contagious diseases.
80
Such strides in the field of microbiology were
responsible for the replacement of the symptomatic and
empirical treatment of the early nineteenth century by
the new causal treatment and prevention. For the first
time, answers could finally be given to the question,
"What causes disease." The whole of medicine was
transformed. The field of public health mushroomed and
surgery was undergoing a complete rejuvenation.^^
With the advent of the germ theory and recognition
of the need for aseptic conditions, coupled with the
availability of anesthesia and medication for pain, the
surgeon's field rapidly progressed. Halstead introduced
the rubber glove and they were used for the first time
in surgery at JohnsHopkins Hospital in Baltimore, 1890.
With the advent of asepsis, the surgeons could now enter
the body cavities without the dreadful fear of certain
death due to infection. The period of appendectomy was
opened in 1885. Cholecystectomy was undertaken by J. M.
Sims in 1878. Repair of hernias, esophagus and stomach
operations, joints, vetebral column, head, previously
areas never to be invaded were now accessible to the
surgeon. The list goes on and on and the techniques were
l^Ackernecht, pp. 182-184.
81
rapidly improved. The procedure of using steam to
sterilize surgical instruments was developed in 1886 by
von Bergmann.
A new era was born. The new era, born of micro-biology,
initiated the rise of preventive medicine.
Sir William Osier once called the modern period
the age of preventative medicine. The truth of this
statement is obvious once it is realized that the
great accomplishment of modern medicine--the
dramatically increased life expectancy in Western
countries from forty years in 1850 to seventy years
in 1950&#8212;is due much more to preventive than to
curative medicine. Miraculous and admirable as the
new antibiotics, for instance, may be, they have
never saved nearly as many lives as the rather
prosaic procedure of pasteurizing milk.^^
Certainly the advances in bacteriology emphasize the
necessity for individual hygiene and public hygiene. Snow
had already shown that cholera was a water borne disease.
Budd had also shown that typhoid was a water borne disease
and these demonstrations were prebacteriological ; so the
sanitary movement had already begun prior to so many
discoveries in bacteriology. But bacteriology led to
unprecedented advances in preventive medicine.
Direct attack against certain diseases could
now replace haphazard measures. The incidence of
typhoid fever and dyphtheria could be rapidly
reduced through control of the water and milk
supplies, through control of carriers, and through
^^Ackernecht , p. 210
82
immunization. After the identification of the
mosquito as the carrier of yellow fever, William
Crawford Gorgas, was able to carry out his spec-tacularly
successful campaigns against yellow fever
in Cuba and Panama, which won him world fame.
Parallel discoveries made possible the effective
control of malaria. The first great campaigns
against malaria were directed by Sr. Ronald Ross,
the discoverer of the transmission of malaria by
mosquitoes. Gorgas, too, played his part in malaria
control. As a whole the fight against water-borne
diseases has been more successful than that against
air-borne diseases .
&#8226;'-'
Improvements in sewage disposal, pure water supplies,
attention to personal hygiene and hygienic preparation and
storage of foods received increasing attention.
The formal education of doctors, however, was lagging
behind the brilliant discoveries in science. The American
Medical Association had been founded in 1847 and was
constantly pushing toward improvement of medical education.
It fought to establish a code of medical ethics, promoted
health measures, and generally sought to improve the
professional status of physicians. The developments in
medicine itself was the largest force demanding reforms
and improvements in medical education. The first medical
school to lead the reform movement was associated with Lind
University in Chicago (presently Northwestern University).
In 1859 Lind raised its entrance requirements and
l^Ackernecht , p. 214
lengthened its academic year to five months. The school
received no support in its fight to raise educational
standards until 1871 when Harvard instituted a three year
graded course, a nine month academic year, and written and
oral examinations. Within a few years, Pennsylvania,
Syracuse and Michigan swung into line.
Then, in 1893, the Johns Hopkins University School of
Medicine was established. A remarkable faculty was
assembled there including William H. Welch, William Osier,
William S. Halstead and other outstanding professors.
This university drastically reshaped American medical
education and set a pattern which persists today. From
its inception Hopkins required a college degree as a
prerequisite for admission, provided a four year graded
curriculum, made extensive use of laboratories for
teaching purposes, and integrated the hospital and college
facilities to provide clinical training to advanced
students. The institution flourished, and, within a few
years, its students and professors were carrying the
Hopkins' system to all parts of the United States.
The Carnegie Foundation employed Abraham Flexner, a
man who had studied American higher education, to survey
the field of medical education. Flexner 's report was a
damning indictment of medical education. In 1904 the AMA
84
created a permanent committee on education which two years
later became the AMA council on medical education. The
council had begun to classify schools on an A, B, C basis,
evaluations which played a role in standardizing medical
education. The Carnegie Foundation brought foundation
money to the better schools, and, by improving them,
forced the weaker schools out of business. ^^
Another outstanding discovery at the end of the
nineteenth century was X-rays by Dr. Wilhelm Roentgen. The
field of radiology was thus born. Originally the X-rays
were applied only in the diagnosis of fractures and of
foreign bodies but soon the scope of X-ray examination
was extended.
The intravenous infusion of physiological salt solu-tion
came into use in the 1890s as a result of the
effective sterilization of needles, tubing and solution.
This immediately had a dramatic effect on the mortality of
the various dysenteries which had been attended by severe
dehydration.
The need for blood transfusions had been recognized
for years but also was recognized as being unsafe. It was
^^Albert S. Lyons, M. D. , F. A. C. S., and R. Joseph
Petrucelli, II, M. D. , Medicine An Illustrated History
(New York, N.Y. : Harry N. Abrams , Inc., Publishers, 1978),
pp. 534-537.
85
not until 1901 when Landsteiner of Vienna discovered three
main blood groups. A fourth group was discovered by
DeCastello and Sturli in 1902. Then in 1909 Jansky of
Prague defined and designated by letters the four main
blood groups that we recognize today; A, B, AB, and 0.
Landsteiner ' s discovery of the blood groups solved the
riddle of why some transfusions were successful while
others were fatal . It now became apparent that to avoid
such reactions, it was necessary to transfuse an individual
with blood that matched his own blood group. Blood trans-fusions
were used extensively for the treatment of the
wounded in World War I but it was not until the latter part
of the war that the citrate method of anticoagulation was
sufficiently developed and standardized. Prior to using
citrate in blood, a common problem was the coagulation of
blood in the tubing or in the needle. With citrated blood
the blood could be stored in bottles and administered when
necessary. The introduction of intravenous fluids and
blood for transfusion was a giant step forward in the
treatment of various medical and surgical problems.
By 1920, the avenue of approach to modern medicine
was being well paved. The elaboration of the germ theory,
the development of aseptic surgery, the rise of preventive
medicine and development of antitoxin, the development of
86
intravenous fluids and availability of blood transfusions,
as well as the advancement in the quality of medical
education formed the foundation for the enormous strides
witnessed in the twentieth century.
CHAPTER IV
MEDICAL PRACTICE IN RUTHERFORD COUNTY 1860-1920
The Medical Society of Tennessee met in Murfreesboro
in 1861. Benjamin Ward Avent was elected its president
but he had little opportunity to preside over the society
for the storm clouds of war were gathering. After forty
years of increasing bitterness and misunderstanding between
the North and the South a division seemed inevitable. A
movement for secession of the southern states began in
1860, and in December of that year the first southern state,
South Carolina, seceded. In February, 1861, the Confederate
States of America was formed but there were only seven
states as members at that time. Tennessee showed little
enthusiasm for South Carolina's position and remained loyal
to the union as evidenced by her vote for the constitu-tional
candidate, John Bell, in 1860, instead of the pro-slavery
candidate, Breckenridge. Rutherford County also
cast its vote for Bell. Furthermore, Tennessee did not
believe that the election of Lincoln was sufficient ground
for secession, and took the lead in trying to effect a
compromise. In January, 1861, the Legislature submitted
the question of secession to the people and the people voted
against secession, but the firing on Fort Sumter changed
the situation. On May 6, 1861, the Legislature passed an
act to organize and equip a provisional force. On the same
87
Dr. Benjamin W. Avent
President
Tennessee Medical Association
1861-1863
and
1877-1878
89
day, it voted to resubmit the question of secession to the
people. This time the state voted for secession by over a
two to one margin. There was an overwhelming vote for
secession in Rutherford County.-'- Fort Sumter made war
inevitable and President Lincoln's call for troops revealed
that war was to be carried into the South. In June
Tennessee formally withdrew from the Union and was the last
state to secede. Dr. Avent was appointed by Governor
Harris as the Surgeon General of the Provisional Army of
Tennessee, and he continued in that position until
Tennessee's army was turned over to the Confederacy .2
An unheralded but vital contribution to the
Provisional Army of Tennessee was the establishment
of the Medical Board of Tennessee and the office of
Surgeon General by Governor Harris. This department
was considered to be one of the best in the
South. Under the vigorous leadership of Surgeon
General B. W. Avent, a solid medical department was
founded. A tireless worker, Avent assigned surgeons
to each state regiment and established central
hospitals throughout Tennessee.
^
^Carlton C. Sims, Editor, A History of Rutherford
County (Murfreesboro, TN. : Reprinted by Rutherford County
Historical Society, 1981), pp. 41-42.
^Phillip M. Hamer, Editor, The Centennial History of
the Tennessee State Medical Association 1830-1930
(Nashville, TN: Tennessee State Medical Association,
1930), p. 137.
^Harris D. Riley, Jr. and Amos Christie, "Deaths and
Disabilities in the Provisional Army of Tennessee,"
Tennessee Historical Quarterly , V. 43 (1984), 149-150.
90
War fever was spreading in the area. A citizen of
Murfreesboro wired Nashville: "All excited and aroused.
All united. Secession flag waves over us. All for war."^
April 16, .1861 (Beech Grove)
This has been quite a cold day. The ground is
completely saturated with water. Crops will be late.
The war has begun. Fort Sumter was taken last
Saturday and Major Anderson was taken prisoner.
There is a general belief that a general war will
ensue between the sections. Blood has flowed and
the cry is becoming universal--Give us liberty or
give us death! The South has our sympathy and when
she falls we will be found within the ruins and
rubbish of that, our proud fabric of human liberty.^
Rutherford County is said to have furnished more men to
the cause of the Confederacy than any other county in the
state in proportion to its population. She furnished
infantrymen to twenty different regiments and cavalrymen
to more than a dozen regiments.^ The physicians also
rushed to the aid of the Confederacy. Thirty-one physicians
in the area provided their professional services to the
Confederacy. Nine other individuals fought for the Con-federacy
who became physicians after the war. Approximately
one-fourth of the physicians in the area were commissioned
into the Confederate Army.
^Sims, p. 42.
^William M. Hoover, M. D. , diary entry.
^Sims, p. 94.
91
Area Physicians Serving in Civil War
C. C. Abernathy
Surgeon
B. W. Avent
Surgeon-General
Prov. Army Tenn.
(Murf reesboro
)
Thomas J. Bennett
Samuel P. Black
Ass't. Surgeon
James N. Bridges
H. H. Clayton
Surgeon
(Murf reesboro)
Robert W. Couch
Surgeon
(Wartrace)
John James Covington
(College Grove)
Benjamin F. Duggan
Surgeon
( Unionville)
John N. Dykes
Surgeon
Thomas J. Elam
Surgeon
Watson M. Gentry
Surgeon
(College Grove)
Nathaniel Gooch
James W. Gowen
Surgeon
( Auburntown)
G. W. Harris
Surgeon
(Walter Hill)
Robert B. Harris
Surgeon
Henry M. Hearn
(Woodbury
)
William M. Hoover
Surgeon
(Beech Grove)
Robert N. Knox
Amasa W. Manire
Ass't. Surgeon
(Eagleville)
Pleasant H. McBride
(Beech Grove)
William H. McCord
Surgeon
Lyman B. McCrary
Surgeon
(Woodbury)
Thomas C. McCrary
Ass't. Surgeon
(Bell Buckle)
Allen p; McCul lough
(Milton)
Armstrong E. McKnight
Surgeon
(Porterfield)
James B. Murfree
Surgeon
(Murf reesboro)
Robert Owen
(College Grove)
John Patterson
Surgeon
George W. Robinson
Surgeon
(Big Spring)
Leonard N. Sanders
Ass't Surgeon
(Smyrna)
Samuel W. Scales
Surgeon
(Triune)
Ephraim A. Speer
Ass't Surgeon
(Readyville)
John W. Steele
Surgeon
(Deason)
Robert F. Tatum
Surgeon
(Woodbury)
H. Joseph Warmuth
Ass't. Surgeon
( Smyrna
)
Robert S. Wendel
Surgeon
(Murfreesboro)
92
Area Physicians Serving in Civil War (continued)
B. N. White
William Whitson
Surgeon
(Fosterville)
Thomas W. Wood
(Woodbury)
Studied medicine after the war.
93
Governor Harris offered the Provisional Army of
Tennessee to Jefferson Davis on July 2, 1861, but the
transfer of the state army to the Confederacy did not
begin until July 31. Confederate officers had to travel
to each camp and outpost of the state troops to muster the
men into Confederate service. When the Provisional Army
of Tennessee was transferred to Confederate service, it
boasted twenty-four regiments, ten artillary batteries, an
engineer corps, quarter-master corps, a medical department,
and an ordnance bureau. '^ After Tennessee's army was turned
over to the Confederacy, Dr. Avent served as a surgeon in
the Confederate Army and he served successively as medical
director of the army corps of General A. S. Johnston and of
General Breckenridge.
&#176;
No area of Tennessee and probably no equal area
of the entire South can point to as many finger-prints
of the war as can Rutherford County. War came
time and time again, and not only to the doors, but
to the very firesides and dining tables of Rutherford
County families. The section west and northwest
of Murfreesboro bore the brunt of the burden,
though no area escaped the ravages of war.
Geographically, Rutherford County is in the
exact center of the state. For that reason, Murfrees-boro
and the surrounding county afforded a strategic
position in the control of the state. Moreover,
good roads radiated in every direction from the town,
and the Nashville and Chattanooga Railroad, a most
"^Riley, p. 138.
^Hamer, p. 137.
94
vital artery, bisected the county. The eyes of both
armies were upon Rutherford County. During the late
summer and fall of 1862, the 'Confederate Army hoped
to hold the county, and even in the early winter of
that year when Jefferson Davis, Commander-in-Chief
of the Confederate Army, visited the army at
Murfreesboro, the prospects for the reorganized and
heavily reinforced Confederate Army of Tennessee
looked rather good. General Braxton Bragg was in
charge of this army. This was the army that was to
fight the three-day Battle of Stones River against
the Union Army of General Rosecrans.^
With the fall of Fort Henry and Fort Donelson,
Nashville became vulnerable and was occupied by the Union
Army. When the Confederates withdrew from the Murfreesboro
area, the Union forces occupied Murfreesboro in the spring
of 1862. General Forrest's daring raid in July of 1862
brought Murfreesboro again into Confederate hands, but the
Union Army was still massed in the Nashville area, and in
December, 1862, began to move south toward Murfreesboro,
setting the stage for the Battle of Stones River. The
battle began December 31, 1862.
Provost Marshall John Fitch wrote what he saw
among the hosts of Union wounded: "Those who
witnessed surgical operations at the noted brick
house hospital will never forget those scenes.
They were the headquarters for cases requiring
amputation; and, at times, three tables were thus
in requisition. Human limbs and pieces of flesh
^Sims, p. 89.
95
ca</dc:description>
<dc:description>This publication presents a detailed overview of the history of the medical practice in Rutherford County</dc:description>
<dc:description>State of the Medical Art 1803-1860 -- Medical Practice in Rutherford County 1803-1860 -- The State of the Medical Art 1860-1920 -- Medical Practice in Rutherford County 1860-1920 -- State of the Medical Art 1920-1980 -- Medical Practice in Rutherford County 1920-1980 -- Black Professional Presence in Rutherford County -- Contemporary Medical Practice in Rutherford County</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.); Rutherford County Historical Society; Medicine--Tennessee--History</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Doctors; Medical Art</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Periodical</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>328 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-01</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication24ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/85</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>