<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Dedication to Dr. Homer Pittard</dc:title>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 19</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1982</dc:date>
<dc:description>DS)ICATION
to
Dr. Homer Pittard
When Shakespeare had Malvolia challenge Fabian In Twelfth Night to
be what he willed to be a pattern was set for all those who achieve great-ness
through courageous determination. Dr. Homer Pittard is a notable
example of Rutherford countains trtio were neither bom great or had great-ness
thrust vpon them - - but achieve greatness through intellectual
ability and prodigious labor.
This remarkably gentle man of gigantic frame may be best remembered
for his contributions to the painstaking pursuit of historic minutiae
in education and religion. These activities^ along with the organization
of the Rutherford County Historical Society in November 1971, his decade
of work as County Historian, a member of the Rutherford County Historical
Ccamnission, an ardent developer of Canncnsburg, his authorship of two books
and numerous publications, make the dedication of this volume of RCHS
Publications percularily fitting and apt.
From the relatively obscure Trimble Community in northeast Rutherford
County emerged this versatile individual who was to have such marked
irecognition as an educator, historian, author, lay religioiis leader and
community servant. He came to know and be known by his conten^raries
In each of these areas. It was fittingly said he was "qualitatively in-volved
in so much."
As an educator, Hcmier first gained reputation for his ability to
S3-02201
combine stem discipline with a synqpathetlc comprehenaion of the children
of the McFadden Commmlty. As principal of the Murfreesboro Central High
School he Introduced such sound administration and perception for growth
requirements that Central's athletic prowess and academic excellence became
regionally recognized.
While at Central he foxBnd opportunity at nights, on weekends and in
the summer to coiq&gt;lete his Doctor of Philosophy at Peabody College with
unusual distinction.
In 1955 &#187; twenty years after ejdilbltlng the paradoxical abili-tgr to
both captain the undefeated football team and edit the Mldlander&#187; Dr.
Plttard returned to his Alma Mater to teach.
Dr. Plttard 's numerous contributions to the enhancement of Middle
Tennessee State Ibilverslty were most notable in the department of Edu-cation
and later when he served as alumni and campus relations director.
He organized MTSU alunnl clubs from Miami to Washington, D.C. He was
promoter of the MTSU Foundation, counselor of the Midlander, editor of
the MIDSTATER and author of Fifty Golden Years , the story of the first
half centoiy of the school. He was a representative on the Southern
Association of Schools and served as chairman of many Association
evaluating committees.
HLs dedication to Christian living and his First Baptist Church
affiliation offered opportunity to serve as deacon, teacher and Svnday
School si?&gt;erlntendent. TYm Pillar and Ground was a lofty labor of love
depicting with historical candor the story of his congregation.
As a chairman of the Rutherford County School Board, as past president
of the Murfreesboro Rotary Club, trustee of the Sam Davis Home, and work
with the Oaklands Mansion Men's Board he g&#171;ve generously of his forcefol
personality to build the comounlty.
The college romance of Homer Flttard and Mable Baxter of Laurence-burg
culminated in a beautiful and lasting marriage* To their son, John,
a member of the M\irfreesboro City Council, and their dau^ter, lam, they
transmit a challenging heritage.
Dr. Hcxner Pittard was a modest, sensitive, coiiq)a88ionate man. In
his varied writings he disdained hyperbole while demonstrating and enter-taining,
acctxrate and informative slyle.
A man of steadfast dl^iily, tireless devotion, unusual talent he
was a dell^tful conversationalist, a trusted advisor and confidant.
Certainly the passing of this one dlMidLshes us all.
In recogni2dng his acc(&#187;ipllshiQants as a historian. In education,
religion and as public servant the Rutherford Coxnty Historical Society
dedicates this Publication No. 19 to his memoxy.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Describes the contributions of Dr. Homer Pittard to Murfreesboro, Rutherford County and the RCHS, while mentioning some of the events of his personal and professional life</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Pittard, Homer; dedications</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>3 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-08</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication19ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/169</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>