<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Dr. Murfree meets Champ Ferguson</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Pittard, Homer</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 2</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1973</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>15
DR. MURFREE MEETS CHAMP FERGUSON
Dr. James B. Murfree, a Murfreesboro native, experienced two
significant brushes with history: the first was a pleasing experi-ence
associted with family preeminence, and the second, startling,
if not critically dangerous. In the first place, Dr. Murfree'
s
uncle. Colonel Hardy Murfree, became the town's namesake. Dr.
Murfree, son of Matthias Murfree, was born in Rutherford County in
1835, attended Union University, briefly engaged in the mercantile
business, and later attended the medical department at the University
of Nashville, and still later received his medical degree from
the Jefferson Medical College in Philadelphia in 1859. His home-town
practice was cut short by the outbreak of the war two years
later. He enlisted in Company F, First Tennessee Infantry, and
served as private until June and then was appointed surgeon. In
September he was elevated to assistant surgeon of the Confederate
Army. It was during his assignment at the hospital in Emory,
Virginia, in the fall of 1864, that he was confronted by the
Tennessee Confederate bushwhacker. Champ Ferguson. Ferguson's
reputation as a killer or executioner of Blue Coats had spread far
from his White County home. By his own estimate he had murdered
over one hundred mostly by a knife plunge through the heart followed
by a coup de grace shot through the back of the head. His reasoning
for the bloody rampage is not clear. Wrongs, real or imagined,
committed by Union soldiers on his family may have been a motive
force. His mountaineer instinct of total war, with no quarter
16
asked for or given , may have been another. Whatever it was, he
played his role well, so well he was a high priority for Union
search parties roaming the mountains and late battlefields.
Champ Ferguson's unexpected visit to the Emory hospital,
with some compatriots, was a planned mission and in line with his
sworn oath to eliminate every Blue Coat that strength and resource-fulness
would allow him.
Years later, in Murfreesboro where he was a well-known and
respected physician. Dr. Murfree sat down and wrote an account of
the Emory incident as he remembered it. This was his story:
During the year 1864 and the early part of 1865
I was stationed at Emory, Virginia, as the Surgeon in
charge of the Confederate Hospital located at that
place.
In the fall of 1864 a large force of Federal
calvary from Kentucky under command of General Stoneman
made a raid through Southwestern Virginia for the
purpose of destroying the railroad between Bristol and
Lynchburg. They were met by Morgan's command and a
fierce and bloody battle was fought near Max Meadow in
which the Federals were defeated and driven back into
Kentucky, A large number of Federals were taken prisoners,
many of them being wounded, some very badly.
The wounded were sent to the General Hospital at
Emory and Henry College, of these there were 150 or 200
Federal prisoners. The Hospital was on the railroad,
nine miles from Abingdon, beautifully located and in
a fine section of country. The college buildings were
large and commodious and were occupied by the Confed-erates
as a hospital, containing 350 beds and was under
my care as the surgeon in charge. The Federal wounded
were placed on the third and fourth floors of the main
building which could be only reached by two stairways,
one at either end of the building. In order to prevent
the escape of any of the Federal prisoners guards were
placed at the foot of each of the stairways.
On a cold and bleak Saturday in November, 1864,
Champ Ferguson with twelve or fifteen of his men, quietly
rode up to the hospital, dismounted, hitched their horses
and entered the hospital almost unnoticed. They attempted
to ascend one of the stairways to the ward on the third
floor where Lieutenant Smith, a wounded Federal prisoner,
was confined.
17
The guard halted them and told them that they
could not go up those steps (this guard was an
Irishman and as brave as Julius Caesar) . Champ
Ferguson followed by his men advanced on the guard
swearing that they would go up the steps in spite
of him. But the guard undaunted by their threats,
raised his gun and leveling it at Champ Ferguson
coolly yet firmly told him that he would shoot him
if he came any farther.
Unable to scare this guard they left him and
went to the other stairway where they overpowered
the guard stationed there and ascended the stairs
to the ward where Smith was in bed suffering with a
severe wound. Champ Ferguson went directly to Smith,
sat down on his bed, and patting his gun with his
hand said, "Smith, do you see this? Well, I'm going
to kill you," and without another word placed the
gun at Smith's head, fired, sending a minnie ball
through Smith's head instantly killing him.
I was busily engaged in the office of the
hospital when a nurse came rushing in saying a lot
of soldiers had killed a man in the hospital. I
immediately went to the hospital followed by Major
Stringfield of the Army of Virginia (who was visiting
in that neighborhood) . On reaching the hospital we
rapidly ascended the steps to the second floor where
we were halted by one of Ferguson's men with a drawn
revolver. I promptly told him to go down the stairs,
to which he replied that "Captain Ferguson had ordered
me to let no one pass up the steps." I pushed by him
going on up the steps while Major Stringfield remained
behind contending with the guard. On the next flight
of steps I met Champ Ferguson and his men, and I said
to them, "Gentlemen, you must go down from here, this
is a place for the sick and wounded, and you must not
disturb them," to which Champ Ferguson said with an
oath, "I will shoot you." Standing within a few feet
of each other I said to him, "This is a Confederate
hospital, I am in charge of it, I command here, you
must go down from here." Champ Ferguson then advanced
to within three feet of me, raised his cocked pistol
and pointed directly at my breast saying, "I don't
care who you are, damn you, I will kill you." Realizing
the desperate character I had to deal with and being
myself unarmed, yet impelled by a sense of duty, I
again said to him, "You must go down from here and out
of this hospital." While we v/ere standing in this
threatening attitude, face to face with Ferguson's
pistol at my breast and swearing he would kill me,
Lieutenant Philpot of Ferguson's company stepped in
between us at the same time motioning with his hand to
Ferguson when they all went down the steps, I, going
18
down with them, Ferguson cursing and swearing as he
went. They passed out of the hospital, mounted their
horses and as they rode off shouted, "We have killed
the man that killed Hamilton."
Afterwards I was told that Lieutenant Smith, whom
Champ Ferguson had just killed, had mistreated Ferguson's
family; that he made Ferguson's wife undress and marched
her before him along the public road in a nude state.
The killing of Smith was promptly reported to General
Breckenridge at Abingdon, he being in command of the
Department of Southwestern Virginia. Champ Ferguson was
arrested, a court-martial ordered and held, but it was
so near the close of the war that nothing more than this
was done with him.
Editor's Note: Dr. Murfree did not complete his story. Champ
Ferguson was captured on May 30, 1865. His trial opened in
Nashville on July 15 and droned on until September 26 when
Ferguson was found guilty and sentenced to be hanged. The order
of the court was carried out in the morning of October 20. His
last words were a request that his remains be returned to the
little cemetery near his home in White County. To the last he
was fearful that his body would be consigned to the medical school
in Nashville. Champ's wishes prevailed.
THE FINAL DAYS OF CHAMP FERGUSON
There is little doubt that Champ Ferguson failed to receive
a fair trial in Nashville beginning on July 11, 1865. The three
Nashville newspapers. Daily Union , Nashville Dispatch , and the
Daily Press and Times were Northern- held, and Ferguson was a
Confederate guerilla. Daily, the citizens were fed an emotional
diet of lurid stories, vicious attacks, and personal reporter
assessments of the killer's war career. The reactions of the
citizens and the "reporting" apparently made little impact on
Ferguson. There is no shred of evidence that he ever felt any
real compunction concerning his actions. The sketches below are
from Harper's Weekly (September 23 and November 11, 1865).
ASaviLLS, TKSNE8SKE, Ockbm &#187;. iesft.-&#163;SiiTCK&#171;&#187; bt J. H. AwfotJ.]
</dc:description>
<dc:description>Tells of the interaction between Murfreesboro native Dr. James Murfree and Champ Ferguson, a notorious murderer of Union soldiers, whose last victim was one of Murfree's federal prisoner patients at the Confederate Hospital at Emory</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Memoirs and biographies; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865; Violent crimes</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Confederate hospitals; Ferguson, Champ; Murders; Murfree, Dr. James</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>9 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-15; mt2011-05-05</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication02ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/63</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>