<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Abstract of wills from Rutherford County, Tennessee</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Daniel, Susan G.</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 21</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>198?</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1810-1819; 1820-1829</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>ABSTRACT of WILLS
from
Rutherford Comty^ Tennessee
by Susan G. Daniel
Other Will Abstracts in Publications Nuaber
17 and 19&#171; by Susan 0. Daniel
-U9-
ABSTRACT OF WILLS FROM RUTHERFORD CO., TN RECORD BOOKS 5 &amp; 6
RB = Record Book DOW = Date of Will F = Filed in Court
R = Recorded in Record Book S = slave s = son d = daughter
W = witness E = Executor/Executrix gs/gd = grandchildren
N: Named but relationship not given L: Landowner mentioned
1. RB 5, P. 10 - Obadiah Smith of Rutherford Co., TN
DOW: 26 July 1816 F: June term 1819 Wife: not named
S: (loan to wife) Jim, George, Aggy &amp; Hannah s: William
Smith "all my children" E: sons, John Smith, William
Smith, Thomas Smith W: John Smith, Robert Smith, James
Leatherman
2. RB 5, P. 13 - Coleman Mason DOW: 3 February 1819
F: June term 1819 Mother: Susannah Mason Brother:
James Mason (not of lawful age) Sister: Susannah Mason
Sister: Patsey Mason W: Griffin Dodd, Joseph Patterson,
Joel Matheny, Job Matheny
3. RB 5, P. 39 - William Still of Rutherford Co., TN
DOW: 3 February 1819 F: June term 1819 Brother: John
Still S: man, Jesse to brother, John Father: John
Still, Sr. S: Joseph &amp; Abigail to father E: Joseph
Morton and James Morton W: Joseph Morton, Thomas Edwards,
Nancy Edwards
4. RB 5, P. 50 - Jesse Patrick DOW: 25 March 1820 F: June
term 1820 Wife: Jemima Patrick N: George Songer
Son-in-law: Joshua Vasser d: Syntha Vasser L: bought
land from Thomas Hopkins N: Eli Harrison Children:
John Patrick, Allen Patrick, Levy Patrick, Nancy 0. Patrick,
Raliegh Patrick E: Joshua Vasser, Jesse Todd W: George
Songer, Henry Cooper
5. RB 5, P. 52 - Isaac Ledbetter DOW: 31 December 1818
F: March term 1819 Wife: Nancy S: (lend to wife) Isa-bell
and her children, Easter and her children, old Annica,
Anthony, Sam, Daniel L: Benjamin McCullock 3 s: William
L. Ledbetter, Richard R. Ledbetter, Isaac H. Ledbetter
"children not married or 21" S: bought from Sterling
Lankford and William' Southerland [but apparently not in
the household] - woman, Phoebe &amp; child L: William Lytle
N: John M. Tilford d: Elizabeth Guardians &amp; E: Edmund
Jones, William L. Ledbetter W: David Ledbetter, Elias
King, George E. Harris
6. RB 5, P. 61 - Matthew Edwards DOW: 27 April 1820
F: Sept. term 1820 s: William M. Edwards d: Rebecca
Edwards Wife: Elizabeth Edwards my children: Polly
Wheeler, Matthew, Pasha, Issabel E: wife and son, Matthew
W: George Rutledge, Jain Pollett
50
7. RB 5, P. 90 - Owen Edwards DOW: 15 November 1820 F: Dec.
term 1820 Wife: Judith Edwards s: Ewen H. Edwards,
Arthur M. Edwards, James A. Edwards, William Edwards,
Owen H. Edwards d: Catharine W. Loftin, Nancy F. Nelson,
Sally M. Edwards, Judith M. Edwards, Liensarey Edwards
S to wife: Jim &amp; Nelly, Rose &amp; Primas S to Catharine:
Eady S to Arthur: woman, Fanny S to James: boy, Nimrod
S to Nancy: Ream &amp; Molly S to Sally: Clarisa, Henrietta
S to Judith (daughter): Sarah, Harriet S to Owen: boy, Tom
S to Liensary: Betsey, Winney (James Ridley owed deceased
money) L: Murphey, Nixon E: John Nelson, Arthur M.
Edwards, James Morton W: Jacob Payne, Zephaniah H. B.
Anthony, James Morton
8. RB 5, P. 93 - Mary Smith DOW: 20 Sept. 1815 Codecil: 5
Nov. 1820 F: Dec, term 1820 s: Samuel Smith, Cunningham
Smith, William Smith, Charles Gilliam, Jonathan's heirs
"lawful heirs": Samuel, Jonathan, Robert, William, Cunning-ham,
Sampson Smith, Thomas L. Hamilton, Charles Gilliam
S: girl, Suffy to be sold; boy, Spencer whose parents
are Tom &amp; Lid E: Charles Gilliam and William Smith of
Wilson Co. W: Cunningham Smith, Robert Warwick, W. Yan-dell
CODECIL: S: Tom, deceased W: Wilson Yandell,
Robert Smith
9. RB 5, P. 95 - Ann Smith DOW: 20 Oct. 1818 F: Dec. term
1820 d: Lucy Maner, Rhoda Garrett and her 3 children,
Levi Maner, Martha Maner, and David Smith Maner gd:
Nancy Maner E: Jordan Williford W: David Price, Samuel
Williford, Larkin Jackson
10, RB 5, P. 96 - Samuel Henderson DOW: 16 May 1818 F: Dec.
term 1820 Wife: Mary Ann Henderson d: Mary McNeese,
wife of Robert McNeese; Nancy Rodgers, wife of William
Rodgers; Patience Rodgers, wife of Andrew Rodgers; Susannah
Rodgers; Christian Davis; Sally King s: Richard Henderson
gs/gd: "heirs of son, Samuel Henderson which he has by
his present wife, Sally" (Samuel appointed guardian)
Minerva, Abner B., Eliza H. , Samuel F., Jethro P. gs/gd:
"heirs of James Henderson and wife, Fanny (James appointed
guardian) - Eliza E., Samuel W. , Pleasant F. E: William
Adkerson, and sons, James and Samuel W: Frederick E.
Beeton, William Bowman
11. RB 5, P. 100 - Joseph Burrus DOW: 13 January 1819
F: March term 1821 Wife: Sophia s: De La Fayette "land
purchased of Groce Scruggs"; Philip Johnson; James Rucker
(not 21 or married); William C. J.; Charles d: Elizabeth;
Lucy Ann; Sally Woolfork L: Col. Thomas Rucker,
Foster "owns land in Madison Co., KY" S to wife: Sawney,
Letty, Reuben, Violet, Manda, Appleberry, Major, Harriet,
Delilah, Austin, Nicy S to De La Fayette: John, Nelson,
Bill, Linda, Ben and Sally (children of Linda) S to
Elizabeth: Lewis, Yellow Nancy, Black Nancy, Caleb, Clary
and her son, Edmund S to Lucy: Alfred, Patty, Jack (son
of Patty), Parker, Kit, Anna, Narcissa (daughter of Lucky)
S to Philip: Lucky, Zechariah, Jordan, Charles (son of
^1
(Will of Joseph Burrus cont'd)
Violet), Esther, Henry (son of Mary) S to Sally: Polly
(daughter of Lucky), Wyatt, Jesse, Richard, Tilda and
her son, John Beverly S to James: Washington, Samuel,
Eliza (daughter of Matilda), Joshua (son of Mary), Charles
(son of Matilda), Charlotte (daughter of Letty) S to
William: James, Armistead (sons of Harriet), Martha, Well-ington
and Joseph (children of Nicy), Abram (son of Letty)
E: Wife and Ebenezer McGowen, Benjamin Rucker, Samuel
Anderson W: Edmund Jones, Sterling Orgain, Alfred Moore
12. RB 5, P. 133 - Joseph Ship DOW: 1 May 1821 F: June term
1821 eldest s: Joseph Ship eldest d: Mary Ship
s: Lewis Ship, James Ship d: Lynda Johnston N: Barberry
Rappid W: Daniel Nichols. John Earwood
13. RB 5, P. 157 - Lewis Ashman DOW: 19 Aug. 1819 R: Sept.
1821 N: John Smith "money left to repair Methodist
Meeting house known as Garretts Chapel" N: Brooking
Burnett (with whom I now live) E: Brooking Burnett and
Robert Montgomery W: Joseph Burnett, Reuben Burnett
14. RB 5, P. 158 - Elizabeth Whoberry DOW: 1 June 1821
F: Sept. 1821 d: Patsey Blacketter E: Norman Blacketter
and Patsey Blacketter W: Andrew Cuff, Susanna McCombs
15. RB 5, P. 161 - John Yous [Hughes?] DOW: 13 June 1821
F: Sept. 1821 Wife: Temperance Yous my 3 children:
Elizabeth, Thomas, George "my father's estate" to be
allotted E: Burrell Gannaway W: William Molloy, William
Matthews
16. RB 5, P. 173 - Thomas Pullen DOW: -4 Aug. 1820 F: June
term 1821 Wife: Amelia Pullen eldest s: John W. Pullen
second son: Josiah Pullen d: Elizabeth Pullen s: James
F. Pullen youngest d: Amelia Pullen S to wife: man, Tom
and Betty, his wife; man, Kinchen; man, Barn; girl, Nice;
woman. Cherry; 4 children - Jack, Rhoda, Prince, Madison;
girl, Fanny; Charity; Maria S to John: woman, Esther;
boy, Lewis S to Josiah: boy. Squire; girl, Nice S
to Elizabeth: girl, Fanny; boy, Prince S to James: boy.
Jack; girl, Rhoda S to Amelia (daughter): girl, Charity;
boy, Madison E: wife and son, Josiah Pullen W: Isaac
Fromey, Josiah Watkins , Peter Warren
17. RB 5, P. 185 - John Davidson DOW: 11 Oct. 1821 F: Dec.
term 1821 Wife: Nancy "land purchased of George Beard,
Limestone Co., Alabama" s: James Davidson d: Polly
Kirk, Sally Belleu, Dovey Ewell, Nancy W. Davidson
N: Major Locke S to wife: Reuben; woman, Dinah; girl.
Creasy; child, Jerry S to Polly: girl, Alice S to
Sally: girl, Frances S to James: man, Elijah; boy, Isaac;
girl, Caroline S to Dovey: woman, Kodah S to Nancy:
woman, Hannah and child, Rebecca S: boy, Joseph E: wife
and John Davidson of Bedford Co. W: T.B.Henly, Elijah
Cox, Sarah Cox
18. RB 5, P. 197 - John Biles DOW: 29 Dec. 1821 R: Nov. 8,
1823 Wife: Elizabeth eldest s: Obadiah Biles
second s: Smith Biles s: Willie Biles s: Herbert Biles
d: Lucy Biles, Polly Biles s: William Jefferson Biles
d: Cinthia Biles, Sophia Biles S to wife: Sally, Solomon,
Purchase, Mourning, Mariah, ned, Lewis, Arrena S to
Willie: boy, Anthony S to Herbert: boy. Purchase S to
Lucy: girl, Maris S to Polly: girl, Nice S to William
J.: boys, Solomon and Lewis S to Cinthia: girl, Arrena
S to Sophia: woman, Sally E: Willie Biles and Herbert
Biles W: James Mason, John Clark, Benjamin Marable
19. RB 5, P. 209 - Henry Robinson DOW: 16 Nov. 1821 F: 9 Nov.
1822 E &amp; son: Hugh Robinson d: Elizabeth Hanes , Abigail
Moore, Jane Patten N: Andrew J. Hanes N: Thomas Woods
L: Benjamin Ransom W: Ezekiel Murphy, John Murphy, H.
Robinson
20. RB 5, P. 220 - James McKnight DOW: 24 March 1817
R: 9 Nov. 1822 Wife: Eleanor/Eleander McKnight d:
Jane Orr s: James McKnight d: Isabel Sharp s: Alex-ander
McKnight, Joseph McKnight d: Margaret Knox
s: John Martin McKnight, David McKnight [David to take
care of mother] S to wife: woman, Rachael S to David:
man, Isaac E: James McKnight W: John Alexander, James
Andrews
21. RB 5, P. 237 - John Adcock DOW: 15 Sept. 1822 R: 25 Nov.
1822 d: Levina Adcock, Polly Adcock s: Jesse Adcock
[not of age - apparently youngest child], Willie Adcock,
William Adcock, Marcus Adcock, Harmon Adcock, Stephen
Adcock, Doctor Adcock, Robert America Adcock gd: Nancy
Adcock E: William Vinson and son, John Adcock W: A.
Pearce, Ephraim Medows , Andrew Inglis, John Adcock
22. RB 5, P. 248 - Charles Fogg DOW: 24 Sept. 1822 R: 26 Nov.
1822 Wife: Winiford Fogg s: Jonathan W. Fogg (not
of age) W: William Sargeant, Nathan Chaffin, Jonathan
Wilburn
23. RB 5, P. 248 - David Moore DOW: 7 March 1820 R: 26 Nov.
1822 s: David Moore, George D. Moore, James Moore
d: Nancy Jetton, Peggy Moore gs : Samuel McClanahan
L: Blanin (?) E: Robert Waron, James Jetton W: Jos.
Dickson, Thos. Beavers
24. RB 5, P. 250 - John Kirk, Senior DOW: 9 Oct. 1822
R: 26 Nov. 1822 Wife: Eleanor Kirk d: Elizabeth
all my children: Jane Bell, Hugh Kirk, Agness McEwen,
Martha Montgomery, Eleanor Killough, John Kirk, Jr.
S to wife: woman, Dinah &amp; her 2 children S to Elizabeth:
man. Jack E: sons, Hugh &amp; John and wife W: Joseph
Marlin, Samuel R. McKlroy
25. RB 5, P. 251 - Jarret Barnet DOW: 29 June 1821 R: 26 Nov.
1822 d: Winney s: Daniel d: Jenny Brown d: Nancy
Underwood s: Jarret Wife: Margrett N: Joseph McCane
of Rockingham Co., N.C. 3 youngest children: Susanna,
Ambrose, Peggy W: John McMumemsy (?), Cornelius Sanders
E : George Underwood and wife
26. RB 5, P. 253 - Jesse Brashear DOW: 25 Aug. 1821 R: 26 Nov.
1822 Wife: Betsey son's grandfather: Isaac Wright,
deceased d: Docia Bivens, Rebecca Jarrett, Betsey Bra-shear,
Patsey/Polly Brashear s: Isaac W. Brashear (not
21), Nathan (not 21), Abraham (not 21), Jesse W. (not
21) S to wife: woman, Cate (no children) S to Docia:
girl. Bleary S to Rebecca and son Isaac: boy. Nelson
S to Nathan: boy, Bob S to Isaac: boy, Netran S to
Abraham: boy, George S to Jesse: boy, Aston E: Guy
Smith, Charles Ready, John L. Jetton W: Alexander McEwen,
William Childress, William Byers
27. RB 5, P. 259 - Joseph Lannum DOW: 21 Mar. 1822 R: 1 Mar.
1823 Wife: Delilah s: Green B. Lannum, Simpson Lannum
"my 4 daughters": Sarah, Tabitha, Lucinda, Mary E: William
Lannum, Jacob Browning W: A. Robertson, Alfred Arnold
28. RB 5, P. 273 - Joseph Morton DOW: 29 Nov. 1822 R: 11 Mar.
1823 Wife: Cicely s: James Morton, Joseph Morton
d: Elizabeth V. Morton, Mary Anne A. Anthony, Martha Eliza-beth
V. Morton, Manassa Morton, Cicely Harriet Morton
S to wife: Sam &amp; Tilleh, his wife; Dorcas; Lish; Jerry;
Jesse &amp; his wife, Trecy and Billy S to James: boy, Henry
S to Joseph: boy, Adam S: "negroes heretofore given
to Mary Anne" E: brother, James Morton and Thomas S.
Anthony W: Arthur M. Edwards, John Allen, William Walker
29. RB 5, P. 31^4 - Burrell Carter DOW: 24 Dec. 1822 R: 28
June 1823 Wife: Sarah d: Patsey, Angelina d: Burrell
S to wife: Tom, Batey, Jerry, Littleton, Mason E: wife,
S. Powell and George Anderson W: Solomon Beesley, Charles
Puckett
30. RB 5, P. 315 - Archibald Harris DOW: 9 Jan. 1823 R: 28
June 1823 Wife: Kiturah Harris Nephew: Archibald Aug-ustus
Harris, son of Thos . A. Harris brothers: Augustus
Harris, Robert Harris, Thomas A. Harris sisters: Temper-ance
Bryant, Susan Hicks S to wife: man. Jack; woman,
Dorcas; girl, Emily E: Thomas A. Harris and John Moseby
W: Thomas A. Harris, John Moseby, John Nelson
31. RB 5, P. 316 - Philip Sanders DOW: 9 Jan. 1823 R: 28
June 1823 Wife: Elizabeth youngest child, son: Philip
(will be of age in 17 yrs . and about a month) "next
son will be of age in about 15 yrs" "nine last children"
E: son-in-law, H Northcutt W: Richard Stephens,
Sampson Stephens
32. RB 5, P. 332 - John McHenry (being old) DOW: not given
R: 12 Sept. 1823 Wife: Rachel d: Peggy Hall, Jenney
Wilson s: John McHenry, Silas McHenry L: Benjamin
Mcculloch gs: William Hall gd: Nancy Wilson sons-in-law:
William Wilson, William Hall S to wife: girl, Lissey
S: Lissey to Abeline Brown after wife's death S to Peggy:
girl. Lot "which William Hall has disposes of some time
ago"; boy, Jim S to gs : boy, Andy S to Jenney: woman,
Pryss; girl, Eliza S to Nancy: girl, Mary S to John:
man, Jo S to Silas: boy, Rodger; boy child, Jo 5:
old man, Jo to be freed but taken care of by 2 sons until
death E: Samuel McAdo , Capt. Ambrose McKee W: Henry
Grouse, Polly Grouse
33. RB 5, P. 336 - Nancy Morton DOW: 19 June 1820 R: July
term 1823 d: Susannah Pea, Patsey Williams, Polly Lips-comb,
Fanny Burleson s: John Morton N: John Strong,
1st husband of Patsey and their children E: John Morton
W: Joseph Morton, James Morton [in subscribing oath,
Joseph Morton was deceased]
3^. RB 5, P. 337 - Margaret Seat DOW: 15 Feb. 1823 R: 13
Sept. 1823 N: Margaret Caroline Burnett, Brooking Burnett
"with whom I now live", Fanny R. Seat S to Marg. G.
Burnett: boy, Alfred S to Brooking: woman, Hannah and
boy, Lym E: Brooking Burnett, Henry Seat W: Anderson
Freeman, Robert Montgomery
35. RB 6,P.l - Mary Warren DOW: 12 Aug. 1823 R: Jan. term
1824 gs: Willis Snell, Hays Snell (not 21), James Snell
(not 15) gd: Elizabeth Snell, Susan Snell (not 15),
Mary/Polly Griffin N: Loderick Alford and Cade Alford
of Wake Co., N.C., executors of estate of George Warren
of Wake Co., N.C. "which I am entitled to receive some
money fro several years" S to Willis: woman, Burchett
and her 2 oldest children named Anderson and Darkis
S to Hayes: boy, Nathan S to James: boy, Burrell S
to Elizabeth and Susan: Charlotte, Harbert, Irvin and
youngest child Burchett has at breast about 2 or 3 weeks
old not yet named E: Willis Snell W: Thomas Montage,
James Day
36. RB 6, P. 3 - John Garter DOW: ^ Jan 1824 R: 1 March 1824
Wife: Rachel children: Margaret, William, Gaty, Mary,
Amy, John, Jr., Rachel, Jr. S:Isham kept for the family;
Sawny and Fanny have choice of being sold or hire E: wife
and Nathaniel Overall, William Thomas W: Neal Smith,
Samuel S. Wilson, George Peebles
37. RB 6, P. 18 - John Wallis DOW: 17 June 1823 F: Jan. 1824
s: Amos S. Wallis, Mortimer Randolph Wallis, John F. Wallis
d: Clarisa Alexander, Sophia G. Ewing, Emma W. Hall
Wife: Isabella S. Wallace gd: Mira Alexander, Isabella
Alexander (Mira's sister), Isabella Ewing N: John Wallis,
son of Alfred Wallis S to Amos: man, Joe; boy, Tom
(Will of John Wallis conf
)
S to Mortimer: man, Sam; boy, already in his possession
named George; woman Hannah and her child now at the breast
S to wife: woman of colour named Jenny Hasper S to John:
boy of colour: Aleck S to Emma: girl, Moriah S to
Mira: girl, Jinsey (1st offspring to Isabella) S to
Isabella Ewing: girl, Harriet S to be sold: boy, William
"be paid to Mira Matthews in Carolina for the benefit
of the famiy of Alfred Wallis [apparently still alive]
E: John F. Wallis, Amos S. Wallis, Mortimer R. Wallis
W: William Robb, Thomas J. Mabry CODECIL: 25 Nov. 1823
d: Eliza B. Ham
38. RB 6, P. 4-2 - Mary Gatlin DOW: 17 Dec. 1823 R: 18 May 182-4
E: John G. Wilkins "a child I raised from his birth" entire
estate willed to John G. Wilkins W: Lewis Sutfin, James
Sutfin
39. RB 6, P. 43 - William McFarlin DOW: 1824 R: April term 1824
Wife: Sarah 2 sons not of age: Pleasant Nelson and
Benjamin (youngest son) 5 d: Elizabeth Ann, Kasey A. ,
Nancy B., Louisa J., Sarah Mother: (living) S to sons:
boy, Austin; woman, Nelly E: wife and Joseph Youree
W: B.L. McFerrin, Benjamin McFarlin
40. RB 6, P. 44 - Peter Garrison DOW: 10 Feb. 1824 R: 18 May
1824 brother: Josinah Garrison Josinah's son: Peter
Garrison of South Carolina (not 21) N: Serenus Garrison
Dickson's son, Asahel Dickson (not 21) N: (left money
to American Missionary and American Bible Societies)
brother: James Garrison of York, S.C. James' son: Peter
Serenus Garrison Wife (deceased): Mary E: John Martin,
Joseph Canon W: Ephraim G. Harris, James Baker
41. RB 6, P. 56 - Simeon Vaught DOW: 11 April 1824 R: 24 Aug.
1824 Wife: Nancy children: Susannah, Mary, Elizabeth,
Phebe and James (all not of age or married) L: Zadock
Bell N: Jesse Brashear (deceased) E: Elijah Vaught,
William Bishop W: H. Trott, William Bishop, Elijah Vaught
42. RB 6, P. 57 - Tigner Dameron 'doW: 1 Sept. 1822 R: 24 Aug.
1824 Wife: Nancy s: Edmund, William, Sion d: Lidia,
Midda, Sally, Nancy, Mary, Judy E: Henry Vincent of
Rutherford Co. W: John Dunn, Benjamin Dunn
43. RB 6, P. 59 - Nathan Baker DOW: 10 Sept. 1824 R: 5 Nov.
1824 E and wife: Elizabeth Baker children not named
W: Theophiles A. Canon, James Sharpe , Robert Martin
44. RB 6, P. 60 - Rachel Sharp DOW: 2 April 1823 R: 5 Nov.
1824 s: James Morris Sharpe, Joseph Canon Sharpe (not
21) d: Peggy Carlile Hibbets , Jemima A. Sharpe S to
Peggy: woman and girl, Milly E: brother, Joseph Canon;
son, Alfred Sharpe; son-in-law, Robert H. Hibbets
W: Wilson Yandell, Samuel McCleary, John Canon
56
^5. RB 6, P. 61 - David Ledbetter DOW: 13 July 1824 R: 5 Nov.
1824 Wife: Nelly children: Malissa R. Ledbetter, Polly
W. Ledbetter, Martha D. Ledbetter, Benjamin Ledbetter,
James A. Ledbetter L: land purchased of Henry Finger
on Overalls Creek Mother (old): Jane Ledbetter E: wife
W: Anderson James, Silas Read
46. RB 6, P. 63 - Alexander Jordon DOW: 10 Sept. 1824 R: 5 Nov.
1824 Wife: Nancy s: John, David, James, William, Alex-ander,
Joseph d: Gracy, Jane Ball, Nancy S to John: boy,
Jesse (now in his possession) S to Gracey: girl, Phillis
S to Jane: girl. Si Ivy S to Nancy: negro not named
S to William: boy, Benjamin S: Peter, Tabitha, Dinah,
Tibby E: wife and son, John W: Jno. G. Murphey, Guy
Clopton, E. Donoho
47. RB 6, P. 87 - William G. Kimbro DOW: 4 Sept. 1824 R: 14
Feb. 1825 Wife: Lucinda Kimbro [oldest child not 21]
4 children: Isaac N. Kimbro, Joseph T. Kimbro, Amanda
A. Kimbro, William G. Kimbro S to wife: man, Tom; woman,
Nelly, and others not named E: Nathan Williams, John
Kimbro W: J. H. Coartz , Joseph May
48. RB 6, P. 89 - John Sharpe DOW: 22 May 1822 R: 15 Feb. 1825
eldest d: Jemima A. Canon eldest son: James Sharpe
s: Cyrus Sharpe, John McKnight Sharpe, Edwin Sharpe, Will-iam
Sharpe (deceased) d: Polly Young Canon, Martha Louisa
sons-in-law: Abraham W. Canon, Samuel Wilson 4 children
of son William: John Christopher Columbus Sharpe, William
Wilson Sharpe, Martha Caroline Sharpe, Sarah Jane Sharpe
L: "tract conveyed to William Alexander by State of N.C.
and Alexander conveyed to me : S to Jemima: yellow boy.
Ransom; yellow woman, Harriet and child S to James:
man. Jack S to Polly: boy. Bob N: Samuel McCleary,
William Robb , John M. Tilford E: William Robb, Theophilus
A. Canon W: Samuel McCleary, Joseph Canon
49. RB 6, P. 110 - John Brothers DOW: 25 Mar. 1825 R: 8 June
1825 Wife: Polly s: Robert, Benjamin, Burton, Thomas
(not 21), Jackson C. (not 21) S to wife: Jim, Tiller,
Minty S: to be hired then sold when Thomas aged 21
5 to be sold: Peter, Sarah L: "tract of land I bought
of John P. Smith" E: Stephen Linch, Capt. Sublett
W: Stephen Linch, Thomas Brothers
50. RB 6, P. 112 - John Johnston DOW: 29 May 1819 R: 8 June
1825 Wife: Cathrine eldest d: Nancy Stubblefield
d: Susannah Eskridge, Cynthia Banton sons-in-law: Wood-ruff
Stubbelfield, Samuel Eskridge, Glover W. Banton
3 grandchildren: Eliza W. Knight, Washington J. Knight,
Cynthia C. Knight S to wife: Ede , Green S to Nancy:
man. Bob S to Susannah: man, Dick S to Cynthia: girl,
Mary S: Ede to Cynthia after wife's death or marriage
E: Samuel Eskridge, Glover W. Banton W: Hezekiah G,
Cooke, Jacob Tilman, Richard Ramsey
57
51. RB 6, P. 114 - Joseph Dickson DOW: 8 Oct. 1823 R: 8 June
1825 s: James Dickson N: Elizabeth Graves and her
daughter, Adaline d: Isabella d: Margaret Henderson
s: John Dickson and his wife, Margaret gs: Joseph Dickson
(son of John) gd: Peggy Dickson (daughter of John)
s: Joseph Dickson, Robert Dickson, William Dickson, Ezekiel
Dickson gs : William Dickson, Jo. Dickson "my large
Bible" [unclear if left to Ezekiel or Sarah M. Dickson]
gd: Sarah M. Dickson S to Sarah: girl, Phillis (7 yrs)
E: sons, James and Robert Dickson W: William Bumpass,
Robert McLin
52. RB 6, P. 116 - John Smith DOW: 29 April 1822 R: 9 June
1825 Wife: Jane C. Smith 5 s: William Madison Smith,
John Smith, George Washington Smith, Robert Henderson
Smith, James Rush Smith d: America C. Smith, Evelina
Crockett, Carolina Matilda Johnson, Julia Granville Crock-ett,
Jane (Sarah Jane ?), Sarah Jane Smith [apparently
not married] L: "tract of land I bought of David P.
Harris", "tract of land I got of General E. P. Gaines
containing 846 acres" S to America: Cinda &amp; her son,
Edmund; Moriah &amp; her son, Sanders; Buck S to Evelina:
Flora &amp; her child. Will; James &amp; Gate S to Caroline:
girl, Eliza S to Julia: Ciasar; Lucy &amp; her child; girl,
Mary S to wife: George &amp; his wife, Julia "my harrican
hill tract of land" E: wife; son-in-law, William H.
Smith; borhter, Robert Smith, Jr. ; son, William M. Smith
(not 18); son, John Smith (not 18) W: William R. Rucker
,
William Smith CODECIL: 8 Sept. 1823 s: born after
making of first will 5 youngest sons: John, George W.
Robert H. , James L. R. and Ephraim Foster Smith
53. RB 6, P. 120 - Edmund Sutton DOW: 24 Dec. 1824 R: 9 June
1825 Wife: Polly my children [apparently all unmarried]:
Rozamiah P. Sutton, Alcy Sutton, Cholson Sutton, Alexander
Harrison Sutton, Anne Eliza Sutton, Sally Sutton, Enoch
Sutton, Mary Sutton, William Sutton, Elizabeth Sutton,
Margaret Jane Sutton E: wife and Isaac Ellsberry W:
Pleasant Henderson, Richard Tenpenny, Robert George
54. RB 6, P. 121 - Andrew Freeman DOW: 2 April 1825 R: 9 June
1825 "to my beloved old Gate whom I bought from Benjamin
McCulloch and do own her as my wife" my 3 children:
Ben, Isabel and Jack E: Lent Brown, William H. Ballew
W: John Lyell, William Darnall
55. RB 6, P. 122 - John Anthony DOW: none given R: 9 June 1825
Wife: not named d: Sally Davis, Matilda Manus s: Z.H.B.
Anthony oath to veracity of will: Solomon Beesley, Wil-liam
Anthony, James Morton, Zepheniah H. B. Anthony
56. RB 6, P. 149- John Chisenhall DOW: 6 July 1825 R: 10 Sept.
1825 Wife: Rebecca Chisenhall E: wife and Hiram Cox
W: Wm. H. Smith, E. Chisenhall
:?o
57. RB 6, P. 150 - Margaret Moore DOW: 28 Feb. 1825 R: 10
Sept. 1825 3 brothers &amp; 3 sisters brother: James Moore
niece: Mary Moore, Letty Moore nephew: Peter Moore
niece: Cynthia McClanahan sister: Agness Jetton niece:
Maneria Cartwright, Susan Cartwright nephew: Rufus Jetton
brothers: David Moore, George D. Moore sister: Letty,
Malinda E: James S. Jetton W: James Kelton, Catherine
Bowman, E. Jetton
58. RB 6, P. 152 - Abner Johns DOW: 16 June 1825 R: 10 Sept.
1825 Wife: Susan Johns d: Mary Johns, Roda Trigg Johns,
Sarah Anne Johns, Catherine Elizabeth Johns, Susan F,
Johns s: William R. Johns, Franklin A. Johns S to
wife: Sam, Hannah, Joe, Isabel, Lucy S to Mary: Blackman
&amp; Esther S to Roda: Cesar &amp; Little Judy S to Sarah:
Washington &amp; Harriet S to William: Forda S to Catherine:
Fanny &amp; Jack S to Susan: Patsey &amp; Little Sam S to
Franklin: boy, Sterline S to wife: girl, Hannah S
to be sold: big Judy, Mary &amp; her child E: Joseph B.
Johns W: David Dickinson, John R. Wilson
59. RB 6, P. 166 - Alexander McKeen DOW: 6 Aug. 1825 R:
1 Dec. 1825 Wife: Mary McKeen eldest d: Elizabeth
Ashbrooks second d: Sarah Warner my 2 sons: John H.
McKeen, Alexander D. McKeen 5 youngest d: Mary D., Nancy,
Emelina, Henriette and Jane L: farm I purchased of Mary
Ann Pace "my interest in 4-00 acres of land lying in
Haywood Co. as a legatee of James Doak, deceased" S
to wife: man, Howel ; man, Harry; woman, Hannah S to
Elizabeth: woman, Betsey &amp; her child, Edy E: wife &amp;
Thomas Blair W: William D. Baird, John H. McKeen
60. RB 6, P. 168 - Travis Marable DOW: 17 Aug. 1824 R: 1 Dec.
1825 Wife: Martha Marable children: Mary Anne, Martha
Jane, James Alexander, Isaac, John (youngest child not
of age) S to wife: man, Jeffrey &amp; his wife, Chloe; boy,
Daniel; boy. Bob; boy, Tom; girl, Milly S divided amongst
5 children: boy, Joe; boy, Abel; woman, Mary E: Henry
H. Marable, Bemjamin Marable W: Amaze Jones, Carey James,
Samuel Watkins
61. RB 6, P. 169 - Abraham Tennison DOW: 9 April 1821
R: 1 Dec. 1825 Wife: Jane "my children that have left
me I have given them their share" d: wife of Cor-nelius
Brandon; wife of Samuel Fulks ; wife of
Hugh Carnahan s: Solomon Tennison, Edmund Tennison
d: wife of James Hilton; Rebecca; Nancy Adams
s: Hiram, Archibald E: Solomon Tennison (son) and Alexan-der
Lorance W: Britton Pace, John Wilson, James King
62. RB 6, P. 172 - Cornelius 0. Flyn DOW: 13 Aug. 1825
R: 7 Dec. 1825 late of Newfoundland, town of St. Johns,
a native of Ireland, county of Waterford 2 sisters:
Elizabeth and Mary of County of Waterford, Ireland
59
(Will of Cornelius 0. Flyn cont'd)
nephew: only son of brother, John niece: daughter of
birbther John Estate owed money to: Jabez Maury of Leu-beck,
Passaraaquody bay, Massachusetts N: Roman Catholic
Church of Nashville; Dr. William Donnagan of Carboner
,
Conception bay, newfoundland and if Dr. Donnagan be dead
to give to William Behen the son of the doctor's niece;
John Elson, Carboner, Newfoundland E: Joseph Spence,
Jonathan Currin W: L. H. Laughlin, James Vaughan
63. RB 6, P. 174 - Ingram Blank DOW: 30 July 1825 R: 24 Feb.
1826 Wife: Martha niece: Elizabeth Parham Sills now
Elizabeth Parham Beaty L: King, Sherwood Green
S to Elizabeth: Nat, Ned, Lawrence, Nancy, Dilcy N:
Joseph Thomas Blanks Turner (not of age) S to Joseph:
Moses &amp; Winny, his wife and their 3 children; Edmund;
Lucy; Jennetta; Little Ephraim; Louisa; Mary; Fanny
"land allotted to me of the late Daniel Marshall in the
Western district mother of Joseph: Mary Ward Sills Lytle
5 to Mary: Joan; Tom; Aleck; Nancy and her 4 children;
Milly; Lewis; William; Lucind; Crecy; Young Milly; Ephraim;
Rebecca; George; Enoch; Little Moses; Little Lewis; Anaky;
Athy N: John Devereux Lawrence, son of Jonathan Lawrence
N: George Washington Beaty, son of William F. Beaty
W: L. H. Laughlin, Sol. Beesley, Charles Puckett, Nathaniel
Puckett
64. RB 6, P. 179 - John Nash Read [a medical doctor] DOW: 15 Nov
1825 R: 24 Feb. 1825 Wife: Mary, formerly Mary Barks-dale
"land whereon I now live known by the name of Grove"
s: Thomas H. Read, John H. Read, Clement (deceased), Sion,
James Allen Read d: Harry [sic] Anne Read "specifically
provided for in consequence of misfortune and affliction",
Mary H. Read and her husband, Randolph Barksdale N:
John Night (deceased) of Virginia, grandfather of James
and Francis S to wife: Jerry &amp; his wife, Polly; America
6 her infant, Caswell; Lucky; man, Joe S to Harry Anne:
girl, Polina S to Thomas: girl, Betsy - $350; boy, Dennis
- $220 S to wife: 2 old negroes - Jack and Aggy E:
son-in-law, Randolph Barksdale; son, Thomas H. Read; wife
W: Peter LeGrand, David Robinson, Nathaniel Barksdale,
Archibald H. Harris
65. RB 6, P. 182 - Joseph Nichols DOW: 7 Nov. 1824 R: 24 Feb.
1826 Wife: Elizabeth 4 d: Jane, Phebe , Levina, Abigail
(all unmarried) s: Joshua d: Euphemia Tomlinson
s: Jonathan Nichols d: Elizabeth Davis E: son, Joshua
and wife W: William Travers , John Andrews
66. RB 6, P. 184 - Thomas Jones Mabry DOW: 2 Dec. 1821
R: 22 Mar. 1826 Wife: Sally children not named, under
18 years L: John Buchanan, Robert Weakley, Peter Garret-son,
Levi White S to wife: Lucky, Davy N: sisters*
children E: Moses Ridley, William Robb proven will
by oath: Theophilus A. Canon, John M. Williams, Silas
Tucker
60
67. RB 6, P. 219 - James Bass DOW: 2-4 Nov. 1825 F: April term
1826 Wife: Temperance s: Thomas Bass, Benjamin J. Bass,
James Bass, Jr., Hartwell Bass d: Temperance W. Rucker,
Nancy Smith, Mary C. Laughlin "daughters and daughter-in-law"
L: Abraham Herring; William Smith; Alfred Blackman;
James Ridgeway (deceased); Martin Clark S to wife: men -
Nathan, Austin, Shade, Sandy; woman, Effey &amp; her 7 children
namely - Minerva, Chaney, William, Edmund, Julia, Doctor
&amp; Manuel; Sal &amp; her 2 children - Mariah, Jerry S to
Thomas: Bob &amp; Biriah S to Benjamin: Champion &amp; Phil
5 to daughter. Temperance: Daniel, Jesse &amp; Deli la (or
Silla) S to Nancy: Michael, Randel , Vinea S to James:
Abram, Jesse, Davy, Isham, Lewis, Lucy S to Mary: Clarissa
6 Leanah S to Hartwell: man, David Trustees for Mary
C. Laughlin &amp; her children: John R. Laughlin, William
Ledbetter E: sons, Thomas &amp; Benjamin; son-in-law, Peyton
Smith W: Claiborne Howse , Hezekiah Howse
68. RB 6, P. 236 - Benjamin Sherwood DOW: 9 June 1826
Wife: Polly s: Hezekiah L. Sherwood (not 21 or married)
d: Rebecha H. Shearwood (not 18 or married) E: wife
and William Brown W: A. Gowen, Jane Brown
69. RB 6, P. 243 - James Stewart DOW: 23 June 1816 R: 23
Nov. 1826 "my aged body" Wife: Margaret d: Polly
Wallace, Jane Wallace, Hannah Gosset/Garret s: James
W. Stewart, Daniel M. Stewart E: John Wallace, James
W. Stewart W: Hary McCoy, Polly McCoy CODECIL: 9 Sept.
1826 W: Daniel M. Stewart, William Webb
70. RB 6, P. 251 - Hugh Montgomery DOW: 23 Feb. 1820
F: July term 1826 Wife: Elizabeth Montgomery s: Joseph
A. Montgomery d: Rebecha Kidd Montgomery, Martha Stewart,
Isabella Montgomery, Janett McMurray, Mary P. McMurray,
Elizabeth Moore "house and lot in town of Murfreesboro
rented to McKiernan H. Butcher" S to wife: girl. Luff
S to Joseph: man, Cato; boy, Lewis E: wife; son, Joseph;
son-in-law, James Moore W: David Phillips, James Neelly,
Robert Jetton
71. RB 6, P. 252 - Charles Statham DOW: 4 June 1824 F: July
term 1826 oldest son now alive: Love Statham "land
deeded to me by William Hill" s: Thomas Statham
L: Elijah Murfree , Alexander McKeen S to Thomas: man,
George (learning blacksmith's trade); woman, Betty; woman,
Louisa d: Jane Statham L: Nicholas Woodfin S to
Jane: man, Peter; woman, Nancy; girl, Eliza s: Richard
Statham, William Statham (deceased) gs : Charles Statham,
son of William son-in-law: Charles Stewart d: Sally
Stewart S to be sold: Jesse, Bartlett E: Thomas Statham
and W. Guy W: T.Y. Blood, Peter Arnold
61
72. RB 6, P. 255 - Joseph Dill DOW: 21 April 1825 F: July-term
1826 s: Isaac Dill, Newton Dill, Parson Dill, Martin
Dill (not 21), Thomas, Marvel Dill (not 21) d: Lavinea
Dill, Hannah Petty, Molly Cole, Harriet Dill, Amanda Dill
S to Martin: boy, Moses S to Harriet: boy, Spencer
S to Amanda: boy, Nurvy s to be freed: woman, Pat
E: Jacob Wright, Isaac Dill W: William Bumpass, Daniel
Maberry
73. RB 6, P. 257 - Henry Windrow of Williamson Co., TN
DOW: 2 Mar. 1826 F: July term 1826 Wife: Carey Windrow
3 children: Miranda, Louisa, Cleveland, "child my wife
now pregnant with" S t wife: boy, Sam; woman, Venus
S to children: Isabel, Harry, Anaky, Gabreal , Edney, Nelly,
Minerva, Chaney, Jarvis E: wife and John Windrow W: Ben
Carr, Byars Windrow, Samuel Stewart
74. RB 6, P. 306 - Rebecca Powel DOW: 20 Dec. 1826 F: Jan.
term 1827 son-in-law: Jessee Eaton d: Elizabeth Powel,
Lydia Ward, Rebecca McMurtree , Edy Powel "debt due me
in Haywood Co., N.C. from Henry Plot" S used by Elizabeth
and Edy for 2 yrs . then sold: man, Valentine gs : Pleasant
Ward E: Peyton Smith W: William Pope, William Atkinson,
Hikes [Hicks] Ellis
75. RB 6, P. 308 - Arthur Puckett DOW: 6 Nov. 1826
Wife: Lucy eldest s: Pleasant eldest d: Mary W. (not
of age or married) second d: Sarah S. second s: Leonard
(not of age or married) s: John M. , Edward youngest d:
Betsey S to wife: Zilphy, Winny, Elin, Peter, Ned
S to Pleasant: boy, Daniel S to Mary: woman, Nancy &amp;
her child S to Sarah: girls, Gilly, Livina S to Leo-nard:
boy, Cato S to John: boy, Caleb S to Edward:
girl, Sarah S to Betsey: girl, Barlena E: sons, Plea-sant
and Leonard W: George Buchanan, Hiram D. Robertson,
John Smith
76. RB 6, P. 310 - Joseph T. Thompson DOW: 9 Dec. 1826
F: Jan. term 1827 Wife: Isabela s: John 2 d: Ann
Thompson, Isabela McCracken 4 grandchildren: William
McCombs, Rosanah McCombs , Jane Thompson, Mary Thompson
N: Elizabeth (presently sick) Kelly's son, Samuel; Jane
Allen S to wife: girl. Mill E: Joseph McCracken, Robert
Thompson W: Jonathan Rucker , James L. Armstrong
77. RB 6, P. 311 - John Thompson DOW: 19 Jan. 1824 F: Jan.
term 1827 Wife: Grizzel Thompson s: William Thompson,
David Thompson, Jesse Thompson, Joseph Thompson 4 d:
Jenny, married to John Lawrence; Catherine, married to
William Warren; Sally, married to James Turrentine; Peggy
Thompson gs : Orvil Thompson "land I purchased from
Capt. William Lytle" S to wife: Bill; Dinah; Jeffry;
Tim; Phillis &amp; her 2 daughters - Bethy, Francis S to
David: woman. Unity S to Jesse: Jack S to William: boy,
Caesar S to Sally: girl, Anne S to Peggy: girl, Edy
L: Cox E: wife and 2 sons, Joseph &amp; David W:
Samuel Anderson, Thomas Woods
78. RB 6, P. 316 - Sarah Carter DOW: 12 Jan. 1826 F: Jan.
term 1827 s: Burrell d: Angeline, Patsey S to Burrell:
man, Tom; boy, Littleton; girl. Mason S to Angeline:
woman, Jennet; girl, Margaret; girl, Sitter S to Patsey:
woman. Petty; girl. Jama; boy, Robert E: sons-in-law -
S.M. Powell, George W. Anderson W: Sol. Beesley, Charles
Puckett
79. RB 6, P. 317 - Polly Blackman DOW: 13 Nov. 1826
"little d" : Levenia Laura Malvina Augusta Blackman (not
21) "my part of my father's estate pending" S to d:
girl, Lucinda Owed money to estate: Abraham Henry, Ad-miral
Blackman E: Abraham Herring W: Devrent Beesley,
Polly Mabry
</dc:description>
<dc:description>Abstracts of wills and court proceedings listed in Record Books 5 &amp; 6 housed at the Rutherford County Archives</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.); Rutherford County (Tenn.) -- Archival resources; Wills; Public records</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-08; mt2011-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication21ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/27</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>