<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Peter Jennings</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Sloan, Eugene</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 10</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1978</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>18th century; 19th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>36
PETER JEmnilGS
by Eugene Sloan
Tira hundred ycaro ago, a bitter test of loyalty of the men of the
Continental Arry tras cjqpGricnccd&#8212;the "Winter of Docpair" at Valley
Forge, Pcnncylvania
.
Follo\d.ng the defeat at Germantown, the army of about 10,000
moved into the little valley among the hills of the Schuylkill River,
27 miles northwest of Philadelphia. With little food and hardly
enough clothing to protect themselves against the rigors of one of
the worst vrinters in colonial history, the arny morale deteriorated.
On DGCcnbor 23, 1777, General George VJashington wrote: "We have
this day no less than 2,873 men in can^j unfit for duty because they
are barefooted and othervdse naked."
But in that brave body of men who endured the harshness of that
winter were two men v;ho were to later make their homes in Rutherford
County. One of them v;as Peter Jennings&#8212;a black man&#8212;and the other,
Elijah Caith.
Smith, at age 77, v;as to appear in the Rutherford County Coiirt
in September, 1832 to support the claim of Jennings, age 80, for a
Revolutionary War pension.
Jennings was a notable character in his day. According to a story
appearing in the ^'turfreesboro News Banner . November 22, 1900, the first
house erected on the comer of Vine and Church Street, a one-story
frame building, vias occupied by "a free Negro, named Peter Jennings, as
a baker." This was during the time Murfreesboro was the capital of
Tennessee.
37
Henry G. Wray, former ai&#187;chlvist for the Rutherford County Historical
Society, along with Ernest King Johns did considerable research in con-nection
\srith the study of Revolutionary War soldiers v;ho came to Ruther-ford
County after the v/ar. Mrs. Edna Fry has followed up this work
by studying the official records in Washington, D.C. Among her findings
is the affadavit of Peter Jennings of August 23, 1832:
State of Tennessee
Rutherford Coimty
August term 1832
On this 23rd day of August 1832 personally appeared before Henry
Trott, V. D. Cov/an, and James C. Mitchell Esquires, Justices of the
Court of Pleas and Qxiarters Session for the county and state aforesaid,
now sitting in open coxirt, Peter Jennings, a man of colour, a resident
of the tov/n of Murfreesboro in the County and State aforesaid, aged
eighty years, four months, and twenty-one days, who being first duly
sworn, according to law, doth on his oath, make the following declar-ation,
in order to obtain the benefit of the provision made by the Act
of Congress passed June 7, 1832. That he enlisted in the array of the
United States, according to the best of his recollection in the year
1776 with Corporal Edenton and when he entered the service he belonged
to the 5th Regiment of Artillery of Blacks in the Continental line,
under the following named officers; He belonged to Capt. Vener Angel's
Company in which a man by the name of Hawley, whose given name he does
not now remember, was first Lieutenant, and man whose name v;as Ray,
second Lieutenant, his given name not remembered. The regiment was
commanded by Col. Edward (Oney), and a man whose name was Halsey, was
first Major, and he thinks his given name was Joseph. Who his second
Major was, he does not remember. He thinks his regiment joined General
Washington's amy at West Point and, after remaining there a few days,
38
Torched to Saratoga, vhere they rcnnincd a considerable length of time.
At tho cr.nis tiro they ucre cncanpcd at Saratoga, thinks that Gen. Dick-con
or Dickcnccn xno encamped \rith a division of Virginia militia, and
he thinl:3 ha rcmcnbers Colonels Canipbell and Forguson v/ere there in the
Virginia nilitia, Aftor rcnaining at Saratoga several weeks, he thinks
Ms regiment v-as divided and part of it attached to the troops under
the ccrrrand of Gen. Greene, a part of it to the troops under the comnand
of Gen. Gates, a part of it probably to the troops under Gen. (Cadwallader)
,
and a part of it Gen. V/ashington retained \dth the troops under his
immediate ccrj::and. He remained with troops under Gen. Washington's
inmediats ccrmand, and he thinks the regiment to v/hich he was attached
v;as corsnndcd by Col. Clifford, to whose regiment a I'la j . Talbot belonged,
but he docs not remember whether he was first or second major. He does not
remember the number of Col. Clifford's regiment, nor does he remember
the Colonel's given name, nor the given name of Ikj . Talbot. He thinks
James Starling ^.-as at this time his Captain, and that his Lieutenant's
name j-.'as Dlccmfield, but his given name is not x^eiaciaoered . Shortly after
this division i.'as made of the black regiment, he thinks the battle of
Trenton took place, and he well remembers he was in that engagement. He
has a distinct recollection that on the night of the 25th of December
after he entered the service as a regular soldier, which would be Decem-ber,
1776, if it was that year he enlisted, and he thinks it was Gen.
V/ashingtcn who crossed hJ.s troops over the Delavnre about nine miles
above Trentcn and marched upon the enemy and attacked them by surprise.
A part of the /jnerican forces, he thinks, were commanded by Generals
Ewing and Cad^.'allader, the foi^mer of v;hom belonged to the Virginia troops.
The forces under their command he thinks v;ere to cross the Delaware
higher up than the point at v/hich declarent crossed with General V/ashington,
and were to attack the left wing of the enemy, but he well remembers he
39
did not croG3 over, vihich he thinlco vras ouing to the ice, for it was vd.th
extreme difficulty that Gen. V.'achington got his troops over on accoiint
of the ice and the cxtrcne cold v;cathor. Cn account of Generals Ewing and
Cadv;allader failing to cross the river as hzd been previously arranged, we
uere corbelled to cake the attack \;lth such forces alone as crossed over
i-'ith Gon. IJachington. The cnezr;.! co little c;:pecting an attack from us,
&#8226;jcre thrcv.'n into great confusion, and \j3 obtained a coraplete victory over
them, killing many of them and taking ccvcral hundred prisoners, v;ho wore
principally Hessians. V/e also took a largo amoimt of milit^rj- stores, a
number of pieces of cannon, and a great many small arms. He thinks the
greater portion of the cneny's forces were killed or taken pri'soner. He
thinks there xras a Colonel commanding in the Hessian troops k' lied, but
he does not remember his name. There v;ere but few on the side of the
Americans killed and not many wounded; amongst the wounded ho thinks
there was a Captain ifeshington, remembered from his being of the same
name as his General VJashington. After this engagement he steles he
marched back across the Delaware \fith. the prisoners and captu- ed stores.
The prisoners, he thinks, were conducted to Philadelphia. In a few days,
however, he returned v/ith Gen. Washington to Trenton. They h?d not been
long in pocsecsion of Trenton when the British forces collected and
marched tovrard Trenton for the purpose of giving battle; in feet, they
had actually commenced firing on the American troops in the evening and
considerable cannonading took place between the two armies. 'Hhe firing
from our artillery somewhat checked their advance upon us, and night
coming on, they halted on the opposite side of a creek from us and
ceased firing. It was supposed that they intended making a general
attack upon us the next morning. We were ordered to light fires along
our lines in our front for the purpose, as declarent afterward discovered,
of deceiving the enemy. However, instead of remaining at the fires, we
AO
were inarched off with all possible expedition toward Princeton, where some
regiments of the British troops were quartered. We reached there very-early
the next morning and made a vigorous attack upon them. Declarent
has a perfect recollection of an occurance which took place during this
engagement v/hich will never be effaced from his memory. A part of our
troops were driven back by the British and were thrown into much confu-sion.
Gen, Washington, perceiving it, seized a standard and rushed in
front of our troops and dashed several paces ahead toward the enemy,
exclaiming "Cone on boys," or some such expression. His example had
the desired effect of rallying our troops, and they followed the com-mander
v/ith renev/ed ardour. While Gen. Washington was betv/een the two
armies, at least one round was fired on each side, and he remained un-touched.
Soon after this occurrence the British troops gave way and
retreated into some public bioildings. VJo pursued them and kept up such
a play of artillery upon them, that all those who had taken refuge were
compelled to surrender to us. In this engagement the British were com-pletely
routed and defeated. Many of them were killed and wovmded and
a great number taken prisoner. The loss on the American side, he thinks,
was inconsiderable. He remembers that General Mucerj who he believes
belonged to the Virginia troops was severely wounded in this engagement,
and thinks he died shortly of his wounds.
After the battle at Princeton, we marched to Morristown and took
up vrinter quarters. There we remained until some time in the spring.
From Morristovm, he marched to Middlebrook; from there to Peek's-Kill
where some fortifications were erected. From this point he marched toward
the Delav;are River; and the army was occupied for several weeks in ad-vancing
and receding, marching and counterimrching, sometimes toward
Philadelphia and then toward the Delaware. This lasted for several
weeks until the battle finally ensued at Brandywine. This engagement
^1
coicnenced early in the morning, the attack being brought on by the
British who ucre under the command of Gen. Cornwallis. They crossed the
creek about a mile above our forces and made an attack upon our rear.
V/e were about the same time attacked in front by a British General
v/hose name is now not remembered. The American troops were compelled
to retreat v/ith great loss. He thinlcs they retreated towards Chester,
and v/ore purcucd a considerable distance by the enerqy. He v/ell remem-bers
seeing Gen. Lafayette in this engagement and seeing him receive a
i/ound, v.'hich he thinks \.'as in his right leg. He also remembers that
there was another American General wounded, but he has forgotten his
name. He thirds Gen. Lincoln was in the battle. T\io or three weeks
after the battle of Brandywine, Gen, Washington, having received a
considercble reinforcement from Virginia, marched on Germantovm and
made an attack upon the British stationed there. The attack was made
early in the norning, and, from the sudden and unejqpected character,
the British forces were throvm into great disorder. It being a cloudy
foggy morning, it was difficult for our troops to keep in regular order,
which caused considerable confusion amongst us. Taking advantage of this,
the encry rallied from the confusion into v;hich they had at first been
throvm and drove back our troops. V/e v;ere, at length, compelled to re-treat
\ath great loss. In this engagement an American General&#8212;Nash
&#8212;
v.-as Icilled. After recovering from the defeat, we marched to a place
called l.Tiite Ilash, v/here we remained sometime in expection of an attack
from the British, t;ho had taken a position not far distant from us.
They, however, withdrew vdthout malting an attack, and we v;ere marched to
Valley Forge, i:here we took up winter qxjarters.
^
Declarent was at the battle of Yorkto;m. '.-/hen he reached there,
Lafayette had been engaged in some severe fighting with the enemy.
The principal fighting, however, after we reached the place v;as v;ith
the artillery, with an almost constant cannonading kept up. He well
remembers the position of the. French fleet on the occasion, which had
taken a stand in the Potomac River to prevent Cornvrallis from being
reinforced by the British troops under the command of Gen. Henry Clinton.
He remembers that about two days before the surrender, fourteen of the
British soldiers deserted and came into the American encampment and
surrendered themselves, and that from them, we received a good bit of
information about the affairs in the enemy's camp. The surrender, he thinks,
was on the 18th of October, 1781. He has a most perfect recollection of
uhe circiimstances v;hich occured when Cornwallis surrended up his sword,
for he was present and saw this transaction. Cornwallis offe ed his
sword to Gen. V/ashington, who stepped back and declined taking it.
General Lincoln, who he thinks had been previously agreed should receive
it, stepped forvrard and accepted it from him. Declarent remained at
lorktovm several weeks after the surrender. He thinks he marched to
Winchester, Virginia with the British prisoners, and that Cornwallis
was in company. After he retiu-ned to Yorktown from Winchester, he
remained there five or six days, at the end of which time, he was dis-charged
from the service. He received a writien discharge from Capt.
Edgar, by whom his company had been commanded for some time. His former
captain had been compelled to retire from the service on account of bad
health, v.'hen Captain Edgar succeeded to the command. He lost his dis-charge
a few years after the war was over, he thinks, on the eastern
part of the Bahama Islands, where he was shipwi^ecked while on a voyage
in a merchantman bound from New York to Teneriff on a trading expedition.
43
It is impossible for declarent to remember every place through which
he marched during a service of five or six years, or to detail all the
occurrences id.th which he met during that time and in which he acted a
part. He can only pretend to state important transactions and occurrences
to which his attention was particularly directed by some peculiar cir-ciunstance
upon vfhich the mind vrauld then fasten, so as not to let escape
the recollection of the event.
Declarent enlisted in Providence, Rhode Island, where he at that
time resided. He was born at Pequanock, three miles east of Fairfield,
Connecticut.
He has never received a pension for his services, and he hereby
relinquishes every claim whatever to a pension or annuity except the
present, and he declares his name is not on the pension roll of the
agency of any state.
Sworn to subscribed this day and year aforesaid.
J. R. Laughlin, Clerk His X mark (Peter Jennings)
And the said court do hereby declare their opinion that the above
named applicant vras a revolutionary soldier, and had served as he states.
H. Trott, J. C. Mitchell, V. D. Cowan
I, John R. Laughlin, Clerk of the Court of Pleas and Quarter Sessions
of Rutherford County, Tennessee, do hereby certify that the foregoing
contains the original preceedings of the said coiirt, in the matter of
the application of Peter Jennings for a pension.
In testimony whereof, I have hereunto set my hand and seal of office,
this 23rd day of August 1832.
John R. Laughlin, Clerk
u^
The attesting affidavits supporting the claim of Peter Jennings, which was
granted include the interesting fact that Jennings was recognized by Lafayette,
State of Tennessee
Rutherford County
On the eighth day of September 1832, personally appeared before me,
William Gilliam, as acting Justice of the Peace for the County of Ruth-erford
and State of Tennessee, Elijah Smith, aged seventy-seven years
and twenty days, a resident of said Rutherford County, who, having first
dvily sworn according to law, doth upon his oath, say that he was a
soldier of the Revolutionary War, that in the winter of 1777 when the
American troops \fere quartered at Valley Forge, he was an assistant
forage master under one Cochlerow, and that he knew a man of colour who
belonged to the New England troops, and was in the artillery.
He is acquainted \dth Peter Jennings, a man of colour who now re-sides
in Rutherford County aforesaid, and he believes him to be the man
he knew at Valley Forge. He does not remember him by name so as to
state him to be the same man, but from his size and general appearance,
so far as he can remember, as it would correspond at so distant a period.
He believes him to be the same, and on frequent conversations with him
in relation to facts and circumstances which occiired then, which said
Jennings remembers, and which he is confident he could not have known
had he not been there, and especially from his narration of a man being
hung there, he is confident he is the same man, whom he then knew.
Elijah Smith
Subscribed and sworn to before me
W. M. Gilliam, J. P.
Murfreesboro, August 13th, 1828
K'^
Honorable Richard Rush
Sir, I herewith endorse you the petition of Peter Jennings, praying
for his dues as a Revolutionary soldier. The declaration set forth by
him is done from memory alone, and which he relates with freedom nnd
confidence.
The general opinion here is that he served as a soldier in the
Revolution, which opinion was strengthened by his being recognized by ^
Gen. LaFayette in Nashville two years ago,
I believe the evidence set forth here combining partly with the
evidence now in possession will be satisfactory. If not, please say
v;hat other evidence is necessary.
Hoping to have the pleasure of hearing from you soon,
I am Respectfully,
William T, Christy
A record by Charles Ready certifies that Jennings died Jan. 22, 184.2.
The pension records indicate that during the last ten years of his life,
he received a pension from the United States Government.
Mike West, editor of Accent Magazine , a supplement of the Sunday
Daily News Journal , uncovered a tombstone in the old City Cemetery bearing
the name of Peter Jennings, identified as a Revolutionary War Soldier.
The modest oval stone is inscribed with a cross and was apparently erected
by one of the patriotic societies some years after Jennings ' death.
</dc:description>
<dc:description>Tells the story of Peter Jennings, a free African American baker in Rutherford County who served in the Revolutionary War; includes information on his request for a veteran's pension</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.); United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1783</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African-American history; veterans</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>19 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-16</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication10ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/99</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>