<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Jerry Sneak</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Pittard, Homer</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 32</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1955; 1989</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>19th century;</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Foreword
The following article, "Jerry Sneak", from the play,
"The Mayor of Garrat",was written by Homer Pittard in 1955-
It is a dramatic account of a presentation given by James
K. Polk while he was a student at Bradley Academy.
The article also contains information about Samuel Black,
Headmaster of Bradley Academy at the time that Polk was
enrolled there as a student. There are also references to
Dr. Robert Henderson, a friend of the Polk family and a member
of the Bradley Academy faculty. It is thought that Dr. Henderson
who came over from Columbia, Tennessee to teach at the Academy
may have influenced James Polk to come there as a student.
The article is included in this publication with the per-mission
of Mabel Pittard, wife of the former Dr. Homer Pittard
who was a member of the Rutherford County Historical Society
for many years.
90
"Jerry Sneak"
There was the smell of autumn in the air. The stars were
spilled out over the heavens like a great natural extravaganza
serving as a colossal backdrop for the high-riding full moon.
The one story log courthouse lay in the center of the darkened
square and not a single light burned in the cluster of shops.
The village itself lay in a virtual blanket of darkness. The
only perceptible living thing was an old cow sloshing aimlessly
across the commons and pausing in the ooze to drink from the
puddles.
The village streets that fanned out from the square were
deserted with a completeness that only a Goldsmith could have
described. It was October k, 1815 . There were ominous rumblings
in the far north. The British were laying waste the Capital
City. Dolly Madison had ripped the portraits form the White
House frames, snatched up the White House silver, and hied to
parts unknown. But here in Murfreesborough, with the baffles
of hundreds of miles; almost impassable roads, and only an
occasional word from the outside world brought by a flatboat
docking at nearby Jeffeson, life was serene and war remote.
Too, on this particular night Professor Black's closing exercises
were being held at Bradley Academy. These occasions were rare
ones, and the townspeople hurried through their chores and
closed their shops early in order to be among those present
at the Academy. It was said that the plaintive lowings of
91
of unfed and unmilked cows were indications as valid as any
that it was examination night at the Academy. The people
turned out enmasse.
Out Academy Street, south and beyond the brick Presby-terian
Church, near the village limits, stood Bradley Academy.
It was a spacious log building, and rays from the various oil
lamps cut the night. Hitched to the side of the structure and
to the nearby cedars were horses of every description and
color. Some fine whites were standing for tasseled carriages,
and they were wrapped in blankets against the cool October
breezes. Others, singly, were without saddles, and the callouses
on their bellies and hocks betrayed their acquaintance with
the plow.
Inside, every rough-hewn bench was filled as was all avail-able
standing space on three sides of the room. The only island
was a small, raised platform to the front. Pushed to the side
was the teacher's high podium where reposed two scrubbed and
starched young children.
In the audience near the front of the room were Professor
Samuel P. Black, the venerable scholar and rector, and Dr.
Robert Henderson who also taught at the Academy. Nearby sat
Mr. and Mrs. Samuel Polk, parents of James K.Also, among those
present were Mr. and Mrs. Joel Childress with Susan and Sarah,
as well as Samuel Laughlin, a close friend of James K. Polk.
92
Prefatory to each scholar's appearance from behind the
draperies to the side of the rostrum, Professor Black would
rise and present a brief, dignified, and deferential- summary
of the student's activities and general progress. The student,
his character and abilities having been oratorically embellished
to the point of embarrassment, would then emerge from his pro-tective
niche behind the curtains. He would stride to the center
of the stage to a prescribed spot marked by a charcoal "X" on
the floor. After gaining some- semblance of equilibrium, he
would embark on his piece for the evening. It might be a con-fident
Mark Anthony at the bier of a fallen Caesar or a
bristling Horatius at the bridge. VJhatever the choice, the
classic would be brought to full flower.
Professor Black, with a flair for showmanship, always re-served
the best for the last. On this occasion, October 4,
1814, as the time for the last examination came, the headmaster
arose and made his introduction. It was an extended presentation
and one that fully extolled the highest virtues of the prize
pupil
There was a stir in the audience as Jim Polk's name was
called. A reproving glance from Mrs. Childress stifled the
giggle from her oldest daughter. Then as Jim made his appear-ance
there was a wave of laughter. Here was the characterization
of Jerry Sneak from the play, "The Mayor of Garrat", a farce
by old Samuel Foote. Jim Polk was in ragged, patched regalia,
93
with a dunce cap perched atop his head. Polk stepped near
the front of the stage, rolled his eyes, and with a comical
grimace, he began the lines to an imaginary shrewish mate:
"Yes, and you shan't think to hector and domineer
over me as you have done; for I'll go to the club
when I please, and stay out as late as I list, and
row in a boat to Putney on Sunday, and visit my
friends at Vitsontide, and keep the key to the till
From this Polk went on to other selections, accompanying
his presentations with pantomine and gestures appropriate
to each new character he addressed. That night Jerry Sneak
came to life, and the ovation he received at the conclusion ^
fully justified Professor Black's faith in him.
There was the usual round of congratulations, hand--
clasping, and goodbyes. Bradley Academy had closed its
session, and the spectators were filing out into the night.
As Professor Black secured the windows and turned down the
lights, he reflected on the past months. He was certain that
that there were those who sat at his feet who were destined
for greatness. Soon the village lights were burning again.
The carriages were in their houses and the horses in their
stables or barn lots. Soon the lights were turned low again,
and Murfreesborough slept. An old cow leaned against the
rough logs of the Courthouse and settled to the ground for
the night. Just above her was the window of the town clerk's
office.
94
The next morning James Polk with his father and mother
visited Professor Black and before leaving received this
letter of proficiency from the headmaster. It read:
"I hereby certify that James K. Polk has been a student
under my direction for nine months preceding the date
hereof, and that his proficiency in his studies and
unexceptionable conduct entitles him to the attention
and patronage of all lovers of literary merit or moral
worth. "
^ T, T^-i 1 Sam P. Black
Rector of Murfreesborough
5 th October 1815 Academy
Several years later this letter found its way into the
archives of the Tennessee Historical Society. Young Polk on
the strength of this appraising transcript entered the
sophomore class at the University of North Carolina and
was graduated with honors three years later.
Why did James K. Polk come to Murfreesborough? Some
have said that it was an affair of the heart since his
future wife, Sarah Childress, was a resident of that village.
This seems improbable for Sarah was only ten years of age at
the time and Polk was seventeen. Their paths crossed only on
occasion. Prof. Black/did contract his tutorial services for
the two Childress .girls, Sarah and Susan. These sessions took
place after the Academy hours were over. Mr. Childress, a
well-to-do tavern keeper and merchant, was anxious that his
children have more than the rudiments offered in the common
school.
95
The best explanation seems to be that concerned with
the person of Dr. Robert Henderson. Dr. Henderson was at the
time of Polk's youth a prominent clergyman in Maury County.
His services as a private tutor were engaged by Samuel Polk
for his son James who was in poor health, recovering from a
very serious gallstone operation. When Dr. Henderson came to
Murfreesborough to found the First Presbyterian Church and to
teach at Bradley Academy, young Polk soon followed. Henderson's
History of Murfreesboro cites several instances of the Presby-terian
leader's activities in the affairs of the County. At one
place he is recorded as having made an impassioned speech before
a committee delegated with the task of choosing a seat for '
Rutherford County. On another occasion he preached a funeral
sermon at a public hanging. Also, he officiated at the wedding
of James K. Polk and Sarah Childress. Doubtless, Dr. Henderson
exerted a strong influence on Polk's early years, but it was
Samuel P. Black whose inspiration and depth of scholarly attain-ment
kindled the fires of ambition in the mind of the young
scholar.
Samuel Pitts Black included not only James K. Polk among
his successful students but also John Bell, Lunsford Yandell,
Governor of Campbell of Virginia, and several other students
who later became distinguished men. According to a manuscript
entitled "Reminiscences" left to the late Dr. Samuel Wilson of
Nashville by his father, Thomas B. Wilson, Professor Black was
96
born in Guilford County, North Carolina about 1758. The
manuscript infers that Black fought in the Revolutionary
War and was given a grant of land for his services. His
descendants now living in Rutherford County aver that this
grant was the basis of the vast acreage near Black's Cross-roads,
now Walter Hill. It has been recorded that Black at
the age of 19 opened a classical school near Abbingdon,
Virginia. He held a professorship at the University of
Georgia for a brief period and came to Nashville in 1798.
There he taught at Cumberland College. Shortly thereafter,
he went to Sumner County and established a school near the
home of Colonel Elmore Douglas, on Station Camp Creek, and
called it Montpelier Academy.
In 1805, according to the manuscript, he married Mrs.
Fannie Sanders, a young widow who had one child, a son
named Alexander who died in infancy. Fannie was the daughter
of Lunsford Pitts of Dixon Springs, Tennessee. Soon after
his marriage, Black went into merchandizing, building flat
boats, and shipping produce to New Orleans. Failing in this
venture. Black moved to Rutherford County in 1810. Shortly
afterwards, Bradley Academy was opened and Professor Black
was to be at its helm for 27 years.
Information concerning courses of study, faculty members,
and rostfirs of students is fragmentary. Th e Nashvill e Whig
97
of October 25, 181^ carried a very interesting notice of the
opening session of the Academy. It read:
"Murfreesborough Academy will commence next April 1,
1815 near Murfreesborough under the direction of Mr.
Samuel Black. Subjects to be taught are: English Grammar,
the Latin and Greek languages,, Arithmetic, the most
useful branches of mathematics. Belles-letters, Logic,
and such other useful and ornamental branches of Liter-ature.
Students may board either in or out of town with
genteel families at reasonable terms. Trustees pledge
every care will be taken with morals. Trustees&#8212; Edmond
Jones, Frederick Barfield, William Lytle, Jonathan
Estill, Joel Childress."
That Professor Black was an exceptional schoolmaster
is attested to by many of the present-day residents of
Rutherford County. Confirmations, untinctured by time,
have come down through the years to these residents. Several
years ago, Mrs. John Woodfin, a great-great- grandaughter of
Professor Black received as a gift a massive cherry press,
purported to have been the property of Samuel Black. In it
were found several of his books. Included were: Johnson's
The Rambler , Dr. Blair's Lectures on Rhetoric , Beatlie's
Elements of Moral Science , Plutarch's Lives, Comstock's
Chemistry , Works of John Bunyan , and Dotta's History of the
War of the Independence.
Professor Black died in I838. His remains lie in the
Black Cemetery on the Lebanon Road near the Veteran's Hos-pital.
The cemetery is now abandoned and overgrown with
trees and underbrush. Two box-like tombs cover the final
resting place of his ashes and those of his consort, Fannie.
98
On a clear day when the sun is high in the heavens,
one can climb the iron picket fence, stand atop the
weathered marble, and see the Courthouse in the distance.
Over beyond just a ways, at a log schoolhouse one hundred
and forty years ago this October (1955). Jerry Sneak
received the blessings of Professor Black and went on
to fame and renown.</dc:description>
<dc:description>An article written as part of the play "The Mayor of Garrat," dramatizing a presentation given by James K. Polk as a student at Bradley Academy</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Polk, James K.; Bradley Academy</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro;</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>19 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-01-26</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication32ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/151</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>