<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Rutherford County Historical Society publication no. 25: Legends and stories of Civil War Rutherford County</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Pittard, Homer Peyton</dc:creator>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>August 1940</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Publication No. 25
Captain Bromfield L. Ridey
SUMMER 1985
Murfreesboro, Tennessee 37133-0906
Cover Photo:
Captain Bromfield L. Ridley
member Lt. General A. P. Stewart's Staff
Army of Tennessee
Ridley was born in Rutherford County,
Tennessee near the Jefferson Community
Ridley was the author of:
Journal of B, L. Ridley
Lt. General A. P. Stewart's Staff
C.S.A .
Battles and Sketches
Army of Tennessee
1861-1865
Ridley's Journal was published in 1906
V. 15
RUTHERFORD COUNTY HISTORICAL SOCIETY
PUBLICATION NO. 25
Published by the
RUTHERFORD COUNTY HISTORICAL SOCIETY
OFFICERS
President ... Mrs. Homer Pittard
Vice President Mr. Steve Brown
Recording Secretary Mrs. Cathy Goode
Corresponding Secretary Mrs. Susan Daniel
Publication Secretary Mr. Walter Hoover
Treasurer Mrs. Kelly Ray
DIRECTORS Mrs. Lalia Lester
Mr. Jerry Gaither
Mrs. Judy Lee Green
Publication No. 25 (Limited Edition'--650 copies) is
distributed to members of the Society. The annual member-ship
is $10 (family&#8212;$11), which includes the regular pub-lication
and the monthly NEWSLETTER to all members.
Additional copies of Publication No. 25 may be obtained at
$5 per copy.
All correspondence concerning additional copies,
contributions to future issues, and membership should be
addressed to: Rutherford County Historical Society
P. O. Box 906
Murfreesboro, TN 37133-0906
8&#171;-0:iS34
FOR SALE
THE FOLLOWING PUBLICATIONS ARE FOR SALE BY:
The Rutherford County Historical Society
P.O. Box 906
Murfreesboro, Tennessee 37130
PUBLICATIONS 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 8, and 9 are out of print.
PUBLICATION 7: Hopewell Church, Petition by Cornelius Sanders'
for Rev. War Pension - - - $3.50 + $1.00 postage
PUBLICATION 10: 1864 Diary, Peter Jennings, Henderson Yoakum, Early
Methodist Church, and Overall
family $3.50 + $1.00 postage
PUBLICATION 11: State Capitol, Ben Mc Culloch, Petition of Michael
Lorance, Country Store, and Soule College
$3.50 + $1.00 postage
PUBLICATION 12: Out of Print
PUBLICATION 13: Tennessee College, Coleman Scouts, New Monument in Old
City Cemetery and James Boles' Revolutionary War
Pension - $3.50 + $1.00 postage
PUBLICATION 14: Murfreesboro Presbyterian Church, Kirks and Montgomerys,
Russell Home, John Lytle and John M. Leak's Revolution-ary
War Pension --------- $3.50 + $1.00 postage
PUBLICATION 15: John W. Childress' home (1847), Whigs in Rutherford
County, 1835-1845 $3.50 + $1.00 postage
PUBLICATION 16: Hart, Childress, Miles, Fosterville, Cherry Shade,
William Cocke - $3.50 + $1.00 postage
PUBLICATION 17: Jefferson 1803-1813, Will Abstracts (1803-1814),
Old City Cemetery $3.50 + $1.00 postage
PUBLICATION 18: Railroad Stations in Rutherford County, Rion Family
Stones River $3.50 + $1.00 postage
PUBLICATION 19: Footprints ... at Smyrna, V.A. Medical Center, Manson
Family, Jenkins' Homes, Will Abstracts (Record Books 3 &amp;
4), Rutherford Co. Hist. Society, Early News, Bio. Sketch
from Macon Co., 111., 1981 in Rutherford County - &#8212;
$3.50 + $1.00 postage
PUBLICATION 20: Roads and Turnpikes of Rutherford Co. (includes many
Rutherford Co. names) $5.00 + $1.00 postage
Digitized by the Internet Archive
in 2010 with funding from
Lyrasis IVIembers and Sloan Foundation
http://www.archive.org/details/publication25ruth
FOR SALE
PUBLICATION 21: Jefferson Springs Resort, Lascassas Baptist Church,
John Price Buchanan, Will Abstracts, 1836 Tax Records
of 25th District $5.00 + $1.00 postage
PUBLICATION 22: Ft. Rosecrans, Big Springs, East Main Church of Christ
Tax Record District 23 &amp; 24, for 1836, 1837, and 1849
Mathias Hoover $5.00 + $1.00 postage
PUBLICATION 23: Harding House, Milton Country Stores in Jefferson area,
Will Abstracts book 7, Tax Record of District 15 &amp; 16
for 1836, 1837, and 1849 $5.00 + $1.00 postage
PUBLICATION 24: History of Medicine in Rutherford Co.. .$6.00 + $1.00 postage
History of Westbrook - Williams and Smotherman of Rutherford Co. with
fustories of Midland, Oak Grove School and Old Leb Church
$12.00 + $2.00 postage
History of Versailles (southwestern Rutherford Co.) in hard cover, (some
families included are: Adcock, Brown, Burns, Carlton, Covington,
Crick, Dyer, Farris, Garrett, Gillespie, Hendrix, Ivey, Jackson,
Jones, Lamb, Lawrence, Leathers, Lowe, Manier, Maxwell, Mc Gee,
Morris, Nance, Pinkerton, Opoe, Powers, Puckett, Ray, Ralston, Rice,
Rutledge, Sharver, Smotherman, Tabor, Taylor, Whitehead, Williams
Windrow, Winsett) $9.00 + $2.00 postage
History of Rutherford County by C.C. Sims (pub. 1947) Reprint - -
$12.00 + $2.00 postage
1840 Rutherford County Census with Index $5.00 + $1.00 postage
Deed Abstracts of Rutherford County 1803-1810 $10.00 + $1.00 postage
GRIFFITH : Illustrated by-centennial publication .... $2.00 + $1.00 postAGE
CEMETERY RECORDS OF RUTHERFORD COUNTY :
Vol. 1 Northwestern third of county and part of Wilson and Davidson
counties, 256 cemeteries with index and maps $10.00 + $1.00 postage
Vol. 2 Eastern third of Rutherford and the western part of Cannon Co.,
241 cemeteries with index maps $10.00 + $1.00 postage
Vol. 3 Southwestern third of Rutherford Co., 193 cemeteries with
index and maps $10.00 + $1.00 postage
Available from: William W. Walkup, 202 Ridley Street, Smyrna, TN 37167
1878 Rutherford County Map, shows land owners $3.50 + $1.00 postage
Avai lable from : Mrs. R.A. Ragland, P.O. Box 544, Murfreesboro, TN 37130
Marriage Record of Rutherford Co. 1851-1872 $10.00 + $1.00 postage
Note Cards : Box of twelve with six different designs of covers for our
puBTTcations by Jim Matheny $3.00 + 500 postage
LEGENDS AND STORIES OF CIVIL WAR
RUTHERFORD COUNTY
by
Homer Peyton Pittard
Master of Arts' Thesis
George Peabody College for Teachers
August 1940
TABLE OF CONTENTS
Page
ILLUSTRATIONS V
Chapter
I. THE CIVIL WAR IN RUTHERFORD COUNTY 1
The Battle of Stone's River 4
Joe Wheeler at Lavergne 14
Rosecrans' Post Battle Headquarters .... _16
Brickhouse Hospital 17
Fort Transit 18
Forrest's Birthday Party 19
II. DEWITT SMITH JOBE 29
The Jobe Family 29
Dewitt S. Jobe's Military Career 38
The Jobe House , 49
The Old Hearse Road ^ . . . . 51
The Family Burying Ground 52
III. OTHER PATRIOTS OF RUTHERFORD COUNTY 54
Dee Smith 54
John Bowman 59
Sam Davis 60
IV. LEGENDS AND STORIES OF CIVIL WAR
RUTHERFORD COUNTY 79
TABLE OF CONTENTS (continued)
Page
Mollie Nelson 79
Mary Dean Arnold 83
Grandma and the Yankee 85
William Arnold &#8226; &#8226; &#8226; 87
Two Letters 89
Munro Bond on a Furlough 92
Munro Bond and Professor Pennington ... 95
Missing at Murfreesboro 95
General Thomas Benton Smith 99
Sam Winston and Major Childress 100
The Unknown Soldier 102
A Rendezvous in Spence Hotel 105
Rousseau or a Rabbit 105
A Practical Camp Joke . . . 106
Bragg and His Private 107
Life a Drag 108
A Rebel "Pow-wow" Denied 108
Girls' Wit 109
A Soldier Tells of the Battle 109
A Dodge for a Pass 110
A Brave Boy in Battle Ill
TABLE OF CONTENTS (continued)
Page
Forrest and a Lady 112
A Civil War Wedding 113
An Escape 114
CONCLUSION 116
BIBLIOGRAPHY 118
INDEX 121
Wheelea&#187;s Raic
'fersoi
\^
m'-y
^
Irevllle
^
rale
'/
A Map of
RUTHERFORD COUTITY
in Civil TISiT Times
ILLUSTRATIONS
Page
Map of the Battle of Stone's River ... 5
Dewitt Smith Jobe 30
Squire Elihu C. Jobe 32
Kate Jobe 34
Price Jobe 35
Martha Ann Jobe Beasley and Husband ... 37
Ben Jobe 42
Where Dewitt Jobe Was Born 50
Where Dewitt Jobe Was Buried 50
ACKNOWLEDGMENTS
Acknowledgments are made to the relatives of Dewitt
Smith Jobe for their kindness and help; to Mrs. J.T.
Mc Carty of Abilene, Texas, for the use of the treasured
pictures of the Jobe family; to Mr. W.S. Beasley of Lancaster,
Texas, for the use of "A Tribute to the Dead"; to the William
Lytle Chapter of the United Daughters of the Confederacy, and
to Miss Jeanette King of Murfreesboro, Tennessee , for the use
of two scrap books, and to those who have aided in the collection
of the material.
CHAPTER I
THE CIVIL WAR IN RUTHERFORD COUNTY
Geographically, Rutherford County is located in the
exact center of the state of Tennessee. It is a fact that
the center of the state is less than two miles from the
Rutherford County courthouse, and this center is a flat rock
about three acres in extent, practically bare of vegetation
of any character. This spot was once a popular picnic
ground because of its close proximity to town, and its
level spaciousness.
The county has an area of about 580 square miles, and
has about 6,000 farms with an average of seventy acres to
the farm. The county is practically encircled by a chain of
foothills, ranging from an altitude of 570 feet to 1,352
feet above sea level.
Rutherford County was organized by an Act of the
General Assembly then in session at Knoxville, on October 25,
1803, but the organization was not complete until January 3,
1804. The territory now comprising the county was originally
a part of Davidson County. At that time the state had
only three members of the Lower House of Congress, the dis-tricts
being known as the Washington, the Hamilton, and the
Mero district, this county being in the last named.
The county was named in honor of General Griffith
Rutherford, a Revolutionary officer who had been active
in the Indian wars in this section of the country. He
commanded a force of frontiersmen who served in small
protective groups against forays of bands of Indian
warriors
.
Stone's River, upon whose banks and in whose vicinity
was fought one of the bloodiest battles of the Civil War,
was discovered by Uriah Stone in 1776. He explored it
as far as Jefferson.
A donation of sixty acres in the center of the county,
north of "Murfree Spring Branch," by William Lytle in 1811
resulted in the organization of the present county seat,
Murf reesboro. The selection of this spot came after a pro-longed
debate and cross-firing between various sections of
the county. Today, Murf reesboro, according to the 1940
census, has a population of 9,513. It is ideally located
for the seat of government, lying practically in equal
radius from all county extremities. Good roads radiate from
this hub, making the center a short drive from any section.
Today, Murfreesboro is the prototype of other small
southern towns. There is the square, the historic court-house,
and the Confederate Monument. There are the long
tree-canopied streets stretching out and rarifying in the
scattered suburbs. There is the Main Street, with its
doughty mansions of Civil War days, where "Room and Board"
signs now appear unexpectedly and Neon Tourist Homes smack
of anachronism in the bosom of aristocracy. Here, once,
Bedford Forrest charged up the sleeping avenue at the head
of a yelling cavalry to surprise a Yankee garrison.
Murfreesboro is truly pro-southern, and even today when so
much water has passed over the dam, the culture of ante-bellum
and rebellion days still remains like a poignant
dream in the minds of the people who have heard and have
seen.
Murfreesboro with its surronding undulating plain
served as a remarkably well-chosen setting for the tragedy
of Rosecrans and Bragg enacted on December 30, 31, 1862,
and January 1, 1963.
The official report of any battle by a military tech-nician
is often devoid of any color or picturesqueness
.
Military terminology is bereft of life except as it deals
with killed and wounded and number engaged. It is not the
purpose here, primarily, to give an official report of the
Battle of Stone's River, often spoken of as the Battle of
Murfreesboro. Nor, does this present report necessarily
vouch for the historical, official authenticity of any-thing
herein given. The material here gathered merely
relates the story of events as this has been given by
veterans and other individuals who, in 1940, assume to
know. There are also interspersed a few quotations from
published sources that may aid in vivifying the course of
events
.
The Battle of Stone's River
The opposing generals of this battle were General
Braxton Bragg of the Army of Tennessee, Confederate, and
General William S. Rosecrans of the Army of the Cumberland,
Union. Both had had their baptism of fire, and had proved
themselves capable and efficient commanders. They had not
before met each other on the field, and each went into the
battle with eagerness and expectation of success.
The Confederate Army of Tennessee, after retreating
from Kentucky, had been reorganized and heavily reinforced
at Murf reesboro, Tennessee. It was well established that
this town occupied a strategic position in the control of
Middle Tennessee and ultimately a possibility of controlling
Tennessee in its entirety. States to the north, also, would
be vulnerable to a Confederate attack if the strong position
at Murf reesboro were held by Bragg. Murf reesboro was a key
to East Tennessee where Union sympathizers were clamoring
for deliverance. It was no wonder that Rosecrans wished to
dislodge the well-ensconced command at Murf reesboro.
Besides, good roads radiated in every direction and the
Louisville and Nashville Railroad, a vital artery, bisected
the position. A control of the railroad would mean control
of certain supplies and communications. Middle Tennessee
had not as yet suffered from the ravages of war, conse-quently
the surrounding country afforded a wealth of
untouched supplies. It is said that on December 13, 1862,
the President of the Confederacy, Jefferson Davis, visited
the Army at Murfreesboro and remained with it several days.
It is probable that he realized the importance of the
position at that town. A success here for the Southern
Cause would make possible a new attempt to annex Kentucky
to the Confederacy.
At the close of the Kentucky campaign in the fall of
1862, the Union Army of the Cumberland was rapidly con-centrated
at Nashville, thirty-two miles from Mufreesboro.
Rosecrans had relieved Buell from the command. Nashville
was a logical military base for an operation against
Chattanooga, which was acknowledged to be one of the most
important positions in the Confederacy and a gateway to
East Tennessee and Georgia. Realizing the importance of
the control of Murfreesboro, General Rosecrans on
December 26, 1862 began a movement toward that town.
Bragg was cognizant at all times of his enemy's
movements, and he dispatched cavalry units under Joe
Wheeler and John Morgan to harass the advance. By the
evening of December 29 the Federal Army had reached the
northern outskirts of Murf reesboro. After a number of
skirmishes with the Confererate cavalry, they assumed a
position stretching westward from Stone's River, at
McFadden's Ford, to the banks of Overall Creek.
Bragg 's strong defensive position presented an
extended line almost parallel with Stone's River, which ran
in a northeasterly direction in front of the town of
Murf reesboro. Bragg had divided his army into two corps.
One of these was commanded by Lieutenant-General Leonidas
Polk, who had the name of being Bragg's pet aversion. Polk's
corps formed the left wing, and the right wing was under the
command of Lieutenant-General William J. Hardee. Beginning
with the left wing and transversing to the right wing were
divisions under the following commands: McGowan, Cleburne,
Cheatham, Withers, and Breckenridge. The latter was on
the east side of the river.
Approximately one hundred yards away, within shouting
distance, were the Federals, in lines almost parallel to the
Confederates. Rosecrans, too, had divided his army into
right and left wings, for convenience designated as corps.
The right wing was under the command of Major-General
McHowell McCook, and the left wing was under the command
of Major-General Thomas L. Crittenden.
In war-council that evening the two opposing generals
planned their attack. Bragg instructed his command to begin
hostilities at daylight the following morning, his left
wing under Cleburne to attack Johnson's division under
McCook. Cleburne was then to drive the right wing of the
enemy back to the Nashville Pike, meanwhile being strongly
supported by the center. Johnson's division was supposed
to be the weakest point in the opposing line. The strategy
thus planned was intended to flank and completely rout
Rosecrans and destroy his army. By a peculiar quirk of
circumstances, Rosecrans planned an identical attack. He
planned a movement upon the Confederate right, hoping to
drive them back beyond Murf reesboro, and thus give him
command of the town. Coincidently, the hour of attack was
approximately the same.
That night the armies faced each other across the short
stretch, watching the campfires and the dark silhouettes
of cedars.
Just before daylight the Confederate camp stirred.
The men were quietly examining their arms and fixing
bayonets. Cartridge belts were replenished, and the officers
felt of their horse pistols. The order was to move silently
through the broken woods. Through breaks in the low cedars,
the Confederates saw the Union camp moving around in the
lethargy of early morning. Their rifles were stacked, and
the Rebels could even smell their breakfast cooking over
the fires. Down to the right of the Confederates were some
men watering horses. The proximity of the gray host was not
as yet realized. In a few moments, however, they were
apprehended. A shout rang out, and the encampment suddenly
seized their arms, but too late. The order to charge was
given and the stealthy Confederates charged almost in solid
ranks out of the cedars. Consternation and confusion were
everywhere. The Federals tried to form a line of battle.
Arms were quickly snatched up and discharged. Finally,
the scattered lines broke and fell back rapidly in disorder.
The Confederates pressed on, forcing the enemy back until
the Nashville Turnpike was reached. Here a stubborn
resistance was met. Support from Rosecrans ' left wing came
to Johnson's aid. For the remainder of the day this was
the battleground. Charges and countercharges were made by
each army. Brickham gives a vivid picture of the storm
as it broke upon the Federal camp:
The din of battle swelled rapidly. Its volume
increased, and it seemed sweeping "nearer, clearer,
deadlier than before." It could not be! This must
be hallucination! It cannot be disaster! No
tidings yet! Wiles and a comrade were sent to the
right to observe and report. They galloped across
the field and plunged into the forests. Directly
a tide of fugitives poured out of the thickets
&#8212;
negroes, teamsters, and some soldiers. You have
seen cinders from burning buildings flying when the
conflagration was invisible. You could hear the
roaring flames and crackling beams. Seeing the
cinders you would say, "there is a fire." You have
observed broken twigs and leaves whirling in the air
when there was a roar of mighty winds in the forest.
You had not yet felt the blast, but its avant
10
couriers were unmistakable. You said, "a tornado is
coming." There was a conflagration, a tornadeo, now
rushing through the forests in front, raging forward
with vengeful fury. These teamsters, negroes,
soldiers, flying before it were cinders, twigs,
leaves, fugitives from the flames and tornado of
battle.
"What is the matter? Why do you run?" Many
push on heedless of stern questioning. A cocked
pistol brings a squad to halt. "We are beaten! The
Right Wing is broken! The rebel cavalry is charging
the rear! The enemy is sweeping everything before
them! General Sill is killed! Edgarton's Battery
and part of Goodspeed's are captured!" Incredible!
But few soldiers, thank God! in that panic-stricken
mob, and most of them cling to their muskets. The
negroes, poor souls, had cause for fright. The enemy
murdered them as if they were beasts of prey. Wiles
gallops back to report. His comrade moves further
on, and meets straggling multitudes. The awful
uproar increases and stretches swiftly now to the
left. Bullets are clipping the twigs overhead and
chipping the bark from trees. Heavy drops which
precede a thunder storm seem to be falling on the
dead leaves .
'&#8226;
As darkness settled down over the field, the din of
battle lessened and finally subsided. Both armies were
exhausted, and they rested on their arms in their new
positions. That night in a war council, Rosecrans
suggested a possible retreat, it is said. Thomas, one of
Rosencrans ' commanders, had fallen in a doze during the
talking, but he awoke when the unpleasant words were uttered.
2
"Retreat!' he exclaimed. "This army can't retreat!
W. B. Brickham, Rosecrans' Campaign with the Four-teenth
Army Corps (Cincinnati: Moore, Wilstach, Keys &amp; Co.,
1863) , pp. 207-08.
2
W. J. Vance, Stone's River (New York: Neale
Publishing Co., 1914), p. 57.
11
The possibility of retreat was avoided, and the
Federals determined to hold the new position, as it was
stronger than the former. The following is a version of
the war council of the Federals, held after the first day
of battle:
At Stone's River, during the evening of
December 31, several of the generals of the Army of
the Cumberland assembled at the headquarters of the
commander-in-chief. It was a momentous occasion.
Our right wing, comprising more than one-third of
our whole force, has been driven back with great
loss. The generals arrived after dark at the tent
of their commander, near the torn and bloody battle-ground,
yet reeking with the dead. Each reported as
to the status of his forces, and then, after other
brief remarks of a personal character, conversation
gradually subsided. General Rosecrans was the most
conversational and cheerful, and had a smile and a
pleasant word for all. Excefiting himself and
General Thomas and Van Cleve our commanders are
young in years, and to most of them this was their
first, and to all their greatest battle. Hence,
their gravity and reticence&#8212;as certainly became
them--upon this occasion. It was noticeable that
they volunteered no opinions as to the best course
for the morrow, whether to attempt to hold the
present ground, to advance, or to retreat to
Nashville. The supply trains had been sent back
to that city during the day by the general commanding,
to relieve them from the horde of Rebel cavalry.
Thus left almost empty-handed, retreat to Nashville,
even during that night if necessary, was a course not
entirely beyond reason, the enemy's superior force
and nearness to his supplies considered.
If any of our generals at this conference had
such thoughts or opinions, they certainly would not
have advanced them. It was a time and occasion&#8212;
a
turning point--that rarely happens in a lifetime or
century. Even the sage General Thomas, now calm
and placid in manner as summer eve, waited to hear
from his chief, and a stiffness pervaded the assembly
until General Rosecrans broke the spell.
"Gentlemen," said he, and the substance of his
remarks is given from recollection, "we have come
12
out to fight and v;in this battle, and WE SHALL DO IT.
True, we have been a little mixed up today; but we
won't mind that. The enemy failed in all his attempts
after we found what he was driving at. Out supplies
may be short, but we will have out our trains again
tomorrow. We will keep right on, and eat corn for
a week but what we win this battle. WE CAN AND WILL
DO IT !
"
As the general advanced in his remarks, he
became the more warmly in earnest. The effect of
his words upon his officers was marked and exhilarating,
All restraint was at once removed, now that their
course was fully settled, and plans for the morrow soon
engaged general attention.
Candor requires us to state that in all proba-bility,
had General Rosecrans determined differently,
had he upon this occasion taken a darker view of the
situation and whispered words of caution and favored
a prudential retreat, our army would have fallen
back ingloriously behind the forts at Nashville, and
thus, unquestionably, Tennessee and Kentucky would
not be as they are today, entirely free from rebel
armies, and the Gulf states threatened from the VJest,
but on the contrary, they would now be the strongest
sections of the so-called Southern Confederacy. Is
there any impropriety, then, we ask, in classing
this instance with those recorded in the world's
history, where one master-spirit has saved an army and
made a successful campaign, and thus proven himself
a prominent instrument in solving the destiny of his
country .3
The following day, January 1, 1863, there was little
activity, except sporadic engagements by cavalry units
against supplies and wagon trains. Bragg was jubilant over
the success of the first day's fighting, so much so that he
flashed a message to Richmond, "God has granted us a happy
New Year! "^
3 John Fitch, Annals of the Army of the Cumberland
(Philadelphia: J. B. Lippincott &amp; Co., 1864), pp. 676-77
4Vance, p. 10.
13
At four o'clock on the afternoon of the next day,
January 3, the second and last engagement in the Battle of
Stone's River took place. Bragg chose again to take the
offensive. He noticed the Union detachment that had been
thrown across the river in Breckenridge ' s front, and he now
determined to dislodge it. This was the Confederate right
facing the Union left. Reinforcing Breckenridge, he
ordered the advance. The Federals under Beatty fell back
under superior force and finally fled across the river
pursued by the enemy. The Confederates pushed on crossing
the river at a shallow breach called McFadden's Ford.
Scrambling up the bank on the opposite side they continued
the rapid advance. But an error in judgment, either by
Breckenridge or because of the impetuosity of the pursuing
men carried the charge too far, much to their ultimate
sorrow. They found themselves in an open field, unpro-tected
by cavalry or by cannonade fire from Bragg '
s
artillery.
On an eminence some three hundred yards away, were
posted fifty-eight Federal guns. These rained a withering
fire into the advancing ranks. Line after line was
decimated, until a retreat was ordered. The Confederates
fell back across the river, shattered and demoralized,
leaving over seventeen hundred men dead and dying. The
river itself was choked with bodies and ran red with blood.
14
Undoubtedly, this was the decisive engagement of the battle,
for twenty-four hours later, on January 3, 1863, Bragg
retreated, leaving his dead to be buried by the enemy.
The importance of the outcome of this battle is great.
Yet few historians have given it recognition. Vance, in his
Stone's River , has this to say of the battle:
It was at Stone's River that the South was the
very pinnacle of confidence and warlike power, and it
was here that she was halted and beaten back, never
again to exhibit such strength and menace. It was a
battle that marked the turning point of the war. To
the people of the two sections, it seemed at the time
but another Shiloh&#8212;horrifying, saddening, and
bitterly disappointing .
^
It is the contention of authorities today that had
Bragg chosen to take the defensive instead of the offensive,
he might have held his position indefinitely. Furthermore,
he knew the ground, and most of the Federals certainly did
not. It is said, for instance, that very few of the
Federals knew the correct name of the stream upon whose
banks they fought.
Joe Wheeler at Lavergne
While the battle was raging at Murfreesboro, cavalry
units under Wheeler and Wharton were attacking the rear of
the enemy, capturing wagon trains and picking up stragglers
5Vance, p. 10,
15
from Rosecrans ' army. In this era the cavalry units were
practically the backbone of the army, the tentacles that
reached out into the unknown country and tested the strength
of an adversary. This military department has been aptly
nicknamed the "eyes and ears" of the army. It was in the
battle of Murfreesboro that the cavalry came into action.
One of the skirmishes well-known locally as a part of
the Battle of Stone's River was the attack of Joe Wheeler's
cavalry on a Federal garrison at Lavergne. Lavergne is a
small village in the northwest extremity of the county and
lies at the emergence of the Nashville Turnpike and the
Nashville, Chattanooga, and St. Louis Railroad. It had
devolved into an important position because it offered a
key to communication through the two thoroughfares. Wheeler,
with about three thousand men, was dispatched to dislodge the
garrison and open the communication or else destroy it.
The Federals, said to be a part of the Michigan Engineers
and Mechanics, had taken a position behind an improvised
cedar brush barricade on an elevation to the rear of the
village. Wheeler stormed up the acclivity and demanded an
immediate surrender. This was refused and a charge was
made upon the position. Time after time the charges were
repulsed. The Confederates became enraged and dashed
their horses against the flimsy brush fence, which was only
shoulder-high, in an attempt to crush it. Behind the
16
barricade, the Federals fired and reloaded with precision.
Finally, Wheeler despaired and ordered a retreat. The
cavalry soon disappeared in the cedar thickets, leaving
about fifty dead and wounded. The Federals came out from
their position and after surveying the bloody mass of men
and horses began the gruesome task of burial.
Rosecrans ' Post Battle Headquarters
After the Battle of Stone's River, Rosecrans had his
headquarters in the heart of Murf reesboro. He took possession
of the Keeble residence. A search has been made for the old
home, but it has been found that the house was torn down a
number of years ago. Mr. Sam Mitchell, veteran, remembers
it as do others of advanced age. It was a fine, two-story,
country-town house, with a large, pretty garden attached.
Its owner was a lawyer, county clerk, and secessionist, and
held a position in the Confederate Army. The old timers
claim that Keeble attached himself to Bragg when the latter
evacuated Murf reesboro in retreat toward Tullahoma. His
wife and smallest children joined him. On Monday,
following Bragg's search for quieter fields, Rosecrams
entered the deserted house and set up headquarters. The
house was said to have been filled with family goods and
even the kitchen was well supplied. Also, this bounteous-ness
was easily matched by the presence of a number of
17
young Africans left behind in the sudden departure of the
owner. As most of the African contingent v;as of young
feminine gender, Rosecrans thought it expedient to see that
they were hastily removed. It was said that Rosecrans and
his staff remained in this house ten days recuperating from
the strenuous activity of Stone's River.
Brickhouse Hospital
One can imagine the tasks of any surgeon in the wake
of a battle with the proportions of Stone's River. With
the thousands of piled on the ground, moaning and crying
in anguish, some slov/ly dying from loss of blood, the
surgeons did what they thought practical and expedient after
a hurried analysis. Considering that a great number of the
surgeons were young men, snatched prematurely from medical
schools, it was small v/onder that many of the badly wounded
joined their dead comrades by way of the operating table. A
description of Brickhouse Hospital, set up after the Battle
of Murf reesboro, gives a ghastly picture of a field hospital.
This hospital was located in the center of the battlefield
to facilitate easy access to the wounded.
Those who witnessed surgical operations at the
"Brickhouse Hospital" during and after the battles of
Stone's River will never forget many of those
scenes. There were headquarters for cases requiring
amputation. Human limbs and pieces of flesh were
cast outside of the house, through the windows, and
the amount would have filled a cart. The floors of
18
the premises ran rivers of blood, and the surgeons
and attendants, in their long dress and appearance
resembled butchers at work in the shambles. The long
line of graves, of both Union and Rebels, now
coursing down the sloping field behind the Brickhouse
Hospital attest the many sad results of battle, in
which these humane and skillful efforts to save were
unavailing. The picture we have drawn is harrowing
to the soul; but it needs be thus brought home that
we may realize the deepest and most terrible ordeal
of the army surgeon.
&#176;
Fort Transit
About eight miles from Murfreesboro on the Woodbury
Pike, Mother Earth has fostered a mammoth wart on her ample
bosom. It is an imposing hill rising majestically over the
surrounding countryside. Sometime in the far distant past,
it was given the name of Pilot Knob. People motoring along
the pike now can see the smooth sides reaching to the summit
where clusters a luxuriant tuft of trees. Down on the
other side, obstructed from view, is a large apple orchard
planted there by some industrious primeval. Old timers
questioned about the history of the spot will tell you
that it was a very important place during the Civil War.
After Rosecrans had won the battle of Stone's River,
he set about hooking up some signal stations over the
county. The cupola of the courthouse at Murfreesboro was
^Fitch, p. 292.
19
chosen as the central station, with auxiliary stations at
Lavergne, Triune, and Pilot Knob.
The Yankees had selected a gigantic elm, whose limbs
reached far above the other trees, as the ideal spot for
the signal platform. Here, during the day, the people in
the neighborhood far below could see the little wig-v/ag
flags spelling out a code to the courthouse eight miles
away. Sometimes the flags would be red with a white
center; again they would be white with red centers. It is
said that the weather conditions had something to do with
the color selection. Then at night, torches kept up the
endless wagging. The Yankees termed the station, "Fort
Transit.
"
Today, people seeing the huge mound, like an inverted
ice cream cone, remark about its unusual shape. The
settlers in the low country don't mind the size so much,
except when they climb up its sides to pick blackberries
or apples in the fall.
Forrest's Birthday Party
Today Murfreesboro citizens point with pride to the
minie ball marks in the walls of the old courthouse.
The jagged holes are reminiscent of a misty July morning
seventy-eight years ago when Nathan Bedford Forrest
charged up East Main Street and captured a garrison of
20
drowsy-eyed Yankees. The story is prevalent. No Jeff
Davis birthday speech is complete without recounting it
in its full resplendence. No loyal sons and daughters
of the Gray Army fail to use it as a theme in their formal
gatherings
.
Bedford Forrest comes down to present Murfreesboro,
through story and legend, as a conquering cavalier, a
gracious, hard-riding, fire-eating Southern hero. Arguments
are projected that if Jeff Davis had recognized the military
genius in Forrest, and had not been blinded by the petty
thrusts of jealousy by Braxton Bragg, the South might have
fared better in the war. People with Union sentiment call
Forrest the "Butcher," reminiscent of the massacre at Fort
Pillow where hundreds of negroes were slaughtered.
The appearance of Forrest in Murf reesboro, on July 13,
1862, was in compliance with an order by General Beauregard,
then in Alabama. It was necessary to dislodge the garrison
of Federals occupying Murfreesboro in order to open com-munications
by railroad between East Tennessee and Nashville.
Forrest, because of his conspicuous service in Kentucky and
at Fort Donelson, was chosen for the task. He left Tupelo
in June, 1862, and proceeded to Rock Martins, near
McMinnville. Here he assembled his various commands con-sisting
of Terry's Rangers under Colonel Wharton, the Second
Texas Regiment under Colonel Lawton, a Georgia batalion
21
under Lieutenant-Colonel Morrison, and a squadron under
Colonel Baxter Smith. The entire force consisted of about
one thousand men. After sending out reliable scouts and
discovering that Murf reesboro was garrisoned by about two
thousand men, Forrest held his first council of war. As a
result of the conference, it was determined to make a
descent on Murf reesboro, and on Saturday, July 18, 1862,
the movement began. The following excerpt relates the
origin of the "Birthday Party":
After it had been determined to make a descent
on Murf reesboro, Forrest had his brigade drawn up
and made a stirring appeal to the officers and men
to sustain him in the effort he was about to make.
He told them that the next day (July 13) would be
the anniversary of his birth, and that he would like
to celebrate it at Murf reesboro, near his birthplace,
in a becoming manner. All of the command promised
that they would contribute what they could to the
felicitation of the occasion.'
About midnight the command reached Woodbury, where the
whole population of the town seemed to be on the streets.
It is said that the ladies gathered around Forrest, and
tearfully and vehemently related the events of the evening
before when a large detachment of Federal soldiers swooped
down on the town and took or carried away almost every man
in town, young and old, and rushed them off to prison in
^B. L. Ridley, Battles and Sketches of the Army of
Tennessee (Mexico, Missouri: Missouri Printing &amp; Publishing
Co., 1906) , pp. 106-07.
22
Murfreesboro. The women appealed to the commander to rescue
their brothers, fathers, and husbands. It is said that
Forrest informed them in his most gracious tones that he
would oblige them.
After a few hours rest, Forrest and his company moved
on to Murfreesboro. Reaching the outskirts of the city
a few hours before dawn, he sent forward a small detachment
and captured the pickets. The way now being open, he
planned the attack. It was desired to attack the enemy at
all points simultaneously. The Federals were divided into
encampments at different points. One encampment was sleeping
peacefully on the lawn of the old Maney home in the north-eastern
part of town, another about one mile to the west of
the city on the banks of Stone's River, and still another
in the courthouse yard. The first encampment was taken after
a brief skirmish, but the attack on the courthouse did not
go so well. At the outset the Confederate cavalry was
virtually in the midst of the camp before the Federals knew
it. The Confederates tore over the tent ropes and unleased
a devastating fire onto the surprised men. A number of the
Yankees sought refuge in the courthouse, where a small
detachment was already its occupants, and barricaded the
doors. The windows served excellently for sniping. Soon
Forrest came on the scene and ordered his men to secure
axes and storm the doors. The doors collapsed under the
23
pressure of Forrest's men, but the Federals who had taken
refuge on the second floor, which was occupied also by a
hundred or more prisoners, refused to surrender. Forrest
ordered a fire built inside the lower hallway, and after a
short time the enemy almost suffocated from the smoke
came down the stairway. Behind the Federals streamed the
prisoners shouting in joy for their release. By this time
a hugh crowd had gathered and there was shouting and merry-making.
Many soldiers were reunited with their families.
Some of the men who hurried out to freedom had been
sentenced to hang the following morning.
The third encampment, the Third Minnesota, near Stone's
River, was offering a spirited resistance. It was now past
noon, and still the Federals were in their original position.
Forrest turned his attention to this task. After making a
rapid tour of the encampment, he ordered a charge by Major
Smith and Major Harper. This charge was repulsed, and still
a second attempt was made which likewise met with failure.
It is said that Forrest, after these failures, placed
himself at the head of his troops and made an appeal to
them, saying that if they lost this skirmish it would be
their first defeat. The charge was again ordered and the
encampment penetrated, and the greater part of the Federals
were either captured or wounded.
24
Following is an incident that admirers of Forrest
contend has been grossly misrepresented. It was said that
a negro captive was brought before Forrest, who cursed
loudly and at the same time leveled his gun at the negro's
head and blew out his brains. Ridley's version of the
incident is parallel with the accounts of others of
Forrest's admirers.
While passing through the encampment he was
fired at several times by a negro, who suddenly
emerged from one of the tents. Forrest returned
the fire and killed him, and did exactly what he
ought to have done. This came under the personal
observation of the writer.^
After a short skirmish the Federals were brought under
submission. Forrest forwarded an ultimatum to the Maney
homestead to Major Duffield, the commander, who was at the
time seriously wounded. The dispatch ordered a complete
surrender within thirty minutes or else the Federals would
suffer the consequences. The tone of the ultimatum
impressed Duffield, and after a conference with his staff
during the alloted time, he acquiesced to Forrest's terms.
The results of the battle as given by B. L. Ridley were:
The results of this affair were some 1,765
prisoners including Brigadier-General Crittenden,
commanding the post, 600 head of horses and mules,
forty or fifty wagons, five or six ambulances,
four pieces of artillery and 1,200 stand of arms.
^Ridley, p. 110.
25
A Federal writer from Murfreesboro estimated their
loss in property and munition at $1,000,000.^
After the destruction of a few railroad cars con-taining
supplies and tearing up sections of the railroad,
Forrest put his troops, prisoners, and captured supplies
into motion toward McMinnville.
Miss Lillian Jetton, who now lives with her sister and
brother in the old Maney home, relates this story as told
her by her mother, a young girl at the time of Forrest's
descent on Murfreesboro:
Mother was a young girl at her father's home
in Readyville, the first brick house in Rutherford
County, which had been built by her grandfather.
Colonel Charles Ready, when word came that General
Forrest's brigade was coming. Forrest had stopped
in Woodbury that day, July 12, and had pledged to
the Confederate women that he was going to celebrate
his birthday by capturing Murfreesboro and freeing
the confederates held prisoners there.
That day, my mother summoned her loyal slaves.
Aunt Minnie, Uncle Martin, and Malindy, and they
prepared bread and meat for the Forrest cavalrymen.
That evening she stood on the horse block at the
gate of her home as General Forrest and his men came
riding along. She noticed that their horses' hoofs
were wrapped to muffle them and that the men did not
speak or cheer, moving silently through the summer
night in order to accomplish more effectually the
maneuver which their commander had planned for them.
The old Maney home, now called Oak Manor, is rich in
Civil War lore. As has been stated before, the lawn of
the old home was used as a Federal encampment prefatory to
^Ridley, p. 110
26
Forrest's raid on Murf reesboro. The house itself was the
headquarters for a staff of Federal officers. One of the
officers occupying this house was ill and in bed. Probably
the most intimate account of the camp on the lawn of the
old estate was given by Private Charles W. Bennett of
Company G of the Ninth Michigan Infantry. This is in
diary form and excerpts from it are preserved by the
Captain William Lytle Chapter, Daughters of the American
Revolution. The graphic account of Forrest's capture of the
Federals at Oak Manor follows:
I arose at a quarter past four, Sunday, July 13,
and while in the rear of the camp on the east side,
I heard two guns in the direction of our pickets on
the Woodbury Road, the road east toward Chattanooga.
As reveille was not until five o'clock and all
were sleeping quietly except a few cooks who were
chopping wood for their breakfast fires, I returned to
our cook's fire and while washing, each time I stooped
down, I could hear an unusual roar like a distant
windstorm, but as I raised to listen I concluded it
was the echoes of the chopping. But to satisfy
myself I at last put my ear to the groUnd and then
distinctly heard the clatter and roar of cavalry on
the gallop.
,,
I ran to each tent in our company yelling. Turn
out, the Rebels are coming." By the time I reached
the second tent our company bugler, William White,
began to blow the alarm (poor fellow he was killed
in his tent, shot through the head before he got
dressed) and that aroused a drummer who beat the long
roll. By this time the Rebels had reached the
brigade teamsters, camped about eighty rods on our
left towards town, and then came to the cavalry which
was beyond where the Third Minnesota Regiment and
Hewlett's Battery had camped on our left. The
cavalry hardly had time to get out of their tents,
let alone arming and mounting their horses. There
was a great deal of yelling and scattered fire in
27
those camps and the ropes stretched from tree to
tree for hitching the horses tumbled many a Rebel
horse and rider, but these delayed the Rebels only
a few minutes.
Captain Mansfield was sick in bed in Major
Maney's house. First Lieutenant Hull was acting
adjutant, and Second Lieutenant Sellon was officer
of the guard, leaving my company, G, without an
officer.
I got the company all in line, divided off into
sections and platoons, and started to form on the
color line in front of the camp but the adjutant
called me to come to the left with Company C which
was the only other company then organized. Company C
being tented next to our left and had been aroused by
my calling out Company G.
When Colonel Parkhurst rushed out of his tent
he commanded to form square on the left previously
occupied by the four companies gone to Tullahoma.
But there being not rules to form squares only when
in line or column, each company rushed to that
space and while in that dilemma of trying to form a
square, the Rebels came in sight, yelling like
Indians, their horses on a gallop. We were all in a
huddle. The Rebels began firing, being armed largely
with shot guns loaded with big shot, which came like
hail.
Colonel Parkhurst ordered, "Fall back over the
fence," meaning the picket fence on the right of
the camp and about eight rods away. The order was
obeyed by many, but others fell back part way but did
not go over the fence, some getting behind trees.
About one o'clock in the afternoon Forrest drew
up all his forces in sight on our left (towards
town) and front and then sent in a flag of truce
demanding a surrender with his usual threat that no
quarter would be given if we refused. The adjutant
counted only one hundred and twenty-five men with
guns able for duty. Out of about two hundred and
twenty-five men of the five companies in camp for
duty at four o'clock in the morning, thirteen had
been killed and seventy-eight ihad been wounded. We
had lost ninety-one from these five companies.
The Rebels rode up to us in good order which
they did not do in the morning, led by General
Forrest, who assured Colonel Parkhurst that our
private property would be respected.
Captain Mansfield, though wounded, had come
from his sick bed in the Maney house and remained
28
with his men until the fighting stopped. Wounded
and sick in the hospitals were paroled officers in
this category agreeing to report to Confederate
headquarters in Chattanooga as soon as they were
well enough. The rest of the Federal prisoners were
started on the road to Chattanooga that afternoon.
We passed through Woodbury late in the evening
and went into bivouac in a field about midnight,
the ground being our only bed with only the sky
for a covering. A large number of officers and men
were allowed to ride horses and mules which our
cavalry had captured a few days before.
CHAPTER II
DEWITT SMITH JOBE
Dewitt Smith Jobe ' s life parallels that of many others
during the War Between the States of 1861-65. During this
period when passions were high and "glorious death" was
accepted with a flourish, many young men went to their
graves with an enemy curse. Scouting in and behind the
enemy line was precarious work and if the soldier was
unlucky enough to be captured, the natural procedure was
to exact, if possible, any information that he might be
carrying. If the captors were unsuccessful, the soldier
was executed, usually in a macabre manner. Jobe shared
his fate with fellow countians including John Bowman,
Dee Smith, R. M. Dillard, and Sam Davis, the latter the
best known of the group.
The Jobe Family
Little is known of the early life of Dewitt Smith
Jobe. His father was Elihu C. Jobe, who was undoubtedly
one of the enterprising farmers of Rutherford County.
Elihu Jobe was born in Maury County, Tennessee, August 7,
1809, the son of James and Catherine (Pitt) Jobe, natives
respectively of Virginia and North Carolina. His father
29
30
\
DEWITT SMITH JOBE
31
came to Maury County at an early date and settled on a farm.
He was one of the constructors of the first cotton gin in
that county. He died in 1833. Elihu was a farmer boy and
received a good common-school education. At an early age
he served an apprenticeship in a cabinet shop. After
finishing his trade he started in business for himself in
Rutherford County. He purchased the farm on which he
operated a cabinet shop besides cultivating the fields.
There are a number of old homes in Rutherford County today
that contain furniture made at the Jobe shop. Also, a
number of people in the Mechanicsville district were buried
in the coffins fashioned by the hand of Jobe. In 1833 he
married Mary W. Smith and to this union were born seven
children, namely: Luke E., Benjamin A., Nancy Price (wife
of T. H. Hollowell), Martha A. (wife of J. T. Beasley)
,
Elizabeth Katherine, Lavina S. (wife of W. F. Edwards),
and Dewitt S. Jobe.
A letter dated October 28, 1938, from one of the
grandchildren, gives some information concerning the family.
An excerpt follows:
Elihu C Job, father of Dee Jobe, was a farmer
and slave owner. He was also a cabinet maker and
held some office in Rutherford County or precinct;
I think we would now call it Justice of the Peace.
He had an office near the old home where he did his
work as cabinet maker and also attended to duties of
this office. He, too, looked after a number of war
widows during the war.
32
SQUIRE ELIHU C. JOBE
33
The mother of the family died, I think, about
the time the war closed, grieving terrible over the
loss of her son. The family attended, and were
members of, the Methodist church.
Luke Jobe was the oldest child of the family
and taught school near the old home. Later he was
a farmer in West Tennessee, and was never very strong
physically. He has a daughter, Mrs. Wesley Cannon
of Buchanan, Tennessee, who could probably give you
details of her father's life.
Kate Jobe was the second child and before the
war she directed the slaves in spinning and
weaving cloth for their garments. She directed the
slaves also in making those garments, and after her
mother died, Kate mothered the family. She helped
her father line the coffins which he dressed by hand.
She never married, living at the old home and taking
care of her father who was paralyzed and lay in bed
four years before he died, I think, at the age of
seventy-six.
Ben Jobe, Horace's father, was the third child
of the family and also a spy during the war. I
think Dee was just younger than Ben. Then came
Price who later became Mrs. Tom Hollowell, Sr., of
Murf reesboro. She has three daughters in Cincinnati,
Ohio. The oldest one, Mrs. William Jennings (Mary
Hollowell) could probably give you more information
about the Jobe family, having lived in Murfreesboro
longer than any other niece or nephew of Dee Jobe.
Martha Ann (my mother) was a very jolly woman,
though a good Christian, musical, and very hospitable.
They always had guests and especially young people
pulling candy, dancing, singing, and having a jolly
good time. She said when the Union soldiers were
camped not many miles from there, several of them
would ride over every evening, and they v/ould have a
lot of fun, for there were always other girls there
v;ho were lonely in their homes.
The youngest child of the family was Lavenia,
who married a Mr. Edwards. She died with pneumonia
when quite a young woman, leaving two sons who used
to own a dairy at Nashville. I think they still
do, though I am not sure.-l-
Letter from Mrs. J. T. McCarty, October 28, 1938,
34
KATE JOBE
35
PRICE JOBE
36
An excerpt from another letter, dated October 21, 1938,
gives further information as to the family. This, also,
was written by one of the grandchildren of Elihu C. Jobe.
I know that the Jobe family has been entirely
removed from Rutherford County for twenty years or
more, and no doubt many other old families of the
Civil War times are either removed or have died out
since.
I wrote you som.e thing about my mother, Mattie
(Martha, originally) Ann Jobe, who became Mrs. J. T.
Beasley and who always signed her name M. A.
Beasley. Also I mentioned Uncle Ben Jobe, father of
Horace A. Jobe of Paris, Tennessee. Besides two
brothers, Ben and Dee Jobe, my mother had two sisters,
Kate Jobe, spinster, v;ho died at the home of my
mother and father at Lancaster, this county, in 1901,
and is buried with my father and mother in our family
burial lot there. The other sister was Price Jobe
who became Mrs. Tom Hollowell of Murfreesboro. I
never saw our Aunt Price, but once visited, for an
hour only, a daughter of hers, whose married name I
do not remember, who lives in Cincinnati. Uncle Ben
Jobe died about 1926 or 1927 at the home of his
daughter, Mrs. Marie Jobe Pillow, in Galveston, Texas,
and was buried, I believe, at Paris, Tennessee, the
home of his son, Horace Jobe.
2
Horace E. Jobe of Paris, Tennessee, in a letter
concerning his father, Ben Jobe, says, "Ben Job enlisted in
the Eighteenth Tennessee under Colonel Palmer, was taken
prisoner at Fort Donelson, carried North, but escaped
and served under Wheeler and Forrest the remainder of the
2Letter from W. S. Beasley, October 21, 1938.
37
MARTHA ANN JOBE BEASLEY AND HUSBAND
38
Dewitt S. Jobe ' s Military Career
Dewitt Smith Jobe was born June 4, 1840, at Mechanics-ville
in Rutherford County. He enlisted in 1861 at College
Grove in Williamson County, ten miles from his home. The
company that Jobe joined later became Company D of the
Twentieth Tennessee Regiment. He served with this company
until after the Battle of Murf reesboro. He was wounded and
captured at the Battle of Fishing Creek and after his
exchange participated in the Battle of Murfreesboro.
In the spring of 1863, while Bragg' s army was at
Shelbyville, General W. J. Hardee had Job detailed for
service in which he did a great deal of dangerous work. He
did this work for General Hardee until Bragg 's army fell
back into Georgia, when he was transferred to the Coleman
Scouts. This was a very responsible position and
necessitated working in behind the Federal lines.
In the summer of 1864, D. S. Jobe, Tom Joplin, and
others came into Middle Tennessee and were scouting about
in the area of College Grove, Triune, and Nolensville, in
Williamson County. These villages were about seven miles
apart and connected by the Nolensville Pike. The scouts,
when in danger, would separate. On the night of August 29,
1864, Jobe rode all night and about sunrise the next
morning he called at the home of Mr. William Moss, who had
two sons in Company B, Twentieth Tennessee Regiment, and
39
got his breakfast. Mr. Moss lived about halfway between
Nolensville and Triune, on the pike. His house was about
two hundred yards west of the pike which ran between some
very high hills.
After Jobe ate his breakfast he went about one mile
west of Mr. Moss's house into a cornfield on the Sam
Water's farm. Here he concealed himself and his horse. At
this time a party of Yankees, fifteen in number, were
scouting in the same neighborhood under the command of
Sergeant Temple of the 115 Ohio Regiment, and to them
Jobe ' s presence in the community was made known. They
tracked his horse to the field, surrounded and captured
him, and when Jobe saw that he would be captured or killed,
having on his person some very valuable papers that would
condemn himself and others (some thought that these papers
were procured by a sweetheart of his in the neighborhood)
,
he destroyed these papers by tearing and chewing them up.
After they had captured him, they tied him and tried to
make him tell the contents of the papers, but he would not.
The Yankees told Jobe that they would kill him if he did not
divulge the contents but still he refused. Then they tied
a leather strap around his neck and began to choke him to
death, but the brave boy in gray, who was alone, disarmed,
and both hands tied, with fifteen of his armed enemies
standing over him thirsting for his blood, would not
40
concede to their demands. Jobe, in this condition, chose
not to betray his friends or to divulge his secret but
preferred death. The captors beat him over the head with
their guns, knocked out his upper front teeth, and dragged
him by the leather strap that they had placed about his
neck until he was strangled to death.
These fifteen men, who had the courage to murder one
man who was tied and disarmed, went back to the pike and
told some acquaintance of Jobe ' s what they had done and said
he was the bravest man they had ever seen.
Word was sent to Jobe ' s home, six miles away, that he
v;as killed and the old negro servant, Frank, who had nursed
him when a child, volunteered to take the wagon and go for
him. He was carried to his childhood home by the faithful
old servant and buried in the family burial ground in the
presence of his mother, father, and others. "No braver
soldier, no greater patriot, no truer comrade gave up his
life in this great struggle of ours for the right against
the wrong, Sam Davis was not excepted.
It is said that the bloody and cruel act prayed on
Sergeant Temple's mind and eventually he went insane.
^W. J. Murray, History of the Twentieth Tennessee
Regiment. Volunteer Infantry. C. S. A. (Nashville:
Publication Committee, 1904), p. 223.
41
This account from a letter, dated September 28, 1938,
is a version given by Jobe ' s nephew:
My father, Ben Jobe, always said that his
brother Dee, of whom you inquire, was entitled
to just as much credit for daring bravery as Sam
Davis. I believe Captain B. L. Ridley mentioned this
fact in his memoires of the Confederate Soldiers of
Rutherford County. My uncle. Dee Smith Jobe, was
born in 1840, enlisted in the Twentieth Tennessee
under Colonel Battle, was taken prisoner at Fishing
Creek, Kentucky. In his first fight he was carried
north and kept in prison several months but made his
escape, and came back to his old command. I have
always understood that Coleman's Scouts was a company
of picked men from General Bragg 's entire army.
After making several trips inside the Federal lines
gathering information, one morning after riding all
night he stopped at a friend's home near Triune,
Tennessee. They told him that the Federals were in
the neighborhood and that it was not safe for him
to be in the house but to hide in a nearby thicket
and they would bring him his breakfast and feed
for his horse, but a squad of Ohio Cavalry soon came
and tracked his horse to the thicket and killed him.
The captain of this bunch of murderers afterwards
told my grandmother that they took a bridle rein,
put it around his neck and strangled him to death
because he would not divulge the information they
sought. However, the captain said, "Madam, your son
was the bravest man I ever saw."
I hope this information will be of some help
to you, but I always get mad when I get strung out on
the Confederates and damn Yankees.^
Without a doubt, Dewitt Jobe died a horrible death.
All versions agree that he was inhumanly tortured before
being put to death. Dyed-in-the-wool Southern soldiers were
venomous in their denouncements of their northern enemies,
the "damn Yankees," as they chose to call them, and they
Letter from Horace E. Jobe, September 28, 1938,
.m
42
BEN JOBE
43
were never reluctant to give vent to their passion even
when in danger. It is probable that Jobe further enraged
his captors by heaping epithets upon them as they tried to
force the information from him. In examining a number of
old records and official reports, no mention could be found
of the scout's death. It is the practice of commanding
officers to make detail reports of engagements, movements,
and captures, but there could not be found any report by
Sergeant Temple or by anyone else. As the story has been
proven beyond a doubt to be authentic, it is probable that
the Sergeant, even considering that war is horrible and
brings with it inhumanities that may be justifiable under
this premise, was ashamed to make a report. Of course the
Federal soldiers may have had their side and it have been
a good one, but hearing the story now after over seventy-five
years of countless transm.ittances , it sounds horribly and
coldly executed.
A Letter from Mrs. J. T. McCarty, a niece, gives the
following information:
I do not know just how much my brother and
cousin, Horace Jobe, have told you concerning
Uncle Dee, but I do remember that the valuable
information which he was carrying from Nashville
to the Confederate Army of officers was very
important, and it would be dangerous to the Con-federates
if the Northern army learned of it.
Dee was going through thei^woods horseback, I
think, rather early in the morning and only a few
miles from his father's home where he had
expected, no doubt, to stop for a brief time for
44
food. As they always had food ready to serve if
any soldiers stopped by the house, this was probably
Jobe ' s destination.
Dee Jobe was surrounded by Union soldiers
and forced to halt. They demanded the secret
information which he had, and upon his refusal to
divulge it, they first threatened him, then began
to torture him, trying to force him to tell the
secret which he was carrying. Finally they told
him that if he would not tell what they wanted to
know, they would cut out his tongue. He still
refused and they did cut out his tongue but stopped
after they had begun this, and gave him his last
chance to save his life. He still refused to
betray the trust, hence sacrificed his life for
what he believed was his duty to his country.
This is the story told by my mother (his
sister)
.
A young woman, a friend of the family, and
her escort rode by and found his body. The woman
recognized Uncle Dee and she got off her horse
and spread a nice clean handkerchief over his
face to keep off the sun.
After an hour or two there were two or three
Northern soldiers who rode to his father's home
and told him that they came to tell the family
what a heroic son Dee was. They also told how
they had treated Jobe and said they were sorry to
bear such sad news, but thought it might lessen
their grief to know how bravely he died.
Another letter from W. S. Beasley' gives some
description of Dev/itt Jobe and a vivid account of his death.
I am sure my mother had a photograph of
Uncle Dee, but we have been unable to locate it.
I recall that he appeared to have been slender,
of slightly more than medium height and youthful
in age. He was dressed in a plain military
uniform.
The story of Uncle Dee's death, as my mother
recited it, has remained a vivid recollection of
my youth and a life long inspiration to duty at
any cost.
Since his capture and death occurred in
another county and in a vicinity where he had
only a few war-made friends through his operations
45
as a scout, accurate and complete details were
hard to secure by his family. My mother's story
of it was that Uncle Dee was scouting with one
companion within the Yankee lines after they had
captured Nashville. Uncle Dee, temporarily
separated from his partner, was getting some sleep
in a thicket in the daytime on the farm of a friend
and sympathizer in Williamson County when he was
surprised and captured by a band of Yankee guerrillas
who found papers on his person which proved that he
had operated within their lines and received informa-tion
from friends within their lines.
In the effort to make him tell the source of
his information they beat him brutally, hung him
and then let him down for two or three times, and
finally shot him and left his body hanging from
a tree. They secured his papers, but no informa-tion
as to how he got the papers
.
It was always understood that the enemy informa-tion
that he had was secured through a young woman
in or near Nashville who passed freely behind the
Yankee lines and who was smart enough to do this
dangerous service. Dee S. Jobe nor any other
chivalrous soldier could have done anything else but
die gladly in the defense of such a friend.
B. L. Ridley, Lieutenant General of A. P. Stewart's
staff. Confederate States of America, gives the story of
Jobe ' s action prior to his death and his subsequent fate:
Those to whom I refer were private soldiers.
Dee S. Jobe was a scout, and of the famous men
commanded by "Coleman." Jobe lived near Mechanics-ville,
Rutherford County, Tennessee. He was only
a boy of twenty years. Detailed from the Twentieth
Tennessee and ordered into the lines of the Federals
from Bragg ' s army, he had fallen asleep in a thicket
and some one telling of his hiding place, he fell into
the hands of the enemy. They dubbed him "bushwhacker,"
but offered to spare his life if he would tell of his
comrades and of their proposed meeting place. Jobe
declined and they tortured him to death by putting
out his eyes and pulling out his tongue. The leader
v;ho had him killed became a raving maniac in con-templating
his bloody deed. He said that Jobe was the
bravest man he ever saw.
46
Some of his comrades of the Coleman Scouts
who survived the war, after a fitting preamble,
resolved, "That while we regret, with the sorrow
of our inmost souls, D. S. Jobe ' s cruel fate,
we can but recollect with pride how nobly he
died&#8212;strangled, beaten, and abused; yet he defied
his persecutors to the end."
"Death makes no conquest of this conqueror.
For now he lives in fame, though not in life."
The signatures to that paper are given to show
their membership: H. B. Shaw, Captain, William
Roberts, George D. Hughes, John C. Davis, James T.
Patterson, W. H. Portch, Sam Roberts, Alex Greig,
J. T. Brown, A. H. Douglas, T. M. Joplin, L. A.
Owen, N. J. Vaughn, W. J. Moore, Richard Anderson,
J. M. Shute.5
C. C. Henderson in his Story of Murfreesboro gives
somewhat the same account:
D. S. Jobe, a young man of limited social
advantages and education, living at Mechanicsville
(Big Spring) , this county, volunteered his services
to the Confederate cause. Jobe enlisted in a
company that was raised in his neighborhood, which
was later made a part of the Twentieth Tennessee
Regiment.
Although only twenty years of age his fitness
for special service as a member of the 'famous
Coleman Scouts was recognized by his superiors and
he became attached to the command of Coleman, the
same organization to which Sam Davis belonged. On
one occasion he was detailed to attempt to penetrate
the Federal lines to secure certain information,
thought to be of much importance to General Bragg.
He fell asleep at night in a thicket and was dis-covered
by some unknown party who reported him to
the Federals. He was captured and although he
assured his captors that he was a member of the
, B. L. Ridley, Battles and Sketches of the Army of
Tennessee (Mexico, Missouri: Missouri Printing &amp;
Publishing Co., 1906), p. 503.
47
reqular army he was convicted of being a "bushwhacker"
and was sentenced to be shot.
The officer in command of the Federals offered
to spare his life if he would inform him of the where-abouts
of Coleman's famous scouts and their future
plans. He refused. His captors then proceeded to
torture him in the hope of exhorting a statement
from him but with no success. He was cruelly put to
death.
^
A nephew, son of Lavenia Jobe (Mrs. Edwards), gives
the following information concerning his Uncle Dewitt's
death and the family burying ground located about one-half
mile from the house on a knoll overlooking the old Jobe
'home
:
I have been told that Dee Jobe was murdered in
a corn field near Triune, Tennessee, where he was
captured by some Yankees. He had some papers which
he destroyed by chewing to such a state that they
could not be placed together so as to be read.
After having been murdered, Jobe was left lying in
the field and the Yankees went to his father's house
and told the father about it and where the body
could be found. His father sent one of the negroes
by the name of Frank Jobe to bring the body to
where it was buried on the hill you visited. There
are four graves at the north end of the graveyard
without markers except some sandstone which was made
by the negro that brought Dee Jobe home for the
burial. The graves are those of Dee, his father and
mother, and my mother, Lavenia Jobe Edwards, but I
am sorry I do not know which one is which.'
Miss Jeanette King of Murf reesboro, Tennessee, whose
father was a soldier in the war, gives the account as it was
told to her while she was a young woman:
C. C. Henderson, The Story of Murfreesboro (Murfrees-boro:
News-Banner Publishing Co., 1929), pp. 81-82.
^Letter from Hugh O. Edwards, November 10, 1938.
48
After Dee Jobe had refused repeatedly to
divulge the contents of the papers and the name of
the person giving them to him, the Yankees proceeded
to torture him. They beat out his teeth with the
butt of a pistol, punched out his eyes with a bayonet,
and finally after Jobe showered them with epithets,
they cut out his tongue. Not satisfied with this
they choked him to death with a rope. His body was
thrown into a deep sink hole. Luckily, Jobe '
s
clothing caught on the side of the hole, and his
family was able to find his body.
Most of the versions differ as to the manner of Jobe '
s
death. This can be explained by the number of years
transpiring between the actual deed and the relating of the
present versions which have probably been changed to some
extent or embellished with a hatred of the murderers. From
printed and oral sources it seems that he was either
hanged or strangled to death by a bridle rein or leather
strap, or hanged and then shot, or merely tortured to death.
There is a difference of opinion as to whether he was
captured during the day or at night, and whether he was
asleep at the time or not, and what disposition was made
of his body. The few people who are familiar with the
deed contend that his bravery and patriotism were as great
as that of Sam Davis, the Confederate boy hero.
Mechanicsville
Mechanicsville is thirteen and one-half miles from
Murfreesboro, in close proximity to Almaville and Rocky
Fork in Rutherford County, Tennessee. It gained this
49
sobriquet by virtue of the type of work carried on at the
Elihu Jobe home.
VJhen Elihu Jobe came to Rutherford County around 1840
and settled in the community soon to be known as Mechanics-ville,
he set up a cabinet shop. Among the products that
he made were plow points, wagon and buggy accessories,
furniture, and coffins. His children, both boys and
girls, helped in the shop. Price Jobe (Mrs. T. H.
Hollowell) and Kate Jobe were very adept in the work. Kate
Jobe was very skillful in lining and finishing coffins.
In the years before the Civil War, Elihu Jobe built a
number of additions to the shop but his work was disrupted
by the war. His sons enlisted and the mother and girls
were engaged in sewing and making clothing for the soldiers.
The community of Mechanicsville was progressive enough
to have a post office, but it was discontinued after the
war. The settlement is never spoken of as Mechanicsville
anymore except by older people who remember something of
its history. It is now known as Big Springs.
The Jobe House
The Jobe house was built in 1833. It is a large two-story
log house of six rooms. A long porch extends the
length of the front of the house. For about twenty-five
years the house has been occupied by various tenant farmers
50
WHERE DEVJITT JOBE WAS BORN
WHERE DEWITT JOBE WAS BURIED
51
and their families. One enterprising itinerant built a
small kitchen on the west end in 1918. Also in the span of
time the building has been weatherboarded and the roof
covered with tin. In places the unpainted boarding has
fallen off and the huge logs with much of the chinking still
intact can be seen. A large brick chimney has been built
on the side of the house opposite the large original stone
chimney which is still standing. In one corner of the front
lawn is a small building of large logs with the chinking
gone and the roof fallen in. This is all that is left of
Elihu Jobe ' s cabinet shop, and it is now used as a chicken
house.
The road to Rocky Fork now passes the rear of the house
since the thoroughfare has been rerouted. The premises
bear no marker by an organization and are in great need of
repair.
The Old Hearse Road
The old hearse road is now a path and hardly perceptible
in some places. It begins at the front of the Jobe home and
winds around a small hill through a level glade and ends
at a rail fence. Beyond this at a distance of approximately
fifty yards is the family burying ground.
52
The Family Burying Ground
About one-half mile from the house on a little knoll
is the burying ground. It is connected with the lowland
by a winding hearse road, now practically indistinguishable
in the underbrush and weeds.
There is no available record of a Jobe interment here
before 1864 when Dee Jobe was buried after his death at
Triune. There are evidences though of a number of bodies
having been interred here because of twenty-five or thirty
sandstone slabs still visible. The four graves of the
immediate family of Elihu Jobe are at the north end of the
grounds. The four members of the family buried here are:
Dewitt Jobe, 1864; Dewitt's mother, 1865; Lavenia (Mrs.
Edwards), 1875; and Dewitt's father, 1885. There are no
inscriptions on any of the slabs and there is no record as
to their identity.
Today it is difficult to find the graves. Trees and
bushes have pushed their way through the graves and most of
the slabs have fallen down. The grounds are in an isolated
spot, and no one has been buried there for more than fifty
years
.
Old settlers of the community say that the graveyard
was once inclosed within a fine looking fence made of
dressed cedar posts and connected by two lines of chain.
53
When the burying ground was deserted, the cedar posts
gradually disappeared and were used probably for firewood
by surrounding farm owners.
CHAPTER III
OTHER PATRIOTS OF RUTHERFORD COUNTY
Rutherford County was productive of patriots and
martyrs for the Southern cause as is evidenced by the fore-going
chapter on Dewitt Jobe and the present one on three
of his fellow scouts. Dee Smith, John Bowman, and Sam Davis.
Dee Smith
Dee Smith was a cousin of Dewitt Jobe. Between the two
there existed a close friendship. When Smith learned of the
bloody deed at Triune perpetrated against his intimate
cousin and friend, Dewitt Jobe, he became enraged. B. L.
Ridley, in his Journal , tells the story as follows:
There is a sequel to Jobe ' s tragic end that in
sentiment and devotion is as beautiful as that of
Damon and Pythias or of Jonathan and David. Jobe
had a kinsman and a brother scout, Dee Smith, a
neighbor and friend. When he was told of Jobe '
s
torture and persecution he grew desperate and his
mind became unhinged. He left the Forty-fifth
Tennessee Regiment near Chattanooga, raised the
black flag and declared that henceforth he would
never take a prisoner. It is asserted that he slew
not less than fifty of his enemies. At last they
surrounded him near Nolensville, Tennessee, and shot
him. Afterwards they brought him twenty miles from
Nolensville to Murf reesboro. Although in excruciating
pain when the doctors probed his wounds, he said that
he would die before his enemies should see him
flinch. Fortunately, he died before noon of the
next day, at which time he was to be hanged. &#8226;&#8226;&#8226;
B. L. Ridley, Battles and Sketches of the Army of
Tennessee (Mexico, Missouri: Missouri Printing &amp;
Publishing Co., 1906), pp. 503-04.
54
55
Mr. Sam Mitchell, ninety-seven, one of the two remaining
Confederate veterans in Rutherford County, Tennessee, tells
this story of Dee Smith:
When Dee Smith learned of his cousin's death,
he swore an oath that he would never take another
Yankee prisoner. Sometime during the night he
slipped away from his regiment at Chattanooga,
which was the Forty-fifth Tennessee, and headed
toward Rutherford County. A number of miles from
his army he secured a horse at a farmhouse and
spurred on until he came to Tullahoma. On the out-skirts
of this town he discovered the sleeping
camp of a small company of Yankee cavalry. He dis-mounted
outside the picket lines and managed to
slip into the camp. He crawled around in the darkness
until he found the mess tent. He rummaged around
until he discovered a large butcher knife, and arming
himself with this formidable v/eapon he crawled out
into the darkness outside the glare of the campfires.
In a few minutes he threaded himself back among the
rows of tents, each containing eight men. Here he
went about the methodical work of slitting the
throat of each sleeping man. Finished with this tent
he sought out another. Here he was in the act of
finishing off the fifteenth man when the single
live soldier stirred in his sleep and sat up. This
sent Smith into a panic. He sprang up and hurried
out of the tent. In searching for his horse, he
aroused the pickets who, discovering that the
stranger did not intend to halt, began firing. He
found his horse and scrambling on its back rode madly
out the road to Murf reesboro. The Yankee pursuers
said afterwards that Smith still carried a big
bloody butcher knife in his hand as he rode, waving
it menacingly in their direction. Somewhere past
Manchester Smith eluded his enemies and before many
hours was in Rutherford County.
While Smith was in Rutherford County he hid out in the
woods close to his home and close to the spot where his
friend, Jobe, was killed. Smith's neighbors and friends
gave him food for some time and a bed for the night. Smith
56
was constantly in danger of being apprehended by roving
bands of Yankees. He followed out his resolve to kill
every Yankee he met, and although fifty may have been a
slight exaggeration, without a doubt. Smith did murder a
great number. These two stories by Miss Jeanette King, as
told to her by her father, reveal something of Smith's
state of mind and his desire for revenge. The first
concerns Smith and two Yankees.
On the road between the Charles King home and
the Franklin Road bridge. Dee Smith surprised two
Yankee horsemen and forced them to dismount. Smith
carried two braces of pistols but no ammunition, so
he marched his captives down the road to the home
of an acquaintance. He ordered them to hold his
horse while he secured a meal. The two men had
evidently learned by this time that their captor
was the half-insane Dee Smith, so they acquiesced
obediently.
While Smith's friend, whose husband was away
in the army, prepared the meal, he preceeded to
mold bullets and load his pistols. At a little
distance from the house the two men stood by the
horse, glancing apprehensively in Smith's direction.
After eating. Smith tested his pistols and joined
the two men again. He directed them back in the
direction which they had previously traveled.
After going about one-half mile he ordered them to
halt with their eyes to the front. On the side of
the road was a shallow sink hole that had been
partly filled with soil from the rains. Smith drew
two of his pistols, took careful aim at the back
of the Yankees' heads, and fired. They crumpled to
the ground. He quickly scribbled two notes, and
after placing the murdered men on their backs and
in the^bottom of the hole, he secured the two
notes on the uniform of each. The paper bore this
legend:
"Part of the debt for my murdered friend.
Dee Jobe."
57
This is Miss King's story of Dee Smith and Mr. Puckett
as related to her by her father, Charles King:
Mr. Puckett was a Union sympathizer living on
the Franklin Road. He had sworn allegiance to the
Union a few months before and carried the papers
on his person. Smith in his most maniacal stage
since deserting the army met Puckett one day and
demanded to see his papers. Puckett produced them
with misgiving.
Smith then placed the barrel of his big horse
pistol against the temple of the sympathizer, and
demanded that he eat the papers. Puckett, knowing
Smith's state of mind, complied and after choking the
last fragment down his throat, asked,
"Dee, why did you make me do that?"
"Because you wouldn't let me run rabbits in
your pasture when I was a boy," Smith answered.
Smith developed a deep hatred for Union sympathizers.
A number of Rutherford countians had taken the Oath of
Allegiance to the United States, some by desire and some by
force. This is the oath as taken by Mr. Puckett and
others
:
I, . . ., solemnly swear, without any mental
reservation or evasion, that I will support the
Constitution of the United States and the laws
made in pursuance thereof; and that I will not take
up arms against the United States, or give aid or
comfort, or furnish information, directly or
indirectly, to any person or persons belonging to
any of the so-styled Confederate States who are now
or may be in rebellion against the United States.
So help me God.^
2
W. G. Stevenson, Thirteen Months in the Rebel Army
(London: Sampson, Low, Son &amp; Co., 1862), p. 223.
58
Mr. Tom Batey, who was a close friend to the Smith
family, tells two stories that are in keeping with Dee
Smith's temperament. The first is significant of the
legendary fear in which the deranged Confederate deserter
was held.
Dee Smith, while still a deserter from his
ranks and an avenged killer, stopped at Mr. Snell's
store on the Franklin Road to purchase some
tobacco. The storekeeper and a number of stragglers
noticed that he carried six pistols strapped around
his body besides a large musket in a sling across
his shoulder. After making his purchase he mounted
and rode away. Hardly had he vanished when a small
unit of Yankee cavalrymen rode down the road and
pulled up at the store. They inquired of Smith's
whereabouts and being told that he had been there a
moment ago, asked,
"Was he armed?"
The storekeeper answered that he carried six
pistols and a musket. The soldiers went into an
impromptu council of war and after a few moments of
deliberation turned their horses and headed back
toward Murfreesboro in a gallop.
Mr. Batey 's second story is one of many concerning
Smith's long list of victims.
One day while Rosecrans was occupying
Murfreesboro and adjoining territory and making
sporadic forays in search of Dee Smith, the hunted
man himself was crossing the ford on Stone's River
near where Franklin Road bridge now crosses the
stream. When Smith reached the middle of the
river, he was accosted by another horseman fording
from the opposite side. Smith discovered that the
man was a negro dressed in the brevets of a
corporal. The negro rode abreast of Smith and
demanded that he halt. Smith carried a small cap
and ball derringer with a single load and quickly
producing the gun fired at his would-be captor.
The ball entered the negro's throat below the chin
59
and tore out through his temple. He slumped off the
horse and sank from view in the water. Smith
shouted, "By God, you saved Rosecran's life." Smith
had been carrying the single-barreled firearm for
some time in hopes of assassinating the Yankee
General, Rosecrans.
When Smith was finally captured at Nolensville, in
Williamson County, Tennessee, and brought to Murfreesboro
for execution, he was mortally wounded. It is said that
during the night preceding his execution some friends came
to visit him and gave him a drug that would hasten his
death, so that he would not die at the hands of the Yankees
the following day. Smith did succumb before the appointed
hour.
John Bowman
John Bowman, a member of Colonel Paul Anderson's
cavalry, was cut off in Hood's retreat and took shelter near
Murfreesboro, his home. The Federals caught him near
Drennon, a town midway between Murfreesboro and Lebanon,
tied him to a tree, and threatened to kill him. Instead
of begging for his life. Bowman defied his captors and
heaped epithets upon them until they, in frenzied rage,
riddled him with bullets. The following is one of
Bowman's exploits as a soldier as given in B. L. Ridley's
Journal
:
60
I had an experience with Bowman in 1866 that
showed his recklessness and want of fear. While
Hood was environing Nashville and Forrest was
dashing upon Murf reesboro, seventy-five "Yanks"
had been in a block-house near Smyrna depot, guarding
the railroad between Nashville and Murfreesboro.
Things were getting so "squally" that they left their
fortress at Murf reesboro. Four Rebs had skipped
through from Hood's army to see homefolks, John
Bowman among them. They looked up the pike and saw
it black with blue coats. The idea was that naturally
they were so badly frightened a shot or two would
stampede them, and that we would get at least their
wagons and teams. Knowing every pig path, the four
Rebs rushed through the cedars and ensconced them-selves
in a thicket on Searcy's farm alongside the
old road. As the seventy-five marched along, each
Reb on his horse drew his Navy and fired. Did they
run; Well, never in the wide world. I can hear that
Yankee officer now cry, "Haiti Right wheel! Fire!"
They peeled the saplings, made shot holes
through our clothes and saddles; it looked like
demons had turned loose upon us, and it seemed that
they would kill me in spite of fate. We got over
the hill after a time; they did not pursue us nor
did we pursue them. Bowman wanted to go back and
attack again, but the rest of us demurred. We dubbed
that battle, "Hardup," for if ever there was a hard
time getting out of a thicket, that was one. Capture
"Yanks?" No, we were glad enough to save our
scalps. It was John Bowman's recklessness that
induced four of us to attack seventy-five! One of
the young men, only fourteen at that time (Dr. G. W.
Crosthwait, of Florence, Tennessee, and who received
only this baptism of fire during the great war) , often
now speaks of the battle of "Hardup" as one which
ought to be recorded.-^
Sam Davis
The best known of Rutherford County patriots is Sam
Davis. His patriotic sacrifice during the Civil Was has
&#8226;^Ridley, pp. 506-08.
61
since stirred many writers to pen eulogic words in praise
of his act. Accounts of the incident have been incorporated
into various book supplements. Robert H. White's Tennessee ,
Its Growth and Progress , a state adopted textbook published
in 1936, carries an account of the deed.
The life and story of the execution at Pulaski, Giles
County, Tennessee, November 27, 1863, is well known. Davis
was born October 6, 1842, near Smyrna, Rutherford County,
Tennessee. He spent his early boyhood working on his
father's farm. At the outbreak of the war, Davis was a
student at the Western Military Institute (now Montgomery
Bell Academy), at Nashville, Tennessee. His instructors
were Bushrod R. Johnson and Edmond Kirby Smith, later to
distinguish themselves as officers in the Confederate Army.
Davis enlisted in the First Regiment of Infantry. His work
proved so good that when Bragg organized a company of
scouts in 1863 Davis was recommended as a member. This
company, distinguished as "Coleman's Scouts" from a
nonemclature of Captain H. B. Shaw, came under the personal
direction of General B. F. Cheatham.
These scouts, especially active in Middle Tennessee,
worked in and around the Federal lines securing information
from friends and by observation of the general status of
the enemy. It was sometimes necessary for them to sleep
62
in thickets and caves and secure food from loyal friends
in the territory that they traversed.
The latter part of 1863 General G. M. Dodge, with a
large command, was stationed at Pulaski in Giles County,
Tennessee. This was an expediency by the Federal authori-ties
to keep open to the Confederacy the Louisville and
Nashville Railroad. General Bragg became anxious to
ascertain the movements of his enemy, therefore he dis-patched
Captain Shaw and some of his scouts to this vicinity.
It is said that Shaw entered the occupied town of Pulaski in
the guise of an herb doctor and was able to secure first-hand
information as to numbers, supplies, etc. It is said
that Dodge had recently received a very important dispatch
from headquarters that contained very vital statistics
relative to his position and orders for further occupation.
How Shaw managed to secure the valuable information has
never been told. It has been said that a negro servant
employed about the camp found the papers on the general's
desk and carried them away to Shaw. There is another
version of the incident which involved a young woman. This
young woman inveigled a soldier about the camp into bringing
the papers to her. Since she was a friend to the chief of
the scouts, it was an easy matter to convey the valuable
information to him. At any rate, Shaw, by some ruse,
secured the papers and with some other information.
63
including a letter to General Bragg, succeeded in getting
the reports in the hands of Davis on November 19, 1863.
It was Davis' task to carry these through the Federal lines
to the Confederate encampment at Chattanooga. He secreted
the dangerous papers in his shoes and saddle. It was a
difficult undertaking as the countryside was thick with
patrolling cavalrymen. He had traveled only a short
distance when he circled a dense thicket of woods and came
almost face to face with a small unit of cavalrymen. This
unit proved to be a part of the "Kansas Jayhawkers"
(Seventh Kansas Cavalry) which was scouring the country in
search of scouts. Davis was searched and the papers found.
One of the letters found in his boot was a communication
to Colonel A. McKinstry, Provost Marshal-General, Army of
the Tennessee at Chattanooga.
Giles County, Tennessee
Thursday morning,
Nov. 18, 1863
Colonel A. McKinstry
Provost Marshal-General
The Army of Tennessee,
Chattanooga.
Dear Sir: &#8212;I send you seven Nashville and three
Louisville papers and one Cincinnati, with dates
to the 17th, in all eleven. I also send for
General Bragg, three wash-balls of soap, three
tooth brushes and two blank books. I could not
get a larger size diary for him. I will send a
pair of shoes and slippers, some more soap, gloves
and socks soon.
64
The Yankees are still camped on the line of the
Tennessee and Alabama Railroad. General Dodge's
headquarters are at Pulaski; his main force is
camped from that place to Lynville; some at Elk
River, and two regiments at Athens. General Dodge
has issued an order to the people in those counties
to report all stock, grain and forage to him and he
says he will pay or give vouchers for it. Upon
refusal to report he will take it without pay.
They are now taking all they can find. Dodge says
he knows the people are all Southern and does not
ask them to swear a lie. All the spare forces
around Nashville and vicinity are being sent forward
to McMinnville. Six batteries and twelve parrott
guns were sent forward on the 14th, 15th, and 16th.
It is understood that there is hot work in front
somewhere. Telegrams suppressed.
Davis has returned; Gregg has gone below. Everything
is beginning to work better. I send Roberts with
things for you and General Bragg with dispatches. I
do not think the Federals mean to stay; they are not
repairing the main points on the road. I understand
part of Sherman's forces have reached Shelbyville.
I think a part of some other than Dodge's division
came to Lynville from the direction of Fayeteville.
I hope to be able to post you soon. I sent Billy
Moore over in that country and am sorry to say he
was captured. One of my men has just returned from
there. The general impression of the citizens is
that they will move forward some way. Their wagon
trains have returned from Nashville. Davis tells
me that the line is in order to Summerville. I send
this by one of my men to that place. The dispatches
sent you on November 9, with the papers of November 7,
reached Decatur on November 10. Citizens were reading
the papers the next morning after breakfast. I do
not think the Mayor will do to forward them reports.
I am with high regard,
E. Coleman, .
Captain Commanding Scouts.
^Ridley, pp. 260-61.
65
Sam Davis was inmediately arrainged before General Dodge,
who, realizing that the information came from someone close
to the headquarters, questioned him as to the source. Davis
naturally refused to divulge the secret.
After Dodge's efforts to extricate the information
proved futile, a commission was chosen for a court martial
to try the captive. It is an extraordinary fact that
Captain H. B. Shaw was captured at the same time as a person
of suspicious character and was in the same cell with Davis.
No evidence of recognition passed between the two men.
Joshua Brown, who was also in the cell with Davis, gives
an account as was related to him by Dodge some months
later.
The next morning Davis was again taken to
General Dodge's headquarters, and this is what took
place between them which General Dodge told me
occured:
"I took him. into my private office, and told
him that it was a very serious charge brought
against him; that he was a spy, and from what I
found upon his person he had accurate information
in regard to my army, and I must know where he
obtained it. I told him that he was a young man,
and did not seem to realize the danger he was in.
Up to that time he had said nothing, but then he
replied in the most respectful and dignified manner:
'General Dodge, I know the danger of my situation,
and I am willing to take the consequences.' I asked
him then to give me the name of the person from
whom he got the information; that I knew it must
be some one near my headquarters or who had the
confidence of the officers of my staff, and repeated
that I must know the source from which it came. I
insisted that he should tell me, but he firmly
declined to do so. I told him that I should have to
66
call a court-martial and have him tried for his life,
and from the proofs we had, they would be compelled
to condemn him; that there was no chance for him
unless he gave the source of his information. He
replied: 'I know that I will have to die, but I
will not tell where I got the information, and
there is no power on earth that can make me tell.
You are doing your duty as a soldier, and I am doing
mine. If I have to die, I do so feeling that I am
doing my duty to God and my country .
' I pleaded with
and urged him with all the power I possessed to give
him some chance to save his life, for I discovered
that he was a most admirable young fellow, with the
highest character and strictest integrity. He then
said: 'It is useless to talk to me. I do not
intend to do it. You can court-martial me, or do
anything else you like, but I will not betray the
trust reposed in me.' He thanked me for the interest
I had taken in him, and I sent him back to prison. I
immediately called a court-martial to try him."^
The action of the court-martial, November 26, 1863, was
to sentence Davis to be hanged the following morning. It is
said that Davis evidenced no fear when informed of his
fate. He sat down that night and wrote a letter to his
mother. It reveals a calmness that is remarkable for a
man as young as Davis. The letter which follows was
taken from the Confederate Veteran .
Pulaski, Giles County, Tenn.,
November 26, 1863.
Dear Mother: O, how painful it is to write you!
I have got to die to-morrow&#8212;to be hanged by the
Federals. Mother, do not grieve for me. I do
not fear to die. Give my love to all.
Your son, Samuel Davis.
^S. A. Cunningham, "Sam Davis" ( Confederate Veteran ,
VII, No. 12 (1899) , 540.
67
Mother, tell the children all to be good. I wish
I could see you all once more, but I never will any
more. Mother and father, do not forget me. Think
of me when I am dead, but do not grieve for me.
It will not do any good. Father, you can send after
my remains if you want to do so. They will be at
Pulaski, Tennessee. I will leave some things, too,
with the hotel keeper for you. Pulaski is in Giles
County, Tennessee, south of Columbia.
S. D.6
Joshua Brown, a scout and an eyewitness to the
execution, tells this story of succeeding events:
After his sentence, he was put into a cell in
jail, and we did not see anything of him until on
Thursday morning, the day before the execution.
We were ordered to get ready to be removed from the
jail to the courthouse in the public square. Davis
was handcuffed and brought in just as we were eating
breakfast. I gave him a piece of meat that I had
been cooking, and he, being handcuffed, was compelled
to eat it with both hands. He thanked me, and we
all bade him good-by. The guard was doubled around
the jail.
The next morning, Friday, November 27, at ten
o'clock, we heard the drums, and a regiment of
infantry marched down to the jail, and a wagon with
a coffin in it was driven up, and the provost
marshall went into the jail and brought Davis out.
He got into the wagon, stood up, and looked around
at the courthouse, and, seeing us at the windows,
bowed to us his last farewell. He was dressed in a
blue Federal coat, such as many of us had captured
and then dyed brown.
Upon reaching the gallows Davis got out of
the wagon and took his seat on a bench under the
tree. He asked Captain Armstrong how long he had
to live. He replied: "Fifteen minutes." He then
asked him the news, and Armstrong told him of the
battle of Missionary Ridge, and that our army had
been defeated. He expressed much regret, adding:
Cunningham, p. 54 0.
68
"The boys will have to fight the battles without
me." Armstrong said: "I regret very much having to
do this. I feel that I would rather die myself
than do what I have to do." Davis replied: "I do
not think hard of you; you are doing your duty."
General Dodge still had hopes that Davis
would recant when he saw that death was staring him
in the face, and that he would reveal the name of
the "traitor in his camp." He sent Captain
Chickasaw, of his staff, to Davis. He rapidly
approached the scaffold, jumped from his horse, and
went directly to Davis, placed his hand on Davis'
shoulder, and asked if it would not be better for
him to speak the name of the one from whom he
received the documents found upon him, adding: "It
is not too late yet." And then, in his last extremity,
Davis turned upon him and said: "If I had a thousand
lives, I would lose them all here and now before I
would betray my friends or the confidence of my
informer.
"
Davis then turned to the provost marshal saying:
"I am ready," ascended the scaffold, and stepped
upon the trap.
7
Mrs, Oscar H. Davis, Sr., sister-in-law of Sam Davis,
issued privately a pamphlet concerning the brave act of her
kinsman. She says that Davis wrote a short letter to his
mother five minutes before he fell through the trap to
his death.
Dear Mother: I have five minutes to live and will
spend it in writing to you. I don't want you to
grieve after me. I don't only feel I am doing my
country's bidding, but that all Heaven is sanctioning
the act I am about to take. I have asked the
chaplain to sing "On Jordan's stormy banks I stand
Cunningham, p. 540.
69
and cast a wistful eye to Canaan's fair and happy
land where my possessions lie."
S. D.^
After his body was cut down and placed in the coffin,
it was interred in a grave close to the scene of the
execution.
Communication was hampered in the absence of regular
mail service, and it was some days before the Davis family
learned of the fate of their son. When the letters finally
reached them, Sam's father send John C. Kennedy and Oscar H.
Davis, Sam's younger brother, to Pulaski to bring the body
home for burial. They went into Pulaski and opened the
grave, and after removing the top of the old box coffin,
they lifted Sam's body out and placed it in the casket they
had b:fought with them. On their return home they were
forced to cross Duck River on a flat boat since all of the
bridges were burned. There they found a number of army
wagons belonging to the Yankees being moved over the same
river. Mrs. Davis gives the following incident:
Some of the soldiers, seeing the wagon with
its cargo, sent one of their number to investigate
the identity and course of the two men. The
soldier came up to the wagon and said, "Whose wagon
is this?"
Kennedy answered, "This is young Davis you all
hanged out here a few days ago. We are carrying
him home for burial."
Mrs. Oscar M. Davis, Sr., Last Few Days of the Life of
Sam Davis (Place of publication, Publisher, and date,
unknown) , p. 2
.
70
The soldier went down to the flat boat and told
the other men. They readily made room for the wagon
to pass over, and Oscar Davis says that every hat
was off in respect to the dead boy. Two soldiers
walking beside the wagon were overheard talking. One
said to the other, "We will have to suffer for this,"
meaning the execution of Sam Davis.
^
Davis was buried in the graveyard at the rear of the
home. A number of years ago the state purchased the site
and improved the grounds. Today it is a historic spot
visited by thousands of tourists each year. A fine
memorial highway branches off from the Nashville Highway
and passes by the house.
Mrs. Davis tells of an experience with Van Pelt, the
soldier that pulled the death rope at Pulaski.
One Sunday morning, quite a long time ago,
since I have been living at the old Davis home, the
front door bell rang. Mr. Davis (my husband) went
to answer the ring and met there a man who said,
"Mr. Davis, my name is Van Pelt."
Mr. Davis said, "Come in, but I'll have to take
you to the family room as there is no fire in the
front of the house."
The man answered, "That is where I want to go."
Mr. Davis could not understand why he said that,
but they came in. When asked to have a seat, Mr. Van
Pelt instead leaned his head upon his arm against
the mantel piece. We couldn't think what the trouble
could be until he turned around and said, "Mr. Davis,
I'll have to explain. I'm the man who pulled the
rope that broke Sam Davis's neck." He showed in
every way a great grief. Later he told us that his
business sent him to Nashville, and that he couldn't
9Mrs. Oscar M. Davis, Sr., pp. 2-3.
71
return to Detroit without seeing where Sam Davis
rested. He, upon being asked, remained to dinner and
talked most courteously with the manner and appear-ance
of a well-educated gentleman. He said that he
had tried to pay out of the duty of executing Sam
Davis, but the captain would not release him from the
the task.-^"
The spot where Davis is buried is about fifty yards to
the rear of the house and is marked by a shaft of white
marble about twelve feet high and resting on a granite
pedestal. This marker was made possible by contributions
from Confederate veterans and friends of Davis. The
inscription on the marker reads:
In
Memory of Samuel Davis
A member of the 1st
Tennessee Regiment of Volunteers
Born October 6th, 1842
Died November 27th, 1863
Age
21 years 1 month and 21 days
He laid down his life for his country
A truer soldier, a purer patriot, a
braver man never lived who
suffered death on the gibbet rather
than betray his friends and country.
There are other monuments that have been erected to
Davis' memory. In Pulaski and its vicinity there are three
monuments: one on the public square, one at the spot of
execution, and another at the place where he is supposed to
10
Mrs. Oscar M. Davis, Sr., pp. 2-3.
Copied from the marker at Sam Davis' grave, Smyrna,
Tennessee.
72
have been captured by the Yankees. An excellent statue,
made possible by contributions of friends, reposes on the
Capitol grounds in Nashville. It is an established fact
that no picture of Davis is extant. it is highly possible
that none was ever made. When agitation arose for a statue
in Nashville, the promoters were in quandary as to the
features that the statue would carry. Miss Jeanette King
and other United Daughters of the Confederacy of Murfrees-boro
say that when Zolnay, the famous sculptor, came down
from New York to fashion the statue he demanded some copy
to follow in his work. There was much discussion as to what
disposition would be made of the matter, when it was
recalled that one of Davis' sisters. Miss Andromedia Davis,
bore a close resemblance to her brother. A portrait was
painted of her and Zolnay used this as his model.
There have been a great number of poems written to
Davis' memory. Five of these efforts, collected from
various sources, have been included in this study. The
following poem by Ella Wheeler Wilcox was copied from the
bronze tablet on the Sam Davis monument on the Capitol
grounds at Nashville, Tennessee:
Sam Davis
When the Lord calls up earth's heroes.
To stand before his face:
O, many a name, unknown to fame
73
Shall ring from that high place;
Then out of a grave in the Southland
At the just God's call and beck,
Shall one man rise with fearless eyes
With a rope about his neck;
Southland! Bring your laurels.
And add your wreath, O North!
Let glory claim the hero's name
And tell the world his worth.
On a visit to St. Paul, Minnesota, in May, 1906, B. L.
Ridley related to A. S. Morton, a poet friend, the story of
Sam Davis. It is said that the story affected the poet so
much that Morton wrote and gave to B. L. Ridley a poem
concerning the incident. Although the poem is written by a
Northern man the feeling expressed in it is none the less
worthy of the Southern hero.
Sam Davis Was Too Brave To Die
A fitful gleam of dying light.
The herald of a gloomy night
Illumed the thrilling scene
&#8212;
A silent group of men-at-arms,
A guard inured to war's alarms,
A captive scout between.
"Your life I give," the leader said,
"For ^traitor ' s name, to honor:.dead.
Who gave you this design?"
A flush o'erspread the captive's cheek;
"My life is yours, your vengeance wreak.
But honor still is mine."
"A soldier I, this dress of gray
Proclaims the truth of that I say:
This life I hate to yield.
But you have asked too great a price;
Dishonor ne'er was the device
Emblazoned on my shield."
74
"He chooses death, your orders, men,"
The captor grimly said, and then
The fateful noose was brought.
"Again I offer, soldier, free.
Your life if you but name to me
The traitor you have bought."
The loop of death was 'round his throat;
The captive smiled, nor seemed to note
The moments' fleeting speed.
"I scorn to buy the life you take
At price of faith," 'twas thus he spake;
"It were a coward's deed."
With curling lip and flashing eye.
His knightly head uplifted high.
As though 'twould death defy.
He spoke the noblest words e'er penned
&#8212;
"Before these lips betray a friend,
I tell you I will die."
From flashing eye the tears now start
&#8212;
Those tears for mother's broken heart.
He tears his buttons loose:
"I pray you these my mother bear."
A moment spared for silent prayer,
He dangles at the noose.
That fatal noose is glorified.
For thro' its port the deified.
Heroic soul did fly.
His proudest epitaph, the vain
Remorse of him who judged the slain:
"Too brave, too brave to die. "12
The poem which follows was published in April, 1869,
and signed by Louise who, it is said, was the sweetheart of
Sam Davis:
A Tribute
Highest on the head roll of fame.
The name of Davis shines as bright
As yon stars that luminous flame.
12Ridley, pp. 273-74
75
On the sable brow of night!
With the undimmed glory radiant,
'Twill forever brightly shine,
Won from life&#8212;to liberty lent
&#8212;
A noble death for truth divine.
No hero of the ancient orient
Could such unyielding valor boast.
As that boy, whose deeds resplendent
Glory won for the cause now lost.
Ere life had reached youth's full tide,
He left his home and mother dear;
With Spartan valor and manly price
He grasped his shield&#8212;made foeman fear,
When on Pulaski's fatal field
He was seized and held a spy
&#8212;
Told he must not the traitor shield,
Or most surely he must die!
He asked, "How many hours have I?"
"Ten minutes more to you remain!"
"Tell them no! I can dare to die!
I'll not my proud escutcheon stain!"
Homage to his country he did lend
&#8212;
Ne'er cowered in the deadly fight.
And died rather than betray a friend,
For God, liberty and the right!
When life to him was offered as the price
Of honor, plighted faith and truth.
For another he paid the sacrifice
How bravely died the Southern youth.
Memorial incense shall ever rise
From the dust of the martyr's tomb.
While honor gilds the deathless prize
For glory of his tragic doom!
No prouder name among the brave
Who died to save their truth
A holocaust on liberty's grave.
Offered by that noble Southern youth.
Immortal truth can never die,
Although its light awhile may dim.
For vice and error it will outvie
If faith its vestal fires shall trim!
76
With silent harps along the strand,
Still girt with immortal truth,
Downtrodden Tennessee shall stand.
And with new reviving youth! ^3
In October, 1892, J. M. King, Jr., of Murf reesboro,
Tennessee, made a plea for recognition of Sam Davis. This
was delivered before the Erosophian Society of the Univer-sity
of Nashville. Included in this address was a poem by
Margaret Preston:
A Hero of Heroes
Only a private--who will care
When I pass away.
Or how, or where I perish, or where
I mix with the common clay?
IPhey will fill my empty place again
With another as bold and brave.
And they'll blot me out ere the autumn rain
Has freshened my nameless grave.
Only a private&#8212;it matters not
That I did my duty well.
That all through a score of battles I fought.
And then, like a soldier fell.
The country I died for never will heed
My unrequited claim;
And history cannot record the deed.
For she has never heard my name.
Only a private&#8212;and yet I know
When I heard the rallying call
I was one of the first to go.
And I am one of the many who fall.
But here as I lie, it is well to feel
That my honor's without stain.
13Jeanette King, Murf reesboro, Tennessee, "A Civil War
Scrap Book.
"
77
That I only fought for our contry's weal.
And not for glory or gain.
Only a private&#8212;yet he who reads
Through the guises of the heart,
Looks not at the splendor of the deeds.
But the way we do our part.
And when He shall take us by the hand
And our service own.
There shall be a glorious band of privates stand
As victors around the throne. ^^
One of the best known poems dealing with Sam Davis is
the one by John Trotwood Moore. For many years this poem
was recited at the annual memorial services held at the
Sam Davis home.
Sam Davis
"Tell me his name, and you are free,"
The general said, while from the tree
The grim rope dangled threat 'ningly.
The birds ceased singing&#8212;happy birds.
That sang of home and mother-words.
That sunshine kissed his cheek&#8212;dear sun.
It loves a life that's just begun!
The very breezes held their breath
To watch the fight ' twixt life and death.
But 0, how calm and\ sweet and free
Smiled back the hills of Tennessee!
Smiled back the hills as if to say,
"0, save your life for us today."
"Tell me his name and you are free,"
The general said, "and I shall see
You safe within the rebel line
&#8212;
I'd love to save such life as thine."
A tear gleamed down the ranks of blue
&#8212;
(The bayonets were tipped with dew)
,
Across the rugged cheek of war
God's angels rolled a teary star.
14&#8222;. King.
78
The boy looked up&#8212; 'twas this they heard:
"And would you have me break my word?"
A tear stood in the general's eye:
"My boy, I hate to see thee die
&#8212;
Give me the traitor's name&#8212;and flyl"
Young Davis smiled, as calm and free
As He who walked on Galilee:
"Had I a thousand lives to give,
I'd lose them&#8212;nay, I'd gladly die
Before I'd live one life, a lie!"
He turned&#8212;for not a soldier stirred
&#8212;
"Your duty, men&#8212;I gave my word."
The hills smiled back a farewell smile
The breeze sobbed o'er his hair awhile.
The birds broke out in sad refrain.
The sunbeam kissed his cheek again
&#8212;
When gathering up their blazing bars.
They shook his name among the stars.
0, stars, that now his brothers are,
O, sun, his sire, in truth and light.
Go tell the list'ning worlds afar
Of him who died for truth and right!
For martyr of all martyrs he
Who dies to save an enemy.
15King.
CHAPTER IV
LEGENDS AND STORIES OF CIVIL WAR RUTHERFORD COUNTY
As the smell of powder becomes fainter and the rattle
of cannon dies in a fading echo, minds become dimmer and
reminiscences come more slowly and less coherently. Stories
and legends of the Civil War in Rutherford County are dying
with the years. A little while longer and the few published
snatches of fact here and there will be all that is left.
The following legends and stories have been collected
through personal interviews, from scrap books on the Civil
War, and from published sources.
Mollie Nelson
There's a well-known story that is recounted when
Forrest's raid on Murfreesboro, April 13, 1862, is mentioned.
It is a true story because one of the characters still lives
in Murf reesboro, virtually on the same spot v/here the
incident occurred, and she will verify its authenticity.
The Yankees had occupied Murfreesboro for a number of
months before the great Battle of Stone's River of 1862-63.
There were various encampments of soldiers scattered over
the town. A large company had pitched their tents on the
courthouse lawn. All of the hostelries and some of the
79
80
private homes were occupied by officers. Martial law
prevailed on the streets. The citizens were subjected to
many insults and no service was tendered to anyone unless
an Oath of Allegiance to the Union was made. Those who
cried out against the unjust acts were imprisoned in the
jail or courthouse to await trial.
Today there is a large ornate house on East Main
Street about two blocks from the front door of the court-house.
It was built some years after the Civil War by
Dr. John Nelson, now deceased. Dr. Nelson's aged wife lives
in the house today, a vestige of the harrowing days of
1861-65. During the war she was a young girl, Mollie
Nelson, living in a large two-story brick house that sat
flush with the brick walk just a few steps in front of
the house of today. Her father owned a number of slaves
who remained loyal and refused to run away even when the
Yankees dominated the town. Included in the group of
negroes was a large number of children. Mollie played with
these little black slaves constantly. Most of the time
they frolicked Jon the wide brick walk in front of the
house. Yankee officers occupied most of the rooms in the
back of the house and they commanded the children to stay
out of the back yard as they were prone to sleep late and
the noise disturbed them.
81
On the morning of April 13, 1862, Mollie and her
playmates failed to converge at their favorite spot for a
long time. Early in the morning the populace had been
shaken out of their sleep by the crash of firearms and the
rattle of horses' hoofs. Bedford Forrest and his cavalry
had surprised the Yankee garrison. Molly heard the Yankee
officers upstairs rushing around in the haste of dressing
themselves. She heard their loud profanity as they condemned
Forrest to an ultra-southern clime. Finally they clamored
down the stairs and hurried away to assemble their commands.
Firing continued most of the morning. Yankee snipers
kept up a sporadic fire from buildings and private houses.
Mollie, not realizing the danger of a stray bullet, was
interested in joining her little black playmates in front of
the house. Collecting her friends and in disobedience to
her parents, she assumed the accustomed spot on the brick
v/alk in front of the house. She was having a good time in
general in the noise and confusion when a Yankee sniper
from a window in the house next door shot point-blank into
the midst of the children. It was probable that his aim
was directed at a spot farther down the street, but neverthe-less
the bullet found its mark in the group of children.
Mollie was the unlucky victim. The minie ball tore through
her throat, crashing out through the jawbone, barely
82
missing the jugular vein. She screamed and ran into the
house leaving a stream of blood in her wake. The family
gathered frantically around her. It was evident that the
wound was dangerous and would prove fatal if medical aid was
not secured. By this time a number of Yankee soldiers had
entered the house to witness the excitement. Mollie was
now lying on a divan in the hall. A blood soaked cloth
was wrapped around her throat. Her father resolved to get
a doctor, regardless of the penalty, considering he had not
as yet taken an Oath of Allegiance to the Union. As he
started to leave the room, one of the soldiers seized him
roughly,
"Where you're going?" he demanded.
"I'm going for a doctor. My child is dying."
"Ain't you refused to take the Oath of Allegiance?"
asked the soldier.
"Yes."
"Well, you don't go after no doctor."
"But my child will die. She must have medical
attention. You damn Yankees are responsible for it."
"Don't make no difference. It'll teach you rebels a
lesson. She'll have to get along as best she can."
Then Mollie lingered on for a few days in a wild
oblivion. She was at the point of death constantly.
Finally, a young officer, one of the occupants of the
83
Nelson home, broke under the strain and procured a physician.
Mollie, after expert medical attention, regained her strength
and slowly recovered. Her father, as a result of the
incident, was marched to the courthouse and forced to take
the Oath of Allegiance,
Mrs. Nelson today enjoys talking about her experience.
She has an ugly souvenir of the incident, too. There still
remains the livid scar on her neck from a wound that almost
left her on the fatal roll of the two battles of
Murf reesboro.
Mary Dean Arnold
The Civil War came to an end approximately seventy-five
years ago. It is remarkable to discover that fires
still burn unabated in the hearts of many. When the stories
are recounted there is a quickening of the pulse and a
brightening of the eyes. Sometimes the teller will lean
forward tensely and a tremble will pass through his body as
he utters "the damn Yankees."
Mrs. Hallie Hunt Edwards, of Murf reesboro, whose father
was a captain in the Confederate Army, and whose mother
went to an early grave as a result of maltreatment from
Yankee soldiers, tells with a certain amount of fire
stories related to her by her mother.
84
Her grandfather. Captain Ed Arnold, at the time of the
war, lived about one mile east of Murfreesboro on the
Woodbury Pike. The old home still stands and is in good
condition.
At the time the Federals were occupying Rutherford
County, Tennessee, the farmhouses and fields were constant
recipients of raids by roving bands of soldiers. Very
little, if any, resistance could be offered as most of the
able-bodied men were away in the ranks. It was a habit of
Captain Arnold to make periodic visits to his home and this
the enemy knew. Acting on a false clue, one day a
Federal officer drew up his horse in the Arnold yard and
fired two rapid shots. In a few moments the house was
completely surrounded by "blue coats." Mrs. Arnold
gathered her children in the kitchen and awaited the action
of the soldiers. In a loud voice the commander of the
group demanded that Captain Arnold come out of the house,
adding that if he refused they would fire upon the house.
Mrs. Arnold answered in a voice without any evidence of fear
that he was not in the house.
"You lie," answered the officer and began firing.
Unluckily, Mary Dean, the twelve year old daughter, was near
the kitchen door that was standing slightly ajar and
caught one of the minie balls in her side. She fell to
the floor, a large crimson spot forming on her dress.
85
Mrs. Arnold picked up her daughter and placed her on the bed
in the front room. She then ran to a window and raising it
with a flourish attacked the soldiers in a vituperative
voice
.
"You dirty rascals, you've shot my daugher."
The soldier nearest the window answered with a sneer,
"A young 'un with the name of Arnold don't deserve any
better fare. Madam."
Mrs. Arnold continued, "She'll die without a doctor,
die right in that bed she's lying on now. Captain Arnold's
not here, but when he does come you will know about it."
One of the soldiers who had been listening, dismounted
and with a histrionic bow, said,
"Why Madam, I'm a doctor."
"You'll not touch my daughter," Mrs. Arnold shouted,
and she ran to the door to bar it. But the self-imposed
doctor, with the rest of the company who refused to miss
the fun, pushed open the door and brushed Mrs. Arnold aside.
The soldier walked over to the bed where the child was
suffering intense pain. He removed a stubby pencil from
his coat and with this began probing the wound. In a few
minutes the flat minie ball fell out on the floor and the
soldier straightened with a triumphant grin on his face.
86
"Who's been saying I ain't a doctor?"
This twelve year old girl escaped blood poisoning and
recovered. Mrs. Edwards says that wound bothered her
mother for the remainder of her life and probably caused
an early death.
The soldier who fired the ball into the kitchen was
termed a "home-made" Yankee, one who resided in the county
and joined the Federal Army while it occupied Rutherford
County. A number of years later when this same soldier
was on his deathbed, he sent word to Captain Arnold that he
must see him before he passed away. Captain Arnold refused.
Grandma and the Yankee
Grandma Arnold, the mother of Mrs. Hallie Hunt Edwards,
carried a bowie-knife strapped around her waist. She was
prepared for the worst, for there was no telling v;hen the
Yankees would storm into the yard, get off their horses, and
start mistreating the children. One day while grandma
was bathing Mary Dean's v;ound, given to her by a dirty
Yankee, she heard a loud knocking at the door. Grandma was
a little slow about answering the knock and whoever it was
hammered so hard that the door almost fell off its hinges.
When the door was finally opened, there stood a big Yankee
all decked out in blue. He said to grandma.
87
"Got any meat in there, old lady?"
Grandma asked him what difference that was to him,
meanwhile feeling of the big sharp knife at her side. The
soldier didn't like grandma's tone, so he walked in, giving
her a big push to get her out of the way. That made grandma
angry and she thought this was as good a time as any to
make a reputation. The soldier didn't examine any of the
rooms downstairs but started to the second floor. Grandma
pulled out the knife and made for the stairs in a trot.
Just about the time grandma got in good striking distance
for a jab through the short ribs, the soldier turned just
in time. The knife whistled through the air in a ii/ide arc
and struck the rail of the stairs. With such terrific
force did she swing the knife that v;hen it struck it cut off
fully eight inches of the railing. The soldier seeing
that grandma was in earnest very quickly found the door and
his horse. Grandma could hear his horse beating a tatoo
down the road.
William Arnold
William Arnold, an uncle of Mrs. Edv/ards, served as
a scout in the war. He was killed by the Yankees near
Milton, Tennessee, while asleep under a tree.
One day during the early part of the war, William was
scouting around Milton, Tennessee, near the eastern edge
of the county. It was a dangerous undertaking as the scrub
cedars and glades were thick with Yankees. Seeing a log
house half hidden in the bushes, he stopped and inquired of
the occupant, who happened to be an old lady, if any
Yankees had been seen in the neighborhood. She replied
that the country was thick with them. He had been talking
to her only a short time when he heard the clatter of
hoofs. The old lady shouted,
"Son, you'd better get in this house quick!"
William ran into the house. In short time his
benef actoress had him tucked snugly in bed with a lace
night cap covering his head. She patted his head and said,
"There ain't nothing the matter with you that can't be
cured by a little Yankee bumdoozling, daughter."
In a few minutes a number of Yankee horsemen pulled
up to the cabin and dismounted. They pushed open the door
and walked inside.
"Seen any rebel in these parts?" one of the soldiers
asked.
"No," the old lady answered, "been too busy looking
after my daughter. She's powerful porely."
The Yankees took one look at the reposing figure and
left probably with the feeling that the ailing daughter,
because of her size, made a fine hand at shocking corn
when she was in better health.
89
Two Letters
Mr. J. 0. Abernathy of Murf reesboro, Tennessee, has
in his possession two letters that were written by his
uncle, A. A. Abernathy, during the war. A. A. Abernathy
was a resident of Rutherford County, Tennessee, and was
killed at the Battle of Stone's River. These two letters
give a graphic picture of camp and prison life. The first
was written from Bowling Green, Kentucky, and presents a
rather whimsical picture of food shortage and camp routine.
Bowling Green, Nov. 15, 1861
Dear Mother:
This day being set apart by our Colonel for
washing day, we are therefore excused from drill
and I not feeling incl</dc:description>
<dc:description>Homer Pittard's Masters Thesis from the George Peabody College for Teachers, attempting to enlighten readers about lesser-known figures of the Civil War in Rutherford County by preserving both oral and printed legends and stories</dc:description>
<dc:description>The Civil War in Rutherford County -- Dewitt Smith Jobe -- Other Patriots of Rutherford County -- Legends and Stories of Civil War Rutherford County -- Conclusion -- Bibliography -- Index</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.); Stones River, Battle of, Murfreesboro, Tenn., 1862-1863; Ridley, Bromfield Lewis; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865; Stones River, Battle of, Murfreesboro, Tenn., 1862-1863; Rosecrans, William S. (William Starke), 1819-1898; Forrest, Nathan Bedford, 1821-1877</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Periodical</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>146 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-01; mt2011-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication25ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/37</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>