<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>John Taylor Lytle</dc:title>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 14</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1980</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>19th century; 20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>55
JOHN TAYLOR LYTLE
by
Clarice Miller
The driveway of the J. B. McNeil's home six miles
out the Franklin Road from Murfreesboro, Tennessee,
winds around in a curve, skirting the house. On either
side of the driveway, the smooth, emerald grass is
shaded by huge trees with knarled trunks that speak of
olden times. There are pecan, maple, spruce, boxwood,
and a magnificent magnolia which stands quite close on
the right hand side of the house.
The modern home is built on the site of the
original home place of John Taylor Lytle, oldest son of
Captain William Lytle. The Captain had given sixty
acres of land north of "Murfree Spring Branch" in 1811
for a permanent seat of justice for the county. This
was part of the original grants to William and Archibald
Lytle after service in the Revolution War, as well as
other grants purchased by them.
William Lytle 's family migrated from Pennsylvania
to North Carolina, then to Middle Tennessee. He visited
the region in Tennessee and returned to "Hillsborough,
North Caroline, by 1786 . . . for he married Ann Taylor
that year. She was a girl of sixteen or seventeen and
C. C. Henderson. The Story of Murfreesboro,
1929. News Banner Publishing Co. p. 28.
56
he was a man of thirty-one." William continued to buy
land grants from Revolutionary veterans who did not
wish to come to Tennessee. After his brother, Archibald's
death, William had 26,441 acres. He probably left North
2
Carolina for the West in 1798 or 1799.
After they arrived in Middle Tennessee, William's
wife was referred to as Nancy. According to Andrew
Nelson Lytle, they chose a "site on level land, by a
creek, with rising ground to the south and east and
rolling hillocks to the west. To the north lay a cedar
grove." Here they built their home on the site of the
present Carnation Plant, which is no longer in use.
William Lytle died in 1829 and is buried near the original
home site. The house according to Andrew Lytle, was tvro
story of hewn cedar logs, weatherboarded on the outside,
and had ceilings of poplar painted light blue. Nancy
Lytle was the leader of fashion and patron of all balls
3
and parties in Murfreesboro. She died in 182 5.
When, in 1811, the Legislature appointed a
committee to choose a new site (instead of Jefferson)
for the seat of county justice, at least four locations
were eagerly proffered by the owners, the Rucker place,
the Black Fox Springs, the Captain William Lytle land,
and the Ready place . . . "Captain Lytle enhanced his
2Andrew Nelson Lytle. A Wake for the Living.
Crown Publishers, Inc. New York. @ 1975.
^Ibid.
57
offer far beyond the others." He staged a large
reception and banquet presided over by his wife, Nancy.
The committee accepted Lytle's offer. The lytle property
of sixty acres on a slight elevation, appeared to be
well adapted to meeting the criteria for a central
location. Lytle at first declined to suggest a name
for the new county seat, and the General Assembly, on
October 27, 1811, designated the town as Cannonsburgh
in honor of Newton Cannon. Shortly afterward, Lytle
suggested it be named Murf reesborough in memory of his
4
friend. Colonel Hardy Murfree. It later became
Murfreesboro.
"John Taylor Lytle was the Captain's oldest son.
He was named for his mother's father and in his youth
was a wild one ... He finally got religion and built
a church house on his farm (given to him by his father.
Captain William Lytle) and made slaves and family attend
5 with the zeal only the saved can manifest."
His house, according to Andrew N. Lytle, six miles
out from Murfreesboro, was still standing some few years
ago. It was a frame and unlike the usual country house
of the region. The living room was paneled halfway up
and papered the rest. Across a narrow hall was the
dining room. The kitchen and out houses were mostly
gone. The house was commodious enough.
4Homer Pittard. Griffith .
Andrew Nelson Lytle. A Wake for the Living .
58
"There were large dressing rooms upstairs attached
to the bedrooms. In the yard is a great stone brought
for his tomb. Since it was unsuitable, it was dropped
and, Andrew Lytle says, he supposes it still lies there.
At the entrance to the drive is a buggy house, with
handmade snake hinges."
Mrs. John Grooms of Murfreesboro, a descendant of
John Hartman, who purchased the Lytle place, has a
picture of the Lytle house made in approximately 1916,
or about two years before Frances Hartman (Mrs. Grooms'
mother) was born in 1918. Frances Hartman married an
Odom, which is Mrs. Grooms' maiden name. John Hartman 's
son. Jack, lived there until his marriage. His daughter,
Ida Mildred Hartman, who currently works at the Murfreesboro
Post Office, was instrumental in locating the picture of
the Lytle home place.
The large twenty by sixteen inch tinted photograph
in an oval frame of stained wood shows the house as
Andrew Nelson Lytle described it. In the picture is a
pump house next to the dwelling with a latteced porch.
It is now enclosed in concrete at the McNeil farm. The
foundation of the barn, seen in the picture, is now found
back of the current McNeil barn.
The large lawn in front of the home in the picture
has no trees except the magnolia at the right hand corner,
of the house and two large stumps. That same magnolia
^Ibid.
THE JOHN LYTLE HOME PLACE
THE CRYPT - Mrs. McNiel stands at the west side of the
crypt where the tombstones are piled.
59
The small cemetery near the crypt. Notice the double gate
to allow room for pallbearers.
The McNiel home today on the siteof the former John Lytle
home.
The stones from the buggy house near the road were laid
under the old magnolia tree at the corner of the McNiel
home
60
61
is still there. It is a magnificent old soldier of a
tree showing the scars of many cold winters, wind, and
snow. Limestone slabs surround the magnolia's foot.
Mrs. McNeil says the slabs came from the front
yard near the driveway entrance. She had thought they
were the foundation of a slave cabin until she learned
of the buggy house mentioned by Andrew Nelson Lytle
which stood by the entrance to the driveway.
The McNeil's became curious and interested in the
crypt found back of their home and to the right side.
It contains John Lytle 's grave with his second wife,
Mary. She was a widow when he married her, Mary Ward
Sills Turner.
7
Andrew Nelson Lytle says "John Lytle 's first wife
was Tabitha Morton. . . Tabitha is buried in the Lytie
burying ground on the original homeplace (at the site
Q
of the Carnation Plant). This is set apart in a lonely
spot, although at the time no doubt a place had been
reserved by her for her husband's repose. As such things
go in a hard country, he lies by his second wife, in the
rear of his dwelling on the Franklin Dirt Road. He
built a tomb out of limestone rock, and he and my
ancestress lie there. The lightning struck the top and
through the crack it is possible to see the two skulls
^Ibid., p. 130-131.
Information given by Andrew Nelson Lytle in a
letter to the author of this article.
The old magnolia at the east
corner of the McNiel home, \A/hich
can be seen in the old picture of
the Lytle home.
This old tree, probably planted by John Lytle, was recently
blown down by a storm. It measures 75 feet high and 1 5
feet around the trunk about 2 feet from the ground.
62
63
Andrew Nelson Lytle
THE LOa CABIN
MONTIAOLt. TKNN S7SS*
Jep. 16, 1978
Dear Ulsa 11111 er:
Tablatha la buried in the Lytle
oemetary, at Carnation site. I underatand
a storm bleu the headstones ciown, but that
they have been fixed. I'm pretty aure about
this, beoaus e John is buried by his aeoond
wife. I remember she awaited him in vain.
You have my permission to quote.
If you quote too lengty passages, you might
have to get permission from the publishers.
iincerely YkurS . ,
.
I
64
leaning towards each other, with the constant grimace
of silence and privacy. He had chiseled into the stone
a curse on anyone who may disturb or move his bones."
The four or five inch crack is in a right angle,
and the only thing that can be seen now is something
resembling a silver knife. Mr. McNeil jokingly tells
visitors, "Old John gets up sometimes in the night and
wanders around, but he doesn't bother me and I sure
don't bother him."
The engraving on the vault reads, "Molest not the
dead, nor spoil his resting place." Mr. McNeil says he
has no intention of harming it in any way. He and John
get along well together.
Mr. and Mrs. McNeil asked to have the burying
ground researched. Mr. E. K. Johns and Mr. H. G. Wray
did the investigation of the vault and cemetery. A
copy, loaned by the McNeils, of the result of their
research follows.
Since it is called Lytle-Blanks Cemetery, it is
assumed that it was a community cemetery. The 1878
map (found in Murfreesboro Historical Society) mentioned
in the research shows the home called "Rosydell" with
Captain John Lytle in residence. This must have been
John Taylor Lytle' s son, who was called Jack. According
to Andrew Nelson Lytle 's family tree, he married Helen
King,
Mr. &amp; Mrs. J. B. McNeil &amp;
E.K.Johns &amp;
H.G. Wray, June 1972
LYTLE-BLANKS CEMETERY (Sheet 1 of 2)
Rockvale Quadrangle. On Highway #96, 0.8 of a mile East of
the intersection of Windrow Road (now named Coleman Rd.) The
cemetery is about 'l+OO' south of Hwy. 96 and about 100' west
of the J. B. McNeil home. A large old house once stood where
the present home now stands.
Large vault about 12' x 12' and about 5' high with a flat
roof. The walls are of finely cut limestone blocks 8" thick,
and the roof of solid limestone pieces 8" thick, 3' wide and
12' long. At one end (east) are these inscribed slabs:
John Lytles Tomb
Built 1835
John Lytle
July 9, 1788
Aug. 31. 18^1
Molest not the
dead, nor spoil
his resting place
On the west side is this inscribed slab
In memory of John &amp; Mary Lytle
John Lytle July 9, 1788-Aug. 31, 1841
Mary W. Lytle Jan. 11, 1800-Nov. 30, 1847
About 40' southwest of the Lytle vault is a small iron fence
enclosing four graves:
Martha S. Floyd
Mar. 30, 1861
Nov. 9, 1897
M.A.W.
No dates
James M. Floyd
Nov. 15, 1893
Feb. 5, I894
Drury S . Floyd
June 18, 1897
Oct. 13, 1897
There were nine broken tombstones stacked on the west side of
the Lytle vault and have been stacked there for a long time but
the inscriptions are well preserved.
Martha G. Lytle
Aug. 26, 1822
Aug. 18, 1825
Ingram Blanks
Dec. 18, 1755
Dec. 12, 1825
Martha Blanks
wife of
Ingram Blanks
Mar. 6, 1756
June 9, 1826
James E. Webb, Esq,
Sept. 6, 1794
July 9. 1873
Msirtha Ann
wife of
James E. Webb
Mar. 1, 1794
Oct. 3, I872
Mary E. Vaughan
Feb. 9, 1847
Nov. 9, I89I
Mary J . Webb
wife of
Harvey Haynes
Apr. 6, 1820
June 5. 1897
Harvey H. Haynes
Apr. 11, I8I5
Mar. 18, I863
66
LYTLE- BLANKS CEMETERY (Sheet 2 of 2)
Broken and part missing:
Burns, wife of
Burns, dau&#187;, of
h Webb
Nov. , 1848
Sept. 5, 1879.
NOTE: On 1878 map this place is named "Rosydell" and lists
Capt. John Lytle as living there.
In 1820 Census Ingram Blanks had 33 slaves
67
The McNeils have lived on this farm for eight
years, the fifth family to live there. First the John
Lytles and heirs, then John Hartman purchased the farm
from the Lytle heirs. Later his son. Jack Hartman,
lived there, and then August Leeman purchased and tore
down the house and built a new (the current) home. The
Hugh Samples came next and the McNeils purchased the
farm from the Samples.
John Lytle gave the land in Murfreesboro for the
United Methodist Church on College Street at Church
Street. The following information was furnished by
Mrs. Lody Lytle Houston (Ivan) Brown:
The organization of this very popular branch of
the church in this country dates back to about 1812.
At that time there was held a camp meeting at the
Windrow Camp Ground at which there were many professions
of religion. Other camp meetings now held at which
itinerant ministries of the Methodist faith were present
and worked with that zeal that was peculiar to the
pioneer ministries of that faith. Rev. Robert Paine,
who became bishop in the Methodist Episcopal Church,
was a circuit rider over a district embracing Rutherford
County. During the season of the General Assembly, he
preached in the courthouse and many members were present
and took a part in the exercises, among them Felix
Grundy, the distinguished lawyer and statesman. A class
was organized at a house on College Street in 1821.
68
The charter menbers are: Benjamin Blankenship and wife,
Edward Fisher and wife, Thomas Montague and wife, John
Lytle and wife, Martin Clark, Willis Reeves, John Jones,
William Ledbetter, G. A. Sublett , D. Henry Holmes,
Dr. W. R. Rucker, Levi Reeves, J. D. Neugent and David
Hammis. Preaching was furnished by traveling preachers
at first and services were held either in the courthouse
or in a private dwelling until the year 1823. In 1823
John Lytle deeded a lot, near where Soule's College, now
stands for the purpose of having a church erected thereon.
The lot was deeded to
John R. McLaughlin
Samuel McLaughlin
Simpson Bimons
Benjamin Rucker
S. Ogden
A. Childress
Edmond Jones
as Trustees
A brick house, one story high, with gallery for
Negroes, and bell, was completed at a cost of about
$1,800.00
Goodspeed p 8 39-840
Warranty Deed of John Lytle to Methodist Church Trustees
Dated January 11, 1823,
Registered July 3, 183 2
Register's Office for Rutherford County, Tennessee
Deed Book 5, page 5 74
The progress of the church was slow until 1828
when the first conference met in Murfreesboro, at which
69
a great revival was begun and the church was greatly
strengthened. John Lytle, Mrs. Wasson, and the Rev.
John Lane deserve mention for their zeal and piety;
also Captain Jones who conducted the first public
prayer meeting at the old Bradly Academy in 1818.
Goodspeed p. 839
(&#171; BQ
C
in
c
c
&lt;
E-
-J
V
ij
c
c n
fi &#8212;
)
&#8212; CI
JS E E-c
u
cV
X
51
C-l X&#8212; b
-c
l~
? ^
.A
5 &#163; -^
~ &#163; *&lt; ^
i$x &#163; 3; E-E
u
-C
&gt;. ^&lt;
E"2
^ "0
^. c
-J i
J t
32 -c
-c ,,
ra I&#8212;
^ "O
1^ c
E i-is
t
V i&#171; j= -5
r&#8212; W &#8212; *
6C 00
70
E -!: -
0^
&#171;
&#8226;^
0 0
c .A
%j X
wc3
C it/t n ^&gt;
bC
2 0**
" 2|
c " o
Q- S
, ^ &gt; '^ ^
i u &#8212; CO c^
E E E-a.
-
&amp;
-*. 3
&lt;
f eo Jt
_^ i- ~
- * J
c 6C23 &#8226;
Li
&#8226;0
-0
o
c3
3
c
)^
C 2
':2 ^
&#8226;^
u
^ &#171;/
b X
I ^
c c
rs -
u &#8212;
&#8482; -2
^ c
be ^U
E ^
&#8212;1 X
X
c
LI u
"O 1-
rr: tj
JZ c
&#8212;
&#171;
&gt;
X "
&#8226; -^ - X u
n SI
h -
o &#8212; ?l
X^ "E" E--
X ~
^ X
cj 3 re
&lt; w &lt;"
X
u
&#163;?.
-52
3
c
X
i -a
E^
111
I
E-
- S
c
U a,
.2 "I
-&#8212;"3 &#8222; 1 c3&lt;
-&#163;
it
u
&lt;
-5 p
&gt; 71
i
y.
c
JC
a
c
00
3^
1^
C
y.
E
c
f&#8212; 4J
E-
14 X
^
"re c 6C
\j s ,&#8212; ^
5 s i
t/1
u
c
a:
m ^,
S \i
&#8226;u ^
"-5
s 1;
JZ
c .?5
1^1 c
f9
u
rs
5
/ y. ^
sc
u. ^M C-l
c -*
^ E E- E
5^ -&#171;'
*""
a.
c &#8482;
-C a-i
o r
X
I
c
i
X.
St
J I
&#163;-
&gt;
C
&gt;
-1
5
c
E
7!
-o
&#8226;&#8212; 1 -C
&#163;
c
3c
1/
X
a.
E-i E-i
X
3
c a.
o &#8482;
/:
c X
c
-n&#8212;
c _
\j X
X C
- E
^ "C
- c
1/
00
E
</dc:description>
<dc:description>A history of John Taylor Lytle and his family, focused heavily on the site of the former Lytle home and the Lytle family cemetery, now owned by the McNeil family</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Cemeteries; Family history</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>homes; Lytle, John Taylor</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-01; mt2011-09-06</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication14ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/110</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>