<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>"Fergusan" memoirs of Milton</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Craddock, Ladelle</dc:creator>
<dc:contributor>Fergusan, Allan; Fergusan, Ocie</dc:contributor>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 23</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1978</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>"FURGASCN"
MEMOIRS of MILTON
1978
A very pleasant afternoon was spent in the home of Mr.
and Mrs. Allan P. Furgason of Milton, Rutherford County on
April 20, 1978.
Mr. Furgason, hereafter referred to as Mr. Allan, now
87 years young, is the son of Sam and Lucy Black Furgason,
and the grandson of George and Sara January Furgason. The
George Furgasons came to Milton from Smyrna in 1851.
Mr. Allan was first married to Miss Lizzie Dement, and
to this union was born one daughter, Frances Elizabeth. Mrs.
Lizzie died in 1921, and on the 8th of October 1932, Mr.
Allan was united in matrimony to Miss Ocie Simpson, daughter
of Tommy and Emily Hays Simpson, born in Wilson County,
Tennessee. Two grandchildren add to the beauty of this home .
Mr. and Mrs. Furgason chose not to relate incidents
relative to their individual lives, but rather refer to
Milton itself. Mr. Allan has been a lifelong resident of this
community, and this is home to him, while Mrs. Furgason has
shared Rutherford County with that of a neighboring county^
Wilson.
The original "Milton Male and Female Academy" was erected
on land purchased from Mr. George Furgason in 1851. Trustees
were Dennis Smith, Bob Daugherty and Sam Erantley. Mr. Allan
related that ''I have been told a cannon ball went through this
building during the Civil War."
52
Ocie Simpson Ferguson
53
In 1898 the Milton Baptist Church was organized by a
group that withdrew from the Twelve Corner, now called
Bradley Creek, Baptist Church. There were 13 charter members.
In 1937 this frame building, facing north, was burned by
lightning. A new brick building was erected the same year.
A very interesting incident was related by Mr. and Mrs.
Furgason that occured in 1937 at the Milton Presbyterian Church.
Bro. James Cox was the evangelist. In the winter, this church
was heated by a pot-bellied stove, however, tMs was during
the revival, at such time when the stove had been taken down,
and the flu was open. A chicken snake fell from the ceiling
at the flu site, near the choir and pulpit. Mrs. Nell Alexander,
a widow, became so excited, she jumped up on a bench. To relieve
the pressure and excitement, Mr. Raymond Bell picked the snake
up by the tail, carried it outside the church and snapped its
head off.
Mr. Allan's great grandfather, Robert January was the first
pastor of First Baptist Church, Murfreesboro, He later quit
preaching and became a doctor.
The Milton Cemetery was organized by 1892. The first
person who died and was buried there after its organization was
Gertrude Furgason, aged 8 years, in 1893, a sister of Mr. Allan's.
Prior to this organization, several graves had been opened on
the opposite side of the road. These were transferred into the
newly organized cemetery.
The Milton Cemetery was started with one acre of land. Lots
consisting of ten grave plots were sold for $10 each. This
54
MILTON
burial area has been extended, until there are 169 lots
with area for 10 graves each, with two feet between each
lot and a drive of 12 feet through the center.
The old cemetery located approximately one and one-half
miles from Milton, off the Porterfield road is referred to as
the "Cook" or "McKnight" cemetery. This burial ground was in
use before 1862. Mr. Allan has a grandmother interred there.
The Milton community first received phone service in
1905 through the Eell Telephone Company. This service was
later owned and operated by different residents of the
community. In the late 1950' s Mr. Ira Knight, owner, sold
to the DeKalb Cooperative, ano! Milten is still served by this
cooperative.
At- one time there was a bank in Milton with a stock of
$12,500.00. $3600.00 was spent for a building, and a vault
was secured. Everybody was poor and there wasn't any money
to lend.
Some of the earlier doctors in the community were McGee,
McCullough, Doak and Kelton. Dr. Riley Vanhook later practiced
here out of Auburn, Cannon County. Sometime later, about early
1950 's, Mr. Wendell Porterfield, President of the Milton
Community Club informed the people they could have a doctor
come to the community if they would erect a building for a clinic,
Dr. Carl E. Adams was the first, Dr. S. C. Garrison and Dr. J. W.
Tenpenny served this community from this clinic.
55
JMJ.Jj'1 UN
The first year the Clinic was entered in the Home
Improvement contest it was awarded second place winner,
however, the second year it was entered in the contest,
it took first place and won $7 50.00.
Mrs. Furgason relates being in a play during the years
of depression. In reading over the play she stated she would
act any part in it except the 'man'. She was told that was
what they wanted her to be, which she did. Mrs. Ruth Matthews
played the part of the woman, and one of her duties was to
churn, and she actually turned out pure butter. The Home
Demonstration Club presented this play under the title of
"The Butter, and Egg Woman."
The community of Milton did not have electricity until
about 1937. A few people were being furnished electricity
by Tennessee Power, operating by motor in an old shop.
Misfortune came by the death of Bill Brantly when he poured
gas on the motor. This "being in town in the country"
appeared when Middle Tennessee Electric Membership Corporation
began serving rural areas like Milton. Many conveniences are
now experienced that were never heard of before.
Even though Milton has had electricity for a number of
years, the ball field on the "Milton Square" hasn't always
had electric lights-so they could play ball at night. A
concession stand was also erected there. Many years previously,
an annual picnic was held on the Jim Ro Vaught farm, now owned
by Mr. and Mrs. W. D. Vaught, on Highway 96, between Milton and
56
MILTCN
Lascassas. The sum of $100.00 per day was paid Mr. Vaught
for the use of his land for the annual picnic. There were
a number of good shade trees, with ample space in the center
for two good ball games. Refreshments included ice cream,
barbecue and cold drinks. , Uncle Dave Macon was always a
featured entertainer with his banjo.
What a contrast in today's life style and years ago.
Mr. Allan recalls the days of 40C wages for a day of labor.
Recalls to mind when Uncle Dave Macon used to sing "Eleven
cent cotton and forty cent meat, how in the world can a poor
nun eat." (And this was the last song ever sung by Uncle
Dave, according to his son, Archie.)
In 1944 another tragedy touched down on Milton. Two
-men and a 14 year old boy were killed by lightning running
in on an improperly grounded wire. The Youngblood family
was the victim.
Mr. Furgason stated that Mr. Ralph Jarratt was travelling
out west one time, and when asked where he lived, he said,
1 Murfreesboro. &#8226; He was then asked "is that anywhere near
Milton?" This was unusual, the man knew where Milton was rather
than Murfreesboro.
Thus we conclude this delightful experience of hearing
our friends reminisce.
The foregoing was related to Mrs. Ladelle R. Craddock
on the above date.
57
</dc:description>
<dc:description>Ladelle Craddock recounts memories told to her by Allan and Ocie Fergusan regarding Milton, Tennessee.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Family stories</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Milton</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>6 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-01</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication23ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/81</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>