<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Record of Jordan Williford</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Williford, Jordan</dc:creator>
<dc:contributor>Rushing, Mrs. Elvis</dc:contributor>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 8</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1836; 1977</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1770-1779; 1780-1789; 1830-1839</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>RECORD OV JORDAN WILLI FORD
Obtained from Records in the Pension Office Washington, D .C.
by Mrs. Elvis Rusliing
State of T ennessee
R ulherford County
On l.his first day of August, 1836, personally appeared in open court,
before the County Court of said Rutherford County, now sitting, JORDAN
WILLIFORD, a resident of McKnight's district //17 in the said County of
Rutherford and State of Tennessee, aged 77 years the 30th day of May, 1836,
who, being first duly sworn according to law, doth on his oath make the fol-lowing
declaration in order to obtain the benefit of the Act of Congress passed
June 7, 1832.
I. JORDAN WIIJ-.IFOR.D, was born in SoutJiampton County in the State of
Virginia, on the 30th day of May, 1759, as I learned from my parents and
from the record of my birth in my father's Bible. At the time I entered the
service of the United States in the Revolution I lived in the said County of
Southampton, with my father, WIT_.LIAM WILLIFORD, with whom I had lived
fronn the time of niy birth and with whom I continued to reside, when at honrie,
until after peace was made. I now have a record of my age which I copied
from my father's Bible.
I first entered the service of the United States in the month of May, 1778,
to the best of my recollection, in a militia company under Captain Lewis
Joiner, in the regiment commanded by Colonel Benjamin Blunt (Blount?).
My father lived some 25 miles from Southampton Court House, afterward
called Jerusalem, and in about 15 mil^s from Smithfield, then the County
82
Seat of the Isle of Wight County. I first entered the service of the United
States under a draft, to prevent the landing of the enemy at Smithland (Smith-field?).
The rendezvous was at the bridge on the Blackwater River at a
place called Broadwater, thence we v^ent to Smithfield where wo met other
forces. Colonel Wells and Colonel Parker were there from the County of
Isle of Wight. I also remember Colone] Richardson who seemed to be our
chief in command.
Benjamin Griffin and Bowen were lieutenants in Capt. Joiner' company .
I believe that Butts was Major in Col. Blunt's regiment, other field officers
not recollected. I remained in the service at Smithfield two weeks. During
the time no fighting took place. I served on a guard at Mackey's Mills, about
4 or 5 miles from Smithfield. It was said another guard was stationed near
the mouth of Piggin Creek from whence the enemy's vessels were seen in
Hampton Roads. After the British ships, or tenders, as they were then
called, left, we were discharged. I received a written discharge from Captain
Joiner, but have lost it. In this campfagn I served at least 2 weeks.
I was again called into service of the United States some time in the
year 1780, I believe in the spring of tl o year, but cannot state the date
precisely. I again entered and served under Capt. Joiner in the regiment
of Capt. Blount. The rendezvous of the regiment was again on the Blackwater
River at the place called Broadwater. The British at this time were under-stood
to be in and havc^ possession of Norfolk and Portsmouth. I understood
our objective to be to protect our people from the British scouting parties.
Colonel Blount's regiment moved in the direction of Norfolk. We met
Col. Wells with the Isle of Wight regiment. We moved in different directions.
83
We were through the Coimty of Nansemond; we were also in Norfolk and Isle
of Wight Counties. A detachment was frequently garrisoned at A/lead's Mill,
also, at a little village called Jericho. I occassionally served in these detach-ments.
In this tour of service 1 was engaged at least 45 days. We had no
engagement with the enem.y. We were discharged at Crocker's Old Field
in the Isle of Wight County, about the first of July, 1780, to the best of my
recollection. I, then, also, received a written discharge from service,
written by Major Boykin, which discharge I have since lost.
I again entered the service of the U.S. in March, I believe, 1781, in
Southampton Militia Regiment commanded by Col. Blount, under my old
Captain Joiner. The rendezvous was again on the Blackwater at the same
place as before mentioned. We inet the militia from the adjoining counties
at Lawrence's Field to the best of my recollection. General Muhlenburgh
was there and was chief in command. Colonel Merriweather, who, it was
said, had been an officer in the Continental Line, joined us and took command
of our regiment. Blount then v^'ent home, but I believe returned before we wer
discharged.
Major DeCloman, a Frenchman, was an officer in our regiment and muc
esteemed as a gentleman and skilfi;'] .soldier. Col. Parker was along and
had command of the regiment from the Isle of Wight. In this tour Major
DeCloman was put under arrest for insulting and abusing Colonel Parker.
1 remember to have seen DeCloman under arrest, and was informed that
in a conversation about the French assisting us in the war, Col. Parker had
said that he believed the French were deceitful; that they talked of help, but
had never done us any good; whereupon DeCloman seized him by the collar
84
and in the scuffle tore off a piece of Parker's coat. But DeCloman was
again resored to command.
The army went from Lawrence's through Suffolk and on towards Norfolk.
We remained at Suffolk one or two days. The whole number under Muhlen-burgh
was supposed to be 1200. The forces crossed a branch of Norfolk River
on a bridge and took camps at a place called Shoulder's hill, about a half mile
frora the bridge. The British could not easily attack us here without crossing
the bridge. About a inile before we got to the bridge we passed a British fort
some half-mile to our left, and 3 cannons were fired from the fort, but without
effect. While stationed at Shoulder's Hill, the Whigs of the neighborhood, as it
is imderstood, gave note that a party of the British had left the fort and were out
after beef. A detachment was sent ^Her them under Col. Parker, who had a
skirmish with the British party at a church not far from the fort. I did not go out
with Col. Parker, but was sent with others under Captain Cuinmings to Parker's
assistance. Captain Cummings m.et Col. Parker retiirning. Col. Parker had one
man killed. His name was Hutchins. He was a true Whig that lived in the neigh-borhood
and was serving as a pilot. Parker's detachment killed and wounded 5 or
6 of the enemy and had them brought into camp in a cart. While encamping at
Shoulder's Hill we had many alarms., but no more fighting.
One evening, just as the inen v,'"ere gettiag supper, we received orders to
march. We started about sunset and crossed Northwest River on a bridge, at a
place called Northwest Landing, about Midnight. There was a breastwork there
called Gregory's Fort where we encamped 2 or 3 days. Fi*om this place the
Infantry crossed the Dismal Swamp, and the baggage with a small company of
housemen went round the swamp.
85
I crossed with the Infantry, and we went on through Suffolk to Lawrence's
Field where, I tliink, we met the baggage and horsemen, thence to Broadwater
on the Blackwater , where we found men ready to take our places in the
service. We were then discharged. I received a written discharge from
Capt. Joiner, which I have since lost. In camp I served at least 9 weeks,
and was discharged, as 1 belic^ve, in June, 1781.
In the last of July or first of August, 1781, I was again called into ser-vice
under Captain John Simmons in Col. Blount's regiment. The rendez-vous
was at Surry Old Court House in what then was called Sussex County.
We there met the militia from the adjoining counties. Col. Judkin was there
from Sussex, and Major Boice from Surry County, who had been in the regular
service. There was five or sLx hundred of us met at Surry Old Court House,
thence, we marched in 2 or 3 weeks to Jamestown, remained there about
2 days, and thence to the New Magazine near Williamsburg, stayed there 2
or ;) weeks imtil the arrival of the northern troops under General George
Washington. I there saw General Washington on horseback.
The regulars under Washington went ontoward Yorktown and our militia
followed on in a few days. We arrived at Yorktown before a gun was firec'
in the seige of that place. The particulars of the battle of Yorktown are known
from history. I was present and in service during the whole of that memorable
battle. I remember only one out of Capt. Simmons company was killed.
Aft(;r the capitulalion of Cornwallis and his army, Col. Blount's regiment
went with the guard of prisoners toward Winchester, but was relieved at
Falmouth. We then marched back to Fredericksburg and were there dis-charged.
I received a written discharge from Captain Vaughn who had taken
86
command of our company in the place of Simmons who had returned home
after the capture of Comwallis. In this compaign I served at least 9 weeks.
I stated that I had been drafted in the first campaign herein mentioned.
I was called into the service in the same way in each campaign in which I
served. The County of Southampton was at am early period put into classes
or divisions. Every man drew a ticket from a hat or box, which ticket when
drawn designated the class or division to which he belonged. They were then
called into service by divisions and I suppose we were rather considered
Minute Men than as drafted. I always served as a Private, except during
the Battle of Yorktown I acted as Sergeant.
I married my present wife Charity, formerly CHARITY HOI.LOMAN,
in Surry County, in February, 1783. I continued to reside in Southampton
County imtil 1801 or 1802, then I moved to Guilfoil County, North Carolina
(there is a Guilford Co. , in North Carolina) resided there 2 years and thence
removed to Tennessee, Rutherford County, in which County I have ever since
resided. I refer to Joseph Trimble, Robert Overall, Jesse Barton, Jacob
Wright, Esra Jones, ROBERT SAUNDERS, David M. Jarratt, Jarratt
Cocke, and Enoch H. Jones, as my neighbors to whom I am known, and who
can testify as to my character for vei-acity, and their belief of my services
as a soldier of the Revolution.
I do not know of any person living by whom I can make direct proof of
my services as a soldier in the Revolutionary War.
I hereby relinquish every claim whatever to a pension or an annuity,
except the present, and I declare that my name is not on the pension roll
of any agency in any state.
JORDAN WILLIFORD
87
Sworn to and subscribed
on the day and year
first aforesaid
Robert S. Morris, Clerk of the Comity Court
We, David Clark, a clergyman residing in the County of Rutherford in the
state of 1 ennessee, and David M. Jarratt; residing in the same county,
hereby certify that we are well acquainted with Jordan Williford, who has
subscribed and sworn to the above declaration; that we believe him to be
77 years of age; that he is reputed and believed in the neighborhood where
he resides to have been a soldier of the Revolution, and that we concur in
this opinion.
David Clark
D. M. Jaratt
Hobart S. Morris
Clerk
and the said court do hereby declare their opinion after the investigation
of the matter, and after putting the interrogatories prescribed by the War
Department, that the above named applicant was a Revolutionary soldier
and served as he states. And the Court further certifies that it appears to
them that David Clark who has signed the preceding certificate is a clergy-man,
residing in said county of Rutherford, and that David M. Jarratt, who
has also signed the same, is a resident in the same county and is a credible
person, and that their statement is entitled to credit
William Vinson, Chairman of the Co. Court
for said County of Rutherford
88
I, Robert Morris, Clerk of the County Court of Rutherford in the State of
Tennessee, do hereby certify that the foregoing contains the original pro-ceedings
of the said court, in the matter of the application of Jordan
Williford for a pension.
In testimony whereof I have set my
hand and seal of office at Murfreesbo rough,
this second day of August, in the year of
our Lord One Thousand eight Hundred
and thirty- six.
Robert S. Morris, Clerk
Note: The label endorsed on the outside is 33796
Jordan Williford, Tennessee
Admitted 6 mos. 5 days
$20.55
100
COPY OF A LETTER FROM D. J. SANDERS, MURFREESBORO,
TENNESSEE TO CARRIE WILLIFORD
89
Murfreesboro, Tenn.
June :18, 1916
Miss Carrie Williford
Dear Great Niece,
I received a letter from niece Fanny Willard enclosed in a letter from you
making inquire about the Williford Family.-
The only Willifords I have known anything about are your father's ancestors.
Jordan Williford, a Revolutionary soldier, lived in sight of my father's
and I remember him. He was small and slender. He lived to be nearly
one hundred years old.
I was at his burial. He is buried about two miles west of Hall's Hill, a
post office on banks of Stone River, Rutherford County, Tenn. He was your
great-greatgrandfather. His sons were Jordan, Willis, Samuel, Robert.
Sam was your great grandfather. His sons were CLAIBORNE, Jesse,
William, John and James. I suppose you know about Uncle Jesse as he lived
in Anna. I do not know what became of William. I saw John Williford in
the army in our Civil War. He was out from Mississippi, but that is more
than 50 years ago. James Williford died at Hall's Hill this county about 7
years ago. He left no children.
It may be you would like to know who it is that is writing to you. Well, I am
your Grandmother Williford's youngest and only living brother. My youngest
sister is living. Her name is Sarah Lucille Rion. Her post office is^
Murfreesboro, Tenn. RR7. There was one other sister, Nancy Jane, who
raised a large family in Texas, and died at Pine Mills, Texas. She married
a Mr. Reed.
My brothers were Richard and John, Thom.as and Robert. Richard was the
father of Joe, the man that visited at your father's. Thomas raised a fam-ily
in Arkansas and died there. John and Robert died young.
Well I guess you are tired of reading family history. I will give my age and
quit. I lack a little of being 79 years old.
I have two children, Joe and James. Joe is a dentist in Murfreesboro,
Tennessee. James lives with me. Married 53 years. Have never had a
death in our family.
B.J. Sanders
Murfreesboro , Tennessee
RR7, Box 50
DRURY JOSIAH SANDERS, brother of Mary Elizabeth Sanders Williford,
wife of Claiborne Holloman Williford.</dc:description>
<dc:description>A reprint of Revolutionary War soldier Jordan Williford's 1836 petition to Rutherford County courts for a pension from his years of service; includes a 1916 letter from D.J. Sanders to Carrie Williford in response to her query for information about the Williford family</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Family history; Genealogy; Military pensions; United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1783; Court records</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>veterans</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>17 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-02</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication08ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/155</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>