<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>House on the hill</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Rooker, Martin J.</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 39</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>199?</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>18th century; 19th century;</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>THE HOUSE ON THE HILL
Some of the first information recorded about the Cumberland River and surrounding country was by an
explorer by the name of Dr Thomas Walker (1). Long Hunters were also explorers, but their main mission was
killing animals for hides (2) . "By the early 1770s, it was no longer possible for the large parties of other years to take
skins enough to make a hunt pay" (3).
Two names mentioned with hunting parties were Uriah Stone, whose name survives in Stones River, and
Michael Stoner for whom Stoner's Lick was named (4).
Kasper Mansker became better known as an Indian fighter than a Long Hunter (5). Goodlettsville has a
replica of Mansker's Station which was originally built in 1779. Their annual Frontier Day activities demonstrate
some of the chores performed during early times, but they cannot duplicate the everyday dangers and hardships
which the settlers experienced.
Before Indian hostilities subsided in the better part of the 1700s, people began settling further down the
Cumberland.
'AndrewJackson arrived on the Cumberland late in Ortober, 1788" (6). While AndrewJackson was buying
and selling land along the Cumberland and Stone's River, the Ruckers (James, Thomas and Gideon) were doing
the same by 1797 and 1799 on Stone's River (7, 8).
"Sam Donelson, Jackson, and Benjamine Rucker were the closest fiiends. It is said that when Benjamine
Rucker came, theJackson family used to consider it quite an honor, and the same was the case when theJacksons
visited the Ruckers. It is also said, that the garden ofthe great soldier, Jackson, and that ofBenjamine Rucker were
equally the same. When Rucker obtained a new plant or flower for his garden he also secured one for his fiiend
AndrewJackson" (9).
North Carolina was making land grants to early settlers in the late 1700s and early 1800s. Much of this land
was granted to people who settled along Stone's River, including both the east and west forks. The fiirst town, in
what was to become the new county of Rutherford, was called Jefferson (10). This town was located in the fork of
the east and west forks ofStone's River. Land that was being bought during this time was paid for in Spanish milled
dollars, pounds, and dollars (1 1). One deed has land being paid for in 6,000 Spanish milled dollars (12). A bond
was made between a Benjamin Josling and Thomas Williamson in 1792 for 4,000 silver dollars (13).
The state of North Carolina granted Col. Isaac Shelby 5,000 acres for services in the American Revolution.
This land was located on both sides of the east fork of Stone's River. This deed was dated 1784/85. Col. Shelby and
his wife Susanna sold this 5,000 acres to Thomas Rucker, Simon Miller, and James Rucker on February 1, 1801, for
7,000 dollars (14). Thomas Rucker bought 1947 acres from Simon Miller andJames Rucker onJuly 10, 1802 (15).
I believe Thomas built a house soon after he bought this tract, and I believe he lived here during 1804.
If this is true, then this would likely have been his second house. This part ofthe 5,000 acres became known
as the northwest comer of Shelby's 5,000 acre grant. Thomas Rucker, Simon Miller, James Rucker and others
continued to buy and sell land among themselves and others for years to come.
"Thomas Rucker, another one ofthe early settlers, was one of the seven justices and lived between Murfi-ees-boro
andJefferson. His place came -within one vote ofbeing made the county seat instead ofMurfreesboro" (16)
.
"In 1804, the first session of the county court met, according to provisions ofthe Legislative Act, at the home
ofThomas Rucker, near where the Veterans Hospital now stands" (17). This may be contrary to the fisting in 206&gt;
years of Ruckers in Middle Tentiessee by Mary Rucker Estes which gives the date of that house as 1809- 1 believe
Thomas built this third house at the VA in 1809.
The house in question is a typical house ofthat time with two large (approx. 22' x 18) rooms with a "dog trot"
between. This open space between the rooms had a roof There was a separate log kitchen which was torn down
and moved years ago.
Thomas deeded two acres dose by for the Baptist Meeting House in 1813 (18). He sold nine and a half acres
to Philfip Lowe in 1814 (19). The deed speaks ofthe South border joining that ofthe academy land. This indicates
that no one lived in the house at that time unless someone fived there while the house was used as an academy
Thomas sold 500 acres toJohn M. Tilford in 18 16 which included all ofthe northwest comer ofShelby's 5,000 acre
Page 7
traa except for two acres of church property, Lowe's nine and a half acres, and the twelve and a half acres of
academy land (20).
Tilford sold thirty acres to Joseph Newman in 1820 (21). Samuel E Black bought 464 acres through foreclo-sure
on Tilford in 1822 (22) . Samuel P Black sold this property to Henry L. Douglas in 1828 (23) . This deed stated
"which the said Black now lives". Samuel P Black bought the Lowe house and academy land in 1829 (24).
Thomas Rucker retained ownership of the academy land until he sold it to Black. Samuel P Black bought the
414 acres, which he sold to Douglas back in 1831 (25). That deed suted "it being the same track on -wiiich said
Black now lives".
"Dr. Black lived for a time at "Pebble Hill", the place which he and his brother Lumsford, had bought and later
had purchased "Eveip-een", five miles fix)m Murfreesboro" (26).
Personal history ofthe Black family in possession ofHarold L. Beasley contains the following: 'About 1836 he
(Thomas C. Black) removed from Jefferson to Pebble Hill (near where his father died) , still engaged in a laborious
practice".
Dr. Black bought said house with 166 acres of land in 1838 (27). If the place was known as Pebble Hill, it
could have been named that as an academy.
"Indenture made August 13, 1792, for the sum of 1,000 hard dollars, David Wilson, Daniel Smith, Andrew
Jackson, Robert Hays, Thomas B. Craighead, Ephrin McLane, James Robertson, and Lardner Clark, trustees ofthe
academy established by virtue of an aa of assembly ofNorth Carolina passed at New Bern sessions 1785, entitled
an aa for the promotion oflearning in the county ofDa\idson, have sold for the use ofthe academy a tract ofland
containing 640 acres to John Caffrey and Col. John Callov^^y on Stones River knov^Ti as Stoner Lick traa" (28).
In listing the many improvements in Nashville by 1814 Zadok Dramer, editor of the Pittsburgh Navigator and
Almanac, mentioned Nashville's 200 or more houses, many ofthem large elegant buildings ofbrick. He had words
of praise for the two churches, the courthouse, the jail, the Rrverbend Thomas Craighead's Davidson Academy"
(29).
The above references mentioning an academy are for additional understanding and not to be confused with
property under consideration as being the same academy.
Thomas Rucker may have taught here after it became an academy because Thomas was one of the board
members of BradleyAcademy (30).
Samuel P Black was an educator, and he could have taught here as well as being the headmaster of Bradley
Academy (31).
A partial school record shows  that there were private classes throughout the county as late as 1888. This
record lists pupils at Red Oak Grove, Overall's Chapel, Fox Camp School House, and Twelve Comers. One entry
reads as follows: "Began school at Twelve Comers the 5th of March, 1888 with only three pupils. I have alvrays
heard it said, 'A bad beginning, a good ending", but felt somewhat discouraged at the gloomy prospects. Second
day, eight pupils, quite an improvement on yesterday. Third day, ten pupils. I think my school v^ill be very good by
next week if they continue to come in like they have been this week. Monday of the second week, have thirteen
pupils" (32).
I am satisfied with this report because I learned more than I expeaed starting out, I do defend this report as
being as valid as a lot of published materials. Look how much more important it would have been to be exaa
rather than to say "Thomas Rucker lived between Murfreesboro andJeSerson". I consider this an unfinished work
because there may be more information out there, and I will continue to put the word out.
I am grateful to those who helped in making this report as factual as possible: Martha Wright at the Ruther-ford
County Office Building Register of Deeds who went above and beyond the call of duty in helping to search
and make copies ofdeeds. Michael Strutt and associates at MTSU Center for Historic Preservation; Michael made
two trips here for thorough stud}' of construction and material used. They concurred that the house was a first
quarter 19th century structure. Harold L. Beasley made available to me all the information that he had on the Black
femily. Ann Pickard pro\'ided me with a copy of2(90 Years ofRuckers in Middle Tennessee by Mary Rucker Estes.
The staff at Tennessee Historical Commission was helpful in obtaining a copy of the deed of Isaac Shelby from
Tennessee Archives.
Martin J. Rooker
Pages
BroUOGRAPHY
The Cumberland byJames McCagne
1. Page 26
2. Pages 30, 31
3. Page 39
4. Page 34
5. Page 36
6. Page 77
29. Page 144
DeedAbstracts on Stones River from Deed Books A, B, C, D, E, F, ofDavidson County, Tennessee 1784 - 1806
by E.K Johns, 1981.
Fite, Emerson D., and Freeman, Archibald, eds. A Book ofOldMaps Delineatiiig AtJierican History. New
York: 1969.
7. Deed Abstracts page 79
8. Deed Abstracts page 96
10. Deed Abstracts page 136
11. Deed Abstracts pages 104, 105
12. Deed Abstracts page 104
13. Deed Abstracts page 32
14. Deed Abstracts page 120
15. Deed Abstracts page 124
28. Deed Abstracts page 38
History ofthe RuckerFamily and TheirDescendants by EdytheJohns Rucker Whitley
9. page 67
16. page 225
AHistory ofRutherford County by Carlton C. Sims.
17. page 24
30. page 148
31. page 148
32. School record in possession of Martin Rooker
Rutherford County Deed Office
18. Book K, page 41
19. Book K, page 58
20. Book L, page 5
21. Book M, page 399
22. Book O, page 315
23. Book R, page 419
24. Book S, p^es 97, 98
25. Books, page 359
27. Book 8, page 57
Hearthstoites: Tlje Story ofHistoric Rutheiford County Hom&amp;s by Mary B. Hughes
26. Page 22</dc:description>
<dc:description>Describes a series of land transactions related to "Pebble Hill," a house that was associated with the Rucker family and other early county residents</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Rucker family</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro;</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>3 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>mt2011-01-24</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication39ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/4</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>