<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>A history of the town of Jefferson, 1803 - 1813</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Markuson, Kevin</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 17</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1981</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1800-1809; 1810-1819</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>A HISTORY
OF
THE TOWN OP JEFFERSON
1803 - 1813
Kevin Markuson
PREFACE
With our modern world changing so fast before our eyes,
it is important to preserve and keep alive the traditions and heritage
of our ancestors. It is in this spirit of preservation of our heritage
that the researching and writing of this short history has been done.
It is also in this spirit that I offer this work to the people of
Rutherford County; that they may more fully understand the life and
times of the people that settled this land and thereby perpetuate a
continuity with their past.
This history of Jefferson does not purport to be a complete,
detailed history of the town. As more research is done, I am sure
more facts concerning the town and events surrounding it will come
to light. I have tried to cover, as thoroughly as possible, the ten
years in which the town was formed and grew, up until the courts moved
to Murfreesboro in 1813.
I would like to extend my most deep and heart felt gratitude
to those persons who were so kind to open their homes, materials and
memories to me, while I was researching this history. Ernest K. Johns,
Everett Waller, Mr. and Mrs. Lee Victory, Mrs. Becky Spring, Mrs. Peyton
Smith, Walter K. Hoover, Hatton Ward and Kathryn Barrett. I would like
to extend a special note of gratitude to Dr. Ernest Hooper for all his
instruction, guidance aFfd inspiration that he gave me during the
researching and writing of this history and to ray wife Cathy for her
never failing moral support and interest.
THE FORMATION AND EARLY GROWTH
OF THE TOWN OF JEFFERSON
The town of Jefferson was located within the forks of
the Stones River. This land was part of an assignee land grant to
-1
Robert Weakley and Thomas Bedford from the state of North Carolina.
The original grant reads, "by an act of our General Assembly entitled
an act for the relief of the officers and soldiers in the Continental
line and for and in consideration of the signal bravery and persevering
zeal of James Pearl, a captain in the Continental line of said state ....
Robert Weakley and Thomas Bedford were the assignees of James Pearl.
This land grant is dated December 12, 1801 and was for 3,840 acres, that
being the amount of land granted to a captain.
The town of Jefferson was laid out by Weakley and Bedford
prior to June 1803, when these lands were still a part of Davidson
County. A plat of the town was registered with th&#163; Davidson County
Clerk according to early deeds for town lots. The town was laid out
2 with a public square and 102 town lots.
Weakley and Bedford held the first sale of town lots on
June 10 and 13, 1803 as many of the early deeds for town lots, registered
with the Rutherford County Register, bear these dates. It is interesting
to note that Weakley and Bedford gave town lots to certain individuals
at this time. William Nash (a Justice of the Peace) and Joseph Herndon
(County Trustee for Davidson County and soon to be County Clerk for
Rutherford County) were given lots #20 and #81 respectively " for and
in consideration of the respect and friendship they (Weakley and Bedford)
5
bear ... .
" -^ A total of 40 lots were sold on June 10 and 13, 1803.
I no. 18 shows
boundaries
of land grant
to Weakley
and Bedford
for 3,840
acres
A/?
/
2
3
-/&#8226;
s
G
7
8
9
lo
II
ri
'3
1^
/S
fC I
/-? I
Qr^ n i eff Ds
Euse-kius fbfsh n &lt;=// \M&gt;r. Car.
^''^ihAnieJ Hc^rf- h e/'n
Ed i*^ 3rci Co/.
5h3iir6ick uoni?s
Josttfh MSrfif) '
S^e/ohen C,in fri II
Pa.ru &#171;f Chcotibers
&#163;^An Shelby i"
\f'/0 fS ftLtn *i /'*'&lt;
Kfor. Ln,-
/Vcr.rir
HZ
IT
1739
37?
D^f-e
J;3n.'2i,/800
Apr. 17 I7P&amp;
Apr t-^. 11^)1,
Apr. irj.n-]'i
i\-r. ff,!7S7
QJi/. Co.
A- ^i8
It-ifi
L - 2oy
A '^/o
D iq
C &#8226; lV-t&gt;A
C". Joo
C- Z5-/
C- 3/1?
&gt;]- t 'I
t.'-;-5c'
A- ?-"
Acyei
6 &#165;0
Z7V-IS?
6M9
note: the
grant number
for no. 18
should be
5390
&lt;i.' Wet. 9 '7S7 A '-"&#8226;^ '^'&gt;'^
From "The Southern Virginia Weakley ]?arailies and their Descendents"
by S.A. Weakley Courtesy Mrs. Becky Spring
Some of the first buyers were John Hill, James Sharpe, Alexander
McCulloch and William Nash, soon to be prominent personages in the
growing community of Jefferson.
During the summer of 1805, a growing movement for the
formation of a separate county in the environs of Stones River was
about to reach a climax. Petitions were sent by a number of citizens
in Davidson and Williamson Counties requesting that a new county be
laid off due to the vast extent of the counties and the hardships
to the citizens in attending courts, general musters and elections in
the towns of Nashville and Franklin. A petition of August 26, 1803
further requests that the navigation of Stones River be kept open
from Cummins Mill to the mouth of the river to carry produce to the
market. The petition also requests that Captain Joseph Walton, James
Sharpe, Robert Smyth, Captain William Doran, John Andrews, O.M. Benge
and James Campbell be appointed commissioners to establish the place
of the seat of justice. Petitioners included John Cummins, Travis
Nash, Cader and Abner Dement and Samuel Wilson.
It is interesting to note that as early as 1802, settlers
living south of the Cumberland settlements were desiring a separate
county. This is evidenced by a petition, in the Tennessee State Library
and Archives, to the General Assembly from citizens living on or
near the Big Harpeth River, dated December 8, 1802. The land included
within the bounds proposed by this petition would have included the
present eastern portion of Williamson County and the present western
portion of Kutherford County.
There were some opposing the creation of a new county in 1803.
This is evidenced by a petition to the General Assembly from
citizens of Davidson County requesting that a new county not be
laid off for reasons of inconvenience if the request for a new
7 county should be granted.
Rutherford County was formed by an act of the General
Assembly , October 25, 1803, entitled, " An act to erect the
counties of Davidson and Williamson into three separate and
distinct counties.'^ Contained within this act, the courts were
to meet on the first Nonday in March, June, September and December.
The first court was to be held at the home of Thomas Rucker and
subsequent courts were to be held at different places until a
courthouse was built. It was further declared that Rutherford
be a part of Mero District for all military and civil purposes
and that the sheriffs of Davidson and Williamson Counties be free
to collect taxes that were due the date of the act. On November 7,
1803, the General Assembly passed " A supplementary act to the
act creating Rutherford County. &#176; William Nash, on the part of
Rutherford County, and Samuel Weakley, on the part of Davidson
County, were appointed commissioners to run the line between
Rutherford and Davidson Counties. They were to make out a plat,
with the distances to the major water . courses, and file this with
the clerk of the county. The lines of the county were to be run
by the " first of January next. " The several justices that fell
into Rutherford County after the lines were run were appointed
justices in Rutherford with the same powers as before.
Nashville, August 18,1802
"During the last two weeks, the Indians have
stolen horses three different times from the
inhabitants on the waters of Stones River- in
the two first instances the horses have been
recovered but not in the last. Such depredations
as these it is not probable, will be submitted
to with impunity- they are supposed to be Creeks
or Cherokees."
_**-x- **}&#171;.
Tennessee Gazette, August 18, 1802
After the sale of lots in June of 1803, there v/ere only
a few sales of lots in Jefferson by Weakley and Bedford in August and
September. On New Year's Eve 1803, Weakley and Bedford sold to Joseph
Herndon 501^ acres, lying on both sides of the West Fork of Stones
River, situated not far from the town of Jeff erson.^'^This was to
become the home of Joseph Herndon as evidenced by later court entries
describing roads in the county. That same day, Weakley and Bedford
also sold to Joseph Bowman 141-^ acres lying on the West Fork of
1
1
Stones River. On this land, Joseph Bowman was authorized by the
1 ? courts to build a mill in January 1808. "^
The court, according to the above mentioned act of the
General Assembly, met for the first time at the home of Thomas Rucker,
near where the Veteran's Administration stands today. The first mention
of holding court in Jefferson was in the adjournment of the first
session, when it was recorded that the "court in course be held at
the forks of Stones River at the junction of the main West and East forks."''
In July, 1804, the county court met at the "courthouse" in Jefferson
agreeable to the adjournment of the previous session J ^ Court was
also held in Jefferson in October 1804.'''' It must be remembered that
Jefferson at this time had not been chosen for the seat of justice
for Rutherford County yet. However, Weakley and Bedford, without doubt,
must have envisioned Jefferson to be the seat of justice. At this
time, Jefferson was the only organized town in the county and its
situation between the forks of the river made it a potential center
for trade and commerce for the area.
These early references to a courthouse in Jefferson support
the tradition that the early courts were held in the Lenoir house.'"
This house stood on the north side of what was the old square. During
demolition for the Percy Priest project, a two story log structure
was uncovered that was incorporated into the house. Most likely, Weakley
and Bedford donated this log building to the county for use as a
courthouse in an attempt to have Jefferson selected as the county seat.
Later, in 1806, the Commissioners of Jefferson would order the sale
of this building when the new courthouse was finished.
On August 3, 1804, the General Assembly passed an act
appointing commissioners to fix a place for the seat of justice for
Rutherford County. John Hill, Fredrick Barfield, Mark Mitchell,
Alexander McKnight and Peter Legrand were appointed commissioners
to select a site "having special regard to good water." '' It was
further enacted that the commissioners acquire 40 acres of land for
the erection of the public buildings, lay off a town to be named by
them and sell lots at a public sale. A tax was also authorized to
defray the expenses of a new courthouse that was to be built. With
an organized town, containing several good springs and access by-road
or watercourse, established and growing within the forks of
Stones River, Jefferson was a logical choice for the seat of justice.
Unfortunately, no records are available today of the proceedings
of the commissioners that would reveal to us any alternative sites
they may have considered.
There was very little real estate activity in Jefferson during
the year 1804, with just a few lots being transferred by the original
buyers. Weakley and Bedford did not sell any lots in Jefferson, in
1804, according to present deed book records.
Although the county court had temporary facilities, in the
log "courthouse", apparently there were no facilities to hold prisoners.
During the July session, of 1804, the sheriff, Samuel McBride, entered
a protest to the court that there was no jail within the county to
1
8
hold prisoners.
In the October session of court, Peter Legrand, John Hill,
Mark Mitchell, Alexander McKnight and Fredrick Barfield came into
Jefferson and gave bond and security for the office of commissioners
to fix a place for the seat of justice.''^ For some unknown reason,
James Sharpe, the other commissioner named in the act of the General
on
Assembly did not give bond until January 10, 1805.^ On this same
day, Alexander McKnight and Fredrick Barfield filed their resignations
as commissioners with the County Clerk! s office. ' As the records of
the proceedings of the commissioners are not known to be in existence
today, the question of why they resigned is open to conjecture. It may
have resulted from some disseneion within the commission, or an
8
inconvenience of the duties of the appointment to the above commissioners.
The court moved from Jefferson after the October session
of 1804 and convened at Simon Miller's house on the first Monday in
January, 1805. The court met for the ensuing sessions, through January
1806, at the home of Nimrod Menifee, except for the July session which
22 did go back to the log courthouse in Jefferson. Within the act creating
Rutherford County, it was stipulated that the courts were to move from
place to place until the seat of justice was chosen.
j^i &gt;-
N
courtesy Sam Davis Home
"The Weakley Map of Jefferson"
photo courtesy Everett Waller
Ephram Waller's house was located on the South side of the square,
The main section of the house is said to have been constructed
of logs, beneath the weatherboarding. This could have been one
of the buildings built during the early years of the town.
photo from Nashville Banner Feb. 14,1967
The Bone house was built across the main street from the Lenoir house.
This house is also said to have been built with logs and appears to be
a double pen type. 9
10
ROBERT WEAKLEY
SURVEXUR, LAND SPECULATOR AND POLITICIAN
R6bez*t Weakley was bom JtQy 2, 176U in Halifax County
23
Virginia. In 1781, at the age of 16, he was in the Continental
Amy and foxight in the battles of Alamance and Oxdlford Courthouse.
On ^ril 18, 1782, it is said that young Robert Weakley
left his home in Halifax County with a horse, bridle and saddle and
$1.75 and vent to Rowan County, North Carolina to study surveyijig
with General Griffith Rutherford for ^om Rutherford County was
named. During the winter of I783-U4 he came to the Cumberland
settlements b7 way of the Cumberland Gap and the old wilderness road
throTi^ Kentucky. He then set vp residence on Whites Creek in
Davidson County until moving to his estate in Nashville, "Lockland",
in 1800.
Robert Weakley married the dati^ter of General Mathew Locke,
Jane Locke, of Saulsbury, North Carolina, in 1791. They had four
children, Mary, Narcissa, Robert Locke and Jane Baird. His brother,
Samuel Weakley, also lived in the Nashville area and worked with
him as a chain carrier during early surveying work.
Robert Weakley's fortune was made in land speculations
and land surveying. He surveyed many of the early military land
warrants throughout Middle Tennessee. Ha did much of the early
survey work around the Dtick and Elk rivers and in later years
11
surveyed in the West Tennessee area. Robert Weakley accumulated
massive land holdings through his surveying work and land grants.
Only assignee or purchase grants were ever issued to Robert Weakley,
An assignee grant was issued if one purchased the right to the land
from one who is entitled to it, but may not want the land( as in
the case of the land grant #3390 to Weakley and Bedford - they
bought the right for the land grant from James Pearl). Purchase
grants were issued for so much per acre or 100 acres.
Robert Weakley owned 8,000 acres on the waters of Half
Pone Creek and Sycamore Creek. He also owned land on the Cumberland,
Red, Harpeth, Stones, Elk and Duck rivers and on Whites, McAdoo and
Richland creeks. Some of his surveying work in West Tennessee was
in Obion, Tipton, Haywood and Shelby counties.
Prom his earliest times in the Cumberland settlements,
Robert Weakley stood out as a leader among his fellow settlers. In
the Draper Papers ( Draper MSS 32-5-353 ), there is an account of
Robert Weakley's role in averting an abandonment of the Cumberland
settltments in 1786. According to the Draper Papers, the settlers on
the south side of the Cumberland had become very discouraged due
to the continued depredations committed by the Indians during the
winter of 1785-6. Hearing of the discouragement and the talk of
abandoning the settlement, young Robert Weakley drew up a paper,
for himself and other friends to sign, pledging themselves to "remain
and protect the country".
During the eariy spring of 1786, the settlers held a meeting
at Robertson's Station to decide their fate. According to the Draper
Papers, several settlers spoke, "representing that from the depredations
12
of the winter, and the loss of friends, that they had nothing to
hope from raising a crop this coming season, and it was proposed
that such as had horses to pack them and go to Illinois and such
as had none to prepare large piroques and go by water." Weakley
asked Robertson permission to speak. "Weakley represented that
although he was a young man, he felt a deep interest in the permanent
occupation of the country; that if the people on the south side of
the Cumberland broke up and abandoned the country, those on the north
would certainly follow their example; that he and they had toiled
and risked their lives for succesive years in acquiring lands and
now to abandon them, it would be extremely uncertain when they be
resettled and hence after all their toils and sufferings they could
little hope ever to realize anything for them. He then read the paper
containing the proposition of himself and other young men and he
pledged himself that they should remain as promised. Robertson arose
with a cheerful and inspiring countenance and simply said, "Lid you
hear this? - Let's all agree to stay." "Agreed" was the unanimous
response and it was everyone to his tent, ho Israel! Robertson's
station, which had become dilapidated was now repaired, the same of
other stations, and the young men guarding, a good crop was raised
in the country.
"
Robert Weakley continued to be a leader in the area and
became very involved in politics throughout his life. In July of
1788, he represented Lavidson County on the commission to decide on
the seat of government for North Carolina and that November, he was
elected an Esquire for the county. Robert Weakley was a member of
the Tennessee House of Representatives in 1796 and of the Senate in
13
1799,1803,1807 and 1819. He was also a member of the U.S. House of
Representatives at Washington May 1809 - March 1811.
Robert Weakley also had an active role in the militia of
the Cumberland settlements during his younger years. In 1791, he was
the Brigade Inspector of the militia of Mero District, with the rank
of Lieutenant Colonel. In 1798, he was a Colonel of the 2nd Regiment
of the Davidson County Militia.
Robert Weakley's survey mark
which he would carve on corner trees
14
THOMAS BEDFORD
A DREAM NEVER REALIZED
Thomas Bedford was "born sometime between 1754 and 1758,
24
in Cumberland County, Virginia. At an early age, he moved with
his family to Drakes Branch in Charlotte County, Virginia to live
on lands inherited by his father, Thomas Bedford Sr. The Bedfords
of Charlotte County, were one of the most wealthy and prominent families
of that county with extensive land holdings in that part of the country.
Thomas Bedford took an active role in the Revolutionary
War. He enlisted on February 5, 1776 as a private in John Brent's
Company, 4th Virginia Regiment. Records of Henry County, Virginia
indicate that near the end of the war he was made a Lieutenant by the
justices of that county. These records also indicate that he served
in the last military campaign against Lord Cornwallis at Yorktown.
According to a family tradition, he personally outfitted a volunteer
company and led them during a part of the conflict. Another tradition,
concerning Thomas' military career, holds that he refused a promotion
in the army because he had promised the mothers of the young men,
serving with him, that he would stay with them during the fighting and
see them safely home when the war was over.
After the Revolution, Thomas Bedford represented Charlotte
County in the Virginia Assembly. After a brief political career, he
moved to the new settlements at Nashville, where he had accumulated
extensive real estate holdings in the area (presumably for his
military services in the Revolutionary War). He also owned more than
5,000 acres in Christian and Harrison Counties, Kentucky, receivino"
15
them as land grants for his military service.
Thomas Bedford was associated with a man named Maury, in
Nashville, concerning some land holdings. Bedford left Nashville to
return to Virginia to close his affairs there and left his lands for
Maury to sell. When he returned to the Cumberland, he discovered that
Maury had sold all of his real estate holdings in that area. Maury
tried to persuade Thomas Bedford to join him in a new settlement to the soul
of Nashville, but he refused. Instead, he joined in a partnership with
Robert Weakley and undertook the joint founding of the town of Jefferson.
He left the Nashville area and took up residence on the West Fork of
Stones River. The partnership of Weakley and Bedford was formed sometime
before 1801, as this is the date of the land grant that was issued to
Weakley and Bedford. This land grant was the only holding of the
partnership.
The earliest mention of Thomas Bedford in the Davidson
County records is an entry in the County Court Minute Book 1783 - 1809,
page 325, dated July 13, 1802. In this entry, a road is ordered to be
laid off from Thomas Bedford's home to Nashville one way, and Cripple
Creek the other way.
Thomas Bedford was not able to see his dream of a town within
the forks of Stones River come to a full fruition, for he died suddenly
sometime in the summer or early fall of 1804, before Jefferson had
officially been selected as the county seat of justice. On October 2,
1804, Ann Bedford, his widow, came into the Rutherford County court
and relinquished her right of administration and nominated her eldest
OR
son, John R. Bedford, to administer the estate. In addition to being
appointed administrator of the estate, John R. Bedford was also
appointed, , by the court, guardian for his minor brothers and sister;
16
Thomas, William, George, Nancy, Benjamin and Littleberry.
Thomas Bedford left no will and his estate and financial
matters were in such shape that nearly all his holdings were lost
through outstanding debts and law suits against his estate. The
remaining portion of unsold land that was held by Weakley and Bedford
was divided equally between Robert Weakley and the heirs of Thomas
Bedford by a commission appointed by the County Court of Rutherford,
In 1807, when a new county was organized out of Rutherford,
on the south. side in the. area of the Duck River, General Joseph
Dixon proposed that the new county be named in honor of Thomas Bedford.
Accordingly, the legislature followed this proposition.
27
^A'^'
;a^
;
,
^^~^,~ ^j^,^:r^^,/iC /..^ ^,
Inventory of Thomas Bedford's estate
17
JEFFERSON
THE COUNTY SEAT OF JUSTICE
The commission must have selected Jefferson as the site
for the county seat by April of 1805, for it was on April 4th that
they levied a tax for the purpose of erecting the public buildings
in the county as provided for in the act of the General Assembly.
Although it appears that the town of Jefferson was chosen as the
seat of justice in 1805, Robert Weakley did not deed the land to the
29
commissioners of Jefferson until Feburary 16, 1806. He deeded 40
acres of land on the south and east sides of the town, "for and in
consideration of the regard he bears toward the said county of
Rutherford." This particular tract of land was one of the divisions
of the unsold portion of the 3,840 acres that was owned by Weakley
and Bedford, and was alloted to Robert Weakley after the death of
30 Thomas Bedford. Referring to the Weakley map of Jefferson, Weakley
donated the land contained in lots #103 through #162 which the
commissioners had surveyed and laid off to be sold to help defray
the cost of the new courthouse.
During the year 1805, the town of Jefferson must have been
bustling with activity. Presumably, the new courthouse was being
constructed on the square and wharves and warehouses were being
erected by the river to handle the trade that was increasing with the
growing population of the county. Most likely, other structures were
also being built in Jefferson to accomodate the business needs of
the community and surrounding area.
18
Robert Weakley deeds 40 acres to the commissioners of Jefferson
"Beginning at the Northeast corner of the said tovm of
Jefferson aiittle above the head of a spring on the East Fork of
Stones River on the North side of the main street of
the public square running thence North thirty three degrees East one
chain sixty five links to a stone in the bank of said East Fork of
Stones River, thence up the East Fork with it's meanders to a
and large ash in the original East boundary of a tract of three
thousand eight hundred and forty acres belonging to Robert Weakley
and Thomas Bedford dec'd. Thence with said boundary line South
fifteen chains and eighty links to a red oak, thence West thirty seven
chains to the West Fork of Stones River, thence down the said West
Fork with it's meanders to a stone due South of the now South West
corner of said old town of Jefferson. Thence North to said corner
six chains, thence East with the South boundary of said old town
to the main South street of the same, thence up the West boundary of
said street to the public square, thence around said square so as to
include the whole to the Eastern boundary of the aforesaid street,
thence down the same South to the aforesaid South boundary of said
town, thence North with the East boundary of said town to the
beginning. . . ."
From the Seed, Robert Weakley to the Commissioners
of Jefferson
Rutherford County Register, Deed Book E, p. 400
19
Norton Gum was appointed the overseer of the streets and
public square in Jefferson, on July 2, 1805, with all the hands
within the bounds of the town to work under him. He had also been
licensed to keep an ordinary at his dwelling house, in the town of
32 Jefferson. The Norton Gum ordinary was the first to be licensed
in the town of Jefferson. Tradition holds that Mark Mitchell had the
first ordinary within the town, but no evidence could be uncovered
to support this.
During 1805, Wm. P. Anderson petitioned the court to build
a mill, on the East Pork of Stones River, about 600 yards from the
33 town of Jefferson. -^^ This site now is the picnic area of the East
Fork access area. There was indeed a mill built here which in later
years was known as the Ridley or Davis mill. A small portion of the
mill dam can still be seen today.
It appears that the commissioners had a sale of town lots
in Jefferson on December 26, 1805, as a number of deeds registered
in Rutherford County for town lots bear this date. A total of 11
lots were sold that day. Robert Weakley, Samuel Bell and John Bell
were among the purchasers of lots. 35
The first election held in Rutherford County, with Jefferson
as its political center, was held in 1805. On July 2, 1805, the court
appointed James Sharpe, Samuel Wilson, Hugh Robinson, Constant Hardeman,
Alexander McCulloch and Joseph Herndon as inspectors and judges of
36
the next election. Jefferson was undoubtedly the polling place for
the county.
By order of the commissioners to fix a place for the seat
of justice, Wm. Quisenbury, a surveyor, determined the center of the
20
county sometime in 1805. The county seat was usually centered so
as not to put any part of the citizens at a disadvantage in attending
courts, elections and general musters. On January 7, 1806 while court
was being held at the Menifee house, Wm. Quisenbury was allowed eight
37 dollars for his services.
Clarissa of Jefferson
A Black Woman's Fight for Freedom
Clarissa's legal fight for her freedom started in April
of 1805 and was to last for at least two years.
On April 2, 1805, the court ordered William Edwards to
to give bond to permit Clarissa to appear at the next court when
she was to pursue her appeal for her freedom. The court further
ordered that Clarissa "be treated with humanity" by William
&#8226;zo
Edwards in the mean time.
William Edwards must not have taken any action by this
court order, for on July 4, 1805, the court again ordered William
to give bond, in the amount of one thousand dollars, to permit
Clarissa, "who has sued him in this court for her freedom", to
appear before the court during the proceedings of her suit against
39
him. Again, the court ordered William to treat her with humanity.
The next court entry. concerning this suit was on October 7,
1806, fifteen months after William was last ordered to give bond
for the assurance of her appearence in court. ^ The court entry
for this date reads, "Clarissa vs. Wm. Edwards - False Imprisonment,"
21
In this particular case, the jury granted a mistrial to the
defendant, Wm. Edwards.
During the following session of court, on January 7,
1807, William Edwards and Clarissa, along with their attorneys
came into court where Clarissa was again suing him for false
imprisonment. ^ The jury found the defendant "not guilty as
charged in the plantiff's declaration above, and that the said
plantiff is the slave of him, the said defendant." An appeal was
"prayed and granted;" On the same day, January 7, in a separate
entry, it was recorded that Alexander Moore, a witness for the
plantiff was called but did not appear and therefore "forfeited
agreeably to an act of the General Assembly. "^Was this the appeal
that was granted by the court? Unfortunately there are no further
entries in the county court records concerning the case of Clarissa
and William Edwards, but the story of Clarissa is not over yet.
On July 1, 1810, O.M. Benge sold to a Clarissa Boushane
lot #122 in the town of Jefferson for two dollars. '^'^ In the 1810
census for Rutherford County a Clarissa Beshano was recorded as
residing, as a head of household, in the town of Jefferson. ^^
She was at least 45 years old and had one slave, according to
the census. The County Court Minute Books for Rutherford County
reveal that Clarissa bought two more lots in Jefferson on October 8,
1812; one from 0. M. Benge and lot #124 from William Locke. ^^ .
In a report, dated 1813, on improved lots in the town
of Jefferson, Clarissa appears again as "Clarese Bushoug, a woman
of color from one of the French Islands." Is this the same
Clarissa who six years ago brought William Edwards into court
to sue him for her freedom? If so, how did she finally gain her
freedom? Could a settlement between Clarissa and Wm. Edwards have
taken place out of court, with Clarissa gaining her freedom and
taking up residence in the town of Jefferson where she could have
found work in an ordinary: or some other business? Without further
documentation, the answers to these and other questions will remain
unanswered.
In April of 1806, the court moved back to Jefferson,
presumably to the newly constructed courthouse on the square. 47
In Goodspeed History of Rutherford County , the courthouse is said
to have been constructed of brick -and measured roughly 40 feet
by 40 feet. The cost is said to have been between two and three
thousand dollars. A copy of the Weakley map of Jefferson, at the
Sam Davis Home in Smyrna, describes the courthouse as built with
brick and stone.
The town as well as the county was growing rapidly in
these first years. On April 9, 1806, Thomas Mitchell , obtained a
48 license to keep an ordinary at his dwelling house. The Mitchell
ordinary was the second ordinary to be licensed for the town of
Jefferson, the Norton Gum ordinary being the first. 49&#8226; According
to an article in the Nashville Tennessean,' dated March 26, 1950,
John Nash Read came into Jefferson and established another tavern
on the square sometime in 1806, The Read tavern was said to have
had stables across the east main street, which in later years was
50 turned into a blacksmith's shop after the tavern closed down.
23
photo from the Walter K.
Hoover collection
Thurman Francis Jr. High
Smyrna
The Ridley or Davis mill, as it was known
in later years. Wm. P. Anderson obtained
permission to erect a mill on this site
in 1805.
The logs used in thi- l.::i- -ici.juse were said
to once have been used for the old jail in
Jefferson.
photo courtesy Everett Wall&#171;
The Read tavern was built around 1806 and
stood on the Northeast corner of the square.
24
The rates for ordinaries were set by the court in 1804 and were
31
as follows:
dinner 25 cents
breakfast and supper 20 cents
lodging 8 ''/3 cents
corn or oats per gallon 8 1/3 cents
stabling a horse for 24 hours
with corn, fodder or oats 33 1/3 cents
"good wiskey" 1/2 pint 12 1/2 cents
peach brandy 12 1/2 cents
French brandy, rum or wine 50 cents
As the town was growing and prospering, there was also
an increase in violence and disturbances of the peace. There were
three taverns in Jefferson at this time, and after a journey up
the river from Nashville, they surely must have been a welcome sight
to a thirsty riverman. No doubt, on different occasions, overindulgence
of the spirits may have caused some brawls and other disturbances
in the town of Jefferson. Throughout the county court minutes for
1806, there are numerous cases of assault and battery and trespassing.
John Spence and William Gilliam were appointee the first patrollers
for the town of Jefferson on April 17, 1806.^2 Patrollers were also
appointed for McCoy's militia co., Capt. Wm. Searcy's militia co
.
53
and Capt. Nimrod Jenkin's militia co. out in the surrounding county.
In July of 1806, the county clerk, Joseph Herndon, and
the sheriff of the county were provided space in the new courthouse.
The court ordered that Joseph Herndon "have leave to appropriate the
corner of the courthouse upon the upper floor at the head of the
25
of the staircase for the purpose of an office so as not to interfere
with a sufficient passage at the head of the staircase." The court
also ordered that " the sheriff of this county have leave to make
for his own use a closet under the staircase in the courthouse, in
such a manner as he may think proper, not injuring said staircase."
As the new courthouse must have been completed by now,
with the county offices taking residence within, the court ordered
the commissioners of the public buildings to put up for public sale
the old courthouse in the town of Jefferson. ^5 Unfortunatly, several
deed books for the county are lost and it is impossible to trace this
further. If a deed were to be located between John P. Lenoir and the
commissioners, this would confirm the tradition that the first courts
were held in the Lenoir house.
A jail for the county had been constructed of logs and was
probably located on the north west corner of the square. I'lr. Lee
Victory, former owner of the Lenoir house prior to the Percy Priest
Project, claims that the logs of his smokehouse were the logs used
in the first jail for the county. He moved the structure from Jefferson
to his present home, in Smyrna, during the dismantling of the town
for the Percy Priest Project.^"
In April of 1807, James Lewis deeded to the commissioners
of Jefferson one half of lot #101 "for the benefit of the citizens
and the public buildings use.''^' He was paid 54 dollars for the half
lot. It remains a mystery what the commissioners did with their half
of lot #101. In referring to the Weakley map of Jefferson, Lot #101
was one lot away from the square on the northwest side. This v/ould
have been a logical choice for a public building, being in close
proximity to the courthouse, but no records can be found today to
26
ST /&lt;^I)lSlBJ^^^'
From Tennessee State Library and Archives
A portion of a surveyors map of the first district, 1807-8 , showing
the town of Jefferson and the major roads leading to Nasnville, Franklin,
Lebanon and the settlements at Readyville.
27
pursue this further.
By the latter part of 1807, the commissioners' tasks were
completed and they were made allowances for their services and
expenditures in fixing a place for the public buildings for the county.
The court ordered James Sharpe 16 dollars, Constant Hardeman 8 dollars,
John Hill 50 dollars, Mark Mitchell 50 dollars and Peter Legrand
75 dollars on October 5, 1807.^^ Fredrick Barfield, one of the
commissioners who resigned, was allowed 10 dollars for his services. 59
Alexander McKnight, the other commissioner who resigned, was not
appropriated any compensation for his services until the January
session of 1808, when he was allowed 20 dollars.
In addition to the courthouse, jail and stocks, wharves,
warehouses, taverns and houses in Jefferson, there was also a
blacksmith's shop in October 1807. On October 6, 1807, the court
ordered certain individuals to lay out a road, "beginning at the mouth
of the main street near the blacksmith's shop" leading from Jefferson
to Lebanon.^'' According to the map of Jefferson, this would have put
the blacksmith's shop down the hill from the courthouse near the
riverfront.
There also may have been a government land office in
Jefferson for a short time in 1806-7. In a move to settle the continued
land disputes between Tennessee and North Carolina, the General
Assembly of Tennessee, in 1806, passed an act entitled, "An act directing
the division of the state into convenient districts, for the appointment
of the principal surveyors thereof, and for ascertaining the bona
fide claims against the same." In section eight of this act, the
locations for the district offices are as follows: the first district
office at Nashville, the second district office at Jefferson, the
2B
third district office at Alexander's, the fourth district office
at Kingston, the fifth district office at Knoxville, the sixth district
office ay Joneshorough and the office for the territory south of the
French Broad and Holston rivers at Sevierville. Rutherford County
was within the bounds of the first district according to the boundary
descriptions in the above act and an early surveyors map in the
Tennessee State Library and Archives. The office for the second district
may have been located at Jefferson because it was the closest organized
town to the district ( the southern bound.ary between the first and
second districts was roughly the. boundary between Kuxneriord and Bedford
counties ). When Bedford County was organized, in 1807, the land office
may have been moved there, to Shelbyville, where it would have been
in the same district that it was authorized for.
On November 7, 1807, the General Assembly passed an act
entitled, "An act for the regulation of the town of Jefferson in
Rutherford County." According to this act, the sheriff was to hold
an election at the courthouse in Jefferson in April of 1808 to elect
five persons to act as commissioners of the town. Only those who
were either inhabitants of the town or owned property in the town
were allowed to participate as candidates or voters. The commissioners
were empowered to regulate the town including calling on inhabitants
who were; -iiaoi-e to work -^he roads, appointing an overseer of the
streets, "prevent encroachments on the streets or burials on the
public square" and appointing a surveyor to re survey the town,
agreeable to the original plan, and designating the lots by stone
cornerstones at each lot. They were also authorized to lay an annual
tax on the town as follows:
29
Not exceeding $100 worth tovm property. .. 1 2 1/2 cents
White poll 12 1/2 cents
Each black poll 25 cents
Each stud horse 75 cents
The appraisement and collection of this tax was subject to all the
rules and regulations of the state tax. Section VIII of this act
stipulated that the monies collected through this tax were to be
appropriated only for the benefit or improvement of the town and that
the commissioners were not to receive any compensation for their
services.
The town must have grown considerably by this time to
require a town commission and a town tax for its proper upkeep.
As the population of the county increased, the business and traffic
in and through Jefferson must have increased proportionately. There
was the river traffic, bringing goods up river from Nashville for
sale or trade in and around Jefferson and when the court was in
session, the town must have been busy with the Justices, witnesses,
petitioners and jury members that came in for the court. In many of
the early court cases, witnesses were allowed so much money for so
many days attendance. This must have been to help defray the expense
of coming to Jefferson, possibly staying a night or two at one of
the ordinarys. For many , it was a long trip into Jefferson on horse-back
or in a wagon.
The population of the county had grown, by the end of
1807, to the extent that the General Assembly authorized another
place, in addition to Jefferson, for the next election to be held.^5
This act specified that all persons living in the 2nd Battalion
30
of the militia and those living east of the road from Cummins mill
(located on the East Fork of Stones River) to William Kelton's
were to vote at the house of William Kelton. William Kelton lived at
the Black Fox settlement. The sheriff was to carry the polls to the
courthouse in Jefferson, to be added and included in the total poll
of the county. It was also stipulated that "any person who votes at
both places of the holding of the election, shall pay ^10 to any
person who may sue for the same."
The pattern of migration, into Rutherford County by these
early settlers, was from the north by way of Jefferson and that
vicinity. As settlers pushed further south and east in the county,
they were at an increasing distance from Jefferson and consequently
under more of a hardship to attend courts and elections there. As
we shall see, in just a few short years, this will be a key factor
in the seat of justice being removed from Jefferson.
In January of 1808, an order by the county court extended
the area for which the overseer of the streets was responsible for
in Jefferson, to the east bank of the West Fork at the low water
mark. Norton Gum was still the overseer of the streets in Jefferson
at this time. Apparently, the area mentioned must have come into
disrepair, possibly from the traffic connected with the river trade.
The log jail must have also fallen into a state of disreDair, about
this time, for John Griffin was allowed 6 dollars and 16 3/4 cents
for repairing the jail. ^
Again in 1809, a separate election was held at the Black
Fox settlement in addition to the polling place at Jefferson. The
inspectors and judges of this election for Governor and members of
31
the legislature were Charles Ready, William Lofton, Robert
Smith, Sr. and Ezeckial McCoy. They were to oversee the election
at the Black Fox settlement as they were all inhabitants of the
southern and eastern portions of the county. With polling places
elsewhere in the county, Jefferson was rapidly losing its importance
as the legal and judicial center for the county.
On April 7, 1809, Joel Dyer, a resident of Jefferson,
was appointed overseer of the western boundary of the town to the
low water mark on the West Fork with all the liable hands within the
en
town to work under him. ' Later, in 1811, Joel Dyer was licensed
to keep an ordinary at his house in Jefferson. According to Goodspeed
History of Rutherford County, Joel Dyer moved his business to
Murfreesboro in 1812.
The census for 1810 shows the total number of inhabitants
in Jefferson to be 107, including heads of households, spouses,
children and slaves. Joel Dyer had the largest household within
the town with 11 males, 7 females and 9 slaves. As he was operating
an ordinary at this time, it is possible that some of the males and
females counted were boarders. He and George Simpson were the
largest slaveholders in Jefferson, each having 9 slaves. The heads
of households in the town of Jefferson were as follows: Joel Dyer,
James L. Armstrong, George Shall, Thomas Mitchell, Clement Read,
George Simpson, George R. Nash, Thomas Johnson, James Sharpe, Neil
B. Rose, WilliajTi D. Hill and Clarissa Boushane.
Again the jail had fallen into disrepair as John Griffin
was allowed ^3.45 for fixing the jail. 69 On the previous day he,
as sheriff of the county, protested about the "insufficiency of
32
THE LENOIR HOUSE
photo courtesy Hatton Ward
The Lenoir house in the 19th century
The Lenoir house during demolition,
showing the log structure that was
used as the first courthouse in
Jefferson.
photo from Nashville Banner Feb. 14, 1967
In later years, the log building was
added on to and the whole was covered
with weatherboards. The front was
changed from the East, facing the main
street to the river, to the South,
facing the old Jefferson Pike.
photo from Rutherford Courier
Aug. 7, 1967
33
70
the jail" in Jefferson. During the same session of court, on
January 2, 1810, Joseph Herndon resigned his position as the County
Clerk, having served 6 years in that position. '''
In January of 1811 new rates for taverns in Jefferson
and those out in the county were established by the court. They
were as follows:
Breakfast and Supper 16 3/4 cents
Dinner 25 cents
-5 Pint whiskey, peach brandy or gin 12^ cents
Each 24 hrs. horse kept in stables 57i cents
Each person a bed 6t cents
J 3?int rum, wine or French brandy 25 cents '^
The Tragic Story
of
Herbert Hardy
An interesting story comes to light, in Jefferson, in
an examination of the County Court minutes for April of 1811. It
appears there was a Dr. William Ward in Jefferson at this time
and on April 2, 1811, the court ordered that "if Dr. William Ward
will receive Herbert Hardy and will give him such medical aid, and
also furnish him with such nourishment as his situation may require,
that this court will make him a suitable allowance. " '^ Who this
Herbert Hardy was, where he had come from, and what injuries or
ailments he had is a mystery. All that is evident from an examination
of the records is that he came into Jefferson, injured or ill to
3k
the extent that the court was moved by his situation and appropriated
county funds for his care.
The next day, April 3, the court ordered that Thomas
Mitchell, who operated a tavern in town, be allowed $25 for furnishing
Herbert Hardy with a bedj'* The efforts to revive Herbert Hardy failed
for he died sometime between April 3 and July 2, 1811. It was on
this last date that the court reimbursed Dr. William Ward ^8 for
a coffin he provided for the "late Herbert Hardy dec'd."'''^ This same
day, the court ordered the sheriff of the county to take possession
of the bed and other effects of Herbert Hardy and sell them at six
months credit, making a return of the sale at the next court session.
It appears that Herbert Hardy must have been in a destitute state, for
when the sheriff made a return of the sale of his personal belongings
on October 10, 1811, it only amounted to fourteen dollars and thirteen
cents. '^^ On October 7, James Havins was allowed by the court ^25
no
for caring for Herbert Hardy while he was ill in Jefferson.
Dr. Ward must have had James Havins care for Herbert Hardy, while he
gave the necessary medical treatment. The next day, James Gray was
79
granted ;tti12 by the court for his amount against Herbert Hardy.
During April of 1811, the court ordered that the courthouse
in Jefferson be repaired and that a courthouse tax be laid on all
taxable property in the county, being equal to one half of the state
tax.^^ It appears the courthouse had fallen into an extreme state of
disrepair. Within the court order, it was specified, " to paint the
window frames, doors and cornice with some cheap paint, to repair
35
the doors, ceiling, justices seat and bar, to erect a clerk's table,
plaster the inside of the house, fill the windows with sound glass
and mend any sash that is broken." So here we have a picture of the
courthouse in 1811 with broken doors, peeling paint on the trim, an
unplastered interior with exposed brick and broken windows around the
house.
THE REMOVAL OF THE SEAT OF JUSTICE
On October 17, 1811, the General Assembly passed an act
entitled, "An act to establish the permanent seat of justice in the
county of Rutherford."&#174; The passing of this act represents the
culmination of a growing dissatisfaction with Jefferson as the county
seat by a portion of the citizens over the last few years. Within the
above act, the reasons for moving the seat of justice away from
Jefferson were as follows: that the town of Jefferson was not near
the center of the county; that the town was laid out and lots sold
before the county was established; that the greatest part of the
citizens were put at a great disadvantage and inconvenience in
attending courts and elections in Jefferson ( we have already seen
separate polling places designated in the county for elections over
the past several years)
.
The courts meeting in Jefferson had a tremendous impact
on the growth and prosperity of the town. 'i/^/hen the courts were in
session, the town must have bustled with activity. Business, because
of this, would be attracted to the county seat. As it was the
judicial and legal center for the county, it was also the business
and trade center for the county.
36
Another setback hit the town of Jefferson, for tradition
holds that the waters of the Stones River "began to diminish periodically
and the boats coming up the river, bringing trade and commerce to
Jefferson, could no longer navigate the river year round.
With the passage of this act, the fate of Jefferson was
sealed. The town that once looked to be the thriving, prosperous
commercial and judicial center for the county now faced an uncertain
future with the courts moving away and the river traffic it depended
on diminishing.
There was quite a bit of controversy and commotion in the
county at this time concerning moving the seat of justice from
Jefferson to another place. The people with lots and business
interests in Jefferson and others living in the vicinity stood to
lose much through the court's moving, while other citizens of the
county stood to benefit by the convenience and economic benefits with
the relocation of the seat of justice. There was widespread reaction
throughout the county over this matter.
The citizens of the town of Jefferson sent a petition,
sometime in 1812, to the General Assembly asking for indemnity if
82
the county seat was moved. In the petition, it is stated that
"many men made large expenditures for improvements in Jefferson which
have been reduced to almost nothing." The land values in Jefferson
would surely have dropped rapidly with the courts moving away. There
was to be a tremendous impact on the town with the courts gone,
causing taverns and other businesses to close their doors. This
petition was signed by 17 individuals including Joel Dyer, John
Griffin ( the former sheriff ), Thomas Mitchell, John Spence and
Thomas Sappington,
37
Another petition was sent to the General Assembly, in
1812, from the citizens of the county asking that the county seat
be chosen by referendum.&#174;'^ The petitioners state that a few men in
the county ( presumably the commissioners named by the General
Assembly to find a permanent seat of justice ) have kept the county
in perpetual confusion concerning the seat of justice. They further
state that there are some who want Lytle's and Murphey's (sic) spring,
while others represent the negative aspects of this site and yet others
who are disinterested in any particular place. The 59 citizens that
signed this petition called for a general vote on the matter, this
being the only way to do justice to the citizens of Rutherford County.
Even though a new courthouse, jail and stocks were slated
to be built at the new site of the seat of justice, on April 8, 1812,
the court ordered that the sheriff of the county to put the jail, in
Jefferson, in repair. The cost of this was not to exceed S-l^. The
court order specified that all of the repairs were to be done on the
"lower room and the same to be used as a debtors room." This last
phrase leads us to believe that the log jail must have been a two
story structure ( the log section of the Lenoir house was two storys -
could this have been used as a jail after the new courthouse was
built? ). The jail must surely have been in an extreme state of disrepair
for the county to appropriate funds for fixing the jail, when by an
act of the General Assembly, a new jail was to be built in the near
future. On this same day, a Matthew McClanahan was allowed $1.50 by
the court for repairs already done on the jail.
As there was continued commotion and controversy over the
seat of justice in Rutherford County, two of the commissioners who
selected Jefferson as the county seat, Mark Mitchell and Peter Legrand,
sent a letter to the General Assembly explaining why they had chosen
3S
Jefferson. They sent this letter because of the "frequent mis-representations
(that) have been made relative to the conduct of
the five commissioners." In their letter, Mitchell and Legrand
state that the principal part of the population was in the north
and northwestern parts of the county when the commissioners chose
Jefferson and that the part of the county that was beyond the old
Indian line was not part of the county at that time and could not
have been taken into account in centering the county. Mitchell and
Legrand went on to state that the forks of the Stones River ( at the
time Jefferson was selected as the county seat of justice ) was
seven miles from the center of the county and when the benefits to
the town by the navigation of the river were considered with the good
springs and "elegance of situation" that more of a general satisfaction
would have been felt by the citizens of the county toward this site.
The commissioners also felt that many "merchant and saw mills" would
be built on the many streams in close proximity to Jefferson "sufficient
to supply the largest town not only with flour and meal, but with
building materials at any season of the year." Mitchell and Legrand
refer to the fact, in supporting this, that W. Crosthwait was then
erecting "extensive merchant mills" within one half mile of Jefferson.
They referred to Stones River as still being navigable, with large
boats descending the river once a year and smaller craft being able
to make the trip three fourths of the year. The letter was closed
with, "these were our principle reasons and we fondly hope that they
will satisfy an impartial publick (sic)", signed Mark Mitchell and
Peter Legrand.
It appears that on October 8, 1812, there was a sharp
39
confrontation, in court, between those in favor of moving the court
and those wishing it to remain in Jefferson. At the adjournment on
October 8, with 14 justices present, it was ordered that the court
meet the following day at 10 o'clock in Murfreesborough. &#176;' William
Searcy, Theophilus Cannon, John Hill, Glover Banton, James L. Armstrong
and William Edwards, who all were justices, then appeared before the
bench and commanded the sheriff to adjourn the court to meet at
Jefferson the next day at 9 o'clock. This was done, for the court
entry for the next day has the court meeting in Jefferson.
Following this incident, a petition was sent to the General
Assembly, dated October 10, 1812, calling for the removal from office
those ju,;tices who conducted the "illegal" adjournment to Murfreesborough."
The petition was signed by sixty five citizens of Rutherford County.
It appears in this petition, that on the day following the confrontation
in court, those justices who called for the adjournment to Murfreesborough,
went to the house of William Lytle, in Murfreesborough, and held court
there while court wae being held in Jeff er son- by the sheriff's order
of the previous day. The petitioners state that there were only
fourteen of the fifty one justices of the county present on October 8
when they called for the adjournment to Murfreesborough and therefore
they did not constitute a majority. The petition goes on to state,
"the said fourteen gentlemen were repeatedly admonished and advised
by the gentlemen, learned in the law, who were then present as
practicing attornies of said court - and who were ernestly and repeatedly
remonstrated against such an unwarrantable act ... they were well
advised of the illegality of such a proceeding." According to the
petition, a great many of the citizens were inconvenienced as the court
kO
docket was full and many had traveled considerable distances to
attend court, only to have it disrupted and the proceedings delayed.
For these reasons, the petitioners requested that those justices
who composed the court at the illegal adjournment be removed from
office "by impeachment or otherwise." Petitioners included John
Nash Read, William Dyer, Constant Hardeman, John Coffee, James Espey
and Thomas Bedford (the son of Tho. Bedford dec'd).
On June 5, 1813 with twenty seven justices present at court,
which was being held for the last time in Jefferson, a majority of
acting justices was determined and the court was adjourned, to meet
the following day at Murfreesborough, "agreeable to the act of the
General Assembly. "
^
With the courts moving, went the dreams and aspirations for
the town of Jefferson to be a prosperous, active center for the county.
As fewer people were coming into town since the court was moved,
many of the taverns and other businesses closed their doors. Over
the years, Jefferson became another quiet country community with farms
dotting the land that once held the first county seat of justice for
Rutherford County.
EPILOG:
THE DEATH OF JEFFERSON
Authorized by the Flood Control Act of 1938, construction
of the Percy Priest Dam, on Stones River, was begun in 1963. The
impounded waters were expected to cover most of the site of the town,
perhaps only leaving a small island. During 1966-7, the town was
a
destroyed with all of the buildings either dismantled or moved to
different locations. The waters of Percy Priest lake never fully
covered the site of Jefferson and it is still possible today to
walk over the small knoll that once held the first seat of justice
for the county.
42
NOTES
%orth Carolina land grant #5390 to Robert Weakley and Thomas
Bedford. Land Grants, North Carolina, Roll 22, Book 11, p. 190.
Tennessee State Library and Archives, Nashville, Tenn. (hereafter cited
as TSLA)
^Tradition holds that the town was laid out with 150 lots, but
evidence cited later suggests that the town was laid out with 102
lots and the remaining lots were surveyed and laid off by the
commissioners of Jefferson after the town was chosen as the county
seat.
Rutherford County, Tenn., Register's Office (hereafter cited as
RC Reg.), Deed Book A, p. 17 and Deed Book E, p. 396
'^"Petitions to the General Assembly from the citizens of Davidson
and Williamson Counties to form a new county", Legislative Petitions,
65-1803, TSLA.
^Ibid.
^"Petition to create a new county from the citizens on or near the
Big Harpeth River", December 8, 1802, Legislative Petitions, 32-1-1803,
TSLA.
'''"Petition to the General Assembly from the citizens of Davidson
County not to have a new county laid off", 1803, Legislative Papers,
46-1-1803, TSLA.
^Acts of Tennessee 1803 , (Knoxville, Tenn.), p. 119
^Ibid., p. 130
^^R.C. Reg., Deed Book A, p. 25
^""ibid., p. 10
''^Rutherford County, Tenn., County Clerk's Office (hereafter cited
as R.C. Ct. Clk.), County Court Minute Book (hereafter cited as
C.C.M.B.) - B, p.131 .
"&#8226;^R.C. Ct. Clk., C.C.M.B. -A, p. 8.
^"^Ibid., p. 18.
^^Ibid., p. 29.
1 fiInterview with Mr. Lee Victory, Smyrna, Tenn., 10/15/80.
43
'''^
Acts of Tennessee 1804 , (Knoxville, Tenn.), p. 87.
''%.C. Ct. Clk., C.C.M.B.-A, p. 26.
"^Ibid., p. 36.
2&#176;Ibid., p. 53.
^''ibid., p. 54.
^^Ibid., p. 44, 57, 75, 123.
23
All biographical material on Robert Weakley is from "The Southern
Virginia Weakley Families and their Descendents" by Samuel Anderson
Weakley unless otherwise noted.
All biographical material on Thomas Bedford is from a paper by
Redmond S. Cole and a paper by Hugh Bedford, geneological vertical
files, TSLA , unless otherwise noted.
^^R.C, Ct. Clk., C.C.M.B.-A, p. 33.
2^Ibid., p. 39.
^'^Ibid., p. 51.
^^Ibid., p. 73.
^^R.C, Reg., Deed Book E, p. 400
^&#176;R.C., Ct. Clk., County Court Records Indexed, 1804-1814, p. 23.
^''r.C, Ct. Clk., C.C.M.B.-A, p. 80.
32 Ibid., p. 59. The Norton Gum ordinary was probably in the town
of Jefferson since Gum was appointed to oversee its roads. An overseer
for the roads was appointed to those that they lived on or were in
close proximity to.
^^Ibid.,p.89.
-^^Mill file, Walter R. Hoover Collection, Thurman Francis Junior
High School, Smyrna, Tenn.
^^R.C, Reg., Deed Book B, p. 189 and p. 191, Deed Book E, p. 400.
kk
^^R.C, Ct. Clk., C.C.M.B.-A, p. 80.
5'^Ibid., p. 126.
5^Ibid., p. 62.
5^Ibid., p. 93.
^&#176;Ibid., p. 202.
^hbid., p. 227.
"^^Ibid., p. 229.
43'R.C., Reg., Deed Book H, p. 241.
^"^Population Schedules of the Third Census of the U.S., 1810,
Rutherford County, National Archives Microfilm Publication, Microcopy
252, roll 63.
^^R.C, Reg., Deed Book F, p. 189.
'^^"Report of improvements on lots in Jefferson - Report of lots
sold by commissioners in Jefferson", Legislative Papers, Rutherford
County, 27-1-1813, TSLA.
'^\.C.,Ct. Clk., C.C.M.B.-A, p. 142.
4^Ibid., p. 166
^^The Thomas Mitchell house was in Jefferson at this time, as a
court entry in C.C.M.B.-B, p. 128, makes reference to the "house of
Thomas Mitchell in Jefferson.
"
^^Interview with Mr. Everett Waller, Smyrna, Tenn. , 10/21/80.
^^R.C, Ct. Clk., C.C.M.B.-A, p. 14.
^^Ibid., p. 144.
^^Ibid., p. 145, 155
^^Ibid., p. 195.
45
^^Ibid., p. 184.
^Interview with Mr. Lee Victory, Smyrna, Term., 10/15/80.
^'^R.C, Reg., Deed Book E, p. 391.
^^R.C, Ct. Clk., C.C.M.B.-B, p. 78.
^^Ibid., p. 103.
^&#176;Ibid., p. 114.
^hbid., p. 81.
^^Acts of Tennessee 1807 , (Knoxville, Tenn.), p. 130.
^Ibid., p. 154, "An act to establish a separate election in the
County of Rutherford.
"
64 R.C.,Ct. Clk., C.C.M.B.-B, p. 126.
^^Ibid., p. 179.
66
^Ibid., p. 130
'R.C., Ct. Clk., C.C.M.B.-C, p. 162.
67-
Population Schedules for the Third Census of the U.S, , 1810,
Rutherford County, National Archives Microfilm Publication,
Washington D.G., Microcopy 252, roll 63.
^%.C., Ct. Clk., C.C.M.B.-C, p. 221.
"^^Ibid., p. 220.
'^'' Ibid., p. 205.
'^^R.C, Ct. Clk., C.C.M.B.-E, p. 51.
'^^Ibid., p. 67.
'^^Ibid., p. 89.
'^^Ibid., p. 152.
46
'^^Ibid., p. 153.
'^'^Ibid., p. 217
^^Ibid., p. 172.
'^^Ibid., p. 184.
^&#176;Ibid., p. 54.
ft 1 Acts of Tennessee 1811 , (Knoxville, Tenn.), p. 38.
ft? "An appeal for indemnity to the General Assembly from the citizens
of the town of Jefferson", Legislative Papers, 40-1-1812, TSLA.
-^^,'Petition to the General Assembly that the county seat be chosen
by referendum". Legislative Papers, 47-1-1812, TSLA.
^"^R.C, Ct. Clk., C.C.M.B.-F, p. 15.
"Peter Legrand and Mark Mitchell to the General Assembly",
Manuscripts, THS I-D-1, box 1, ac. 305, TSLA.
^'^R.C, Ct. Clk., C.C.M.B.-F, p. 192.
"Petition to remove certain justices from office". Legislative
Papers, Rutherford County, 50-1-1812, TSLA.
^%.C., Ct. Clk., C.C.M.B.-F, p. 205.
</dc:description>
<dc:description>A ten-year history of the small town of Jefferson, TN, in Rutherford County</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.) -- History</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Jefferson</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>95 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-15; mt2011-02-17</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication17ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/49</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>