<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Charles Dement, Tennessee pioneer</dc:title>
<dc:creator>DeMent, Samuel H.</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 34</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1994</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>18th century; 19th century;</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>-i-;.;\H
Figure 1
Abner Demerit's Homeplace
circa 1817
53
CHARLES DEMENT
"Our Tennessee Pioneer"
by Samuel H. DeMent, M.D.
Charles Dement appears to be the first man of the
aforementioned surname to enter the frontier lands of North
Carolina beyond the mountains. The first record of his presence
in these parts was in January 1792 in Sumner County, when he
acquired 320 acres from James Wilson. ^
History records that Charles Dement left Bertie County, North
Carolina in November 1790 at which time he sold his acreage to
Henry Clay Milburn. ^ The land was located on Wanton Swamp on the
Cashie River and numbered 2 00 acres. He was living on the land at
the time of sale. ^
Charles Dement was an active juror in Bertie County, North
Carolina from the period of November 1774 until 1779. He was not
mentioned again in Bertie County until spring of 1783. Charles
was probably the son of John Dement who first acquired a British
Land Grant in November 1744. The Council at New Bern records his
^North Carolina Land Grants I, p 379. Sumner County Archives
^Bertie County North Carolina Court Minutes, Book P, p 114,
Bertie Co., North Carolina.
^Bertie County North Carolina Court Minutes, Book P, p 239,
Bertie Co., North Carolina.
54
petition for 250 acres in Edgecombe County, North Carolina. * He
is recorded in the Edgecombe County, North Carolina court minutes
(Halifax County) and sold the acreage in 1751 to John Hardy. ^ The
actual deed recorded the original land patent date as March 18,
1744. A witness to the land exchange was William Dement. In 1751
(September 6, 1;'51) John Dement acquired 400 acres from Daniel
Highsmith on Cashie Swamp (Wanton Swamp) in the area now in the
vicinity of Lewiston. ^ Two hundred acres of this land lying on
the Northeast side of Cashie Swamp was sold to William Edwards on
July 26, 1756.^
The William Dement mentioned previously also relocated to
Bertie County, North Carolina where his name is recorded in 1769
and 1778 (August 28, 1778) at which time he purchased land from the
estate of the late Benjamin Rogers. &#174; A William Dement served in
the American Revolution and his North Carolina pension land grant
^Colonial Records of North Carolina, Vol. IV B, pp 708, 9, 11,
1744.
Halifax Co., North Carolina Real Estate Conveyences, Vol. IV,
p 165, Halifax Co., North Carolina.
^Bertie County, North Carolina Court Minutes, Book G, p 415.
Bertie County, North Carolina.
^Bertie County, North Carolina Court Minutes, Book H. , p 417.
Bertie County, North Carolina.
&#176;Gamon D. Records of Estates of Bertie County, North Carolina.
Raleigh: D Gamon Publis. Vol. I 1728-1744, 1762-1790, p 79, 1986.
55
was assigned to Archibald Lytle. ^
Charles Dement and his brother John Dement, Jr. acquired a 200
acre land grant in Brunswick County, North Carolina (Oxpen branch
of the Little Shallote River) in 1771. '&#176; Both were listed in 1772
Brunswick County tax records. In 1773 the 200 acres were sold in
two 100 acre tracts to William Cause. ^^ On November 14, 1774,
Charles Dement was deeded the remaining 250 acres that his father
John Dement owned on Wanton Swamp. '^ Charles Dement signed an
Oath of Allegiance to the independent government in either 1774 or
1777. ^^ He apprenticed Mary Barfield in spinning and weaving in
1777. ^* In 1779 Charles Dement registered his cattle mark (crop
and nick under right ear; half moon over left) .
'^ He was a member
^orth Carolina Land Grant in Tennessee 1778-1791, p 184,
Grant #1377.
%orth Carolina Land Grant #139, Nov. 1771. NC St Archives.
^^ Brunswick County, North Carolina Court Records, Book B, pps.
94-96, 1773.
^^Bertie County, North Carolina Court Minutes, Book M, p 242.
Bertie County, North Carolina.
^^Bertie County, North Carolina, Revolutionary War Papers,
1774, 1777. North Carolina State Archives.
^*Haun WP. Bertie County Court Minutes 1772-1780. Durham:
WP Haun, Publis. Book IV, p 259, 1976.
"ibid p 302.
56
of the North Carolina Militia from Bertie County. ^&#174; In 1780, 18
Militiamen and 112 draftees from Bertie County refused to march to
Hillsborough, North Carolina until they had received bounty, since
they were not supplied weapons. ^^ The Militia rendevoused with
General Jethro Sumner's North Carolina Continentals in 1780. These
patriots fought on the front line in several skirmishes and battles
in the Southern campaign in 1781. '&#176; Charles Dement was noted in
Bertie County Court Minutes again in February 1783 as a juror and
again in 1785 as guardian of Sarah Thomas. ^^ He was mentioned in
1780 as the husband of Selah Thomas in her father's last Will and
Testament. ^ Charles Dement is not mentioned in Bertie County
after October 18, 1790. He may have inherited land from John
Dement (father or brother) in Burke County, North Carolina. ^'
^^Gandrud PJ, McLane BJ. Alabama Soldiers (Rev, War of 1812,
&amp; Indian Wars) Hot Springs: Arkansas Ances. Vol VI pp 66-67, 1979.
^^Rankin H. The North Carolina Continentals. Chapel Hill: North
Carolina Press, p 239, 1971.
^&#176;ibid, pp 247-51.
^^aun WP. Bertie County, North Carolina County Court Minutes
1781-1787. Durham: WP Haun, Publis. Book V, p 136, 1982.
^Bertie County, North Carolina Court Minutes 1780, p 158,
Bertie County, North Carolina.
^^Huggins EW. Burke County, North Carolina Land Records 1779-
1780 and Miscellaneous Records 1777-1780, Vol. II. Estate papers
1777-1795. Easley: So Hist Press, p 164, 1987.
51
Charles was mentioned in tax records as owning 326 acres in Captain
Adam's Company in 1790. ^ He sold several parcels over the ensuing
years (presumably as an absentee landowner). On June 18, 1793, 120
acres was deeded from Charles Dement to a son David Dement. ^
David Dement deeded the 120 acres to Mary Dement (widow of John)
in 1797. ^* Mary later sold the land in 1800.
On January 11, 1792, Charles Dement acquired 320 acres from
James Wilson in Sumner County, North Carolina. He sold this land
in 1815 to James Douglass. ^ On May 27, 1795, Charles Dement and
William Standley of Sumner County acquired 1000 acres along the
East Side of the Main Fork of the Stones River in Davidson County,
North Carolina. The land was acquired from Noah (Aquilla) Sugg,
a planter and minister. ^,^, Charles Dement later received the
entire 1000 acres through the court from William Standley. Charles
Dement was active in the Sumner County Court records from 1792
^ibid. Tax Records 1782-1793, p 128.
Muggins EW. Burke County, North Carolina Records 1775-1821,
Easley: So Hist Press. #191, 1987.
^'*ibid, #534.
^Sumner County Deed Book, Vol. VII, p 396 Sumner County
Archives.
^orth Carolina Land Grants 1, p. 13 5, Tennessee State Arch.
^^Carr J. Early Times in Middle Tennessee. Nashville: Stevenson
and Owen, p 103, 1857.
until July 1803. He was recorded as a Justice of the Peace in
1800. ^ Sumner County court records are missing from 1804 until
1810. Charles Dement received a Rutherford County Land Grant
(#4550) in the 1st District for 680 acres on November 5, 1812 from
assignee William Lytle. ^ The land was situated on the East Side
of the Stones River near Jefferson. In 1809 and 1814 he received
2 quarter sections of section #26 in the Mississippi Territory,
Madison County (NW 1/4 and SW 1/4) and was a taxpayer in Madison
County Alabama in 1815. He resided on the Madison County property
at the time of his death in 1820. His son John Dement confirmed
his burial site at Beaver Dam in his 1848 will. ^'
Charles Dement 's impact on Middle Tennessee is best reflected
by his descendants. Two of his sons, Abner and Cader, were among
the first residents in Rutherford County. In fact, they signed a
historic petition which established Rutherford County from its
parent counties, Davidson and Williamson. ^ The petition was dated
^Charles Dement, Secretary of State Revolutionary War Papers,
North Carolina State Archives.
^Rutherford County TN Deed Book, Book L, p 54.
"Madison County, Alabama Public Library, Surname: Charles
Dement -Government Entries, Madison County, Alabama.
^^Madison County, Alabama Probate Records, Book 14, pps. 181-
2. Huntsville, Alabama.
^McBride R. "An 1803 Census of Rutherford County." Ruth. Co.
Hist. Soc. No 3, pp 52-56, 1974.
59
August 10, 1803 and Rutherford County was organized on January 3,
1804. They probably lived on the 1000 acre plantation on the Main
Fork of the Stones River, in the Smyrna/Old Jefferson area today.
Cader Dement was a large landowner and plantar who was given power
of attorney by his father Charles on December 26, 1816. The land
involved was the aforementioned 1000 acres plus the 680 acres on
the East Fork of the Stones River. ^ Cader left many descendants
in Middle Tennessee and served in the War of 1812. ^ Abner Dement
acquired 3 land tracts totaling 816 acres from John Donaldson in
1817 in the Lascassas area of Rutherford County. ^ The original
private residence stands on the Cainsville Pike and is registered
as a National Historic Site (Figure 1) . ^ Abner was killed by a
slave, intestate, in 1825. ^^ His minor heirs were William, John
&amp; David, who were reared by Elizabeth Dement, Abner 's widow. ^
Rutherford County Court Minutes, Vol. K, p 4 62.
^oore JT (Ms) . Records of Commisioned Officers in the
Tennessee Militia. 1796-1815. Baltimore: Geneal Publ. Co. p 235,
1977.
^Jernigan MP. "Rutherford County, A Long Look Back." The Daily
News Journal, July 2, 1972.
'^est M. "Dement House to Enter National Historic List". The
Daily News Journal. August 2, 1986.
'^Minutes of the County Court of Rutherford County, Book T,
1824-5, p 189.
^ibid, p 358.
60
John, when of age, remained on the residence. His brother David
DeMent settled nearby along Bradley's Creek. David died in 1907
having fathered 12 children by 2 wives. ^ He is buried behind his
home, which still stands on Bradley's Creek Road. His great
grandson, David Barton DeMent, Jr., was a prominent attorney in
Murfreesboro. He also served in the State House of Representatives
and Senate for 10 years with distinction. A World War II veteran
he died at the age of 52. On January 26, 1965, a Senate Joint
Resolution was adopted and later approved which recognized his
numerous contributions (Figure 2) . ^
Yes, Charles Dement was a true Middle Tennessee pioneer and
patriot, who immigrated to this area by covered wagon and flat boat
from North Carolina several years before Tennessee statehood. Two
of his seven sons were directly involved in the establishment of
Rutherford County in 1804. Many of Charles' descendants remain
in Rutherford County, and along with others who did relocate,
continue to shape Middle Tennessee and the nation as educators,
homemakers, law enforcers, physicians, ministers, agrarians, public
servants, and etc.
39DeMent SH. "Dement Family Bible Records." Bits of Dements
Vol. 10 (1) pp 18-20, 1992.
Joint Senate Resolution #6, Acts of Tennessee, 1965.
Bmutt 3fnmt BJfsnluttnn No. fi
-By-
Atkini OutfhfieM Holbrook Pittea Ttylor
Biird DuggCT KeUey Pipkin Teny
Berry Flippiu Maddux Rty Todd
Cuter Carlud Mithii Soodgrass Tuner
OuBolm ConeU Motlow Siegill WiUcer
Oiwford Guffey Nave Stewiit
Ooucb HarviU 03riea TalitfoTO
61
A Senate Resolution to the Memory of
THE HONORABLE BARTON DEMENT
of Muxfrecsboro
Whereas, On June 17, 1963, there passed away lud-denly
a veteran of many legislative battles, a man loved
sd respected by all legislators who knew him and worked
with him during his six legislative terms, the Honorable
Barton Dement of Murfreesboio; and
Whereas, Senator Dement was often addressed in a
piiit of triendliness and fun as "The Great Man". This
fond appellation, however, was more 6lting than not
because of his outstanding service to his community, his
Mate, and his nation; to his fellow citizens, he was truly
a great man, a jealous guardian of the rights of individuals,
of our constitutional system of checks and balances, the
aanctity of the ballot box and our jury tystem; and
Whereas, On the floor of the House or Senate, Senator
Dement was a formidable opponent and an effective ally,
sensitive to the merits of an issue, quick to spot phony
arguments or false premises, with an unerring ability to
go straight to the heart of a matter, cementing his posidon
or demolishing an opponent's view with a few deft, probing
questions; and
Whereas, Senator Dement served the people of Ten-nessee
with enthusiasm and ability in six consecutive
lepslatures, beginning in I9S3 and ending in 1963, fint as
&#8226; direct Representadve from Rutherford County in 1953,
195S and 19S7, and then as a Senator representing the
13th Senatorial District in 19S9, 1961 and 1963, and was
an outstanding member of the legislative Council Com-mittee
in 1957 and 1959; and
Whereas, He also served well the people of his home
town of MurfrcciboTO, not only u a member of the Qty
Council from 1952 until the time of his death, but also u
charitable citizen, who made no public display of his
ADOPTED&#8226; y^V&#187;*&lt;-*Ay '^^^ /7^S'
APPROVED: Vic&#171;&#171;&#171;&#171;&gt;&#171;/i^- J^J/JCS-good
works, preferring instead to perform his charity
quietly, privately, without fanfare or recognition; and
Whereas, Senator Dement served his country in
World War U; and, at the time of his death, was a member
of the American Legion; Disabled American Veterans; the
Chamber of Commerce; the American, Tennessee, and
Murlreesboro Bar Associations; Stones River Country
Gub; the Church of Christ; and was a Shriner, a Moose,
a York Rile and Scottish Rite Mason, and a trustee of
the Sam Davis Home in Smyrna, Tennessee; and
Whereas, Senator Dement't passing will take away a
little something from all of us, for from him by his example,
we gained some of his strength, his vigor, his enthusiasm
for taking on the many vexing problems confronting the
legislative branch of government and through the legislative
process, coming to workable solutions;
Haw, Thereiore, Be it retolved by the Seruae oj the
Eighzy-FourUx General Assembly of the State of Tennessee,
The House of Representatives Concurring, That we by this
Resolution express the sorrow that is ours at the loss of
our dear friend and colleague. Senator Barton Dement, an
outstanding public servant, a fine lawyer, a loyal Ten-oessean,
and a patriotic American&#8212;truly The Great .
Man". We will miu him.
Be It further resolved. That a copy of this Resolution
be sent to Senator Dement's wife, Mrs. Marie Dement,
1603 Jones Boulevard, Murfreesboro, along with the
prayers and best wishes of the members of the Eighty-fourth
General Assembly for Mrs. Dement and her (our
fine children&#8212;Andrew Jackson Dement, Sam Houston
Dement, Debra Diane Dement, and Patrida Aiuette
Dement
Fiqure 2
</dc:description>
<dc:description>Describes the life of Charles Dement, early Rutherford County area settler, primarily using land grants and court records. Dement's sons went on to be prominent founders of the county, signing a petition to make Rutherford County distinct from Davidson and Williamson.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.); Land grants--Tennessee--Rutherford County</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>10 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-01-26; mt2011-02-02</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication34ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/18</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>