<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Kirks and Montgomerys</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Kirk, Alexander Montgomery</dc:creator>
<dc:contributor>Woods, Jane Snell</dc:contributor>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 14</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1903</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>19th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>33
"KIRKS and MCWTGOMERYS"
from-
The Home Journal
Murfreesboro, Tennessee
September 22, 1903
Furnished by: Jane Snell Woods
The following was written by Alexander Montgomery Kirk, of
Oxford, Florida, who intended to deliver it as a speech at
a reunion of the Kirk Family held in the past July 1903.
But on account of unfortunate circumstances the reunion was
not held. Mr. Kirk is a native of Rutherford County, and is
now 81 years of age. His article is full of interesting
events and will be read with interest,
* * * *
Fellow Citizens, Ladies and Gentlemen:
This is one of the greatest pleasures of my life, to be
at my old homestead, where I was born over 4 score years ago,
where I spent my youthful days, and where I now have an oppor-tunity
of mingling with my fellow Tennesseans, I am glad to
be in the land of my Nativity. I am glad to be near the roof
under which I saw the light. I am also glad to be near the
trees I was nursed and reared under. But there is a sadness
hovering over me that I cannot very well get rid of. I find
that the people I left here 57 years ago - 1846 - are not here
today; that they have passed away, and await the morning of
the resurrection. And others have risen up in their stead.
Such, my friends, is life, and such is the way of the human
family.
The object of this meeting is for the purpose of a reunion
of the Hugh Kirk Family.
The family was a large one, eleven children born to my
parents, three of whom died in infancy, eight lived to be grown.
34
Seven married and had families, and one-my youngest brother -
never married, was killed at the Battle of Franklin during the
Civil War. There are only two of that large family left, Mrs.
Snell (Melissa Kirk) , my youngest sister, and myself.
Mrs. Snell was the wife of James Curtis Snell, who was a
member of the Mitchell Company. He was 2nd Lieutenant of the
Company and died at Winchester during the Civil War.
Now, my friends, I am standing where I stood in 1845, 57
years ago and bade my parents, brothers and sisters farewell,
and left for the state of Mississippi. And now after the lapse
of this time I am back on the same portico. M^^ parents have
passed away, and my brothers and sisters all except the youngest
sister-Mrs. Snell-and the dewlling has passed away into other
hands. Those of Mr. Frank Overall, who has opened his doors
and grounds and unites with us in this reunion, for which we
tender him our many thanks. I find that the slaves who cultivated
the fields are all gone. I find that the citizens that lived on
Lytle Creek and Fox Camp Branch a distance of 10 miles and about
30 families in number have likewise all passed away, no one left
except my nephew Hugh Kirk, who lives on Lytle Creek. He is still
here and stands like a wall and all alone, no wife to control him,
no children to squall, and no one to morn his loss when he is gone.
So you see from the above time has wrought many changes in 57
years. My f riendsj I have been out on a long journey for 4 score
years - running from 1823-1903. Forty years of my journey have
been peacefully and pleasantly spent. My path has been smooth
and thornless with but few obstacles to impede it.
Prosperity attended me on every hand. But the next 40
35
years were rough and rugged, full of disasters, full of
calamities, full of affliction, my path was full of thorns,
with many obstacles difficult to overcome, besides many storms
to weather. I have been tossed to and fro many ways and many
directions. The hand of affliction fell upon me and I lay upon
my bed 9 long weeks, with a mortified foot, as helpless as a
child.
While the Battle of Stones River was being fought I was
carried out of my room by 2 men, placed in a vehicle in bed,
hauled 14 miles away, to where my family preceded me, which was
on Tuesday of the "big" fight. On Sunday news came that "Bragg
was retreating." I had my teams hitched up, consisting of 3
horses, 2 vehicles and 3 servants with 2 small children, one of
them an infant, my wife and myself.
My wife took charge, we steered our course in the direction
of our home in Mississippi, passing through Bragg' s retreating
army - arrived at home on the 11th February 1863. We had a rough
trip, it being in the dead of winter, sometimes raining, snowing,
sleeting or hailing with roads in a wretched condition, bridges
washed away and many other difficult obstacles to overcome. With
an infant child and a helpless husband, yet my wife was equal to
the emergency.
With heroic and courageous effort she took us safely home,
walking the 2 last days of our journey to relieve the worn out
animals. (She was a wife among wives and surpassed by none, ever
ready at any time to do whatever she could for her helpless and
afflicted husband both by night and by day. I found her near
Murfreesboro in 1855; where they know how to raise good wives.
36
and lost her in my home in Mississippi in 1870 ~ leaving an
infant child just 6 months old behind her.)
I remained at home until the "Fall of Vicksburg." I
then gathered up my personal effects. With my wife still in
charge we crossed the Mississippi River and went over into Texas.
We reached the Brazos River in 1863 and struck camp. While on
my journey from Stones River in Tennessee to the Brazos River
in Texas I consulted every doctor who crossed my path. Invari-ably
their answer was - "It ought to come off in order to save
your life."
While riding out on the Brazos River prospecting I met
an old gentleman riding a mule, and seeing me riding in bed
wished to know what my trouble was. I told him I had an infected
foot for which I had been in bed for 12 months. He said he would
like to see it. I asked if he were a doctor. He replied, "I
claim to be." I showed it to him and after examining it, I told
him I had had a number of doctors to examine it and they told me
it would have to come off to save my life and I would like to
hear what he had to say. He replied "I see no use of its coming
off, but can put you to walking in a few days", which was the best
news I had heard in all my journey; of course I did not believe a
word of it, but concluded as we were in camp here I would let him
try, so he began the treatment.
Now, my friends, I will tell you in all candor this man
who rode the mule had me walking on both feet in less than 6 weeks,
with a walking cane, attending to all my business generally. I
had been greatly reduced in flesh, but under this treatment I re-gained
it until I weighed 208 pounds. He relieved me of my
37
suffering, which was intense, so that my sleep was sound and my
slumber sweet, both by day and night. I had suffered untold
misery and was reported twice as dead - but am still living. I
had a pair of crutches while on my journey but having no further
use for them left them on the plains of Texas. I have had 2
financial wrecks and once was covered with boils, 70 in number,
almost as many, I suppose, as Job had. I had a 9 year seige of
sickness, with half dozen doctors to attend me (at different
times) but my troubles baffled them all, and was told they could
do me no good. So I was left at sea with no hope of recovery-a
physical wreck. The only alternative seeming to be - I should
take charge, and be my own doctor, so I did. And by divine help
I discovered a remedy. And I don't think it was more than a month
until my troubles were removed. My troubles were numerous, being
5 in number - bronchial, indigestion, rheumatism, kidney and
bowel trouble. I have had charge of my case nearly 7 years and
if I did not know I was over 4 score years I would feel quite
youthful yet. So you see, my friends, I have had a pretty rough
journey, and the wonder is that I am still living, but a greater
wonder is that I have anything to live on. But I have weathered
through 4 score years and I think I will be able to make the
balance of the trip.
I want to give you a short sketch of my war record.
I was in the army 12 months. Was in 2 days fight at the
Battle of Shiloh, was in the Court Martial at Vicksburg at the
time tide Battle of Baton Rouge was fought. I lay on my back 9
weeks near Murf reesboro , but while the Battle of Stones River
was being fought, I was carried out, placed in bed, hauled 14
38
miles, as stated above. I now want to say to my old comrades,
the most reluctant thing I ever did in my life was to send up my
application for a discharge. "Iliey had complimented me as a
Standard Bearer at Corinth, Mississippi, and I didn't want to
leave them, but my health would not permit. As was proven after-wards.
Now I will tell you something of my ancestors. My grand-father
Jetton was born in N. C. in 17 57, and I heard my mother
say he was of Irish descent. He married a Miss White, but I know
nothing of her nativity. There were 4 children born to them,
when he concluded to move to Middle Tennessee in about 1800 and
did so and bought lands on each side of the Manchester Pike (now
runs) 2 1/2 miles from Murf reesboro. He built a house on the right
hand side of the Pike, on a hill about 200 yards off the Pike.
There Robert Jetton, Jr., had a very handsome residence.
During the Civil War the Yankees came one night firing off their
pistols and frightening off the family, who escaped in their night
clothing. The Yankees pillaged the house and then burned it.
My grandfather Jetton opened an extensive farm, which he
cultivated for 30 years. On one occasion (?) my mother wanted
to visit her parents. She took me-a boy of 6 years with her for
company. When we arrived at my grandfather's, we found him sitting
in the yard under a shade tree in a large arm chair, with a
Revolutionary soldier's uniform on, short pants, long stockings,
and knee buckles - the first and last I ever saw.
My mother spoke to him and passed a few words, and then
she went on in the house to see her mother. I remained with him.
In order to amuse me, with his pocket knife he whittled me a
39
small wagon, making the wheels out of turnips and gave
it to me, which I hauled about over the yard - very proud of it.
Not long after that my grandmother died and was buried
in the old graveyard in Murfreesboro about the year 1830. That
left my grandfather all alone, his children all having married
and left him. There was a lady named Winsett that waited on my
grandmother during her illness. After a reasonable time my
grandfather addressed her and she agreed to share life with him.
They married very much against the wishes of the children, on
account of an ungovernable temper. Not long after this, his son
Isaac concluded to move to West Tennessee, and he concluded to
move with him at the age of 7 3 years, after having tilled 30
years on his fertile plantation. This move was supposed to have
been because of the opposition of his children to his marriage.
He bought a farm adjoining his son Isaac. After farming several
years, he became dissatisfied and moved back, leaving his second
wife behind him, which showed that all was not lovely between
them - caused by display of that ungovernable temper, which caused
the opposition to his union with her. He came back to his son
Robert's, and after he became rested he spent a week with each of
his children, of whom there were 2 sons and 5 daughters. He
commenced his rounds and when he got to my father's he asked if
anyone in the neighborhood could write his will. My father told
him a man by the name of Phillips, who sometimes did such work
and he sent for him. Mr. Phillips wrote his will and the sum of
$5 was left his second wife. The will was never contested.
He finished up his work and got back to his son Robert's
when he died. It looked very much like he had a presentiment
40
that his career was coming to a close. He was buried in the old
Murfreesboro graveyard in the 81st year of his age. He was a
Revolutionary soldier 7 years, further than that I know nothing
of his war record.
My grandfather Kirk was born in Scotland about 17 51. He
emigrated from that country to South Carolina about 1772 or 73.
He married a Miss Montgomery. But I know nothing of her birth-place
or ancestry. He farmed in South Carolina up to 1802 when
he concluded to move to Middle Tennessee, and did so buying lands
near my grandfather Jetton's, and farmed there from 1802-1821,
and died there and was buried in the Montgomery graveyard. When
I was up there in 1902 I asked my nephew to go with me in search
of his grave. When we got there we found it had been lost sight
of for a number of years, all grown up in trees, saplings and
bushes. We went in and found 5 vaults in a row. On one of them
I found Joseph Montgomery's name and date of his birth and death.
The next-his wife, the next his father James Montgomery. Joseph
was full cousin of my father's and James was a brother of my
grandmother Kirk.
(Continued in next issue of The Home Journal-September 25,1903)
About 10 steps away there was a headstone and a footstone
and on it was written John J. Kirk died 1821 and in the 70th
year of his age. So we accortplished what we went for and returned.
He was under Sumter during Revolutionary War. When
Teleton captured a large part of Sumter's Company, grandfather
was down on the Saluda River washing his clothes with several
others. They swam the river and made their escape. Further than
that I know nothing of his record.
41
Joseph Montgomery was born helpless in his limbs and when
old enough to go to school his father had a boy take him to and
back from school night and morning. Joseph was a bright boy and
learned very rapidly, by the time he was grown he had as good
an education as was given in those days and was said in after
years to have been one of the best informed and most intelligent
men in Rutherford County. His father made his will and left his
property to Joseph on account of his condition. Joseph took charge
of the property at his father's death. The same boy hauled him
over the plantation and he supervised and directed everything
and was said to have been a neat and successful farmer. Joseph
concluded he needed a companion, and I suppose he did much more
than the companion needed him. He found a Miss Rankin who
accepted him. They married and it is said they lived happily
together. Joseph was a churchgoer before and after his marriage.
The boy would drive him up to the window so he could see and hear
the preacher. She would get out and go into the church herself.
They would be driven back home by the boy.
In 2 years Joseph died and she fell heir to the property.
and with the assistance of the relatives she managed it very
successfully. In 2 years more she died, and the property all
went to her relatives. The 2 sisters did a great deal of talking,
but Mrs. Montgomery kept the property all the same. It was an
oversight in Joseph's father not making some provision for his 2
daughters. But who would have thought of Joseph's marrying?
But stranger things have happened. I always thought that Joseph
should have done something for the slave Stephen who waited on
him from childhood until 30 years of age. But if he ever gave him
anything I never heard of it.
42
My grandfather Kirk had a peculiar case in his family,
a son-in-law by the name of Keylov; became strangely affected.
He was like a mad man. It took 6 men to hold him in bed, and
the news spread far and near. He had a presentiment that he
wanted to go to the back of the field to get something he
wanted. So the nurses went with him and pulled out of a
hollow tree a ball. The ball was found to be composed of hair-pins,
needles and other articles. They returned to the house
and the crowd examined the ball. They threw it in the fire
and strange to say, Mr. Keylow began to improve, got well and
hearty. Then Granmother Kirk her daughter and snn- in-law moved
-&gt;
to West Tennessee. He went with them. In about --- my grand-father
and myself visited them in West Tennessee. We rode up
to his house just after dark.
We cried, "Hellol" He came out and my father asked, "Is
that Capt. Keylow?" He answered, "It is Major. How do you do?"
He knew him by his voice. Mr. Keylow was well and quite jovial,
and also next morning when we left. And we never heard of him
anymore.
My father was born in S. C. 1785 of Scoth-Irish ancestry.
He went with his father in 1802 to Middle Tennessee in the 17th
year of his age and then started out for himself. He bought
up a large drove of horses on credit, and had to drive them
through a wilderness to New Orleans, spending one night with the
Indians. He made several trips and when the Battle of New Orleans
occurred fought by Gen. Jackson January 8, 1815 near New Orleans.
I have heard him say he had been in that city when yellow fever
was raging and hearses were running all day and night hauling the
&lt;! V
Mr
43
dead bodies out of the city. He kept a bottle of whiskey with
assofallida (?) (asafetida ?), and always believed it prevented
his taking the disease. He returned home and bought a farm
from a man named Phillips, settled down to farming and married
and moved to the Phillips house 250 yards from his own house.
In 1817-18 the Creek War broke out and he raised a conpany
and enlisted under Jackson, in his campaign. After the war
he resumed farming.
In 1812 he built this dwelling on whose portico we now
stand, my friends, as well as I can calculate.
I was the first person born in this house February 22,
1823. My father continued farming and also ran a road wagon
from Nashville to different towns, hauling goods at a profit in
those days. In 1851 he died in the 66th year of his age, and
was buried in the graveyard in Murf reesboro.
I have always thought my mother unsurpassed among women.
She was a pious member of the Presbyterian Church, as was my father.
She was a very domestic woman, of untiring energy and devotion to
her family. I remember she had a shop, made lamp and often the
needle by its light till 10 o'clock at night. She had a real
factory consisting of a small flax wheel, 2 spinning wheels and
cards, a pair of winding blades, a spool frame and a pair of
winding blades and a pair or warping bows (?) and a loom. The
thread was converted into cloth for about 30 people on the place.
She would often barter bolts of cloth in Murfreesboro for such
things as she could not make at home. She was a kind and loving
mother, always giving good Christian advice. She died in 1859 in
the 62nd year of her age and was buried by my father's side.
44
Winding to the close of my remarks I wish to say that my
ancestors, my grandfather and my grandmother and their descendants
never had any one in jail or the penitentiary for any crime as
far as we have any account of them.
Postscript
Before closing, however, I wish to mention the short and
prosperous career of Col. Robert Jetton, who was a son of my
grandfather Jetton. He was quite an important character in and
around Murfreesboro, and would be called in these times and days
"a hustler". When grandfather Jetton concluded to move to West
Tennessee Col. Robert purchased his father's landed property, and
this in connection with his own made a magnificent plantation.
It was but a few years before he had this plantation stocked
with laborers and made abundant crops. He also owned landed
property in West Tennessee. He was Colonel in Gen. Jackson's
army during the Seminole and Creek Wars. He represented Ruther-ford
County one term in the legislature. He contracted and had
the brick made and built the first Courthouse that was ever built
in Murfreesboro. He contracted for the delivery of mails all over
middle portion of Tennessee and owned the stage line. He also
contracted and built a large portion of the Nashville and Murfrees-boro
turnpike. He was engaged for a number of years in the mercan-tile
business, also owned a tan yard and a blacksmith shop and 2
furnaces and did work for the surrounding county. He also owned
a gin and did all the ginning for the surrounding neighborhood.
He also kept a horse mill so when the water was too low he could
grind with it and attend it himself, although a wealthy man. I
remember being there on one occasion when a boy his hopper was
45
about 10 feet above the ground with elevated steps. He took
a bushel bag and carried it up the steps, and emptied it in
the hopper and when ground brought it down, put it on the horse
for me and started me home.
The largest reception I was ever at in my life was at
his house. His son, Robert married a niece of ex-President
and Mrs. Polk. Polk was governor of Tennessee at that time, and
he and Mrs. Polk were there on that occasion. And I think all
the carriages in and around Murfreesboro were there that night.
The first piano I ever heard in my life was there that
night, and I was greatly impressed with the music. None but the
most wealthy could afford pianos at that time. He died at 55
years in the very prime of his life, and was buried in Murfrees-boro
in the old grave yard.
My friends, we are all here for a short time and like the
bird will soon pass away and be forgotten. The preacher of
olden times said, "All is vanity and vexation of spirit and no
profit under the sun of all our labors." We struggle and we toil
to lay up treasures on this earth. We build our fine mansions
and furnish them most elegantly. We have every want supplied,
we lean back and promise ourselves long lives and happiness but
the dread disease of sickness comes upon us. And we are then
prostrate upon our beds. Medical aid is summoned but they fail
to give relief. And we linger along a few days and pass away.
A coffin or casket is provided for us, and we are carried out of
the mansion feet foremost, to some lonely spot, and a hole is dug
in the earth, and we are placed therein. The dirt is heaved
upon us. And others rise up in our stead and we sink to oblivion.
46
and perhaps strangers occupy the fine mansions we build.
Hugh and Alexander (Montgomery) are Montgomery family names.
There was the name Hugh however in some of the earlier Kirk
records.
Mary is an old Kirk name as is Eleanor. The family did keep
the Scottish Custom of keeping family names for hundreds of
years.
The KIRK cemetery was found in 1978 between Elam Road
and U. S. 41. The cemetery is 1/2 mile east and be-hind
the Seventh Day Advent ist church on Elam Road.
It is about 100 feet out in a pasture from a line fence.
John Kirk' s grave was found along with Alexander
Nisbett and his wife. The base stones and pieces of
other markers indicate other graves there.
RE: KIRK 47
Hugh Montgomery, Sr.
Son: Hugh Montgomery, Jr.
Dau: Mary Eleanor Montgomery
Wed-John Kirk Sr. 17 51 - 1821, Scotland &amp; Tennessee
I. Hugh Kirk - born 17 85 South Carolina
died 1850 in Tennessee
Wed: Jane Jetton born 17 86 South Carolina
died 1859 in Tennessee
A. Mary Kirk
Wed: Mr. Alfred Lowe - Mid Tennessee
1
.
Mary Lowe
Wed: P. A. Lyon
a. Alfred Lyon
b. Adeline Lyon
Wed: A. J. Brandon, Jr.
2. Melissa Lowe
Wed: A. J. Brandon, Sr.
a. A. J. Brandon, Jr.
3. Mattie Lowe
Wed: Mr. Pinkard , 1st
Ellen Pinkard
Wed: Dr. J. P. Lyon , 2nd
Melissa Lyon
Wed: Jim Nisbitt
a. Alene Ross Nisbitt *
b. Sara Lyon Nisbitt *
c. Helen Nisbitt *
B. Elizabeth Kirk
Wed: Mr. Tenpleton
a, Ellen Templeton
Wed: Mr. Walton
C. John J. Kirk 1820 - 1861
Wed: Nancy Parker
a. Mary Jane Kirk **
Wed: William Ossie Snell
b. Fannie Kirk
Wed: T. B, Osborn ***
c. Hugh Kirk never married
D. Alexander Montgomery Kirk
Wed: Sarah Brothers
a. Lizzy Kirk
b. William Kirk
c. Sally Kirk
d. Roberta White Kirk
e. Montgomery Kirk
All born in Washington County, Miss.
and moved to Florida
E. Franklin Kirk
Wed: ?
48
* Mrs. Ramsey Snell can supply information
** Refer to Jane Stone's "SNELL " book for our long line-
Ramsey Emmett Snell, 92 and Mary Kirk Snell Ransom, 88,
are still living 1979
*** Mrs. John Osborn, Murfreesboro can supply this line.
Hugh Kirk
Killed at Franklin, Tennessee
Never Married \
Melissa Kirk
Wed: James C. Snell (Curtis)
(Half brother to William Ossie
Snell&#8212;above)
a. Etna Snell
Wed: Jim Johnson
b. Florence Snell
Wed: Mr. Napier
c. James C. Snell, Jr
Wed: Dora Butler **</dc:description>
<dc:description>Originally written as a speech to be given at the Kirk/ Montgomery family reunion of 1903, this family history was printed in the Murfreesboro Home Journal later the same year</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Family history; Stones River, Battle of, Murfreesboro, Tenn., 1862-1863; Rutherford County (Tenn.) -- Newspapers</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>family reunions; Murfreesboro Home Journal</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>31 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-01</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication14ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/124</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>