<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>The artist at Stone's River</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Pittard, Homer</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 4</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1974</dc:date>
<dc:description>35
THE ARTIST AT STONE'S RIVER
Homer Pittard
There was a time when the United States Park Service ranked
the Stone-s River National Battlefield as a "B" grade facility.
This meant, of course, that the winter struggle two miles west
of the town limits was somewhat less than of prime importance in
the outcome of the Civil War. Thus, it was not a pivotal battle
in the assessment of the Park Service historians.
Yet, later judgments have placed Stone's River at the well-spring
of the Union strategy to sever the South in half. This
proved to be successful as the Blue legions moved relentlessly
from Murfreesboro to Chattanooga, to Atlanta, and then to Savannah.
This segmentation served to destroy or drastically impair the
movement of food supplies and ordnance from the deep South to
the armies in the East and to other fields of operations. At
this early period in the war, late 1=862, at Murfreesboro, the
first fatal step may have been taken in the total dissolution of
the Confederacy.
in many ways the battle of Stone's River was one of indecision
and blatant errors that was presided over by probably the two
most inept field commanders on both sides. General Braxton Bragg,
Confederate Army of Tennessee and Major General William Starke
Rosecrans, Union Army of the Cumberland. The battle opened on
December 31, 1862 with a magnificent strategy that would have
titillated the most erudite West Point professor (Bragg and
Rosecrans were both graduates of the Military Academy). As the
day progressed, the battle plan, particularly that developed by
Rosecrans, began to segment and crumble. When darkness came, an
36
elated Bragg dictated a telegraphic message to Richmond which
read, in part, "The field is ours. . . God has granted us a
happy New Year!" Indeed he had won the battle. Next day, the
New Year was relatively quiet with only occasional exploratory
firing and some repositioning of troops by both armies. To
complete his task. General Bragg, in the late afternoon of
January 2, sent Brickenridge ' s division against a Union division
deployed in a damaging position across the River. Regarded as
a foolhardy maneuver, the Confederate division charged headlong
into a concentration of masked batteries and was repulsed with
great losses. That night and the following day, Bragg sat pondering
in his tent. Had he won the battle? At another place on the
field, Rosecrans struggled in the same quandry. But it was left
to the Confederate general to break the deadlock. Grumblings
from his division commanders, his peculiar talent for indecision,
and his proclivity for overestimating his opponent, caused him
to order a general retreat of the army at midnight on January 3.
Thereby, Bragg inadvertently gave the first impetus to the long
road leading to Appomattox.
For some reason, the photographer with his wet plates and
springwagon was a scarce commodity at Stone's River. Only two
pictures related to the period are known to exist. One depicts
contraband (Negroes) working on the railroad near Murf reesboro
.
The other is a broadside of the courthouse probably taken in 1863
or 1864 with the photographer's tripod resting some one hundred
yards down East Main Street. It was therefore left to the field
artist and later lithographers to record the battle for posterity.
Artists known to have made some depictions of the struggle and
of related subjects were Alfred Mathews, Henry Lovie, Henry R. Huber,
and F. B. Schell. m most cases, rough sketches replete with
scrawled instructions were forwarded the publisher's home office
and there an artist would develop and complete the drawing. Many
of these appeared in the "Life" magazine of the day. Harper's
^^^^^y ^i^d Frank Leslies Illustrated Newspaper .
Some of the drawings appear on the following pages. Most of
these are from the files of avid collector Walter King Hoover
of Smyrna, Tennessee.
Key to Artists' Sketches on Following Three Pages:
1. Not identified: possibly Brig. Gen. Phillip Sheridan's second
&#163;&#176;^'"^^&#176;" between Wilkerson's Pike(Manson) and Franklin Road,
2.
December 31, 1862. Artist: Alfred Mathews
Stylized drawing depicting opening of battle on Franklin Road,
Artist Unknown.
10.
11.
43.. RDeetsreerattedofConCfoendfeerdaetreatecamaprmyaftaefrterbatbtaltet.le, FrJoamnuaHrayrpe4r, 's Weekly. 1863^ From Harper ' s Weekly .
5. Boarding the cars to Mur f reesboro War . From Soldi ers of the Civil . &#8212; i^^
6. Center of Army, January 2, 1863. Probably division of Br^'g Gen. James Scott Negley along Nashville Pike. Artist: Henrv R. Huber. ^
7. MSaoju.rceG:en WBiatltllieasm aRnodsecLreaandse'rs headquarters on Nashville Pike .
8. Disciples of Christ Church on East Main Street in Murf reesboro
.
LBsreiitaged.erosfGenM.ainJamSetsreeAtbraCmhurGcahrfioefldChrhiesltd. serSvouirccees: herBea.ttlePsresaendnt .
9. Maj. Gen. William Rosecrans' Headquarters in Murf reesboro
.
aKnedeblLeeadheorusse now site of Delbridge's Studios. Source: Battles .
MEulvrifereeMscbFoardodenin Sc1h8o6o3l.. SkSoeutrcchee:d fHraormpear point near present ' s Weekly . Hazen's Brigade Monument on Stone's River Battlefield is
regarded as the oldest monument to Civil War dead in the country.
Locale for a short story by Ambrose Bierce. Source: Battles
and Leaders.
12 Batteries of Guenther and Loomis along Nashville Pike. "Round
Forest" is in distance. Source: Battles and Leaders.
37a
13. Nashville Pike bridge across Stone's River. Section of
Fortress Rosecrans in background. Source: Battles and
Leaders .
14. Counterattack of Negley's Division across Stone's River at
McFadden's Ford, January 2, 1863. Artist is F. B. Schell,
from Harper ' s Weekly centerfold.
15. Confederate General Braxton Bragg' s headquarters in Murfrees-boro.
Location uncertain. Source: Battles and Leaders .
16. Union counterattack on Confederate right. Probably Brig. Gen.
Richard Johnson's division, December 31, 1862. Artist unknown.
17. Counterattack of Brig. Gen. James Scott Negley's division at
McFadden's Ford across Stone's River, January 2, 1863. Artist:
Alfred Mathews. Note other version by F. B. Schell.
18. Brig. Gen. Joe Wheeler destroying McCook's wagon train at
Lavergne, December 31, 1862, just prior to the opening of the
battle of Stone's River. Artist: The Nashville Banner'
s
Bissel 1
.
19. Death of Lt. Col. Julius Peter Garesche, Rosecrans' Chief of
Staff, December 31, 1862. A sketch by Henry Lovie for Harper'
s
Weekly . Finished drawing probably never completed.
20. Burial of Lt. Col. Julius Peter Garesche near present Hazen's
Brigade Monument. Garesche' s remains were later removed to
Washington, D.C.
21. Stylized sketch representing battle of Stone's River from the
Currier and Ives series.
22. Searching for the dead and wounded at Stone's River. Source
and artist unknown.
23. From a rare Kurz and Allison lithograph of Stone's River. The
artist for the Chicago lithographers (1891) attempted to embody
the two-day battle into one sketch.
24. A Confederate eye view of the eminence at McFadden's Ford.
Source: Battles and Leaders
.
.\\i: T^
4
&#8226;'f^^f^l
^i
Qi^^i'..
%'^^'^^ a^
m^^mct^^'
4&lt;^.
-^fpI?
i^ '
15
&#187;f fX
'/I\
'&gt;&#171;w*
^V/
</dc:description>
<dc:description>Some field drawings from the Battle of Stones River, with background information</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Stones River, Battle of, Murfreesboro, Tenn., 1862-1863; Bragg, Braxton, 1817-1876; Murfreesboro (Tenn.) -- History; Rosecrans, William S. (William Starke), 1819-1898; Stones River (Tenn.); Stones River National Battlefield (Tenn.); Stones River, Battle of, Murfreesboro, Tenn., 1862-1863; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Field artists; Lithographers</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>13 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-15; mt2011-05-05</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication04ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/62</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>