<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Two gallant leaders at the Battle of Murfreesboro</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Riley, Jr., Harris D.</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 34</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1994</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869;</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>TWO GALLANT LEADERS AT THE BATTLE OF MURFREESBORO*
Harris D. Riley, Jr., M.D.
*From the Children's Hospital of Oklahoma, University of Oklahoma
Health Sciences Center, Oklahoma City, Oklahoma
"In the cedar-brakes that border the stream of
Stone River, in Tennessee, was fought on the
last day of 1862 an action that must always be
memorable in the history of war. When first
its story was flashed over the land, men only
saw that a battle, fierce and terrible beyond
all previous example in the West, had been
delivered. . . . But when the true relations of
this contest came to be apprehended, it was
perceived to have a weight and meaning beyond
that which attaches to any mere passage of
arms--it was seen that it bore upon the whole
life of the rebellion. . . .We readily discern
that it is one of those few pivotal actions
upon which, in very truth, turned the whole
issue of the war (1)."
This is how William Swinton in his The Twelve Decisive Battles
of the War characterized the Civil War battle of Murfreesboro (or
Stones River) in Middle Tennessee which took place on December 31,
1862-January 2, 1863. As battles go, the fierce and far-reaching
encounter at Murfreesboro between Braxton Bragg 's Confederate Army
of Tennessee and William Rosecrans ' s Federal Army of the
Cumberland ranks as one of the bloodiest ever (2).
Heroes were numerous on each side at Murfreesboro. Of the
many, I have selected two &#8212; one from each side &#8212; to tell about
because of the key role each played in the battle. They were
Brigadier General James E. Rains, Confederate States Army,
commander of the 2nd brigade, McCown's division of General
Hardee's corps (Fig. 1) and Colonel George Washington Roberts,
United States Army, commander of the 3rd brigade, Sheridan's
division of McCook's right wing (Fig. 2). Although they were
opponents in the battle, there were certain pertinent similarities
between them. Both were graduates of Yale University. Both
belonged to the same social fraternity &#8212; Delta Kappa Epsilon. In
civilian life both were attorneys. Both were killed leading
23
24
charges in the battle. However, before looking at their individual
roles, let us consider the general military situation, and
particularly that in the Western theater, in late 1862.
December, 1862--the last month of the first full year of the
Civil War&#8212;showed a military picture quite different from that of
the summer and early fall. Confederate arms had been victorious
on the Peninsula in Virginia, at Second Manassas and for a time in
Kentucky and at Sharpsburg in Maryland had held its position in the
face of an army twice as large. Despite this there were foreboding
signs for the Confederacy. In Virginia, Burnside's Army of the
Potomac was obviously preparing for direct action against Lee at
Fredericksburg; in Middle Tennessee, Bragg at Murf reesboro,
southeast of Nashville, was confronted by a readying Rosecrans at
Nashville, and on the Mississippi Grant was building up for a drive
by land or by river against Vicksburg. In Arkansas, from New
Orleans and along the Carolina, Georgia, and Texas coasts smaller
forces were preparing to attack the Confederacy. Offshore there
was always the naval blockade, although penetrated by the
spectacular roaming of CSS Alabama. President Davis of the
Confederacy, well aware of the threat of the poised Northern
armies, was attempting to gather his widely spread forces together
despite lack of men and materiel (3).
On December 26, 1882, Major General William S. Rosecrans, and 2^
his Federal Army of the Cumberland numbering some 47,000 officers
and men, launched an offensive southeast from Nashville, Tennessee.
His immediate target was the Confederate Army of Tennessee which
was at Murfreesboro blocking the main road and railway routes to
Chattanooga. It was under the command of General Braxton Bragg
and numbered slightly less than 38,000 troops (4).
Rosecrans' army consisted of three corps commanded, from right
to left, by Generals Alexander McD. McCook, George H. Thomas and
Thomas L. Crittenden. Rosecrans' plan was to turn the Confederate
left while refusing Crittenden's corps (5).
The Union army required four days to march the 25 to 30 miles,
being retarded by rain, fog, and the highly effective delaying
tactics of "Fighting Joe" Wheeler's Confederate cavalry. In fact,
the advance was virtually one continuous skirmish, in which the
Federal infantry was forced to deploy at every hillcrest. The
Union cavalry was not so well handled and as a consequence
Rosecrans was ignorant of his opponent's moves while Bragg was well
informed by Wheeler (6).
By the evening of December 30, it was obvious to both
commanders that preparatory maneuvering was over and the next day
would see the onset of battle along the banks of Stones River.
Interestingly, each was planning to attack the other's right.
Early in the evening of the 30th Rosecrans sent orders to Major
General McCook to have large camp fires built on his right to
deceive the enemy, making him think that troops were being massed
there. Murfreesboro has been criticized as a place to do battle
because it was vulnerable to attack from several different
directions ( 7 )
.
The Confederate division of Breckinridge was left east across
Stones River, northwest of Murf reesboro, while Hardee's other two
divisions--McCown (4,500) and Cleburne (7,000) &#8212;moved into position
opposite the Federal right. The Confederate center was held by
Polk's two divisions: Withers (8,500) in front, and Cheatham
(5,500) to his rear. McCown's division was to attack at dawn (8).
The alignment of the opposing forces early on the morning of the
Dec. 31, the first day of the battle, is shown in Fig. 3.
Brigadier General James E. Rains commanded the 2nd brigade,
one of three brigades of McCown's division directed by Major
General J. P. McCown. Rains' brigade contained the 3rd and 9th
Georgia battalions, the 29th North Carolina and the 11th Tennessee
Infantry regiments, and the Eufaula (Alabama) light artillery.
It was on the far left of the Confederate line (9) (Fig. 3).
BATTLE-FIELDS OF
Stones River Tenn.
Dec. 31- Jan. 3 1862-3
The Federal right, where the initial Confederate blew was ^
about to fall, was held by McCook's corps; Johnson's division
(6,300) was on the extreme right flank, on the Franklin road, with
the divisions of J. C. Davis (4,600) and Sheridan (5,000) extending
left to the Wilkinson Pike. Negley's division (4,700), of Thomas's
corps was in the center of the line. Crittenden's division of
Palmer (4,400) and Wood (5,100) extended the line to the river.
In conformity to the Union plan of attacking with their own left,
two divisions were in assembly areas behind this f lank--Rousseau'
s
(6,200) of Thomas's corps, and Van Clave ' s (3,800) of Crittenden' s.
Two of Thomas's divisions were absent: Mitchell's was garrisoning
Nashville; Reynolds was pursuing General John Hunt Morgan's
Confederate raiders. Only one brigade of Fry's division took part
in the battle; one arrived on January 2 and the other was pursuing
Morgan. Rosecrans had ordered his attack to start at 7:00 a.m.,
after his troops had eaten breakfast (10).
Colonel George W. Roberts, U.S.A., commanded the 3rd brigade,
one of three brigades of the 3rd division under the direction of
Brigadier General Phillip H. Sheridan of McCook's right wing. It
was made up of the 22nd, 27th, 42nd, and 51st Illinois Infantry
regiments (11). It was located on the left of McCook's right wing
(Fig. 3).
Bragg gained the ascendancy in the battle by moving first.
He ordered General Hardee commanding the far left of the
Confederate line to attack the enemy at daylight on Wednesday,
December 31, the attack to be taken up by Lieutenant General
Polk's command in succession to the right flank (Fig. 3).
As the 11,000 Confederate infantrymen of McCown and Cleburne's
divisions moved in the half-light of early morning against McCook's
extreme right, about at the juncture of Grisham Lane with the dirt 28
road to Franklin, the full force of their attack fell on the
brigades of Kirk and Willich of Brigadier General Richard W.
Johnson's division of that corps. Kirk's men were up and under
arms, with a strong picket line in their front; but just about
dawn some of the horses of their artillery were unhitched and
taken to water. It was at this moment that the yelling
Confederates came swarming into them. The resulting confusion was
compounded when General Kirk was mortally wounded in the first few
minutes of the engagement. General Willich was not with his
brigade, having gone to see General Johnson. His men were cooking
and eating breakfast, their arms stacked. Willich, returning, was
captured before giving an order. The surprised Federals fought
gallantly, but over-matched and confused, were forced to retreat
(12).
McCown's 2nd brigade, under Brigadier General James E. Rains,
had marched directly west, staying south of the Franklin road, then
turned sharply north, sweeping across the road and around the right
flank of the Union position. It led the Confederate attack. Also
swinging around the Federal right wing and vigorously slashing at
their right and rear was Brigadier General John A. Wharton's
cavalry brigade, which succeeded in capturing about 1,500
prisoners, a four gun battery, several hundred wagons, and
generally spreading terror behind the front line. One of the
Federal commanders said he saw cavalry on his right, infantry
assailing his left, and heavy masses rushing to assault his front.
The only alternative to annihilation or capture was to be at a
rapid retreat (13).
Two of the three Yankee brigades were overwhelmed. Leaving
their artillery in the hands of the enemy, the brigades broke up 29
and streamed back to the northwest (14).
The Confederates were pressing with fury and driving the
Federals on McCook's right, but they were paying a heavy price in
lives. As his brigade slashed into the Union lines. General Rains
himself was shot through the chest, falling from his horse
mortally wounded. Rains' last words were, "Forward, my brave
boys. Forward!" His men pushed on (15). A Captain McCauley, who
was with Rains watched spellbound, then attempted to tell one of
his men that Rains had been hit, only to have a bullet rip through
his rib cage, knock him to the ground, and paralyze his right leg.
McCauley states that the site at which Rains was killed was reached
after driving the enemy approximately one and one-half miles (16).
General McCown reported that Rains was shot through the heart at
the moment the enemy was routed (17). Rains' brigade suffered 199
casualties ( 18)
.
jf"-**--.
James Edwards Rains was born in Wilson County, Tennessee,
April 10, 1833 (19). He was the son of Rev. John and Lucinda
Rains. His father's means being limited, young Rains was obliged
to work to assist in the support of the family; up to his
seventeenth year he had attended school but five months. At this
time he entered Washington Institute, a seminary near Nashville
and attended for one five-month session. He was then sent to
Connecticut where he was under a private tutor for a few weeks.
Rains then entered the sophomore class at Yale University (20).
He joined Delta Kappa Epsilon. James Rains was greatly beloved
by his classmates. After graduating from Yale in the class of 1854
at the age of 21, he returned to Tennessee and assumed charge of
Millwood Academy in Cheatham Co. (21). Rains held this position
for two years and in his spare time prepared himself for the
profession of law. He then entered the law office of John Trimble
of Nashville and devoted himself to legal studies until admitted
to the bar. Taking an interest in politics, he stumped Tennessee
during the gubernatorial canvass of 1857, and made frequent
speeches in behalf of the candidates opposed to the Democratic
ticket. After the election, Rains became associate editor of the
the Nashville Banner , the oldest political journal in Tennessee,
and a long recognized exponent of Whig doctrines. He performed
most effectively in this capacity during the one year period with
the newspaper. In 1858, he resumed the practice of law and was
elected city attorney of Nashville. During his term of office, he
compiled and published in book form the corporation statues (22).
On June 22, 1858 Rains was married to Miss Ida Yeatman, a
step-daughter of U.S. Senator and Presidential Candidate John Bell
of Tennessee. They had one child, a daughter born in 1859. In
1860, he served as district attorney general for the counties of 31
Davidson, Williamson, and Sumner (23). Rains was said to oppose
secession and had voted for the Bell and Everett ticket in the
presidential campaign of 1860 (24). However, he went with his
native state of Tennessee when it seceded.
At the outbreak of the Civil War Rains enlisted in April, 1861
as a private in the 11th Tennessee Infantry. He was elected and
commissioned colonel of the regiment on May 10, 1861, which was
ordered to East Tennessee. During the winter of 1861-62, Rains
occupied Cumberland Gap in East Tennessee, but was finally flanked
out of his position by superior manpower in June, 1862. Rains'
bravery at Cumberland Gap became well-known (25). When Kirby Smith
advanced into Kentucky, he left Stevenson's division, including a
brigade under Rains, to operate against Federal General Morgan in
the Gap. For his services in forcing Morgan northward. Rains was
promoted to brigadier general on November 4, 1862. He was made
brigade commander and was assigned to Major General John T.
McCowan's division of Lieutenant General Hardee's corps positioning
near Murfreesboro (26).
Brigadier General St. John R. Liddell, a brigade commander in
Cleburne's division at Murfreesboro, states that on the night
before the battle opened, he encountered "young General Rains of
Nashville," now commanding a brigade under Major General McCown,
in conversation with General Cleburne in a deserted house near the
battlefield. Liddell goes on to state, "I soon found Rain (sic)
to be an able and prompt officer. By reference to my locality the
day before, he quickly made known to me my new position which had
been taken in the dark. This brave young man was killed the next
day at the head of his men. His death was greatly regretted."
Professor N.C. Hughes, the editor of Liddell's Record , commented:
"Not yet thirty. Rains had made his mark politically in middle
Tennessee. As a lawyer turned soldier, he proved to be a leader
and promised to become an effective general" (27).
General John P. McCown, division commander, terming Rains "a
gallant officer and accomplished gentlemen," praised his
performance in the battle and his great value to the army (28).
When McCown's men had exhausted their momentum, Cleburne moved
up and continued the assault. Meanwhile the front brigades of
Polk's left were driving in on the right of Cleburne and McCown,
and Wharton's cavalry had swung around the Federal right and
smashed at their right and rear (29) (Fig. 3).
Following the rout of Johnson's division, the Confederates
fell on Brigadier General Jefferson C. Davis' division driving it
back towards the Nashville Pike. Davis' troops were able to delay
the Confederates only long enough for Brigadier General Phillip
H. Sheridan to prepare his men to receive the first shock of the
Southern attack. Sheridan's command, the left division of McCook's
corps, received the first attack on terrain that was largely
cultivated and thus had little cover. Nevertheless, they threw off
three successive attacks made by the brigades of Cheatham and
Withers from Polk's left (30). Robert's brigade was in the center
of this ferocious fight (Fig. 3).
About 9:30 a.m. Sheridan counterattacked with Robert's brigade
and gained sufficient time to withdraw to a new position behind
the Nashville Pike and at a right angle to Negley's division (31).
Finally, however, as Cleburne pressed in on Wither ' s left,
Sheridan was overpowered by the envelopment and the enfilading
artillery fire and was forced to give way towards the Nashville
Pike. Rousseau's division had been sent to Sheridan's support, but
there was no stopping the fury of the Confederate drive. Rousseau
was swept back, and even Sheridan was forced to withdraw. As
Sheridan commenced to fall back, Patton Anderson's brigade of
Wither 's division moved against the division of Major General
Negley posted in a dense cedar glade on Thomas' right, near the
Wilkinson Pike. Federal artillery raked the cotton field across
33
which Anderson's men had to advance, repulsing Anderson's first
charge. But A. P. Stewart's brigade was brought up in support,
and the Confederates charged again. The Federals fell back,
abandoning eleven cannons, most of which had belonged to
Sheridan's division, and which had caused such havoc (32).
So determined and irresistible was the Confederate attack and
follow-through that by 10:00 a.m. they had put Johnson's and Davis'
division of McCook's corps to flight in a wide sweep of four or
five miles to the Nashville Pike (Fig. 4). Sheridan's division was
still fighting hard during this period. Indeed Sheridan's troops
were never put to flight. Sheridan's left brigade under Colonel
George W. Roberts bore the brunt of the attack by Anderson and
Stewart. The first Rebel assault on Roberts was beaten back, and
Roberts made a counterattack before he also retreated to join the
remainder of Sheridan's command. Alexander F. Stevenson, whose
42nd Illinois regiment belonged to Robert's brigade, recalled the
scene: "Suddenly the grand form of Colonel Roberts could be seen
riding in rear of the regiment, telling the officers not to let a
shot be fired; Then, wheeling around the left wing, he rode in
front of the regiment along the whole line, with his cap in his
hand, cheering the men to endless enthusiasm and shouting to them,
'Don't fire a shot! Drive them with the bayonet!'" Following the
order to advance, the 42nd Illinois raced forward, causing the
southerners of Manigault to retreat. However, the Illinoisans soon
found themself surrounded by a host of southerners from the units
of Polk and Wood. Sheridan attempted to establish a new line
stretching east from the Gresham house and bending back to the
north, where Roberts' brigade maintained its position immediately
south of the Wilkinson Pike. Roberts led his brigade in a
3^
desperate bayonet charge against the command of Manigault (33). 35
But the strength of the Confederate attack was too great. Roberts'
brigade threw back three infantry attacks while an artillery duel
raged at a range of no more than two hundred yards. It was in the
midst of this fighting that Roberts was killed (34). Stevenson,
wrote that, after being hit by three bullets, Roberts gave the
order that he be strapped on his horse. He was preparing to lead
still another charge against the enemy when he died (35). Roberts
fell about 10:45 a.m. (36). Robert's determined resistance delayed
the attack on the Union right wing for a time, thus allowing the
reforming of broken columns (37). His brigade suffered 566
casualties (38). Although he lost three brigade commanders,
Sheridan conducted a fighting withdrawal. By noon, however,
Bragg' s first objective had been attained; the Federal line was
doubled back like a jackknife blade until its right wing was at
right angles to the original line of battle. But the Confederates
were not able to deliver the knock-out punch (39).
George Washington Roberts was of Welsh descent and was the son ^
of Pratt and Ann Wilson Roberts. His father had migrated from New
England to Pennsylvania. George, the eldest son, was born in
Chester County, Pennsylvania, October 2, 1833. He spent his
boyhood days on the family farm and attended the schools of West
Chester, Pa. He entered Yale University where he was a member of
Delta Kappa Epsilon. He graduated in the class of 1857 with
honors. On his graduation he first studied and then practiced law
in West Chester, until March 1, 1859, when he removed to Chicago.
Although successful in his profession there, he was determined to
enter the army and began recruiting for the 42nd Regiment Illinois
Volunteers. On July 22, 1861 he received his commission as major
of the regiment, and on September 17 was elected lieutenant
colonel. Upon the death of Colonel Webb on December 24, 1861, he
was chosen colonel. With his regiment Colonel Roberts took part
in the well-known march of General Fremont to Springfield, after
which the 42nd went into quarters at Smithtown, Missouri. After
the fall of Fort Donelson, the colonel proceeded with his regiment
to Fort Holt, near Cairo, where he held command of the post, at
that time garrisoned by the 42nd Illinois, 8th Ohio, and a battery
of the 2nd Illinois Artillery. From there he was ordered to
Columbus, Kentucky, after the evacuation by the enemy, and next
proceeded to Island No. 10 on the Mississippi River (40).
At Island No. 10, Colonel Roberts first made his mark as one
of the heroes of the army. On April 1, 1862, in the midst of a
fierce storm, he led a small expedition of 40 men in five small
boats which successfully spiked the guns of the upper battery
which allowed passage of Union gunboats. He gained further praise
in the engagement at Farmington, Mississippi where he covered the
retreat. He received praise from General Rosecrans for his
performance in the seige of Corinth following the battle of Shiloh
(41). In command of a brigade he distinguished himself in several
skirmishes during 1862 in route to Nashville (42).
Of powerful physique, he was as fearless as he was strong.
It is said that, on one occasion in the early part of the war, he
relieved a temporary blockade on a railroad by replacing a flat
truck on the track single-handed (43).
When Nashville was captured by Federal troops, Robert's
regiment was assigned to garrison duty in that city. With the
certainty that active operations in the field were impending, he
was transferred at his own request to the army near Murfreesboro.
In the ensuing battle, as previously related, he was killed.
Among the most remarkable incidents of the battle was the
tribute paid to Roberts by the Confederates who had witnessed his
bravery while directing Sheridan's 3rd brigade. The Confederates
dug a grave among the rocks and cedars. Major Luke W. Finlay, a
Yale graduate, wrapped the body in his own military cloak and read
the service of the dead over the remains; a military salute was
fired and a bugler played taps. Last of all, a group of privates
brought a large smooth stone and placed it on Colonel Roberts'
grave, having chopped an inscription on the stone (44).
General Phillip Sheridan, in his Memoirs , writes: "Colonel G.
W. Roberts came to me in the re-organization. He was an ideal
soldier both in mind and body. He was young, tall, handsome,
brave, and dashing and possessed a balanced wheel of such good
judgment that, in his sphere of action, no occasion could arise,
from which he would not reap the best results."
37
Rosecrans, forced by advance to change his original plans for
a flank attack on the Confederate right, gradually formed a
formidable line along the Nashville Pike, making a desperate
attempt to maintain communication with the rear. When the
Confederates had bent back the Union flank to the Nashville Pike,
Rosecrans brought Wood's and Van Cleve's division back from the
east side of Stones River to bolster the retreating Federal
defense (Fig. 5). As the Confederate drive against the Federal
right began to slow down about 10:00 in the morning, Bragg called
on Breckinridge to send from east side of the river, first one
brigade and then two brigades, to Polk's support. Through a
failure in communications, Breckinridge did not supply these
troops to help Hardee's men who had encountered the fresh Federal
line along the Nashville Pike. The new position of the Federal
line created a sharp salient at the center and in this salient was
a thick clump of trees covering about four acres. In and around
this forest Rosecran assembled every available brigade not already
in action, and backed them up with artillery on high ground in
rear of the infantry division. The general area of this
stronghold, referred to in the reports as the Round Forest, was
defended against successive waves of furiously attacking
Confederates throughout the rest of the day. Finally
Breckinridge's brigades began to come on the field from across the
river in accordance with the original orders and Bragg threw them
into action as they arrived. One by one the Confederate brigades
were hurled against the Round Forest position, with the courage
and abandon that won the admiration of the defenders, but the wall
of fire drove them back with terrific losses. At length, the
short winter twilight deepended to darkness, putting an end to the
38
fighting, to the great relief of both exhausted and decimated
armies ( 46 )
.
Thus closed the first day of a battle which was really two
separate battles, two distinct engagements separated by a day of
relative inactivity. In this first day's fighting the Federals
were driven from their positions on their right for a distance of
four or five miles, and the Confederates held the field at the
close of the day. Both armies had suffered shocking losses, but
the Confederates were justified in feeling that the day was theirs.
On December 31 the Confederates were so close to victory that it
can be speculated how the Union army could have escaped disaster
if Carter Stevenson's 7,500-man division had been present rather
than detached to Mississippi (47).
At the close of the first day of the battle on December 31,
the body of General Rains and many other dead and wounded were
taken to Murfreesboro. The stately little town had been converted
into a hospital. A wounded Confederate wrote, "We saw.... the long
black casket containing the body of our beloved General Rains,
which cast a deep gloom over our spirits. His presence in battle
had been equal to a regiment of men" (48).
Rosecrans seriously considered retreating during the night but
finally decided against it. New Years day was a day of relative
inactivity. Bragg returned Breckinridge to his original position
on the east side of the river. This move was countered by
Rosecrans' ordering a division across the river where they formed
a line of battle confronting Breckinridge.
For a time on the morning of January 2nd, it seemed that the
inaction might continue through another day. However, in the
afternoon Breckinridge was ordered to cross the river and drive the
jy
Federals from the high ground west of the river. The Federals,
however, had assembled all available artillery on the west bank of
the Stones River which totalled 58 guns at McFadden's Ford.
Breckinridge's advancing lines were met by murderous fire from the
artillery and small arms delivered by the Union infantry. The
over-all result was devastating and Breckinridge was forced back
Sj^to his original position. He left 1,700 of his men dead and
wounded on the field (49).
On the night of January 3-4, 1863, Bragg withdrew his
exhausted army towards Shelbyville. Rosecrans did not pursue. It
was not until June that Rosecrans renewed operation in this area.
The Federals lost 12,906 men and the Confederates 11,739. The
historian Rope said, "Few battles have been fought which have
better exhibited the soldierly virtues than the battle of
Murf reesboro or Stone's River, the Confederate assaults were
conducted with the utmost gallantry and with untiring energy.
They were met with great coolness and resolution...." (50).
Murf reesboro was a tactical victory for the Confederates, but
Bragg lacked the strength to destroy Rosecrans' larger army or
drive it from the field. From a strategic standpoint the campaign
was a Union victory (51).
"'Stones River!' What a host of memories comes back with the
name!" wrote the author, Mrs. L. D. Whitson as she recalled the
battle. "It seems but yesterday since we laid our hands on the
cold, dead face of General [James] Rains, who was shot through the
heart, killed instantly. ... It seems but yesterday since the screams
of his sister, who refused to be comforted. .. .What must have been
the feelings of the. . .young wife. .. .environed by Yankees
in. . .Nashville, unable to come to him?" (52).
40
Because General Rains was a prominent citizen of Tennessee
as well as a distinguished military figure, a minister requested
permission from General Rosecrans to remove Rains' body to
Nashville, his home, for burial. Rosecrans acceded to the request
but responded: "You may have the corpse, sir; but remember
distinctly that you can't have an infernal secession 'pow wow' over
it in Nashville!" (53). For whatever reasons the disinterment was
delayed. It was not until 1888 that General Rains' remains were
transferred from the grave in Murfreesboro to the Mt. Olivet
Cemetery in Nashville (54).
^1
CAPTIONS
Fig. 1. Brigadier General Jcunes E. Rains, Confederate States Army.
(Reprinted with permission from Yale in the Civil War , p.
126).
Fig. 2. Colonel George W. Roberts, United States Army. (Reprinted
with permission from Yale in the Civil War, p. 138).
Fig. 3. The alignment of the opposing forces on December 31,
1862--January 3, 1863. The first day of the battle (Dec. 31)
took place chiefly west of Stones River. The first position
of Hardee's corp and two of his division (McCown and Cleburne)
early on the morning of Dec. 31 can be seen in the lower left
portion of the map. McCown 's division was first in the line
against the Federal right. Rains' brigade is shown on the
far left of McCown 's line. In the center of the map
immediately south of the Wilkinson Turnpike the position of
Roberts brigade of P. H. Sheridan's division early on the
morning of Dec. 31 can be seen.
Bragg and Rosecrans each planned to attack the others
right flank, but Bragg seized the iniative by attacking first.
By 8:00 a.m., Hardee's troops had advanced a mile crushing
Willich's and Kirk's brigade. Bragg attained his first
objective by 10:00 a.m., having driven the Federal right back
to the line of the Nashville Pike, and put to flight Johnson's
and Davis' divisions. Sheridan's division, including the
brigade of Roberts, conducted a fighting withdrawal.
Rosecrans assembled several brigades along with artillery at
the Round Forrest, a salient in the area between the railroad
and the river. The Confederates launched several charges on
this strongly defended site but were unable to deliver a
knockout punch.
Most of the fighting on Jan. 2, 1863 took place on the
east side of Stones River. The position of the 58 Federal
guns on the west side of the river is shown. (Reprinted with
permission of Battles and Leaders , III, p. 612).
Fig. 4. The Nashville Pike out of Murfreesboro. By 10:00 a.m. on
the first day of the battle Bragg had forced Rosecrans all the
way back to the Pike. (Reprinted with permission from Battles
and Leaders , III, p. 606).
Fig. 5. Federal General Samuel Beatty's brigade (Van Cleve's
division) advanced to aid the Union right. (Reprinted with
permission from Battles and Leaders, III, p. 622).
43
ACKNOWLEDGMENT ^^
Appreciation is expressed to DeEtta Covey and Kristi Sue Stone
for typing the manuscript.
REFERENCES ^5
1. William Swinton, The Twelve Decisive Battles of the War .
New York: Vick and Fitzgerald, Publishers, 1873, 178.
2. Frank E. Vandiver, Their Tattered Flags . New York: Harpers,
1970, 170-1.
3. E.B. Long, Civil War Dav-bv-Day; An Almanac
,
1861-1865.
Garden City, New York: Doubleday &amp; Co., 1971, 291.
4. Stanley F. Horn, "The Seesaw Battle of Stones River," Civil
War Times Illustrated (Feb. 1964), 6-11, 34-39.
5. Mark M. Boatner, III, The Civil War Dictionary . New York:
David McKay Co., 1959, 803-811.
6. Horn, "The Seesaw Battle...," 6-7.
7. Ibid; Thomas L. Connelly, Autumn of Glory: The Army of
Tennessee, 1862-1865 . Baton Rouge: Louisiana State
University Press, 1971, 47.
8. Boatner, The Civil War Dictionary , 805.
9. James L. McDonough, Stones River &#8212; Bloody winter in Tenn-essee
. Knoxville: University of Tennessee Press, 1980, 253.
10. Boatner, The Civil War Dictionary , 805.
11. McDonough, Stones River. .
.
, 235-36.
12. Horn, "The Seesaw Battle...," 8.
13. McDonough, Stones River. .
.
, 90-91.
14. Ibid , 91.
15. Time-Life Books, "The Struggle for Tennessee," The Civil War.
(By James Street, Jr. and editors of Time-Life Books).
Alexandria, Va. : Time-Life Books, 1985; Peter Cozzens, No
Better Place to Die: The Battle of Stones River. Urbana and
Chicago: University of Illinois Press, 1990, 141.
16. McDonough, Stones River. .
.
, 92. ^^
17. U.S. War Department, War of the Rebellion; A Compilation of
the Official Records of the Union and Confederate Armies .
Volumes 128. Washington, DC: Government Printing Office, 1880-
1901, Series I, Vol. XX, Part 1, 913; hereinafter cited as ^.
18. Ibid , 681.
19. Ezra J. Warner, Generals in Gray . Baton Rouge: Louisiana
State University Press, 1959, 250-51.
20. Letter of July 30, 1985 from Wesley H. Poling, Director of
Alumni Records Office, Yale University, New Haven, CT to
author
.
21. Eliot Ellsworth, Jr., Yale in the Civil War . New Haven, CT:
Yale University Press, 1932, 38-39.
22. Letter of July 30, 1985 from Wesley H. Poling, Director of
Alumni Records Office, Yale University, New Haven, CT to
author.
23. Warner, Generals in Gray , 250-51.
24. Ellsworth, Yale in the Civil War, 38-39.
25. Confederate Veteran , XVI, 390-91.
26. Warner, Generals in Gray , 250-51.
27. Nathaniel C. Hughes, Jr., Liddell's Record. St. John
Richardson Liddell, Brigadier General, CSA. Dayton:
Morningside Books, 1981, 107.
28. James D. Porter, "Tennessee," Confederate Military History .
Volumes 13. Atlanta: Confederate Publishing Co., 1888, VIII,
60.
29. Horn, "The Seesaw Battle...," 9.
30. Ibid, 10-11.
31. Boatner, The Civil War Dictionary , 805.
32. Horn, "The Seesaw Battle...," 9.
^
33. Alexander F. Stevenson, The Battle of Stones' River Near
Murfreesboro, Tennessee, December 30, 1862 to January 3_l 1863
.
Boston: Jas . R. Osgood &amp; Co., 1884, 54-57; Cozzens, No Better
Place to Die, 117-118; Stanley F. Horn, The Army of Tennessee;
A Military History . Indianapolis: Bobbs-Merrill Co., 1941,
201.
34. McDonough, Stones River... , 107; Report of Brigadier General
Phillip H. Sheridan, OR, Series I, Vol. XX, Pt. 1, 347-54.
35. Stevenson, The Battle of Stones
River. . . , 68.
36. Report of Colonel L.P. Bradley, OR, Series I, Vol. XX, Pt. 1,
370.
37. Ellsworth, Yale in the Civi l War, 39.
38. Hughes, Liddell's Record, 109; OR, XX, Pt. 1, 209.
39. Horn, "The Seesaw Battle...," 9.
40. John Fitch, Annals of the Army of the Cumberland, Phil-adelphia:
J. B.Lippincott, 1864, 250-2; McDonough, Stones
River.. . , 110; J. Smith Frithey, and Gilbert Cope, History of
Chester County Pennsylvania, with Genealogical and B i o -
graphical Sketches . Philadelphia: Louis H. Everts, 1881, 713.
41. Fitch, Annals of .^.^ Cumberland, 251; Maurice Melton, The
struggle for Rebel Island, No. 10. Civil War Times
Illustrated , 18(April, 1979):4-15.
42. Ellsworth, Yale in the Civil War, 40-41.
43. Ibid.
44. McDonough, Stones River. .
.
, 157.
45. Phillip H. Sheridan, Personal Memoirs of P.H. Sheridan,
General United States Army . 2 volumes. New York: Charles L.
Webster Co., 1888, II, 210.
46. Horn, "The Seesaw Battle...," 9-11. ^8
47. Ibid , 11; McDonough, Stones River. .
.
. 219-220.
48. McDonough, Stones River. .
.
, 164.
49. Horn, "The Seesaw Battle...," 34.
50. Boatner, The Civil War Dictionary . 807.
51. Ibid ; Robert G. Albion, Introduction to Military History . New
York and London: Appleton, Century Crofts, 1929, 246-7.
52. McDonough, Stones River. .
.
, 211.
53. Ibid .
54. Warner, Generals in Gray , 251.
</dc:description>
<dc:description>Riley describes the Battle of Stones River (Battle of Murfreesboro), particularly through the contributions of two soldiers killed in the battle, Brigadier General James E. Rains, CSA, and Colonel George Washington Roberts, USA.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865; Rutherford County (Tenn.) -- Newspapers; Stones River, Battle of, Murfreesboro, Tenn., 1862-1863; Stones River (Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Civil War Stories; Rains, General James E.; Roberts, Colonel George Washington</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>28 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-01-26</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication34ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/102</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>