<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>History of Bethel-Leana community</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Sanders, Mr. and Mrs. Robert M.</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 8</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1977</dc:date>
<dc:description>HISTORY OF
BETHEL - LEANA
COMMUNITY
BY
Mr. and Mrs. Robert M. Sanders
FOREWORD
The history of Bethel-Leana Community was started before the
Historical Society announced plans for the community histories. It was
our desire to try to help those who wanted to learn something about their
community. We are happy to cooperate with the Historical Society in its
worthy project. We are deeply grateful for the wonderful cooperation in
our efforts to obtain material.
The history has been compiled through research, contributions by
those interested in the community and its history, and in a trek down
memory lane.
Mr. and Mrs. Robert M. Sanders
BETHEL-LEANA COMMUNITY
Let us take you on a tour of Bethel-Leana community, show you the
area it embraces and tell you about places and events that have contributed
to its history. We will start where Sulphur Springs Rd. starts, at the
Lebanon Pike - today's 231 N. out of Murfreesboro. Sulphur Springs Rd.
curves aro\xnd many of the old farms as it winds its way through the com-mvinity
to the west fork of Stones River.
We always knew when we got to the Bostic place we turned left off the
pike. There the long straight lanes began, each one led generally north or
west and how cold in winter and hot in summer these lanes could be. They
were bad, too, sometimes almost impassable.
One of the first landmarks called to mind was the creek ford, where
the horses were watered before starting the long drive home. The kids
were allowed to wade while the horses drank. The ford is gone with time,
having been bridged, as most of them are. There was a pretty waterfall
of twelve inches or more near where the bridge is. Many people admired
the little waterfall. It was especially pretty when the snows fell in winter.
Then came the Joe P. Smith farm next to the Haynes place, where
Mr. and Mrs. Reed Brendle live. Between these places was the double
creek ford, where the creek ran through the fence made a horseshoe bend
and went back into the lot.
By this time things were picking up. Jim Hutcherson built a store
near Battleground Drive, now Mears Street. The sign over the store read,
"STOP AND GET YOUR FORGOTS" . This store was very convenient,
as something would usually be forgotten and remembered on the way home.
Next came the Vol Dill farm. The house was a story and a half.
IV., tk
Map of
BETHEL - L EflNA
/^lA. v-f,-f ^ i k.&gt; r
built of logs with a lean-to for the kitchen. At this point there was another
creek ford. Then came the Cranor hill. Off to the left was the Cranor
house which still stands. From this hill to the northeast could be seen the
James Haynes home, Castlewood. Now we come to that long Haynes Lane,
so hot in summer and cold in winter. At the end of this part of the road
we turn west. A little way off the road, to the left, is the Billie Mitchell
farm, where Mr. Sam Mitchell was born and spent most of his boyhood
days.
At this point the road turns north by the Rayburn place and the little
ceraetery. On the right is the Horace Palmer farm. He was a noted lawyer
of olden days. The place is now owned by J. I. Bowers and Mrs. Owen
Jacobs.
The road turns west and we come to the old Sulphur Springs from
which the road we are traveling got its name. The rock covering around
the spring is still intact. Changes have been made in the original road.
This road has often been confused with the road by the same name that leads
to the Sulphur Springs resort near Jefferson.
Long before the road was built a little community was born about
eight miles northwest of Murfreesboro. We are now entering this com-munity.
It is bounded as follows: on the west by Stones River, on the
so\jth by the river, sinking creek and Sxolphur Spgs. Rd. , east by Old Sulphur
Springs Rd. , now known as Siegel Road; north and west to Swamp Road, west
to present Leanna-Central Valley Road to the road known as the Joe Brown
Road; then generally west to the Buckeye Valley Road.
At first the community was known as Bear Wallow because the bears
inhabited the rugged territory and came out of hibernation to sun and take
a dip in the "bluehole", a large, deep hole of water so clear it looked blue.
It was on the land that is now owned by Mr. Buchanan.
When Ebenozer MacGowan, one of the early settlers in the com-munity,
gave land for a church and school he called both the church and
school Bethel, and changed the name of the community from Bear Wallow -y
to Bethel.
When a postoffice was established in the community Mr. Billie Smith,
operator of the store where it was to be located, was asked what name to
give the postoffice. He replied, "Leana", believing the name of Mrs. J.
E. Stockird, wife of another of the early settlers was Leana. She was
the former Miss Leonora Russworm, the daughter of Col. John Russworm,
also an early citizen. She was greatly beloved by all who knew her and every-one
spoke of her as "Miss Lee", Mr. Smith had known someone by the name
of Leana who was called Miss Lee. Thinking this was ture with Mrs.
Stockird, he suggested the name of Leana for the postoffice. The name con-tinued
to be used after the postoffice was closed and until this day the com-munity
is known as Bethel-Leana community.
Now that we know something about the location of the community, its
boundaries, and how it got its name, let's go further down the road and
learn something about its homes and its people. We do not presume to be
able to give exact boundary lines, amount of acerage on farms, nor all fam-ilies
at given locations throughout the area. We endeavoring the acquaint
you with some of the first citizens and land owners by locating their pro-perty
through present ownership.
On the left, as we enter the community, is the home of Mr. and Mrs.
Edward L. Jordan, Sr. The house is on part of the Billie Mitchel] place.
Across the road is one of the many new homes being erected, an example
of the growth and development taking place throughout the area.
Names of the earliest settlers we have found, who lived within the
bounds of the community are Bowman, Elliott, Russworm, Stockird,
MacGowan and Wade.
Beginning somewhere near the community boundary line on the east
and covering a large territory was the Wade settlement. John Wade and
two of his brothers, William and James, immigrated, with their families,
from Maryland to Rutherford Cotinty prior to 1820. They became large
land owners, acquiring immense wealth, and also became patrioch of a num-ber
of offspring who have become widely scattered in this county and state.
We are driving west past the Presbyterian Campground where, for a /
number of years, people of different denominations gathered for a few weeks
during the summer months for worship and Bible study. The Campground
was on land known today as the T. A. Jamison farm. There was also a
Presbyterian church in this area.
As we drive past the Campground we come to the Ross place, on the
right, formerly Wade property, where the George Walkup family settled
when they came to this community in 1901. Mr. Walkup built a house on the
property in 1906. It was a very attractive home, with beautiful shade trees
on the lawn. In later years the place became the property of Mr. Walkup 's
daughter, Mrs. Florence Walkup Brown. Mr. and Mrs. Foster Vaught have
a home on the Walkup, Ross Wade land, as do the Ralph Goes and others.
The remainder of the farm has been sold to Obrien Realty Co. and is being
developed into home sites.
Off to 1.he left we see the "Mitchell Farm", as it was called for many
years, it being the home of Mr. Sam Mitchell. The property belonged to
a Carney before Mr. Mitchell owned it. At least a part of it was Wade
land at one time, as evidenced by the fact that Richard W. Wade mentioned
in his will his "Carney Tract". However, it later came into Mr. Sam
Mitchell's possession. The land joined the property of his father, Billie
Mitchell. It was here "Mr. Sam", married. Many have owned acerage and
lived on the land. The Thomas Becton home is where the Carney house
stood. It is now on Thompson Lane. A part of Riverview Drive is on Mit -
chell- Carney -Wade land.
Until the last three or four years one would have to be very careful
when driving further down the SiiLphur Springs road because if followed the
river for some distance. At this point there was a dangerous curve, and
on one side a drop of 20 to 40 feet to the water. During heavy rains the
water rose to great depths, making the road impassable, and driving haz-ardous.
This was eliminated when Obrien Realty Co. , at the request of
many citizens of the community, closed this segment of the road and
opened a new link a few hundred yards north of the closing point. It
crosses Thompson Lane connecting with Sulphur Springs Road to the right
at the T. A. Jamison farm, on the left near the bend of the river. Several
houses have been built on the new loop of road, among them the attractive
home of Mr. and Mrs. Robert Ragland, a two- story log structure. The
place is called "Rooster Hill". Near the location of the Ragland home
stood the old Ross house, many years ago. It, too, was a log structure
built along the plans of its day .
As we enter the original road, and follow its trail further into the
community, wc pass, on the left, the home of Mr. and Mrs. Aubrey Thompson,
near the banks of Stones River. A short distance down the road is the home
of Aubrey's parents, Mr. and Mrs. D. W. Thompson. Here we will stop
for a few minutes and view the surrounding territory . The place where Mr.
and Mrs. Thompson live is the homestead of John Wade, Sr. , one of the
brothers who immigrated from Maryland. At his death the homestead was
inherited by his youngest son, Richard W. Wade and another son, Henry
C. Wade. This place has been in multiple possession, some of the owners
having lived on parts thereof. Among those owning the property were F. R.
Burris, S. H. Mitchell, E. B. Hunt, B. L. Ridley, J. A. and Doc Thomas,
W. H. Christopher and W. E. Tilford. Mr. Thompson purchased the place
from G. Y. Smith.
At his death in 1880 Richard W. Wade owned a large acerage in dif-ferent
sections of the county. His land in this area was sold in six tracts,
bought by G.C. Batey, N. C. Collier, James Moore, E.K. Thomas, and
E. B. Hunt. Those living on the homeplace of John Wade, Sr. , in addition
to D. W. Thompson, are Aubrey Thompson, A Ivin Hudson, and W. B. Atchley.
The land extended to the river. There are records showing John Wade, Sr.
bought the other land in this immediate area.
Across the lane, now River Road - according to legal papers "opened
for the benefit of all the lots" - is property once owned by Mordici Burgess
Wade, another son of John Wade, Sr. He owned a large tract of land. The
main body was known as his homeplace upon which he resided at his death.
It contained eight or nine hundred acres of land, bound in general terms as
follows: "on the north by J. E. Stockird and others; on the east by Julius
C. Wade and others; on the south by W.R. and H. C Wade; and on the west
by James Mayberry, C M. Miles and others. "
The homeplace contained land he purchased from the estate of John
C. Wade; from O. H. Wade; William Smith; two tracts from his late father,
John S. Wade, Sr. ; a portion from the estate of William Elliott; another
from the Weakley estate, bought jointly by Mordici and his brothers, Rich-ard
W. and Henry C. Wade. The balance of said home tract was purchased
from persons not known but was in his possession for more than 20 years
before his death. He also owned land in other locations. It was stipulated
in his will that his real and personal property not be divided for two years
after his death. About two years later commissioners were appointed to
make divisions of said lands, setting out to R. W. and H. C. Wade their por-tion
of the Weakley tract, and to the children of M.B. Wade their respec-tive
portions of the whole estate.
The tract where his home stands contained 607 acres and extended
from the River Road to the present Shacklett Rd. At his sale, land in this
tract was purchased by N. C. Collier and James C. Moore. In 1905 N. C.
Collier sold his interest to J. A. Jones, in 1916 James A. Moore sold his
interest to Mr. Jones. Jones, Collier and Moore owned the land exclusively
for 40 years. Mr. W. W. Vaught came in possession of a portion of the land
in 1885. He sold to T. A. Jamison, who sold it to Mr. Jones in 1920.
Among those living on the property today are, facing River Rd. Mr.
and Mrs. Jack Jones, Mr. and Mrs. Allen Jones, and the Allen family,
the Allen property was once owned by W. W. Vaught, later by the Schell
family. Fronting the Sulphur Springs Road are the homes of the Eubanks,
Buggs, B.T. Walkups, Mary Fann and Johnnie Eakes, Mrs. Tom Arms
8
down the road.
To our right is property known as the Gran Batey place. It joined
the Ross-Walkup (formerly Wade property) on the south. This plot of
ground was bought in three tracts, Ninety-nine acres from the estate of
R.W. Wade, forty acres from S.H. Mitchell, which he bought from F.R.
Burris, ninety- six acres bought by Mrs. Gran Batey from Thomas Miller.
Mrs, Howard Primm lives at the Batey homeplace. The house, more than
150 years old, was torn down and replaced by a beautiful modern home a
few years ago. The old house is thought to have probably belonged to the
Col. William Wade estate, since he is known to have owned this property
at one time, or to the previous owner, Major Joel Dyer.
Others who have owned it are E. H. Burton, C. M. and W. E. Stockard.
T. A. and Lee Jamison. The land was divided into many smaller tracts.
Jim Sloan owned acreage on the southern border, which he sold to E. O.
Peel. It was later bought by Mr. and Mrs. G. E. Knight and sold by them
to Mr. and Mrs. Robert Jennings. Mrs. Jennings still ownes the property.
Mr. Sloan also sold a parcel of land to Mr. Joe Brewer, where Mrs. Brewer
lives. F.B.Arms, James (Buck) Arms, Jack Arms and Jack Davis fam-ilies
are other present day owners.
Next is land owned by Mr. and Mrs. John B. Jones, where Mr. and
Mrs. Frank Clifton and Mrs. Mary Arms live. It was once Tom Zumbro
property. Little Ranch Acres, the first housing project in the community,
was formerly owned by Mr. and Mrs. Lum Gannon, prior to them by Mr.
Gail Tomberlain. The Lloyd Adams farm joins Little Ranch Acres on the
north and is adjacent to Alford Road.
This land is not specifically mentioned as part of the Wade property
but from iaformation in deeds and from individuals, it seems likely that
Col. William Wade, or some member of the Wade family, owned most, if
not all, of this large tract of land. There is a Wade cemeteiry on the F. B.
Arms property where Col. William Wade, his wife, Casandra Jones Wade,
and members of their family are buried. Among tiiem is a daughter,
Caroline Wade Watkins, and her husband. Col, Wilson S. Watkias. On the
bill of sale of the Col. William Wade estate, Oct. 14, 1849, it was noted
that he bought this land from Major Joel Dyer. Deeds on record in the court-house
verify this statement. Col. W, L. Watkins also owned land in this
vicinity, according to deeds.
Mrs, Tom Arms and Mrs. Bea Arms (Miss Tom and Miss Bea, as
they are so lovingly known) live across from the Adams place, on Sulphur
Springs Rd. We are again seeing a part of the Mordici Wade land. Across
from this tract is other land belonging to him, now owned by a descendant,
Russ Stockard. It extends to the Allen Road,
As we come down the road and round another of those numerous curves
we see still more of the Mordici Wade property, passing the new home of
the Gilberts, the homes of Mr, and Mrs. Wayman Arms, Roy Arms, Buddy
Arms, and River Oaks, the second housing project started in the community.
Next is one of the oldest and most beautiful houses in Bethel-Leana
community, the homeplace of Mordici Wade. Its huge columns, spacious
and attractive structure has been admired by many passers-by. It was
for a number of years the home of the Allen James family. Mrs. James
was Texana Wade, daughter of Mordici. She came in possession of this
10
tract in the division of her father's estate. Russ Stockard, a groat grandson,
lived here for several years, until he and Mrs. Stockard built their home
across the road. The Max Carter family live at the Wade homeplace now.
Just down the road is the trailer home of the White family. Their
neighbors are the Neals, Dockerys and other families not known.
Opposite these homes is property at one time owned by Walter Wade,
one of the fifteen children of William and Cassandra Jones Wade. He died
in 1849 and the land was owned by other people. On his parcel of land fac-ing
Sulphur Springs Road are the home of the Lee Brewers, Leana Church
of Christ, and the homes of B. T. Lane and the Robert Lane family.
Across from his property, as we round another curve, is the old Bowman
place. Early records show this land was purchased from Thomas Bedford
and Robert Weakley, and was part of a grant from North Carolina. It is said
to be the first Deed of Conveyance made in the newly formed county of Ruth-erford
in its first session of County Court in 1804. Living on the Bowman
land fronting Sulphur Springs Road are James Boyd Gannon, J. W. Tomber-lain,
and Ernest Tomberlain families. The Riley Marlins lived at the J. W.
Tomberlain place for many years.
Joining Bowman on the north, also Walter Wade on the north, was
Ebenezer MacGowan. On March 14, 1817, MacGowan bought 1184 acres of
land from Alpha Kingsley for the sum of $2, 500, a little over$ 2. 00 an acre.
According to the deed, the land lay between the east and west forks of Stones
River, a few miles south of the town of Jefferson, bounded by John AlcNairy,
Joseph Moderall, and Robert Weakley. It was a tract of land granted by the
state of North Carolina to Robert Weakley and Thomas Bedford in 1801, and
conveyed to Alpha Kingsley by Robert Purdy by deed bearing the date of
11
July 15, 1813.
Bethel Methodist Church, and parsonage, a store and a number of
homes have been established on the MacGowan land to the right of the road.
Opposite the store is Bethel School and next to the school is the home of
Billie Reid. The MacGowan house stood on the now vacant lot between the
homes of Billie Reid and his father. Tommy Reid.
The house was built in 1817 by Mr. MacGowan with logs out of timber
cut from the still dense forest. Rooms were later added on the front by
J. E. Stockird, son-in-law of Ebenezer MacGowan. The stately old house
stood for a long time on the large, shady lawn but was torn down several
years ago. Within its walls were found records that revealed information
of interest.
The last direct descendant to live in the house was Mattie Stockird
Hunt (Mrs. J. W. Hunt). She lived there for thirty- five years. The house
was later occupied by Mr. and Mrs. John Buchanan, then by the Marcos
Vaughter family. Mrs. Vaughter out-lived her family by a number of years
and lived at the MacGowan house for the remainder of her life. Mr. and
Mrs. Tommy Reid and family were the last people to live in the old house.
The building was bought by Martin Rooker and is part of the log house near
the Lebanon Road, occupied by he and his family.
Joining Tommy Reid is the Charlie Ross home. The house was built
many years ago for Mr. Jim Burnett, who lived there at various times.
T. R. White lived in the house for a while. Mr. and Mrs. T. W. Cox bought
the place in 1919. These families operated the country store, the only store
in the community at that time. Ronnie Ros.s lives next to his father and
operated a barber shop in his spare time. Down the road and around the
corner on the left are the homes of the B uchanans and Willie Peyton Young.
The MacCxOwan land joined the Elliott property on the west. The Elliotts
are known to have been here since around 1801. A record has been found
of land bought by John Elliott that was part of a soldier's claim by the name
of James Frick. The Elliott's were also large land owners. Their land in
this community extended from McGowan's line to Stones River . The first
house on Elliott land, joining Willie Peyton Yoirng home is one of the oldest
houses in this area, the T. A. Stockird homeplace. It is known to have been
built prior to 1816. Ebenezer MacGowan lived here for awhile before build-ing
his house. Several of the Stockird descendants have lived at the old home-place.
It was later owned by Mr. and Mrs. Jack Howse. Mr. and Mrs.
Williams live there and across from the Buchanans, Young and Stockird
places are the homes of Mr. and Mrs. Elmer Dickerson, Mr. and Mrs.
Jack Tomberlain, Mr. and Mrs. Herschel Tomberlain, R. M. Miers, and
others who have recently moved into the community.
Next, on the left beyond the Stockird place, is the Elliott homeplace.
The old house, built of logs, consisted of two rooms with a story above one
room, and an outside staircase. The house is gone but an old pear tree in
the yard still bears fruit. Pieces of dishes, earthenware, and cookware can
be found in the yard. The last family to have lived in the house were a Mr.
Reartoe and his widowed daughter, Mrs. Anna O'boy. About 200 yards
northeast of the house is the family burying ground, where most of the
Elliott family, and probably friends and neighbors were buried. Most of
the old places of that day had a cemetery nearby where family and friends
were laid to rest.
Embracing most of the Elliott homeplace is land bought by Drury J.
Sanders, a few years after he returned from service in the Civil War.
The first house he built was two log rooms with an open hall between. Other
rooms have been added from time to time. A grandson still lives at the
old home. Dury J. Sanders married Frances Jane Stockird, on November
12, 1860. She was the daughter of James E. Stockird and Lucy MacGowan.
James E. Stockird was the son of Jane Elliott and William Alonzo Stockird.
Among other Elliott descendants who lived in the immediate area were Mary
Elliott, who married Captain William Smith, Eleanor Elliott, married
William Arnold, James, John, William, Catherine, and A Iford Elliott, all
descendants of William and Debroah White Elliott.
Joining the Sanders place, as we continue toward the river, is land
once owned by George and Amanda Elder, which they bought from Zachery
Dismukes. It has been sold in several plots and a number of houses have
been built on the one-hundred acre tract.
Adjoining the Elder property was the Zachery Dismukes place, once
owned by Mr. and Mrs. John G. Stockard. It was previously owned by Mr,
and Mrs. Percy Jarrett. Mrs. Jarrett is the daughter of Zathery T. and
Lockie R. Stockird Dismukes. Another daughter, Hattie and her husband,
Harry Smith, lived in an attractive stone house they built on a knoll and a
few hundred yards southwest of the old Dismukes home. Mr. and Mrs.
Creel have built a lovely new home just north of the rock house, so many
houses, old and new have been erected on Elliott land.
Levi Wade, at one time, owned the land across the road adjacent to
the river. He purchased it from the estate of James Elliott and later sold
it to Richard W. Wade. The tract covered a large acreage on the north side
of the road, including the "Arthur Place", mentioned in the will of Richard
W. Wade. It is known as the D. C. Vaughter place, and is the northwest
border of the commijnity. The Bob Davis, Bob Cook, Harvey Clark (formerly
the Sumner Dismukes place) and the Jim Taylors at Suits-Us Farm are among
the families who have lived or are living on this part of the Elliott property.
Much of the land that constitutes Bethel-Leana community is on roads
leading from Sulphur Springs Road. Between the east boundary, where we
entered the community, and Stones River, the west boundary, there are
five roads on the right- -old Sulphur Springs, now Siegel Road, Alford,
formerly Brandon Lane, Allen Road, and Swamp and Buckeye Valley Roads .
On the northern border is the Joe Brown Road, connected with Swamp Road
by a part of Central Valley Road,
On the old Sulphur Springs Road was the home of Judge Joseph
Lindsey. He, too, owned a large acreage, at different times, in various
parts of the community. His home place extended across what is now
Thompson Lane. There is record of his having bought a small tract of land
in this area from W. L. Watkins, and two tracts, containing more than
300 acres, from the estate of William Wade. Tract #3 of Joseph Lindsey
land was bought from his estate by Thomas Miller, which he later sold to
Mrs. Granville Batey, 96 acres and is part of the land owned by Mrs.
Howard Primm. The Lindsey land was bound on the east by Palmer property,
now owned by J. I. Bowers. The present Sulphur Springs Road borders the
land on the south. Roads and lines have been changed since the early set-tlers
bought their land, making it difficult to establish boimdary lines as
they were originally. Many of the old deeds mentioned Murfreesboro Road,
but not the road to Murfreesboro just as we know it today.
In his will. Judge Lindsey spoke of his Mansion House, his home on
15
old Sulphur Springs Road. A citizen of the community remembers being
in the old house in the early 1900 's. It had 15 or 20 rooms then. ?Ie remem-bered
hearing some of the older people say several of the rooms had been
torn away because they were so dilapidated. Only a small part of the old
mansion house remains. Camillas SimSj Arthur Bass, Ed and John Hooper
have owned the property. Today Stan Hooper and his family live in a beauti-ful
modern home on the same grounds.
Not far from the Lindsey property was the home of T. G. Miles. The
house faced present Thompson Lane, then known as the Batey, Miles, or
Sims road. It was a beautiful structure of its day. Mr. Miles was lovingly
known as "Uncle Tom" by kinsfolk and friends. For many years they
enjoyed meeting at his home on the Sunday nearest his birthday, which was
usually Mother's Day, to celebrate with him his Special Day. There was
always a huge basket dinner spread on the spacious lawn. These gatherings
were always memorable events, but one e.xpocially will long be remembered.
A bountiful dinner had been spread by the large crowd present. Each one
was ready, with plate in hand, to enjoy the delectable feast when a sudden
downpour of rain sent them scampering hither and thither trying to save the
food, and themselves, from a drenching rain.
There were several more acres of the Miles property with frontage
on the Bun Jolins Lane. The land has been sold in smaller percels upon
which new homos have been constructed.
Eddie Jordan joins the Miles place. His land includes acreage extend-ing
to the Cherry Road and embracing the farms once known as the Theo-dore
I-.ong place, better known as the Dockery home, and the Cas and
WilHam Stockard place, the old Adams property, where Eddie and his
16
family live.
The Driver Trailer Court also faces Bun Johns J^ano, which con-nected
with the Swamp Road at the John L. Rooker place. This segment
has been named West Compton Road. Next is the beautiful new home of
Frank and Ann Stone.
On the Alford (or Brandon) Road, coming from the Bun Johns lane,
are the homes of Richard Mingle, Gary and Patsey Moore and Golden Moore,
who lives at one of the oldest places in this area, the old Brandon homeplace,
previously the home of Mr. and Mrs. J. W. Hunt. The old deed states the
land was part of lots #3 and #4 in the division of the estate of John O. Wade.
Much of the land in this area was Wade land. Others living on the Alford
Road are Roger and Sue Austin, the Blansetts, Hubert McColough, B. B.
Wheeler, James Drake, and Hoyte Mingle. Hoyte's grandfather, George
Mingle, was one of the older settlers. He lived on this road, near Hotye's
home. Mrs. Loyd Adams lives on the corner of Alford and Sulphur Springs
Road. In this vicinity is property owned years ago by the Hollowell family.
On the right as we come to the Sulphur Springs Road is land owned by Russ
Stockard, once Mordici Wade property.
The Shelia Adams family own the farm on the Allen Road
adjacent to the Bun Johns Lane, re-named at this point Leana Road. The
Bennett's, Pointers, and William and Shirley Mingle are among those who
have built lovely new homes on Allen-Cherry Road. Shirley operates a beauty
shop in her home. On the right is the John T. Allen property, bought by
John's grandfather, J. J. Allen, in 1877 from the Julius C Wade estate.
It was bound by O. H. Wade, land once owned by M. B. Wade, Mrs. John
C. Wade, Leroy Wade, and J. E. Stockird. Mr. Allen later married Mrs.
17
Julius C . Wade.
Originally a log cabin stood on the land, similar in Construction to
the houses of the day. In 1830 Mr. Wade built a beauliful new house. He
ordered the finest of lumber from Philadelphia. It was shipped by rail to
Florence, Tenn. The house was one of the most attractive in the community
depicting the beauty and charm of an era that is past. It stood as a landm.ark
for more than 100 years.
Mr. Allen was the owner of fine stock. In 1897 he went in his buggy
to the World's Fair in St. Louis, driving one of his fine horses. It took
about a month to make the trip.
The Andrew Jackson Trail, the road Andrew Jackson followed on his
trips to Washington, crossed the Allen farm and continued to the Compton
Road, crossing the Lebanon Road near where the V. A. Hospital is located.
Mr. and Mrs. Tom Allen, John's father and mother, spent their entire
married life on this farm. It was Mr. Allen's childhood home. In 1906 a
tract of land across the road was bought by Mr. Allen from Allen James.
It was Mordici Wade property.
Next to John's home is the 100 acre tract owned by Plarry and Ann
Ward, a part of the Walter Wade land. It has been divided into several
smaller plots. Among those living there are James B. and Julius Ward.
Joining the Ward acerage are the homes of Mr. and Mrs. Hobart Reid,
Mr. and Mrs. Roger Hale, Mr. and Mrs. Charles Bullock, on Walter Wade's
land.
Across the road is the northern border of Mordici Wade land belong-ing
to Russ Stockard. Parallel to the road is the Wade slave buring ground, -y
One of the graves is that of Martin Wade, a servant of many of the Wade
18
descendants. He was born in a log cabin on the place. Here he lived his
entire life and raised his family in the house where he was born.
The Hoyte Sanford land borders Leana Road on the right, between
Allen and Swamp Roads. A few hundred yards from the Sanford farm are
homes of Mr. and Mrs. James Shipp, the Scotts, and other families who
reside at Bethel-Leana.
The Wendell Rooker heirs own acreage on the left as we turn onto
the Swamp Road. Joining this land is the Odell place, the home of Mr. and
Mrs. Raymond Tarpley. Mr. and Mrs. J. W. Hunt lived here several
years. According to Mr. and Mrs. Tarpley's records it was once owned by
J. E. Stockird.
Robert Jenkins, Aaron Hunter, Dot Cantrell, W. T. Mullins, Calanus
Wrather, Mrs. Andrew Mays, Kelly Ross, Zion Hill Baptist church and
parsonage are on land owned by Ebenezer MacGowan. His property on this
road extended from the Jenkins place south to Walter Wade line, thence
west to Sulphur Springs Road.
Across the Swamp Road from Leana Road is the home of Mr. John
L. Rooker., where Mrs. Nodie Barrett lives. The Lawrence Barrett place
is also on John L. Rooker land. The Sam Wrather home on Haynes property,
Mr. and Mrs. Hurt on Robert Wrather land, Jesse Young families at Simeon
Hunt place, Mrs. Sallie Barrett on Will Atkinson property are some of the
people residing on the right-hand side of Swamp Road. Now we come to
Central Valley Road. Here are the homes of the Johnnie Russell family
and Mrs. Mahaffey, who joins the Joe Brown Road. Johnnie and Vernie
Harrell border it on the north. Living further down the road just outside
bounds of the community but attending church here are the Willie Russell
19
and C. C. Barrett families.
On the Joe Brown Road are the homes of Joe Brown and many of his
descendants and John Swader and many of his descendants. It connects
with Buckeye Valley Road.
Joe Brown is the oldest bJack citizen in the community, having spent
most of his ninety years here. He is the son of ?Tosea and SalJie Huddleston
Brown. John Swader is another of the older black citizens. ,
Mj'S. Charlie Wrather's homeplace is on the corner of Leana-Central
Valley and Swamp Roads. The original owner of the tracts land on this side
of Swamp Road has not been definitely determined. Mrs. Wrathe^r's pt-o-perty
joins Tri-Way Market, on ihe corner of Sulphur Springs and Swamp
Roads. Mr. and Mrs. Brown, who operate the market, live in the ne.xt
house.
Buckeye Valley or Buckeye Bottom is the namt^ given the next road on
the right. It is adjacent to the McElroy place, which fronts Su]phur Springs
Road. Mr. and Mrs. Benton Hestand and family live in the first house on
Buckeye Valley Road. Among other families on this part of the road are the
Rhodens, Goods, Hutchisons, Tomlins, Halls and Barretts, l^uckeyo VaJh^y
Road continues to the b'red Gannc^n farm. Here it turns Jefl and crosses a
hill, forming a curve and connecting with Sulphur Springs Road betw(;en (he
property of JoJm Stockard and J. W. Taylor. Some of the families on this
loop of the road are the Watleys, Kimbros, Frank Maynards. Eltner T,owcrys
Jack Browning and J. N. Spears.
There are only two I'oads leading from Sulphur Springs Road on th(^
left. The first, coming from Murfreesboro, is River Road, which has
already been d(;scribed as lying between the Richard W. Wade and MtirdJci
20
Wade property.
The Shack) ott Road was known at one time as Miles Road beca nso the
only places located there were those of the Miles families and their scn-vants.
It was called by this name for many years, even after other homes wi-r-e
established. Later it was caUed Two- Mile Road, being two nijl(\s in length.
More recently, when the County did some work on the road, jt got its pre-sent
name. The road lies between the Mordici Wade and Joseph Bowman
property, as it was once known. The Mordici Wade will states his land was
bound on the west by "James Mayberry, C. M. Miles and others"
.
The Mayberry and Hill families were closely related, both families
lived at the same location for several years. It was known by some as the
Mary Jane Hill place. This was the only place in the community where water
was known to have bef?n obtained from an old open well, drawn by a well sweep.
Today on tlic^ Mordici Wade property, with frontage on Shacklett Road,
are a number of houses and trailer homes. The Byrd family and the Toombs
families live here, to name a few.
The Bowman property is best known as the George Tomberlain place.
The old house burned several years ago. Mr. Tomberlain bought the place
from the Thompkins heirs. It was owned at one time by James and Viola
Thompkins, Mrs. Tompkins was the daughter of John Bowman, granddaughter
of Joseph Bowman. As with so many places, the land has been divided into
smaller tracts on which new houses are being erected. Down the ShackleU
Road from the Tomberlain place is the home of Mrs. Virgie Puckett May-field,
also on Bowman Property. The Joseph Bowman land joined the Miles
land on the west.
The A.C. Shacklett farm will be remembered by many as the Cas Miles
21
place, which ho inlierited from his father, Caswell M. Miles, Sr. Mr,
and Mrs. Shacklctl lived there a number of years. Mr. Shacklett operated
a dairy
The Ru.ssworm place, as it was known by the earlier settlers, joined
the Miles-Shacklett farm on thc&gt; north. It also belonged to Mr. Cas Miles,
Sr. The Russworm family was living on the Lebanon Road, where Murfrees-boro
Airporl. is located, during the years of the Civil War. While the menfolk
were in service the mother and daughters were living alone. They harl
many unhappy experiences. The Yankees destroyed Iheir property . broke
info their house and ate their food. One of the Russworm daughters, I.aura
(later Mrs. Rihw Marlin), was digging potatoes one day when a Yankee
soldier came to pilfer and plunder. Laura ordered the soldier to leave and
when he did nol , she sho1 him. He took her gun nnd returned to the camp
to report the shooting. Mrs. Russworm went to the camp and talked to the
Provost marshal. He made Ihe soldier return the gun and told Mrs. Russ-worm
if the soldiers annoyed them again to shoot them, they had no right
to steal food.
Finally the situation became such that Mr. Caswell Miles, Sr. moved
the Russworm family to a house on his place for protection. Mrs. Russworm
was Mrs. Miles' mother. The property spoken of so often as Russworm pro-perty
was bound on the north by Elder and Sanders, east by Sanders and
Miles, south by C. M. Miles, and on the west by the road. The house was
built of logs. Th(&gt;re were two rooms and an open hall, with a stairway lead-ing
from the hall to Ihc upstairs rooms.
It was later kiiown as the Bell place. Mr. Bell married .Sara Miles,
daughter of Cas Miles. Sr. She inherited the property from her fa1 Iter's
The T. A. Stozkarc JfcBie&#8212;Ccnstructed nrior to 1816. Home of the late Z. T. Disnukes&#8212;Circa 184C.
-*5x-ar\
Betiifil r*:thodist Q-.uixh Tonberlain Gi:ocer\-&#8212;Owner Emiist Tcrtoerlain en portii. \y
. !!ill&#8212;Baptist QrurtSi on aranp Boad Bethel Sdiool&#8212;Now closed.
"Vhe Seward Horoe&#8212;Fran left: Mr. and Mrs. Ed Seward,
^teggie Sewarc Cilburtscn, and James T. Sarard,
Bowman Hemp (Land Grant 1801) - Mr. and Mrs. James Tcnpkins.
Ward's Mill (circa 1880). Mill ttouse - Mr. and Mrs. Lassiter, cwn and coerate mill.
Julius C. Wade House (circa 1310) - Qtma Collier on porch, &lt;snter. Ebenezer Macgovan (1767-1850)
22
estate. They sold to Mr. O.C. Alley, who sold to Jacob Robinson. The
Robinson heirs sold to Buddy and Riggs Norris. Mr. Clyde Hall purehased
the land from the ISTorris brothers. It changed hands a coupic or more limes
and today it is .Toneswood Estates, another of the housing projects being
developed in the community. Originally it was land given to Mary Elliott
by her mother, DeborahEllioit, as a part of the Elliott estate.
Next lo this property, on land that belonged to Gc^orgc and Amanda
Elder, is the trailer home of Willie Ike Victory, and the home of his son-in-
law and daughter, Mr. and Mrs. Hobart Parker, on the corner of
Shacklctt and Sulphur Springs Road. Tom and Anna Woods lived here at one
time and operated a saw mill. All of the land at this p&lt;jint on Sulphur Springs
Road south to Stones River was Elliott property, as shown by maps and legal
papers.
The home of Caswell Miles, Sr. was across the road and southwest
of the Russworm place. It extended to the river on the south and west and
was bound on the north by Z. T. Dismukos.
The Miles house has been described as a stately old house, with tra-ditional
charm. A beautiful wedding was solemnized here, that of Almyra
Miles, daughter of Caswell M. Miles, Sr. and Sara Russworm Miles and
Thomas Alonzo Stockird, son of James E. and l/ucy MacGowan Stockird.
It was atlc^nded by a large assf^mblage of relatives and friends. Following
Ihe ceremony a wedding supper was given at the home of the bride's parents.
The next evening another huge wedding supper was enjoyed at the home of
the groom's parents. People from miles around were invited. Rolh occas-sions
were remembered for years by those who were present, and by those
to whom the incidents were related years later. No doubt planning and pre-
23
paring these affairs involved many people.
The old MjJes house burned. It was replaced by anoihc^r bu! smaller
house. In IDOf) the land was purchased by Mr. Harding Hays. The famiJy
moved io the place on February 14, 1907. In 1925 Mr. Hays built an
attractive brick house on the property. Today it is the home of Mr. and
Mrs. Reece Hays. Recce has acquired acreage adjacent to thai owned by
his father, namely the Louis Miles property and the HiJliary Elder property,
the latter a part of the land owned by George and Amanda Elder. Mr. and
Mrs. Hay's son, Bobby, and his family live on adjoining farms.
Land on this side of Shacklolt Road from Sulphur Springs Road south
to the river was also originally Elliott property. It was part of a large body
of land owned by James Elliott at the time of his death, and was part of a
grant to William ElJiott from the state of North Carolina. It was conveyed
to James Elliott about the year 1820.
Other families have called this community "home". Although all of
the homes past or present have not been listed, we trust a fair picture^ of
the area has been given by naming some of the citizens of today to help
establish the location of homes of some of the early settlers, who chose the
liitlc community of Bear Wallow and helped develop it into the present-day
Bethel- Leana community.
Information on the early .families has been obtained through research
and material furnish(^d by individuals. On the Wade families and lands Ihey
owned, help was given by Mr. D.W. Thompson, F. B. Arms, Mrs. Howard
Primm, John T. Allen, Mrs. Florence Wajkup Brown, Mrs. Roberts.
Edwards and Russ Stockard, the last two named being descendants of the
Wade family; Joseph Bowman, legal papers and from E.C. Tomberlain;
24
Russworm family, Russ Stockard, MiJton Stockard, Russworm dosccMidanls,
and Mrs. Williatn Walkup, wife of another descendant; MarGowan and FiJljott
family records, and legal information furnished by Rc&lt;;ce Hays, who livens
on Elliott land; Joseph I^indscy, through legal papers.
FolJowing is a short biography of a few of the earliest s(^tt]ers- we were
able to obtain, a descendant, and a prominent citizen for a few months:
JOSEPH T.INDSEY.
Joseph Lindsey was born Apri] 4, 1804. His parents, Caleb and
Temperance Lindsey, were born in Granville County, North Carolina. It
is not known just when (he family came to Rutherford County, but Ihey are
known to have been here by 1838 and thought to have been here earlier.
He became a minister in the Methodist Church in 1825. His work as
a ininister received favorable coTnmcnt in the writings of .John B. McFerrin.
In 1850 he was made County Judge, which office he held for 17 years, the
longest period of time anyone has served as Judge in Rutherford County.
He was held in high esteem as attested by his active participation in
county and community affairs.
In his will he mentioned his sisters, Eanny and Temperance, his bro-thers,
Caleb and Dudley H. hindsey, nieces and nephews. He also men-tioned
his wife but gavc^ no namcv
Joseph IJndsey died October 18, 1869 and was laid to rest in the fam-ily
cemetery, with his parcnis and other members r)f his family. Acc-ord-ing
to the inscription on his tombstone, his last words were "l know my
Redeemer livelh". Another inscription said, "He died very happy. His
25
death chamber was filled with heavenly light."
EBENEZER MACGOWAN
Another early settler who was to i^'iflaence the history of Rutherford
County was Ebenezer MacGowan. He was born in London, England, Feb-ruary
17, 1767, the son of John and Mary Hirper MacGowan, and grandson
of James and Elizabeth Stajnforth MacGowm. Plis father was a noted prea-cher,
writer, and close friend of John Wesley.
Ebenezer was 13 years old when his father died in 1780. Four years
later he immigrated to the United States, and settled in Dinwiddle County,
Virginia, where he married Sally Stell in 1786. They had three children:
John, James, and Elizabeth. Sally died in 1793. He moved to St. Tamany's
in Mecklenberg County, VA, , where he married Frances Baugh, on July 22,
1797. They had five children, William Baugh, Samuel Goode, Thomas
Harper, Martha Ann, and Lucy B.
He was ordained deacon in the Methodist Episcopal Church on March
10, 1798, as evidenced by a.n old parchment signed by Bishop Francis Asbury.
In 1816 he and his family left Virginia and came to Tennessee, travel-ing
in oxcarts over the mountains ajid rough terrain- -as did many of the
early settlers who came to this new land while the forests were still dense,
there were few roads and the oxcart was a prevailing mode of transporta-tion.
He came to Rutherford County and settled in a small windemess com-munity,
northwest of Murfreesboro, known as Bear Wallow.
He was ordained elder in Columbia, Tennessee, November 28, 1824,
by Bishop Joshua Soule. He was one of the earliest ministers in Rutherford
Coimty.
Ebenezer MacGowan died April 30, 1850, at the age of 83, and is
buried in the garden at his old home. Quoting from the history of .lohn R.
McFerrin. "He h'ved to an advanced ago, and was a man of lini^ learning.
He has gone to rest and left the .savor of a good name. "
He was a man of strong convictions, and firm in his beliefs. His
granddaughter often recalled an incident in her childhood. Urr mother had
made a new dress for her which she was planning to wear to church -m a
Sunday morning, with great pride. Pre- shrunk materials were not yet on the
market so her mother put a five or six inch hem in the skirl, which came
almost to the ankles. When her grandfather saw her in her new dress, he
immediately picked her up and stood her on the staircase while he took his
pocket knife and ripped out the hern, saying in a disgruntled tone that no
granddaughter of his was going to disgrace herself by wearing a dress that
short. One cannot help bul wonder what his reactions would be to the pre-vailing
styles of the present age.
JOHN WADE, SR.
John Wade, Sr. , son of John Edgar and Abagail Brawner Wade, was
bom in 1760 in Fredrick County, Maryland. He had 2 sisters, Elizabeth
and Ann, .3 brothers, James. William, and Jessee.
Jolm Wade, as did his father, fought in the Revolutionary War. He
enlisted as a private under Captain John Reynolds in Fredrick County,
Maryland, July 18, 177G, re- enlisted May 5 , 1778. He served during the
War in Captain Bernard Hubley's Co. , under Lt. Col. T.udwig Wellner,
German Batallion, Continental Troops. His name appears in Register
1783, and on a similar list November 2. 1784.
Pie was married in 1781 in Montgomery Co. , Maryland to Elizabeth
Offutt, who was born in Maryland. They had 13 children:
1. Mordecai Burgoss, b. 4-28-1800, d. 10-30-1886, m. Martha A. Campbell,
b. 7-5-1818, d. 9-10-1863.
2. Eliza, b. 1803, d. 1840, m. William Snell who died ll-i -1836
3. Elizabeth, b. 1-8-1804, d. 10-21-1886, m. 7-15-1825 to Ed Alexander
Cochran.
4. John M. , b. 1805, d. 1886. m. Harriett Calhoun, 12-21-1826. She was
bom 1808, died 1887.
5. Richard William, b. 4-1811, d. 1-3-1880, m. Narcissa Frances Noal,
4-10-1844. She was born 12-- 26-1824, d. 12-18-1905.
6. Annie, b. 11-11-1817; married Billy Timmons
7. Martha, b. 7-21-1821, m. Robert Bumpass.
8. Mehaley or Mahala, b. 3-27-1823, married Eiisha B. Vaughn.
9. Jane, b. 11-4-1824, married Isaac Brown.
10. Henr&gt;' C. (bachelor) d. Sept. 6, 1882, no birth date given
11. Lucinda, b. 1-8-32, married Randolph Johns.
12. Sally, married 1. John Sperry, 2 John Wade (her first cousin).
13. Catherine (Kitty), married Osias Wade (first cousin).
Six of these were confirmed in the will of John Wade, Sr. .
Sometime prior to 1820 John and two of his brothers, William and
James, with their families, immigrated to Tennessee. John and William
settled in the northwest section of Rutherford Covmty, in what is now
Bethel- 1.eana Community.
John Wade, Sr. was a member of the Presbyterian Church at Sulphur
Springs. He was a highly respected citizen and a man of integrity. He had
an eminent ancestry. Four generations back, Zachory Wade, bom in J627,
died 1677, and his wife, Mary flatton, who died in 1678, came as immigrants
to Maryland from Warwiehshire, England. He was an extensive land owner.
28
and a donor of land upon which Washingl.on, D.C. is located.
There is a monument, in Washinj^on, D.C. , on iSth Street, between
Constitution Ave. and East Street, erected by the National Daughters of
American Colonists, April 25, 193G. It bears the following inscription,
"To the original potontees prior to 1700 whose land grants embrace the
site of the Federal City." The name of Zachory Wade is among those
listed, followed by the date 1670.
John Wade, Sr. died in 1840, his wife, Elizabeth, died in 1835 in
Rutherford County. A number of his descendants still live in Rutherford
County, some in the community where their ancestors settled so many years
ago.
JAMES E. STOCKIRD
James E. Stoekird was bom in Rutherford County, Tennessee, Sept-meber
9, 1817 , son of William Alonzo and Jane (Elliott.) Stoekird who
were natives of North Carolina. The father settled in this county in 1809.
He was an energetic and successful farmer, and lived a long and useful life.
He was a Whig in politics, and a member of the Presbyterian Church. He
served a number of years in the Indian War. His death occurred in 1876.
James E. was reared by his grandmother, Debroah Elliott. Ho grew up
on a farm and secured a limited education. At the age of (nghtccn he
served an apprenticeship in mechanics and engaged in making cotton gins,
a business he followed for sixteen years.
On February 17, 1842 he married I,ucy B. MacGowan, daughter of
Ebenezer Macdowan, a prominent Methodist Episcopal minister. To Mr.
and Mrs. Stoekird were born eight children: Frances Jane, who married
Drury Josiah Sanders; William Elliott, married I^ockie Russworm; Mary
20
Ann died young; Martha Caroline, married James V/. ITunt; Jamc^s Edwir^.
Jr. , never married; Alice Elvira, married Thomas Gentry Miles; Nancy
Fletcher, never married; Thomas AJonzo, who married Almyra MiJes.
Mrs. Stockird died April 23, I066, and in ]8fi0 Mr. Stoddrd marricni
Mary I^eonora Russworm, daughter of Johi S. and S.-iilie Marii)i Russvvoi,-;. .
They had four children; Samuel Russworm, married Emma James; Rosaiinci
Deborah, Mrs. W. I. Gresham; John Elliott, married Crc;orgia A mbrose;
Virginia T^eonora, never married.
Mr. Stockird did not Lake an active part in the Civi) War, bu1 sym-pathized
with the Southern cause. He was a Dt^mocrat, and a squire of
the ninlh District for fweniy years. IF(^ and his family were members of
the Methodist E piscopal Church, where th(\y v/ere active in church affairs.
JOFIN R(nVMAN
Most of the following ariicle is fj-om the Journal of B. I.. Ridley;
"] had an experience wil.li John Bowman iji 18()4 that showed his
recklessness and want of fear. WhiJe flood was environing Nashville and
Forest was dashing upon Murfreesboro, seventy-five "Yanks" had hacu
"^i^ in a block- house near Smyrna depot, guarding the railroad between
ashville and Murfreesboro. Things were getling so "squally" l:hal Lhey
left their fortress at Murfrcn^sboro. Four iii.-'bs had slipperi through from
.flood's army to see hom(&lt;folks, John Bowman aiiiong them. Thr^y loo,\'(&gt;d
up the pike and saw it blac-k witli blue coats. The idea naluraJly was that
they were so badly frejghtened a shot or two would stampede thi-m, and thai
we would at least get iheir wagons and teams. Knowing every pig path, lhey
rushed through ihe cc&gt;dars and ensconced themselves in a thicket on Sc^arcy's
farm alongside of the old road. As the seventy-five marched alons;. each
Reb on his horse drew his Navy and fired. Did Ihey run? Woll, never in
the wide world. I can hear that Yankee officer now cry, "ITalt' Rjfjht
Wheel! Fire!
They peeled the saplings, made shot holes through our clothes and
saddles; it looked like the demons had turned loose upr^n us, and it seemed
that they would kill us in spite of fate. We got over the hill after a Ijme;
they did not pursue-nor did we. Bowman wanted to go back and all nek
again, but the rest of us demurred. We dubbed that battle "Hardup," for if
there was ever a hard time getting out of a thicket, that was one. Did wo
get wagons? No, did not want them. Capture, "Yanks?" No, we wc;rn
glad enough to save our scalps. Jt was John Bowman's recklessness that
induced four of us to attack seventy-five! One of the young men, only
fourteen at that time, (Dr. G. W. Crosthwait, of Florence, Tennessee,
and who received only this baptism of fire during the great war) often now
speaks of the battle of "Hardup" as one which ought to be recorded. " ( Dr.
Crosthwait lived in an adjoining community but was well-known in the
Bethol-Lcana area, where he had many friends, and ofter administered to
the needs of those who were ill .
)
John Bowman was not always as fortunate as in the battle of "Hardup",
as further related by Mr. Ridley. "John Bowman, a member of Colonel
Paul Anderson's Calvary, was cut off in Hood's retreat and took shelter
near Murfrecsboro, his home. They caught him about midway between
Murfreosboro and J.ebanon, and tied him to a tree. Instead of begging for
his life, he defied and heaped epithets upon his captors until they, in
frenzied rage, riddled his body with bullets."
31
James E. Stockird, with a helper, carried a wagon and brou^Fii .lohn
Bowman's body back to the community where he had spent all '.)|' his jjfe,
except the time he was in service. Pie was buried in the MacGownn-
Stockird Cemetery.
His father, John Bowman, son of Joseph Bowman, was himscvlJ' n sol-dier,
having fought a battle of another kind. He was both do;i.r and dumb.
The story is told that each time a child was born into his home he would
lase an ax, or other heavy instrument, and strike the floor to see if tiie
child was deaf or dumb, so great was his fear that one of his children
might have to suffer from the same affliction as he had for all of his
life.
Many of the young men in this community laave gone into cnnibat in
other wars. Most of ihem came back but a few gave their lives for their
country. Charlie Fann, son of Mr. and Mrs. Houston Fann, was reported
missing in action in World War II, but was later found. He was identified
by the high school class ring on his finger. He was given a hero's burial in
Arlington Cemetery. David Thompson, son of Mr. and Mrs. David W.
Thompson, was also reported missing in World War II but liis body was
never recovered. We are proud of the boys of the community who have
served in any war in which our country has been involved. The memory
of those who gave their Jives is indelibly imprinted on our hearts and our
minds.
SOON CHIAOCHTJN
A Chinese native resided in this community for a brief time. Soon
Chiaochun had come from Trinity college, now Duke University, Durham,
N.C. , to VandorbiJt University to further pursue; his studies in Ain(M-i( on
colleges. It was tht^ summer of 1885 that James E. Stocki rd, ;i trustee of
the University at Nashville, learned about Charles Jones Soon. I.hc bap-tismal
name Soon had given himself after becoming eonver1&lt;:(l in North
Carolina.
Mr. Stofrkird be&lt;:ame interested in the Chinese boy aad invited him
to spend the summer with he and his family-at the old MacGowan house,
tlien the home of ihc Stoekird family. Charlie Soon, as he was called
here, spent two summers in the Stoekird home, enjoying fishing, and all
of the activities in whieh the young people of the community participatcKl.
Upon completion of his studies at Vanderbilt, he returned to North Carolina.
He left many memories of his visit. He gave to Sally Martin, a nj(^cc
of the Stockirds, a picture of himcelf, which is preserved in a volume on
the Chiangs of China. One corner is slightly burned where, according to
legend, Sally threw it in the fire when she was teased about it. As the
stories go, Sally had to tak(^ more than her share of teasing. He gave to
Mrs. Stoekird, his ho.stcss, a gold ring with his initials engraved on tiie
inner side. It was iater uscxi in making a cameo, which no doubt, is still
prosc;rved in l.he family.
He remain(!d in North Carolina two years doing missionary work.
r,ater he returned in hjs native land. He added a "g" to his name and became
a leader in religious and polilical affairs. Shortly afier his return to China,
he married Miss Ni Kweitseng. One? of Iheir three daughters is Madame
Chiang KiaShek, a nationally known figure.
CHURCHES
After Eb&lt;MK'zer MacGowan built, a home; for liia famiJy aiul quarters
for his slaves, his next conr-'^rn was a place for the people of !he com-mimity
1o worship. He began holding services in his iiome. Pjcjng small
of stature, he stood on the stairway and preached to lh(^ people who galh(.;red
from time to time to worship God. to thank Him for safe arrival in the new
country, and to ask His guidance in their daily lives and in thcur c&gt;ffort.s to
establish homes and develop the wilderness territory.
As the community grew, there was need for a larger place of wor-ship.
Mr. MacGowan gave a little grove, containing four acres of land,
acrr^ss the road and a few hundred yards southeast of his home. He donated
the cedar logs and helped in the construction of a little church, ut^stled in
the recesses of the grove, deep within the wilderness of the newly settled
country. He called the church Bethel. It was the first church in the new
community, which he called Bethel Community. It was no longer known as
Bear Wallow community. The church stood back of where the Methodist
Parsonage now s1;ands.
Some people believe th(&gt; church was erectc^d in 1827, but according \o
the family history given by his descendants, who have information from
MacGowan 's own lips, it was erected in 1818. Bethel was put on Stones
River Circuit, where it remained until it bc^came a station.
Rev. MacGowan was Bethel's first pastor. He had become a minister
in Virginia, where he was ordained deacon in the Methodist church on March
10, 1798 by Bishr)p Francis Asliury. He was ordained F]ldr^r l^y Bishop
Joshua Soule, Nov. 28, 1824, in Columbia, Tennessee. A great grandson
has in his possession the original certificates, which are on parchment.
:m
Pholoslalic copies were placed in Ihc sancluary a1 Rc^thcJ by anolhcf grra'
grandson, who also has pholoslatic copies of the certjficalos in hjs pos-session.
According to Ebenezer IVIacGowan's wiJl, probated May 18ri0. he
devised to the trustees ol" the church, Johii I_&gt;ane, Joseph I ,inds&lt;&gt;y, John
.lonos, Captain WiiJiam Smilh, James E. Rtockird, and 1heJr successors
in office, according to the discipline of the Mcthodis! Episcopal Church
(South) "that part of my land where-on Bethel Meeting Mouse stands."
Among fannily names not mentioned above, but found in the church
record which dated back to 1830 are: Adams, Allen, Arthur, Atkinson,
Batcy, Bowman, Gentry, Hunt, Lewis, Macon, Robb, Rooker, Ross.
Rowlette, Russworm, Thomplxins, Wade, and Ward.
Records show there was a Sunday School at Bethel as early as 1878. v
A Sunday School quarterly for that year has been found.
In 1887 a nt^w church was built, and the old church became Bethel
school. The new church was described as a frame structure 30 ft. x 50 ft
with a sealing capacity of 300-350. The church was dedicated the first
Sunday in September 1387.
Bethel Church still stands but the house in which it was founded has
been torn down. It stood so majestically for inany years, as if watching
the growth of the church it nurtured, and the development of the community
from rugged traiLs and ox carls to paved roads and modern modes of travel;
from the log cabin homes to attractive modern structures. Jn memory the
o!.' house still stands as a m;)num:.&gt;nt to posterity.
From the History of Bethel Church compiled in
1962 by Mr. and Mrs. Robert M. Sanders
NEW SCHOOL PRESBYTERIAN CHURCH
The following is from a deed on record in Rutherford County Court-house:
"Know all men by these presents that I, Wilson L. Watkins of the
County of Rutherford and State of Tennessee for the purpose of promoting
the cause of Christianity, and for the consideration of one dollar to me in
hand paid by Walter Wade, Samuel McFadden and Addison Mitchell of the
same county and state, the receipt whereof is hereby acknowledged have this
day sold, transferred and conveyed unto the said Walter Wade, Samuel
McFadden, and Addison Mitchell as trustees, for the use and benefit of the
new School Presbyterian Church at the Sulphur Spring in the said county
of Rutherford, and their successors in office, the following described tract
of land, --with erections and improvements thereon, and bounded as fol-lows:
beginning at a stake my southwest corner, thence east to a stake,
thence north to a stake, thence west to a stake in William Mitchell's east
boundary line thence south to the beginning; containing by estimation one and
three fourth acres, be the same more or less, --given under my hand this
28 day of Nov., 1843. Registered Nov. 29, 18i3. Deed Book i, page 404. i^
Evidently the church was located near the Presbyterian Campground.
Little else is known about the church except that it was thought to have been
destroyed during the Civil War. Nothing definite has been learned about
its pastors or its membership. There was probably a large membership
at the time it was organized.
LEANA CHURCH OF CHRIST
It was a long way from the old ramshackle Bethel School building,
with its rickety benches and broken window panes, to the modern brick
structuro which now houses the members of I^cana Church of Chrisl , bul.
the distance was covered in iess than ten years and the spiril of love.
cooperation and desire for progress which permeated the small group who
organized the work, still is a notic.euble characteristic of the church 1oday.
It was June 1047, the stcond Sunday to be exact, when [ivo families
held the first service in the old scJioolhouse. Church records show the char
ter members were: C.C. Barrett, Houston Fann, Joe Brewer, Hobart
Reed, S. D. Wrather and members of their respective families.
Early in the next year the group, still small in number, purchased
an old storehouse close by and, after a few repairs, worshipped there first
in March of 1948. AH the (^arly work of the church was under the oversighl
of the Westvue Church of Christ. W. E. Watts, one of the elders of the
Westvuc church, was more directly responsible for the teaching program
during the first two years and the congregation enjoyed remarkable growth
and spiritual prosperity durin:; the period. C.S. I^ocke was minister of
the church from ]949 through 1952.
Early in 1953 elders and deacons were app&lt;jinted. The^y were: M.F.
Allen and Joe Brewer, elders; Cleveland Wrather and Ray Bul lock, deacons.
Through the more than ten years since the; congregation was estab-lished
almost forty guest ministers filled the pulpit at one time or another.
Mason Tucker bscame minister in 1952. During the past five years
the church has n\ore than doubled in size and contributions. In 1955 a new
$15, 000 meetinghouse was eomj:)leted. The building was designed and built
by one of the members, R. A. Patrick. The structure seats 175 in the main
auditorium. Four classrooms, when opened, increase seating capacity to
37
350. An overflow audience of 450 attended the first service held in the
building.
In 1961 two Sunday School rooms and a baptistc^ry wer(^ added: and in
1970 a centra] heating and air conditioning system. Five more classrooms
were built in 1972, and the floors were carpeted. Today it is a beautiful
edifice, in which a large congregation worships.
Some who have served as church secretary are Joe Brewer, Charles
Bullock, John Bowman, and Lee Brewer, as treasurer, and William NeaL
Those who have served the church as pastor, in addition to C. S.
Locke and Mason Tucker, are Clifford Brothers, James Ryan, Marvin
Brothers, and Maurice Tho mason, present pastor.
(Information obtained from Mrs. Howard Primm, and Mr. and Mrs.
Charles Bullock).
ZION HILL INDEPENDENT BAPTIST CHURCH
Another attractive church in the community is the Zion Hill Indepen-dent
Baptist Church, on Swamp road a few hundred yards from Sulphur
Springs Road. It was organized by David E ubanks, at Lascassas. Bro.
Eubanks was the first pastor.
For about six months services were held in the Russ Stockard house,
where the Max Carter family lives. The congregation worshipped here
until the church was built. Jim Hunter was first Sunday School Superinten-dent.
Others who have served in this capacity are David Ross. Danny
Flick, and John Good.
The deacons are Kelly Ross, Jim Ormcs, Leonard Barrett, Howard
Hunter, and Walter Westover. The first clerk was Mrs. BiHie Singleton,
38
rol)nwt;d by Mrs. Ruth Good.
Pastors who have served the fhirch are David Eubanks, Kennolh
Armstrong, Bill Shaw, Bill Vv'oodv'G.rd . of Nashville, isoncaJl.
Average attendance at church services is about 150, al Sunday School
about 70. The church has a thriving congregation doing a gron1 work in
the sei-vice of the Lord.
(Information given by Mr. and Mrs. Kelly Ross.)
Mt. View, a colored church, stood v/c3t of Mrs. Mahaffey's house on Central
Valley Road, just back of Mrs. Charlie Wrather's farm. It is known to
have existed in the IGOO's but closed l^,v many years and the building torn --
down. It is remembered as being a B;xptist church. McVeigh's Chapel,
also a colored church, was located on the sulphur Springs Road, opposite
Alford Road, where Mrs. Tom and Mrs. Bea Arms live. It was regarded
by both black and while as a respectable church. The land was given by Mr.
Jim Moore. The deed was made to Alex McVeigh and elders of the church
and their successors in office for as long as it continued to be a church.
Alex McVeigh was a preacher, and probably at some time pastor of the
church. McVeigh's Chapel was in exitcncc for several years. .
A story is told about a v/edding that was solemnized at McVeigh's
Chapel. The mother of the groom w in.^jd some of "her white folk" to
attend her son's wedding, which they did. 't was a pretty wedding and a
large crowd was in attendance. The bride and groom faced the congrega-tion
for the ceremony, instead of facin:^ the preacher. At the close of the
ceremony the preacher pronounced t i.,..i man and wife and said to the groom,
"Now, you can kiss the bride. " After r^ moment's hesitation the groom
39
looked lip at the preacher and said, "STX)sin you kiss 'or fust."
John's Hall This church was east of the Hoyte Sanford place, jusi onlsido
the community boundary, but people from this community altonded churcli
there and buried their people in the cemetery back of the church.
Antioch , a missionary Baptist churc i, was organized in the late loOO's,
and is still in existence. It is on tiio .Joe Brown Road.
These churches are known to have been in existence, but the time of
organization cannot be definitely established.
40
SCHOOLS
The first, school known to have been in what is now Bclhcl Community
was the Elliott School, so caJled because it was on the PlUioU property.
The old Elliott home stood a few hundred yards northwest of the school.
Little is known about this school except that it was a log building, with a
chimney at one end. Foundation rock can still be found where the building
stood. Signs of an old road having been near the school are still visible.
Peyton Randolph and J. E. Stockard are among those who attended this
school. Older settlers think Nellie Elliott was a teacher there.
The exact date of the next school in the community cannot be obtained,
either. After Ebenezer MacGowan built his home and had founded Bethel
Church , a school house was built two or three hundred yards southeast of
the church. Since it was on MacGowan property, it is thought he probably
gave the land, furnished some of the building material and helped build the
first Bethel school.
In style it was a typical early American building, similar to the church
nearby. It was built of logs cleared from the wilderness, hewn by hand and
put together with pens. The roof was ribbed poles, to which crude but sub-stantial
boards were nailed, with cut nails. It was a small building, about
18 X 20 feet, with puncheon floor. Light was furnished from a door in the
front and a few small square windows. There was a fireplace at the south
end of the building. The chimney had a rock base. Above the coping it was
made of sticks and mud. The seats were split logs supported by pegs. They
had no backs. Water was obtained from a hand dug well nearby. The scliool -
41
house was separated from surrounding property by a rail fence.
The building was in a low swampy place. Sometimes, when heavy
rains came, the water was so deep someone would have to built a raft and
row across the water to get books and other articles needed, or carry the
teachers and children to and from school . Sometimes classes would have to
be held in the church building.
Playground equipment in those early days consisted of a grape vine
jumping rope, that had to be replaced about every week; grape vine swings;
homemade seesaws, usually a pole placed across a stump. The side of a
ditch by one of the early roads was used for slides. Two poles, with limbs
cut to hold a cross pole, provided equipment for high jumping.
Some of the teachers in the first Bethel school were Petty Henderson,
a blind man, Al McClain, and Mary McQuilkin. .. fi-om Pennsylvania. Evi- ^
dently Miss McQuilkin taught at Bethel a number of years. A register of
the early eighties gave names of great grand children of the early settlers.
Mrs. Mamie Adams, who lived in Donelson for a number of years,
had many memories of "Old Bethel School". It was here that she started
to school, and where she attended with her sisters, Fannie and Martha.
Her first teacher was Miss McQuilkin whom she described as "a fussy
old maid, lank and skinny, and all the kido were afraid of her". Mrs.
Adams also recalled the most embarxassing experience of her young life,
her first whipping at school. She got the whipping because she couldn't
pronounce a certain word but somehov/, after Jim A/Iullins went out and got
a switch and Miss McQuilkin "ticded her little bare legs with it" she could
pronoimce the word. Her brother thoi jht ii was a funny joke to tell about
4;j
her whipping every time they had visitors. She would always go upstairs
and stay until the visitors left.
Other teachers she remembered were Miss Vinnie Burton, "She
stayed several years and was loved bj' all the children"; Miss Alice Bruger
and old professor Miller, an old m&amp;n with white beard. Her outstanding
memory of him was the time he threw a book at Martha James because she
couldn't spell a certain word.
In memory she saw "that old gully", as it was called. When the child-ren
went out on the playground they were charged to be careful and not get
too far back in the hollow for there was quicksand in the hollow "that would
swallow you up"
.
School was held in the church building much of the time during the
years of 1885-1886 because of the poor condition of the schoolhouse. In 1887
when the new church was erected the first Bethel church was deeded to
Rutherford County by the Quarterly Conference of Stones River Circuit,
and the first Bethel Church building became the second Bethel school build-ing.
Papers pertaining to this transaction, and other material about Bethel
School arc in the hands of a descendent of some of the early settlers in the
community. In those early days there were School Commissioners. This
method of choosing teachers was used until the present plan was enacted.
The first commissioners of the school district were David Massey and
Jimmie Stockird; later came Z.T. Dismukes and Bud MuUins; still later,
CM. Miles and T.A. Stockird were commissioners.
Mr. George Tomberlain remembered the first Bethel school building,
although he attended school in the second building. His first teacher at
4;^
Bethel was Miss Ola Marlin. He remembered how attendance would fluc-tuate
and at intervals during- the year two teachers would be teaching in
one room.
In the fall of 1905 a room wa.s added on the south of the one- room log
building. The first principal 5n the two-rc=om school was Moore Andrews,
with Nora Stockard assistant. For years ;he old wood stove used in the first
church, a 36x24x18 inch ironside, v/as used in the second school building
but by now the pot-bellied stove with an added air drum was also used.
When the second Bethel school came into being, a well was dug north of the
buDding. In 1915 a well was dug west of the school. In 1915 a porch was
added on the west side of the building. In this year, also, a stage was built
in the north room, on the north end. Sometime between 1921 and 1924
accordion doors v/ero put between the two rooms, and about this time or
probably a little later more and larger windows were put on the east side
of tine building. Another memory of the two-teacher school, the Friday
afternoon programs when the parents were invited to see the children
"perform".
Bethel became a three-teacher school in 1925. A new room was added
on the northx -est corner of the original log room. The teachers were Mrs.
Earl Roberts, Mary Hall and Lavada Bowling. It remained a three-teacher
school for a few yea-s, then became a two-teacher school again. In 1926
Bethel had its first school bus, driven by Mr. Lum Gannon. Other drivers
for the school were Ernest Adams, Howard Whitley, and Ernest Tomberlain.
A lunch room was added in 1936. Cooks in the first kitchen were Mrs. Tom
Arms and Mrs. Bea Arms. They continued as the cooks as long as the
44
school existed.
Interested citizens, because of the regard they had for their commu-nity,
worked earnestly and faithfully for a new school building. It was due
to their untiring efforts that in 1950 a new school building was erected across
the road from the second Bethel school, a part of which had stood for 132
years and had been used for a schoi 1 building for 63 years.
The new building was cherished by those who loved Bethel Community
and wanted the school to continue to function as one of the important links
in the life of the community. The new building was an attractive three- room
block structure, built in modern sytle, with the use of modern building equip-ment.
It was floored in hardwood, heated by gas, lighted by electricity and
with light from spacious windows that was controlled by Venetian blinds --
Quite a contrast from the earlier buildings. The students studied at comfort-able
desks, v/ith many kinds of materials to make the preparation of their
lessons easier and more interesting".
When the building v^as completcci, visitors from all over the state came
to look over the structure, as it was considered a model plan for other rural
schools. The first teachers in the new building were Mrs. Ray Donnell, Mrs.
Robert Lane, and Miss Ann Sv/ain.
At the time school work v/as started in the new building there was practi-cally
no extra equipment, but the school and community club went to work
immediately and obtained oeveral pieces of playground equipment, a piono,
water cooler, a 24 foot deep freeze, radios, record player, record collection,
film strips, book cases, and cabinets, science equipment, two television sets,
and installed a public address system. All of this was done in a remarkably
45
short, period of time which further indicated interest in the school. Bethel
was chosen from the schools of the county for a one week dental flouridation
clinic, sponsored by the State Board of Education. The school received recog-nition
in a nationally known magazine. It also participated in the eye-testing
clinics, sponsored by the Lions Club. Bethel was also a participant in the
Blue Ribbon Health Program.
The school had an active 4-H Club and rated in the blue ribbon group
most of the time. Local winners in county- wide contests did outstanding work.
Bethel Community Club held its meeting in the building and worked closely
with the school. Each year they sponsored, jointly, a community club and
school picnic and planned projects for use of the proceeds that would be bene-ficial
to both but keeping the needs of the school especially in mind. There
was also a Bethel Home Demonstration Club which made contributions to
the school.
Bethel was always an elementary school, but its graduates who have
attended high school and college have carried the colors well and have own
outstanding achievements. From the time of the first log building, around
which clusters many memories, girls and boys have gone out from Bethel to
become successful citizens and worthy representatives of Bethel school and
community.
A complete list of teachers cannot be obtained but others in addition to
those already mentioned are: Mary Knott, Edith Littler, Ada Ewing Wendell,
Mrs. Myrt]e Johns, George Rice, T.A. Jamison, Louise Gi]l, Ora Mai BaU,
Gertrude Vaughn, Ollie Mai Overall, H. E. Baker, Ella Tarpley. Herbert Well
Anna Stockard, Alice Rooker, Gordon Davis, Elizabeth Smith, Bessie Seward,
46
Delay, Mary Elizabeth Blankenship, Mary Kelton, Maggie 1-cc Knox, Gladys
Jones, Clara Harris, Kathleen liar r-is, Estelle Tilford, Mrs. B. Brandon,
Mrs. Mark Womack, Kate Ashley, Annell Smith, Ruth Allen, Bessie Baskett.e,
Sallie Dement, Mrs. T.G. Harris, Mr. Russell, Mrs. Putman, Mrs. Mamie
Youree, Mrs. Pauline Atkerson, Mrs. J.D. Roberts, Mrs. Azilee Moore,
Mrs. Charles Tilford, Mrs. Sue Clift, William Key, R.D. Barrett, Mrs.
Drayer, Jimmie Tvme, Mrs. Em.mett Wood, Mrs. Fannie Murphy, Mrs.
William Money, Mrs. Simon Glanton; Mrs. Levoy Bivins, Mrs. Pack Barrett,
Richard Tune, Sonya Sample. The teachers names are not listed in the order
of their service, nor the teachers with whom others taught because complete
ijiformation is not available. Every effort was made to get a complete list
of the teachers who taught at Bethel down through the years, but this was a
difficult task. Perhaps some who read this will think of other names that
should be on the list.
Bethel school, like many other rural schools, was as a golden thread
in a tapestry, iaterwoven in other historical events of the county. A direct
outcome of the buildings of pioneer days, it was a development and a continuou,
part of the pattern from the b-ginning until its close. The struggles and accor
plishments of the school closely parallels the progress of the community in its
other respects. The community has grown from a tiny hamlet to typical rural
area which continues to grow v/ith many new homes already constructed and
plans being made for further development.
&#8226;Although it had been operated only on an elementary basis. Bethel School
hardened and strenghtened by the travail of its birth could have continued to be
a living, pulsating, vibrant part of an expanding community, as an elementary
47
school, and inet the needs of a progressive people had it been given the oppor-tunity
and the support and maintenance it needed. However, those not intorestc
brought about its downfall. Although many now homes and two new churches
have been added to Bethel Communiiy, one important link has been destroyed,
the neighborhood school which had t personal interest in its children, the
citizens of the future who are being drawn from its boundaries. The Communit
Club meets within the confines of its v/alls, and it is used as a voting precinct,
but the school that stood for more than 150 years has been destroyed. It was
closed while maintaining an average attendance of 100 pupils.
One of the citizens of the community, Mrs. Evelyn Primin, when she
was interviewed and give helpful information on different phases of the com-munity
history, summed it up so beautifully regarding Bethel School when she
said: "There are no outstanding characters who went to school at Bethel,
so far as I knov/, but I do know that no school in the county has contributed
more to the welfare or betterment of a community, or provided any higher
type citizens than our Bethel School".
The date of another school in the community, the old Sulphur Springs -
school, cannot be established. It was located in the eastern edge of Bethel
Community, a few yards north of the present Sulphur Springs Road west of the
present Siegel Road, Part of the building is still standing near the Irvin Bowei
place. Drinlcing water was carried from the old Sulphur Springs.
A teacher who is l&lt;nown to have taught there was George Rice. Among
those known to liave attended school at Sulphur Springs is J. D. Roberts, a
former Register of Rutherford County. Before becoming Register, he bought
large tracts of cedar for F and O Cedar Piling Company in Murfreesboro.
48
Others kno\VTi to have attended this school are Arie Knox and other mem-bers
of the Carroll Knox family, and Lucy and Jim Miles.
Later the school was taken over by the colored people and was in
operation as late as 1915.
Another colored school in !he community was Antioch School, located
on what is now known as the Joe Brown road, near Antioch church. Some
of the older settlers in this section of the community were Sam Payne, Joe
Jolinson, Mike Gooch, Phil Gooch, Liz Miller, Baldy Scruggs, Caroline
Scruggs, Jack Huddleston, Sallie Huddleston, George Elder, Amanda Elder,
Doc Miles, Henry Kimbro, Harry Ward, Ann Ward, Hosea Brown and Sally
Brown. They were highly respected citizens of the community. Their chil-dren,
grandchildren, and possibly some of their great grandchildren, attended
school at Antioch. Among teachers who taught there were Annie Gooch, who
later became Mrs. G. W, Hampton, and George Hampton.
OUTSTANDING EVENTS
March 28, 1902 all of the western section of Bethel-Leana community
was flooded from torrential rains upstream on west fork of Stones River,
which caused the river to rise at a rapid rate, so fast, in fact, the river
crossed itself at least three times and flooded many homes. The flood of
1902 has been remembered and discussed by many people over the more than
70 years since it occurred.
A tornado came through this section in 1908, tearing up timber and a
few small buildings. Ward's mill was piled up on the banks of Stones River.
One citizen remembers his grandfather making fishing poles from the
49
sap wood of cedar destroyed by tho tornado. They made good polos and were
used for years and years. After each fishing trip, the poles had to be greased
with axle- grease, or something to make them pliant, so they would bend
without splitting when used.
STORES
The first store known to have been in the community was built by Billie
Smith, sometime before the turn of the century. It stood just west of the house
owned by Mr. and Mrs. Elmer Dickerson. At his death the store was sold to
Jim Burnette, who operated it for a number of years. Mr. Burnett built
a new store across the road. The stock was sold to Frank White and later
repossessed.
In 1919, Mr. Burnett sold to Mr. and Mrs. T. W. Cox, who operated
the only grocery store in the community for a number of years, until Mr.
Houston Fann opened a small store in the triangle across the road. After
Mr. Cox's death, Mrs. Cox kept the store for a few years then sold to Mr.
Fann. Tho store and its contents was destroyed by fire, and Mr. Fann
again operated a store in the triangle, about where Tri-Way Market is located
Jim Burris, a black man, had a store about 1912-1914 on the southeast -
comer of what was then Miles and Sulphur Springs Road, now Shacklett and
Sulphur Springs Road.
Mr. and Mrs. John B. Jones had a store for a brief time, some time
in the early 1920's. It was near where Mrs. Frank Clifton lives.
In 1945, Mr. and Mrs. Brandon King built a store across from Bethel
School and sold it the same year to Mr. Evans, who operated it for awhile.
50
His brother v/as also operator of the store for awhile. Others operating
this store \rere Rt A. Patrick, Euford Hayes, and Ernest Tomberlain, Avho
is the present owner.
POST-OFFICE
For several years people of the community had to go to Florence
Station to get their mail. Neighbors altex'nated days in bringing mail for
the community.
About 1880 a Star Route was started from Florence. Mail was delivered
to each farm occupant Vv'ho furnished a box. The route in tMs community
extended from the river up Sulphur Springs to present Swamp Road, thence
to Central Valley Road. A star route carrier would also deliver mail to ^
Walter Hill and Lascassas and return. I^eana was on the return pickup.
Mail was carried back io Florence and from there by train to its destination.
About this time a postoffice was established, called Leana. It was in
Billie Smith's store. He was postmaster during the entire time the postoffice
existed.
A Rural Route v/as started around 1901-02. It was route 7 out of
Murfreesboro, la.ter changed to route 4. Mail carriers were W.L. Millins,
Charles H. Holmes, John E. Rooker, and Mrs. Roxie B. Jenkins, present
carrier.
COMMERCIAL ENTERPRISES
Gristmill:
A gristmill was operated on the community line between Bethel-Leana
and Florence, on Stones River, where people from both communities carried
corn and wheat to be ground. It was Icnown f s Jim Ward Mill. Mr. Ward
51
oold to Major Street, who transferred it to David and George PJvans. They
operated the mill for several years then sold to T. J. Lassiter. After
operating the mill for a few years, Mr. Lassiter sold to J. E. Nice and son.
From this time on it was known as Nice's Mill, where feed, as well as
corn and w^heat, was ground. It became a landmark in the community. People
have come from miles ai'ound to fish at Nice's mill. The mill was burned
down in October 1965, but it continues to be a popular fishing spot. On
the Bethel-Leana side a space has been paved for parking of cars and campers.
Sawmills:
First sawmill laiown about was operated by a Mr. Shaw, run by
traction engine. Watei' to make stea.m was pumped from sinking creek.
It was on the Sam Mitchell farm, near where the br-idge on Thompson Lane
crosses the creek. At this mill a man by the name of Nathaniel Allen, better
known as Nat Allen, lost his life by being pulled into the saw by accident.
This mill was moved to Manor Cave vSpring in another community. As for
other mills, it is not known how they came in order of service.
Mr, Knox Ridley owned a mill on the Cas Miles farm, almost in front
oftlieA. C. Shacklett farm.
Amos Culbertson had a mill on part of the J. E, Stockird farm. Water
for operation came from the blue hole or Bear Wallow. Jim Oliver and his
sons operated a niill at the same location. Later Oliver bros. had a jnill
just south of the present Robert i^ane Home. Water was pumped from Bethel
pond, which at one time was a rather large body of water,
Charlie, Jesse, Thompson and Jimmy Ward also operated a sawmill
on the J. E. Stockird farm. It was known as Ward Bros, sawmjill.
52
Blacksmith shops :
A blacksmith shop was owned and operated by T. A. Stockird, and was
almost in front of Mr. and Mrs. Elmer Dickerson's home, as we know it
today. Mr. Robert Wrather moved into the community and operated a shop
at the same location. He bought a small farm on the Swamp Road, across
from where Mr. and Mrs. Robert Jenkins live, and moved his blacksmith
shop there. He also had a repair shop for buggies, wagons, and carts. His
son, Jesse, made hickory pipes for sale.
Cotton Gins:
A cotton gin was built about 1870-75, operated by J. E. Stockird sons,
and grandsons, with help of farm labor, and continued in operation until
1885. It stood about halfway between the homes of Tommy Reed and Charlie
Ross, as we know the location today. The drum used at the gin was later
converted into a well windless and is still in use.
For many years Bethel-Leana was largely a farming community but when
industry came to Murfreesboro and Rutherford County many have forsaken
the farms. Some of the farm land has been put in the Soil Bank; some sold
to companies for the development of housing projects; other land has been
allowed to grow up unattended while the owners answer the call to public works.
The little community has come from North Carolina land grants of densely
covered forest land to a prosperous community only a few miles from the
heart of Tennessee.
On the west boundary of the community, a bridge spans the waters of
Stones River, a bridge that has stood for many years. It met the needs of
53
the people when it was finally built 65 years ago and buggies and wagons
were the vehicles used for travel. A citizen of the community remembers
working on the approach to the bridge when he was 13 years old, and drove
one of the first wagons to cross the bridge.
Today the narrow wooden bridge attached to the rickety frame work
causes people to hold their breath or almost skip a heart beat when they start
across the bridge for fear they will not reach the other side in safety. Some
even avoid the road because a narrow and unsafe bridge docs not meet the
needs of a growing community. One wonders why the county will allow a
community to continue using such a dangerous structure.
CEMETERIES
The early settlers who left their native land and chose this part of the
country in which to make their homes were laid to rest beneath the soil of
their chosen land, as were many of their descendants. Below are listed
the cemeteries that could be located. So many of the graves are not marked,
and some of the engraving is not legible;
I - Lindsey family cemetery, near the Lindsay hoine:
1. Caleb Lindsey
b. April 27, 1763, in County of Granville, N.C.
d. Dec. 25, 1838
2. Mrs. Temperance Lindsey, wife of Caleb Lindsey
b. April 1, 1781
d. Feb. 12, 1862
3. Rev. Joseph Lindsey
b. April 4, 1804
d. Oct. 28, 1869
4. Miss Salfy Lindsey
b. Feb. 28, 1761, in Granville, N.C.
d. Oct. 10, 1841, age 81 years, 7 mo. , and 12 days
5. Elizabeth, consort of C. D. Cooper
b. June 28, 1815, in Granville County, N.C.
d. June 25, 1839
54
8.
Dudley House Lindsay
b. May 22, 1803
d. July 7, 1859
Daniel McKalister
b. Feb. 3, 1791
d. Aug. 28, 1851
Dr. W. Henderson Cooper
b. Dec. 23, 1836
d. July 10, 1866
Lewis Sims
b . unknown
d . unknown
II. Slave graveyard of Joseph Lindsey, near the family plot
L Gabriel 18. Ginney
2. Solomen 19. Sam
3. Mat 20. Eliza, her son
4. Caroline 21. Govenor Fox
5. Sally and her two children 22. Joice
6. Hagar 23. Harriett
7. Lucy 24. Issa
8. Bird 25. Charlotte
9. Bob 26. Ellen, one of Nancy's twins
10. BHly 27. Texanna
11. Tim( 28. Peter
12. Leane 29. Catherine
13. Siney 30. Nancy
14. Kit 31. Cader
15. Tim 32. Granville
16. Lige 33. AHie
17. Hanner
Joseph Lindsey specified in his will that neither the family nor the slave
gravej'ard was to be sold or molested in any way.
III. Mitchell graveyard, on a knoll just east of Thompson Lane
1. William Mitchell
b. unknown
d. 1850
2. Wife of William Mitchell
b. July 3, 1773
d. April 7, 1828
3. Curry
b. 1735
d. 1835
4. Azariah Mitchc]!
b. June 6, 1806
d. Oct. 22, 1855
5. Malenia Mitchell
b. June 6, 1800
d. Mar. 19, 1883
55
There are other markers in this cemetery but names and dates are not
readable.
4. Wade cemetery, on Mordici Wade farm
1. Mordici Burgess Wade
b. April 28, 1800
d. Oct. 30, 1867
2. Martha A. Wade, his wife
b. July 5, 1818
d. Sept. 10, 1863
Children of Richard W. and Narcissa Neal Wade
1. Cora Ann Wade
b. .Tune 15, 1845
d. Sept. 6, 1851
2. Alice Josephine Wade
b. June 12, 1847
d. Dec. 4, 1858
3. John Summerfield
b. April 13, 1850
d. Sept. 6, 1855
4. Child born and died March 30, 185 6
5. Wade cemeterjs on F. B. Arms farm
1. Col. William Wade
b. Jan. 1, 1763
d. July 31, 1849
2. Cassandra Wade, consort of Col. Wade
b. Jan. 18, 1769
d. Feb. 6, 1820
3. Caroline vVatkins, dau. of Wm. and Cassandra Wade, Consort of
b. Aug. 22, 1812 W. L. Watkins
d. Nove. 23, 1849
4. Caroline, infant dau. of Col. W.L. Watkins and Caroline W. Watkins
b. Nov. 12, J849
d. July 31, 1850
5. John C. Wade
b. Aug. 20, 1788
d. Dec. 26, 1855
6. Ann Wade
b. 1788
d. Oct. 26, 1828
7. Robert O. Wade
b. April 13, 1823
d. June 27, 1844
8. William Wade, son of Col. Wm. Wade
b. Oct. 26, 1811
d. July 27, 1850
9. Col. W. L. Watkins
b. March 16, 1802, in Montgomery Co. , Maryland
d. Nov. 15, 1861
5 6
10. Rebecca O. Miller
b. Nov. 10, 1802. in Maryland
d. Aug. 1, 1858
6. Wade slave graveyard, on R uss Stockard place -"
Martin Wade is the only person buried there whose name is known.
7. Johns Hall, just outside the community line, back of Hoyte Sanford farm.
1. Lucy Collier
2. Ben Collier
3. Joe Johns
4. Bettie Lou Johns
5. Harry Ward
6. Ann Ward
7. Milton Ward
8. Alice Ward Brown
9. Gracie Ward Brown
10. Nimrod Ward
11. Lou Minti Wade
12. Harry Ward, Jr.
8. Allen graveyard, on John Allen farm.
1. Sally Allen
2. Ella Allen Mothershed
3. Nat Allen
4. Mrs. J. J. Allen
5. Infant Allen
6. Susie Allen Johns
7. Mr. J. J. Allen
There are no markers, but these people are thought to be buried in this
cemetery.
9. Bethel cemetery
1. Daniel Cunningham
b. Jan. 29, J829
d. June 30, 1899
2. Amanda Cunningham
b. Sept. 4, 1837
d. Aug. 27, 1905
3. Mary Oliver
b. 1851
d. 1925
4. Charity Manor
b. Sept. 10, 1828
d. Jan. 12, 1892
5. Sara F. Edwards Pitts
b. June 27, 1862
d. Feb. 12, 1951
6. Willie Estes
b. May 23, 1902
d. May 22, 1969
57
7. Edward A. Barrett
b. Oct. 16, 1893
d. Dec. 15, 1918
8. Grant Riddle
b. May 12, 1876
d. Dec. 30, 1957
9. Doug Taylor
b. 1880
d. 1955
10. Ernest Finch, Sr.
b. July 11, 1926
d. Oct. 21, 1964
11. Abby Palmer
b. 1899
d. 1910
12. J. R. Palmer
b. 1865
d. 1925
13. Joseph McAbee
b. June 8. 1888
d. July 23, 1905
14. Helen Louise Barrett
b. Aug. 15, 1928
d. May 19, 1941
15. Billie Ray Barrett
b. 1939
d. 1940
16. Charles (an infant)
b. 1937
17. Charles C Barrett
b. Oct. 4, 1888
d. Apr. 9, 1961
18. Annie L. Barrett
Feb. 19, 1908
19. Roger Dale Barrett
b. March 21, 1950
d. May 8, 1950
20. Margaret L. Jones
b. 1928
d. 1930
21. Larkin Maize
22. Jane Russell Maize
23. John Mays (no dates for the last three names)
24. Clarence McAbee, Jr.
b. Dec. 7, 1923
d. Dec. 28, 1928
25. Edward Riley Marlin
b. 1833
d. 1888
58
26. Oliver Bari-ett
b. Feb. 18, 1901
d. May 25, 1957
27. B. B. Barrett
28. Fannie O. Barrett (no dates on last two)
29. Oscar Barrett
b. Oct. 16, ]880
d. Dec. 26, ]948
30. James R. Jones
1937
31. Lois M. Jones
1941
32. Margie B. Jones
b. 1908
d. 1941
33. Ritter Jones
1953
34. Robert (Bud) Jones
b. 1871
d. 1954
35 . Baby Cantrell (no dates)
36. Betty Brimm (no dates)
37. William B. Brimm (no dates)
38. Kate Jones (no dates)
40. Sally T.e Grande (no dates)
41. J. J. Taylor
b. June 10, 1888
d. Feb. 22, 1928
42. Robert Williams
1935
43. Henry Barrett
b. 1869
d. 1939
44. Addie Williams
b. March 17, 1902
d. Aug. 17, 1960
45. James Noah McAbee
b. Feb. 29, 1885
d. Nov. 7, 195 6
46. Annie Laurie McAbee
b. March 17, 1887
d. June 23, 1956
47. Mrs. Martha Sloan
b. 1882
d. 1946
48. Verla Brinkley
b. Ma7 29, 1954
d. May 29, 1965
5 9
49. Mrs. Lizzie Thompson, wifeofD.W. Thompson
b. 1893
d. March 10, 1920
50. J. L. McCullam
March 12, age 31 years
51. Harold McCullam (no dates)
52. Mrs. Maroam McCullam (no dates)
53. Beulah Wade
73 years
54. WUliam Wade
1885 - 93 years
55. Nancy Riddle
b. Aug. 3, 1959, age 19 years
56. Estes (no dates)
57. Neil Richard Brewer, infant, March 12, 1963
58. Larry Wayne Brewer
Sept. 17, 1956
59. Vickie Diane McAfee, no dates
60. Bettie Lee McAfee, no dates
61. Mattie H. Warren
b. 1902
d. 1930
62. Hazel Mai Barrett
b. March 19, 1922
d. May 8, 1937
63. Robert B. Wrather
b. July 16, 1847
d. March 1920
64. Bettie Jones Wrather, his wife
b. 1857
d. April 4, 1940
65. Virginia Lee Wrather, died in infancy
b. Sept. 9, 1931
d. Sept. 9, 1931
10. Bowman slave graveyard, in front of Bethel schoolhouse
11. MacGowan slave graveyard, on MacGowan property
12. MacGowan- Stockird family cemetery
1. Ebenezer MacGowan
b. Feb. 17, 1767
d. April 30, 1850
2. Frances MacGowan
b. Oct. 6, 1781
d. Oct. 5, 1852
3. James Elliott Stockird
b. Sept. 9, 1817
d. April 27, 1895
4. Lucy B. Stockird
b. Nov. 22, 1818
d. April 28,1866
60
5. Leonora Russworm Stockird
b. Jan. 4, 1833
d. Sept. 1, 1905
6. Mary (no dates) thought to be a servant of the family
7. Ann G. , wife of William C. Fletcher
b. May 21, 1813
d. Sept. 25, 1850
8. Lucy Ann, infant daughter of W. C. and Ann G. Fletcher
b. Sept. 4, 1847
d. Oct. 10,1848
9. Nanc F. , infant daughter of James E. and Lucy B. Stockird
b. July 8, 1857
d. Dec. 29, 1858
10. Mary Ann Stockird
b. June 7, 1847
d. Feb. 14, 1872
11. William E. Stockird, Jr. , age 6 mo. and 4 days
12. William E. Stockird, Sr.
b. Nov. 18, 1844
d. Mar. 28, 1869
13. James E. Stockird, Jr.
b. June 7, 1851
d. Aug. 1, 1871
14. William B. MacGowan
b. Oct. 9, 1817
d. Aug. 24, 1848
15. Sgt. J. W. Bowman, Co. 'K', 8th Regt. Tenn. Cav. , C.S.A.
16. Members of the Dismukes and Russworm families:
1. Sally Clark Russworm, 1799-1867
2. Rosalind Russworm , 1835-1915
3. Lockie Russworm Dismukes, 1843-1902
4. Zack T. Dismukes, 1846-1910
5. Ernest Jordan Dismukes, 1880-1893
6. Sally Dismukes 1876-1896
7. Hattie Dismukes Smith, 1873-1935
8. Harry Smith, ]855-1935
17. Capt. T.E.S. Russworm, 9 Regt. Ward S, Tenn. Cav., C.S.A.
b. April 8, 1820
d. Oct. 10, 1873
18. Capt. Samuel C. Russworm, 17 Regt. , Miss. Inf., C.S.A.
b. Feb. 25, 1837
b. Aug. 28, 1866
19. In memory of those buried in unnnarked graves
1. Benjamin M. Hunt, 1849-1897
2. SammieA. Hunt, 1882-1911
3. James W. Hunt, 1847-1911
4. Martha Stockird Hunt, 1849-1930
And all other unmarked graves.
61
13. Elliott Cemetery
1. Elenor Elliott Arnold
b. Dec. 28, 1797
d. Jan. 8. 1860
2. James Elliott
b. Oct. 1, 1795
d. Oct. 30, 1836
3. William Elliott
b. 1798
d. Sept. 18, 1835
4. Deborah Elliott, born in North Carolina
b. ?
d. March 9, 1829
5. Jane Elliott Stockird
b. ?
d. 1866
6. Mary Elliott Smith
7. Capt. William Smith
8. Jack Jones
9. Mrs. Jack Jones (no dates found for the above named)
14. Elder graveyard, north of Shacklett Road on Patton property
1. George Elder
2. Amanda Elder
3. John Elder
4. Eliza Akin Elder
15. Miles slave graveyard, south of Reece Hays house
16. Henry Kimbro graveyard, just west of Buckeye Valley Road
1. Henry Kimbro is only name known but others are buried here.
17. Jack Huddleston burying ground, Northwest of Antioch church
1. Jack Huddleston
2. Sallie Huddleston, his wife
3. Anderson Huddleston (son)
4. Hosea Brown
5. SiiUie Brown, his wife
18. Gooch cemetery, jcjins Huddleston cemetery
1. Mike Gooch
2. His wife, and other members of his family
19. Joe Brown cemetery, on Joe Brown's place.
1. Charity B. Collier
2. Her sister
3. Anderson Brown, and others
The above six named are col. cemeteries. Information was given
by members of the families. Information on Johns Hall cemetery given
by James B. Ward
20. Ward cemetery, this cemetery is a short distance over the line, in the
edge of Florence community, but most of the people buried here
were members of Bethel Church, and participated in community
affairs.
62
1. Sara Ann Agnes Shreader Neville
2. Best Ward, died at age 24
3. Mrs. Jarrell, daughter of Sara Ann Agnes Neville
4. Letitia Neville, died as a young lady
5. William (Billie) Miller
b. Nov. 15, 1872
d. Jan. 9. 1886
6. Martha Elizabeth Miller Baskette
b. Feb. 15, 1871
d. Dec. 4, 1908
7. Thomas Miller
b. Dec. 31, 1836
d. Mar. 1, 1914
8. Amanda Ward Miller
b. Sept. 22, 1843
d. June 12, 1912
9. Mary Ward Martin
10. Sara Ann Agnes Neville Ward
b. 1819
d. at age 91
11. Bettie Ward
b. ?
d. May 1922, age 74 years
12. Harriett A. Ward
13. Fannie Sherrell
14. James Ward
</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Cemeteries; General stores; Land grants--Tennessee--Rutherford County; Public schools; Roads -- Tennessee -- Rutherford County; Rutherford County (Tenn.) -- History</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Bethel-Leana</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>133 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-01</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication08ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/108</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>