<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>From Helen Hunt Jackson to John Crowe Ransom: Organized literary interest expressed by the women of Murfreesboro, 1887 - 1945</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Adams, Julie A.</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 26</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1986</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1880-1889; 1890-1899; 1900-1909; 1910-1919; 1920-1929; 1930-1939; 1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>47
FROrV\ HELEN HUNT JACKSON TO JOHN CROWE RANSOM
ORGANIZED LITERARY INTEREST EXPRESSED BY THE
WOMEN OF MURFREESBORO, 1887-1945
By
Julie A. Adams
Helen Hunt Jackson's popular novel Ramona inspired
the formation of a literary society in 1887, "The Helen
Hunt Jackson Reading Club," It evolved into the "Library
2 Association of Murf reesboro" two years later, and even-tually,
through a strong desire to provide a permanent
home for its 2,000 volumes, became incorporated with the
3 Woman's Club of Murf reesboro in 1916. The apex of this
literary excitement shone brightly in the 1924 lecture
series. Among distinguished speakers was Dr. John
4 Crowe Ransom, future "Fugitive Poet." The committment to
quality life, filled with cultural achievement and civic
improvement, expressed by these women from 1887 to 1945
can be viewed in the developments that follow.
How might one judge the beginnings of a reading
club that was initiated by twelve women, each responsible
for acquiring one book? VJhat was essentially a modest
birth, was so enthusiastically nurtured, that in only
twenty-seven years, the circulation reached 2,000--for
a quarter of a century, the sole library in Murf reesboro.
48
Will Allen Dronqoole, a local author, donated some
of the original twelve books in 1887. The members of
the "Helen Hunt Jackson Reading Club" resolved to start a
public library from these books. The first step was to
secure a home for the collection. An empty counter in
the rear of a bookstore, then in the name of "Booker Smith
Bookstore" served the purpose. The space was rent-free,
and early dues v/ere fifty cents.
The move to Mason Court, on the corner of Main and
Church Streets necessitated an increase in dues to one
dollar, as rent was required. Captain Richard Bear
occupied a room, and rented the back office to the
library.
The library officially becam.e "The Library Associa-tion
of Murf reesboro" in 1889. Soon after, in June of
1890, Miss Kate Fowler received a letter. . . .
My dear Miss Fowler,
I have received your note informing me
that I have been made an Honorary member of
the Murfreesboro Library Association.
It is a compliment which I very greatly
appreciate and I beg to express my sincere
thanks
.
Your truely, _
Mary N. Murfree
Undoubtedly the association was in turn flattered to be
recognized by the local author, writing under the
penname Charles Egbert Craddock.
49
A catalogue was published in 1892. Approximately
560 books were in circulation at that time, including
novels, biographies, poetry, history, essays, and
periodicals. The organization was administered by five
officers and an executive committee. In 1892 the women
who functioned in this capacity were:
President&#8212;Miss Addie Ledbetter
1st Vice-president&#8212;Mrs. S. E. Spence
2nd Vice-president&#8212;Mrs. J. F. Fowler
Secretary--Miss Kate Fowler
Treasurer--Mrs . R. W. Vickers
Executive Committee: Mrs. Dewitt Smith
Miss Amanda Curran
Miss Currer Wendel
Miss Florence Nuckols
Miss Thenie McLemore
Mrs. Walter Fox
Subscribers were entitled to check out one book at a time,
and non-subscribers were granted the same option,
although they were expected to deposit the value of the
book while it was borrowed. Subscriptions were one
dol lar
.
The collection relocated a third time, to an
upstairs room over Vickers Drug Store, "between the banks.
Rent was free, and at that time funds were obtained from
the sale of a tenant house. Circulation soared to 2,000,
13 and bookcases were purchased.
The library was incorporated in May, 1911. Mrs.
S. E. Spence, Mrs. G. S. Smith, Mrs. R, W. Vickers, Mrs.
Dewitt Smith, and Miss Currer Wendel were the five
&#8222;12
50
women responsible for the charter and maintenance of a
circulating library for the benefit of the citizens of
Rutherford County. The energy behind the rapid
development of the association is attributed primarily to
the leadership of Mrs. R. W. Vickers and Mrs. Dewitt
Smith. There were hopes for a Carnegie library, but a
destructive cyclone in 1913 shattered these plans by
dem.olishing the housing situation, and lowering the funds
of the members. Although the library was clearly an
established institution, its physical status was
vulnerable
.
It was this concern for a substantial library
facility that prompted the formation of a woman's club.
The Library Association, the United Daughters of the
Confederacy, and the Suffrage League were all in need of
a meeting place. Representatives met in December, 1915
at the home of Mrs. W. A. Ransom, to discuss the idea of
renting a suite of rooms. "It was suggested that women
outside of the organizations represented by invited to
join a woman's club, dues to be one dollar per year."
In January 1916, a second conference was held in
Mrs. H. L. Fox's apartment in the Masonic Building. Two
rooms had been rented here, for $13 a month. The Woman's
Club used one room, the Library the other. The U. D. C.
51
and the Suffrage League had become members by paying their
proportionate share of the rent, "and enough individuals
had enlisted to make up the amount. "'' Mrs. E. B.
Earthman was elected first president of the Woman's Club.
There is considerable question as to whether the
books were moved to the Masonic Building. There is a
reference to a transfer from Vicker's Drug Store, to the
Woman's Club Building. "^^ The Woman's Club was to have a
grand new home.
The opportunity was at hand to purchase a club
building. In March, 1916, Mrs. R. W. Vickers reported
to the club, with three proposals. Two options entailed
purchasing lots, one for $1,100 and the other for
19
$1,500. The alternative that met the most approval,
however, was the chance of buying the J. M. Haynes home
on College Street. The price was $6,125, and on "easy
terms &#8222;20
.
Mrs. Vicker's peers proclaimed she had a head for
business, and that indeed proved to be true. With the
aid of a blackboard, the plan for purchase was revealed.
There were to be one hundred charter members, each contri-buting
ten dollars. The women would then be grouped into
ten subcommittees, each responsible for raising fifty
dollars. "All were enthusiastic and wanted to buy the
52
home. They asked Mrs. Vickers to send a telegram at once
to Mrs. Haynes, then in Florida, accepting her price for
the house .
"
The Woman s Club was incorporated July 22, 1916. 22
A down payment of twelve hundred and fifty dollars in cash
was rendered to Mrs. Miriam B. Haynes, and the remainder
was arranged to be paid in nine notes of five hundred
dollars each, payable through March, 1926. The Library
Association donated three hundred dollars at the onset
provided that the library would be housed in the new
building. This was by far the largest amount contributed
23 by any group. These transactions were made September 9,
1916.
The first meeting in the new club house was
January 3, 1917. The building was paid for in five
years instead of ten, and as Mrs. Vickers said, "Without
a man lifting his hand to help, and the men saying all
24 the time it couldn't be done."
By-laws were published in 1917, stating the object
of the organization as follows:
To aid and encourage the social recreation,
literary culture, and moral, intellectual
and social development of its members, and
to promote the moral, intellectual, and
social improvement of the community and to
take part in philnthropic LgicJ7 work; and
to this end the said corporation may hold
53
meetings, give lectures, and entertainments of
social, literary, musical or other character,
and may charge entrance or admission fees to
those wishing to attend such meetings or
entertainments, do catering, and maintaining
and care for a library. 25
One means of rising to meet such objectives was
through the work of the civic committee. In some old
minutes it was noted that Mrs. Vickers moved that the
club members urge that all "horns of automobiles be
2 fi silenced during church hours, as a civic improvement."
Other projects had long-term impact on the city of
Murf reesboro.
An extremely active year for the Civic Committee
was 1919-1920. "Clean-up Campaign Spring 1920" was
number one on the agenda. Efforts were made to make the
community aware of beautif ication concern. "... Posters
and moving pictures on sanitation and on beautif ication
of the city were used with splendid results, which were
27 commended by the county physican." A subcommittee,
chaired by Mrs. Malhon Brown, co-operated with city
officials in "investigating and improving conditions in
the slums, and with good results urged screening in
28 localities where it was most needed." It is rather
difficult to imagine the town the size of Murfreesboro
harboring a slum neighborhood in 1920, and it is
interesting that the Woman's Club would identify such
54
problems. It is commendable that these women encouraged
the use of screen doors and windows. Apparently they
were not yet in common use, and in southern climates
"screening" is a practical luxury.
The primary emphasis that year was the "Great White
Way." Several months were spent persuading the city
commissioners to pave west Main Street, from the Public
Square to the Railroad Station. "The street was almost
impassable, and, in addition to discomfort and incon-venience
which it caused the citizens, created a most
unfavorable impression in strangers. 29 Persistence
paid off--that spring paving was begun. The brightly
lighted "Great White VJay," a parkway running through the
center of West Main, "will be so arranged to insure greater
safety for traffic, and the improvement of this most
frequented throughfare in the city will be of immense
value to the whole county." The club entertained plans
to landscape this parkway.
In 1922-24 the club chose to grade and sod the
courthouse lawn, enclosing it with a hedge. Park benches
were provided, and some thirty trees set out. Later club
members seemed to regret this action, as the hedge was
31 "constantly in need of tending."
55
Education was an aspect of civic concern expressed
through the Educational Committee. The club provided a
loan scholarship fund to assist one student per year in
32 attending Tennessee College. Perhaps their most
important endeavor was an educational conference in June,
1920. Local educational questions were considered. The
symposium was under the supervision of a committee
composed of representatives from Tennessee College, the
Middle Tennessee State Normal School, Murfreesboro city
schools, and the Rutherford County public school, in
co-operation with the "educational department" of the
33 Woman's Club.
The Library Association was also interested in the
cultural development of the city, and brought lecturers
and musicians to Murfreesboro. One of the greatest
attractions was a performance by the Cincinnati Symphony
Orchestra, under the direction of Eugene Vsaye. The
second concert by the orchestra in Murfreesboro was in
34 January, 1921. (The date of their previous appearance is
not recorded in the minutes that are available.)
The years 1920-1922 were grand years for music in
Rutherford County. Camilla Ponsell, Metropolitan opera
star, and Bruno Steindal, violin-cellist, "formerly cello
soloist of the Chicago Symphony Orchestra" delighted the
35 townspeople at recitals sponsored by the Woman's Club.
56
The true nucleus of the Woman's Club was the
library. The collection was housed in its present room,
and administered by the officers and executive committee
until 1923, when Miss Frankie White took charge as the
first librarian.
Prior to Miss White's administration, arrangements
were made to borrow fifty books twice a year, from the
Tennessee State Library. This loan was secured under the
direction of Miss Emma Clayton, chairman of the library
3 8 committee in 1922.
A card index system was installed in 1924--a real
work saver for Miss White, especially since an average
of fifty books were added each year. So far as enlarging
of the collection was concerned, 1926 was a prosperous
year. "120 of the newest and most popular books of the
39 day have been added." In this year also, the library
became a member of the Literary Guild "which furnished each
month a book selected by an eminent literary board as the
best book of that month." 40 It is exceedingly fascinating
to discover what type of reading material appealed at
different phases of history. In the 1930 's, a time of
national depression, the committee chairman reported,
"One has said, 'Tell me the books she reads and I will
read her character.' A marked increase in demand for,
and supply of purer fiction is pre-eminently the
57
4 1 feature of the past years." It is not surprising that
people turn to fantasy for comfort in hard times.
The library continued to grow, and the original
twelve books were all but lost in the shuffle. The
present library is quite a comfortable room, and proudly
displayed beside the fireplace is the desk of Mary Knowles
Murfree. The desk was donated to the club in 1938, by
42 the local U.D.C. chapter.
The cultural attention of the organization was
most admirably expressed in the impressive, and timely
series of literary lectures. These presentations
included dramatic readings, original poetry, literary
critiques, discussions of current events, and recently
written novels. The local citizens willingly offered
their talents, presenting their views on a wide range
of topics. The Negro Theatre, philosophy of John Dewey,
the "new" southern poetry, modern culture in Maylaya,
the pessisism of Schopanhover , athletic dancing, and
arms limitation were all discussed prior to 1930. (For
a detailed account of topics and speakers, refer to
Appendix F.) Murfreesboro was far from being a provincial
vil lage
.
Guest speakers hailed from Minnesota, New York,
and England. A variety of topics, and a distinguished
platform of speakers marks the year 1924. This lecture
58
series alone vocalizes a prevailing interest in the world
beyond Rutherford County. The special events were as
follows:
Dr. Jefferson Harbord of Boston
"Blessed by Humor"
Mrs. Anadell of New York
"Interior Decoration"
Dr. Edwin Mims of Vanderbilt University
"The Fight for Idealism in America"
Dr. John Crowe Ransom of Vanderbilt University
"Best Sellers"
The recognition of John Crowe Ransom, and the
respect for his integrity are most significant. Ransom's
poetry--his life's work, is definitely appreciated in
1980. His association with Robert Penn Warren, Allen
Tate, and other "Fugitive Poets" represents the "Southern
Renaissance" in literature. Some literary critics claim
that the only significant writing in this century was from
the pens of the Southern writers. The movement can be
liberally interpreted on a counter-revolution to
opinions of a decadent South.
Literature in the South was alive and well.
Organizations such as the Woman's Club of Murfreesboro
played an important role in the dissemination of this
cultural heritage.
59
FOOTNOTES
Mrs. Ivan Brown, "Light on the Women's Club
Library," p. 1. Typed, on file at Woman's Club, 221 East
College Street, Murf reesboro, TN
.
2Mrs. E. Jackson, "Orientation Speech" presented to
membership meeting, September 30, 1970. Filing cabinet
upstairs at the Woman's Club.
3 By-Laws of Woman's Club of Murf reesboro, Tenn .
1917 , p. 1, Mrs. Vicker's name on the cover. Files upstairs
4 The Woman's Club of Murf reesboro, Tennessee
Announcements 1922-192 4, Benson Printing Co., Nashville,
TN. Woman's Club Library.
5 "Woman's Club Library Began With 12 Books,"
Rutherford Courier , June 22, 1939, Murf reesboro, TN.
Clipping. Files upstairs.
Mrs. Ivan Brown, "Light . . . ."
Mrs. R. W. Vickers, "History of the Woman's Club"
(Attributed title), signed by Mrs. Vickers. Files
upstairs
.
g
Mrs. E. Jackson, "Orientation Speech."
9 Letter to Miss Kate Fowler, Murf reesboro,
Tennessee, from Mary N. Murfree, June 5, 1890. Files
upstairs
.
Catalogue&#8212;1892, Murfreesboro Library Association ,
org. 1889 , News Print, 1892. Green pamphlet approximately
6" X 3". Files upstairs.
^ &#8226;'"Catalogue&#8212;1892 ....
12
Mrs. Ivan Brown, "Light . . . ."
13 Mrs. R. W. Vickers, "History . . . ."
14 "Certificate of Registration," State of Tennessee,
Department of State, May 27, 1911. Files upstairs.
60
15Mrs. Ivan Brown, "Light . . . .," files upstairs;
"Woman's Club Library . . . ."
Mrs. J. B. Black, "Beginnings of the Woman's Club
Library," Paper presented to membership meeting February 20,
1961. Typed. Files upstairs.
Mrs. J. B. Black, "Beginnings . . . ."
1
8
Mrs. J. B. Black, "Beginnings . . . ."
19 Mrs. J. B. Black, "Beginnings . . . ."
20
Mrs. J. B. Black, "Beginnings . . . ."
21
Mrs. J. B. Black, "Beginnings . . . ."
22Mrs. J. B. Black, "Beginnings . . . ."
23
Mrs. Ivan Brown, "Light . , , ,"
24
Mrs. J. B. Black, "Beginnings . . . ."
By-Laws ....
Mrs. J. B. Black, "Beginnings . . . ."
27 The Woman's Club of Murf reesboro, Tennessee
Announcements, 1919-1920 , Benson Printing Co., Nashville,
TN. Woman's Club Library.
^^The Woman's Club . . . 1919-1920.
29The Woman's Club . ., . 1919-1920.
The Woman's Club . ., . 1919-1920.
3 1 Mrs. J. B. Black, "Beginnings . . . ."
&#8226;^^The Woman's Club . . . 1919-1920 .
&#8226;^&#8226;^ The Woman's Club . . . 1919-1920 .
The Woman's Club of Murf reesboro Tennessee
Announcements 1922-1924 , Benson Printing Co., Nashville.
Woman's Club Library. '.&#8226;.'&#8226;'
61
^^The Woman's Club . . . 1922-1924 .
^^Mrs. R. W. Vickers, "History . . . ."
3 7 Mrs. Ivan Brown, "Light ....
&#8226;^^The Woman's Club . . . 1922-1924 .
&#8226;^^ Announcements The Woman's Club Murf reesboro ,
Tennessee, 1924-1926 , Publisher not known. Woman's Club
Library.
"^^Announcements The Woman's Club Murfreesboro
Tennessee, 1926-1928 , Publisher not known. Woman's Club
Library.
Announcements The Woman's Club Murfreesboro ,
Tennessee"^ 1928-1930, Publisher not known. Woman's C 1 ub
Library.
4'2 &#8226; Mrs. Ivan Brown, "Light ....
"^&#8226;^The woman's Club . . . 1922-1924.
62
APPENDIX A
Helen Hunt Jackson Reading Club Members
(prior to 1889)
Mrs. W. D. Robinson
Mrs. J. T. B. Wilson
Miss Susie Weakley (Mrs. Eph Lytle)
Mrs. William Wendel
Miss Currer Wendel
Miss Kate Fowler (Mrs. George Cranor)
Miss Lorena Nelson
Mrs. John Nelson
Miss Ross
Miss Lizzie Woods (Mrs. R. W. Vickers)
Miss Maggie Muirhead
Miss Emma Clayton
Miss Carrie Hancock
Mrs. Nuckols
Miss Lovie Eakin (Mrs. George Howse)
Mrs. E. Smith
Mrs. J. T. Rather
Mrs. Dewitt Smith
Mrs. Babb
Miss Dill
Miss Fannie Wade
Miss Janie Murfree
Miss Belle Baird
Mrs. W. Y. Elliot
Miss J. A. Eliot
Miss Addie Ledbetter
"Woman's Club Library Began With 12 Books,"
Rutherford Courier , June 22, 1939, Murf reesboro, TN,
Clipping.
APPENDIX B
63
$10.00 Members, 1917
Avent, Mrs. James
Brown, Mrs. Mahlon
Butler, Mrs. Jim
Bilbro, Mrs. V^J. C.
Butler, Mrs. John
Batey, Mrs. Forrest
Beesley, Mrs. Jesse
Burnett, Mrs. George
Covington, Mrs. C.
Cox, Mrs. Chas.
Covington, Mrs. L. L.
Cawthen, Mrs. Chas.
Cox, Mrs. John
Collier, Mrs. Carmine
*Clayton, Miss Emma
*Cranor, Mrs. George
Cason, Mrs. George
Darrom, Mrs. George
arrom, Georc
ann, Mrs. Lester
jtton. Miss
Da _
Dann, Dutton, Earthman, Mrs. W. B
Elam, Mrs. Tom
Fox, Mrs. Lee
Fletcher, Mrs. Jim
Gillentine, Mrs. L. S
Goldstein, Mrs. David
Ge
fox, F'letcher, Sillentine, S
Goldstein, Davie
3ebers, Mrs. Hans
Gilbert, Mrs. Fred
Gresham, Mrs. Will
Giltner, Mrs. G. B.
Hooper, Mrs. Ed
Howse, Mrs. George
Huggins, Mrs. Camillus
Hale, Mrs. Water
Hale, Mrs. Lura
Huggins, Mrs. Jesse
Hancock, Miss Essie
Ivie, Mrs. Tom
Jones, Mrs. R. L.
Jones, Mrs. E. H.
Jordan, Mrs. Mattie
Kerr, Mrs. H. H.
King, Mrs. Albert
Ledbetter, Mrs. D. L.
Lytle, Mrs. R. L.
Love, Mrs. Clifford
Licker, Mrs. Sam
*Lytle, Mrs. Eph
Leach, Mrs. Rae
Murfree, Mrs. Matt
McKnight, Mrs. E. C.
McClain, Mrs. A. H. J.
Morns, Mrs. W. A.
Miller, Mrs. P. R.
Mitchell, Mrs. Sam
Manson, Mrs. J. E.
Murfree, Mrs. Bettie
Maugan, Mrs. D. L.
Manson, Mrs. Will
McAdoo, Miss Edgar
Marshall, Mrs. J. K.
Nelson, Mrs. John
*Nelson, Miss Lorena
Nelson, Miss Mary
Nelson, Mrs. Cora B.
Overall, Mrs. Marcy
Potter, Mrs. Tom
Partee, Mrs. C. F.
Perkins, Mrs. D. P.
Poff, Mrs. Kelly
Ransom, Mrs. James
Ragland, Mrs. Chas.
Roberts, Miss Cora
Roberts, Mr. R. B.
*Rather, Mrs. J. T.
Rogers, Mrs. Edgar
Rion, Mrs. Ed
Richardson, Mrs. J. E.
Ready, Mrs. Anna
Rathers, Miss Mary
Smotherman, Mrs. Fletcher
Smith, Mrs. Gent
64
Spence, Miss Sarah
Stockard, Mrs. J. E.
Shacklett, Mrs. Arthur
Spain, Mrs. Foster
Smith, Mrs. Frederick
*Smith, Mrs. Dewitt
Tatum, Mrs. E. H.
Tavenner, Mrs. Eugene
Todd, Mrs. Andy
*Vickers, Mrs. R. W.
Woods, Mrs. Walter
White, Miss Frankie
Wright, Mrs. T. J.
Williams, Mrs. J. R.
Wharton, Mrs. A. D.
Williams, Mrs. H. H.
Weisse, Mrs. Aaron
White, Mrs. Frank
Williams, Mrs. John
Youree, Mrs.
*Denotes literary club members according to news
clipping.
"Banner Notebook&#8212;Woman's Club, 'Organized for
$10.00 Members 1917."
65
APPENDIX C
"Rules to Be Observed by the Librarian"
Murfreesboro Library Association
1. The library must be kept open during the hours
directed by the Executive Committee.
2. The library will be open every Saturday.
3. Paid up subscribers or the members of the family
of such subscribers shall have the right of with-drawing
not more than one book from the library.
4. Books can be taken out for two weeks, with the
privilege of renewal for one week. Any person
failing to return a book upon the specified day
shall be fined one cent a day until it is returned.
The Librarian must keep account of such fines and
report to the Treasurer for collection. A book lost
must be replaced by the loser.
5. Non-subscribers can take out books by depositing
the price of book with the Librarian, and upon its
return paying 10 cents a week for the time it
was kept.
6. New magazines must not be kept out longer than one
week under penalty of a fine of 5 cents a week.
7. An old magazine can be taken out with a book, or
four old ones without a book subject to the same
rules as books. A magazine is old when it is no
longer the current number.
Catalogue&#8212;1892, Murfreesboro Library Association ,
org. 1889 .
66
APPENDIX D
"Periodicals&#8212;Catalog, 1892"
Atlantic Magazine 1889-90-91
Century Magazine 1888-89-90-91
Eclectic Magazine 9 vols.
Harper Magazine 1888-89-90-91
Home Magazine 4 vols.
Lippincott 1889-90
Life Magazine 1891
Puck Magazine 1889
St. Nicholas Magazine 1890-91
Youth's Companion 1890-91, 1892
Catalogue&#8212;1892, Murfreesboro Library
Association, Org. 1889 .
67
APPENDIX E
History of the Woman's Club Building
The house was built in 1854, by Dr. William T.
Baskette, on a lot he'd purchased from J. I. Abernathy.
The Contractor of the magnificent building was Samuel
2 Richard Sanders. (His granddaughter, Mrs. John Osborne
presently lives in Murf reesboro.
)
Dr. Baskette 's second wife was Helen M. Crichlow,
grandmother of Mr. N. C. Crichlow. "It is said that James
H. Crichlow, father of Collier Crichlow, sold pies back
in the kitchen to the Union soldiers encamped here during
3
the 'War Between the States.'" (History repeated itself
in regard to "pies" in many homes during maneuvers of
World War II, when children sold pies and sandwiches to
G. I.'s on duty here. "The G. I.'s would sometimes
order pies, pay for them, and be moved before the pies
4 could be delivered." )
The second owner was Judge Fletcher Burrus, who sold
5
the house to Munford Jordan. The next owner was James M.
Haynes, whose widow sold the house to the Woman's Club.
The house originally had no porch on the front and
east side. "It is said that Mr. Haynes had the porches
68
built so he could exercise. His sight was poor, and he did
not like to get on the street."
The building is high style, and when Mr. Haynes
owned it, there was decorative iron grating over the
7 front windows, and a carved door welcomed visitors.
Miss Rebecca Jetton occupied the house for a few
years, and provided clues as to the original state of the
building. "Where we see the rafter in the ceiling here
in the assembly room, the west porch began and extended
the present serving room, and kitchen to the west. The
kitchen was at the northwest end of the porch. A bath-room
was a part of the porch, and where it is now. The
east part of the assembly room was the dining room with
serving rooms and pantry on the north. The present library
and dining room were bedrooms. The upstairs had four
large bedrooms with no partitions in each except a
dressing room on the north side of the large room above
the assembly room."
The Woman's Club made several alterations, and
repairs. In 1920 a hardwood floor was added, emphaisizad
9 with a new rug, upholstries and drapes.
Several "improvements" occurred in 1922. The big
porch was taken in to enlarge the assembly room, and to
create a serving room and kitchen. Electric fixtures were
69
installed in the new kitchen, as was a new stove. A
furnace was put in, and new dining room furniture acquired.
The auditorium was enlarged to seat 300 in 1922. The
porch was screened, and new draperies were hung in the
library and dining room. The next major alteration was in
1930&#8212;a new roof costing $625.00.
m
70
FOOTNOTES
Mrs. J. B. Black, "Beginnings of the 'Woman's
Club Library.'" Paper presented to membership meeting
February 20, 1961. Typed. Files upstairs,
2 Mrs. J. B. Black, Beginnings .
3 Mrs. J. B. Black, Beginnings .
4Mrs. J. B. Black, "Beginnings .
5Mrs. J. B. Black, Beginnings .
Mrs. J. B. Black, "Beginnings .
7Mrs. J. B. Black, "Beginnings .
Q
Letter to Mrs. Black, from Rebekah Jetton, hand-written,
letterhead stationery, "Tennessee Society Daughters
of the American Revolution." Two pages, including floor
plan. (Files upstairs. Woman's Club.)
9The Woman's Club of Murfreesboro Tennessee
Announcements 1920-192 2, Benson Printing Co., Nashville,
TN. Woman's Club Library.
10The Woman's Club of Murfreesboro . . 1922-1924.
Announcements The Woman's Club Murfreesboro
Tennessee 1930-1932 . Publisher not known. Woman's Club
Library.
71
BIBLIOGRAPHY
Manuscripts
Black, Mrs. J. B. "Beginnings of the Woman's Club,"
Speech presented to membership meeting, February 20,
1961, by Mrs. Black, Woman's Club President
1947-49. Typed. Filing cabinet, upstairs.
Woman's Club, 221 East College St., Murf reesboro, TN.
Brown, Mrs.. Ivan. "Light on the VJoman ' s Club Library,"
Typed. Filing cabinet, upstairs. Woman's Club.
Jackson, Mrs. E. "Orientation Meeting." Speech presented
to new members of the Woman's Club, September 20,
1970. Typed. Filing cabinet, upstairs. Woman's
Club.
Nelson, Cora Bristol. "Spring Luncheon." Poem handwritten
in ink, presumable Mrs. Nelson's hand, "About 1946."
Filing cabinet, upstairs. Woman's Club.
"Play." Title unknown, VI Scenes. Dramatization of idea/
decision to start a woman's club. Three drafts.
Filing cabinet, upstairs. Woman's Club.
Vickers, Mrs. R. w. "Manuscript" copies for Mrs. Vickers
by her niece Mrs. Ivy Elder (August 6, 1950).
Handwritten on back of advertisement "McMillans
Company." Filing cabinet, upstairs. Woman's Club.
Correspondence
Letter to Miss Kate Fowler, Murfreesboro, Tennessee from
Mary N. Murfree, June 5, 1890. Filing cabinet,
upstairs, Woman's Club.
Letter to Mrs. Dr. Black from Mrs. R. W. Vickers, 1948.
Filing cabinet, upstairs. Woman's Club.
Letter to Mrs. R. W. Vickers, date and addressee unknown.
Brief history, signed by Mrs. Vickers. Filing
cabinet, upstairs. Woman's Club.
Letter to Miss Ada Young, Librarian, Woman's Club, from
Mrs. R. W. Vickers, January 15, 1946. Filing
cabinet, upstairs. Woman's Club.
72
Letter to Miss Ada Young from Mrs. R. W. Vickers,
January 19, 1946. Filing cabinet, upstairs,
Woman's Club.
Letter to Miss Ada Young, Librarian, Woman's Club, from
Mrs. R. W. Vickers, January 24, 1946. Filing
cabinet, upstairs. Woman's Club.
Letter to Mrs. Black, from Rebekah Jetton, handwritten,
letterhead stationery. "Tennessee Society
Daughters of the American Revolution." Two pages,
floor plan included. Filing cabinet, upstairs.
Woman's Club.
Newspapers
"Lawrence Goodman to Appear at Woman's Club," The Home
Journal , Murf reesboro, Tennessee, Friday,
January 4, 1929.
"R. W. Vickers," Home Journal Souvenir 2nd Edition ,
Murf reesboro, Tennessee. Date unknown.
"Woman's Club Library Began With 12 Books," Rutherford
Courier , June 22, 1939, Murfreesboro, Tennessee.
Clipping. Filing cabinet, upstairs. Woman's Club.
Official Records
"Certificate of Registration." State of Tennessee,
Department of State, May 27, 1911. Filing cabinet,
upstairs. Woman's Club.
Deed Book 62 , p. 336 (notebook 3) , Rutherford County,
Tennessee, November 4, 1919.
Minute Book AA , pp. 551-556, Chancery Court, Rutherford
County, Tennessee. Recorded October 29, 1919.
Yearbooks
By-Laws of Woman's Club of Murf reesboro, Tenn. 1917 .
Mrs. Vicker's name on cover. Filing cabinet,
upstairs. Woman's Club.
73
The Woman's Club of Murf reesboro, Tennessee Announcements
1919-1920 , Benson Printing Co., Nashville, TN,
Woman's Club Library.
The Woman's Club of Murf reesboro, Tennessee Announcements
1920-1922 . Benson Printing Co., Nashville, TN,
Woman's Club Library.
The Woman's Club of Murfreesboro, Tennessee Announcements
1922-1924 . Benson Printing Co., Nashville, TN,
Woman's Club Library.
Announcements The Woman's Club Murf reesboro, Tennessee ,
1924-1926 . Publisher not known. Woman's Club
Library.
Announcements The Woman's Club Murf reesboro Tennessee ,
1926-1928 . Publisher not known. Woman's Club
Library.
Announcements The Woman's Club Murf reesboro -Tennessee,
1928-1930 , Publisher not known. Woman's Club
Library.
Announcements The Woman's Club Murf reesboro Tennessee ,
1930-1932 , Publisher not known. Woman's Club
Library.
Announcements The Woman's Club Murf reesboro Tennessee ,
1932-1934 , Publisher not known. Woman's Club
Library.
The Woman's Club Murf reesboro Tennessee 1934-1936.
Publisher not known. Woman's Club Library.
The Woman's Club 1940-41 . Publisher not known. Woman's
Club Library.
The Woman's Club 1944-45 . Publisher not known. Woman's
Club Library.
Minute Books
"Banner Notebook&#8212;Woman's Club, 'Organized for $10.00
Members 1917.'" (Membership lists, rents received,
etc.) Filing cabinet, upstairs. Woman's Club.
74
"Black Log Book," 1921-1933. Filing cabinet, upstairs.
Woman's Club.
"Green Log Book," 1924-1926. Filing cabinet, upstairs.
Woman's Club.
Other Sources
Catalogue&#8212;1892, Murfreesboro Library Association .
org. 1889 . News Print, 1892. Green pamphlet
approximately 6" x 3". Filing cabinet, upstairs.
Woman's Club.
"Woman's Club Building." Black and white photograph,
5" X 7", Leo Ferrell, photographer, Murfreesboro,
Tennessee. July 6, 1921. Filing cabinet,
upstairs. Woman's Club.
</dc:description>
<dc:description>Describes literary interest among Murfreesboro women, manifested in literary societies, women's clubs, and library associations from the late nineteenth to the mid-twentieth century</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.); Ransom, John Crowe, 1888-1974; Murfreesboro (Tenn.); Jackson, Helen Hunt, 1830-1885;Women--Societies and clubs</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>28 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-01; mt2011-02-03</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication26ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/16</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>