<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Violence in Rutherford County 1907 - 1912</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Burns II, Norman O.</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 31</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1986</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1900-1909; 1910-1919;</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>.'
VIOLENCE IN RUTHERFORD COUNTY 1907 - 1912
by
J' \ N.~rman O. Burns I I
Middle Tennessee state University
History 681
Dr. David Rowe
December 5, 1986
I
"
VIOLENCE IN RUTHERFORD COUNTY 1907 - 1912
John Burns shot and killed his nephew Ike Horgan on Septeznber
15, 1907. 1 This event was the result of extended difficulties
between the two famil,{es'~ This "family feud '1 is one of the many
types of violence prevalent in Rutherford County, Tennessee between
1907 and 1912. This paper will provide a narrative account of the
various types of violence in Rutherford Co~nty during this period.
There are several examples of "feud" violence during this
period. The definition of a feud is difficult to derive.
~mbittered feelings should not be described as a feud, but a feud
cannot exist without them. A difficulty does not make a feud,
though a feud is a series of difficulties. A revenge murder does
not make a feud, but before a feud is over there are usually
several. Thus, gang wars, riots, and lynchings cannot by them&#173;selves
be called a feud, but like the other examples, are embodied
in the concept of feud violence. A feud can be defined as "any'
prolonged quarrel involving blood vengeance between families or
factions.,,2 The p&lt;;)ipular conception of the "blood feud" or
vendetta is one of an, endless series of homicides and although it
is usually between families and clans, an individual relative
may occasionally become the object of vengeance. Homicides are
not the only cause of feuds. They can begin as a result of
poaching on someone else's property, adultery, or even a willful
refusal to repay a debt. 3 This type of violence was, prevalent in
Rutherford County between 1907 and 1912.
37
On December 31, 1873 William Allen Morgan married Frances
ArgQn Burns. 4 At first, the relationship between the two families
was normal; however, Frances' father, Ivey P. Burns, had a
disagreement with his sons-in-law and made a will"that disinherited
the sons-in-law. After his death, the sons-in-law went together
and broke the will andishared in the property.5 Before I.P. Burns
died, he had another disagreement with his son-in-law William
1&#183;1organ. John' Burns, I. P. Burns' son, then had harsh words with
his brother-in-law, William r1organ. Following this incident, Ike
;&#183;;organ, William f'.;organ' s son, sm." John Burns ,driving his buggy
down the road and asked him for a ride. Upon entering the buggy,
Ike Morgan began beating up his uncle with brass knuckles. John
Burns told his nephew, "God damn you, I'll kill you, you little
devil." John Burns was not a man for idle threats. On Sunday
morning, September 15, 1907, John Burn's walked up to Ike Morgan
while he was sitting at a repair shop next to the tile mill, a
short distance from ~organ's home, and shot him. Burns reportedly
said, "I told you I was going to kill you." 6 1
The Nashville American printed this story in the next day's
edition, September 16, 1907. The caption above the article
sensationalized the f~ily dispute:
OLD FAMILY FEUD ENDS IN TRAGEDY John
Byrns Slays Nephew Near Eagleville -- IKE
MORGAN IS SHOT DOWN -- Dies Within Thirty
Minutes and B,yrns Escapes, Coming, It Is Said,
in the Direction of Nashville -- Both Men Are
Prominent in Community.?
The article noted that this feud was " a result of bitter feeling
engendered by' a distorted condition of family affairs that ha~e
JR
e:dcnded over a period of several years. II Neighbors were aware
of the animosity existing between the two families, and they had
anticip~ted a disastrous culmination of the feud. Yet, the killing
C8."1e as a complete surprise and was a shoc}cing calamity to many
of the citizens in this southwest portion of Rutherford County.
.. ' \ ..
If nei8;hbors anticipated~a disastrous culmination to this family
f0Ud, tben why did the killing surprise them? The answer could
lie in the fact that John Burns had considerable land holdings
and '.~'o.s considercd "a prominent Rutherford County farmer. II
~urthcrmore, "both men were prominent in the 3agleville community
dl:d 2:1 joyed the reputations of being law-abiding citizens. ,,8
It could be difficult for a person alien to the southern
8uvironment to conceive of a man that is considered prominent
in a community as being able to deliberately 1&lt;111 a man. This
type of behavior is usually cc;l1fined to the cruder segments of
society. Yet, "in the absence of wholesome legal and moral
restraints, it is undeniably true that in the Southern states
men of a certain amount of education, and often enjoying the
highest social standing, are not infrequently guilty of the most
shocking homicides. 1I9
The lIaDhville American article provides a similar account
of the problems between the two families in the past, noting that
trouble had been brewing for about four years, "0r since some
family troubles began in which Norgan and Byrns were connected." 10
About three weeks before the killing the two men renewed the trouble
and reportedly threatened each other. The lTashville American's
account of the killing was somewhat different from the previous ,
account.
39
,::;arly this morning, lVlorgan went to Pilotville, as
has been his custom on Sunday mornings. \lhile
sitting near a store there talking with some
friends, Byrns 'approached him with a double&#173;barreled
shotgun,and when within 'about eight
or ten feet of Morgffi1, fired. The shot took
effect in rlorgan' s right breast , resulting in
death within about thirty minutes. Byrns left
immediately after the shooting and has not been
apprehended &#8226;. ~ 1 .
J.'he area where John Burns shot Ike ~Iorgan was c,alled Little Rock
aLd wa~ approximat ely two miles from l"lorgan' s house. The area
housed a tile mill and a repair shop, and it was here that John
D-.., urns sh0 t Ike"iVlorgan. 12
After being notified of the killing, Sheriff Primm beg~n
a search for Burns immediately; notifying authorities in
surrounding towns to keep watch for him. 13 Some time later
3urns was apprehended in Lincoln County and brought to trial;
ho~ever, the wheels of justice moved slowly in Rutherford county
in the first decade of.the twentieth century. The prosecutor had
a difficult time securi.ng eyewitnesses, and over the next c.ouple
of years there were several mistrials. The original charge of
murder was reduced to voluntary manslaughter. Burns was ordered
to spend one ye~:r in the state penitentiary by the Rutherford
County Circuit Court. The State Supreme Court of I5rrors and
Appeals in Nashville upheld this decision on December 1, 1910.
Came the Attorney General on behalf of tile State
and the prisoner, John Burns in proper person,
where upon this cause was heard upon the transcripts
of the record from the Circuit Court of Rutherford
County; after consideration by the Court, in appearir~
that there is no error in the judgement of the Court
below, the same is in all things affirmed. It is .
therefore ordered by the Court In. Burns for his
offense do undergo confinement at hard labor in
the Pf2itentiary of the State for the period of one
year.
40
John ~urns only served eight months of the original sentence
and '..:as t::J.en pardoned.
After the jdlling of his younger brother, Arthur Norgan
Vlent to ~~ashville and became a member of the Nashville Fire
~epartment, perhaps to escape the family dispute. Burns returned
.,.,\ \ "
to the Jackson ~idge are~ when he left prison and continued the
f~~ily dispute by getting drunk and going by the Morgans'
place, 9ussing and causing trouble. 15 The Morgans' house sat
approximately thirty to forty feet off the road in Jackson Ridge,
which is in the western end of Rutherford County some five miles
from .:Eagleville. Arthur rvIorgan retired from the Nashville Fire
Department and came back to the community for a family visit a
few weeks before the killing. A Nashville newspaper noted that
.Arthur j ~organ was weltl.-known and liked in l-:ashville and that "he
frequently had trouble with his uncle 'and it was predicted when
he left for ~'Iurfrcesboro that there would be a tragedy." 16
On l':ay 14, 1911 Horgan shot and killed his uncle John
Burns in front of the Morgans' home place. The local and
~ashville papers well documented and sensationalized this event.
All of these :papers mentioned the words Iffamily feud" in their
headlines or within the body of the article. For instance,
The Tennessean l-iashville American pri.nted the story on the front
- page of the next day's edition.
.6...11TI-IDR MORGAN SLAYS JOHN BYRE -- SUlIDAY TRAGEDY
ITSAP. BAGL3VILLE, HUTHT'illFORD COUNTY -- REVENGE
SSEr-IS THE MOT IV::!; -- Byrn killed Horgan's Brother
Three Years Ago -- r-,lorgan a Former Nashville
Firernan 17
41
;,:'he ,ashville Danner carried the folJ.owing ca~~tion above the
article concerning the killing.
FAi-nLY :1?EUD I ': RUTH~~RFORD John Burns Instantly
l:illed By ,His ~~ephew, Arthur l"lorgan -- Shooting
Eo Jurprise18
r;.:~::3 local papers used similar headlines &#8226;
IT.:'\.I'-;ILY FEUD-'BREAKS OUT At:~:1 -- John Burns is
Shot by His 2(ephew, Arthur T'Iorgan, and is
Instantly Killed.
JOlT:; DUn.:::S KILL.'~D DY lL.'i.THUR r'lORGAN -- FAf'ULY FEUD. 19
All four of these newspapers provided a background into the
family dispute, noting that three years earlier John Burns had
;.;:i1lcd :\..rthur I:Iorgan' s brother. Por example, the r;ashvi lIe
3a~ncr acknowledged
strained relations have existed between the
two men and their families for several years,
and vIas further aggravated a fey! years ago
when Burns shot - one Sunday morning - Ike
I';organ, a brotper of the man' who did the
killing yesterday. Burns was bitterly
prosecuted for the killing, and after several
mistrials was given one year in the penitentiary,
~u~ w~B pardoned after serving eight months in
Jall. '
One of the local papers mentioned the fact that a few months
befar-.\:) the killing IvIorgan had left Nashvill-e to return to his
hOEle. lISiIlce his arrival, there it was feared that the feud
':,Tould be re~pened. II 21 '
During the half-century after the Civil ~ar family feuds
became more evident in the South. The larger northern newspapers
helped to turn the national consciousness to these conflicts.
Family feuds became a part of a national fascination with death,
a part of the newspapers' increasing search for saleable copy,
a!:lQ I)Clrt of 1'i.merica's obsession with violence and sordidness. 43
cau::::lt in ~lis clothing. \'/11en f,jorgan saw Durns pull the pistol
.t,rOl:aring to shoot him. 1,:ow, ;&#183;10rgan raised his shoteun and emptied
the cOlctents into Burns while he was seated in his buggy. Five
witnasses, all members of Morgan's fanily, corroborated this
version of the shootine; .-.~ 23
A. different story came from John Burns' son-in-law, John 1\.
':1ale, who was in the buggy with Burns 'when Morgan shot him. In
a signed affidavit to the Circuit Court fore~an, Hale said that
he stayed at the Burns' place the Saturday night before the killing.
111is resulted in a steady stream of newspaper stories, magazine
articlGs, and books. 22 Large l.orthern newspapers,' such as the
~hicaso ~ribune and the ~ew York Times sensationalized the feuds
of I:e!,tucky in order to profit frem this national consciousness.
~1,1h2 Washville and loc'a.l'.'papers pursued a similar form of
ael1sationalism in their re90rts of feuds in Rutherford County.
,ii. large crowd attended the preliminary trial of Arthur
Mors;,Cln that tooK place in E;agleville. Squire ',villiam Ralston
calL~d in County Judge I. tJ. Floyd, Squires B. F. Owen, and
&lt;TO~D1 ~~_'. ',:ilson' as associates in hearing the evidence. There were
~0 ~2alized fro~ his abusive and loud lan3uage that Burns was
biG cO'lflicting stories concerning the killing presented during
I
this l:r,,:limir&gt;.ary trial. Arthur korgan testified that on the morning
01 tLc killins one of his dauzhters told him that a hawk ViaS after
tlle chickens; he then loaded his gun and went out to shoot the
_la\'/l~. 'Iilhen he failed to find the hawk, he returned to his house
and placed the gun on his front porch. At this same time John
Burns passed by l":organ' s home on the way to sa'lt some cattle on
anot~er farm he owned below the Morgans' p~ace. Later, Burns
returned, passing by Morgan's home which sat ap:roximately thirty
to forty feet off thq road. According to !&#183;Iorgan, while he was
seated on his front porch with his family l!he heard Burns driving
d 0\'1i1 the road towards his house cursing and tall&lt;ing in a loud
aDd abusive ffimmer about J1im. tr I"lorgan, not wishing to have any
.L'urt:lcr difficulties, remained on the front porch until Burns
drove in front of his house., .'\t that point, r'10rgan saw Burns
~ut his hand in his hip pocket and partially draw a pistol which
The next day he went with Burns.
I was in the buggy with John Burns we passed
Arthur :';orijan' s and went to Burns' lower plac e
and as \'/e came back I saw Arthur i'riorgan corning
towards the road from his house he had a
shotgun in his hand. ~r. Burns asked me if
that was ~organ, I told it was. Burns leaned
over in the buggy I thought to get his whip
and I\':organ shot him whi le in the leaning
position. When the gun fired the horse began
runnin7 and run about 75 or 80 yards. Burns
fell o~t of the buggy dead. I picked Burns up
and put him back in the buggy. ~e never spoke.
If Burns had a gun I did not see it or know any&#173;thin~
about it. This was in Rutherford 00. 24
&lt;,;)
Tom riolton in a similar signed affidavit noted that "f&#183;'!r. Burns
rer.lar!-;:ed to me Ii 11 go down with Bob and Dr. Hule and get back
in ti me for~ you to go to~:ashville. ~1is guns were at home,
they wasn't around.,,25
After hearing all the evidence the magistrates decided that
~\:organ had acted in self-defense; therefore, the maGistrates
ordered him released. Squire :/illiam :H.alston noted of the case:
I sit on the Burns and r~rgan case. It was
proven by the state's witnesses that ~organ
---~.-----------z:J:'Zlr--......----------- 45
After the shootin&amp; people generally believed that the feud
would be continued. 27 This did not prove to be the case; over
the next few years the relationships between the two families
returned to normal.
was justif~able in shooting Burns as he
feared bodlly harm. He saw a pistol in
deceas~d's pocket he was drawing same to
shoot !10rgan when he fired. It was aJ.so
prove~ by 4 creditable witnesses that Burns
had threatened Arthur Morgan's life. In
fact we found no evidence that would warrant
us binding hi~ over. 26
~wo months before John Burns died his son, Will Burns,
ViaG shot and killed in an unrelated incident. Late ':'lednesday
!2l' ~grit, ~1':'larcll 1 , 10'&gt; 11 , 0I.'dey,'Alcorn shot '.;ill Burns at Hi Johns;
,~ear Jackson Ridge. 28 According to Bill T. Rutledge,.
II-:q.nest Carlton, l'ete Lamb, the Burns - \:lash Burns and Will, Burns
and Ordey Alcorn " were "at John's store at Jackson Ridge.1!29
It was not unusual for this group of young men to be together.
Accordin3 to ;'!r. J. 'il. Sneed in October of 1910
the boys were punching each other' at the
Cumberland Presbyterian Church and disturbing
t~e people going to the church. The boys were
~3l11 11utledge, R. \'/hi te, Ordie Al-corn, Pete
~amb) Will Burns. It is said they went to
the prayer meeting cursing saying God damn you
get out of ~y way.30
They submitted their cases to the Circuit Court and paid their
respective fines. 31 ~hese yo~ng men were no strangers to trouble,
eS:gecially Ordie Alcorn.. In ~larch.of 1909 Sheriff Walter Batey&#183;
took a pair of knucks from' Ordl"e. 32 A .f ew months later, in
September of 1909, l&gt;iiss ~.';able Floyd reported being insulted by him
The paper gave a detailed description of Burns' bullet
One shot entered Burns' heart, one the right
lung, ranging downwards into the liver,. one
entering the left hip, but glanced, making
only a flesh wound, and the fourth entered
the man's right side. The clothing of Burns
was ignited by the fire and the man drop~ed
from his chair to the floor and expired.36
~u.r~J.3 '::ith his left hand and shot him four times. G. ~'!. Burns
*This is card terminology.
wounds. .
by God you d:!.dn't play that card away. Burns says if you say I
didn't flag that deuce you say a damn lie. Alcorn jumped up arid
said you can't say that to ;:le. ,,34 G. '"IT . Burns noted that Alcorn
tllen ran his hand in his overall's pocket, and Burns go.t up and went
you. Alcorn stood there and unloaded the gun and threw the shells
over 3urns' head.,,35 Alcorn then reloaded the gun and left the
building. Apparently the chain of events occurred so quickly that
those present did not have time to react and Alcorn made his
towards him. /..lcorn then drew a 32 caliber revolver and seized
Doted that as '::ill fell to the ground he said "0' me, 0' me."
Alcorn then said, "You might have known God damn you I would shoot
~arlton were playiilS a game of five-up at John's store between
1'::118 dispute between :.hll Burns and Ordie Alcorn beean over
a card t:;ame. ;,Hll Burns, Pete Lamb, Ordie Alcorn and :8rnest
te~l and eleven p.m. ':!ednesday night, March 1, 1911. During the
couy'se of the game Burns and Alcorn engaged in a dispute over
. . *
'.-Iho played the low card. -~ Burns said he ~ "flagged the deuce '.' and
~clcorll said he did. According to Bill T. nutledge, "lUcorn remarked
when she would not allow .hi.m,to go home ,with her. ,Reportedly, Alcorn
told I'liss Floyd to "go to hell God dal'1n you. 1133
, .
The paper noted that ;'.'ill Burns was the son of John Burns,
"who, it will be remembered has had some serious trouble recently."
:iill Burns was about 24 years of age and Alcorn was about 20. The
paper noted that these two men had recently been indicted for
disturbing public worship. "It is also said that there was some&#183;
;. \ ,
bad blood existing between the two men, of course a 'woman being
the cause. However, this statement has not been verified. ,,37;
Alcorn was at large until the Tuesday after the killing
when Deputy Will ~atson received word to go to the home of Hugh
r:;osley, Alcorn's brother-in-law. Alcorn submitted freely to the
arrest. The next night Deputy Rhodes, after receiving a telephone
call that mornipg, met Deputy 'y'!atson and Alcorn out on Franklin
&#183;~toad. The three men then returned together. Alcorn was given
a hearing before Judge John E. Richardson who ordered Alcorn jailed
without bail. This case was carried up from the Circuit Court.
of ;':urfreesboro. In the case of "Arthur Alcorn vs. State, the
court, through an opinion by Judge Landsden, affirmed the verdict
of the lower court, in which' the plaintiff in error was convicted
of Ijmrder in the second degree and sentenced to twenty years in the
peni tentiary. ,,38.
Family dispute~, or disputes between two men ending in
a traeedy, were typical of the various tYl)es of violence that
Rutherford County experienced between 1907 and 1912. The dispute
between James I'f;erritt and Dolph Lane is representative of this
type of violence.
Jim l\1erritt shot and killed Dolph Lane near Nerritt' s horne
in ~alter Hill, fifteenth district of Rutherford County, on
3unday morn.lng, h,.ovembe26r1,91.1 The kl'lll'n~~ was the culmination
of troubles that existed between the two men for about a year,
due to the alleged intimacy of Lane with Merritt's wife. The
Lashville Tennessean and the ~ashville American carried the story
the followine Tuesday with the caption above the article reading
JHI r'ERiUTT"'SIiAYS .AJ)OLPHUS LAES IN RUTHfi:RFORD
CO. -- Latter Persistently Attentive to the
Former's ~ife -- T~IAL ON FRIDAY -- Tragedy
~ear walter Hill CliW8X of Series of Difficulties
Between the Two Men.'~"
'.rhe local papers carried similar headline s.
BODY ~IDDLSD WITH BUC~SHOT -- Jim Merritt Shoots
and I~lstantly Kills Dolph Layne -..;. "''''omen in
the Case" -- Slayer in Jail.
DOLI'II LAI&#183;il~ KILL:&amp;D -- James Eerrit 40Shoots Him
Avenge Alleged D0i11estic Troubles.
These captions are fine examples of how the i':ashville and local
papers' sensationalized these reports &#8226;.
In September, 1910 Merritt had shot Lane in front of Merritt's
home on 1est Eair. street in Murfreesboro, because Lane had
dri~cn up to his home and was talking with Mrs. Merritt. Merritt
had repeatedly warned Lane "to desist from his attentions to
&gt;,rs. j&#183;ierritt. II The wound was not serious, but as a result of
.
these difficulties the men filed several suits and and counter-suits
in the local court. Lane was convicted at the October, 1911
ter'1 of the Circuit C:ourt and sentenced to eleven months and
twenty-nine days in the worle-house, but he aIJpealed his case
to the S-upreme Court . 41
During this same session of the Rutherford County Circuit
Court both rlterritt and his wife entered divorce suits. Judge
JO:1n J".;. Richardson declined to grant them a divorce IIstating
---------- . /
(~ou:;.'thouse in ;':urfreesboro. Testimony consumed the entire day,
2.Y:d 'Ett t~'1e conclusion i\';agistrate Hicks announced an adjournment
llntil ,'':;aturday worning. However, he came to realize the interest
in t:le trial vIas great, so he called for a night session. A local
pap2r described the scene.
J.llie Circuit Court jury returned the verdict of I~not g~ilty"
s~i.()rtJ.'y a.fter noon on Saturday. Only one ballot was taken and
included Dolph IJane&#183;' s two daughters, 2va and Ida, Dr. Harris and
two blac:.. s v/ho testified that they saw part of the killing. 47
~'O),! j'.:ane, the dead :!lan's brother, served as prosecutor and witnesses
~'he court r'obm' was crowded throughout the trial by
interested and curious spectators, as the
previous trouble between Merritt and the man he
slew over the former's wife made it more than
conjectu~~l ~hat salacious evidence would be
deduced. 4o .'
th,.:; vote for acquittal was ur.animous &#8226;. ..:\.ccording to the jury,
1I~llhe testirr,ony showed that bad feelings between the two men had
existed for some time and that Lane had come between ).;erri tt 2nd
his Wife, causing an estrangement, resulting in the bitterness
of feeling which finally led up to the deplorable tragedy. ,,48
~\,nother example of this type of violenc e onc e again
occurred ne2r Jackson Ridge, in the tenth district of Rutherford
~ou.ntJ. On February 24,1912 John lee H8yes died as a result of
gun .shot wounds inflicted three weeks earlier by Richard iI/est.
~icbard \lest was no stranger to violence. In June of 1910 he had
assaulted A. J. Baskin.
~~thur Baskin and Clarence Campbell were going to visit
Mr. Day's girls at his place on Franklin Road and take,,!them
meet, Lane made a,'l1l1ovement as if to draw a
was~filled with buckshot
carry-ing a gun for "self-protection" when the killing he was
a lot 150 yards away from Merritt's home in he met Lane in some
horseback and I"lerritt claims that when Walter Hill. Lane' was on
d t f a perl'od of a "ear, believiug t "hat would suspend ju gemen or J he
bl ,,42 that time would heal their trou es.
1 the troubles between &gt;Terri tt and his ~hile time might hea
not heal the differences between Merritt wife, it ,apparently did
Acco rding to Merritt's testi~ony, on the morning of and J~ane.
S~uire Ed Hooper held a Coroner's Jury to render a verdict
th D J T Harris re'ported, "I was about the cause of dea &#8226; r. &#8226; &#8226; _
d T t h ' death L,ayne had 3 shots in left called to atten ~ayne a lS &#8226;
- 3 in back of head and 3 in right shoulder and 5 in left temple
hip. ,r44 "He had 23 holes in him from buckshot. 1145
Cne of the local papers acknowledged that Merritt did not
C oncerned and felt that his case would be "justified seem
in the eyes of the law." T':1erri tt remained in jail without making
bond until his preliminary trial the following Friday. Squire ~at
Hicks and Squire W. A. Miles held the preliminary trial at the
they were about to
pistol. Merritt then raised his gun that
I h " . tantly Merritt then and fired at Lane three times kil ing 1m lns, &#8226;
went to his brother's house, told him of the killing, and then
to tell h im he had killed Lane. Sheriff 'called Sheriff ~cKnight
t J Hall went immediately to the scene of ;;lcKnight and Depu y ep
the killing and arrested ~erritt. His brother, William Merritt,
and C. D. Nickens were arrested as accessories to the killing
43 but were later released on bond.
::ill got iE S~Wi~lg, "I have got that little foxy girl and you
I:;8 West as~~ed :~~~m!)bell where they were going. Campbell told theI!l
t~18Y \'fsy:e going to old man Day ' s. ',',rall!'"~: then said, "By God I
dc~" t ':::uess yO'l will eo," and got up into the buggy with Campbell
3c./illg, 11"::e just came" from there and raised hell and I don't guess
JO'J.. ':fill eo." ',Jalls tool{ Campbell by the arm, and Lee ';lest searched
'd.::l i'or 2. gUll. I,cc,\'lest then said, "Campbell we are poor boys,
you boys have rubber tired buggy's and we don't have none and don't
d h . d' our gl'rl" Bob ':talls j Ltc::d having you come arouYl" ere rl lng .:;..
t'1011 said God damn you are you going to turn around." Campbell
then replied, "'.lhat for?" ':.Talls said "didn't I tell you you wasn't
':()l.:-i: over t'nere.&#183;'I ',,:.!alls tIlen cll'mbed out of the buggy, and D.
~\.bout this time ':Jest and Hill grabbed Campbell's arm and
he heard shootii.1G behind him. Campbell, looking back, saw Did"\:
.:cst standing on one side of Arthur :Baskin's buggy and Gz Steel
en t '..le a t"}ler &#8226; Both men were standing up in the buggy. Dick
.fest had a pistoJ.. and was shooting it 1:1h:;18 Oz Steel was
whipping the horses. Thl'.s caused the horse to bolt and Baskin's
bu~gy ran into the rear wheels of C~npbell's buggy breaking
sev3ral spokes and seriously damaging the buggy.~O
'Ihile they were repairing the damage to Baskin I s buggy
one of the boys said if there was every anything done about this
incident it would be a dark day. After this Bob Walls said to
,~a!npbell, 11 If there is ever anything done about this you had as
West
treat
called
said why did you
. 52
had to." West
I'll fix you.,,53
Officers were immediately notified,
a box. It";Jest wal"~ed back to !Iayes and
inmediately fled the scene.
i-fell get your gun to kill me the first time you see me." Campbell
Gated, "I have since lived in fear of trouble with these boys.1I 51
~~he dispute between Dicl\. 'dest and John Hayes resulted from
an encounter Hayes had with West's brother five days before. The
:3unday before Dick ';lest shot Hayes, Hayes and Andrew West, an
older brother of Dick"'West, had a fight over a card game in Tom
~'ate' s store. During the process. of the fight John Hayes almost
bi t off one of ;'lest' sears. The follo'iling Friday Dick West
~est remained at large for several weeks until Deputy
~heriff James ~~. Lewis received information that he was in
51
then d2.~ew a revolver and shot Hayes, "The ball entering the man's
rj_ght groin and rangin,g up- and lodging in the shoulder. ,,54 ',vest"
vtalked j,nto Tom I'ate' s store where John Hayes was sitting on
100y brother like you did. Hayes said I
but action was not taken until the. next dq.y when &#183;Deputy Watson
\'lent to the scene of the difficulty~: The local paper noted that
"Eayes was still alive, but in a precarious condition.,,55 Hayes
:{ayes a liar and "said somethins about
died three weeks later.
':illiamson County near Fran~lin. Deputy Lewis with two local
of Ii.ichard Hu':U, was working. Deputy l,miis arrested ~(lest
officials went out to the far~ where West, who assumed the name
and returned him to the Rutherford County jail. At the February
tbrm of the Rutherford County Circuit Court, West was charged with
murder in the first degree. 56 '_ .
50
Walls and
Lee ';Jest,
40
1':0 bacl~. II " o
:Sob ."I,8e "'"'Ia11s and O. z ~~teel stopped them.
112.V8 .sot to
~. .~, 11
_~"'. '. J... _. ,
io~ 0 bU~GY ride. On their way there, Dick ~est,
52
.~eud s were not t'ne onl.y sou:r'ce of violence in Rutherford
:~0L1.l1ty behleel1 1~;07 and 1S12. People seemed to be preoccupied
"'il til t:18 id ca of toting guns &lt;U1d knives and threatening each
other \&#183;,ith these \&#183;/eapons. There are :.literally hundreds of
~xn~ples of assault with a pistol or knife, public drunkeness,
:'luoTrelin~, disturbill&amp;' public worship, rape, and general bad
cO:"-lduct &#163;~:t~: to in tl1e 3.utherforci County Court Foreman's note-
~:he people of Rutherford ;'::ounty during t~lis period seemed
a ctisyute erupted between the two ~en over who was going to
\\'llli( Wss YoungbJood home. j'Ienry Tarply then stepped back and
'Jullcd a pistol froEl his poc'.~et and began snttpping it. The
~'J8tol did not fire and Henry Tarply ran off. 58
.\ similar incident concerning assault with a pistol occurred
in :_';ctooer of 1911. ~)a.lter Garrett came to the house of S. }'.
!'l8.l"]~~il1shipwith a shotgun and said he was going to kill every-t~
liJ1:: in the plac e. I":r. G2.rrett was reported drunk. He came
O:),C:: to '3lankinsh,i,p's place two or three tii'les and got in their
53
.TcoccuDied with the notion of toting guns. ~ ... The Rutherford
Y [t!'d &#8226; The Blanki~ships removed him every time. The next time
&#183;_;OHi;ty ~ourt ?oreman' s noteboo~~ has page after pa~e of affidavits
S\"lorn tl~cLi.nst people seen carrying guns. For example, in rovember,
1'~OC f;. N. Bryant got drunk and shot his pistol. In Dec ember,
1::;0[, Sfrain Jam8s saw Dan i(ato at t:le corner of \1alnut and Castle
:.:;tr2et in I'~urfreesboro with a pistoJ. in his h.and. In I-lay, 1909
R..; cl1ard l:.'est and Alf A,I corn reported seeing Jim Kelton with a
pistol. In JUj,le of 1909 John r~urry and .e.d Dickson reported
s'2c5?-,z Hershial Johns with a p.i.stol. In ~.'Iarch of 1910 ;',1axie
;]harlton reported that he gave a pistol to Richard ';'/ells. He
also noted that h.e h::'ld a pistol in his' pocket when he got into a
scuf.fle VIi tll a gmo.up of boys and accidently shot Gracey Thompson. 57
The people of Rutherford County not only toted guns, but
they used them as well. On Narch 18, 1909 John Lawerence reported
tllD.t Tow Houston shot him. In August of 1909 J. A. Knox reported
t:ilat jiarry Die shot him with a pistol. In June of 1910 a
~r~:ul) of young people were waJ_kinB home from church. Henry
r;:arply and Oscar ::eal were walking beside Sarah Youneblood when
G8rr~tt came by the house, he snapped his gun at Blankinship's
son, ;:Toover Blankinship. aoover \vent into the house and got his
,,'at:l'?r':3 pistol, came back outGide and shot Garrett three time::;. 59
'!lhe i~eople of ~utherford Cour-ty were' just as violent with
knj, ves. In June of 1909 ::::layton Todd reported seejng ~i~ddie Dixson
attacl&lt;: Uershial Jones with an axe and then cut him with a razor.
:::E Ju.:r.e of 1910':-lillie Harland and Oscar noss became involved in
an argument. Harland told Ross, "I'll burst your head open and
Oscai' told him }' am not scared of anyone man." Harland then
sm2.C ',~ed :~oss with,. his hand, and Oscar pulled his knife. At
that point Solomon Bryant came up from behind and stabbed Oscar
60
loss in the back. In a similar incident a J. L. Lowe, who was
drun~, approached Dock Brown. Brown, knowing that Lowe was
dancerous, drew his gun. Lowe grabbed the gun, unbreached
it, a~d 'das hittine Brown when Will ~"lurray ran up and cut Lowe
,~ 61
on tne hand.
It is obvious from this incident that Reuben
n!\ubl'n Alexander went to Mattie Murray's house Cct0ber of 1909.
of ordinary assault and battery occurred in An example
People began suff8red the fate of many agrarian area~ migr2tion.
was the only area of the county that had a sizable increase in
population. Since Rutherford County was mainly agrarian, it
The manuscript census for 1910 reveals a similar pattern,
to leave the countryside looking for work in the larger cities
where industries were beginning to grow. ',~'hile the population
of ~urfreesboro incre~~ea, the population of the county as a
whole decreased. Between 1890 and 1900 Rutherford Co~ntyts
)opulation declined oy 4.4%, and between Flub and 1910 it
dec/inGd by 1.0%. The population as a whole in Rutherford County
decreased from 36,741 in H;80 to 33,199 in 1910. During this s:lme
Derfod of time, middle Tennessee's largest city, Nashville,
increased its population from 43,350 to 110,364. 64
The tenth district of Rutherfond County was an area where
much of the violence discussed in this paper took place. This
southwestern area of the county, like the rest, was agrarian.
~he only other outlet for work in this area besides working on
a farm was at the tobacco factory, pencil mill, blacksmith
shc~s, saw mills, or the shingle factory. However, most of these
operations were very small family operations, employing few
people. The man~script census shows the agrarian nature of
this district. Of the 230 householas listed in the manuscript
census for the tenth district in 1900, 65. 7~ listed "farmer" as
the household occupation. Another 18/&amp; list their occupation as
bein~ ei ther .a farm laborer or day laborer; most of whom wor~&lt;ed
on far:'1s, the saw mill, or t:L1e grist mill. 66
with most of the households listing llfarmer" as their occupation.
After and told her he was going to beat the hell out of her.
"th t aIle but a black son of a bitch would do told Alexander a no
62 her as such."
from the door he returned to her window and raised walkins away
the sash to come in, but he saw Mattie up with a gun in her hand.
Alexander left the house and went to the barn. Mattie Murray
then called Gillie Hallard to come and get Alexander. Murray
he
then went outside looking for AJexander and~assulted her. When
. d flexander was sitting on top of Murray hitting iiallard arrlve , _1-
her in the face. After Alexander finally got off f.!urray she
Alexar..der, a black farmer, was not a stable man. On January 13,
1910 ~euben Alexander murdered his wife Folly Alexander and then
d "d '63 co~~itte SU1Cl e.
As the previous examples indicate, Rutherford County between
1903 and 1912 was filled with violence. Twenty-four people
died as the result 01' some form. of violence, ej ther murder or
:lhy was Rutherford County so violent during this suicid.e.
period? Economi~ and social conditions within the county in
the first two decades of the twentieth century could have
produced violence.
~utherford County during the first two decades of the
twentieth century was still basically agrarian in nature. The
only city with a sizable population was Murfreesboro with a
P9~ulation of 4,679 in 1910. This was an unusual condition
because the thirteenth civil district, which contained Murfreesboro,
T~ere was one substantial difference; it was the number of peoDle
listin~ the pencil mill as their place of occupation. Forty-three
p80ple listed t~e pencil mill as their place of occupation, and
out of these, eleven were women. 67 These girls bundled cedar
s I at s f or sh.l'ppl'ng&#8226;68.
The tenth di3trj:ct&#183;~ was hard hit by migration, too. The
cODulation decreased from 1,217 in 1890 to 1,071 in 1910.
69
... ~ ,
:..od ernizati Qn and industrialization in the big cities continued
to draw people away from the countryside. This trend was no
different in Rutherford County. The economic condition of the
county, its agrarian nature and its isolation from the forces
of ~ndernization cculd be key factors that led to violence in
'':1y di d violen~e occur during this period? 'iihy did farnily
disIJutes end wi th ~:illings? These are difficult '1uestions to an~\'Ier,
for the ele,lents affecting the characters involved are many.
'~harles 3. Sydnor stated, "the form in \'{hich anger is expressed
often indicates much about the characteristics of the actor and
about t~1e mores of the society in which he lives." 70 Recent
explanatjons of ~eud violence focus on changes in the area through
the years and the effect these changes have upon the psyche of
the people involved. Gordon B. ~cKinney argued that violence in
Appalachia during the 1890's did ndt differ significantly from
the llational .norm; however, when the forces of modernization
entered the area violence increased. Thus, violence increased
due to a crisis between conflicting urban and rural societies.
This may be a reason why feuds erupted at the turning point from
57
~reindustrial to industrial society.71 ~his could help explain
'.'IllY 'violence occurred in Rutherford County.
As stated ~arlier, Rutherford County had a basic agrarian
economy with only one small urban center, ;;Iurfreesboro. The tenth
district, where much.of this violence took place, is approximately
.,' 'I _
fifteen miles southwest 01' this urban center. .t5y the second
decade of the twentieth century the district's one industry that
hired significantly, the pencil mill, had closed shop; it moved
closer to the urban centers of r-'lurfreesboro and NashvilJe due
to distribution cost. Furthermore, the population of the tenth
district continued to decrease during this period until the
automobile and the advent of the commuter. Can the decrease
in population be directly contributed to the people of this area
migrating to the fast-growing urban centers? Did this decrease
in population and the area's isolation from a major urban center
breed a sense of despair or discontent? Did these factors contribute
to an eruption of feud violence in Rutherford County? These are
difficult questions to answer and deserve more indepth research.
Yet, one point is clear. The period between 1907 and 1912 was a
violent one for Rutherford County.
59
~ND :WTES
as}1vi.lle&#183;~m8r~c::m, 15 Lay 1~11 ,
5-1 ..,
;Cl---2_11Doal-: &#8226;
F' &#183;':ioi11c Journal and J..'hG r:'ews Banner, 'C:ews:Daper clippil:'.gS
fro:;~ 2.. s2rapboo~\: !:81d as 8. 1)1"1 \Tate; colli::ct.i..,~"'n by ~:rs. :.uth Stca.;sall
~)f : 11:):'.I~r,:;ssbo::'o. '~;liprlngs do not designat e wh5.ch pare:r.s they ca:.le
:1"'..'01:, o:c t.1l:: dat8 of publicat5.on. Since tll!:'?sc articles did not
:":'~':.' ;?:':::' i j) th:: '8,&#8226;.311vi11e pal;ers , it is being assumed they came from
t:L':: }.o2D.l .papers, t!..1.e T~o::)e Journal and t:le ~&#183;e\'ls De,nner. :From this
!.ot~; ()~), art: cles tak211 from thj.s scrapboolc ','/ill be referred to ill
t}l:::,Cldilotes as S-.::ral)book).
.-. ",
:).,-.:, .:"'_orC.~J-~ll . 0 t '?b00'I:" . I a_1 t er l~'~a"lv- e::l.
))Tbid., :;18S ,;ab.G :i.i'loy\!.
17-- . ~
... Old.
'1, .
',.;., , -:i l)ici., ':j.lliaJ:} A8.~.::,to':.
"''7
'~I ~ra").)oc);'
.l., .:; l i\.&#8226;
;~
-.' _ore;;~21:- otebool&lt;, ~0::1 lIoltoE.
22J-ames,........;:"..'..0 t t er, " -..,~\euc1.s in. .'\.1)Dalachia: .:~n Overview,1I
T~lt-~ Ij'ilson Slub &#183;~uarterly 56 (July 1~;82): 295.
)!l .
"'~~~D~sse2,Jou~ty Court Foremanotebook (1~OS-1913).
.,~.';.. _) J~:.~t2d.. ~.'ld.s :::'uthc:c.;~ord~~ou;~ty Jourt forc'n.an' s noteboolc
~o~t~i~~ ~rfi~nvits by DCO)'.C rcportinc civil and criDinal
oi.'i'&#183;:: ..3c:s, aleo testi:;~onies for the :::l..i.. rcuit Court.&#183; From thL:; note
G.:, t:::3tiTJoJ::Les t":l&lt;cn ..fr&#183; m thL:1 notcboolc \'/ill be referred to as
._'or::::o,::~otebook fol:~_o\\Ted ]):, tJ ' e name of the l)erSOn :"iv';117 t'le
t :.~ :::. t i_ !.~O].:}T &#8226; ... .L L.J _. ~l J.
,
1'Phe ~ie..shville American, 16 September 1907.
20 &#8226; L. Sonnichsen, I'll ~-~...,-~.r;,.;;~...;;..-.~~~~.;.;.;.;p;..;..._.::.;.;;;.;;.,.,....;;.,p;.:~
of the Great Feuds of Texas
3-4. J ; _( ~p.
3.'.1L'1.. 1l'am ~.~ eag1 e, The '.,,ues t _f' or .-Law (,I.,ew Yor1c: Alfred :;1.
~~nopf,1941), pp. 36-37.
it
'John ~. ?ance and R. Fred Kance, compilers, The Histor* of
,rcrsail12s Tent~l District ar;d Its PeoDle (I!iurfreesboro: Rut erford
County T[istorical Society, 198 , p. 1 &#8226; Ivey 1' &#8226;. Jurns married
Julia .J..nne Boatwri,sht on January 12, 1fA 7 and had eieht children,
four boys mId four girls. Of ~Ie four Cirls, three m~rried men
froT!! the Jockvale Community of Rutherford County. :Frances A. Burns
married ;/illiam A. fvI;;rgcm, J:1ary Burns rr.arr5.ed Jim Ralston, and
~lice Burns married Bill Pate. Of the four sons, one of these
was John T. Burns. For more information concerning the Burns and
&gt;:orzar. famili es refer to John \'!. !~ance, The History of Versailles
(p &#8226; 26-27, 1&#183;66-167).
,.. . 5JIJterview with Horace ~I. Burns, Roclwale, T'nnessee,
1u .ovS'mber 1986. The knowledge of the Burns-r-iorgan feud was
revealed by my grandfather, }!orace ~{. ]Jurns, on a cold winter
d8y it l 192.5 as he sat upon his great grandfather t s grave on a
~1.ill f..~ide in Roclcvale. For this revelation, I am ereatly
indebted.
6Ibid &#8226;
7Tl1e ~~ashville Ameri can, 16 September 1907.
8 Tb 'd -'- l &#8226;
Ci
"':8. J. ~s.a:nage, "Ho'1icide i11 the Southern states, II Sewanee
}evi~w 4(1895-1096):213-214 &#8226;.
10
The ~.abhville American, 16 September 1907.
11 Ibid &#8226;
12Intervtew with Horace .!I. Burns.
13The l'~ashville American, 16 September 1907.
14Tennessee, Criminal ~inute Book, Rutherford County (1907&#173;1911).
1']11.
j'"~ Ibid., T3. 'e.n':. ,,'\..'''ut_l edp~:e &#8226;
35 Ibid ., G. ~. Burns.
36.scrapbook.
37Ibid &#8226;
-0
)uT_.'D1'd &#8226;
3Cl d th i~ashville American, 28 ~Tovember
"':.ashville TennesBean an e
40scrapbook.
41 Ibid &#8226;
42 Ibid .&#8226;'
43 Ibid &#8226;
44Foreman l'otebook, Dr. J. T. Harris.
45 Ibid ., ::;vrton Holloway.
46.3c:l::'apbook.
471--b1' d.
4GIbid.
4SForeman :':'otebook, Clarence Campbell.
50 Ibid &#8226;
51 Ibid &#8226;
52Ibid., 3d &#183;dilliamson.
53 Ibid ., Aif Alcorn.
54&#183;Scrapbook.
55 Ibid &#8226;
56 Ibid &#8226;
57Fore~an Notebook.
r::n
)0I bid.
59 Ibid ., S. r. Blankinship.
61
62 63
--O;;j~ T011~j"al al1d ":l11('&gt;. lTe-"'" ~.... '0 &#8226; l' . 0 0 .; '! v L ..&#8226; .J.. __ C , .&#8226;. _. __ ,'" ~oY(:J Dn.nner, .".cwspnper c lplJlngs from prlvate
col1ectlO::l. Cl1pplngs do not designate which paper they
caJJJe fror;}, or the date. .
::Jurl:S, ~I. H. ~-:ockvale, Tennessee. Interviev!, 16 Eovcrnber 1986.
American History Illustrated,
Company, 8 7.
Famous Feuds and Tra. edies.
___~"'". lI~he ~Iatfjoeld-Ec(;oy Feud. 1\
1(3 1966):28-37.
~~lotter, James c. "ii'euds in .'\'ppa1achia: Itn Overvie';:." The Filson
81ub ~Iistory '.~uarterl;y 56(July 1982):290-317.
Jones, ~,Tirgil C. The .i:Iatfi elds and the !''-IcCoys. Chapel Hill:
The Universi ty o~, ~'~?rth Carolina Press, 1945.
'"io- ~r Tos epl1. ,'" "nOC1' al fPh ht Tr 0 d' - .:, be ,~, u . ~ v. ,;) _ oue as 'IOlce H'l l.\ural ;Uddle Tennessee
.: 8':1Spa~:~ers, 1878-1898. II Tennessee Historical '.~uarterly
S(~une 1950):131-154.
~eyburn, James G. Frontier -;i'ollc.'.''aOv! s. "l:''e\,1 &#8226;~Iaven : Ya 1 e Un&#183;lverSl. t y
J?rcss, 1935.
Isaac, Paul:::;. :r:rohibition and Folitics: Turbulent Decades iYJ.
J:er.nesseGl 1885-1920. Knoxville: Universi ty of Tennessee
J.T e s s, 19 5.
!~OusGer, J. i&#183;;organ. The 3ha&#183;...,il1tT of Southern Politics&#183;
.:.\.~~trict~ons__and t.tw ~~stablishment of the One-Pa;t Sou
TI.:[-&#183;O-1 '::"e'l'I Haven: Ya e Universi y Press, 19 4.
T&#183;acy, _., '~~c ,:8.ussell. "~~el:messee Teetotalism: Social Fore es and the
l:O_ltl.CS Pr0&lt;fresslvlsm.lI Tennessee Historical Quarterly
24(Fall 1965;:219-240. ' -
::acogdoches, Texas. Stephen F. Austin State College Library,
::;ast Texas Collection. George Louis Crocket Papers.
~~ance!l John ':". al:.d Eance,:-.F,. Fred, comps. The History of Versailles,
Leuth Dlstrlct and I~s People. ~urfreesboro: Rutherford
;)ounty Historical Society, 1983 &#8226;
2;ashv~ lle 3anner. 15 Eay 1911, p. 11 &#8226;
!,iutzenburg, Charles G.
I-Iyden, Ky.: Hyden
1lifhe lJorthern California
11(4 1972):670-674 &#8226;
Historical Studies of American
tew York: . Oxford University Press,
strain of Violence:
Violence and Vigilantism.
1975.
:~.b~'j cr, ;';ichael and Tobin, ~':ugene, eds. The.Ae;e of Urban lleform.
lort ":[as~inc;ton, ;';ew York: Kennikat Press, 1977.
\
Gralla;:" ;Iu~h Davis and Gurr, Ted Roberts, eds. The :Iistory of
.:i olence ; n !U71er:i Cll: Hi storical and Com arative Persnectives.
"e\;/ Yorl~: 5'redericl&lt;: A. Praeger, 19 9.
80r1:"" ~:.obert ',';. Tennessee: A Short j{i:.:;tor
o
,. Ynoxville:
'?he University 0 Tennessee J.-ress, 198 &#8226;
Cutler, J. ~:~. Lynch Lav/. ~&#183;:ontclair ";ow Jersey: ro.tterson
Smith, 1969.
~ay, John F. Bloody Ground. Garden City, New York: Doubleday,
1941.
C2.rranco, I,yrno!ood and Beard, ~&#183;~stle.
....rendetta. \I Journal of the ':,'est
&#8226; "The _trchives of Violence." ;\merican Archivist
----~4~1~(October 1978):431.
3mlers ,&#183;.:i.:.liam Lavalle. "Farmers and Reformers in an Urban Age:
The country TJife I':Iovement and th&#183;.; Eural I'roblem, 1900-1920.'"
I'll. D. dissertation, University of Iowa, 1968.
?.rOVl11 , ~Uchard ;:a..",{\'1eii'.&#183;: "Southern Violence - Regional Pr?bl~m 0 or
.;: ational }~em~sis'f: Legal Attitudes ~oward Southern .l:IOmlClde
i~1 Historical Perspective. II 7anderbilt Law Review
32(January 1979):225-250.
.}ut~ncl.j;, ~lerbert G. ::!ork , Culture and Society in Industrializine
..\JT!erica. :' ew Yor1(: :~no:pf, Random IIouse, 1976.
r'_,' '-T,:,,-91'11 , ';f/ &#8226;.T.l. m1.l"le .')t".'"Logressive Years: America Comes of Age. ~o:rew
Yor',:~: Dodd, ;,~ead, 1975.
:'.arever, 'l',:1ffiara ~~. and Vinovs!d, Haris, eds. Family and populati.on
L"l :il1eteenth ;~cntury America. Pr5.nceton, '1~ew Jersey:
lrinceto~ University Tress, 197C.
~Iistorical Records Survey, ~~ennessee. Inventory of the Cour:ty
;rchives of Tennessee: Rutherford Count. ~R8hvil1e:
~:he Survey, ::r:'J!\, 1938.
J.amace, B. J. II T:Iomicide in the Southern States. II .sewanee Review
4(1GS5-1G96):212-Z31~
::e2og1e, :!illiam. 1:he (2uest for :Lm-/. rel,'" Yorl~: ~1.C' d-J 1~;I~ 1 &#8226; .!'"- J.re J". Knopf,
----------
64
.~~c.~:iro, ':c~:ry :!:. 3alachia O~l C'ur J,:ind: th8 Southern ~'lountains
cd::.d ;;oulitaineers In t~'lC fiJnerican Consciousness. Cha:gel Hill:
. LJJ~ivers5.ty of Nl;rth Carolina iress, 1978.
"::i &#183;,s, :';&#163;1rltOl'~ ;.;., ed. A JTistory of J1utherford County. ~'!urfreesboro:
8arlton 3i~s, 1947.
JO('l).ic:lsen, Ch8.rles I,eland. I'll Die Before I'll Run: The story
of the G~eat 7euds of Texas. New York: Devin-Adair Co.,
'Tt)62.
"::nydor, ::;harles. "The Southerners and the JJ3.\'1. II Journal of ,Southern
:~istory 6(February 1S40) :2-23.
~lr~~1nsssee. COlU1t~T Court Foreman :i:Totebook, 1'908-1913.
!.i~elll1eSsee. Crimil'la1. J'.iinuter;. J.utherford County Circuit Court.
1 December 1910.
lenncssee. Death Records. ~utherford County, 1881-1912.
Tennessee state I,ibrary and Archives. IIInventory of Rutherford
::;OUllt~i" ilecords. II ~:~ashville :'3tate Librar/ and Archlv es, 1964-.
Unpublis~cd typescript.
'.'::11'; 'a.3hv i lle Amer.ican, 16 SepteJ!1ber 1907.
~:18 rl'ennesscan and ~~ashville I'J1lerican, 15 I'Iay 1S11, p. 1.
TinDer12.ke, James H. I'rohibition and the }rop;ressive i.'Iovement,
1900-1920. ~~w York: Atheneum, 1970;
~J. .'. DCp2xtme,nt of Commerc e. Bureau of the Census. Thirteenth
Census of tb.e United States, 1910: l'opulation, vol. 3.
i:anuscript census for the Tenth District of Rutherford
Sounty. Twelth Census of the United States, 1900.
____~--. fIanusGript ce~us for the Tenth District of Rutherford
!:~OUl1ty. Thirteenth r;ensus of the United states, 1910~
',,'est 'TirB;inia University Library. Frederick B. Lambert Papers.
,fiebe, ;~obert:r. The Search for Order, 1877-1920. new York: Hill
and \','ang, 1967.
':,'0 0 dv:ard , C.Yann. Ori ins of the I~ew South 1877-1913. Baton
::::ouge: IJoui;siana Sta e Universi y Press, 19 &#8226;
!~aretsky, ::li Sherman. "Progressive Thoue;ht on the Impact of
lndustrialization on the Family and Its Relations to the
,&#183;-''mergence of the ;'lelfare State, 1890-1920." Ph.D.
dissertation, Universi.ty of Maryland, 1979.
A
Alcorn, Alf.; ;_.52
Alcorn, Ordey 44-46
Alexander, Polly 54
Alexander, Reuben 54
Anderson, B. F.... 25 ;26
Anderson, E.W 26
Anderson, J.L 26
Anderson, Samuel 10
Army of Tennessee.13,19
B
Baird, John L 27
Baldwin, Dr 9
Baskin, A.J 49
Bass, A.J 14,26
Batey,B.B 25,26
Batey, J.B 27
Batey, Sheriff W 44
Batey, W.O 27
Bates Division 21
Battle of Chickamauga
' 19
Battle of Kennesaw Mt.
&#183; ..... 21
Battle of Missionary
Ridge .. 19, 20
Battle of Perryville
&#183; .15,&#183;,16
Battle of Shiloh ..... 14
Battle of Stones River
&#183; .17, 18
Becton, J.W 47
Beesley, James W 27
Beesley, John 27
Beesley, J.M 25, 27
Beesley, T.J 27
Beachboard, William .. 27
Beauregard, Gen 7
Blair, A.H 27
Blair, J.L 27
Blankinship, Hoover .. 52
Blankinship, S.F 53
Bock, Adam 27
Boring, T.M 16,27
Bragg, Gen. BraNton
. .. 17, 18
','
- :INDEX
~rooks, C.C 27
Brothers, A.W 28
Brown, Dock 53
~ryant, S.N 52,53
Burrows, T.W 28
Burns, Frances 37
Burns, Ivey 37
Burns, John 36--46
Burns; G~W_&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226; '&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226; 45
Burns, Wash 44
Burns, Will 44-46
Butler, I.W. 20, 28
C
Camp Cheatham 9
Camp Maney 13
Camp Harris 9
Camp Haynes 10
Campbell, Clarence 49-51
Campbell, Gov 9
Carlton, Ernest 44,45
Carney., L. V 28
Cates, Joe D 16,28
Cheat Mt. Campaign. 11 , 12.:
Cheat Pass 11,12
Cheatham, Gen.B.F. 14,16
...... 21
Clark, George 16,28
Clay, D.D 28
Collier, F.W 28
Cooper, F.W 11
Cooper, T.C 28
Crass, F.H 28
Crichlow, Sam &#8226;.&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;&#8226;..&#8226; 28
Crockett, T.O 20,28
D
Davis, Jefferson &#8226;. 7,13,
...... 19, 23
Davis, Sammy 11,28
Davis, Samuel 20,28
Day, Mr 49
Dickson, Ed 52
Dickson, L.M 15,28
Dixson, Eddie 53
Die, Harry 52
65
</dc:description>
<dc:description>Describes accounts of criminal violence in Rutherford County between 1907 and 1912, particularly related to feuds between families</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.); Murfreesboro (Tenn.); Violent crimes</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Feuds</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>16 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-01-26; mt2011-02-08</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication31ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/23</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>