<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Revolutionary pension record of John M. Leak</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Leak, John M.</dc:creator>
<dc:contributor>Fry, Edna</dc:contributor>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 14</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1831</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1770-1779; 1780-1789; 1830-1839</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>72
REVOLUTIONARY PENSICN REG CRD of John M. Leak
Furnished by Mrs. Edna Fry
STATE OF TENNESSEE )
) Circuit Court, October Term 1831
RUTHERFOID COUNTY )
On this day October 21, 1831 personally appeared in
open court before the honorable Thomas Stewart, Judge,
now sitting for said county, John M. Leak, a resident of
the county and state aforesaid, aged seventy five years;
who being first sworn according to law, doth on his oath
make the following declaration in order to obtain the benefit
of the act of Congress passed June 7th 1832. He states that
he was born in Amherst County, State of Virginia in the year
1758, and in January 1777 (this he is not certain) he entered
the service of his country, from the county of Amherst as a
substitute in the place of William Johnston. Declarent was
then in his seventeenth year. His Captain was David Shelton.
He was marched to the barracks in Albermarle County to aid
in guarding the prisoners then at that place. Declarent
remained in service one month; was discharged and returned home.
In April of the same year declarent was drafted and
called out under Capt. John Deggs from the county of Amherst,
and rendezvoused at the Barracks in Albermarle upon the same
duty and after a service of one month was discharged and
returned home. Declarent thinks that Col. Taylor of the
regular Army commanded at the barracks.
73
In November of the same year declarent entered the
service as a substitute for Josias Dodd from the county of
Amherst, and was attached to Capt. John Christian's Company,
and again marched to the Barracks in Albermarle to guard
prisoners; and was in service one month, was discharged and
returned home.
Declarent was again drafted from that county of Amherst
and was attached to Capt. Richard Ballingers conpany. He
cannot recall the year but believes that it was the same
year or about the time that Arnold burnt Richmond, or the
public stores at that place. And in the month of January,
was marched to Albermarle old court house and there joined
a company commanded by capt. Joseph Tucker. The corps was
transported in canoes down the river within eighteen miles
of Richmond and was there disembarked and marched down to
the city. When the detachment reached Richmond, Capt.
Ballengers company was ordered to Hoods Fort and Capt.
Tuckers to Williamsburg. Capt. Ballengers command was
conveyed to Hoods Fort by water. The duty of the corps
on its arrival at the Fort was to guard it. Declarent
remained in service three months; was discharged and re-turned
home, and he reached home the last of May, and
declarent believes that this last tour of service was
performed in the year 1780.
The tenth of August 1781 declarent was again drafted
in the county of Amherst and entered the service under the
command of Col. Daniel Gaines. The corps was two hundred
The stores at Richmond wete burned Jan. 5, 1781
74
strong and was marched by the commanding officer to Rich-mond
and from there to Williamsburg, where we halted one
day. The French had reached that place, and the corp under
the command of Col Gaines was halted, until they passed
in front and the whole command then moved on to York.
While stationed at York declarent was detached part of the
time to drive a wagon for the purpose of transporting bread
from Williamsburg for Gen. Lawson's brigade. After the
capture of Lord Corn Wallace, declarent was ( ? ) and
marched with the Army to Pages Wharehouse in (Parmanky ?)
and at that point was discharged and returned home. In the
last campaign declarent was in service three months and
ten days. Declarent recollects that one (Mifsous)? was the
Quartermaster and that Thos. Low was the deputy quartermaster.
Declarent was never in any battle. Declarent recollects of
seeing at Albermarle Barracks Col. Taylor and Lee and of
Hardin of the regular army. And at York he saw Genl.
Washington, The Steuben, and he recollects a Frenchman,
a slender young man called the Marquis. He saw Genl. Wayne,
who commanded the New England troops.
Declarent has no record of his age; he was born in
17 58-Amherst County-State of Virginia, and remained there
after the war until the year 1795, and then moved to Rock-bridge
County, and in 1811 moved to Knox County, State of
Tennessee and in 1821 to Wilson County, and for the last
three years declarent has resided in Rutherford County,
Tennessee where he now lives. Declarent never had but one
discharge, and that was from Capt. Ballinger which has been
75
destroyed. Declarent is acquainted in his neighborhood with
Wm. Davis, William Walker, Thomas Nevil, (Edmond) Thompson,
John Edmondson, William Thompson, Joseph Cannon, Nimrod
Thompson, all of whom declarent believes will testify to
his character for veracity and their belief of his service
as a soldier of the revolution. And in the neighborhodd
where declarent moved from Wilson County where he is better
known, he can name John Sneed, William Holland, Lemuel
, James Ewing, Nelson (Bayan) , Mathew , Wm. Davis
and Rich. Hanneh all of whom would testify to their belief
of declarent serving in the war of the Revolution and to
his character for vericity. Declarent has no documentary
evidence in his possession by which he can prove his said
service, and he knows of no one now living by whom he can
prove them.
He hereby relinquishes every claim whatsoever to a
pension annuity except the present, and declares that his
name is not on the pension roll of the Agency.
Sworn to and subscribed this day and year aforesaid.
his
John M. X Leak
Mark
We William Walker, Thos. Cannon and Joseph Cannon
residing in the neighborhood of JOhn M. Leak, Hereby
certify that we are well acquainted with said Leak, who
has subscribed and sworn to the foregoing declaration.
That we believe him to be seventy five years of age;
that he is reported and believed in the neighborhood
76
where he resides, to have been a soldier of the Revolution
and tint we concur in that opinion.
Sworn to and subscribed this day and year aforesaid.
William Walker
Theophilus A. Cannon
Joseph Cannon
A letter attached to the pension application from the
Pension office at Nashville, Tennessee dated Nov. 14, 1840
Sir,
At the request of Mr. Mask Leak, the adm. of John M.
Leak, his father, who was Pensioner under the act of 7th
June 1832 and who died on the 24th day of August last, I
enclose to you the preceeding of the court in the case on
which he expect to draw the areers of the pension due the
deceased under the act of the 19 June 1840.
As I have not been furnished with any form or instruct-ions
under the provisions of the above mentioned act I have
declined making any payments to admins, or executors until
I shall be furnished with such form or instructions, by the
proper department as will enable me, to correctly, to make
such payments.
Very respectfully
J. M. Smith</dc:description>
<dc:description>A reprint of Revolutionary War soldier John Leak's petition to Rutherford County courts for a pension from his years of service; includes a letter to the Nashville office inquiring whether to provide Leak's son with the remainder of the pension, as Leak had recently died</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Military pensions; United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1783</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>veterans</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>9 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-01</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication14ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/144</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>