<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Hopewell Presbyterian Church records 1832 - 1883 Rutherford County, Tennessee</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Coffey, Laura Lou White</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 7</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1976</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1830-1839; 1840-1849; 1850-1859; 1860-1869; 1870-1879; 1880-1889</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>22
HOPEWELL PRESBYTERIAN CHURCH RECORDS I832-I883
RUTHERFORD COUNTY, TENNESSEE
by LAURA LOU WHITE COFFEY
Visiting a dear friend one cold winter day was a most fortu-nate
occasion. Although very ill, my friend was cognizant of my
interest in history, reading my column in the Democrat-Union each
week called "From the Old Courthouse Attic" which contained all
the accumulation of ancient papers since the old courthouse was
built.
This unnamed friend asked if I would like to see some old
church books that had been handed down in his family for several
generations. Of course I was interested, and upon examination I
found what you are about to read. Taking the books home, I became
more and more excited and I Just had to get the information down
on paper somehow. Asking permission in the name of the National
Society Daughters of the American Revolution to copy the book
for the Genealogical Research Department of the National Library,
I was granted permission if I promised to not divulge the source
of my findings, to both protect the family and to keep them from
being constantly bothered with inquiries, not because of dis-interest,
but because of his illness. I agreed, I started copy-ing,
and within a month he was dead. The family wanted me to
complete the work I started and I did, still keeping my promise.
The material was sent into Washington and credit was given Buffalo
River Chapter DAR for the year 1975-1976 as un-published material.
I thank God for letting me be at the right place at the right
time so that these beautiful records were made available to all
who are interested. It is my desire that you the reader receive
the same blessing from reading these pages that I have received in
"THE RECORDS OF HOPEWELL CHURCH VOLUME II
COMMENCING APRIL 1st, I832"
"There are at this time 45 members In communion of the Church.
July 7th, 1832 Session met at the request of the Moderator. Mem-bers
present: Rev. Jessee Alexander, Abner Alexander, William W.
Knight, and John Baxter constituted with prayer."
"The Moderator laid before session a letter which he had
received from Joseph Sharp, a member of Session, in which he
stated his determination to withdraw from the Church and to have
his name erased from our list. --On motion, resolved that in as
much as J. Sharp's character has been attainted, by publick
though no legal pie has been brought against him, and as the
he
session has evidence that/would not attend to any citation--and
as in their judgement the interest of the Church would be as well
supported in his withdrawal, as in his suspension, Therefore
resolved that his name be stricken from our list and he be no
longer considered a member of the Presbyterian Church--Session
adjourned with prayer. --August 9, l832:- A campmeeting was held
at Center Campground within the boundries of this Church--Com-menced
on the 9th of August I832. The whole process of the meet-ing
was marked for good order and attention. Deep solemnity
marked the face of the assembly, while attending in the ministra-tion
of the Word the order of public worship were generaly spent,
by the profession in prayer for their anxious friends in the
groves. About 25 made profession of religion at the meeting."
24
Milton, Tenn. Rutherford County
"August l4th Baptized William &#165;. Knight (This may be McKnlght
as writing Is not plain, but I have reason to believe it is
McKnlght) daughter, Sarah E. Born July l6th, 1832."
"August 24th 1832. Admitted to communion, r.eorge Peebles
and Folemna Smith and administered to her the ordinance of
Baptism. Died on the 21st of August Esther Farr."
"November 10th: Baptized Jesse Alexander's son George A.
Born 16th August 1832."
"November 10th Admitted to communion Jane Knox, and adminis-tered
to her the Ordinance of Baptism&#8212;Nov. 10th, Dismissed
David Morlson, a member of Session with his wife Thezla and their
two daughters Caroline and Ann. Reported to Presbytery 1st April
1833."
(Note. All the minutes of these two books will be printed ver-batum,
so quotation marks will from this point on be omitted)
A Campmeeting was held at the Centre Campground commencing
26th September I833. To this meeting, the Church had been look-ing
forward with prayerful anxiety, and God appeared to be
gracious by entreated for this meeting exceeded all previous
meetings at this place; in the display of Almighty power in the
conviction and converstlon of sinners. About 50 made profession
of religion.
2nd October I832 Session received into Church membership on
examination Ambrose Runnels with his wife Mary. Both received
the ordination of Baptism. Also received Rebecaka M. Alexander,
Martha C. Peebles, Mary A. Alexander, Robert T. Barton, James S.
25
Alexander and Polly Black, This last received the ordinance of
I '.apt ism.
0th October. Session received into iTK^mberslilp on exaniJ.nal- Ion
:
Anon Armstrong, Samuel B, Harwell, Williamson Castrey, James
Pinketon, Mary Dills. These all received the ordinance of Baptism.
Received also the following who had been Baptized in infancy.
Mary Thomas and Joseph A. Knox.
9th November I833. Session received into Membership on
examination, Parthenia Donoho, Benjamin Norgan and Rachel Morgan,
the two latter received the ordinance of Baptism. Also (Caroline,
a black person who received baptism. 2nd March l834. Session
met for the purpose of choosing a delegate to Presbytery. Members
Present: Rev. Jesse Alexander, William McKnight and John Baxter.
A. Alexander received the appointment. Wm. McKnight C. S.
Report: Total in communion 43. Members added 20. Members
examined and approved except in the case of Mr. Sharp, Signed
George Newton Moderator of Shiloh Presby_
3rd April l834. Baptized four children of Ambrose and Mary
Reynolds, ages and names as follows. John A. Born 7th October l829
Hannah M. " 7th February I831
William R. " 9th October I832
Mary Jane " 2nd January 183^
At Centre Camp collected for missionary purposes $5.56-^
and put the same into the hand of Lorenze D. Butts, Agent for the
Western Forreign Missionary Society.
At Hopewell Meeting house 15th July contributed to missions
through Rev. A. Morison $3.50, Collected for the Presbytery's
Missionary Society $7.75. November Dismissed Robert Morison and
his wife Edith.
26
11th Sept. 1834 Camp meeting met at Centre Camp and con-tinued
several days. We think, it may be truly said that this
was an interesting meeting--the preachers were zealous, diligent
and persevering in their labors of love. Professions were indus-trious
in their appropriate duties and appeared to be much
received--Sinners were cut to the heart and made to inquire in
good earnest. "Men and Brethern, what shall we do?:i"--The two
last days of the meeting did appear to be blessed with the felt
presence of the Good Spirit--To God's Name Give the Gloryl More
than fifty persons professed to have found peace in believing.
During the meeting the following persons were received into the
church by examination.
-
David M. McKnight, Wilson Alexander, James McKnight, Enos
McKnight, Moses W. McKnight, Jonathan McNeman. The following
were received by examination and received Baptism*
Alenis A. Black, Hannah Reynolds, Nancy B. Reynolds, Alexander
Doran, Ann Powell,
18th Sept. Baptized Orvel Alexander's son Jesse Eagleton, Born
24th July 1834.
Session met and appointed John Baxter delegate to Presbytery.
March I835 Dismissed Alexander Doran and his wife Nancy.
July 30th, 1835: Died: Miss P.plemna Smith (Polemna)
Sept. 10, 1835: Met in Campmeeting at Centre Campground--
The meeting continued until l6th September.- This was a time of
sickness and of some perplexities in the neighborhood, yet the
meeting was tolerably attended. We had solemn, searching preach-ing
and pungent exhortations. Many prayers were offered for the
27
influence of the Holy Spirit to bear home the word to the hearts
of the hearers. God was gracious I &#8212;His Spirit was poured outl--
Many were convicted--And as many as 30 were hopefully converted.
l6th Sep. 1835. Session met, constituted with prayer--The
following members were received on examination. Elam McKnight,
Theresa McKnight, Mary and Marinda Cook&#8212;the three females just
named were given the ordinance of Baptism. Note: Other meetings
of session and other to the church during Campmeeting are
recorded in the session book of Stones River Church.
16th Sep. Honourable dismissed Cynthia Thomas.
1st Nov. 1835- Session met at Hopewell, constituted by
prayer, and received by examination Ann Morgan and Rachel, a
black woman--These both received the ordinance of Baptism--Said
Rachel's infant Tilpa received baptism the same day. (Report at
end of year April I836 shows total now in Communion 78 and Wm.
McKnight was C. S.) (Examined and approved by Amezi Bradshaw
Moderator of Presbytery.)
29th May 1836:- Hopewell Session met, constituted with prayer,
and received into church membership by certificate from the
regular Baptist Church Nancy Hooper. Concluded with prayer.
May 30th. A collection of $12.43 and 3A^ was taken up for
the Bible Society and put in the hands of Wm. McKnight until
called for by the present society. Baptised Gideon B. Alexander,
son of Jesse and Eliza Alexander, Born 28th April I836.
1st Sept. 1836 Campmeeting commenced at Centre Campground
and continued until the 7th. Preachers in attendance were: Rev.
J. Alexander, Wm. Eagleton, B. Pryland, J, Allison, D. D. Thorn
and J. Porter. The preachers were industrious. Their heads and
28
hearts appeared to be faithfully engaged in their several labors.
Professors in general appeared solemn and prayerful and "kindly
affectionate one towards another in brotherly love." Non pro-fessors
were in a good degree sober and attentive. -The spirit
of prayer and supplication was given to the church; and in
answer to many prayers the same spirit of the Lord did work
mightily amongst those, who had been careless and secure. -Many
were convinced of their sin and were constrained to cry mightily
for mercy. As many as 30 professed conversion to God.
3rd Sept. Session met, constituted with prayer. Edward S.
Weatherford was received into church membership on a certificate
from the regular Baptist Church. Also Elisha Saunders was
received on certificate. Also Nancy Thays and Porthenia Donoho
were received on examination. The last of these received baptism.
Concluded with prayer.
5th Sept. Session met, constituted with prayer and the fol-lowing
members were received on examination. Andrew Barkley,
Eleanor J. McDaniel, Jane R. Barkley, Precilla W. Barkley, George
Cook. The three last received the ordinance of baptism. Concluded
with prayer.
Collected for the Missionary Society of Shilo. $6.00, for
the Commissioners fund $9.00.
Sept. 11, Session met, constituted with prayer. Martha F.
McWhirter was received to membership on examination. Concluded
with prayer.
15th Nov. 1836. Baptised Alexander D. McKnight, born 30th
Sept. 1830.
Eagleton A. McKnight, born 28th
Feb. 1832
29
Mary E. McKnight, born 17th
July 1836.
these being the children of James and Nancy McKnight.
1st Jan. 1837. Collected at Hopewell for F. Missions. $13.00.
Signed &#165;m. McKnight, C. S.
(Report shows increase of 10 since last report, membership
88. Also total of $12.43 and Z/H in Bible Society fund.)
(April 7th, I837) (Examined and approved report thus far, signed
John Allison, Moderator of Presbytery.
28th April, 1837. Put into the hand of Rev. Anozi Bradshaw,
Agent for B. C.
30th April 1837. Baptized Mary Palemna, daughter of John
and Elizabeth Baxter born 26th of November 1836.
3 July. Baptized Alezira Angeline, daughter of Oswin and
Ann Alexander, born l8th of May l837.
2nd August, Rev. A. Bradshaw, Agent of the Bible Society
preached at Centre Camp and a collection taken up and handed to
him $5.84.
A protracted meeting commenced on the 1st and closed on the
5th Sept. at Centre Camp Ground. At this meeting the friends of
the Redeemer met with some trials and difficulties which were
calculated to try their faith and increase their humility. Yet
the Lord (in great mercy) did give us a refreshing season, did
make some of the stout hearted to bow and cry for mercy and did
bind up the broken in heart. Several persons -'ere enabled to
rejoice in the hope of pardoned sin and peace with God. Through
the Redeemer, the number of hopeful converts at this meeting is
not exactly known, but it is believed to be about twenty.
30
2nd Sept. Revd. Thomas Hall preached at Centre Campground
in behalf of the exucation Society and took a collection of
$10.87^.
3rd Sept. Baptized James Grier, son of Robert and Isabella
Cummins, born October l837.
4th Sept. Session met, was opened by Prayer and the follow-ing
persons were received into the church on examination: Elvizy
Sarah Moore, Hannah Barkley, Ann Eliza Berkley and Sarah Roberts,
the last two were baptized.
6th Sept. John H. Baxter duly appointed as delegate to
Senate (Synod),
10th Sept. Dismissed Robert and Isabella Cummins.
27th Oct. Session constituted by prayer and received an
examination: Alexander Morrison and G. Morrison.
11th Feb. Rev. J. Alexander preached at Centre Campground
in behalf of Foreign missions took a collection for F. M. $7.62^.
11th Feb. Dismissed Thomas and Isabella and Sarah Powel.
22nd Feb. Collected for the Bible Society $6.25.
31st March. Wm. McKnight appointed delegate to Presbytery.
(Report of the Church of Hopewell from the April l837 to March
1838 shows total membership at 89.) (Received and approved by M.
Marshall, Moderator)
8th of April 1838. Session met constituted with prayer, and
received the following members on certificate. Wm. White, Sarah
White, Jane White Malinda White.
Met at Centre Campground, 30th August and continued in camp-meeting
until 5th Sept. This meeting was, in its general features
31
similar to other campmeetings which have been held at this place,
which are recorded in this book.- The work of life was exhibited
frequently and plainly and was listened to by a large concourse
of people. Many prayers were presented to God that he would
bless the ministration of his word, and the ordinances of his
house to the salvation of souls; and the Lord of Saboath left
not himself with witnesses. Many Christians were fed and
refreshed; -Many of those who had been hitherto impenitent were
made to inquire what they should do to be saved. -As many as six-teen
were enabled (in the judgement of charity) to give up their
hearts to the Lord, and to rejoice in the hope of peace and
pardon, through the blood of the Lord.
2nd Sept. received into the Church on examination, Mary
Morison.
9th Sept. Abner Alexander was appointed Delegate to Presby-tery.
Wm. Mcknight Delegate to Synot.-
l8th November, Rev. Mr. Jones, Agent for the American Board
for Foreign Missions preached at Centre Nursery and took up a
collection of $19.55 for the A. B. F. M.
20th Dec. Dismissed Jane White and Malinda White.
5th January 1839. Dismissed James Pinchkson.
4th Feb. 1839. Died. Mrs. Mary Doran.
1st March, Dismissed Rebecca L. Doran. &#8226;
1st March, Dismissed Raine, woman of colour.
31st March, Baptized Martha Ann, daughter of Jesse and Eliza
Alexander born 17th August 1838.
9th April. Died. Mary Cosbey, (formerly Mary Cook)
15th Received by Certificate. Mrs. Mary R. Alexander.
32
Baptized Samuel Ed^iar, son of James and Nancy McKnight.
Born 21st June I83B.
Baptized William B. Son of John and Mary Alexander, horn
7 Nov. 1838. Signed. Wm. McKnight. C. S. (Report shows 89 mem-bers
April 1838-39.) (Examined and approved thus far at
Fayetteville, April I9, l839j and signed by G. Newton, Moderator
of Shiloh Presbytery)
May 1st, l840. Sacramental meeting commenced at Hopewell
Church. Ministers present. Msgs. Alexander, Eagleton and Potter,
a Missionary Agent, all of which preached the word of Life faith-fully.
A collection was taken up on Sabboth to defray the
expenses of the occasion and if any over to be paid to Mr. Potter.
Monday 4th May l84o. Paid to the Rev. Mr. Potter $11.25.
To the Rev, Mr. Eagleton $4.00 for Pastoral letter.
May 13, l84o. Died. Mr. William McKnight, ruling Elder of
Hopewell Church and also Clerk of Session.
Monday l4th day of Sept. l84o. died. Mrs. Eliza Knox,
(formerly Eliza D. Dill).
Thursday 17th Sept. Met in Campmeeting at Centre Campground
and continued unti] the following Wednesday.- Our Pastr)r's
assistants were Mssrs. Eagleton and Bradshaw. --Although a time
of serious and general sickness, the meeting was well attended--
The preaching was solemn and pointed. Prayers were frequent and
very earnestly offered for the descent of the Holy Spirit. God
graciously heard, the earnest supplication of his people and many
were brought to inquire after salvation and in the judgement of
Charity we trust somewhere over thirty hopefully converted to God.
Tuesday 22nd. Session appointed Charles Ready delegate to
Synod and delegate to Presbytery.
33
April IPth l84l. Williamson Cnsbey, chosen Clerk of
Session in place of Dr. William Mf;Knight deceased. W 1 HI arnsnn
Cosbey, C. S. (Report to Presbytery shows 90 now in communion
and report was examined and approved thus far, April 11th, l84l
by Amzi Bradshaw. Moderator of Presby.)
June 1, l84l. Commenced a Sacramental meeting at the Centre
Campground on Sabbath of Said Meeting received into Hopewell
Church the following members viz: Martha E. Baxter, Catharine
Stroop, William R. Alexander, Elizabeth A. Morgan, and Henry M.
Morgan. The last two received the ordinance of baptism.
June 6th l84l.- Baptized Sarah R. Baxter, born Aug. 15th
l84o daughter of John N. and E. R. Baxter.
Sept. 23, l84l. Meet in Campmeeting at Centre Campground
and continued until Thursday 30th. Our Pastors assistants were
Messrs. Eagleton, Bradshaw, Ryland and Sloan. The church
experienced great difficulty, from the inclemency of the weather
during the forepart of the meeting. But the ministers ceased
not to warn sinners Solemnly and affectionately. The church
appeared to be upon her knees. Prayers were frequent and solemn
and in answer thereto the Spirit of the Lord descended and many
were made to cry out "Men and Brethern, what shall we do-" They
were directed to the Lamb of God that taketh away the Sins of
the world. -and we hope that the number of twenty-five were
brought sincerely to bow at the feet of Jesus.
On Saturday 28th. Received into membership of Hopewell
Church. James S. McKnight, Nancy E. Alexander, Sarah E. McKnight,
On Sabbath 3rd of Oct. Received Samuel S. Alexander. Samuel
A. McKnight and Edward Donoho which last named received baptism.
34
Feb. 6th l842. Baptized Nancy C. Alexander daughter of
Jesse and Eliza Alexander, born Sept. 25th l84l.
Received Sept. 28th William T. McKnight which should have been
noticed on the foregoing page.
Oct. l84o. Dismissed Mary A. Alexander, formerly Mary A.
Black. Signed Williamson Cosbry. C. S. (Report shows total
membership 101. Examined and approved thus far. Bedford Ryland
Moderator of Shiloh Presbytery)
May 25th l842. Departed this life. Jane Knox.
July 25th. A campmeeting commenced at Centre Campground.
Attended by the united Churches of Stoneriver, Hopewell and
Chapplecreek. It continued 7 days and was interesting minister.
People appeared to partake of the Divine influence about 40
supposed to have imbraced the Savior. During the meeting 12
were added to the three churches. The following were received
into Hopewell Church. Mary Cuningham, Mary S. Saunders, Morton
Armstrong, and the two last mentioned received the ordinance of
baptism.
Another Campmeeting was held at the same place by the same
churches. Commenced on the 22nd of Sept. which was more inter-esting
than the former, the presence of the Lord was felt to be
in the Camp. Christians were reproached, sinners convicted and
many we hope were converted, 75 professed a hope that they had
passed from death to life, 32 were added to the three churches.
The following were received into Hopewell Church. Sarah H.
Neely, James N. Greer, William Greer, Quincy M. Greer, Sarah M.
Armstrong, Ambrose McKee, Abner Knox, Eliza A. Jourdan, Mary A.
Jourdan, Jeremiah P. Jourdon, John F. Morgan, Eliza B. Neely,
35
Elener T. Kook, Stephen Kook, David N. Baxter, Nothunial W. Dunnel,
(this last name is not plain) Samuel P. McKnight, Mary L. Alexander.
Thomas E. Shune . The fourteen first named on the list recei veii
the ordinance of baptism. October 25th. Williamson Cosbey was
dismissed as a member in good standing. David M. McKnight was
appointed session clerk in his place.
Eliza McKnight, Nancy S. Spune and John Q. Spune were
received on certificate Dec. 2nd l842. June Mc Knight died. (I
do not know if this last item goes with the Dec. 2nd l842 notation
or not, but I suppose it does. Writing is so poor that it is
very hard to decipher.)
December 23. A protracted meeting commenced in Hopewell
Church and continued four days. The meeting was well attended.
The people of God appeared to be refreshed and sinners seemed to
feel the force of Divine Truth. Feb. 29. Ebner McKnight Died.
(Report shows 125 members, signed David M. McKnight S. C.
McMinnville May l4th 18^3. Examined and approved thus far,
William Eagleton, Moderator Shiloh.
)
May 9th l843. Baptised James P. (or R. ) son of D. M. and
Eliza A. McKnight. Born Sept. 1st, l842. May 27th paid M.
Potter agent foren mission $7.25. May 25th Session met. Con-stituted
with prayer. Mary A. Knox was received to membership.
Augst. 4th. A. Communion season (Commission session) was held at
Hopewell which continued for four days. This meeting was well
attended ministerial aid William Eagleton preaching was feverent
and edefying.
A campmeeting was held at McKnight Academy commencing on the
last day of August ministerial aid was the two Messrs Deshileds
36
Will Iain I'laril'-ti:)!! and 1"). T . Hl'ian. Preai.'h In,"; &lt;i(i l.he n.-faslDn war.
[jlG,ln f)(")bitoil anil cnnv I nc I rw,. r'.Dluinn ahLonLlt^n wat'. ,":lv(;n hy I, Ik;
lar;j;e assemblyes tViat attended through the whole occasion. Nn\,
much excitement appeared until Thursday evening about 15 pro-fessed
anxiety about their souls interest 10 or 12 professed a
hope in Christ.
Sept. 4th. Session met, constituted with prayer. Isobella
C. Donnel was admitted to communion in the Church.
Sept. 5th. Baptized John H. , Son of John H. and Elizabeth
Baxter born May l4th l843.
October 4th. Dismissed by letter N. W. Danil, 1. R. Jerdon,
Mary A. Jerdon and Eliza A. Jerdon.
December 23rd. A sacremental meeting commenced at Hopewell
Church which continued 4 days. This meeting was pretty well
atended and though our pastor stood solitary and alone, preaching
was edifying and we have evidence to believe the Lord by his Holy
Spirit was with us.
April 1, l844. William McFadden was received to membership
by letter from Murfreesboro Church. Also his wife Clementine by
letter from the Methodist Church of Murfreesboro. James McFadden
was also received by letter from the Presbyterian Church in
Murfreesboro
.
May 1, 1844. Collected for foreign missions $9.75 cts and
paid it over to William Potter.
August 4, 1844. Session met constituted with prayer. John
P. Greer was received on examination and received the ordance of
Baptism.
September 12. A campmeeting was held at Centre Camp. The
37
meeting continued 5 days. Not as interesting as former meetings
although we hope g,oo(] was done. '; expressed a hope in the Savior.
Christians were humbled and felt their dependence on Divine rii-ace.
September 15. Session met constituted with prayer. Hunthew
A. Baxter was received on examination. (this could be Mathew but
(named omitted)
is plain a H. ) Baptized son of John Q and Sarah
Spune.
Sept. l6. William McFadden and his wife Clementine were
dismissed as members in good standing.
October 1, l844 . The Church reported to Presbytery from
Oct. 1, l843 to the present as follows. Members last report 12'3.
added on examination 2 on certificate 3. dismissed G, suspended
0. Total now in communion 124, collected for foreign missions
$4.75. March 27, l845. Rachel, a black person died.
May 2, l845. Session met constituted with prayer. On
examination the records of the church it was found that some
members had removed without applying for certificate, others
had left and joined another church. It being important that
the records give a correct history of the church it is hereby on
motion resolved unanimously that those names be striken from the
list, which are as follows : --Simon, a black person who died and
his death was not recorded in the proper place. Left without
certificate :-McKnlt Alexander, Eliza Farr, John West, Hariet
McKnight, Robert Barton, Mary Thomas, June Kirkpatrick, Elam
McKnight, Wilburn Alexander, Junethen McNamer (or Jonethen M.
Homer,) George Cook, Alexander Morison, James Alexander, Samuel
B. Merel, Elizer A. Black, Martha McWherter, Sarah Roberts.
Examined and approved thus far. Stones River Church May 3rd,
1845. Signed A. H. DaShull, Moderator.
38
August 3i 1845. Baptised the children of Morton W. and
Mary M. Armstrong: William Alonzo Doren, born August 3, l835
Nancy Prunette, born May 12, l837
John Baxter, born July 22, I838
Martha Tennessee, born February 23, l84o
Martin W., born Dec. I6, l84l
Mary Minerva Matilda, born May I8, l844
Also, Mary M. daughter of William B. and T. White and Eliza Jane,
daughter of Tisse and Eliza Alexander.
September I5. Session met constituted with prayer.
Received to membership, John Turk also his wife Muriel Turk on
examination and Mary Barkley on Certificate. Reported to
Presbytery from Oct. 1, l&amp;kk to Oct. 1, l845 as follows: Member-ship
on last report 124. Added on examination 2, on certificate
1, dismissed I7, died 2, total I08. Collected for home missions,
$3.00.
April 1, l846. Collected for commissioners fund, $4.00.
August 4, dismissed Rachel Green, (Greer) also Q. M. Greer
(Green) Wilburn P. Greer and John Greer. (Writer believes these
are all Greer's,)
July 26, l846. Departed this life Sarah Brasher.
January I5, l847. Dismissed Benjamin Morgan and his wife
Rachel also of his family, John F., Ann J., Henry V., 'James
Morgan. Also James McFadden and his wife Elezabeth. January 31,
departed this life Sarah Trailer, fornerly Nealy. Sarah A.
White died on the 13th of March 184?.
Report to Presbytery April 13, 184? membership in communion
92. H. A. Baxter C. S.
(Spring Creek Church April I6, l847. Examined and approved thus
far. Amzi Bradshaw Moderator of Shiloh Presbytery.)
October 21, l847. Collected for domestic missions $8.00.
39
November 12, Baptized Susan E. and Martha R. daughters of
Stephen and Sarah Cook. Departed this life June the 11, l8^8
Betsey McKnight. Departed this life July 2, Hannah Thomas.
September l4, l848. Departed this life Watt (name
omitted) Sept. 17&gt; collected for foreign missions $12.75.
Examined and approved thus far Sept. 22, l848 A. H. Dashiell,
Moderator.
l849. Dismissed Malvina Watson and Ann Witherspoon. April
1, l849. Donnison Haywood and William R. Alexander were elected
ordained Elders.
April 21, l849. Collected for commissioners fund $2.50.
June 3^ l849. Received by certificate Alesmond B.
Witherspoon and his wife June from the Church of Cripplecreek.
August 3. A campmeeting commenced at Centre Campground
which contimie(i 11 days at which 12 were added, viz: Henry
Barkley, Mary McKnight, Elizabeth Cook, A. D. Pebbles, R. F.
Baxter, S. A. Barkley, J. E. R. Alexander, and A. A. Alexander.
The following received the ordinances of Baptism. John M. Mabry,
Palemnes M. McKnight, William T. Hooper, and Julia Stroop.
Dec. 3. Received on examination Nelsom, a bleipK nan belong-ing
to John S. Woodridge.
August 25, l849. Dismissed John Q. Spain and Sarah.
October 9. Departed this life, William R. Alexander, Elder.
December: Dismissed Dr. M. Armstrong and wife Minerver.
Children Baptized. D. Haywood and wife P. W., Martha J., Hannah
R., William R., Henry B., James P., and Ann E.
Children of J. M. Knox and wife Mary. John H. , Joseph B. and
James S.
40
ChJ.l(lren of John Mabry and Wife Murinda. Mar;';arey E., Mary A.,
Charles C,., and Sarah E,
Reported to Presbytery April 1, 1850 as follows. Membership 101.
Examined and approved thus far this date April 13, 185O Dashiell,
Moderator.
April ik , 1850. Session met at Hopewell Church and appointed
D. Haywood Session Clerk. A. B. and Jane Witherspoon daughter
baptised. Mary Margaret
April l4th, 185O: Session met at Hopewell Church. Consti-tuted
with prayer and on examination received T.inda, a black woman
of Rev. J. Alexander. Concluded with prayer.
May 5th. Session met at Hopewell Church. Constituted with
prayer and received on examination Lewis B. Creson, concluded with
prayer. Collected for foreign missions $17.00 also for education
$18.00.
September 12th, I85O. Campmeeting commenced at Centre Camp-ground
and continued till the 19th. The meeting was marked for
good order and attention, deep solemnity marked the face of the
Assembly while attending on the ministration of the word. There
were 13 whites and 10 blacks who we hope found the Lord gracious
to their souls. Ministers in attendance with our pastor were Wm.
Eagleston. On the l6th of Sept. Hopewell Church taken up a col-lection
for Home missions and received &amp;7.50.
Sept. 22, 1850. Session met at Campground and received on
examination Manny A. Cook and also Martha Jane Hagwood. Concluded
with prayer.
Sept. 24, Children baptized of Lewis and Jane Creson to viz:
Mary Ann, Prissilla Rebecca, Dennison Haywood (this may be Hagwood,
41
Viut cannot tell for sure), James Thomas and John P.ell. Concluded
with prayer.
Oct. 6, Session met and appointed John 11. I'.axter a (iele)';al,e
to Synod. I85I, March 10. Tanlssa McKnight departed this life.
Consort of Elurn McKnight.
26th Session met at Rev. J. Alexander and appointed D. Hagwood
a member to Presbytery.
April 6, Hopewell Church taken up a collection for commis-sioner
to the General Assembly and received $6.00. Collection for
tract society $30.00. Total reported membership was IO5. (can-not
read signature of moderator but looks like M. Marshall.) April
26, 1851.
May 27th 1851. Baptized Nancy Neoraia Hannah Cook, Daughter
Df Stephen and Sarah Cook. Also Sarah Elizabeth Knox, daughter
of Samuel W. and Mary A. Knox, also Andrew Barklay Creson, son of
Lewis B. and Jane R. Creson and Dennison Doren Hogwood, son of
Dennison and Prescilla W. Hogwood.
July 26th Collected at Hopewell Church for Home Missions
$18,00 for Education $24.00.
Aug. 7 Campmeeting commenced at Centre campground: Ministers
present Rev, E. T. Brantly, Jessee Alexander and Matt Marshall.
The gospel was preached in demonstration of the Spirit and with
power r);any viere convinced of sin and forty-two professed faith in
Jesus Christ and conversion to God. The meeting was kept up with
preat. interest until the 19th when it was dismissed during the
ocasin the churches have been greatly blessed and made to sit
together in heavenly peace in Christ. During the meeting twenty-six
vjere added to the churches of Cripple Creek, Stone River and
42
llnpeweil. The following persons added to Hopewell Church, on t,he
l8th of August 1851 on examlnation--Robert D. Donoho, John 11.
White, Armstrong E. McKnight, Sarah R. Baxter, Charlott Cook--
Manthue A. Alexander, George A. Alexander, Gideon B. Alexander,
Hannah K. Hogwood, James F. Black, Sarah McKnight, Mary M. McKnight,
Mary E. Barkley, Lucy A.F. Black, Nart N. Oebsekk, The last six
received the ordinance of baptism.
.
Nov. 2, 1851. Baptised Dariah Jane, daughter of William B.
and M.C. White also Moses Jessee Alexander and Sariah Eliza,
Rebeck a Elvlna and William Rea Children of Thomas B. and Mary A.
Cranen.(this surname os not at all clear). Dec. 28th 1851 dis-missed
J.E.R. Alexander.
1852 Feb. 2, Collection taken up on Hopewell Church for
Education. Received $12.25. Feb. 2nd, 1852, dismissed William
Garmany. April 4th D. Hogwood appointed a delegate to Presbytary.
Reported II8 communicants. Examined and approved by Eliza
Alexander, Moderator April 10, 1852. Total collected for year
for education and missions $54.25. Report examined and approved
by Jesse Alexander, M.D.
Jane Barkley, Consort of Henry Barkley departed this life
September First day I852.
Sep 23 Campmeeting commenced at Centre Campground minestary
present E. T. Brantly, Jessee Alexander, William Eagleton and
A. H. Desheell. The gospel was preached in demonstration of the
Spirit and with power. Many were convinced of sin and thirty pro'-
fessed faith in Jesus Christ and conversion to God seven of whom
were plack. The meeting was kept up with interest until the first
day of October. It was dismissed during the ocasin. The church
43
have been greatly refreshed and made to sit together in Heavenly-places
in Christ Jesus. During the meeting twelve were added to
Church of Hopewell, Stone River and Cripple Creek and Murf reesboro.
The following persons added to Hopewell Church on the 24th and
29th Sept. on examination. M. E. Mabry, Mary P. Baxter and Wm.
M. Bradley, M.J.R. Bradley, John T. Barkley the last 2 received
the ordinance of Baptism and W. Alexander received on certificate.
Baptised Dennison Hagwood son of William M. Bradley and M.J.R.
Bradley, also S.A.W. Bradley daughter of W. M. and M.J.R. Bradley.
Oct. 3 D. Hogwood appointed delegate to Presbytery and also
to Synod October Session.
Nov. 15th, 1852 Dismissed Sarah M. McKnight and Mary M.
McKnight
.
Dec. 4th, 1852 Session met and received on examination
Thomas C. Barkley also Nancy J. Barkley on certificate.
Dec. 25, 1852. Session met and received on Certificate L. J.
Barkley.
Feb. 27th, 1852. Collected for education $11.00. Brother
J. H. Baxter appointed to be delegate to Presbytary at Shelbyville,
Total now in Communion 123. Total now in Funds $52.00. Examined
and Approved.
1852. July l4th. Collection for Tract Society $30.00
July 24th Collected for Mission (F) $13.00. A. D. Peoples
departed this life on the 1st day of Sept. 1853.
September l4th I853. Dismissed T. C. Barkley and N. J.
Barkley . ;
hh
Sept. 22, 1853. Campmeeting commenced at Centre Campground.
Ministers present, Wm. Eagleton, Jessee Alexander, A. H. Dashiele,
A. Bradshaw, E. T. Brantley, and J. C. Sloan. The Gospel was
preached in demonstration of the Spirit and with power many were
convinced of sin and forty-five professed faith in Jesus Christ
and conversion to God, nineteen of whome were black persons. The
meetings were kept up with interest until the 30 day of Sept. It
was dismissed during the ocasion. The Churches of Hopewell,
Stoneriver and Cripple Creek have been greatley refreshed and made
to sit together in heavenly places in Christ Jesus. During the
meeting thirty were added to the churches of Hopewell Stoneriver
and Cripple Creek and Murf reesboro. The session met, constituted
with prayer and received on examination in to the Church of
Hopewell the following persons. David C. Witherspoon, Jacob C.
Henndon, Mary F. Knox, Elmenah Hoskins, Samuel T. L. Witherspoon,
Mary S. Hooper, Mary E. Witherspoon, Mary A. Mabry, Virginia Cook,
John C. Sloan, Hugh L. White, Nancy C. Alexander, Elizabeth White.
The first seven recorded received the ordinance of Baptism. Also
received on certificate Virginia Donoho, Matilda Elden, James G,
Elden and Elizabeth M. Elden (note, these last three are pos-sibly
Elder). Concluded with prayer. D. Hagwood, S. C.
Sept. 25th 1853. Baptised Wm. B. Henry, son of L. B. and
June K. Creson, born 6th of March I853. Also E. M. M. daughter
of Stephen and S. Cook, born the 4th of Feb. 1853. Ann E.
daughter of John T. and G. J. Brakley, born 17th of July 1853 and
Mary J. daughter of D. and P.W. Hogwood. born 12 July 1853.
45
Sept. ?8, 1853. Collected for home missionary and rual, $6.^0.
l;rot}ior .TimIim II. I'laxter appointed dele/'-,ate to Syriot at I.ewi sliuT-;'-,e.
D . llofWOod ,
Oct. 2nd 1853. Session met at the Campp.round i-onsti tu teci &#8226;
with prayer and received on certificate Jermima H. McLin also
John D. McLin. On Examination who received the ordinance of
baptism. Concluded with prayer.
Jan. 29th 1854. Collected for education $10.00.
March 25th I854. Mary A. Knox, consort of Samuel W. Knox
departed this life on the above date (Mar. 25th l8'34)
Brother J. H. Baxter appointed delef^ate to Presbytary at heth
Salem Church April 1854. Total Communicants 135. Total in ]''unds
$59.50.
Examined and approved Bethsalem Church April 8th 1854. William
Eagleton Mod.
March 26th 1854. Collected for Church Erection $7.00.
April 23 1854. Collected for Commissioner Fund $10.00.
July 20th, 1854. Collected of Hopewell and Stoneriver
Churches two hundred and thirty five dollars and 35 cts to pay
for the Presbyterian Church at Nashville.
Sept. 2, 1854. Dismissed by letters: A.B. Witherspoon,
Jane Witherspoon, D. C. Witherspoon, G. T. Witherspoon and M. E.
Witherspoon.
D. Hagwood appointed to Presbytery at Cripple Creek, Sept.
2, 1854.
Sept. 21 Campmeeting commenced at Centre Campground and
ministers present. William Eagleton, A. H. Dashiele, Jesse
Alexander, E. T. Brantley, J. C. Sloan, The gospel was preached
k6
in dernonstrati on of the Spirjt. atui with power. Many were i-on-vln''
fMl 111' r.ln -iml nlnol,eon pr&gt; &gt; rr;.-,:-;(Mi I'ai tti in .h&gt;.';iic ('hr-i;-,! nn.l
conversion to dul. Mi/'-jil; oj' wlioine were b]ai'k pc r;;. mis . 'I'lx^ tuool-
Inc.s were kept up with interest \mtii the :^Hth day of Sept, 1 i.
was dismissed durin;,'; the occasion. The churches of Flopewell,
Stoneriver and Cripple Creek churches added nine during the meeting.
Sept. 25. Session met constituted with prayer and on exam-ination
received James H. Watt and Sanaah E. Watt. Concluded witli
prayer.
Sept. 26. Session met, constituted with prayer and on exam-ination
received Mary Jane Knox and Sllvy Knox. They received
ordinance of baptism. Sllvy Knox was consort of B. F. Knox.
Concluded with prayer.
Baptised John D. Spain and Samuel E. Spain sons of John Q.
Spain and S. M. Spain. Baptised Mary Jane Bradley, daughter of
Wm. M. Bradley and Ana J. R. Bradley, also James All'ert l^^axter,
son of H. A. and E. A. Baxter.
Collected for Home missions $9.60.
Paid Brother Jessee Alexander twenty dollars for his services.
Dec. 22, 185^. Dismissed by letter Caroline a free person.
April '5, 1855. Brother J. H. Baxter appointed delegate to
Presbytery at Murfreesboro. Total communicants 13^. Total in
funds $281.95.
Examined and approved A. H. Dashiell, Mod.
June 5th 1855- Collected commissioners fund, $4.00. Sister
Savaah E. Watt, consort of Brother Jas. H. Watt departed this
life.
^7
Brother L. E. McKnight departed this life June 6th 1855.
Sister Eliza McKnight, consort of Brother D. M. McKnight
departed this life on If^tii of Juno iH'V).
Sept. 20, 1855. Camprneeting coniTiienced at Centre Clanipgri'und.
Ministers present. Brother Jessee Alexander, Wm. Eagleton, A. 11.
Dashielal and E. T. Brantley, Meeting lasted until 27th day of
Sept. Twenty-five professed faith in Jesus Christ and Conversion
to God. Nine of whom were black persons. Sixteen were added to
churches of Hopewell, Stoneriver Cripple Creek and Murf reesboro.
Sept. 26th Session met constituted with prayer and on exam-ination
received the following persons in the Church of Hopewell
to wit: Priscella R. Crenson or Creson, Jolm li. Baxter Jr.
Dennison H, Creson, William R. Hog.wood, lleniy I'.. Hog.wood, and
B. I''. Witherspoon by letter. Baptised John D. loggers, son of
Mary E. and R. H. Boggens or Boggers.
Sept. 30, 1855 Baptised Samuel Brantley son of E. T. and
M. E. Brantley. Session met constituted with prayer and on exam-ination
received James E. McLin and administered the ordinance of
baptism. Concluded with prayer.
Oct. 4 Baptised Jas. L. Creson son of L. B. and Jane K.
Creson. Brother J. H. Baxter appointed delegate to Presbytary.
Appointed D. Hogwood delegate to Synod at Shelbyville.
Oct. 30 dismissed A. M. and Mary Reynolds by letters.
Nov. 22, 1855 dismissed July A. Stroops by letter, also Sa.
Catharine Ramsey.
Departed this life on the 20th of Nov. l8^3 Sister Mary E.
Rogers Consort of Brother R. H. Rogers.
1855, Dec. 21 Baptised Albert D. P. Craner, son of Thos.
48
B. and Mary A. Craner.
1856. Bef. 24 Collected for church erection and handed the
same to Rev. Wm. Ea^.leton $8.00.
(next entry seems out of place because of date but is copied as
written)
Dec. 24, 1856 Collected for the American Tract Society
and handed to Brother Wells, $30.00,
Payed out for stoves, $35.00.
Payed to Rec. Jessee Alexander, $45.00.
March 5th. Dismissed by letter. Sister Neomia S. McKnight
and Sister Martha P. Ranken formerly M. B. McKnight.
D. Hogwood appointed a delegate to Presbytery at Shelbyville.
March 29th 1856. Sission of Hopewell met at the call of the
Moderator, constituted with prayer and examininr, the reL-onis oi'
Hopewell church it was ascertained they were incorrect in the
reported membership. Thereupon D. Hogwood and J. H. Baxter were
appointed a committee to take up the records and examine them and
see where they were incorrect. The committee find them incorrect
in the following particulars. They find that the deaths of Nancy
Hooper, E. S. Weatherford, E. Saunders, M. R. Alexander, S. E.
Mc Knight and Reachel McKnight a woman of color were not recorded
as they should have been. They also find on our records the nanies
of J. A. Knox, Enas McKnight, Wm. C. Morison, Sam A. McKni^'-ht,
Mary Cunningham, Mary S. Saunders, Mary Morison, Thoas E. Spain
and Mrs. Spain, J. B. Lusk and Mrs. Lusk, Mary M. Percell, Robert
Donoho, all of which have removed beyond our bounds and some
parts to us unknown without calling for a letter or being dis-missed
so far as the records show. Session therefore in review-
49
inp the case thoup;h aware of it not strictly acordln,'^ to our l)ook
believed the best way can do in the premises is to continue the
names of those members no longer in our reports by order of ses-sion.
Concluded with prayer.
Paid Brother E. T. Brantley fifty dollars for part of his
services for 1855. Membership now stands at 112 and total in
collection of funds $172.00 Examined and approved April 12, 1856.
Amzi Bradshaw Moderator of Pres))ytery.
April 17th 1856. Dismissed by letter Brother J. n. r.loa'i.
Brother William Rhea departed this life the 27th day of May
1836. He was one hundred and four years three months of at';e.
He professed faith in Jesus Christ at the age of eighteen he was
a devoted brother to the cause of Christ.
1856. June 1 Baptised Stephen Alexa, son of Stephen and
Sarah Cook.
Aug. 24, Baptised George Albert, a son of Wm. B. and Martha
G. White, also a daughter named Martha Frances.
Sept. 24th l8s6. Campmeeting commenced at Centre r'ampground.
Ministers present Brothers: Jesse Alexander, Wm. Eagleton, A.
Bradshaw, A. H. Dashield, Woodbury and E. T. Brantley who was
sick Three sermons preached every day. Nine persons enquir-ing
the way; of salvation six of whom pr^jfessed faith in Jesus.
Christ and five attached themselves to the church. Meeting
closed Oct. 2. Home missions collections $3.75. Ministering
bretheren were paid $60.00.
Sept. 30, 1856. Session met, constituted with prayer and
received upon examination John T. Herington who received ordinance
of baptism.
50
Oct. 1, 1856. Session met, and received N. K. Knox for
Baptism. Report to Presbytery shows 112 on roll. Total in
Funds $138.75. Approved April I856.
Brother Jacob H. Thomas departed this life the l6th day of
July 1857. August 1. Dismissed by letter Sister Ann Powell
wife of Allen Powell.
1857 Sept. 2'lth. Campmeetlng begun. Ministers present
Brothers: Woodbury, Eagleton, Bradshaw, Monery and Hantpence.
The total collected for the American Tract Society 1857 was
$40.00 and paid to Wells. Thirteen professed fauth in Christ
Jeses and conversion to God. Also seven black persons professed
faith in Jeses Christ. The meeting closed the 30th of Sept.
During the meeting one was added to Stoneriver Church and the
Sabbath following three were added to the Murfreesboro Church
also Children of the following bretheren were baptised: S. W.
and N. E. Knox son Wm. E. and daughter Mary E. Knox.
Wm. M. and M. J. Bradley his son John Baxter.
L.B. and J. R. Creson, son Robert F.
W. W. and M. P. McKnight son Edwin A.
Nov. l4th 1857. Session received on examination Robert
McGill, free man of color, also Peter, a colored man belonging
to B. Knox. Dismissed Sister Virginia Donoho by letter March 29,
1857. D. Hogwood appointed delegate to presbytary at Hopewell.
Report shows 111 communicants and $45.00 in funds. Approved.
A. H. Hartpense, 1858. Collected for A. Missions $5.00.
April 10, Session on examination received Jan Orr.
April 12, 1858, Dismissed Sister Jan Orr by Letter.
April 25, Paid to brother A. Bradshaw for his services.
51
$14.05.
Jan. 5, 1859, Paid A. Bradshaw for his services for 1858,
$135.00. Brother B. F. Witherspoon dismissed by letter Nov.
20, 1858.
Sister Sarah Ray departed this life on the 22nd day of
November I858. D. and P. W. Hogwood daughter Priscella Rebecca
and Son John Thomas was baptised on the 28th day of November
1858. Session met and on examination received Wm. R. Hogwood
and; he received the ordinance of Baptism.
Sister Partheny Price dismissed by letter March 11, I859.
Collected for Tract Society $1.00.
Dismissed by letter. Sister Harritt McLin, March 21, l859.
Dismissed by letter Brother James McLin, March 21, I859.
Reported to Presbytery 10? communicants and $155-05 in Funds.
Examined and approved by F. A. Thompson Moderator at Shelbyville
April 9, 1859.
Dismissed by letter Elizabeth English, May 6, 1859.
52
"The Records of Hopewell Church Vol. 3 Commencing the 5th day,
May, 1859"
Hopewell Church was called together by the order of SessJon
on the 5th day of May l859, for the purpose of choosing their
Ecclesiastical connection, constituted by calling Rev. J.
Alexander, the object of the meeting was explained by the
Moderator, and a committee of three, to wit, J. H. Baxter, D.
Hogwood, and Geo. Peoples was appointed to draft and present
resolutions. Said committee presented the following preamble
and resolutions, which were severally considered and adopted.
"Whereas the Presbyterian of Church of the United States of
America divided in the year 1838 on the subject of the excinding
acts of 1837, and formed two assemblies known by new and old
school, and whereas a number of the Presbyteries belonging to
the new school Assembly, being aggrieved with the continued
agitation of the subject of Slavery, in their body, withdrew
from said assembly in I857 convened at Cleveland, Ohio, and
formed a Synot at Knoxville, Tennessee in 1858, known by the
name of The United Synod of the Presbyterian Church in the
United States of America.
And Whereas, Shiloh Presbytery to which we belonged was not
one of the number that withdrew, but dissolved by a vote of her
own body on the 9th day of April 1859. We being thereby desti-tute
of any ecclesiastical connection whatever. Therefore
Resolved, First, That it is expedient that we form a connection
with some ecclesiastical body.
Resolved That we approve of the resolution of the
United Synod in excluding the agitation of Slavery from its
Judicatory.
53
Resolved Thirdly, That we also approve of its explanation,
and mode of adopting the confession of faith as embracing the
doctrines contained in the Bible.
Resolved Fourthly, That we in uniting with said Synot make
no sacrifice of principle or doctrine.
Resolved Fifthly, That we the undersigned members of
Hopewell Church unite with said Synot through some one of its
Presbyteries as soon as practicable. Rev. Jessee Alexander,
J. H. Baxter, D. Hogwood, George Peoples, Jane F. Peoples,
J. W. Mabry, M. B. Mabry, M. E. Mabry, M. Mabry, W. B. White,
M. C. White, E. A. White, W. M. Johns, Jane Johns, S. S. .
Alexander, G. B. Alexander, G. A. Alexander, J. F. Black,
N. C. Black, T. B. Craner, M. A. Craner, R. D. Black, E. A.
Black, Rebecca Black, Eliza Alexander, Margaret Knox, Mary F.
Knox, D. N. Baxter, Robert Baxter, E. R. Baxter, S. R. Baxter,
J. H. Baxter Jr., H. A. Baxter, A. E. McKnight, Amanda E.
McKnight, J. T. Bark]ey, E. J. Barkley, Hannah Barkley, M. K.
Barkley, H. K. McKnight, P. W. Hogwood, M. J. Hogwood, W. R.
Hogwood Jr., H. B. Hogwood, W. R. Hogwood Sr., L. B. Creson,
J. K. Creson, P. R. Creson, D. H. Creson, Lucinda R. Martin,
R. J. E. McKnight, L. A. F. McKnight, J. N. McKnight, Martha A.
McKnight, Pernilla McKnight, Margaret Alexander, J. C. Herndon
and Martha E. Herndon. Total 58. l859, Nov. 16 Dismissed by
letter R. J. McKnight and his wife Ann F. McKnight also James F.
Black and wife Nancy C. Black. Signed D. Hogwood, S.C. 1859
Nov. 19 Session met constituted with prayer and on examination
received Sarah E. Craner in communion in Hopewell Church. Closed
with prayer. D. Hogwood, Session Clerk. Cash paid for visiting
54
Brothers for Preaching in the year 1859 $106.7':). D. Ilogwood,
S.C.
Aug. 29, i860 Session met constituted with prayer and on exam-ination
received brother Slman Craddock in communion of Hopewell
Church. D. Hogwood S.C.
Aug. 29 i860 Baptised William H. son of J. L. and Martha E.
Herndon also William Thomas son of Wm. P. and C. P. White. D.
Hogwood S.C.
Aug. 30th i860 Paid Brother Marshel $l6.50 for his services.
D. Hogwood, S.C.
Aug. 31st i860 Dismissed by request William M. Bradley from the
Presbyterian Church at Hopewell, D. Hogwood, S. C.
Session met, constituted with prayer and appointed D. Hogwood
delegate to the next meeting of Presbytery to be held at Pulaski,
Giles Co. on the 5th of Oct. i860. D. Hogwood, S.C.
Clerk of Session of Hopewell Church makes the following
report to North Alabama Presbytery to wit: Members now in -om-munion
55, added since last report 2, dismissed h, haptJsmsno
adults 2 infants. Collections. Commissioners fund contingent
$123.25
Examined and approved thus far by Presbytery of North
Alabama, Pulaski Oct. 6, 1860 Robart Hardin, Moderator.
Dec. 24th i860 Cast paid to Brother G. Eagleton $10. 60, D.
Hogwood S.C. 1861.
Jan. 15. Collected for repairs $2.30, paid out to T. B.
Craner $2.13, D. Hogwood.
April 29. Cash paid to Bro. Shields commissioners Fund
$7.00.
53
Cash paid Clerk of Presbytery $.75 D. Hogwood S.C.
August 8th. Baptised Samuel [Uack, son of Thomas B. and
Mary Crane r, D. Hogwood, S.C.
Aug. 15. Cash paid to Bi'o. Styles $15.^0. Cash for other
. $4.50 D. Hogwood, S.C.
Oct. 2nd Collected for Home Missions and paid over to Bro.
Eagleton $l4.25, D. Hogwood, S.C.
The Session Clerk report to North Alabama Presbytery the Statis-tics
for the year l86l viz: Whole number 55 infants 1 Congrega-tional
collections $33.10. Domestic collections $l4.25. Miscel-laneous
$9.70, Total $57.05. D. Hogwood, S.C.
Examined and approved thus far, Petersburg Oct. 4th l86l
W.E. Caldwell, Moderator
Son W. B. Hogwood departed this life Dec. 12th, l86l, D. Hogwood
C.S.
Brother Hugh L. White departed this life on the 3rd day of April
1862, D. Hogwood.
Brother L. B. Creson departed this life on the 23rd day of March
1863, D. Hogwood.
Rev. Jess e e Alexander departed this life on the 15th day of June
1863, D. Hogwood.
Brother A. Barkley departed this life on the 26th day of Juno I863,
D . Hogwood
.
Sister Jane F. Peebles departed this life on the 4th day of May
1864, D. Hogwood.
Sister M. E. Dill departed this life on the 7th of Aug., l864
D. Hogwood.
56
Sister Nancy McKnight departed this life on the 25th May l8b'i
D. Hogwood.
John R. and Sally A . son and daughter of Protlier J. C. and Sister
M. E, Herndon was baptised on the ?lst May 1865. D. Hogwood
S.C. Brother Wm. M. Johns departed 26 Aug. 1865.
Sept. 13th 1865 Session met constituted with prayer on examination
received Brother Wm. R. McDougal in communion Hopewell Church,
D. Hogwood. Also Sister Sarah J. White .
Also Brother D. D. Hogwood.
Also Sister Sarah A. Bradley .
Also Sister Ann E. Hogwood .
Also Brother David E. McKnight ., the last received baptism,
n. Hogwood, S.C.
Sept. l4th l864. Session met, constituted with prayer. On exam-ination
rece'iveiJ Brother Andrew P.. Ore son and Bennisun H. M.radLey
in communion Hopewe].]. Church.
Sept. 24th 1865, Session met, constituted with prayer. On exam-ination
received the following persons in Communion, Hopewell
Church:
Sisters Lochia W. Weatherly - Baptised.
Ann C. Weatherly , Elvira R. Craner and Brother Larkin L .
Barber.
Hopewell Congregation was called to meet on the 23rd of September
1865 by Rev. Henn C. Smith for the purpose of electing two Elders
which resulted in the election of Brother H. A. I'axte r and Thomas
B. Craner . D. Hogwood C.S.
Oct. 7th 1865. After sermon. Brother H. A. Baxter was ordained
Elder of Hopewell Church Congregation by Rev. H. C. Smith,
57
D. Hogwood, S.C.
Oct. 7th 1865. Session met and exa.Tiined and received Brother J. II.
White in Communion of Hopewell Church. D. no^Twood, S.C.
Oct. 10th 1865. After sermon the session met on examination
received the following persons to wit:
Sister Mary E. Black - Baptised
William A. Black - Baptised
John B. Creson , Mary M. White . Closed with prayer. D. Hogwood,
S.C.
Oct. 18th 1865. Brother John H. Baxter, Jr . departed this life in
the triumph of faith in Jesus. D. Hogwood, S. C.
Nov. 20th 1865. Session met constituted with prayer and on exam-ination
wit: Sister J. Hogwood . She gave satisfaction to the
session that she had obtained forgiveness for her transgression
and she was reinstated. Closed by prayers. D. Hogwood, C.S.
Lucy F. Mc Knight departed this life Dec. 11, 1862, D. Hogwood,
S.C.
Rebecca Black departed this life Sept. 26th 1862, D. Hogwood,
S.C.
Isbellar Huddleston departed this life Jan. 7, l864, D. Hogwood,
S.C.
Nov. 27th 1865. Sister Mary Anderson dismissed by letter of her
request, D. Hogwood, S.C^
Collections taken up at Hopewell Church for the sustentation fund
received $26. 4o March 25th 1866 and handed to Rev. H. C. Smith ,
D. Hogwood, S.C.
Sister N. H. Knox departed this life. She died in the Triumph of
Faith in Jesus April 24th 1866. D. Hogwood, S.C.
58
Sister Sarah M. McKnlght consort of Joseph D, McKnight departed
this life the 21st day of May I866 in Triumph of Faith in Christ.
D. Hogwood, S.C.
A Sacramental meeting commenced at Hopewell Church Friday night
the 25th of May I866. Ministers present Brothers: Smith and
E. T. Brant ly . Session met at the house of Benjamin Knox on
Saturday constituted with prayer and on examination Brother
Benjamin Knox in Communion Hopewell Church. On Sabbath a col-lection
was taken up to defray the expenses of the meeting and
received eleven dollars and forty-five cents which was paid out
to Bro. E. T. Brantley five dollars and $5.00 for wine. This
27th day of May 1866. D. Hogwood, S.C.
Hopewell Church August 25th I866 at the request of Rev. H. C .
Smith , session met constituted with prayer. Present: Rev. H. C .
Smith, Brother J. H. Baxter , H. A. Baxter , D. Hogwood , Rev. H. C.
Smith, Moderator. Brother J. H. Baxter was appointed a delegate
to Presbytery and D. Hogwood his alternate to attend Presbytery
at Louisburg which will meet Friday at 11 o"clock A.M. before the
Second Sunday of Sept. On motion of D. Hogwood the case of Col.
2_ came up for discussion and consideration and
whereas said during a revival last summer made pro--
fession of religion and sought connection with this church and
was admitted to membership but soon after was guilty of drunkenness
and swindling and other crimes and has left for parts unknown so
that process cannot be had in his case resolved therefore he be
expelled which was adopted. D. Hogwood, S. C.
The session clerk report to North Alabama Presbytery the Statis-tics
for the year ending Oct. 1 I86I to Sept. 1 1866. Last report
59
members 55j added on examination 15, adults baptised 4, infants
baptised 2, deaths 15&gt; expelled 1, total in communion 5^. Total
in funds $11. 4o, D. Hogwood, S.C.
The Committee appointed to examine the session records of Hopewell
Church would state that in their opinion nothing should be
recorded but the acts of the session. These records contain
statistical reports-accounts of baptisms and deaths- which ought
not to be in the book. They also notice that in the minutes of
sessional meeting no names are mentioned of Elders present--
and most of the meetings seem to have been held without being
constituted with prayer. The book should also be paged with the
criticisms which your Com. think just. We recommend the approval
of the record to this date.
Sept. 8th l866. Examined and approved with the above exception.
Lewisburg, Tenn, Sept. 8, 1869. J. Simpson Frierson . Mod. Per.
North Alabama.
Sept. 23, 1866 paid for wine $2.50 J. Hogwood S.C.
Sister E. R. Baxter consort of J. H. Baxter departed this life on
the 17th day of November I866.
Jan. 10, 1867. Paid to Brother J. N. Caldwell for visit to
Hopewell Church Five dollars. D. Hogwood, S.C.
Feb. 21st 1867. Dismissed by letter Brother John Herndon by his
request by order of Session. D. Hogwood, S.C.
March 4th, I867. Dismissed by letter Brother D. H. Creson by his
request and by order of Session. D. Hogwood, S.C.
March 10, I867. Dismissed by letter Brother Thos C. Barkley and
Sister N. J. Barkley by their request and by order of Session.
D. Hogwood, S.C.
60
April 8th 1867. Brother J. H. Baxter was appointed a dele-gate
to Presbytery at Murfreesboro which meets the 9th of April.
D. Hogwood, S.C.
The Committee to whom was referred the Records of Hopewell
Church report-Approved as far as written with the following
exceptions. That there is no mention made of the sessions being
opened and closed with prayer.
2. That extraneous matters are recorded in the minutes with
deaths statistical and personal matters. These matters ought to
be kept apart.
3. Members are dismissed without record being made where they
are dismissed to.
4. There is no mention made of the Elders being present at
the meetings of the session. The names of Moderator and Elders
ought to be recorded as present at each meeting. Adopted by
Presbytery at Murfreesboro, Tenn, April 10, I967.
Robert R. Moore, Moderator.
Sept. 16th 1867. Session met Brothers present: Rev . McFeaters ,
Elders J. H. Baxter , H. A. Baxter and D. Hogwood . Rev. McFeaters
Moderator opened with prayer on motion D. Hogwood was appointed a
delegate to Presbytery to meet at the Hermitage Church Sept. 20th,
at 11 o'clock A.M. Closed with prayer, D. Hogwood.
Sept. 23rd 1867. Tax paid to Brother Bunten (Burten) for
Synod Presbytery tax, $1.00, Commission fund total $4.50. D.
Hogwood , S.C.
Dismissed following members by letter: Sister Jane R. Creson ,
Priscella R. Patton and Brothers John B. Creson , Andrew B. Creson ,
by order of Session Sept. 31, 1867. Collected for foreign missions
61
paid to Bunten $1.00, D. Hogwood.
Oct. 4th, 1867. Sacramental meeting commenced at Hopewell
Church the 4th of Oct. 1867. Brothers present Rev. McFeater and
W. L. Rossen . The gospel was preached in demonstration of the
spirit and with power many were convinced of sin and fourteen
professed faith in Jesus Christ and conversion to God. The meet-ings
were kept up with interest until the 11th during the ocasion
the Church of Hopewell were greatly refreshed. Session met con-stituted
with prayer and on examination received into membership
in the Hopewell Church Ella I. Weatherly and Martha A. Whit lock .
Closed with prayer. D. Hogwood, S.C. Last report members 5^,
dismissed 4, members at present 50.
April 24th 1868, D. Hogwood, C.S. Total amount payed out by
church from Sept. l6th to April 1868 $223.95.
Sacramental meeting commenced at Hopewell Church May 2nd
1868. Ministers present Rev. E. T. Brantley , Rev. McFeaters . The
weather inclement the meeting close Sabbath evening. Collection
taken up to defray expenses of Commissioners fund and Presbyteral
Tad whih wre $13.15. Rec. by colection $12.15 Wine cost paid by
D. Hogwood $15.00. Total $26. 80. D. Hogwood S.C.
Sept. 16th 1868. Collected for Presbyterial Mission paid over
to Presbytery $3.75. D. Hogwood, S.C.
Jan. 3rd 1869. Collected for Sustination $12.00 Handed to
Rec. McFeaters D. Hogwood. S.C.
April 4th I869. Collected for Commissioners Fund $3.00.
April 15th 1869. Per last report to Presbytery total number
60, dismissed 2 total number in communion 58. Total amount pay out
by church paid Bro. McFeaters $ll6.20 (This is very dim and hard
Od
to read, may be $l6.20).
May 24th I869 Departed this life S. E. Cranor . D. Hogwood
S.C.
Sacremental meeting at Hopewell Church Wine cost $2.00 paid
by D. Hogwood May 24th I869. D. Hogwood S.C.
August 7th 1869. Collected for Presbyterial Missions in D.
Hogwood hands $9.15, paid over to Presbytery at Murf reesboro,
D. Hogwood, S.C.
Sept. 5th 1869. Sacremantal meeting at Hopewell Church.
Ministers present Rev. McFeaters , Rev. N. L. Rossen and Rev. E. T.
Brantley Continued seven days in which time we trust that ten or
eleven was hopefully converted. Collection for expences for the
$10.10. Paid out for wine Spring and Fall $3.50. For chares
$2.00, for candle holders $1.25. For tax to Synot $5.00. Paid
to Bro. W. L. Rosson for services $l6.00 paid for candle $2.00. D.
Hogwood S.C.
January 7th 187O Departed this life S. R. Baxter. She died
in the Triumph of Faith in Christ. D. Hogwood, S.C.
Feb. 6th 1870 Collected for Sustentation $9.00 sent to Bro.
H. B. Boude , D. Hogwood S.C.
Departed this life Feb. 26th I87O S. J. Martin formerly S. J.
White . D. Hogwood, S.Cc
Departed this life Elizabeth A. Black the 26th day March I87O
consort of R. D. Black . D. Hogwood, S.C.
Per last report to Presbytery at Shelbyville April 4th 187O
64. Added in examination 2 added on certificate 8 Baptisms
adults 2. Money contritacted $255.00. D. Hogwood.
June 26th 1870 Mary T. Vaught departed this life, consort of
63
Thomas Vaught .
July 9th 1870 Jane Johns departed this life the above date. Widow
of Wm. Johns.
Departed this life Mrs. Wm. McKnight the 17th day of August
1870. (This may be Mr. it is only a M. and a line with a dot over
it.)
Collected for hym books for Hopewell Church $9.20. Paid for
question books $9.00 paid for church expences $12.00. D. Hogwood.
Collected for Education Sept. 6th I87O sent to Presbytery
$21.00 by E. A. Baxter.
John H. White departed this life Oct. 5th 1870.
Jan. 1st 1871. Paid Rev. M. Featers $225.00. Paid Rev. R.
Caldwell traveling expences $12.35.
Per last report to Presbytary at McMinnville April 1, 187O
to April 1, 1871 Members in communion 62 added on examination 1
on certificate 1. Money contributed $288.65. D. Hogwood S.C.
Collected for Presbyteral tax and commissioners fund $9.15
April 16th 1871.
Baptism of Rev. E. T. Brantley , Mrs. M. E. Brantley and
children William Edwin and Ally Brantley May 2y, 187I.
Collected for Presbyterial Mission June 4th 187I $6.00
handed to Rev. R. Caldwell . Six dollars for Rev. J. H. McNealy ,
Nashville. D. Hogwood. S.C.
Cost of wine $1.4o paid by D. Hogwood.
Collected Home Missions seven dollars handed to J. H. Baxter
Sept. 2nd 187I. D. Hogwood. S.C.
Sept. 20th 1871. The fall protracted meeting was held in
Hopewell Church. The opening sermon was preached by Rev. R.
64
Caldwell from Romans 10-1. Good Congregation. At night services
were conducted by Rev. Mr. McFeaters. On Sabboth a very large
congregation. Sermon by Rev. M. McFeaters. The communion largely
partaken of and a most pleasant and solemn season was realized.
Meetings were held from day to day until Friday night. The clos-ing
service was one of uncommon solemnity. The people of God
were all tenderness and love and the congregation overwhelmed at
the scene. During the occasion inquiring and prayer meetings were
held and every morning for the benefit of sinnors and inquiring
sinnors. These meetings were full on interest. Souls were con-verted
and Christian hearts were filled with joy. The result of
the meeting was as follows . Fourteen professions all uniting with
the church. It should not be omitted that Bro. Branley gave his
valuable assistance during this occasion. Collected to pay
expences $8.45. Paid out for plank, $5.50. Paid J. H. Baxter
$2.70, paid for wine $1.25. paid for candles $1.00 paid Rev.
M. McFeaters $13.65. Paid for books for Sunday School $7.20.
this Oct. 17th, 1871. $39.75. Collected for education $7.00 Nov.
5th 1871.
At a church meeting heald 5th Nov. 187I S. S. Alexander
was elected Ruling Elder and H. B. Hogwood and Wm. A. Black was
elected Deacons. Collected for Sustentation Jan. 24 1872 paid
Bro. J. W. Neel fourteen dollars.
Hopewell Congregation collected for Publication March 3rd
1872 $6.00 Sent to J. W. Niel. D. Hogwood C.S. Murfreesboro.
Per last report to Nashville Presbytery at Gallatin April 1
1871 to April 1, 1872. number of communicants 75. reed on exam-ination
l4. on certificate 1 dismissed 1. Baptisms adults 3
65
Infiant 2. Monday collected $395.00.
Publication $6.00. Sustentation $l4.00. Education $7.00.
Home Missions $7.00. Presbyterry tax $15.00, Congregation $39.00.
Preachers sallary $307.00. D. Hogwood S.C.
Collected for Presbyterial Tax handed to H. A. Baxter $6.90
also for Brother Dr. R. H. Chapman handed to Rev. Chapman $8.00.
D. Hogwood, C.S.
Milton May 19^ 1872. Collected for Forren Mission at our
Cacnemenltal meetning handed t o W. L. Rossen $8.00. also paid
for wine $1.25 (spelling of above is exact copy of minute book).
Paid by Sunday School book $3.60. Paid catechism 30 vol, $,60.
D. Hogwood S.C,
Benjamin Knox departed this life the 2nd day of June 1872.
D. Hogwood S.C.
J. W. McKnight departed this life the 17th 1872 of June.
D. Hogwood S.C.
Collected for disable ministers Aug. 4th 1872 handed to
W. L. Rossen $7.00.
Paid for Sunday School books in Aug. 4th I872 $7.00. D.
Hogwood S.C.
Amanda E. McKnight Children Baptised the 4th July I872 the
names as follows. Flora E. , Ida M . , Wm ^ M . , Wesley A, , Quinta E .
,
Sexta By Rev. W. L. Rossen .
Departed this life Margret Knox on the 21 1872 (no month
given but is between entry of July 4 '1872 and Aug. 25, I872).
66
Paid for Sunday School books August 25th I872 $7.00. D. Hogwood
S.C.
Delia Weatherly departed this life the l8th of Oct. 187?.
Collected for Presbyterlal mission Oct. 20th I872 handed to
Rev. W. L. Rosson $6.00. Collected for Education March l6th I873
$10.00 handed to W. L. Rosson .
Departed this life Mary J. Baxter consort of R. H. Baxter the
25th of January 1873.
Report to Presbytery l873:
Members in communion 63
Rec. on examination 3
Rec. on certificat 1
Dismissed 1
Baptised infants 6
Money for all funds $330.45.
Approved by order of Presby Alex Cowan Moderator
May 18th 1873 Collected for foreign mission handed to W. L.
Rosson $11.00. Collected for disabled ministers Aug. 17th 1873
handed to Rev. W. L. Rosson $12.00. Collected for Home Missions
Sept. 7th 1873 handed to W. L. Rossen $29.00.
Milton Oct. 2nd 1873 T. B. Craner departed this life on the
above date.
Nov. 16th 1873 Collected for education handed to W. L. Rossen
$11.45
S. A. Craner departed this life Nov. l8th I873.
Collected for Sustentian Feb. 15th 1874 handed to Rev. W. L.
Rossen $12.50. Collected for publication April l8th 1874 handed
to Rev. W. L. Rossen $7.50.
oy.
Per last report to Presbytery from April l873 to April iHyil
.
Members 60
added on examination 12
on certificate 1
deaths 2
total 73
deaths 2
dismissed 8
total in communion 63
collected for foreign' mission $11.00
disabled ministers 12.00
Home mission 29-00
Education 11.45
Sustentation 12.50
Publication 7.00
for Rev. W. L. Rossen 200.00
for Congregational 50.00
Total collected to April I8 332.95 Paid over. D.
Hogwood, S.C.
June 7th l874 Collected for foreign mission handed to Rev.
W. L. Rosson $l6.00.
Aug. 2nd 1874 Collected for disabled ministers handed to
Rev. W. L. Rossen $10.00.
October 4th l874 Collected for Presbyterial missions $17.00.
Oct. 9th 1874 Collected for Rev. J. W . Hoyte $10.00.
J. W. Mabry departed this life Nov. 30, l874.
Collected Congregational $2.85.
Nov. 1st 1874. Congregation met and elected the following
Brothers as Elders. Was elected J. C. Herndon , S. N. Weatherly ,
and H. G. Johnes . Also elected Deacons R. F. Baxter and Jas. N.
McKnight. D. Hogwood, S.C.
Dec. 6th 1874 Being the regular day of meeting at Hopewell
Church, H. G. Johns and J. C. Herndon were ordained and installed
and J. M. Wetherly previous elected and ordained Elder of Stone
River Congregation was installed Ruling Elders of the above named
Church also J. N. McKnight, R. F. Baxter were ordained and W. D.
bO
White elected and ordained deacons In the above church.
Collected for education $l4.00
Per last report 63
Examined 10
Death 1
Dismissed 3
Excommunicated 1
Total Communicants 68
Baptised 4 adults. Collected $302.00 (all funds.)
June 10th l875 Ann E. Craner formally Ann E. Wetherly
departed this life on this date.
July 2nd l875 Margaret Alexander departed this life on the
above date.
Hopewell Church Milton Tennessee April 30, 1875. Elders
and Deacons met and on motion Bro. D. Hogwood chosen chairman and
Bro. H . G. Johns Secretary. After prayer by the Chairman the
Chairman explained the object of the meeting to be to lay off the
work of the Deacons and Elders. Ordered by the meeting that the
Chair appoint a Committee of Three to lay off the work of the
Elders and Deacons. The Chair appointed as the Committees Bros.
White, Weatherly and H. A. Baxter the Committee. The Committee
reported as follows: The North Division begimiing at Margaret
Alexander'
s
on the Turnpike, thence with S. I. Road to the school
house near Milton, thence went including Mrs. Elrod and John
Dillon and all north. Middle Division: Beginning on John W.
Spain thence being west so as to include Dillard McKnight . In
the Middle Division thence West to the Creek at T. B. Vaughts
gate, thence west with S. N. Creek all South of S. N. line to the
Stones River Church line is included in the 3rd Division. The 1st
Division is assigned to Bro. R. F.Baxter the 2nd Division to Bro.
W. B. White and the 3rd Division to Bro. Jas . N. McKnight.
69
James N. McKnlght was Elected Secretary of the Board of Deacons
and W. B. White Treasurer. Minutes were read and approved the
meeting adjourned, H. L. Johns, Sec.
Collections taken up in the Hopewell Church for Congrega-tional
and other.
Per last report members 83 (note: this does not talley with
report as given on preceeding report, but I copied it as given).
deaths 3
dismissed 1
excommunicated 1
baptised 1
total in communion 78
David N. Baxter departed this life July 26th 1876. H. G. Johns ,
S.C. Protem.
N. A. Baxter departe-d this life August 21st I876 calmly
trusting in Christ (this may be H. A. Baxter, it is a strange
character, hard to read).
Session and Deacons meeting at Church March l8th 1877.
Present Rev. W. L. Rossen Moderator, Elders present J. H. Baxter ,
J. C. Herndon , H. G. Johns and D. Hogwood . Deacons present:
Jas. W. McKnight , VJ. B. White and R. F. Baxter . Constituted with
prayer report of Deacons is as follows:
Sustentation $20.00
Evangelistic 15.00
Invalid 10.35
Foreign mission 25.00
Publication 11.00
Education I8.7O
Presbyterial I8.5O
Pastors Salary pd.200.00
Congregational 23. '^5 Total $3^1.85
Fifty dollars of the amount was given George Peables of
Hopewell, D. Hogwood
Report last to Presbytery at Shiloh April 1st 1877.
ru
Total in Communion from last report (S3
added on examination 11
Baptism Adults 8
deaths 2
Total 92
Collected in l877 April 1st and payed $332.85
Children in Sabbath School 38.
Elders 4, Deacons 3. D. Hogwood, S.C.
April 7th I878 per last report to Presbytery total in communion 92
added upon examination 3
added on certificate 2
adult baptisms 3
infants 1
No. of baptisms non communicants 13
Excommunicated 6
Total in Communion 91
Collected since last report $363.00. Pastors salary paid $200.00.
No. of Elders 4, No. of Deacons 3. Children in S. S. 60.
H. G. Johns. S. C. Protem.
Sept. 5th 1878. Baptised Edgar Brantley son of S. P . and
Mary J. Brantley .
Brother George Peebles departed this life the 21st April I879.
Sister Lucinda R. Martin departed this life 19th June 1879.
Sister Ella J. Wetherly departed this life the l6th of May 1880.
Brother J. H. Baxter departed this life the 25th of Oct. 1880.
D. Hogwood S.C.
Saturday May 28th I881. The Congregation met at the Church
and according to previous appointments went into the Election of
Two Ruling Elders for this Church. Elders J. C. Herndon and H. G.
Johns were appointed tellers of said Election which resulted in
the election of George Lorances and Robert Baxter as Ruling
Elders. H. G. Johns C. of S. Protem.
Sabbath Morning May 29th I881. Congregation met for public
worship and for celebration of the Sacrament of the Lords Supper,
when before the morning sermon George Lorances was ordained a
Ruling Elder for Hopewell Church by prayer and the laying on of
the Hands of the Session. H. G. Johns, C. of S. Protem.
71
Approved by Presbytery of Nashville as far as written at Waverly
Church April 1st l882.
May 6 1883. Bessie F. Thompson , Infant daughter of Rev. C . E.
and Cora G. Thompson was baptised by Rev. J. S. Arbuthnot , D.D.
H. G. Johns, S.C. Protem.
The regular Spring Sacramental meeting was held on Sabbath
May 7 and on Sat. preceeding. Rev. J. S. Arbuthnot D.D. of
Murfreesboro Church preached both days and the people of God
were much edified and strengthened and enjoyed a happy session
of Grace. H. G. Johns. S.C. Protem.
The regular fall meeting of the Presbytery of Nashville
having met with Hopewell Church on Friday before the Third Sabbath
in September l4th, 1882. The meetings were continued after the
adjournment of Presbytery. Rev. G. A. Russell of Franklin
Tennessee had intended to remain and preach for us but was pre-vented
by sickness. Rev. E. Brantley Jr . remained and preached
with much earnestness and power. The Church was much edified and
strengthened and we hope an abundant harvest may follow the
Sowing of so much good seed. H. G. Johns, S.C. Protem.
At his meeting of Presbytery on Saturday 15th, John R. Herndon
a member of the church was taken under the care of the Presbytery
as a candidate for Gospel Ministry.
Brother R. D. Black who had been a member of Hopewell Church
since the year I83O a quiet unassiiming Christian living in peace
with all men and full of the Faith of the Gospel was gathered as
a ripe sheaf into the garner of the "Master" on the 26th of Jan.
1883. H. G. Johns S.C. protem.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Transcription of a record book from Hopewell Presbyterian Church, with an introduction by the woman who made the records available</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.) -- History; Rutherford County (Tenn.) -- Newspapers; Women--Societies and clubs</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>churches; church records; Daughters of the American Revolution, Buffalo River Chapter; Hopewell Presbyterian Church; presbyterian churches</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>99 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-15</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication07ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/165</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>