<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Some early news from Rutherford County</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Johns, Ernest</dc:creator>
<dc:contributor>Lynch, Bill</dc:contributor>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 19</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1982</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>19th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>SOME EARLY NSf/S PUCM RUTHERFORD COUNTY
by - Ernest Johns
In 1981, several old newsp^&gt;ers dating in the l830&#187;s or l8U0's
were discovered in the old home of Enoch Jones In the northeast section
of Rutherford County. The newspapers were found by Bill I^ynch. They
contain some valuable early historical information on the people and
places in our county. The following abstracts from the papers give
the more sigiificant news. The papers are still fairly well preserved
and Mr. Ttiii lynch is going to allow the Tennessee State library to
microfilm these rare early newspapers from Rutherford County.
The Courier , Nmber !&#163; Murfreesborou^, Ten. Saturday Nov. 6, I83O
printed every Saturday. Administrator of James H. Blakely by a decree of
the court wiU sale on Dec. 2k a tract of 91 acres on which the widow now
lives-Catherine Blakely. The tract adjoins the land of Robert MiHer on
the south and east, Campbell on the north, Polly Parker on west Seventy
five dollars required down and balence in twelve months.
Lost - On Sunday at Camp Meeting at Walker Camp Ground in Rutherford
County a gold bracelet. The finder will be entitled to the thanks of
the owner by leaving it with Mr. Rolla Morgan.
Coiranitted to the jail. On the 23 a negro wonwn U5 or 50. She give
no Satisfactory account of her owner or where she ran away from.
Bacon for sale - John Lytle has on hand five thousand pounds of bacon
for sale. He will also exchange for good seed cotton delivered to his gin.
New Goods Advertized - James Holmes,
Vftn. T. Christy St Co.
Cloth, women clothing, shoes
Shapard &amp; Mitchell
Hardware, Groceries, drugs
Leinau &amp; Carney
Bonnets, Hats, Shoes, Glassware
Hardimre and Groceries
99
Willis Barker
Boots &amp; Shoes and Confectianarles
en comer of Bank &amp; I^rbls Street
Tariff - a much admired Stallion and a full brother of Arob wiU
stand this spring near Murfreesborough - Martin Clark.
Dissolution - James C. Moore &amp; Co. has gone out of business.
Six cents reward - WLlllan Carter an apprentice of Abraham Ove(rall?)
has runaway. He is sixteen years old.
Estraor taken up by the following persons ;
Harmon ELrod living on McKni^t creek
Nathaniel Wallis living two miles east of Murfreesborough
Thomas Owens near Banton's Ferry on Stones river.
John B. Prewett living twelve miles south of Murfreesborough
James fiiight on Kennards creek ten miles south of Murfreesborough
Vfa. Witherspoon on McKni^t creek
Sherriff sale of the land of James McGiU 150 acres on Horse
Spring fork of Stones river being a tract granted to said James McGill.
Adjoins the lands of Carson &amp; Simpson on east, Whiteside &amp; Poff on the
south, Beede on the west &amp; Slznpson on the north. Being the tract where
the said James McGill &amp; John McGill now live.
The Courier, Vol . II, # 8$ Wednesday Feb. 16, I83I printed every
Wednesday
Benefactor- much admired horse wiU stand for the season coranencing
on March 10 and ending Jtiiy 10 at our stable nine miles from Murfreesboro
on the lower road leading to Shelbyville half of the time and the other
half at Samuel Carqjbell three miles from Murfreesboro on the same road.
Roily Morgan, Saml. Winston
Young Pacolet - Will stand commencing March 10 at otu* stable on the
lower road leading to Shelbyville one-half of the time and Dr. F. E. Beeton
100
stable three miles from Marfreesboro on the same road the other one half.
Samuel Winston &amp; RolLey Morgan
Sir Richard - vill stand at the farm of FhLllp J. Burrus five miles
north of Murfreesboro near the road from Nashville to McMtraiville.
Waterloo - wiU stand at the stable of Robert Smith in Murfreesboro.
Court Action - Thomas L. Woods has been taken to court for a debt.
Hb now resides in Missouri and is beyond the court's jurisdiction. He
HvBd in Rutherford County until l&amp;^8 and was married to PoUy Rowton,
daughter of William Rowton dec. His wife PoUy inherited several slaves
now in the hands of Mary Rowton and William Ledbetter asks the court to
award the slaves to him.
Petition for divorce - Mildred Palmer has petitioned the court for
a divorce from William H. Palmer. They were married in June 1823 and
they have one child. Vfa. H. Palmer now lives in another state.
Washington Hotel - Robert Smith has again taken possessicai of the
house and would like for the public to call. He also asks for those
indebted to the subscriber to make payment as they cannot live on the
wind. Jan. 26, 1831
Bradley Acadeny - Trustees give notice that the next season will
commence on Monday Jan. 10 under Mr. Clark M. Comstock A. M. irtio has
presided over the school for the past twelve months. A pair of globes
and necessary maps have been procured for the academy. Dec. 25.
Estraj-s - The following have taken in stray livestock.
James DeJamett living three miles west of Murfreesboro.
Noah Smith living near Nelson's Mill on Stewarts creek.
Dissolutions - The partnership of Rufus B. Jetton &amp; William D.
HLcks has been dissolved. Rufus B. Jetton and Baily W. Farmer have
formed a new partnership and will continue the business of tailoring
at the same shop.
Id
Becton &amp; HartwoU have dissolved their partnership. Dr. Becton
will continue his business at the place which To B. Hanley recently
sold him, three miles south of Murfreesboro . Dr. Hartwell will continue
In town. Alexander Rankin has been en^xLoyed to close their accounts.
Notice - Drury Robison has purchased the interest of N. C. Dill as
partner and will continue the business at the same place on the north-west
comer of the square. He is making inprovements &amp; additions to the
facilities.
William R. Stewart - gold and silversmith.
David Shepherd &amp; G. W. Shanklin having purchased a tanyard &amp; stock
from Mr. James Bone invite the public to come.
Klne Pock Matter - Genuine and fresh may be had at Dr. Holmes office.
Sheriff sale of land - Five tracts on Feb. 21
1. Tract of $00 acres of David Patton where he now lives on the
waters of the east fork of Stones River. Conveyed to David Patton by deed
dated Nov. 20, l809 by John Overton.
2. Tract of 100 acres of Matthew Patton. Tract lies 2$ poles
west of Charles Wells west comer, beginning on a white oak and hickory
then north 100 poles to a black locust &amp; buckeye, then east l6o poles
to an elm &amp; hickory, then south loo poles to a dogwood &amp; ironwood then
west l6o poles to the beginning.
3. Tract of 75 acres of Peter Moore &amp; Matthew Patton. Bounded
on the north by the military line and includes the premises where Martin
Texmison fomerly lived.
U. Tract of which acres not know belonging to Peter Moore &amp;
Thomas Stokes where they now live. Land adjoins Calvin Curlee on the
west, Joshua Barton on the north, Cullen Curlee on the east and on the
south by the military line.
5. Tract of 5o acres of John T. Fair, being the place where
Gideon Williams now lives. lying south and adjoining Charles Ready,
Joseph Tennison, HLram Tennison &amp; others.
New Fall &amp; Winter goods - Scrape &amp; Elder have moved to the new
building lately erected on the west side of the square by Maj . Ledbetter
between Mr. Sperry and the printing office. They have a splendid assort-ment
of goods from Philadelphia, Baltimore and PittsbTirg.
102
Vfin. T. Christy &amp; Co. advertises a new line of Fall goods.
The Courier Murfreesborough , Vol II, &#163; 22&gt; Wednesday April 6,l83I
printed every Wednesday ly J. D. Hill.
At a meeting of a ntoiiber of the citizens of this cotmly at the
courthouse on Monday evening the l|th for appointing some suitable
person to attend the Literary Convention in Nashville, MaJ. John Nelson
was asked to be chaiiman and Dr. P. D. Neilson was appointed secretary.
Dr. F. E. Becton was appointed to attend the convention.
Wm.is Barker has moved to a b\illdlng on the pubUc square, a few
doors south of the Washington Hotel and in the building recently occupied
"by Mr. R. Spence, selling boots, shoes and confectionaries
.
Married - On last Wednesday evening Maj . Henry D . Ransom to Miss
Pricilla Manor, daughter of Mr. Mills Manor, all of this cotnity.
Charles Ready announces that he has returned home and will now
devote his time entirely to practicing law.
P. D. Neilson offers his services as a physician &amp; surgeon. His
office is the one previously occupied by Dr. L. P. Yandell.
Nlles and Thomas have formed a partnership offer saddles, bridles
and an assortment of plated ware.
Dissolution of Partnerships: James C. Moore Sc Josiah Nichol trading
under the name J. C. Moore &amp; Co. are dissolved. James C. Moore has bought
out the other partner and will continue the btisiness.
James B. Davis &amp; Wilson Thomas have dissolved their business.
James B. Davis will continue at the same place selling saddles St bridles.
A, Sweepstake - now open for two year old colts &amp; fillies to be run
on the Hurricane Hilla Course, mile beats on Sept. 13 next. One hundred
dollars entrance. Benjamin Johnson proprietor Rutherford Co.
103
For Sale - tfy plantation on Stones River 9i mLles northeast of
Murfreesborough. It contains about 180 acres and is recoranended to
those wishing to purchase by a savnnill, grist rdll and cotton gin,
on a never failing stream. Jonathan Rucker
For Sale - 35 acres with an excellent drrelUng and outbuildings
Also a tan-yard of Iwelve vats in good condition. lyin on Long Creek
in the nei^borhood of Robert Miller. George Jones
Estray - Taken in by John Foster living near Morgan's Mill
Notice - Edward Tatura Jr. &amp; W. B, Morris will survey the 5000 acre
tract of John Donelson dec. on April 6 as ordered by the county court,
luring on the west fork of Stones River runs west 6^0 poles and south
1250 poles agreeable to the grant to J. G. &amp; T. Blount. No. 228
The Courier , Wednesday April 20, I83I Vol H. No. 9k
The circuit court now in session has dispatched all the jury trails.
During the term B. G. Coleman was tried for the murder of N. H. Williams
in this coiaity last December. He was found guilty. Rev. Samuel R.
Davidson is e:q)ected to preach at the Methodist church this evening at
early candlelight. Jno. M. Tilford advertizes a new and useful invention
for sale. A harrow &amp; scraper for cultivating com and cotton is for sale
by him as agent for the inventor. He has enlisted Capt. Burrell Perry,
Col. Win. W. Searcy, Vfci. Bennett, George A. Siiblett, John Hoover, V&amp;n.
Rutledge, Robt. Ross, Win. James, Henry Maney, Capt. James Elliott, Tfftn.
Elliott, James Mitchell, and Lemuel Reed. The last four named will
furnish them ready made. They can also be obtained in Murfreesboro
through Dan'l Parker and Mr. Tompkins . . .
Estray - John Foster living near Morgans Mill has taken in a mare
Sheriff Sale of land of Jenkins Whitesides deceased for debt against
lOl*
his heirs- , David WhitestLdes, Richard C. Whiteaides,
Jane Lafferlgr, James , , Newton Parker and his wife
formerly Mary J. Lafferty, , M'Goldric .
Tract 1 - 1150 acres on main east fork in 8th section, 7th
range in Rutherford county. Beginning at ihree lynns and a hickory
the NE comer of said section, running then with the east boundzy of
the Same south 185 poles, to a \ihlte oak &amp; elm, then west crossing
the river at 80 poles in all 3h2 poles to two beeches &amp; an ash, then
north 585 poles to a red oak, elm &amp; hickory in the military line
then with the same to the beginning. Granted to Jenkins Whiteside
on May k, I809 by grant # IO6I*.
Tract 2 - 320 acres in the 2nd district 8th range, 8th section
on the main east fork. Beginning at three lynns &amp; a hickory the NW
comer of said section 4 the NE comer of his ll50 acres tract, running
south with the section line, crossing a creek at 200 poles in all 320
poles to two sugar trees, then east I60 poles to a stake &amp; sugar tree
in a field, then north crossing the river at 60 poles &amp; a creek at 100
poles in all 320 poles to a walnut &amp; lynn in thick cane, then west to
the beginning. Granted to Jenkins VMteside on March 20, I809 by grant
# 959.
Tract # 3 - 100 acres lying in the 2nd district on waters of
the main east fork in the west boundry of section 8 range 8, beginning
at a stake &lt;&#167;t a dead beech in a field 50 poles south of the SE comer of
a tract of 1150 acres of said Whiteside, then with the section line south
160 poles to a sugar tree &amp; beech, then east 100 poles to a beech &lt;^
walnut, then north I60 poles to a white oak &amp; hidcory then west to the
be^nning. Granted to Jenkins Whiteside on March 20, I809 by grant # 96O.
Tract # li - 125 acres in Rutherford county in 2nd district, 7th
range, 8th section. Beginning at a white oak &amp; elm in the SE comer of a
1150 acre survey of said Whiteside running south with the section line
200 poles to a beech &amp; sugar tree, then west 100 poles to a beech, then
north 200 poles to three sugar trees in the south boundry of the 1150
acres, then with the same to the beginning. Granted to Jenkins Whiteside
on March 20, I809 by grant # 96I.
Tract #5-75 acres in the 2nd district on the middle fork of
the east fork. Beginning at a beech &amp; walnut the SE comer of a 100
acre grant of said Whiteside on which Thomas Fullows &lt;St Frederick Meredith
lived, running east 56 poles to two hickories &amp; a dogwood, then south 120
poles to two hickories on the north boundzy of a survey of said Whiteside,
then west 100 poles to a hickory &amp; sugartree, then north 1&#8212; to a stake
in said Whiteside south boundiy, then east with the same to the beginning,
including the place where James Simpson foiroerly lived. Grant # 12,li69
to Jenkins Whiteside dated April 8, I818.
Tract # 6 - li5 acres lying on the middle fork of the east fork in
the 2nd district, beginning at the NW comer of a 125 acres tract of said
Whiteside &amp; in the south boundiy of 1150 acre tract... with said 125
acres 120 ....hickory, then west , then east with the same 60 poles
105
to the beginning. Grant # 12,908 to Jenkins Whiteside dated Dec. 19&gt;
1818.
Tract # 7 - 100 acres on the east fork in the 2nd district.
Beginning at two hickories &amp; a white oak in Charles Wells north boundry
of his 200 acres survey, 25 poles west from his NE comer, runs north
100 poles to a white oak, locust k buck^re, then l6o poles to a hickory
and elm, then south 100 poles to an elm &amp; ironwood, then west to the
beginning. Grant # 962 to Jenkins Whiteside dated March 20, l809.
Tract #8-77 acres in the 2nd district, 7th range, 8th
section on the east fork. Beginning at two red elms the SW comer of an
entry of 68 acres of George Douherty, then with his line north (crossing
a small creek} 1;8 poles to a large beech marked M, then east 68 TX)les to a
a red elm, then south 132 poles to a beech, then east 108 poles
(crossing a small creek} to a stake, then north 81; poles to a white
walnut, then west with Doherty line i|0 poles to the beginning. Grant
# 8liU to Jenkins Whiteside dated Feb. 9, l809.
The members of the Hurricane Hills Jockey Club will meet in Col.
Robert Smith's tavem in Murfreesboro on Saturday the 23. G. S. Crockett
sec'y.
The Courier , Wednesday Jan. 19, 1831 Vol. H No. 81
The person doing the editorial for the paper has left and the editor
asked the readers to overlook this deficiency.
The Courier , Wednesday Feb 2, I83I Vol II No 83
Yeaman Circus will be in town for the remainder of the week. C^nraiastLc
Equestrian, and Theatrical. Doors open at 6 o'clock. Admittance 50 cents,
children and servants 25^. No smoking allowed in the circus.
EstraK " Charles L. Davis living on Stewarts creek near Anthony's
mill has taken in a sorrel mare.
The Courier , Wednesday Feb. 9, I831 Vol II No 82;
Married on Wednesday evening last Mr. John D. Black to Miss Sarah C.
SubLett dau^ter of C^t. William A. Sublett all of Rutherford. Died
at his residence Mr. David Rankin age 61 on Thursday evening the 3rd.
Many years a citizen of this county.
The Courier, Wednesday Feb. 23 &gt; I831 Vol II no 86
106
The Race Horse Defoe will stand at the farm of Hiillip J. Burrus,
The Courier , Wednesday March 30, I83I Vol II No. 91
Died in Dyer County, Tenn. Mr. Mark Mitchell formerly of Rutherford
Covaty (no date given j.
In Nashville Gen Robert Purdy, U. S. Marshal on the 25th. died.
On the 26th Mr, Henry M'Culloch of this coTmly died.
The Courier Wednesday July k, I832 Vol. IV No 157
Locke &amp; Abbott lists a supply of superfine broadcloth.
Auction sale of stock of goods of Chas. B. Egan at his store in Murfrees-borough
on July 7th. He has -wine, brandy, rum, gin, sperm candles,
spices, cheese. Also jewelery, saddlery, hats, shoes, boots &amp; a
variety of dry goods.
S. H. Lau^ilin has a farm for sale on the east fork of Stones River
below the mouth of Bradley's creek.
The Cotirier Murfreesborough Wednesday July 11, I832 Vol IV No 153
Married - On Thursday evening Mr. Collins Farmer of this town and Miss
Elizabeth Kelton da\ighter of Vbi. Kelton of the county. On the same
evening Mr. Francis Vannerson to Elizabeth W. Elam, daughter of _____
dec&#187;d both of this county.
Anniversary - The Temperance society celebrated its anniversarj' on
the l^th. The Hon. J. C. Mitchell delivered an address which was followed
by a few remarks by Rev. John Jones. It was held in the Presbyterian
church
.
Liberal Prices - James &amp; John Holmes wish to buy 20 or 30 negro
boys and men between 12 and 25 years of age for cash.
Two volunteer companies have been raised in Bedford County to repair
to the Illinois frontier against the hostile Indians.
Reward - Fifty dollars for a large black horse taken from his farm
eight miles west of Murfreesboro on the night of the 20th John lytle.
107
One cent reward - An. apprentice to the saddling business named
John Hall about l8 years of age. Charles Nlles of Nlles &amp; Thomas
The following reported taking in Estrays.
^trs. Ann Rucker living on the stage road five idles NW of Murfreesboro.
-John Rowen living near Dic:.kinson's mill 2 miles west of town.
-Jacob Hoover living in Hoover's Gap.
-Joshua Clay living 3 miles below Jefferson.
-Win 1 am Singleton living between Overall and Stewarts creek.
&#8226;^Willie Sanders living about 2 miles east of Ridley's mill.
-John Todd living on Owl creek a tributary of the dry fork and about
2 miles north of Carson's mill.
-Allen Nance living on the Rocky Fork of Stewarts creek about 2 miles
above Nelson's mill
-Jonathan Bateman living on Brawley's fork of Stones River.
- John Snell living near Capt. James M. King on the road from Nashville
to Shelbyville.
Turn pike Notice - The Nashville, Murfreesborough ^ Shelbyville
turnpike stock holders are notified that 10 per cent of the stock has
been called for to be paid on the first of August.
The CoTirier Wednesday July l8, I832 Vol. IV No. 159
An Ordinance to clean up the town due to the threat of Cholera. Jive
persons appointed to see that the ordinance is enforced. James C. Moore,
Moses G. Reeves, M. Spence, Chas. NUes, &amp; John Smith
The Courier Wednesday July 25, 1832 Vol. IV No. I60
Died In this town on Tuesday morning last Jane Deans Hill infant daughter
of the publisher of this paper aged 9 months &amp; 'dh days. Near Salisbury,
N. C. on the l6th last Mrs. Sarah Trott aged about 91
The Jock^ Club races will commence on the second Wednesday in Sept.
108
next. A meeting wiU be held on the day preceding the race at ten
o'clock at the Hurricane Hills course.
The CoTirler - Wednesday August 8, I832 Vol IV No I62
A new newspaper in Murfreesborough . The Western Express may begin soon
as a ps^r however the Courier is not afraid of the conq)etltion.
Died - Mrs. Elizabeth Wade consort of Capt. John Wade Sr. on Sund^
evening aged about 60 years. Leaves a husband and numerous offspring.
On Monday evening the 6th Ifrs. Catherine Warren consort of William
Warren and daughter of Col. John Thompson, aged about UO years. Leaving
a husband and children
To Undertakers - Proposals for the building a brick meeting house
will be received until Tuesday the ZL. A plan of the house may be seen
at Dr. Becton by bricklayer and carpenters who wUl likewise receive
proposals - The commissioners.
A new cotton gin shop under the name of William 4 Alfred Elliott at
William Elliott's residence three miles south of Jefferson. Cotton gins
of the best materials will be forwarded to any point on the Mississippi.
Estray - William G. Parrish living k miles south of Murfreesborough.
- Bamett Elliott living on Stewart creek.
- Hubbard S. Wilkerson Hving 6 miles west of Murfreesborough.
- John Lawrence living at Black Fox Camp
The Courier Wednesday August 15, 1832 Vol. IV No. I63
Twenty five cents reward for a bound apprentice boy to the carpenter
business named Thomas Simmons - James M'Dowel of M\irfreesborough
.
Taxes for 1832 for each type of property:
For eveiy 100 acres I4I cents
For every white poll 31% cents
For every black poU 5U cents
Four wheel carriage 11.00 dollars
Two wheel carriage 5.00 dollars
Each town lot 32^ cents
109
The Coorler Wednesday Aag. 29, 1832 Vol. IV No. l65
Married on Tuesday evening \jy Rev. Eagleton. Mr. James Elder to Miss
Elizabeth dau^ter of Charles NUes of Murfreesborough. Married on
Monday evening by William Gilliam esq. Mr. John D. Murphy to Miss
lAici^tia daughter of Mr. John Watkins all of this town.
The Courier Murfreesborough Wednesday Sept. $, 1832 Vol. I No. 1
Spinning Factory - Mr. Lowry late of Kentucky has within the last ei^t or
nine months completed a spinning factory in our town. It is now in
operation and at present there are about 200 spindles, A new Post Office
has been established at Lascassas in this county and Valentine M. Sublett
appointed postmaster. A Camp meeting tiy the Presbyterians commencing
on Th\irsday evening the 13 at Kelton's five miles southeast of this place.
Died - In the county at the residence of Major R. H. Mason on the 30th
Mr. - - - - Mason in the 80th year of his age. For forty years he had
been a member of the Methodist church. His wife died about sixteen years
ago. On Friday 31 Miss Margaret dau^ter of Ifr. Ezra Jones. On the same
day Mrs. Susan Tear wife of Richard V. Tear.
Notice - Having disposed of the Courier J. D. HtU woiOd like to
collect frcMn persons owing htm money. On the front of the paper the
new owners are listed as F. G. Warren &amp; J. W. White.
Sheriff Sale - A tract of 1^0 acres belonging to the heirs of Thomas
Ivey dec'd, Littleton Screws and Malinda his wife, Abraham S. Ivey,
Margaret I. Ivey, Sarah M. Ivey, and Margaret Jane Ivey all heirs of
Thomas Ivey. Land lying on the west fork adjoining Dr. Calhoun on the
north, Sam'l Bowman on the west, James Daniel on the south, and Nathaniel
Perry on the east.
Anotlier tract on the east fork known by the name of the Cummin's
Mill tract that belongs to David Abbott will be sold on Saturday before
no
the third Monday in Nonroniber, Joins John Hoover on the north and was
bought from John M. Tilford by said David Abbott, (part of this gone).
J. Ciirrin has sold his stock of goods to Mr. G. I. Cain he wish
to close his books and would like to collect all debts.
George I. Cain has an ad for business on the north side of the square,
opposite the market house. He has 100 barrels of salt on hand.
Dissolutions- Niles &amp; Thomas have dissolved their partnership
.
Wilson Thomas has bought the stock of saddlery and will continue the
business at the NW comer of the square.
Doctors Maney &amp; Rucker have dissolved their partnership.
Locke St Abbott have an ad for ST^erfine cloths, groceries, glass
&amp; hardware.
The Courier Sept. 19, I832 Vol. I. No. 3
W. B. Cooper portrait painter has an ad for his services in a room over
Dr. Ruckers office.
Mr. S. Charaux offers his services as a teacher of French. He is
now to be found at Maj. Reeve's tarvem. Yoimg ladies can receive private
instructions.
A Refutation of Campbellism on sell at our store - W. Ledbetter Co.
The Courier Wednesday Sept. 26, I832 Vol. I. No. li
On Thursday the 27 at 9 o'clock the students at Bradley Academy will
ccmanence examinations. They will embrace Greek, Ehglish, Geography,
Algebra &#8212;&#8212;, &amp; Arithmetic.
Cooking stoves for sale by Vftn. T. Christy &amp; Co.
The ft-esbyterians held a camp meeting five miles from this place on
the 13th and concluded on the 19th at which upwards of fifty persons pro-fessed
religion.
The Methodist held a canip meeting at Norell's csaxsp ground in
Bedford Countgr at the same time at \tb&#177;ch over sixty made a profession
of faith. Also another at Bemett's camp ground at which forty pro-fessed
faith.
Nashville Republican Banner - Wednesday March 2, 182;2
Prom the Murfreesboro Telegraph - Vfei. Gilliam an old resident was drowned
last Wednesday while atten^jting to cross Stones River. His body has not
been fovnd.
The Murfreesborough Telegraph has been purchased by Mr. J. W.
Smith and the editorial department is to be conducted by his brother
W. H. Stelth recently one of the editors of the HuntsvilLe Advocate. E.
Harriman Esq. was apparently the old owner of the paper. The new owners
state that they will contintie to be strong supporters of the Whig
principles.
Three Rutherford County citizens published petition for bankruptcy
Wilson H. Kerr, Jesse B. Parrish, and Reuben Boiles.
National Banner, Sept. 1, 1835 Nashville
$100 dollars reward - runaway from John W. Traylor and Vta. B. Traylor of
Rutherford Co. on the night of the 5th of Jvily. Two likely negro men.
Jim about 25 years old 5 ft. 6 inches, dark color, slender, speaks quick,
had on black cloth coat, hangup pantaloons, &amp; a black fur hat about half
worn, weighs about 150 poornds. Gideon about 28 years old, 5*2 to 6 ft
high, stout, speaks slow, has large white eyes. He had on rather in-different
cotton pantaloons, a woolen roundabout i an old black fur hat.
Both of them were purchased in May at Norfolk, Va. &lt;i may go there or try
to go to a free state. Twenty five dollars for each if caught in this
state and fifty each if caught in another state.
112
Republican Banner Dec. 31, 1839 Nashville Vol. 15 No, 1
Rtnaway - from James Morton living near Stewartsborough in Rutherford
Co. a negro boy naxned Tobe. He is about 12 years, dark con^jlected with
a little copper tinge. He left in June and may have gone to Nashville
as he has been there several times with iny wagon.
These additioioal Nashville newspapers were found, however, no
news was foxmd in them of Rutherford County.
National Banner April 19, I83I # I6, Vol. 6
National Banner April 26, I83I
National Banner June 7, I833 # 33, Vol. 8
National Banner Nov 1, 1833 # U3, Vol. 8
National Banner Dec 26, l83it
Republican Banner Oct 2k, l8U2 # h3. Vol. 17
Republican Banner Feb 13, 181*3 # 7, Vol. I8
Republican Banner July 17, l81i5 # 29, Vol. 20
Our thanks to Bill lynch for alloxdug the use of these fragile
early papers to be abstracted in March, I982.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Abstracts of early newspapers found in a Rutherford County home, to be microfilmed at the Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.); Rutherford County (Tenn.) -- Archival resources; Rutherford County (Tenn.) -- Newspapers; Tennessee. Division of Library and Archives</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-08</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication19ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/162</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>