<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Readyville</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hall, Mary</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 4</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1974</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>18th century; 19th century; 20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>READYVILLE
Readyville is located on the East Fork of Stones River,
twelve miles east of Murfreesboro on Highway 70S, which was
the original Stage Coach Road from Knoxville to Nashville,
also called "The Immigrant Trail," and "The Trail of Tears."
It was named for Colonel Charles Ready, who was born
in Maryland in 1770. It is not know when he moved to North
Carolina, but it seems that he came here with his friend,
George Brandon, from North Carolina about 1802. He purchased
a large tract of land from General Griffith Rutherford on
Stones River. He built his log cabin near a large chalybeate
spring
.
Rutherford County was formed from Davidson and William-son
Counties in 18 OH and Charles Ready was one of the seven
justices who made up the first county court.
In the 1820 's he superintended his slaves in building
one of the first brick houses in the county. He named it
"The Corners." It was used as an inn for travelers. Andrew
Jackson frequently spent a night there on his way to
Washington before and after he became President.
In 1811 the Federal Government established a Post
Office there, named it "Readyville , " and appointed Charles
Ready the first Postmaster-
He was one of seven commissioners appointed by the
Legislature in 1811 to choose a permanent county seat.
Colonel Ready tried very hard to get Readyville chosen,
but he lost by a three to four vote, and Murfreesboro
became the County Seat.
In 1812 he built a dam on Stones River, near his
home, and erected a mill, which is still in operation (1971+)
Colonel Ready continued being one of the wealthiest
and most influential men in Rutherford County. The 1850
census lists him as being 8 years of age, with land valued
at $15,800.
He died in August 1859, and is buried in the family
graveyard near his home.
SOURCES:
Goodspeeds: History of Tennessee
Hughes: Hearthstones
Registrars Records of Rutherford County
Sims: History of Rutherford County
1810, 1830, 1850 Census Reports
EARLY SETTLERS
Few people have preserved their family records. We
have used the ones which are available to verify dates of
settlement in this area. For others we have checked in
the Rutherford County Registrar's Office Deed Book Vol. 1
1804-1810; Census Reports 1810-1850; and from the first map
of Rutherford County 18 78.
George Brandon came from North Carolina in 18 02 with
Charles Ready and Joseph Tennison, his sister, Sibella
Brandon's, husband. Samuel Arnett settled on the north
side of Pilot Knob before 1810. David Barton and his son,
Joshua, and Jonathan Hall, his brother-in-law, came from
Virginia and settled on Stones River in 1806.
A deed is on record in the Davidson County Courthouse
showing that George Brandon bought 39^h acres of land, on
the East Fork of Stones River from General Griffith Ruther-ford,
May 11, 1802.
He was born in Rowan County, North Carolina in 1770.
In 179 7 he married Sidney McGuire. They built a log house
on their land where the road through Readyville makes a "^
right-angle turn.
In 1803 George Brandon was one of the men who signed
the petition asking the State Legislature to form Rutherford
County, which was done in 18 4 by taking parts of Davidson
and Williamson counties.
In 1812 he organized a volunteer company and went to
fight with Andrew Jackson in the War of 1812. He died at
Readyville in 1844.
Samuel and Leonard Bivins settled in the area now
called "Bivins Hill," west of Readyville. The Nelson and
Fulks families also settled in that area. Abner Dement
settled on McKnights creek before 1810.
John Pruett Dunn married Nancy Brandon, daughter of
George Brandon. They lived about two miles from Readyville
on the Cripple Creek Road, which had been called "Millers-burg
Road." John Pruett Dunn was the son of John Dunn who
came from North Carolina, and is listed in the 1810 Census.
Another son, William A. Dunn, married Cynthia Brandon,
younger daughter of George Brandon. After William's death
she married Walker Peake for whom "Peake's Hill" is named.
They had a "wagon yard" where people traveling in wagons
could stop and spend the night.
It was said that Mr. Peake gave one thousand dollars
toward building the stage-coach road if it would come over
the hill and by his house. The surveyors ran it down the
steepest part of the hill. Loaded wagons had a great deal
of difficulty getting up the hill. Mr. Peake requested
that he be buried near the road at the steepest place, so
he could hear the wagoners "cuss" as they tried to drive
balking teams up the steep hill. His grave is covered with
large, flat rocks and can be seen near the old road. His
brother, Simeon Peake, lived across the road.
George McGuire Dunn, son of John Pruett Dunn and Nancy
Brandon Dunn, married Sara Elizabeth Helton. They first
lived on land given by his father on Cripple Creek. In
1866 he bought the Walker Peake farm, and was considered
one of the large land owners in the community.
James Dunn married Betty Early. He also sold the
Cripple Creek farm given by his father, and bought the Simeon
Peake farm across the road from his brother, George McGuire Dunn.
Another brother, Thomas Franklin Dunn, married Levicy
Nelson in 186 7. She was the daughter of Evins Nelson
and Jane Fulks, who lived behind Pilot Knob. Mr. Frank Dunn
owned the land now known as the Wharton farm. He was
wounded in the Civil War and never completely recovered.
He died in 1882.
Mr. Pat Davidson and Mr. Jim Champion owned land at
the foot of Pilot Knob on the east side. James McKnight
sold William McKnight 215 acres of land on Stones River and
McKnight Creek in April 1804. William Walkup also bought
land in 1804.
John Lewis Jetton and Robert Jetton recorded deeds for
land in 1806. Mathias Hoover bought 840 acres of land in
1808. Henry and John Goodloe registered deeds in 1813,
and James Holmes in 18 30.
John D. Smith was an early settler. He died in 1892.
He owned a large tract of land on Stones River, which
included a woodland filled with one of the finest cedar
forests in Tennessee. The tall, beautiful trees no doubt
had withstood the winds and storms of a couple of centuries.
This tract of virgin timber remained in the Smith
family for four generations, until 1970, when "woodmen"
could no longer "spare the trees," when it was purchased
by the Lane Cedar Company.
In the early days of settlement an old German man,
by the name of "Goocher," entered land and built a log
cabin at the turn of the road on the west bank of Stones
River, about a mile west of Readyville. The place where the
road crossed the river near his house came to be called
"Goocher's Ford." A concrete slab across the river provides
a safer crossing today. This road which turns right off
the "Bivins Hill Road," used to be called the "River Road,"
has now been correctly named the "Goocher Ford Road."
SOURCES:
Dunn Family records
Interviews with Margaret Brevard
Interviews with Herbert Smith
Rutherford County Deed Books
Census Reports of Rutherford County 1810-1850
CHURCHES
There never has been a church in Readyville, although
it has always been known to be a religious community.
First settlers, Charles Ready and his wife Polly,
attended Stones River Presbyterian Church, three miles
over Bivins Hill Road. Other early settlers went over the
River Road to Antioch Church of Christ, or down the Stage
Coach Road to Science Hill Church of Christ, or to Wilson
Hill Baptist Church.
In 1852 Graham Brandon built the nearest church to
the village. New Hope Church of Christ, about one mile
above Readyville, on land given by John Lewis Jetton.
Antioch Church of Christ
Goodspeeds History of Tennessee records Antioch
as having been organized in 183 3. The first house was
built of logs, and was some distance from the present
building.
Jacob Wright was one of the first members. His wife,
Becky, was a Presbyterian. In 1848 he gave the land on
which Antioch Church of Christ and Stones River Presbyterian
Church were built. He specified in the deed that although
these churches were on adjoining lots, there should never
be conflict in their services, and there has not been during
these more than one hundred years.
The church record book states that the present house
&#171;/as built in 1854. One hundred years later, in 1954,
Sunday School rooms were added. The entire building has
been modernized with carpet, new seats, electric lights,
gas heat and air-conditioning.
Among the early elders were: J. D. Smith, W. T.
McKnight, J. H. Hare, Sam Kerr, and B. R. Goodloe.
Among the early deacons were: J. S. Nelson and T. J.
Wright
.
Early members listed were: Lafayette Smith, J. E.
Dill, Samuel Vaught, J. S. Nelson, J. F. Dismukes, W. T.
Todd, Charlie Keele, Steve Jordan.
No ministers were listed before 190 3. The following
have served in summer revivals since: C. M. Pulias , L. B.
Jones, J. B. Bradley, H. Leo Boles, Rice Sewell, Charlie
Taylor.
Some present members are: Terry McElroy, Neil McElroy,
Edward Shirley, Wilbur Smithson, Cecil Bowman, Ray Hare,
Roy Burrus, Earl Davis.
The present minister is William Mizell. There are no
elders and deacons listed.
SOURCES:
Interview with Mrs. Eula Craddock and Mrs. J. H. Paschal
Church Record Book
Stones River Presbyterian Church
The Stones River Presbyterian Church U. S., located
approximately ten miles from Murfreesboro on the Hall's
Hill Road near the east fork of Stones River was organized
on April 1, 1816 by the Rev. Jesse Eagleton Alexander. It
was the outgrowth of a Camp Meeting previously held about
three miles from the present church on the way to Milton.
After meeting in a small log building on the opposite side
of the road from the present church, in 1848 Jacob Wright,
whose wife, Becky, was a member of Stones River Church,
gave the land on which Stones River and Antioch Churches
were built. Antioch is a Church of Christ of which Mr.
Wright was a member.
A large log church with twelve corners was built just
east of the present building. This building was replaced by
a frame building on the same ground in 1878 west of the log
building which was torn down. An addition of Sunday School
rooms was added in 1954 or 1955.
The building is in a good state of repair and worship
services are held each Sunday and other activities as the
program of the church directs.
The following are the charter members of the church:
James, Eleanor, William and Isabell McKnight; Joseph and
Jane Knox; Charles and Polly Ready; Joseph and Jane Weather-spoon;
Charles and June Porterfield; Polly Weatherspoon;
Peggy, David, and Polly Andrews; John and Sarah Henderson;
John, Peggy, Moses, and Rixney McKnight; Peggy, John M.
and Abigal McKnight.
It might be interesting to note that Frank and Silva
Brantley, descendents of the Brantley slaves, attended
preaching services regularly until their deaths in the
early 1900's.
Ministers who have served as pastors are: Jesse
Eagleston Alexander; E. T. Brantley and his son, Erskine;
Thompson; Mosley; A. J. Crane; T. A. Patten; R. T. Riley;
W. W. Patten; Johnson; W. H. Matherson; William Jones; and
Wythe M. Peyton, Jr. (the present pastor 1972).
SCHOOLS
The first school known to have been at Readyville was
taught in 1810 by James Barkley, a Revolutionary soldier.
The location has not been determined.
In 1850 Mr. W. B. Huddleston had a school called "Pap
Huddleston's School." It was in a large log building in the
corner of his yard, where Mr. Leslie Justice now lives.
Children from all of the surrounding area walked as much
as six miles daily to that school. It closed when Mr.
Huddleston died.
10
Some years after the Civil War after Science Hill
Academy burned, perhaps 1885, a school house was built
across the river, on Talley Hill above Colonel Ready's
mill. It was a large two-story frame building. This was
the only school for the Kittrell-Readyville communities for
several years.
Among teachers were: Mr. John Hines , Mr. J. J. North-cott,
Mr. John Wesley Jamison, Miss Sara Jamison, Miss Mary
Murfree, Miss Cassie McGill, and Mrs. Annie Youree.
The building burned in 1902. Since that time children
have gone to school at Kittrell and Woodbury.
Tilford's Saw Mill is now located on this last school
site
.
SOURCES:
Mrs . Oscar Barker
Mrs. J. D. McFarlin
PROFESSIONAL PEOPLE
Doctors were the outstanding professional people in
the Readyville Community. It had seven doctors over a period
of fifty years, more than most rural communities ever have.
Dr. J. H. Dickens
The first doctor known to live in Readyville was Dr.
James Holt Dickens. He was the son of Baxter and Nancy
Holt Dickens, and was born June 11, 1823. It is thought
that he grew up in, or near the Readyville Community.
11
It is not known where he received his education. He
married Margaret Malissa McKnight January 25, 1849.
He bought the George Brandon home in the center of
Readyville and later became one of the largest land owners
in the community. Dr. and Mrs. Dickens did not have any
children, but they reared one of her nephews, Andrew McKnight,
whom he made his heir.
He practiced medicine in Readyville for many years
,
and died at the age of seventy-two on March 3, 1895.
Dr. J. N. Bridges
Several years after Dr. Dickens began practicing
medicine, a young doctor from New Middleton in Smith County
came to Readyville. He was Dr. J. N. Bridges. He lived
in the house known as the "Betty Craig house." He was
there when the 18 7 8 map of Rutherford County was made.
He later returned to New Middleton. No information is
available concerning him.
Dr. W. E. Youree
Dr. William Eleazer Youree was born in 18U8, the son
of Francis and Elizabeth Lowe Youree. He was reared in the
Murray Community. No information is available about his
early life.
It is not known when he attended medical school, but
he began practicing medicine at Donnell's Chapel. He then
moved to Readyville and practiced medicine with Dr. Dickens
for several years
.
12
He married Miss Rebecca Carter. Mrs. Youree died after
several years, and left him with five little girls. He
later married Mrs, Annie Macon Walling in 1898. They had
two sons, John and Robert.
Dr. Youree was an elder in the New Hope Church of
Christ. He had a wide practice, mostly in the "horse and
buggy" days. He suffered from asthma all of his life, and
in the last few years he had more frequent attacks. He
died of flu at his home in 1925.
Dr. E. A. Speer
No information is available concerning the early life
of Dr. Ephriam A. Speer. It is thought that his father was
a minister and lived in Pulaski. He was a young man when
he came to Donnell's Chapel to practice medicine. He
married Miss Lyon. After some years he moved to Readyville.
He lived a mile from the village on "Squirrel Hill." He
had six children, three sons and three daughters. He had
a good practice and lived to be an old man. He died in
190 3, and is buried in the Lyon family graveyard near
Donnell's Chapel.
Dr. E. M. Holmes
Ernest Martin Holmes was born and reared in Readyville.
He was the son of David Holmes and his first wife, Sallie
Hare Holmes. He attended the local schools before he
entered Vanderbilt Medical School, where he received his
M.D. Degree with honors in 1900.
13
He was presented a pair of saddlebags as an award for
scholastic achievement. He came home to Readyville to
practice medicine. He married Miss Elizabeth Vaughan of
Shelbyville in 1905, and they built a pretty little white
cottage on the north side of the village. They had two
children, Sarah and Ernest, Jr.
Dr. Holmes was a member of the New Hope Church of
Christ. He was a participant in all civic affairs of the
community. He was a Mason and an Odd Fellow. At one time
he was President of the Middle Tennessee Medical Association,
and Vice-president of the state organization.
He gave up his country practice and moved to Murfrees-boro
in 191^+, and went into the office with Dr. W. C. Bilbro,
Sr. Dr. Holmes soon developed leukemia and died in a Nash-ville
hospital January 19, 1918. He is buried in the Ever-green
Cemetery in Murfreesboro.
Dr. J. M. Shipp
Dr. James M. Shipp was born and reared in Yazoo City,
Mississippi. He graduated from Vanderbilt University and
came to Readyville to practice medicine after Dr. Holmes
left in 191U. He bought Dr. Holmes' house and lived there
until he moved to Smyrna in 1920. He stayed there until
19 50 and then moved to Florida. He later returned to Yazoo
City, Mississippi. No further information is available.
Dr. J. D. Hall
Dr. Joseph David Hall practiced medicine in the Ready-ville
and Kittrell communities from the time he graduated
14
from Vanderbilt University in 1883, until he died in
1938.
He married Miss Ella Lowe, daughter of Captain William
S. Lowe, in December after he graduated from Vanderbilt in
June of 18 83. Dr. and Mrs. Hall were the parents of four
children, Frank, who died in 1888, when he was three years
old, Elizabeth (Mrs. J. Lawrence Barker), Martha Lowe
(Mrs. J. Dexter McFarlin) , and Mary.
He was a friend of and worked with all six of the
other doctors who had practiced medicine there. As a young
doctor in 188 3 he appreciated the help and advice given him
by the older doctors, Dr. Dickens and Dr. Bridges. He felt
Dr. Speer and Dr. Youree to be his friends and contemporaries
He looked upon Dr. Holmes and Dr. Shipp as young doctors
whom he should help.
When Dr. Youree died in 1925, Dr. Hall was the only
doctor left in the eastern part of Rutherford County, the
only one between Murfreesboro and Woodbury. He served the
people of the entire area until he died in 19 38. The
"country doctor" was then a thing of the past. There are
no more in Rutherford County.
SOURCES:
Interview with Mrs. S. F. Houston
Mrs. Ruth Wood
Letter from Mrs. J. W. Brown
15
GENERAL STORES
For many years there were two stores in Readyville.
Mr. W. F. Holmes, whom everybody called "Mr. Bill" was
wounded in the battle of Chickamauga , and his left leg was
amputated above the knee at a field hospital near Dalton,
Georgia. From that time he walked with a crutch.
A few years after the was was over he moved to Ready-ville
and opened a store in the middle of the village, on
the west side of the road.
A Post Office was established at Readyville in 1811.
In 1876 Mr. Bill was appointed Post Master and the Post
Office was put in the front of his store.
In 1886 Mr. Lewis Jetton build a store across the
road to the east. Both were the typical country general
stores, with pot-bellied stoves around which men sat,
chewed tobacco and told yarns. For many years, rain or
shine, cold or hot, Mr. Doss Carter, Mr. Albert Dunn and
Mr. Flint Speer never missed a day going to the store.
When the "hack," which brought the mail from Murfrees-boro,
came in one of those men was always there to get a
newspaper. They kept up with the news of the world and
carried on hot political debates. Playing checkers on top
of a nail keg was one of their chief entertainments in
winter, and pitching horseshoes in the shade behind the
store afforded summer amusement.
Both stores kept the common stock of goods to meet
country peoples needs, such as salt, sugar, and soda.
16
Maxwell House coffee for the affluent and Arbuckles for
the poorer ones.
They had wide, strong counters to measure domestic
and calico and upon which men sat on rainy afternoons when
the chairs and nail kegs were all taken.
Children loved to go to Mr. Jetton's store for Clark,
his son, always gave them chewing gum and peppermint stick
candy, which he kept in large glass jars. They also kept
quite a stock of medicine for home remedies, such as sulphur,
salts, castor oil, quinine, turpentine, Sloan's linament,
Dean's pills, and Black Draught.
Mr. Holmes died in 1919 after having been merchant
and Postmaster for forty-three years. Mr. Charlie Dickens
ran the store until it burned a few years later.
Mr. Jetton moved to Murfreesboro in 1928, and Mr. Will
Jetton and Mr. Charlie Melton had charge of his store.
After a few years they sold it to Irvin Stroop. He died
in 19 35, and his wife "Miss Fannie Bell" continued to
run the store for some time.
When the state built Highway 70 it missed what had
been the main part of Readyville. Traffic and business began
going to a new store across the river, and before long Mrs.
Stroop closed the store, and the building was torn down.
BLACKSMITH SHOP
Readyville had a large blacksmith shop across the
road from Mr. Holmes 'store and Post Office.
17
A lucrative business met the community needs from the
early days until trucks and tractors took the place of
horses, mules, and wagons, and buggies were supplanted by
automobiles. Mr. Hunt Bailey is remembered as being one
of the early blacksmiths. He worked there for many years.
Others who followed him were: Mr. Bud Cox, Mr. Will Sain,
and Mr. Jesse Mullins.
BANK OF READYVILLE
Soon after the turn of the century it became popular
to establish banks in small communities all over Tennessee.
In 1912 Harry Carter came from Auburntown and organized a
bank in Readyville. A nice brick building was put up between
the blacksmith shop and Mr. Jetton's store. Stock was sold
readily and the bank opened with a safe foundation.
Mr. Doss Carter was elected President and Harry Carter
was cashier. Among the directors were: J. L. Barker,
A. L. Carnahan, Fletcher Craig, Dr. J. D. Hall, Lewis Jetton,
Will Jetton, Dr. W. E. Youree
.
The bank prospered greatly for several years and soon
Mr. Carter needed help. Rebecca Craig, Mamie Ready, and
Burton Carnahan worked there at different times. In 1919
Harry Carter and Fletcher Craig started a cedar mill which
soon took so much of Mr. Carter's time that he resigned
from the bank, and Doran Williams took his place.
In 1921 the entire community was alarmed for some
time. Bank robberies were rare in those days. One morning
when Mr. Williams went into the bank, he saw that someone
had broken in the front door. Several people had put papers
in the vault for safe keeping. The robbers had blown the
vault open, but did not get the safe open. They had done
a great deal of damage and had taken some notes and private
papers, but as they failed to blow the safe open, no money
was taken.
Officers and bank inspectors came immediately, did
fingerprinting and started a search. F.B.I, men stayed in
the community making investigations several days, but no
trace of the robbers was ever found. The boxes and papers
were found some months later in a woods near Nashville
close to Antioch. Insurance covered the damage. About a
year later another robbery was attempted, but they did not
get into the vault this time, and no damage was done.
Mr. Williams moved to Woodbury in 19 2 3 and Mr. Carter
came back to the bank. In the late 20 's the economy all
over the United States began to slow down, and it effected
the small banks. At the same time large banks began taking
over small ones to keep them from failing in the depression
which the economists saw approaching.
In 19 2 8 the Commerce Union Bank offered to buy the
Bank of Readyville. It was sold and none of the stockholders
or depositors lost any money. Mr. Carter moved to Murfrees-boro
and took a position with the Commerce Union Bank. The
little brick building was sold for a house .
19
SOURCES:
Interviews with:
Mrs . Harry Carter
Mr. Doran Williams
HOME TELEPHONE EXCHANGE
Alexander Graham Bell received his patent for the
telephone iii 1875. The first telephone came to Murfreesboro
in 1883. People did not take to this new means of communi-cation
very rapidly, but after a few years there were twenty-six
subscribers in Murfreesboro.
Mrs. Lady McKnight and Dr. J. D. Hall were the first
ones out of Murfreesboro to have a telephone. For several
years people came for miles in the country to use these
telephones
.
The company began to extend the lines and by 19 00 they
had three thousand subscribers. Around 1912 a move was
started to organize local telephone companies all over the
country.
The Readyville Home Telephone company was one of the
first in Rutherford County. Stocks were sold, and a house
was built for the exchange where Mr. Holmes' store had been.
People donated poles and gave their services to help
build lines. Soon nearly every home in the community for
miles around had a telephone. The lines extended out every
country road, and across fields and woodlands.
20
It was well organized with officers and a Board of
Directors. Mr. Sidney Drennan was the first President.
Mr. Will Shelton succeeded him. Mr. J. VJ . Brevard and
Mr. Sam Wharton were the Secretary-Treasurers.
Ethel Hammond was the first operator. She was soon
succeeded by Mrs. Jennie Mae McBroom. Her husband had died
recently, and she and her children were moved into the
telephone house, where they lived for many years. Mrs.
McBroom rendered a wonderful service to the community.
She was able to keep up with everything and everybody.
If someone called for a doctor she might say, "He has
gone to see Mr. Jim Smith. I'll ring over there and catch
him for you." Mrs. Claude McBroom did a lot of pinch-hitting
at the switchboard during those years.
Mr. Bricey Richardson was the manager and lineman for
a long time. He was succeeded by Mr. Jess Cawthon . His
family lived in the Exchange house. Mrs. Cawthon and the
children took care of the switchboard and Mr. Cawthon "rode"
the lines and mended the telephones. The lines needed to
be rebuilt and more people were asking for telephones.
Expansion was going to be expensive.
The Dekalb Telephone Company bought the Woodbury
Exchange. They wanted to come all the way to Readyville.
Southern Bell also wanted to extend its lines to Readyville.
Finally in 1959 a compromise was worked out, and the
Readyville Home Telephone Company was sold.
21
Peake's Hill was used as the dividing line. Telephones
east of the hill were put on the Woodbury Exchange, and
those to the west of the hill on Murfreesboro . There were
more than three hundred subscribers on the Readyville
Exchange and it had served the community well for nearly
fifty years.
SOURCES:
Mr. W. H. King
Mrs. Claude McBroom
Miss Margaret Brevard
Mr. Jess Cawthon
OUTSTANDING EVENTS
Perhaps the most outstanding event that was ever
experienced by the people in the Readyville Community was
the flood of March 1902.
In the days of early exploration and settlement,
perhaps about 1776, Uriah Stone and a party of hunters came
to this area and found a large river. They named it "Stone's
River," in honor of Uriah Stone. It was thought that Mr.
Stone explored it from the mouth where it ran into the Cumber-land
near Donelson, to its source, which was a large spring
at the foot of Short Mountain. He came back later and built
his cabin near the spring.
The stream which flows from this spring is fed by all
the other springs, branches, and creeks which flow westward
22
from the eastern part of Cannon County. It has become a
large river by the time it reaches Readyville
.
It was a mild spring of March, 1902, and farmers
were plowing their fields, getting ready for planting their
crops. A rainy spell set in toward the last of the month.
It rained constantly for about a week. All the streams
poured their waters into Stones River.
By the middle of the week it was getting out of banks.
By the end of the week. Stones River was at flood stage and
was really on a rampage. People began moving stock to higher
ground, and some left their homes, but for many it was too
late.
By the time it reached Readyville, the river whose
channel was usually about thirty feet had become a roaring
current more than a mile wide. By Saturday afternoon the
rain had stopped, and for miles along the waters edge people
stood and watched their houses, barns, cattle, sheep, hogs,
logs, fences, trees and newly plowed soil go down the roar-ing
river. Every bridge was washed away from Short Mountain
to Donelson, where Stones River empties into the Cumberland.
Some people were caught across the river from their homes.
They hurriedly made rafts and canoes, and for several days
Stones River became a navigable stream. No one could ever
estimate the damage that had been done.
23
LANDMARKS
The Comers
Perhaps the outstanding landmarks in the Readyville
Community are the mill and two houses. Charles Ready
settled here in 1802. No doubt he built a log cabin at that
time. One record says that he built another house in 1804,
but a letter written in 1829 by his son-in-law, James Holmes,
who married Mary Ready, states that, "Mr. Ready plans to
build an elegant house, the bricks for which are now ready."
The latter date seems more likely to be true. The remains
of the kiln where the slaves fired the brick were found in
the corner of a field across the road from the house a few
years ago.
Goodspeeds' History of Tennessee says it was one of the
first brick houses in the county. It was a large three
story Colonial type red brick house, with walls eighteen
inches thick. It had a portico with white columns in front.
Colonel Ready named it "The Corners," as it was located
in the corner where two roads crossed. The wide wainscoated
hall, with a winding stairway, separated the tall-ceilinged
parlours from the dining room and family room.
In 18 3 6 when Cannon County was formed, the line
separating Rutherford and Cannon counties was drawn down the
center of this hall, making part of the house to be in
Rutherford County and part in Cannon County. The bedrooms
24
on the second floor were for the boys and girls. A stair-way
in the dining room led to the boys room.
The third story was one large room, and served different
purposes. Very likely it was used as an over-flow bedroom,
when such guests as President Andrew Jackson were there.
The house was used as an Inn for stage coach travelers.
Andrew Jackson frequently stayed there on his way to and
from Washington before and after he became President.
The attic was used to cultivate silk-worms. The large
third story room might have been where the weaving was done.
Mr. Ready had a dream of developing the silk industry here.
He secured a quantity of silk worms, and planted mulberry
trees all around his garden and orchard. Some of the trees
are there today. The silk worms did not thrive in this
climate, and after some years the project was abandoned.
The third story was taken off when the children grew up
and married, and a new roof was needed.
A brick walkway, or dog-run, led from the east door
of the dining room to a large kitchen, where food was pre-pared
in great quantities for the family and slaves.
Quarters for the slaves were cabins at the back of the house.
As Colonel Ready was considered one of the wealthiest
men in the county, the furnishings were the best of the
times. Wall scones held lighted candles, iron-stone china
and silver filled cupboards. Love-seats and rocking chairs
were in the parlour. Four-poster and trundle beds, chests
of drawers and large wardrobes were in every bedroom. The
25
only closets in the house were under the stairways. The
deep recessed windows in the parlour and dining room had
lace curtains and a Brussels carpet was on the parlour
floor.
When Colonel Ready died in 1859, his daughter, Jane,
Mrs. Peter Talley, and her husband bought the house. The
house played a part in the Civil War. Mrs. Talley served
dinner to Nathan Bedford Forrest and his Raiders on July 13,
1862, as they were on their way from McMinnville to deliver
Murfreesboro from the "Yankees."
After the Battle of Stones River, Colonel Hazen's
Brigade retreated to Readyville. He took this house to be
his headquarters as long as they were in this area.
Mrs. John Macon bought the farm from the Talleys in
1886. It had been in the Ready family for eighty four years.
During the next twenty four years the house changed owners
four times, and came to be in great need of repair.
The Lawrence Barker family have owned the place for
over sixty years, and have restored the house to its original
elegance and beauty. The original tallow candles have been
replaced by electric, crystal chandeliers in the parlour,
hall, and dining room. Heat from the log fireplace is
supplemented by electric heaters throughout the house.
A new kitchen now joined to the house is electrically
equipped, and is supplied by water from a city pipe line
instead of buckets from the spring and well, as is also the
tiled bathroom.
The parlour, bedrooms, and a den which has taken the
place of the dog-run to the original kitchen, are furnished
today with beautiful antique furniture, typical of the period
when the house was built.
Mr. John Lawrence Barker bought the house in 1909.
He married Elizabeth Hall in 1911, and lived there until he
died in 1957. His daughter and son-in-law, Mr. and Mrs.
Jack Oliver, are the present owners of "The Corners."
SOURCES:
Goodspeeds History of Tennessee
Census Reports 1810-1850
Rutherford County Deed Book Vol. 1
Sims: History of Rutherford County
Brown : History of Woodbury and Cannon County
HILL CREST
Major John Howard Wood was born in Iredall County,
North Carolina, March 16, 180 3. His father, John Wood, came
to Tennessee about 1808, and settled in the valley below
Woodbury. One record shows that he owned 5,000 acres of land.
He had eight children, and gave each one of them a farm when
they married.
John Howard married Roxanna Sutton in 1827, and received
his land near Readyville where he built a log cabin near a
spring. Their oldest child was born at Readyville in 1828.
In 1845 Major John H. Wood built a typical Southern
mansion on top of a hill, one mile south of Readyville.
1
1
Major Wood had come to own hundreds of acres of land and
many slaves. He had much work for them to do.
Along the road going up the hill to the house he had
a double rock fence built. Soil was filled in between the
two rows of rock, and flowers were planted on top, which
made a beautiful and spectacular sight on the approach to
the house.
The house was placed on the crest of the hill, with
a view for miles into the valley below. It was a tall,
white weather-boarded two-story house, with an upper and
lower portico extending across the front supported by six
white columns.
On approaching the house one is struck with the
beauty of two tall chimneys, made of dressed limestone rock,
at the east and west ends of the house. There is similar
beauty in the stone of the large fireplaces inside the
front rooms. The entrance hall with a winding stairway,
had a 20 X 20 high ceilinged room on each side. There were
two doors at the back of the hall, one opened onto a long,
wide porch on the east side.
At the right of the hall was the parlour, with large-paned,
glass windows in front. On the left was the family
room, which had, in addition to the large front windows,
smaller windows on each side of the large fireplace.
Behind this room was the dining room.
The bedrooms were on each side of the hall upstairs,
and a front door led onto the top portico. The left side
28
door at the back of the hall opened on a stairway which led
down to a full-sized basement, where the kitchen was located.
The hills in the area provided an abundance of limestone
rock for building. Some of the slaves must have been expert
craftsmen, for the stones in the chimneys, fireplaces and
basement show signs of rare skill in masonry and unusual
beauty. The walls of the basement, which made the founda-tion
of the house, were made of dressed rock twelve inches
thick. Six oak sills above were hand-hewn with an axe, out
of logs fifty feet and ten inches long, and twelve inches
wide. The floor was covered with dressed stone slabs three
by six feet.
Part of this basement, called "a cellar" in those days,
was used for storage. There were shelves no doubt, filled
with jams, jellies, pickles and jars of canned fruit; bins
of potatoes, apples, and pumpkins.
The most interesting room in the house was the kitchen,
which was on the east side of the basement, with a door
opening out into the yard. The large stone fireplace,
where the cooking was done was indeed a work of art. The
cranes, hooks, copper kettles and candle molds gave evidence
that this was the most important room in the house, for to
provide food for the family and slaves, this fireplace was
kept in constant use, and the fire never went out.
There is no wonder that it took four years to complete
tlie house, and it was considered one of the finest m the
29
Readyville area. Major Wood was one of the most influential
citizens of Rutherford County and especially in the Ready-ville
Community.
Major and Mrs. Wood had ten children. One sad experience
which they had was in losing three of them in one year. It
is thought that perhaps two were killed in the Civil War.
They were buried in the family graveyard near the house -
Benjamin born in 1832, died in November 1862; James born in
1848, died in July 1863; Mary born in 1850, died in August 1863.
Major Wood died at "Hill Crest" November 3, 1879 and is
buried in the family graveyard. His son, John Sutton Wood,
inherited this home.
In 1892 Dr. J. H. Dickens bought the place for his
nephews. Mr. Forest Dickens and his family lived there until
191U when Mr. and Mrs. Oscar Barker bought it. The house
remained as it was originally built in the 1840 's until 1969.
Mr. and Mrs. Ray Barker, the present owners, renovated the
entire house.
The white weatherboarding was taken off and replaced
with white brick. The upper portico was removed. The
chimneys showed damage by time and weather. The stones were
cleaned and repointed.
A dining room was added behind the parlour where the
east porch had been. The hall and front rooms were re-decorated,
and a tiled bathroom was put under the stairway.
Behind these was built an electrically equipped kitchen
and breakfast room, with windows across the north side
30
looking out on the fields and pastures below. To the west
has been added a large pantry, utility room and serving
room.
The dining room which was behind the family room on
the west side, has been turned into a den with a bath, and
one wall covered with shelves for books and trophies.
Cabinets and closets fill every possible space.
A bathroom has been added upstairs, and the bedrooms
redecorated for three husky boys.
The fireplaces can still be used, but the house is now
heated, lighted and fully equipped with electricity. The
basement has been extended under the new rooms, with another
stairway and bath, and space for a recreation room. The
only room that is not changed is the old kitchen in the base-ment,
with its large fireplace, stone walls and floor. It
maintains the atmosphere of a period that is gone forever -
more than a hundred years ago.
THE OLD MILL
Of necessity, the early settlers built their log cabins
near a spring. The second need was bread. When Charles
Ready came here in 1802 the closest mill seems to have been
in Sumner County, which was many miles away. No doubt Mrs.
Ready and the slaves ground their meal by hand in a pestle
most of the time.
In 1812 Charles Ready built a grist mill on the river,
near his home. It met a great need for the entire area.
31
People came for miles with their "turns" of corn, and the
mill soon became a very profitable business.
It is today, 1974, the only fulltime water-powered
mill in operation in Middle Tennessee, and is famous for
the high quality of meal and flour it produces.
Peter Talley, Charles Ready's son-in-law, became the
miller and after Mr. Ready's death in 1859, his son Francis
Talley helped his father with the mill. He conceived the
idea of building a dam, which would feed a mill-race for a
sawmill as well as for the grist mill. Sometime near the
Civil War the mill burned.
Robert Carter bought the site and re-built the mill,
and added a wheat mill to grind flour. In 1889 he sold the
mill to Mr. W. B. Hayes. Due to the destruction of houses
and barns during the Civil War, there was a great need for
the sawmill. People brought their logs for many miles to the
Readyville mill. A great tragedy occurred there in 1894.
Mr. Bill Bradley was a "Yankee Soldier" who came back
here to live after the Civil War. He was a skilled sawyer
and had worked at the mill for years. He was expert in
turning off lumber as the logs were rolled onto the carriage.
One day in 1894 a big log was rolling up to the saw.
As Mr. Bradley leaned over to adjust the belt his foot
slipped. He fell on the saw and it cut his body in half.
The men standing by were struck dumb with horror and
finally someone thought to stop the saw. A man jumped on a
horse and ran after Dr. Hall. Mr. Bradley was one of his
32
nearest neighbors. When he got there nothing could be done
except to take the body home. Dr. Hall rode ahead to tell
Mrs. Bradley, and Mr. Bud Cox drove a spring wagon with the
body to his home. The effect of the tragedy hovered over
the mill for a long time.
Mr. W. B. Hayes died and his son, Sam, took over the
mill in 1894. His brother-in-law, Arthur McFerrin, everybody
called him "Rat," soon joined him. They began to make
improvements and the mill took a new life. They started
advertising "King of Patents," flour, whole wheat flour and
water ground meal. The mill did a thriving business.
During the warm summer months people drove to Murfrees-boro
for ice. Sometimes it was half melted when they got
home. Ice cream surely was a luxury in those days. "Mr.
Rat" was a natural-born mechanic. He conceived the idea of
developing an ice plant at the mill. His mechanical talent
went to work, and in a short time Readyville had a plant
which supplied ice to people for many miles in all directions,
After a few years Carl and Fred Adams got a truck and
delivered ice to homes all over the surrounding area. Their
father. Dr. Adams, later bought the plant and moved it to
Woodbury.
"Mr. Rat" developed a small electric plant to make
the ice. He soon saw the possibility of enlarging the dynamo
and developing an electric light plant at the mill. Soon
all the houses in Readyville had electric lights, the first
rural village known to have electricity.
33
Senator George Norris was a man of vision and a "dreamer
of dreams." He saw the possibility of harnessing the power
that was going to waste in our waterways and turning it
into electrical power for the benefit of mankind.
He presented a bill to Congress, and finally after
years and months of Congressional debating and political
bickering, a bill was passed in 1932 creating the Tennessee
Valley Authority. The Middle Tennessee Electric Membership
Corporation was chartered in 19 37. "Following World War II
a major expansion program was undertaken to try to provide
service to all who asked for it," so TVA bought the rights
and the little electric plant at the Readybille mill became
a part of the giant power system of TVA.
In 19 35 Mr. Leslie Justice bought the mill. He did some
remodeling and put in new bins for flour and meal. His son,
Ray, helped run the mill for several years.
The mill has capacity to turn out 6,000 pounds of plain
or self-rising flour a day, and 4,000 pounds of meal. But
it seldom operates at full capacity. Mr. Justice says that
this is perhaps the only mill in Tennessee that still caters
to the "deposit system," that has been a practice for a
hundred years.
At threshing time the farmers in the community sell
part of their wheat, but bring enough to supply their bread
during the year, and deposit it on the top floor of the mill.
It is ground as they need it. Trucks deliver the mill
products to stores over a twenty mile radius. Most of the
34
business comes from Woodbury, Murfreesboro, McMinnville
and Manchester. Tourists frequently stop and buy.
Mr. Justice decided to retire in 1971 and sold the mill
to Mr. Joe Flipsey, a Vietnam veteran, who was interested
in getting the mill into the program for the Preservation
of Antiquities
.
Just across the bridge over Stones River a sign has
stood for many years beside Highway 70S, with an arrow point-ing
to the left which says:
Readyville Mills
Manufactors of King of Patents flour&#8212;Whole
Wheat Flour--Water Ground Meal and Pountry
Feed.
In 1973 Mr. Bill Carigman bought the mill and specializes
in grinding whole wheat flour and the mill that started
grinding in 1812 is grinding still "down by the old mill
stream.
"
SOURCES:
Goodspeeds History of Tennessee
Rober Kollar, Tennessean Magazine
Leslie Justice
Joe Flipsey
The Story of TVA
</dc:description>
<dc:description>A history of the Readyville community, named for Colonel Charles Ready</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Ready, Charles, 1802-1878; Rutherford County (Tenn.) -- History</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Readyville</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>67 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-15</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication04ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/73</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>