<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Sojourn in Murfreesboro</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Wray, Henry</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 1</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1973</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>19th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>SOJOURN IN MURFREESBORO
By Henry Wray, Rutherford County Archivist
Samuel Hervey McLaughlin came to Murfreeaboro in 1815 and
began the practice of law. The Biographical Directory
(1796-1969), Warren County, highlighting members of tne
General Assembly, recorded these terse facts about
McLaughlin
:
"Senate, 23rd, 24-th and 25th General Assemblies,
1839-45 representing Warren and Franklin Counties
in 23rd and 24th; Warren, Gannon, Coffee, and
DeKalb in 25th. Born in Virginia and at 3 years
of age to Knox County, Ky. Family back to Virginia
in 1810. Clerked in store in McMinnville, 1811-15,
reading law meantime. Began practice in Murfreesboro
in 1815. Married Mary Clarke Bass. Resided on
east fork of Stones River below the mouth of
Bradley's Creek. Removed to Nashville in 1832.
Appointed Recorder, General Land Office in
Washington by President James K. Polk on March 4,
1845. Died in Vfeshington."
The Directory further states that McLaughlin was bom on
May 1, 1796 and died May 5, 1850.
Events associated with his several years in Murfreesboro
were abstracted verbatim from a diary in a private collection
and titled: "A Diary of Public Events and a Sketch of My
Life." The diary was written in 1845. Henry Wray's abstract
follows.
"After reading Law with Maj. McCampbell, hard and
diligently, I obtained a license, and in September or October,
1815 removed to and settled in Murfreesboro on advice of
Col. Mitchell and other friends.
When I went to reside in Murfreesboro, I found a very
different condition in the state of society from which
exists there at present. Gen. Robert Purdy, who after
being disbanded in the reduction of the army to a peace time
establishment, came and settled in the neighborhood on a
16
farm inherited by hi 3 wife, who waa a Miss Philips, a sister
of the present Judge Joseph Philips. He was a man of moat
liberal hospitality. His wife waa an excellent woman--
a perfect lady--fond of gaiety, fashion and company.
The late Mrs. Nancy Lytle, wife of the late Capt. Vfa.
Lytle, an old Revolutionary Officer, was and always had been
the leader of fashion and patron of all Balls and Parties
at Murfreesborough, as she had once been at Nashville in
her younger days. She lived in sight of the tovm where her
son 'I'fa. Lytle now lives.
The late Joel Dyer, the old gambler, famous in the old
traditions of East Tennessee and Nashville--also rich and
whose handsome daughters had married respectably, and
afterwards also married respectably, lived in town, having
removed there from his farm where John Mclver now lives,
about the time I went there to live, kept a tavern in town,
where Col. Vfe. F. Lytle now keeps a tavern. Col. Vto.
Mitchell also lived in town and kept a tavern in the old
Jetton House, on the East side of the public square, where
Col. Robert Smith afterwarda lived for many years.
Mr. Joel Childress, a merchant, owned and lived in the
framed portion of the tavern house, on the west side of
the square, now owned and kept by Capt. Geo. Allen Sublett.
Mr. Childress waa a highly respectable man and was the
father of Mrs. Sarah Polk, the lady of James K. Polk, now
President of the United States.
John M. Tilford, now of Warren Co., Hiclcory Creek, was
a prosperous merchant in Murfreesboro when I went there
to live. He waa the 3on-in-law of Gapt. W. and Mrs. Lytle.
Nicholas Tilford and Jame a M. Tilford, now both dead, were
merchants there at the aame time. William Barf ie Id, James
D. Garuthers and Joseph D. Staith were also merchants, as
was one Jonathan Estill, now all dead. In 1816 and 1817,
the late Jonathan Gurrin and the late David V/endel, came
there as merchants. Gurrin from Franklin in Williamson
County and Vfendel from East Tennessee. Old Alexander
Carmichael and James D. Rawlings, both deceased, were
tavern keepers.
Dr. W. B. Butler, Dr. W. T. Henderson, Dr. Elisha B.
Clarke and Dr. Henry Homes were all practicing physicians.
Jiaj. Bennett anith, a remarkable man, still living, had
removed to town to enjoy his fortune, about the time I went
to the place to live. He pretended, however, now and then,
especially when drunk, to engage in the practice of Law.
The late Gen. Blackman Coleman lived in town and was Glerk
of the County Court. My brother, John R. Laughlin,
succeeded him in this office.
I cannot enumerate all those who then lived in
Murf reesboro, but of those who were then business men there,
scarcely any remain, and most of them are dead. Gaming
was then a most prevailing and fashionable vice and was
carried on almost openly. Cards were played for money by
almost everybody and billiard tables were a common resort.
About December, 1815, was the first time I ever saw
President Polk. He was then a very young man, a little
older than myself, and was a student at the Bradley Academy,
an institution which had been removed from near Col. Rucker'
a
to Murfreesborough. The old Academy House was a spacious
log building and stood near where the brick Presbyterian
Church now stands. The same Academy House was used on
Sabbath days as a place of public worship, until it was
afterwards set on fire by a deranged man from Kentucky named
Forsyth. The Rev. Jessee Alexander, still a preacher, and
other Presbyterian clergymen preached and held sacramental
meetings in the House.
At this House, about 25th December 1815, an event
happened to me which I sliall never forget. Having heard
that a Miss Bass, I had not heard her Christian Name, and
several other young ladies, were staying at Maj. Bennett
anith's, with his daughter Margaret (afterwards married to
Uriah Cummin, and since dead) were attending a sacramental
meeting at the place mentioned. I had heard her mentioned
by Dr. Clarke, then a physician in Murfreesboro (a Virginian
and Cousin of her father), and having heard Daniel Barnes,
then a clerk in Estill's store, and \*i. M. Smith, now
General Smith speak of her, I had gone to the meeting, not
being well at the time, more with a desire to see her than
any other person and more from that desire than to hear
preaching. During the concluding prayer, Miss Bass was
pointed out to me. I was greatly struck by her appearance.
Although I had not seen her move, except to turn around and
take her seat at the conclusion of the prayer, and had never
heard her apeak, and although I withdrew and went home to
Mitchell's Tavern without seeing any more of her, I had
from that hour a presentiment that she was at sometime to
become my wife. From the moment I saw her, I determined to
ace her again. I knew Dr. aarke visited at her father's
six miles west of Murfreeaboro, where he lived on a large
fara on the old road from Nashville to Shelbyville.
Three or four days, I think, after the foregoing inci-dent.
Dr. Clarke got into one of his occasional fits or
sprees of drinking. He was an old bachelor, of great skill
in his profession, and was universally esteemed. He had
become very friendly to me. His friends on this occasion
persuaded him to take a ride into the country for exercise
and ride back and he would be over his frollic. He said he
would do so if I would go with him. I told him, at once,
I would. 1 never thought, nor did he, of the place we would
go to, or how far. We ordered our horses, and Col. Mitchell
gave the Doctor, at his earnest entreaty, a glass of toddy
to start on. Wfe mounted our horses, the Doctor taking the
lead, when we started out of town, down the old Nashville
road by Wilson Shoals, which led down on the North and
Northwest of Squire David Dickenson's plantation. While
riding, he spoke of a friend of his, Mr. Ambrose House,
who had lately removed from Virginia to Rutherford County
and near hi a kinsman, Capt. James Bass, and said we would
turn back and come home by the house of friend Ambrose after
we got as far down the Nashville road as he wished to go.
Vfe dashed on until we got to old Mr. Hartwell Marable'a,
another Virginia friend of his. Vfe stopped and went into
the house, he introducing me to the old people. He had
gotten nearly sober. He did not ask for anything to drink,
but went out and up the road where we had passed a black-smith
shop, where he got some whiskey, and presently he was
so much intoxicated again, as to set his tongue to running.
He refused when he went back to the house to stay for dinner,
pretending he was in a hurry to get home and had to go by
Mr. Houses and Gapt. Basses. Vfe set off and took the
Shelbyville road which turned off at the corner of Mr.
Marable's fence to the south, and crossed Stewarts Creek
through what was Searcy's, now White's mill dam. Vfe rode
on to Mr. House's where I hoped he would stop, as I did not
wish to go to Capt. Bass' with him when he was drinking.
Vfe found Mr, House and his negroes out clearing new ground.
He invited us to stop at his house and stay till next
morning. The Doctor refused, saying he must go home and
call at Capt. Basses on the way. So off we went again, he
still showing the effects of his drink and soon got to
Capt. Basses, it being only about a mile.
Here we got down and went in. Capt. Bass was not at
home. The Doctor introduced me to Mrs. Bass, to her daughter
Itemperance anith,then the wife of Thomas B. Smith, son of
Bennett anith, and to Mary Clarke Bass, her sister, who
afterwards in less than a year became my wife.
The Doctor and myself went home that evening, after he
22
got a glaaa of toddy from Mrs. Basa. and in a few days he
got sober.
In 1829 I moved my parents to Rutherford County. 1 was
living on the East fork of Stones River on an excellent
tract of land below the mouth of Bradley's creek, opposite
John L. Jettons, bought of James Gordon. In March 1832, I
moved to Nashville leaving my parents and my brother Sidney
with some negroes on my farm.
My brother, John Randolph, wrote in the Clerk's office
in Murfreesborough under Gen. Blackman Coleman, until he
resigned the office in 1821 or 1822, when my brother was
elected to his place as County Court Clerk, and he held the
office until the change of the Constitution in 183U-5 when
he went out of office and was not a candidate for re-election
In 1837 my brother John R. being a candidate for the legis-lature
in which he was defeated by the falsehoods and
slanders of one Beverley Randolph and Alexander Blair. My
brother just before the election, at a public meeting at
Pace's, in July (The election was in August) took occasion
to cane Blair in company. Just after the election, at a
public collection of people at Maj. John Bradley's at the
fall races, Blair took an opportunity, having been furnished
a knife by one Henderson, his kinsman, insulted my brother
so grossly, that he again raised his cane, when Blair ran in
under, no one at the moment thinking of a knife, except
those that knew his talent, and stabbed my brother in the
groin or pelvis, and in other places before he could be
prevented. Of the firat mentioned wound, he died in seven
or eight days from mortification. I was then at my place
called Runnemede in Gannon County. My brother was buried
at the old Ledbetter place, two and a half miles southwest
of Murfreesborough.
My Dear Wife Mary Clarke Laughlin, died at our residence
at Hickory Hill in !-ferren County, Nov. 11, 18U0 and is
buried at Liberty Meeting House near McMinnville.
I'm writing these biographical notes in my office in
Washington City, and it is now August U, 1845.
</dc:description>
<dc:description>Abstract of a diary written by Samuel Hervey McLaughlin, resident of Murfreesboro, in 1845, with an introduction by Rutherford County archivist Henry Wray</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Diaries; Murfreesboro (Tenn.); Murfreesboro (Tenn.) -- History; </dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-16; mt2011-09-06</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication01ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/116</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>