<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>The Rutherford Rifles</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Pittard, Mabel</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 31</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1988</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869;</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>1840 Rutherford County Census with Index
$5.00 + $1.25 postage
Deed Abstracts of Rutherford Count
Griffith:Illustrated Bi-Centennial publication.
$2.00 + $1.25 postage
Cemetery Records of Rutherford County:
Vol.I(Northwestern third of County and part of Wilson
and Davidson Counties, 256 cemeteries with index and
maps. $lo.bo + $1.25 postage.
Vol. 11.( out of print)
Vol. III (Southwestern third of Rutherford County and
the western part of Cannon County~ 241 cemeteries with
index and maps. $ 10.00 + $1.25 postage
Available From: William W. ~alkup, 202 Ridley St. Smyrna,Tenn.
37167 Map of 1878 Rutherford County (shows land owners)
$ 3.50 + $1.00 postage
Available From: Mrs. R.A.Ragland,P.O. Box 544,Murfreesboro,Tn.
37130 Marriage Records of Rutherford .County 1851-1872.
$10.00 + $1.00 postage
The Rutherford Rifles
by
Mabel Pittard
Rutherford County Historical Society
1988
William Ledbetter, Captain of the Rutherford Rifles
1
Mary Catherine Lytle Ledbetter (Miss Kit) wife of
Captain William Ledbetter
2
The Salem Pike Ledbetter Home
3
4 5
The Ledbetter Family
The Ledbetters came to V'r ' 'f E 1 glnla rom ngland in the early
1600's, They settled on the James River near Richmond, Virginia.
Isaac Ledbetter and his wife, Nancy King Ledbetter, moved to
Rutherford County in the early 1800's, They purchased land on the
Salem Pike from Captain William Lytle, and l't was near here on
what came to be known as Cason Lane that they bu'llt their first
The Salem Pike hOUSE had 18-inch walls of solid brick,
and the upstairs walls were held together by iron bars that
extended the full length of the building. The room3 had high
ceilings,andithe doorways:were at least 10 feet wide. All of
rooms were heated by large fireplaces that burned wood. There
were five rooms&#183; upstairs.- and ,fIve' rooms(.downstairs&#183; With I large
. hallways. It was to this home that Captain William Ledbetter
hoped to return following the surrender of the Confederacy In
home. 1865. However, this home-coming was not to be.
Their son, William, father of Captain William Ledbetter , When Capta.in Ledbetter returned home at the end of the
It was to shelter many generations of'the Ledbetter f amily--among
them was William Ledbetter Who was to become Captain of the Ruther
ford Rifles. It was here that Captain William Ledbetter, born in
18Jl, grew to manhood, and it wap- from here that he left to join
the Confederate cause.
better, Sr. was his appointment as President of the Planters Union
Bank. This bank was located on the public square at the site
formerly occupied by the Murfreesboro Bank and Trust Company.
Th~ 'Sgl~m Pike Ledbetter home was erec~ed in 1828. This~ brick
building followed the traditional four-chimney type of structure.
\
Bank had also been taken over by Union forces. His mother
home had been confiscated by the Yankees.The Planters Union
and his six brothers and sisters had been forced to find living
quarters in an unpartitioned room over the Planters Union Bank.
war, he found that his father had died and that his Salem Pike
to leave his bride to fight for the Southern cause. At a
meeting held in the Rutherford County Courthouse on April 2J,
1861, the .~men who were to become the Rutherford Rifles elected
They had hung sheets in order to provide some semblance of
privacy. Before long the Salem Pike home was sold in bank&#173;ruptcy
proceedings.
When Captain William Ledbetter volunteered for service
in the Confederate Army, he was JO years of age. In May of
1857 he had married Mary 9atherine Lytle, grand-caughter of
Captain William Lytle. Four years later on May 2~ 1861 he_was
William Ledbetter as their Captain.
esteem ~which William Led-was
born in 1800, and in 1829 he married Eliza Adaline Welborn,
William served as Murfreesboro's f'lrst recorder in 1818. In 1825
and again in 1827 he served as the mayor.of Murfreesboro. He also
served in the Tennessee State Senate. He was publisher, along with
G.A. Sublett, of the Rutherford Courl'er. Ano ther l'ndication of the
\ Murfreesboro citizens :, .held for
6
The regiment left Mu~freesboro by train on May 2, 1861
enroute for Nashville where they were to become a part of the
First Tennessee Volunteers, George Maney commanding. There
were about 150 young men in the Rifles , and at the end of the
war of those from Murfreesboro only eleven would return. rear
the end of the conflict Captain Ledbetter himself would be
,wounded and captured.
In a letter to family members Spencer~ Eakin'; General
Agent with the Nashville, Chattanooga and St. Louis Railway had
this to say of Captain William Ledbetter."He was a glorious man
in a gloriuos cause, a true soldier and an honest gentleman, a
steady comrade and friend." Captain Ledbetter said of himself
that he was the oldest captain in the First Tennessee Volunteers,
that he was the smallest in stature(being only five feet six
inches tall), that he had the largest company in the regiment,
and more men than any other company that were over six feet tall.
War records reveal that William Ledbetter, Jr. enlisted May
10, 1861 at Camp Harris and was assigned as a Captain of Company I,
1st (Fields) Regiment Tennessee Infantry, C.S.A. He was captured
near Versailles, Kentucky on December ], 1864 and escaped while
enroute from Louisville, Kentucky to Fort Delaware, Delaware in
J~nuary; 1865. He surrendered at Athens, Georgia May 4, 1865,sub&#173;scribed.
to the oath of allegiance, and was released at Nashville,
Tennessee in June 16, 1865.
7
The Rutherford Rifles
Six weeks after the 1860 election in which Abraham
Lincoln was made President of the United States, South
Carolina seceded from the Union. Florida, Georgia" Alabama,
Texas, Louisiana, and Mississippi followed. On February 4,
1861 the seceded states met in Alabama and selected Jefferson
Davis as President of the Confederacy. On April 12, 1861
Brigadier General Pierre Beauregard commanding the harbor
batteries at Charleston, South Carolina ordered the batteries
to shell Fort Sumter. The fort surrendered and the war was on.
When President Lincoln called for volunteers to put down
the rebellion, Virginia, North Carolina, and Arkansas took
steps to j01. n the Conf ederacy. Although many Tennesseans were
opposed to secession, the firing on Fort Sumter had made them
realize that their best 1. nt eres,~~s m.1ght lie. with the: SouthBrn
states,and in April of 1861 resolutions were adopted by the .Tenn&#173;essee
Legislature authorizing Governor Isham G. Harris to enter
into a military league with the Confederate States. When the
call went out in Tennessee for volunteers, 50,000 young men
at once answered the call .. Among these Tennesseans were 150
young Rutherford' Cbun~ian~who were to become knoWn as the
"Rutherford Rifles.".
A meeting was called for the Rifles to come on April 2],
1861 to the Rutherford County Courthouse at which time
they took'
steps to organize. They elected William Led_
8
better, Jr. as Captain, Hardy Murfree as 1st Lieutenant, R.F.
James as 2nd Lieutenent, C.H. King as 3rd Lieutenent, and A.
Loeb as Sergeant. At this meeting they voted to call them-selves
the "Rutherford Rifles". ., .
The Rifles spent one week in daily'drills'in and ,around
Murfreesboro, Tennessee. On May 2, 1861 they met at the ;depot
at Murfreesboro to depart for the battlefield. T.J. Wade,
one of the members of the company, in an article which appeared
in the Murfreesboro Free Press on April 23, 1880 described the
scene at the depot ~s ~hese young men were separated from their
loved ones. Wade said," Devoted sons received the parting kiss
from broken-hearted mothers; wayward boys submitted to the last
benedictions from indulgent fathers; noble brothers bid a long
farewell to tender sisters, and husbands committed their all to
God."
The company left Murfreesboro by rail and arrived in
Nashville, Tennessee at 11 a.m. They marched to the public
square to the music of "Annie Laurie". At the square the company
was dispersed to meet at the Commercial Hotel for their first
meal away from home. Arriving in Nashville at the same time
were young volunteers from Pulaski, Columbia, Franklin, and the
Rock City Batallion.
At the tap of drums the Rutherford Rifles reassembled and
marched to Sulphur Dell where they became a part of the First
Tennessee Volunteers, George Maney commanding. The company
then returned to the Davidson County Courthouse where they were
assigned quarters and where they spent their first night away
from home.
On &#183;the evening of May 3, 1861 the Rifles marched to the
Fair GroundS in Nashville, Tennessee where they pitched
their tents and built their first campfire. On May 7, 1861
the company left Nashville by rail and went to Camp Harris
on the Elk River near Allisonia in Franklin County. This
"'~~pw;s~~;~d'-ih'''h~~'~roj.'G&#183;~~-ernor Isham G': ~Harri',s-.- There'-
,the Rifles,,&#183;,join~d "by,-&lt;tbe GJarm~&#183;!~fSe~!3:,.remained at Camp,
Harris for one week, and on May 15, they left by rail and
again passing through Nashville they stopped for lunch
at the Female Academy grounds. Continuing by rail they
reached Camp Cheatham in Robertson 'County. Here they !3t~ye~
for several weeks engaging in all types of preparation for
warfare. At Camp Cheatham the Rutherford Rifles were brigaded
with the 3rd and 11th Tennessee under Gen. Robert 'Foster. 'While
at Camp Cheatham the company received its regimental flag
which was presented to them by a daughter of Ex~Governor
Campbell. Also,at Camp Cheatham Dr. Baldwin joined the compa&#173;ny
,and' was elected by the Rifles as their chaplain. T.J.
Wade in the Free Press on April 23, 1880 had this to say
of Baldwin after his election as chaplain,"Dr. Baldwin
preached a notable sermon taking his text from Hosea, the
9th chapter and 6th verse."
After many weeks at Camp Cheatham the Rifles once
again passed through Nashville by rail on their way to
9
Knoxville where they encamped at Camp Haynes, arriving there
on Sunday July 14, 1861. Here they were joined by the 14th
Tennessee under Col. Forbes, and after spending about.~e~
days at Camp Haynes, they left by rail: for Lynchburg, Vir&#173;ginia.
They rested here, and as T.J. Wade said, "They,took
in the town.". Leaving Lynchburg the same day and moving. by
rail they arrived at Charlottesville, Virginia about the 26th
of July. While in Charlottesville, some of the members of the
Rifles visited the renowned University of Virginia.
Instead of moving toward Manassas as they had expect~d,
they moved westward to Staunton, Virginia, arriving there
on Sunday July 28, 1861. Here some of the members of the
company visited the Insane Asylum.
On July, 29 the Rutherford Rifles moved.by rail to
Millboro in the Valley of Virginia. At Vall~y Mountain"Vir&#173;ginia
they,along with the 7th and 14th Tennessee Infantry,
were formed into Brigadier General Samuel R.. Anderson's
Brigade of Brigadier General William W. Loring's Division,
Army of the Northwest. By now they were no longer moving
by rail. T.J. Wade described it in this w8:y,."With knapsacks
on their backs and rifles on their shoulders they began
their march-a mode of life hitherto unknown to most of them."
Marching under the parching rays of a July sun, they
reached Warm Springs, Virginia on July 31, 1861 Where they
spent the night. It was here that the Rifles suffered their
'.
11
first casualty--the death of John D. Smith. Leaving Warm
Springs.on August 1, 1861 they halted at the Jackson River
and cast their vote for Isham G. Harris for Governor of
Tennessee and W.F. Cooper for Supreme Court Judge. Fording
the Jackson River they continued their march and on August 2
reached Huntersville (now in West Virginia near the Greenbrier
River). Here they spent a few days waiting for supplies. Then
they continued their march toward their objective-Cheat Pass.
Here they took part in the abortive Cheat Mountain Campaign
in What is now West Virginia. Although this was a minor action,
it was Robert E. Lee's first campaign of the Civil War-- a
campaign that ended ingloriously.
This march to Cheat Psss proved to be very eventful for
the Rifles. While passing through Edray, they buried a noble
pair of brothers--Brown and Battie Smith. When they reached
the foot of Valley Mountain, they camped for some time and
here another of their comrades died--Sammy Davis. On the 25th
of August they marched to the summit of Valley Mountain
Where they.pitched their tents and sent.ou~ scouts. Here,
the Rifles were detached and assigned out-post duty. After
rejoining their regiment on the 2nd of September they marched
farther north to Mingo Flat. Here, the entire regiment re&#173;mained
While preparations were completed for their march
against the e~emy at Cheat Pass.
Reaching the vicinity of the Pass on September 11, 1861,
they made camp and waited for the dawn to begin their attack.
The rain&#183; fell in torrents, and one of the Rifles, finding the
earth too damp for a bed, perched himself on a log with a
kna~sack over his head and a blanket over that,and there he
remained until morning.
Morning came and the regiment was ready for the charge.
They waited for the agreed signal--a gun firing. No signal
came.The regiment waited throughout the day, posted behind
logs and stumps, on the look-out for the enemy Which was
encamped about one hundred yards dis.tant. Only one "blue-coat"
was seen as he emerged from the bushes, rattling his canteen.
At the crack of Bill Beasley's rifle this Federal soldier was
wounded and taken prisoner. Since no signal came to attack
the enemy, no charge was made and the action was aborted.
Thus ended What the Rifles expected to be their first
encounter in warfare.
On September 16, 1861, the regiment left the vicinity
of the Pass and returned to Valley Mountain. News came of
General John Buchanan Floyd's retreat during the West Vir&#173;ginia
campaign and the. regiment was ordered to march 100
miles to Sewell Mountain to offer assistance. On this march
as reported by T.J.Wade the Rutherford Rifles "were enchanted
by the most beautiful natural scenery they had ever seen~
When they reached Sewell Mountain they found themselves con&#173;fronting
General William S. Rosecrans. The Confederates
12 13
erected breastworks and encamped behind them until early
October at Which time Rosecrans retreated. Finding the roads
unfit for travel and the weather bitterly cold, the regiment
fell back to the foot of the mountain. It was here that they
drew their first two months pay. Remaining there only a short
time they returned to Huntersville. It was now early November,
and the Rifles voted for Jefferson Davis for President. They
were divided on their votes for Congress. Some of the men voted
for Colonel Ready and others voted for Col. Gentry.
Leaving Huntersville in November, they moved to Camp Maney
Where they were ordered to build winter quarters. However, they
did not utilize these quarters since they were ordered to join
General Stonewall Jackson on the Potomac. Leaving Camp Maney
on December 11, 1861 they marched east for perhaps 200 miles
to Winchester, Virginia. Here, they were given winter clothing.
On January 1, 1862 they left Winchester marching to Romney.
During this march they experienced one of the most difficult
of their marches. The weather was extremely cold and bitter.
They remained in Romney for several weeks. It was during this
time that they lost another of their comrades-Columbus Haynes.
After General Stonewall Jackson's Potomac campaign, the
Rifles returned to Winchester Where they remaine~ until .February
of 1862 at Which time they .were-ord~red to Co~i~th, Mississippi.
From now on the Rutherford Rifles were to serve in the forces
of What later came to be known as the Army of Tennessee. Travel&#173;ing
by rail, the Rifles reached Corinth about March 15, 1862.
14 '
During the next two weeks preparations were being made
for a trial of strength between General U.S. Grant of the Union'
Army and General A.S. Johnston. On the ]rd of April 1862, the
Rutherford Rifles began their march north arriving in the
vicinity of Shiloh on the evening of April 5th. At Shiloh the
1st Tennessee, the 7th Kentucky, the 6th and 9th Tennessee
plus a Mississippi battery formed the 2nd Brigade of Major
General B. F. Cheatham's Division. Colonel George Maney was
assigned to command the brigade, but by order of General A.S.
Johnston, Maney's batallion was detached to the extreme right
to guard against a possible attack from that direction.
On the morning of April 6, 1862 the Rutherford Rifles were
greeted with rocket fire and the roar of musketry as well as
the thunder of artillery. 'However, these Rifles had been placed
on the right flank in reserve and'here they remained until
about 2:]0 that afternoon when Colonel Maney's batallion joined
the main battle. Now,the RifJ.es found. themselves actiyely engaged
in battle , and they lost their first comrade ~o actual warfare&#173;Andrew
Bass. Colonel Maney's brigade led a charge which broke
the enemy's lines and caused them to retreat to the river. This
action has been described by historians as one of the most
brillant and decisively successful movements of the 1st days
Battle of Shiloh. On April 7th Colonel Maney led his brigade
in a charge which repelled the 'Federal-advance.
The first days fighting went'\vell for &#183;the Confederates,
however,General A.S. Johnston was killed,juring the battle,
15
and on the second day General Grant's counter-attack forced
the Confederates to retreat to Corinth.:While here the Ruther-ford
,:,Rifl,es&#183; reorganized. William Ledbetter was re-elected
Captain; Hardy Murfree, 1st Lieutenent; G.H.
Wilkinson, 2nd Lieutenent; H.A. Ransom, ]rd Lieutenent,
and J.Jarrett, Sergeant. At Corinth the Rifles buried an&#173;other
of their comrades--Lewis Dickson.
On the night of May 29, the Army of Tennessee marched
south to Tupelo, Mississippi where they remained until
July 24, 1862 at which time they moved by rail to Chattanooga.
Here the Rutherford Rifles remained until the corps of Gen-erals
Leonidas Polk and William Hardee had arrived at which
time the ,ar~y crossed. the Tennessee River on flat boats
and marched to Sale Creek. They rested here until about Sep~
tember 1, at which time they crossed the Cumberland Mo~tains
and reached Sparta, Tennessee. From there the army moved forward.
Rording the Cumberland River near Gainesboro, Tennessee, they
reached Glasgow, Kentucky. Here, they rested for several days.
About the 15th of September the Army' of Tennessee flanked
Bowling Green, Kentucky and reached Munsfordsville about noon.
The next day the troops w~re surprised with the announcement
that the Federal forces had withdrawn. Leaving there the Army
moved to Perryville, Kentucky where they engaged the enemy in
battle.
On October 8, 1862 the constant movement of mounted men
16 '
told the Rutherford Rifles that a real battle was in the
making. The Battle of Perryville proved to be a sad occasion
for the Rifles. Many of their .company were lost on that field
of battle. Around noon, the Rifles were ordered to the right,
and passing near a spring, they stopped to refill their can&#173;teens.
Soon they reached the brow of a hill. To their front
Cheatham's Artillery,was engaging General James S. Jackson's
infantry. During this battle the Union general, Jackson, was
killed. The Rifles continued their movement to the right to go
to General Daniel S.Dbnelson's support. Climbing over rock
fences, running up hills, the Rifles soon formed a line to the
rear of the Confederate General Donelson's, troops:i ",It":..was'!'at
this time that the Rifles lost several of their comrades&#183; when
xhey clashed with the Union reserves of General Lovell Rousseau.
The Rifles lost'Sam..Ransom,Len Smith, J.T. Jarrett, J.P. Seward,
Joe Cates, George Clark, Will Searcy, and M. Boring.Livingston
Pierce was wounded and later died. Night brought the battle at
Perryyille.; to a close,and under the light of a full moon the
Rifles buried their dead. That night the Rutherford Rifles
slept on the battlefield. Early the morning of October 9, 1862
they retreated to Bryantsville Where they remained until the
12th of October after Which they marched through the Cumber&#173;land
Gap and on to Knoxville. The Army of Tennessee reached
Knoxville on October 25, 1862 during a severe snow storm. They
were forced to sleep outside during the bitter weather. The
next day the Rifles left Knoxville by rail and arrived in
Tullahoma, Tennessee Where they remained until November 22,
1862. From Tullahoma the Rifles marched home, arriving in
Murfreesboro about November 24. They encamped near Stones
River. The elation shared by members of the company and
their loved ones upon the arrival of the Rutherford Rifles
in their home town was indescribable. The Rifles rested
near their home town until December 26 when the approach
from Nashville;'T~nnes~eebf General .William Starke Rose-crans
and his.Union troops forced the Rifles into picket
duty near LaVergne, Tennessee. However, as the Federal
troops drew near, the Rifles were forced to retreat and
were pushed back near Stewart's Creek. They continued their
retreat and on the night of December 27 they camped on the
Thomas Hord farm near Stones River. The next morning the
Rifles rejoined the Confederate forces near Murfreesboro.
On December 29, 1862 the Rutherford Rifles took up their
assigned position in reserve near Franklin, Tennessee.
On December )1, 1861 the opposing armies of Union
and Confederate troops faced each other ready for battle.
It was a coincident that both generals had de~ised con-current,
battle plans--that of attacking. the right Wing of
the enemy. However, General Braxton Bragg began his attack
at daybreak, taking the Union troops by surprise. The
Rutherford Rifles were ordered to move forward and support
General Jones Withers Whose troops were forcing s~iff'
17
18 19
resistance near the Wilkinson Pike. It was at this point
with attack and could not move his troops. At length the
twilight came and then darkness, putting an end to the first
angles to the original line of battle. However, at this
point Rosecrans brought up reinforcements a~.ong the.
guard. During their stay at Shelbyville two other members of
their company died--G.B. Wilson and J.H. White.
Leaving Shelbyville about June 1, 1863 the Rifles found
themselves near Morgan's Mill near Murfreesboro. In a skirmish
here another of their company fell--Thomas Kinney. On the 25th
of June the Rutherford Rifles marched to Tullahoma to rejoin
the main force of the Army of Tennessee. Tullahoma had been
fortified by the Confederates, but word came of a flanking
movement of Rosecran's army,which had been in winter quarters
at Murfreesboro,and the Rifles along with the rest of the
Army of Tennessee began a march to Chattanooga.
The Rifles went into camp south of Chattanooga. There
was little activity until September 18 to 20 when the Rifles
performed valiant service &#183;at the Battle of Chickamauga where
the Union troops suffered. a devastating defeat. Followfn~:
-this battlE} :the RvttJ,erfor.d Rifles, went on~. an expedition into
East Tennessee but returned in time to take part in the Battles
of Missionary Ridge and Lookout Mountain.
The Rifles were positioned at the eastern base of Mission-ary
Ridge. on the evening of September 21. They awoke the next
morning to find Wilder's' ;mounted infantry occupying the crest.
The Confederates ch~g~4 a~d after taking the ridge they for&#173;tified
their position. While they were occupying this position,
they were visited by Jefferson Davis who inspected the line of
'batt1ie,
repleniahed their
&#183;and the Confederate drive began to.,slow
down. Bragg called for Breckinridge to come to the support;
however, Breckinridge informed Bragg that he was threatened
Nashville - Pi~e
that two members of the Riflss 'f~ll--Fred James while
attempting to unmask a battery and F.M. Snell upon whose
body no wounds were found. The Rutherford Rifles continued
to give their assistance as the Confederate troops forced
the Union right back towards the Nashville Pike. By noon
the Federal line had been forced back until it was in right
armies rested , buried their dead, .
days fighting.
The Confederates felt the day was theirs and General
Bragg sent a victery telegram to Jefferson Davis, "God has
granted us a happy New Year". On Janurary 1, 1863 both
s~pplies, and made plans for a second days battle. After
suffering the devastating loss at McFadden's Ford on Jan&#173;uary
2, General Bragg and his Army of Tennessee retreated.
The Rutherford Rifles found themselves in winter quarters
near Shelbyville, Tennessee. They remained there until
April 22, 1863 guarding the army stores and acting provost
20
Just prior to the Battle of Lookout Mountain the Rifles
were assigned to outpost duty at the eastern base of Lookout
Mountain. They were at this time separated from the enemy
lines by a 20 yard stream. By mutual agreement both sides
agreed to cease firing, and the men of both armies passed
the time-trading tobacco and newspapers. This truce lasted
only a short while since General Grant was preparing to storm
the ridge. On the 24th of November,1863 the Rifles took
up position under General William J. Hardee's Corps. The:
Federals stormed the ridge and the Confederates fled down
the other side of the mountain. The next day on November 25,
the Confederates were routed at the Battle of Missionary
Ridge, and Bragg's Army retreated into Georgia. The Battle
of Missionary Ridge proved to be the most destructive of
all for the Rifles. They lost five of their company in the
Federal assault--Dock Butler, George Johnson, Thomas Crockett,
John Haynes, and Johnny Jones.
December 1, 1863 found the Confederates in Dalton, Georgia.
Here they constructed winter quarters and rested from the recent
battles. The Rifles spent their time in snow-fights, sham-battles,
and restocking supplies. Up to this time the Rifles had been
considered Voulnteers, but here at Dalton, Georgia they were
enlisted for the duration of the war.Some of the members of the
company protested this actiorl,but they were soon silenced.
It was at Dalton, Georgia that news came to the Rifles of the
death of Sam Davis. This news grieved the hearts of every
21
member.
In February of 1864 the Rifles, as part of Cheatham's
Division, were ordered to Mississippi to reinforce Lieu&#173;tenant
General Leonidas Polk, but after reaching Demopolis,
Alabama they were returned to Dalton, Georgia. The Rifles
spent the next two months in quietude.
May of 1864 found the Federal Army in motion with Gen&#173;eral
Sherman moving rapidly against the Confederate lines.
The Rifles took part in felling trees and setting up forti&#173;fications.
On the 9th of May the COilfederates occupied
Rocky Face Ridge and skirmished with Sherman's center. Then
the Southern Army retreated south &amp;nd on May 15th, the Con-
- _federates took their position in Adairsville, Georgia. There
they formed a line against the Federal forces,and it was here
that &#183;..Lieutenan:t - ., Ransom met his death and Lieutenant
Murfree was so wounded that he became disabled. At New Hope
Church on May 26 Maney's Brigade was sent with General Bate's
Division to engage the enemy near Dallas, Georgia. This order
Was counter...manded and they marched all night in the rain,
arriving the next day at Pine Mountain.
By June 27, the Confederates had heavily fortified Kenne&#173;saw
Mountain. Their position was atop a bold ridge that fell
abruptly about 60 yards to their front. They had sharpened to
a point logs from trees and had placed these logs in a posi&#173;tion
projecting over the abrupt drop to their front. The works
were well built, and when the Union Army pr~pared to assualt
the ridge' they were unable to penetrate the works. The';
Federals lost about ), 000 men while General Johnston.' sloss
was only 800 men. The wounded Union soldiers lay mangled and
dying in front of the breastworks. During the battle some
dry leaves caught fire and burned rapidly around the wounded
Federals. The Confederates suspended hostilities until the
wounded could be removed.
Leaving Kennesaw Mountain ~n July 2, 1864, the Confed&#173;erates
retreated to. Marietta, Georgia. After a few days of
rest they crossed the Chattahoochie River and laid fortifi&#173;cations
near Peachtree Creek. Just as they had completed their
fortifications, they were ordered to storm the enemy line. The
Rifles suffered no losses in this attack.
On July 17, 1864 General John B. Hood assumed the command
of the Army of Tennessee. Following his appointment, the Con&#173;federates
moved nearer Atlanta and began fortifications. The
Rifles were assigned picket duty. Near the close of August the
regiment to which the Rifles belonged moved to Jonesboro where
they attacked the Union troops under General Oliver Howard.
At Jonesboro, the Rifles elected T.A. Snell )rd Lieutenant to
replace Lt. Ransom.
On August )1, 1864 Atlanta fell, and the Confederates under
General Hood&#183; marched to Lovej,oy I s Station below J.onesboro. Gen.
Maney had relinquished command of the . regimen~ _ to which
the Rifles were attached, and Col. Hume R. Field was placed
in charge.
As soon as General Hood realized that Atlanta was doomed,
he felt &#183;the necessity of trying to save the remnant of his
army. From Jonesboro he marched to Palmetto, Georgia where
Jefferson Davis met him for consultation. Upon Davis.' arriv&#173;al'
it was the band of the regiment to which the Rifles be&#173;longed
that serenaded the despondent Confederate President.
Following the consultation with Davis the decision was made
to march the t1l"OOPS' &#183;to' Tenness:ee.
The rou~e'followed by the. Rifles as well as t~e rest of
the army; on this march included crC?s~ing the Chattahooche
River, marching northeast and crossing the Coosa River just
west of Rome, Georgia. The Army of Tennessee moved on to
Dalton, Georgia Where General Hood stormed the Union fort
there, capturing the U.S. 44th Colored Infantry. The Rifles
were assigned the duty of guarding these prisoners for
a time. From Dalton the Confederate troops marched to Gads&#173;den,
Alabama, arriving there the 2)rd of October, 1864. They
crossed Sand Mountain and arrived in Decatur, Alabama on the
October', 28&#183;., From there J they marched to Tuscumbia, Alabama
Where they rested for a few days. Then they crossed the Tenn&#173;essee
River on pontoon boats and occupied and fortified
Florence, Alabama.
On the 21st of November the Army of Tennessee left their
camp at Florence, Alabama and marched into Tennessee. They
passed through Waynesboro, Tennessee, making camp as they
23
24
neared Columbia, Tennessee. Flanking the Union General
John McAllister Schofield who had .been directed to oppose
Hood's invasion of Tennessee, The Confederate troops&#183;
crossed Duck River and reached Spring Hill, ~ennessee on
the evening of November 29,1864. Here they rested for the
night, .and during the dark hours they could hear the
enemy marching past their camping ~ea .. On the morning of
November]O, General Hood's army followed Schofield and
formed a line just to the front of the Union troops in
Franklin, Tennessee. Hood's army made a last grand charge
against the Federals,and it was during this charge that
the last Rifle to be killed in action met his fate--William
L. North, a man whom his comrades had described "as never
having an enemy and who was an enemy to no living soul-.
After being defeated in the Franklin battle, General
Hood pushed forward to Nashville, Tennessee and took up a
position on Overton's Hill. There he met the strong arm
of General George H. Thomas of the Union army. Hood and his
men.were forced to retreat. By now Captain William Ledbetter
of the Rutherford Rifles had been taken prisoner,and only a
handful of the original Rutherford Rifles followed Hood to
Tupelo, Mississippi as he retreated.
The:.AI;'my of(.tTenn~ssee. in early 1865 afteT a tedious
journey through Mississippi, Alabama, Georgia, and South
Carolina joined General Joseph E. Johnston at Bentonville,
North Carolina. By now the Army of Tennessee waS so dec i-
25
mated that a reorganization and consolidation of troops
took place. The Rifles became a part of General Joseph B.
Palmers Brigade. The Army made one last desperate effort
When they engaged the enemy at Bentonville.
On April 26, 1865 the Army of Tennessee laid down
the~ arms Which they had carried so long in defense of their
homeland. With about 38 members of the Rutherford Rifles
killed in action, namy seriously wounded and in hospitals,
some in detached service, some in the hands of the enemy,
and some having died in prison camps, there were actually
only eleven members remaining at the time of surrender. They
were B.F. Anderson, B.B. Batey, J.M. Beasley, T.J. Beasley,
William Beasley, James MoKing,Thomas M. King, S.S. Hollowell,
Pleasant Rutledge, Lieutenant T.A. Snell, and T.J. Kade.
According to ~.J. Wade writing in the Free Press, April 23,
1880, the Rifles had marched across nine states, traveled
thousands of miles, and crossed the Tennessee River ten times.
From North Carolina the Rutherford Rifles, as prisoners
of the Union Army, marched to East Tennessee Where being
furnished transportation they left for Murfreesboro, Tennessee.
They arrived in their hometown on May 2, 1865 on the anniversary
of the day When they first left home.
The J.VIurfr.eesboto Free Press, . on April ?J, 1880. pUbli~hed a
list of the members of the Rutherford Rifles and What happened
to each of them. The list as compilBd by T.M. King, B.B. Batey , .
and T.A. Snell follows:
1. Captain William Ledbetter, elected Captain at
organization in 1861; reelected at re-organization
in 1862; wounded at Atlanta, at Franklin, and was
captured and imprisoned; made his escape and sur&#173;rendered
in 1865.
2. 1st Lieutenant Hardy Murfree; elected 1st Lieu&#173;tenant
at organization in 1861; reelected at re&#173;organization
in 1862; wounded and disabled at
Adairsville, Ga. May 17, 1864; surrendered in
1865.
J. 2nd Lieutenant R.F. James; elected 2nd Lieu&#173;tenant
at organization in 1861; volunteered
after the reorganization in 1862 as staff officer
and killed at Battle of Murfreesboro, 1862.
4. Jrd Lieutenant C.H. King; elected Jrd Lieutenant
at organization in April 1861; volunteered as a
private in same company at reorganization in 1862;
wounded at Perryville, Ky.; detailed in 186J in
Signal Corps Service; surrendered in North Caro~
lina in 1865.
5. Ord. Serg't A. Loeb; elected O.S. at organization
in April 1861.
Privates
6 .. Ailder.son, B. F.; enlisted April 1861; surrendered
wi~h'cofumand in North Carolina in 1865.
7. &#183;Anderson,E.~.enlisted.~pril1861;appointed Cor&#173;poral;
went to cavalry in 1864; died after sur&#173;render.
8 .. Anderson&#183;J~.woundedat Adairsville, Ga. 1864.
9 ...Av.ent,B.1CJ.. ; enlisted in April 1861; detailed on
~ special 'dujiyi.in&#183;&#183;medical .department.
10. Bass, A.J. enlisted April 1861; killed at Shiloh
in 1862.
11. Batey,B.B. enlisted April 1861; appointed O.S&#183;.
in 1862; wounded at Marietta, Ga. 1864; sur&#173;rendered
with command in North Carolina in 1865.
2 27
12. Batey, J.B. enlisted April 1861; captured in
1862 and remained a prisoner.
lJ. Batey, ~!.O. went to cavalry in 186J
14. Becton, J.W. enlisted in April 1861; appointed
Sergeant, didcharged in 186J; captured and died
in prison.
15. Beesley, James M.wounded near Marietta, Ga.in
1864; surrendered with command in North Carolina
in 1865.
16. Beesley, John enlisted April 1861; appointed
Corporal; wounded at Murfreesboro 1862; detail&#173;ed
special duty.
17. Beesley,T.J. enlisted April 1861; wounded at Mur&#173;freesboro
and disabled; afterwards discharged
and died since surrender.
18. Beesley, '. enlisted April 1861; wounded at'
Adairsville, Ga; surrendered with command in
North Carolina in 1865.
19. Beesley, William enlisted April 1861; wounded at
Chickamauga, Ga; Adairsville, Ga.; Franklin, Tenn. ,
and surrendered with command in North Carolina in
1865.
20. Blair,A.H. enlisted April 1861; sutler.
21. B~air, J.L. enlisted April 18?1; wounded at Perry&#173;vllle,
Ky.; captured and remalned a prisoner.
22. Beachboard,William died 186J.
2J. Baird, 'John L.enlisted April 1861; appointed
Surgeon, transferred to medical department and
died during the war.
24. Bock, Adam enlisted April 1861; detached on
special duty.
25. Boring, T.M. enlisted April 1861; killed at
Perryville, Ky.
26. ~:rOpks&#8226;. C;.y &#8226;. enli::'3.:peq... April 1861; wQunded and
disabled at Perryvill~; Ky. and discharged.
31.
39.
30.
27. Brothers,A.W. transferred from 7th Te~essee
1861; captured 1863 and remained a prlsoner.
28. Bu~rows, T.W. wounded and disabled at Adairs&#173;ville,
Ga.
29. Butler, r.w. enlisted April 1861! mortGallY1863
wounded and died at Missionary R1dge, a. . .
Carney,L.V. enlisted April 1861; discharged in
Virginia 1861.
Cates, Joe D. enlisted April 1861; killed at
Perryville, Ky.
32. Clark, George W. enlisted April 1861; killed
at Perryville, Ky.
33. Clay, D.D. enlisted April 1861; wounded aGt
Perryville, Ky.; lost an arm at Lovejoy, a.
afterwards discharged.
34. Collier, F.W. enlisted April 1861! captu~ed 4in
lB6~ '; and remained a prisoner; d1ed Apr11, 2 ,
1880.
35. Cooper, T.C. furnished Thomas Kinney as a sub&#173;stitute
in 1863.
36. Crass: F.H. enlisted April 1861; detached on
special duty.
37. Crichlow, Sam enlisted April 1861; wounded at
Cheat Mountain 1861; discharged and died since
surrender.
38. Crockett, T.O. enlisted April 1861; Killed at
Missionary Ridge 1863.
Davis, Samuel enlisted April 1861; detailed as
a special scout 1863; capturBd and executed by
hanging at Pulaski, Tenn. by the enemy as a
spy Nov. 25, 1863.
40. Davis, '~ enlisted April 1861; died in
Virginia 1861.
41. Dickson, L.M. enlisted April 1861; died at
Corinth, Miss. 1862.
42. Dudley, R.H. enlisted April 1861; went to
cavalry 1864. .
43. Drumright, W.B. enlisted April 1861; wounded
at Murfreesboro, Tenn. 1862; went to cavalry.
44. Edwards, A.M. enlisted April 1861; went to
cavalry.
45. EWing, Joseph W. detached on special duty.
46. Farris,W. enlisted April 1861; discharged 1861.
47. Featherston, W.E. wounded near Marietta, Ga.
captured in 1865 and remained a prisoner.
48. Fletcher, James H. transferred from 8th Tenn.;
went to cavalry 1865.
49. Fletcher, James S. enlisted April 1861; appoint&#173;edSurgeon
and transferred to medical depart&#173;ment;
killed since surrender.
50. Grigg, Joe H. enlisted April 1861; discharged at
Corinth 1862. .
51. Hall, Josephus enlisted April 1861; detailed on
special duty, taken prisoner; died since sur&#173;render.
52. Halliburton, B.F. enlisted April 1861; wounded at
Cheat Mountain, Va.; went to cavalry 1864; died
since the war.
53. Haynes, C.C. enlisted April 1861; died at Win&#173;chester,
Va. 1861.
54. Haynes" J.E.W. enlisted April 1861;. appointed
Corporal; wounded at Perryville, Ky. killed at
Missionary Ridge 1863.
55. Hicks, William H. enlisted April 1861; trans&#173;ferred
to artillery; died since the surrender.
56. Higdon, J.A. enlisted April 1861; wounded near
Mari~tta, Ga. afterwards detailed on special duty.
57. Henry, J.F. enlisted April 1861; appointed
Sergeant; went to cavalry 1864.
29
"
58. Hirshberg, Simon enlisted April 1861; appointed
Corporal; detailed musician.
59" Hodge, S.H. enlisted April 1861; detached as
special scout 186J; captured and kept in prison
until the surrender.
60. Howse, L.H. enlisted April 1861; discharged-and
re-enlisted in 1862; detached as special scout
and surrendered in 1865.
61. Holloway, Daniel enlisted April 1861; discharged
at Camp Cheatham in 1861. . .
62. Hollowell, S.S. enlisted April 1861; discharged
and re-enlisted in 1862; wounded in Atlanta in
1864 and died since the surrender.
6J. James, Allen enlisted April 1861; went to cav&#173;alry
in 1864.
64. Jackson, J.W. enlisted April 1861; captured in
186J and remained a prisoner.
65. Jamison, M.C. enlisted April 1861; appointed
Sergeant; killed at the Battle of Perryville,
Ky.
66. Jarratt, J.T. enlisted in April 1861; appointed
O.S. in 1862; died at Perryville, Ky.
67. Jetton, J.W. enlisted April 1861; transferred to
General Cleburne's staff; died since the surrender.
68. Jetton, Brevard enlisted April 1861; discharged
1862 and died since the surrender.
69. Jenkins', J.F. enlisted April 1861; transferred
to 11th Tennessee Cavalry 1862.
70. Johnson, G.W. enlisted April 1861; appointed
Corporal; killed at Missionary Ridge 186J.
71. Jones, Robert G. enlisted April 1861; surrendered
with comma.pd in North Carolina in 1865; died
since the surrender~
72. Jones, John substituted by Pat Lishley 186J;
killed at Missionary Ridge 186J.
30
73. Keeble, James M. enlisted April. 1861; trans&#173;ferred
to General George Maney's staff.
74. Kerr, J.M. enlisted April 1861; wounded at
Perryville, Ky.;_ went to cavalry.
75. King, John D. enlisted April 1861; captured
at Cheat Mountain 1861; exchanged in 1862 and
transferred to medical department.
76. King, J.M. enlisted April 1861; wounded at
Chickamauga; surrendered with uommand in
North. '.Carolina in 1865.
77. King, T.M. enlisted April 1861; wounded at
Adairsville, Ga. surrendered in North Caro&#173;lina
in 1865.
78. Kinney, Thomas substituted by T.C. Cooper
1863; killed near Morgan,' s Mill, Rutherford
County, Tenn. 1863.
79. Lawrence, J.C. enlisted April 1861; captured
in 1864 and remained a prisoner.
80. Ledbetter, N.C. enlisted April 1861; went to
cavalry; died since the surrender.
,
81. Leiper, Sam C. enlisted April 1861; went to
cavalry 1864.
82. Leiper, William F. enlisted April 1861; trans&#173;ferred
to 4th Tennessee Infantry.
83. Levy, Henry wounded and disabled at Resaca,
Ga.
84. Lillard,M. enlisted April 1861; discharged 1862.
85. Love,J.R. enlisted April 1861; furnished a
substitute (Pat McMan) in 186J.
86. Lishley, Pat transferred from artillery 1863;
furnished a substitute (John Jones) 1863 and
joined 1st Tennessee Band.
87. Loeb, Maurice musician.
88. Mayberry, W.G. enlisted April 1861; dis&#173;charged
in 1862; died since the war.
31
32 33
890 McLean, A.V. enlisted April 1861;- went to cav- 105. North, W.Lo enlisted April 1861; killed at
aIry 1864. Franklin, Tenn. 1864.
90. MaIcrLyea1n8, 6C4..L. enlisted April 1861; went to cav- 106. Oprdiesno, nTehro.mas M. captured 1865 and remained a
110. Pritchett, Ed enlisted April 1861; detailed
-musician.
111. Ransom; A.R. enlisted April 1861; wounded at
Perryville, Ky. and Adairsville, Ga.; dis&#173;charged;
died since the war.
Ransom, H.R. enlisted April 1861; elected
3rd Lieutenant 1862 at re-organization;
wounded at Perryville, Ky. 1862; wounded and
died at Adairsville, Ga. 1864.
Ransom, S.H. enlisted April 1861; transferred
to quartermaster's department 1861; rejoined
the company 1862; killed at Perryville,Ky.
1862.
107.
108.
Pierce, E.L. enlisted April 1861; wounded and
died at Perryville, Ky. 18620
Poindexter, J. R. enlisted April 1861; captured
1863 arid remained a prisoner.
109. Phillips, J.L. wounded at Marietta, Ga. 1863;
went to cavalry 1865.
l1J.
112.
114. Ransom, William _enlisted April 1861; died at
Warm Springs, Va. 1861.
115. Rucker,Robert enlisted April 1861; discharged
1861; .died since the war.
116. Rutledge, Pleasant; surrende~ed with command
in North Carolina 1865.
117. Searcy, William enlisted April 1861; killed
at Perryville, Ky. 1862.
118. Seward, Z.T. enlisted April 1861; killed at
Perryville, Ky. 1862.
. .
910 McFarlin, Marion P. detached on special duty;
captured in 1863 and remained a prisoner.
92. McMann, Pat substitute for J.R~ Love 1863;
wounded and died at Chickamauga, Ga.
93. Miller, Charles enlisted April 1861; appointed
Sergeant 1862; went to cavalry 1865.
940 Maney, D.Do transferred to commissary department.
950 Mitchell, William enlisted April 1861; trans&#173;ferred
to 4th Tennessee Regiment Infantry.
96. Moore, William enlisted April 1861; discharged
in Virginia 1861; died since the war.
97. Morton, James transferred from 8th tenn. Infantry
1861; captured in 1865; remained a prisoner;
died since the war.
98. Mosbey, James C. enlisted April 1861; captured
1863 and remained a prisoner.
990 Murfree, Hal enlisted April 1861; discharged in
Virginia in 1862.
100. Murfree, J.B. enlisted April 1861; promoted to
Surgeon and transferred to medical department
1861.
101. Neal,Fount E. enlisted April 1861;wounded at Cheat
Mountain; appointed Sergeant; killed at Atlanta
July 22, 1864.
1020 Neal, John enlisted April 1861; discharged 1861.
10J. Nance, I.W. enlisted April 1861; went to cavalry
1863.
104. North,J.M. enlisted April 1861; wounded at Mission&#173;ary
Ridge 1863; went to cavalry 1865.
3 35
147. Wilson, G.B. died at Shelbyville, Tenn. in 1863.
144. White J.H. enlisted April 1861; died at Shelby&#173;ville,
Tenn. '1863.
150. Wright, John enlisted April 1861; transferred
to ordinance department 1861.
~~heelJ..~g,:&#183;C. enlisted April 1861'; caPtblr~d at
Cheat Mountain in 1861; detached on speclal duty
in quartermaster.' s department.
l.&#183;
Wilkinson, oW. A. wounded at Marietta, Ga.;
wounded and disabled at Franklin, Tenn. 1864.
Wilkinson, George H. enlisted April 1861; elect&#173;ed
2nd Lieutenant at re-organization in 1862;
wounded and disabled at Atlanta, Ga. July 22,
1864.
148. Wilson, T.H. discharged lab3. ,,'
, -. , -.' ~. -. (~
145.
135. Traylor, J.W. enlis~ed April 1861;, died at
Tupelo, Miss. 1862.
136. Tucker, J.T. enlisted April 1861; detailed as
hospital steward 1862.
137. Turner, E.L. enlisted April 1861; wounded at
Perryville, Ky. and LaVergne, Tenn.; went to
cavalry 1864.
138. Turner R.J. enlisted April 1861; promoted to
Assistant Surgeon and transferred to medical
department 1861.
139. Vaughan, E.R. enlisted April 1861; went to cav.&lt;.
aIry in 1865.
140.' Vaughan, J.F. detailed as special scout 1863.
141. Watts, William enlisted April 1861; wounded at
Cheat Mountain and discharged.
142. Wade, T.J. enlisted April 1861; wounded at
Peach~ree Creek, Ga. and Franklin, Tenn.;
captured and remained a prisoner.
143. Walter, George enlisted April 1861; detailed
as a musician.
146.
120. Sims, E.B. enlisted April 1861; discharged
in 1862.
121. Sims, N.H. enlisted April 1861; transferred
to cavalry.
124. Smith L.H. enlisted April 1861; killed at
Perryville, Ky.
125. Smith, J. Battie enlisted April 1861; died
at Edray, Va. 1861.
126. Smith W.B. enlisted April 1861; died at Edray,
Va. 1861.
119. Shelton, W.D. enlisted April 1861; trans&#173;ferred
to cavalry in 1863.
122. Smith, John D. enlisted April 1861; died at
Warm Springs, Va. 1861.
123. Smith, L.J. enlisted April 1861; captured in
1864 and remained a prisoner.
132. Sublett, D.D. enlisted April 1861; wounded at
Shiloh; captured in 1864 and remained a prisoner;
committed suicide since surrender.
127. Smith, John wounded at Chickamauga, Ga. after&#173;wards
died in 1863.
128. Snell, J.T. enlisted April 1861; appointed Ser&#173;geant
in 1862; wounded at Perryville, Ky. and
Franklin, Tenn.; went to cavalry in 1865.
129. Snell, T.A. enlisted April 1861; appointed 2nd
Sergeant in 1861; wounded at Murfreesboro, Tenn.
in 1862; elected 3rd Lieutenant in 1864, and
surrendered with command in North Carolina 1865.
130. Snell, F.M. killed at Murfreesboro, Tenn. 1862.
131. Sudberry, Henry went to artillery in 1864; died
since the war.
133. Tucker, E.R. enlisted April 1861; discharged 1861.
134. Tignor, enlisted April 1861; detached on
special duty 1861.</dc:description>
<dc:description>A short history of the activity of The Rutherford Rifles, a group of 150 local CSA troops led by Captain William Ledbetter</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Tennessee. Militia; Rutherford County (Tenn.); United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865; Militias;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Ledbetter, William</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>19 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-01-26</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication31ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/159</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>