<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>First Presbyterian Church, Murfreesboro, Tennessee: the first century</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hooper, Ernest</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 14</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1980</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>19th century; 20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>FIRST PRESBYTERIAN CHURCH, MURFREESBORO, TENNESSEE
THE FIRST CENTURY
Ernest Hooper
"Rev. Robert Henderson settled among us and Commenced his Labours
June first 1811." This inscription on the fly leaf of the first record
book of the congregation indicates that Presbyterians were worshiping in
the vicinity of Murfree Spring at least ten months before the formal
organization of the congregation which is recorded as follows:
April 1812
A number of persons living in the neighborhood of Murfree Spring
in Rutherford County, Tennessee, being desirous that a church
should be organized in that neighborhood of the Presbyterian
order, met, and were accordingly organized into a church denom-inated
the Murfree Spring Church, by the Rev. Robert
Henderson. . . .
Next the record lists three ruling elders: Robert Wasson, John Smith,
William D. Baird and, then, fifteen other charter members: Joseph Dickson,
Margaret Dickson, Mary Dickson, Isabella Smith, John Henry, Susanna
Henry, Frances Henderson, Mary Stewart, Abigail Baird, Margaret Jetton,
Mrs. Samuel Wilson, Grace Williams, Elizabeth Kelton, Margaret Wasson,
Jane C. Smith. Assuming that each surname represented a separate family,
there were eleven families represented.
From 1812 to 1818 the minutes only list the names of the ministers:
Robert Henderson, Thomas J. Hall, James Bowman, George Newton, and Jesse
Alexander. It appears that the congregation worshipped twice a month,
first in a log schoolhouse near the spring then in another near the pres-
2
ent site of St. Paul's Episcopal Church.
The Reverend Mr, Henderson had moved to Columbia in 1813 and, in
addition to preaching, had taught school. One of his students was James
Reverend William Eagleton, D.D.
Minister, 1829-1866
This portrait \A/as presented to First Presbyterian
Church by the artist, Richard C. Shacklett, on
January 1 1, 1976.
In 1 829, Dr. Eagleton \A/as laid to rest beside
his \A/ife(\A/ho had preceded him in death about
two years before) in the burial plot on the
plantation of their daughter and her husband,
Elvira Eagleton Campbell and Samuel Campbell.
The Burial Site is three miles south\A/est of
Murfreesboro on the Midland Road.
K. Polk who was destined to have several connections with the Presbyterian
Church in Murfreesboro. Perhaps, on Henderson's advice, he came to
Murfreesboro and studied for a year in the academy of another Presbyterian,
the Reverend Samuel P. Black. In 1819, he would return as clerk of the
Senate and serve through the special session of 1822, which met in the
First Presbyterian Church after the courthouse burned. In 1823, he
entered the House of Representatives from Maury County. On New Year's
Day 1824, he married Sarah Childress, another Presbyterian, with her pas-tor
and his teacher, the Reverend Dr. Robert Henderson officiating.
^
Greeneville College had conferred a doctorate in divinity on Henderson in
1818, the same year he returned to Murfreesboro to serve the church he
had founded six years before.
Murfreesboro and the Murfree Spring congregation were born about
the same time, and in October 1818 the congregation changed its name to
First Presbyterian Church, Murfreesboro. By April 1, 1820 it had built
a brick building on Vine [then known as Church] Street. While the minutes
do not mention the construction, William Lytle's deed, of that date,
mentions the church building upon it.* Later (1837) the city bought land
to the east and south for a cemetery. When the congregation moved in 1867,
it sold its property for burial plots and the land is now included in the
Old City Cemetery area.
The building was approximately forty by sixty feet with a cupola,
probably capped by a dome. There were three large doors facing Vine. A
vestibule had stairs on either side leading to the gallery which surrounded
the east, north, and west walls of the sanctuary. The north part was the
choir loft, and a pipe organ was installed about 1855. In the sanctuary
there were eight-foot pews on the east and west sides with a twelve-foot
pew in the center, probably twelve or fourteen rows since the capacity
was estimated at two hundred fifty to three hundred. The pulpit was
approximately five by ten feet and two or three steps above the floor.
There are only four references to the property in the minutes before
the Civil War. We may hope that this reflected the Session's conviction
that the Church was the body of believers and not the building. There is
no record of the number of communicants when Dr. Henderson returned in
1818, but there were seventy when he left in 1825. He had seen the Church
grow four- fold in thirteen years. A newspaper notice expressing thanks
indicated that he also taught school while in Murfreesboro.&#176;
The Reverend Dr. John W. Hall succeeded Dr. Henderson, and the
first fairly complete report recorded was in September 1826 for the
previous year. The year had begun with seventy communicants; ten had
been added by letter and twenty-one by examination; ten had been removed
from the roll: six by dismissal, one by suspension, and three by death;
leaving ninety-one conmuni cants, a gain of twenty-one or thirty percent.
Two adults and thirty infants had been baptized. The minister had been
promised $400 per year and the congregation had given a total of $176.50
to benevolences: $21.00 to Chickasaw missions, $1,00 to domestic missions,
$1.00 to Presbyterial Fund, $133.00 to a theological seminary and $20.50
to an educational fund. Dr. Hall moved to Gallatin in 1829.
The most remarkable pastorate in the nineteenth century began in
December 1829 when the Reverend William Eagleton, D. D. brought his family
across the Cumberlands from Southern and Western Seminary in Maryville and
from the Grassy Valley Presbyterian Church. Dr. Eagleton had been educated
by a very remarkable minister and teacher. When Dr. Isaac Anderson con-cluded
that he could not persuade enough ministers to come to the Southwest,
he founded the Southern and Western Seminary in Maryville-'forerunner of
Maryville College. Young William was ordained and served the Presbyterian
Church in Kingston until he was called back to teach in the Seminary.
Meantime he had married Margaret Ewing, also of Blount County, in 1817.
Dr. Eagleton's skill as a teacher is attested by the fact that after his
son, George, graduated from Union University in 1851, he studied theology
with his father for a year and was admitted by examination for the other
two years of seminary training, one at Maryville and the other at Union
Seminary in New York.
Dr. Eagleton was also an effective evangelist, both in the church
and in the camp meetings which were so popular. The records are incom-plete,
but for the twenty-eight years for which we have the figures, there
was an average of twenty-four additions per year and an average membership
of 217. Despite the fact that this was still a frontier area and large
numbers of adults were moving in, the ratio of admissions by profession
to those by certificate was better than four to one, 544 to 128. This
growth was even more remarkable when we note that a number of members
left over a church schism about 1840, that sixty-odd were encouraged to
organize a congregation at Kelton Camp Ground in 1838 and another thirty-three
organized a congregation at Sulphur Springs about 1854.
The controversies which split Presbyterians in the late 1830s divided
the Murfreesboro congregation briefly. The names of the two groups are
confusing, but in the 1830s, the general assemblies of the Presbyterian
Church, U.S.A. were riven by struggles between the New School group which
wished to continue the cooperation and easy fellowship with the Congrega-tional
Church, which had prevailed as they sought to evangelize the fron-tier,
and the Old School group which objected to receiving ministers into
Presbyterian fellowship unless they fully accepted the standards of the
Westminster Confession of Faith. The Old School group also wished to
establish denominational agencies instead of participating in the inter-denominational
mission boards that had been established. The Old School
group secured control in the assemblies of 1837 and 1838, expelled several
presbyteries and synods, and established denominational boards.
In the fall of 1839, the Synod of West Tennessee, meeting at Hunts-ville,
Alabama, divided and Dr. Eagleton and Elder William D. Baird affil-iated
with the New School Synod. When Eagleton and Baird returned to
Murfreesboro, they found Elders James Maney and Johnathan Currin prepared
with resolutions repudiating their actions and declaring that the Church
would adhere to the Old School Synod. One of the resolutions bore elo-quent
testimony to Dr. Eagleton's stature; it declared that the repudiation
was necessary "not from any want of confidence in the ministerial qualifi-cations
or piety of our beloved pastor" but because he had withdrawn himself
from the Presbyterian Church, U.S.A. When the resolutions were put to a
vote, Maney and Currin voted aye. Elders George Calhoon and David Mitchell
voted nay. Elder Baird declined to vote, feeling it unconstitutional.
This left the moderator. Dr. Eagleton, under the awkward necessity of
breaking the tie, and he voted nay. Dr. Maney and Mr. Currin promptly
entered a protest claiming to be the constitutional Session and entitled
to the books, muniments, etc.
There is not space here to trace the fascinating effort at concilia-tion;
we may summarize by saying that Dr. Eagleton and the three New School
members of the Session regularly acknowledged the rights of the Old School
members to worship in the building and offered to divide the use of the
building according to the number of adherents of the two sides, which this
group judged as 188 New School to 18 Old School, but no satisfactory
arrangement was worked out. A congregational meeting elected Samuel Hodge
and David Wendel to the Session in early April 1840, and the congregation
supported the ideas of the New School church courts. It switched its
support from a ministerial student who sided with the Old School party
and it supported benevolences through the various interdenominational
agencies.
The sentiments were indicated by a contribution of $53.25 in January
1841 to the American Tract Society for foreign distribution. Later in the
same month, it made a contribution of $30.00 to constitute Dr. Eagleton a
life member of the A.M.E.S. which appears to have been an interdenomina-tional
education society. In April of 1841, the Session proposed to call
attention to the benevolence requests of Shiloh Presbytery: domestic
missions, foreign missions under the American Board of Commissioners for
Foreign Missions, and the education of young men for the ministry. However,
it pled the number of calls for aid as an excuse for delay.
Elders Maney and Currin resumed their seats in the Session without
any recorded explanation on November 10, 1841. The Minutes of November 28,
1841 do say, in reference to a protracted meeting (18 days &amp; 19 nights):
. . . the saving arm of the Lord has been uncovered and His
mercy gloriously triumphant. The [fearful] difficulties which
have distracted the councils and paralyzed the energies of this
8
Church have been healed and we are once more an undivided and
harmonious church. About 90 souls have been hopefully
converted. 53 members added to this branch of Zion.
In his authoritative Presbyterians of the South , Ernest Trice
Thompson cites the Murfreesboro congregation as one in which the spirit
of love overcame strife and the breach was soon healed.
7
It was fortunate that Elder Johnathan Currin returned when he did
because in April 1842, the congregation faced a financial crisis. Although
it had pledged to pay Dr. Eagleton $500 a year after his first year and
had, perhaps, increased the amount somewhat, it was approximately $1,000
in arrears by 1842. In addition, David Wendell and Samuel Hodge had
obligated themselves on behalf of the church for $300 for repairs on the
church building in 1838. The congregation agreed to transfer the parson-age
to Dr. Eagleton when he cancelled the arrearage and assumed the $300
debt. Johnathan Currin was the trustee holding title for the congregation.
8
The parsonage was a two-storied frame house set back from the Readyville
Stage Road on an eight acre lot between what is now East Main, North
Highland, and East College and Dr. Eagleton had already bought a two acre
pasture to the east taking him nearly to the Union University line.
A major role of the nineteenth century Church was discipline of its
members. Twentieth century Christians are likely to see this as meddle-some
and to scoff at people who strained at the gnat of girls attending
dancing parties while swallowing the camel of human slavery. Admittedly,
there were absurdities, but a study of the minutes of the Session indicates
concern for the members and a potent civilizing force.
The first and most frequent problem for discipline was intoxication.
In September 1825, the Session issued its first citation for a member to
9
appear to answer a complaint by "common fame" of intoxication. On October
8, 1825, the member appeared and
acknowledged that he was sensible of being intoxicated . . . yet
not so as to destroy his reason nor prevent him from attending
to his necessary business but inasmuch as it appeared to be dis-covered
to the wounding of the friends of Zion, to the opening
of the mouths of gainsayers against the cause of Christ and to
the injury of his own soul, he was truly sorry . . . and having
promised to be more guarded against this sin in the future, he
was restored in the spirit of love and meekness to the full
communion and fellowship of the Church.
In minutes covering about forty years, there were twenty-one citations
relating to intoxication. In nine cases, the admission and apology of
the accused was accepted. In seven cases, the member withdrew or was
suspended.
Some of the explanations are very interesting. When seven were
accused at one session in December 1844, two explained that they had been
overcome by hot toddy in the heat of the 1844 presidential campaign between
Polk and Clay. On another occasion, the accused acknowledged his intoxica-tion
but stated that he had drunk to avoid a greater evil and did not admit
to any sin in the matter. The Session was very tender with an aged member
because of his infirmities and deafness, but after a year of conferences,
it finally suspended him, A militia man blamed his dereliction on the
inclement weather while he was on parade and the Session accepted his
explanation. Several drinkers insisted that they drank for reasons of
health and one admitted frequenting the dram shops, regretted the reproach
on the church, and promised to abstain. In the spirit of a Scotch cove-nanter,
he added that he believed his health required his drinking and if
his health deteriorated, he would notify the Session before resuming his
dram.
10
Whatever the southern tradition, the Session of the First Presbyterian
Church disapproved of dancing parties. In January of 1829, a committee
waited upon James Patton who admitted that he had opened his boarding
house for a dancing party. He insisted that he had only agreed to open
the house that the participants might sup, but the day had been rainy and
the streets muddy and it was necessary to open the house for the party or
lose all the expense to which he had gone for supper as well as antagoniz-ing
his boarders. He promised not to be taken in again, and the minutes
reveal an understanding Session which, "taking into account . . . the
indigence and inexperience of this brother did restore him to the fellow-ship
of the Church," The minister was appointed to confer with Col. F.
N. W. Burton about his breach of church discipline in permitting his
daughter to attend. There was enough concern that on June 23, 1829, the
Session adopted a preamble and resolutions disapproving of dancing parties,
calling on parents not to allow children under their control to attend,
and accepting the responsibility for the discipline of parents who offended.
In February 1831, the Session was again concerned and, after numerous
conferences, suspended James Patton on April 17, 1831 for permitting his
daughter to attend a dancing party. Colonel Burton's daughter had also
attended, but the Session accepted his assertion that he did not know it
was to be a dancing party, he disapproved, and he would use his influence
against his children attending in the future. Incidentally, it was Elder
James Maney who conferred with Burton so it may be assumed that he dis-couraged
dancing parties at Oakland. On May 15, 1845, the Session reaf-firmed
the position in the 1829 resolutions and requested the minister to
preach on the subject of dancing. As late as April 1889, the Session
11
overtured Nashville Presbytery to make a pronouncement on the dance, the
card table, and the theater. The Presbytery obliged with a statement to
be read from the pulpits of the Presbytery.
More significant, perhaps, was the concern of the Church over the
business practices of its members. In April of 1829, the Session heard
evidence on three charges against Dr. J. R. Wilson: that he had intoxicated
John H. Johns and defrauded him of land (Johns denied this), that he had
oppressed Mrs. Massey, a widow (she deposed that he had actually assisted
her when others were pressing her for payments due), and that he had
deceived Mr. Robert McLin in a money transaction. The Session decided
that the first two charges were disproved and that the third had not been
proved, but Dr. Wilson asked that his name be removed from the Church roll.
One of the saddest incidents in church discipline, but one which
illustrates the role of the Church in settling disputes among members,
involved two of the three charter elders. In August 1836, a committee
appointed to investigate the complaints of Elder William D. Baird that
Elder Robert Wasson was spreading false reports about him, reported that
Wasson claimed that: Baird had sought to collect twice for communion wine
which he had purchased; Baird had refused to pay the remaining $3.00 due
on a note to Wasson after Wasson had turned over the note to him; Baird
had refused to pay the interest on a note for which he had been security,
even though the signer had turned over two Negroes to Baird to cover the
debt and interest; and Baird had occasionally taken wood from Wesson's land.
Having failed at reconciliation, the Session ordered a hearing for August
22, 1836. It lasted for four days and there were a dozen or more witnesses
before Wasson requested permission to withdraw the charges and asked for
12
a letter of dismissal. The Session granted both and concluded that the
withdrawal of the charges was evidence that they could not be proved. The
hearing covers some ten pages in the Minute Book and provides considerable
detail. It appeared that the main grievance was that Baird was only will-ing
to pay 6% interest when the note had been written to bear 12%. Mr.
Baird preferred a slander charge against Hiram Wasson August 24, 1836; it
was continued for several months for various reasons; and May 23, 1837,
Baird requested that action be suspended because Mr. Wasson's mind had
been seriously affected for some months.
In the late 1850's there were realignments of the Old School and
New School synods and presbyteries and the Old School groups became more
conciliatory. The Presbytery of Shi 1 oh, to which the Murfreesboro congre-gation
belonged, voted its own dissolution and so the congregation had to
form a new connection. In the Session, Dr. Eagleton, Elders Maney, McFadden
and Wendel favored a recommendation to join the Old School Presbytery of
Nashville. Only Elder J. M. Baird, whose father had supported Dr. Eagleton
in joining the New School Synod in 1839, opposed the recommendation. The
congregation voted to join Nashville Presbytery by 99 to 3 with a number
of members declining to vote in the interest of harmony in the church.
This led the Session to declare that it regarded "... the brethren who
declined the ecclesiastical connexion of their own preference for the sake
of the peace of the Church as having presented on the altar of the Church
a grateful offering." After the Civil War began, Nashville Presbytery,
including the Murfreesboro Congregation, joined in the Presbyterian Church
in the Confederate States of America, which after the War became the
Presbyterian Church in the United States.
13
Although the official records do not indicate any hesitancy, there
must have been soul-searching for Dr. Eagleton about the course of the
South. His teacher, the Reverend Dr. Isaac Anderson for whom he had named
his second son, had been strongly opposed to slavery. Under Anderson's
influence, he had freed the few slaves he owned and sent them to Liberia
through the American Colonization Society. However, for house servants,
he had bought slaves and owned two at the outbreak of the war. We do know
something of the feelings of the Reverend George Eagleton, who greatly
admired his father. He was opposed to slavery and wished that the slaves
might be colonized, but he was also bitter about the abolitionists. As
late as December 1860, he was preaching against secession in the Hopewell
Church at Milton. He was delighted when Tennessee voted against secession
in February 1861, but furious when President Lincoln called for volunteers
after the firing on Fort Sumter.
^
In this period the Church records reveal no pressures. Just after
Tennessee voted against secession, the Session was busy raising a subscrip-tion
for the cause of missions under the Assembly's Board of Missions; it
raised $54 in March 1861. In the fateful month of April is recorded the
last admission of a slave: "Lizzie--a colored girl belonging to Samuel
Campbell was baptized and admitted to membership." Three days after Sumter,
the annual report indicated 188 communicants, salary payments to the min-ister
of $821.85, and it hinted at Dr. Eagleton's poor health, saying he
had given satisfaction and "rendered all the service that his age and
infirm health would permit." There may be a further hint at this in the
June 23, 1861, entry that the Lord's Supper was administered with the help
of the Reverend Mr. Provine of the Cumberland Presbyterian Church.
14
About the beginning of 1862, Dr. and Mrs. Eagleton went to East
Tennessee to stay with relatives in the hope that the rest would restore
their health. They were away when the church building was occupied and
then destroyed.
It has not been possible to determine whether services were held
in the remainder of 1862. When the battle was fought along Stone's River
at the end of 1862, the building was used as a hospital by the Confederates
and then by the Union forces. The Union troops set up their camps south
and west of the cemetery and church building. There is conflicting testi-mony
on whether the soldiers began taking the bricks to build chimneys
and huts or whether the Army officially ordered the building torn down
and the materials used for government purposes. A young member, Samuel
McFadden, managed to rescue the church bell and to dispose of some heavy
timbers.
The Session pursued a long effort to recover damages from the govern-ment,
beginning in 1865 and succeeding in collecting $6,500 in 1899. This
effort will be described later.
Although a number of baptisms are recorded in the minutes, it appears
that the Session did not meet between January 2, 1862, and July 18, 1864.
Dr. and Mrs. Eagleton returned to Murfreesboro in the summer of 1864,
and Mrs. Eagleton died on July 7. She was buried on the plantation of
Samuel and Elvira Eagleton Campbell, southwest of Murfreesboro. Dr.
Eagleton resumed his ministry as the Cumberland Presbyterian and Christian
Churches offered their sanctuaries.
The Session met on July 18, 1864, and the record deserves quotation.
15
There has been an unprecendented destruction of property both
private and public . . . and even the resting place of the dead
. . . and the sanctuary itself . . . have been and still are
desolated and desecrated l
The entries conclude:
Having made this sad record the Session would humbly rear an
Ebenezer and render thanks to God for mercies that are still
continued, and to the honor of his name acknowledge that we
have never yet seen an end of the goodness of the Lord!
Dr. Eagleton presided over the Session meetings until his death March 28,
1866. He was buried beside his wife on the Campbell plantation.
Without a postor, without deacons, without a building, and with only
three elders, the one hundred eighty-seven members had the faith to press
on. In October 1866, they called the Reverend John Witherspoon Neil to
the pastorate. Elders recalled that he
. . . was a young man but an able and eloquent preacher. He was
gifted with great executive ability and was peculiarly endowed as
an organizer. . . . preached eloquent and learned sermons,
instructing the congregation in the duties of religion and he
was unsparing in his strictures upon the derelict members.
Mr. Neil secured the use of the Circuit Courtroom and services were
held regularly. The congregation chose Gideon H. Baskette, Dr. Alex
Hartman, William D. Killough, William H. McFadden, Dr. James B. Murfree
and Dr. James E. Wendell as deacons. They were ordained and installed
December 30, 1866, and met to organize January 2, 1867.^0 Mr. Neil pre-sided.
Deacon Wendell was chosen treasurer and Deacon Murfree was chosen
secretary. The Diaconate proposed a system of financing which the Session
approved. It included subscriptions for the Pastor's salary, special
offerings on Corimiunion Sabbaths for the needy of the Congregation, and
special offerings on the third Sabbath of each month for incidental expenses.
Despite the fact that the Church was planning to build, the proposal also
;.r '. n^^j-
16
scheduled special offerings for the Boards of Domestic Missions, Publica-tions,
Foreign Missions, and Education.
A December 4, 1867, report&#8212;presumably for the first eleven months
of 1867--shows these receipts:
building fund $3 ,138.84
pastor's salary 1 ,443.00
Board of Publication 61.25
Board of Foreign Missions 28.25
educational fund 50.00
Domestic Missions 122.45
incidental expenses 180.66
poor fund 109.20
total $5 ,133.65
In the spring of 1867, the Congregation moved rapidly. It acquired
a lot on the corner of College and Spring Streets. On May 15, 1867, a
Congregational Meeting authorized the pastor to name a committee of three
to divide the church lot on Vine Street and sell it for burial plots. Mr.
Neil named Charles Ready, J. M. Baird, and E. D. Hancock.
Two days later, a meeting described as "a meeting of the male members"
passed a resolution to elect a committee of five with full power "... to
take charge, oversight, and . . . direction of everything pertaining to
the building . . . [and] to commence their work immediately and prosecute
it as rigorously as possible." The meeting balloted and chose D. D.
Wendel, J. M. Baird, Edwin A. Keeble, E. D. Hancock, and Dr. L. W. Knight.
The property on Vine Street was laid off and sold. The plat would
indicate that the eastern half of the original lot had already been used
for burials as the plat covered the western half.
The Building Committee secured the services of a Nashville architect,
W. A. Kiddell, who provided the design and specifications. It let the
contract for the brickwork to Arnold and January and for the woodwork to
18
pews to provide the minister's salary be discontinued, allowing members
to choose their pews and contribute as they were able. It also recommended
a salary of $1,500.00 and housing or a housing allowance of $300.00.
Apparently the pew rentals continued through 1876. For example ^ on
November 8, 1869, Dr. Murfree rented the pews for 1870 at public outcry.
Not all of the amounts were recorded, but those recorded ranged from $15.00
to $85.50. The deacons had asked that sixteen pews be reserved&#8212;whether
for visitors or new members was not specified. Pew number 1 was reserved
for "the Pastor's use" and numbers 38, 40, 41, and 80 were reserved for
"the colored people." The writer has been unable to discover how long
Negroes continued as members and worshippers. Miss Campbell reports that
some older Negro members continued to worship but no new ones joined.^'
The conclusion that the rentals ended in 1876 is based on the
Diaconate's decision, March 2, 1877, to place cards in the vestibules
and hotels announcing that the pew system "had been abolished and th^it
seats were not only free to all but that a cordial Christian welcome was
extended to the public generally."
The deacons had to be resourceful to manage. In 1868, they employed
a Negro Sexton, Edmond Wendell at $6.50 per month. In January 1869, they
employed Col. W. H. Blanch, a member, at $10.00 per month. In the spring
of 1871, they decided to reduce the pay in the spring and summer&#8212;presum-ably
because there were no fires, ashes, etc. When Colonel Blanch refused
to accept the reduction. Deacon Lewis Maney secured the service of another
Negro Sexton, S. Maney, who would accept $6.00 per month for April through
September and $10.00 per month for October through March. The deacons
regularly had to call on members to urge them to keep up their subscriptions
Presbyterian Church, Murfreesboro, Tenn
I &lt;&gt;/
The second home of First Presbyterian Church.
This building stood on the northeast corner of
Spring and College Streets until it was destroyed
by a tornado on March 21 , 1913.
Two Ministers
'fi-ip-
\^: -:*;.
Rev G \A/ Patterson,
1893 - 1901
Rev. E.A. Ramsey, D.D.
1 884 - 1 893
18b
19
When one pastor wrote urging the deacons to take more responsibility, they
responded that they were doing their best and suggested that Pastor and
Session put more emphasis on the spiritual responsibilities of stewardship.
There were some amusing items. The Church installed gas lighting
and sold its chandelier to another local Church. After about two years
a committee was appointed to confer with the other Church and suggest that
if it didn't want to pay the balance, it could return the chandelier and
receive its $40.00 back. Finally, it paid the $12.40 balance. There is
no explanation of whether the Diaconate rejected a proposal for lightning
rods for theological or financial reasons.
Church members and ministers might suspect that many boards have
"mule committees," but this Board of Deacons had both a "Mule Committee"
and a "Jack Committee." Evidently some one had given the Church a mule
and a jack. Since there are no earlier references, it has not been possi-ble
to determine how long it had owned the animals. When Dr. D. S. Knight
notified the deacons that he could no longer "accommodate the Jack of the
Church," committees were appointed to sell the two animals. In about six
months the committees secured $45.00 for the mule and $75.00 for the jack.
To return to a more serious vein, the Deacons' Minutes reveal other
things about the Church's activities. Although there was no explanation
as to why the street lamp was not lighted regularly, Dr. Murfree contracted
with the gas company--for 50(t per month--to light the street lamp in front
of the building on the nights when there were services. We learn that
there was a Ladies Society meeting on Wednesday afternoons as early as
November 1873, and a Young Men's Prayer Meeting on Thursday nights as
early as February 1874.
20
It may have seemed odd to a congregation which had one minister. Dr.
Eagleton, for thirty-seven years to have eight ministers and three stated
supplies in forty- three years. For seventeen of those years, the record
is limited to a few references in the Deacons' Minutes and the substitute
minute prepared to sunmarize the 1869-1885 volume of Session Minutes lost
in a fire.
The Reverend John W. Neil who led the congregation in reorganizing
and in building a new building resigned on June 4, 1871, to accept a call
to a Nashville church. Students can be especially grateful because Mr.
Neil is the reputed author of a sketch of the history of the Church to
1867.^^
The Reverend Henry Howard Banks of Asheville was called to the pas-torate
on September 17, 1871, and began his ministry in December. The
substitute minute recalled him as follows:
The Rev. H. H. Banks zealously entered upon his pastoral work
with great effectiveness and acceptability. Like David of old,
he was small of stature, and unprepossessing in appearance, but
armed with the Truths of the Gospel and inbued with the spirit
of the Master, he manfully fought against the Goliath of wick-edness.
Physically, he was feeble, yet he was earnest, diligent,
and faithful .... His sermons were replete with Biblical
Truths, elegant, learned and instructive, while his delivery
was earnest and forcible.
His health was so bad that in December 1873 the Session ". . . without
his solicitation granted him a leave of absence for six months--salary to
continue--in the hope that a rest from his labor would restore him to his
pristive vigor." The hope was in vain, and at the end of the leave, he
tendered his resignation. He died in Asheville a few years later.
The Reverend Dr. John Holt Rice served as Stated Supply Pastor from
December 1873 to October 4, 1874. The substitute minute expressed special
21
gratitude for the preaching of the Reverend Dr. J. B. West, Principal of
Soule College who "... preached to the congregation every Sabbath morn-ing
except when a visiting minister of our own denomination was with us."
In the spring of 1875, the congregation called the Reverend Henry
Sale Yerger from Palestine, Texas, and he began his ministry in June.
When the deacons wished to eliminate special offerings for benevolences
and apply all the funds to paying the debt, Mr. Yerger dissented and
requested the Diaconate to meet with the Session. Since those minutes
are not available we do not know how the issue was settled. When Mr.
Yerger tendered his resignation in the early fall of 1878, however, the
congregation declined to accept it. When Presbytery requested the con-gregation
to reconsider. It declared the pulpit vacant in October 1878.
On January 1, 1879, the Reverend Dr. John S. Arbuthnott, an English-man
who had been serving the Gallatin Church, was installed as Pastor.
The substitute minute recalled him as a very effective minister and active
In a revival beginning soon after his arrival and noted "... our church
received many additions." Dr. Arbuthnott tendered his resignation and the
pulpit was declared vacant August 9, 1883.
In January 1884, the Congregation issued a call to the Rev. G. S.
Finley of Romney, West Virginia, but he declined the call. Then it called
the Reverend John Martin Otts. The substitute minute summed up his service;
"... not seeing his way clear to accept the call, he compromised by
becoming a stated supply . . . [and] endeared himself to the whole con-gregation."
Mr. Otts served from May to September, when the Reverend Emmett
Alexander Ramsey began a six months term as stated supply on September 20,
22
1884. The Congregation was so pleased with him that it issued a call on
the second Sabbath of January 1885.
The Reverend Mr, Ramsey must have had boundless energy. He served
as superintendent of the Sunday School and it flourished, though he did
note a "scarcity of teachers" in 1886. He also preached at the Henderson
School House and at McClure's School House. Apparently, members were
included in the roll of First Presbyterian Church until there were enough
at "McClure's Chapel" to organize the Florence Presbyterian Church. On
October 15, 1893, eight members were dismissed to the new congregation.
After considering the idea for about four years, the Session decided
on a plan for elders to undertake responsibility for members and on Sep-tember
9, 1891, Mr. Ramsey assigned the responsibilities for families
living:
s. of Main and w. of Maney to Elders J. H. Allen and Charles Ordway
s. of Main and e. of Maney to Elders J. B. Murfree and W. Y. Elliott
n. of Main and w. of Maney to Elders Alex Hartman and Wm. Park
n. of Main and e. of Maney to Elders D. D. Wendel and S. H. Hodge
Earlier in 1891, Elders Murfree and Elliott had been appointed to
"consider the propriety of establishing a mission Sabbath School in the
western part of town in the suburb known as Riverside." On August 12, 1891,
the Session decided that the way did not seem clear.
Dr. Ramsey ministered to the whole community. One day he watched
the volunteer firemen at a fire and became so concerned that he took charge
and directed their efforts. The city fathers were impressed and asked him
to take charge officially. He conditioned his acceptance upon improvement
of the waterworks. The improvements were made, and he served as fire
chief until he accepted a call to the First Presbyterian Church of Memphis
in March 1893. He also served as chaplain of the First Regiment of the
Two viexA^s of the First Presbyterian Church following the tornado of
1913. The view of the interior is furnished courtesy of Mary Belle
Robinson, \A/hose father, J.W. Robinson made the photograph.
24
State Guard and accompanied the guardsmen when they were sent to Coal Creek
in the Cumberland Mountains because of a miners' strike.
No doubt, a bachelor minister&#8212;thirty-five when he came to Murfrees-boro--
aroused a good deal of interest in the community. He married Miss
Lena Wilhoite of Shelbyville just after accepting the call to Memphis,
but he died in less than five years. After his death, the Nashville
American recalled that, when he preached his final sermon in Murfreesboro,
the churchyard and street were filled with the overflow from the sanctu-ary
. ^ 3
Dr. George W. Patterson served the church from November 1893 to
April 1901. He was only twenty-seven when he and his wife came to
Murfreesboro and he appears to have been especially gifted in his work
with young people and in evangelism.'^
Some indication of interests and attitudes in the nineties may be
gleaned from minutes of the Session. In September 1891, the minister
named Elder William Park to the Committee on Publication and Colored
Evangelization. A presentation of the cause of Colored Evangelization
was authorized for the first Sabbath of April 1892. In May 1898, Elders
J. B. Murfree and W. E. Hudson were named "to look after" the Negro Sabbath
School begun by some of the ladies in the church, and in July, Dr. Murfree
reported that there were twenty-nine scholars and a need for Bibles and
educational literature.
The Session cancelled the evening worship service on the first
Sabbath in March 1893 in order to make the sanctuary available to local
Jewish citizens for services to be led by Rabbi Levinthall of Nashville.
Early in 1894, the Session declined to decide to participate in union
25
evangelistic services without full attendance, but it later decided to
participate and the services were held in the summer of 1894 with the
Reverend Gilbert Fife as evangelist.
In March 1899, a long effort to collect compensation for the build-ing
destroyed in the War was successful J^ On October 9, 1865 Dr. Eagleton
and the elders petitioned Major General George M. Thomas for $10,000 and
submitted affidavits estimating the cost of replacement at that figure,
stating that the building had been used as a hospital, commissary, and
barracks and had been destroyed while the Union Army controlled it. The
petition was referred to Captain E. B. Whitman, Chief Quartermaster, Dis-trict
of Middle Tennessee, and he made his report on December 28, 1865.
Captain Whitman admitted difficulty in getting information on the
points necessary for compensation. He concluded that while the building
was being used by the Amiy, woodwork had been removed by soldiers and
citizens, that the brick walls had later collapsed of their own weight or
been blown down; and that bricks had been taken by "soldiers to build
chimneys, and that citizens and officers of the Society removed others."
He added that the commander of the Post, Brigadier General Horatio Van
Cleve, "constantly used every effort in his power to protect and preserve
it from ruin." He judged the building as worth no more than $5,000, as
it stood, but estimated that it would cost $10,000 to build a modern
building of the same size.
On the critical question of the loyalty of the congregation, he was
much more positive. He insisted that the minister had preached treason
and rebellion and constantly prayed for God to foster the infant republic
and paralyze "the arm of the Federal government. ..." He believed that
26
most of those who signed the affidavits were "avowed rebels, or secret
sympathizers." He added that he could not judge the current attitudes but
had been informed that the few members who had been loyal to the Union had
left the congregation. He concluded that he did not believe the Church
qualified for compensation. His recommendation was approved by the Quar-termaster
General in Washington.
In February 1872, the Session and Diaconate addressed a petition to
Congress asking for compensation. The petition denied that the building
was burned or ruthlessly destroyed, insisting that it was used to care for
sick and wounded Federal soldiers, and that later the materials were used
for the comfort and benefit of the Army. It also insisted that "neither
Minister, Elders, Deacons nor any leading communicants . . . held office
or bore arms in the service of the Confederate Government."
Accompanying this petition was a set of specifications (six foolscap
pages in longhand) for a building "... in all respects the same as the
one occupied by the Presbyterian Congregation up to the late War." Bills
for compensation were introduced to Congress in 1872, 1876, and 1886. The
Claims Committee referred the matter to the Court of Claims. Lengthy
depositions were taken in Murfreesboro on August 27-28, 1890 and September
14, 1891.
On March 23, 1898 the Court of Claims reported to the Committee on
War Claims. The report indicated that there was no evidence of disloyalty
by the Church. It judged that the building was probably worth $6,500 at
the time it was seized. It pointed out that the law provided for compen-sation
only for the value of the materials and the evidence did not dis-close
the value of the materials. The opinion pointed out that it was not
deciding the case but submitting the facts for Congress.
27
A claims bill, including $6,500 "to the elders of the Presbyterian
Church at Murfreesboro," was signed on March 3, 1899.^^
On March 22, 1899, Attorney John Richardson met with the Session to
discuss "the claim recently allowed by Congress" and went over the contract
the Session and Diaconate had entered into with him in 1889. On July 21
the Session met, gave each elder an opportunity to suggest how the money
should be spent, and named a committee to report to a joint meeting of the
Session and Diaconate. On July 26, the deacons joined the Session. It
was announced that the net proceeds were $4,550. The Pastor read Psalm
103 and elders and deacons joined in prayer of thanksgiving and praise.
After considerable discussion on how to use the money, including
interest in providing a manse, it was decided to refurbish the building.
Windows were repaired and memorial windows were installed: one to Dr.
Ramsey and one to William Y. Elliott and Joseph Ewing. The portico was
enlarged, the interior redecorated and new pews and carpeting installed J7
The Reverend John G. Garth served the church from December 1901 to
October 1905. Perhaps the strongest evidence of congregational concern
was the purchase in June 1903 of six $50 shares in the Luebo Mission in
the Belgian Congo. When Mr. Garth left, the Reverend Dr. James W. Gray-bill,
a former medical missionary supplied the pulpit from February to
September 1906.
Dr. Graybill had declined a permanent call, and the Session, on
August 29, had called a congregational meeting to choose a pastor. Four
days later, it rescinded the call because it had received a letter from
Elder John T. Woodfin, Clerk of Session of the Murfreesboro Cumberland
Presbyterian Church, proposing a union of the two congregations.
28
The fellowship between the two congregations was of long standing.
The Cumberland Church had made its building available on numerous occas-ions.
Ministers of the two congregations had supplied either as the need
arose. The proposal, however, arose from the plan approved for uniting
the Cumberland Presbyterian Church and the Presbyterian Church U.S.A.--
generally known as the northern Presbyterian Church. Apparently, a sub-stantial
number of members preferred union with First Presbyterian, which
was part of the southern Presbyterian Church.
A joint committee from the two sessions worked out a plan which
involved First Presbyterian's calling the Cumberland minister, the Reverend
Reuben G. Newsome; electing all Cumberland officers to the same positions;
and continuing organizations of each congregation unless the organizations
decided to merge. The writer has not been able to locate the congregational
meeting minutes, but the union began on October 3, 1906. Miss Campbell
reports that the Reverend Mr. Newsome led the congregation from the
Cumberland building on the corner of Main and Spring. They came singing
"Leaning on the Everlasting Arms" and as they entered the sanctuary, the
two became one in song. On Wednesday night, October 13, Mr. Newsome was
formally installed.
Not only did the First Presbyterian Church receive Elders, A. J.
Patterson, J. T. Woodfin, A. C. Johnson, R. T. Bell, P. A. Lyon, E. J.
Raid and Deacons J. K. Poff, J. S. Nugent, Ross Nelson, and Charles
Cawthon, it received their families and a host of others who became
pillars of the congregation.
For several years there had been discussion of the need for a
"lecture room" and classrooms for the Sabbath School. Shortly after the
29
merger, an annex was added to the north side of the building. It included
a semi -circular basement room under the whole annex. The main floor was
a semi -circular assembly room with classrooms around the circumference.
There was a gallery around the assembly room with classrooms around its
circumference.
The Reverend Mr. Newsome resigned in March 1909 to accept a call to
the Tatnall Square Presbyterian Church, Macon, Georgia. In October 1909,
Reverend Dr. J. Addison Smith arrived from Richmond, Kentucky and began a
ministry that was cut short by his death in 1920, but he began a legend
that lives on even in the minds of those who never saw him but know him
because of their parents' affection and stories. ^^
Dr. Smith was erudite and eloquent but also entertaining. Apparently,
his prayers were especially memorable. For some years he wrote a column
"Musings Under the Maples" for the Christian Observer . We shall leave the
treatment of Dr. Smith's ministry for another time because this article
was planned to cover about a century and end with a bang: a tornado, better
known as the "Cyclone of 1913."
On the night of March 21, 1913, a tornado came bounding in from the
southwest, hitting the fairgrounds. South Walnut, the northwest corner of
the Square, First Presbyterian Church and points northwest. While parts
of the walls and a couple of the stained glass windows remained standing,
the roof had fallen through; the pews, rafters, bell, etc. lay in a pile
of rubble. The recently completed Sunday School annex suffered little
damage and could soon be used for services. The organ was not destroyed
and tradition has it that the organist played a hymn of praise amidst the
rubble. ^5 The congregation, however, could join Dr. Smith in gratitude
that there were no fatalities.
30
How the members picked up the pieces and began anew, for the second
time, Is another story.
31
NOTES
^Minutes of Session, Murfree Spring Presbyterian Church--later First
Presbyterian Church, Murfreesboro, Tennessee. These minutes are the source
for the bulk of the paper; citations will be limited to other sources.
Ralph M. Llewellyn, "Others Have Labored," an address at the sesquicentennial
of First Presbyterian Church, April 29, 1962. (Mimeographed.) This address
concentrates on the first two decades, the charter members and their descend-ants
who were members in 1962. Two additional member descendants have been
identified since then; Cecil Nelson Smotherman and Jane Smotherman LaPaglia,
descended from Elizabeth Kelton.
^Annie E. Campbell, "A History of the First Presbyterian Church,
Murfreesboro, Tennessee, 1811-1935," p. 2. (Typewritten.) Miss Campbell,
a life-long member of the congregation was a great granddaughter of the
minister from 1829-1866. Hence, she had access to the traditions of the
congregation as well as being a participant in part of what she described.
She will be cited as Campbell, though the writer is reluctant to refer to
"Miss Annie" in that way.
^Charles Grier Sellers, James K. Polk : Jacksonian , 1795-1843 (Princeton:
Princeton University Press, 19?7T7pp. TrT3, 59-61, 69-72, 76-79, 92-94.
^William Lytle to W. D. Baird, April 1, 1820, Book M, pp. 445-448,
Rutherford County Register's Office, Murfreesboro, Tennessee.
^Campbell, pp. 3-4; Congressional Jurisdiction Case 6575, Presbyterian
Church vs. U.S., Record Group Number 123, National Archives, Washington,
D.C.; ATTce N. Ray, "The State Capitol, 1819-1826," Rutherford County
Historical Society Publication 11 (Sumner 1978): 1-6. The Archives collec-tion
(hereinafter cited as C. J. Case 6575) contains hypothetical specifi-cations
prepared in 1872 and sworn depositions about the building, taken
in 1890 and 1891.
^[Murfreesboro] Courier , April 15, 1824.
^Ernest Trice Thompson, Presbyterians of the South : Volume One : 1607-
1861 (Richmond: John Knox Press), pp. 548-5457
Sjohnathan Currin, Trustee to William Eagleton, April 11, 1842, Book
Z, pp. 235-236, Rutherford County Register's Office, Murfreesboro, Tennessee.
^Alden B. Pearson, Jr., "The Tragic Dilemma of a Border-State
Moderate: The Rev. George E. Eagleton 's Views on Slavery and Secession,"
Tennessee Historical Quarterly XXXII (Winter 1973) :360-373.
l^The passage characterizing Mr. Neil is from a "Substitute Minute,"
prepared by Elders Alex Hartman, J. B. Murfree, and James Wendel to cover
the gap created when the Session Minute Book for 1869-1885 was lost in a
fire. It was entered in the minutes on October 15, 1888. Providentially
or by a remarkable coincidence, the only surviving Deacons' Minute Book
before 1918 covers the years 1867-1888. Most of what follows to 1888 is
based on these two sources.
32
1'' Campbell, p. 13.
^^This four page single-spaced sketch was copied by Miss Annie Campbell
from a newspaper article preserved in her mother's scrap-book.
13campbell, pp. 17-19; Nashville American , January 14, 1898.
l^Campbell, pp. 19-21.
ISjhere are very few references in the minutes, but C. J. Case 6575
provides documentation of the thirty-four year effort, summarized in these
six paragraphs.
"&#8226;^U.S. Statutes at Large . Vol. 30, Chap. 426 (1899).
17campbell, p. 20.
18"Two Mighty Oaks" is a reminiscence of Dr. Smith and of Dr. J. B.
Murfree, an elder in the church. It is Chapter 10 of Elisabeth 0. Howse
[Ridley], Falling Stars (Murfreesboro: Mrs. G. S. Ridley, 1960), pp. 126-
134. The writer would welcome stories about Dr. Smith to add to the store
he is trying to record.
l^The writer has not been able to determine whether the stained glass
windows were saved and used in the new building. Any clues from readers
would be appreciated.
</dc:description>
<dc:description>A history of Murfreesboro's First Presbyterian Church from its founding in 1812 until a devastating Murfreesboro tornado in 1913 destroyed much of the building</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Historic buildings; Murfreesboro (Tenn.) -- History; Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A.</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Churches, First Presbyterian Church; Tornado, 1913</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>63 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-01; mt2011-05-20</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication14ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/72</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>