<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>The year 1981 in Rutherford County</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Goode, Cathy</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 19</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1982</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1980-1989</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>THE YEAR 1981 in RUTHERFORD County
by
Cathy Good&#169;
JANUARY
A public meeting was held in Smyrna by the state Department
of Transportation concerning the proposed route of an access road from
1-24- to the new Nissan plant. The two proposed routes suggested by the
Department of Transportation were met with disapproval from local residents,
and no formal action concerning the road was taken at this time.
The Rutherford County Board of Commissioners approved a resolution
to recommend that+ the County support a Duty-free Trade Zone.
To be located near the Nissan plant site, the area would be a sub-zone
of the trade base zone planned in Nashville.
Wherry Housing Action Committee has proposed to form a co-operative
and rehabilitate the County owned housing units on the former
Sewart Air Base in Smyrna. Wherry could become the State's first converted
co-operative community.
Heritage Farms Dairy is under construction in Murfreesboro.
The Dairy is Kroger Company's milk processing plant, and all milk will
be procured within a 100 mile radius of Murfreesboro, Tentatively
scheduled to open in August, the Dairy will employ 85 persons.
1^3
Construction has begun on the new livestock pavilion &#176;t KTv'tTT.
Dedication ceremonies will be held in early August. The Tennessee'-e Live-stock
Pavilion is located on +he MTSU campus. Among^ the features are a
heated show ring^, hog pens, space to tie 4^0 head of cattle, a portable
raised sale ring and a nearby horse ring.
A new Smyrna elementary school is under construction on Sam
Davis Road. The school will have an ultimate enrollment of 9OO students
and is expected to be completed March 19f^?.
President Carter signed into law the National Historic Preservation
Amendments Act of 19^0 ?ind the Tax Treatment Extension Act of 19*^0.
The new bill supersedes The National Historic Preservation Act of 1966.
FEBRUARY
Ground-breaking ceremonies were held on February 3, 19^1 for
the new Nissan truck plant, Dignitaries attending the ceremonies included
Marvin Runyon, President of Nissan Motor Manufacturing Corp., U. S. A.,
Nissan Ltd. Executive Vice-President Masataka Olnjma, Governor Lamar
Alexander and Smyrna Mayor Sam Ridley.
The University of Tennessee Press has published "Stone's River:
Bloody Winter in Tennessee" by James Lee McDonough.
Murfreesboro Cable TV and Rutherford Cable TV will begin to
expand their services to County residents.
124
Middle Tennessee Electric Membership Cooperative announced
construction of a substation in Smyrna on the old Air Base property.
The Stones River Guardian, a new weekly newspaper has begun
publication.
MARCH
The Eagleville Bicentennial Public Library which is currently
located in the old City Hall and Jail is raising; funds +x) build a Library
and Community Center.
Developers unveiled plans for a luxury condominium complex on
East Main Street in Murfreesboro, the complex will be named Childress
Court in honor of Sarah Childress Polk.
Construction h&#171;^s begun on the access rail line to the new
Nissan plant, According to the State Department of Transportation, t^
tunnel will be built \under Highway ^-l -705 and the access line will run
from the current L ^- N line to the rail yard planned ^t the Nissan site.
Plans were announced for a new Fire Hall and elevated water
storage tank to be built in Smyrna. Located on property southeast o^
the city, the Fire Hall and storage tank would serve both the city and
the Nissan plant.
A new entryway to the VA Hospital on Highway 231 was completed
this year. The old entrance was constructed in 193^, and the new entry-way
will provide a safer entrance and exit from the Hospital grounds.
125
Rutherford County Utility District announced plans for a new
water plant. The facility will be located at the intersection of the
East and West Forks of the Stone's River near Old Jefferson Road and
will draw water from Percy Priest Lake. Construction will take approximately
two years.
AmiL
Construction has begun on the first phase of Georgetown Square,
a 12B acre residential development in Murfreesboro located off West North-field
Bird, and Georgetown Square. Ground-breaking ceremonies were held
in March.
Dedication ceremonies for the new nature trail and Park at
Oakland s were^ held this month.
Kentucky Pried Chicken in Smyrna moved into their n'=^w facility
in early April Local civic and business leaders attended the ribbon
cutting ceremony.
MAY
The Tennessee Agricultural Museum at the Ellington Agricultural
Center in Nashville has been opened to the public. The museum contains
primitive agricultural machinery and hundreds of other objects from our
rural past. The Tennessee Agricultural Hall of Fame is also housed h^
the Museum and honor men who have made substantial contributions to
fanning in the state.
126
A new water storage tank is under construction on top of
Shiloh's Hill in Murfreesboro . The tank will hold 3 million gallons
of water and will aid the City in stored water supply in case of a
water shortage.
Sponsored by the Arts an^ Humanities Council o^ Murfreesboro
and Rutherford County, a Street Festival was held this month. Consisting
of 76 different booths, the attractions varied from arts and crafts to
entertainments and pr-motions of local organizations.
JUNE
Rutherford County's Judicial Offices will begin this month to
move into the new Judicial Building located on the West side of the Square,
The building will house two General Sessions courtrooms, two Chancery
courtrooms and a Circuit courtroom.
Ramo, Inc. announced plans to build a machine-gun factory in
Smyrna. Currently located in Davidson County, the new facility will be
built underground with solar heating.
Mrs., Jean MacArthur, a native of Murfreesboro, received the
History Award from the local chapter of the DAR. The Colonel Hardy
Murfree*^ Chapter presented the award to Mrs. MacArthur for her outstanding
contributions to American history. Also honored was astronaut
Rhea Seddon Gibson, a native of Murfreesboro.
Sponsored by the Necedah Bow Hunting Club, a five acre hunting
course has been opened to the public. The archery range is located be
127
between the Poole Knobs Recreation Area and the Percy Priest Wildlife
Management Area. The course consists o^ 14 targets and is about one
mile long.
JULY
Smyrna's first radio station, WSVT, will begin broadcasting
this month. The Station will cover all of Rutherford and most of David-son
and Williamson Counties, as well as part of other Middle Tennessee
counties.
The Industrial Development Board approved a bond package for
a metal fabrication plant. Quality Metal Products Co. Inc. plans to
build at a site on Waldron Road in LaVergne.
On June ?1 , 1981, after 5 years of planning, the twinning of
LaVergne, Prance and LaVergne, Tennessee occurred in Southern Prance.
Mayor A. C. Rickett of LaVergne headed the group which also included 5
LaVergne^ youth and several local citizens. In addition to the twinning
ceremony a tree -planting ceremony was held by both Mayors.
Uncle Dave Macon Days were held on July 10 &#8226;^ 11. A motor less
parade was held through downtown\.m Murfreesboro, Banjo, fiddle, ^guitar and
string band competitions all paid tribute to tie native of Rutherford
County,
Stone's River National Battlefield was host for a Civil War
living history encampment. The reconstructed historical Union campsite
128
also featured several demonstrations of how to ^ire a cannon. "Soldiers"
from Kenesaw Mountain, Ga. and Chickamauga National Battlefield also participated
along with several who cooked meals on the campground.
Hardee's, the newest restaurant in Smyrna has opened. Located
in the Smyrna Square Shopping Center, the restaurant will have a staff
of 30 and a seating capacity of 90 person*.
AUGUST
The County Industrial Bond Board approved an inducement contract
with Capitol Air, one of the fastest growing air carriers in the nation.
Capitol now occupies 9 buildings and U trailers on the old Smyrna Air
Base. The Company would like to construct an office building to consolidate
all its personnel.
The Bond Board also recommended a bond issue with United Bolt
and Screw Co. of Dearborn, Michigan which plans to build a plant on Salem
Pike in Murfreesboro near Heritage Farms Dairy.
SEPT'JIBER
Citizens Central Bank has announced plans to move from their
existing branch office on Lowry S+. in Smyrna at the corner of Enon Springs
Road and Highway 'l-'^OS.
Commerce Union Bank of Rutherford County announced plans to
open a branch office in Smyrna.
129
Granny White's Kitchen opened in Laverne.
The U. S. Postal Service announced their decision the locate
the new Murfreesboro Post Office on South Church St.
A new fire service has been formed in the County. The Ruther-ford
County Fire Department, staffed by volunteers, will replace the past
Civil Defense operations.
Dedication ceremonies for the Rutherford County Judicial
Building were held September 13, 1 9^1
.
OCTOBER
Two Murfreesboro developers has purchased the old Home Journal
Building on West Main St. and plan to turn it into/j office condominiums.
The building? was constructed in the 192'^'3 and held the bi-weekly news-paper.
The Home Journal which -as the predecessor to the Daily News Journal.
NOVEMBER
Sponsored by Historic Middle Tennessee Association and Murfreesboro-
Rutherford County Chamber of Commerce, 2"^ Nashville tour brokers
Participated in a special tour of the County, its historical sites and
other points of interest. The Chamber of Commerce hopes that this social
tour will encourage tour groups from Nashville to visit the County.
Results of the Smyrna City Election are as follows:
130
Sam Ridley Mayor
Sam Griffin Commissioner of Health and Public Safety
Frank Johns Commissioner of Taxes and Revenue
Paul Johns Commissioner of Pire, Police and Parks
Kenneth Victory Commissioner of Justice
</dc:description>
<dc:description>Presents an account of prominent happenings in Rutherford County month-by-month from January to November 1981, as well as results of county elections</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.); Local elections -- Tennessee</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>9 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-08;mt2011-02-22</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication19ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/55</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>