<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>William, Robert and Nathaniel Overall, pioneer settlers at the Bluff</dc:title>
<dc:creator>McGee, Lula Virginia Ramsey</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 10</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1908; 1978</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>16th century; 17th century; 18th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>78
William, Robert and Nathaniel Overall, Pioneer
Settlers at the Bluff
Copied from a handwritten report by: Lula Virginia Ramsey Mc'C!e(\
Jackson, Tennessee, February, 1908.
The Overalls were of Saxon origin. The first of whom we have any
knowledge was George Overall, who settled in Thuxted, Essexslii I'c, I'lngland
during the reign of Henry the Eighth. He died in 15 61 leaving two sons,
William and John. John was born in 1559 and died at Noi-wich in Kil!). IIi&gt;
was educated at Johns College but later went to Trinity Colicgt' wIum^' he
became noted for his piety and great learning. Dr. Overall becann' Dean of
St. Pauls in London in 1601 and at the Hampton Court Meeting held by King
James the First in 1604 was the second man chosen of the fifty appointed
by the King James to translate the Bible. As everyone knows this Js llie
King James Version used for almost three hundred years. Dr. John Overall
wrote much^but his best known work was his Convocation Book. Di-. Ovei-all
was made Bishop of London in 1614 and died five years later in 1619.
There are many Overalls in England at the present time; and all both
in England and America, are descended from the same English stock. Many
claim descent from Bishop Overall, but others say that all in both countries
are descended from his elder brother William.
The Overalls came to America in 1698 settling in Prince William and
Stafford Counties, Virginia. William Overall of Stafford County, Vii'giiiia
had four sons, Jolin, William, Nathaniel and Robert. John went to
Frederick County, Virginia and married Sara Jane Froman. Their old
homestead is now a railroad station and post office called Overall, though
since the divisions made of the old Frederick County, it is now in Page
79
County. The old place is still occupied by one of the name. Miss Ilarriol
Overall.
John and Sara Jane Overall had four sons and throe daughters- J olm,
William, Nathaniel, Robert, Mary, Nancy, and Christina. Of these seven^
only John remained in Virginia, the others all coming to TennesHcc-. John
married Elizabeth Waters^ and they had three sons; Abraham, Isaac, and
Jacob. Two of these, Abraham and Jacob^ came to Tennessee in J 304.
Isaac remained in Virginia^ and his descendants live in Washington,
Philadelphia and Virginia.
William Overall went from Virignia to the Watauga settJemont in East
Tennessee^ and we find his name among those who signed the petition for
annexation to North Carolina^ which bore no date but was i-eceived in Ualejgh
in 1776.
t
When James Robertson set out from Watauga for the Cumberland to
found a settlement in a fairer land, he was accompanied by seven oIIkm-white
men. These were George Freeland, William Neely, James llanly,
Mark Robertson, Edward Swanson, Zachariah White and William Overall.
They left Watauga in the early spring of 1779 and reached the CumbcM-land
on Christmas Day. They made a crop of corn that summer near where
Nashville now stands. After the corn was made. Overall, Swanson and
White were left to keep the buffaloes from the corn, while the others
returned to Watauga with Robertson for their families and to induce others
to come with them that they might have a strong colony to make defense
against the savage foe when they would attack their forts. How fearless
must have been these three who remained in the wilds alonel
80
They were not molested during this time, but during the battle at the
Bluff, White was killed by the Indians and Swanson had an extremely narrow
escape; and many years after the 1794 Overall was Hlle^ bv this i^-'- -&#8226;hr::. '&#8226;^.&#8226;
fought against so long and bravely.
Surely braver men have never lived than these Tennessee pioneers.
Gilmore in his "Advance Guard of Western Civilization", says "Nothing
more heroic is recorded of these people than the migration of three hundred
and eighty of their number from Watauga into the wilds of West Tennessee
under the lead of James Robertson in the winter of 1780. " Every name
should be rescued from oblivion and placed among the names of the heroes
of our Volunteer State.
They must have realized to some extent that they were laying the
foundation stones to a great commonwealth for Robertson is said to have
explained to Sevier when the latter was trying to persuade him to remain
at Watauga, "We are the advance guard of civilization and our way is across
the continent ." From this utterance, Gilmore must have obtained the title
for that intensely interesting book^ "Advance Guard of Western Civilization .
"
Robertson returned to Watauga by the Kentucky trace as before, the
journey extending from November the first 1779 to Christmas Day. They
began at once erecting the fort and ten log houses at French Lick as to have
them in readiness for their families. This was the beginning of our fair
Capital City.
The women and children were coming by the long river route under
the leadership of John Donelson and a guard of thirty men. These women
and children numbered one hundred and thirty, ready to share the dangers
and toils and brighten the new homes for fathers and brothers and husbands.
Their trip by the Holstoru Tennessee , Ohio and Cumberland rivers took
four months and was attended by many dangers aThirty three perished by the
way. This journey has no parallel in^he hJ..'^ ;.o -7 o" ca.'- :"&#8226;'.
Among the several hundred returning with Robertson and his i^ai'ty lo
the Cumberland settlement were William Overall 's two bi'othcrs, Nathaniel
and Robert and the Thomas brothers, John and Joshua. The Thomas and
Overall families became closely connected by marriages. William Ovcu-all
married Susanna Thomas, sister to John and Joshua. NathanieJ OvimmII
married Annie Thomas^ another sisterj and Nancy Overall, sis1(.M- of ihc
three Overalls, married Joshua Thomas. There were two other Overall
sisters'. Mary who married James Espy, and Christina who mari-ied a \1r.
Williams and moved to South Carolina. Within a few months after their
arrival at the Bluff early in 1780, Robert Overall was killed by Indians.
Joshua Thomas was killed during the Nickajack expedition, the only m.u^
killed in that raid; William Overall was killed in 1794; and James i'-lspy.
while Sheriff of Sumaer County. These were the sorrows the Indians
caused these families. Indeed few there were, if any, but experienced at
some time a like tragedy. It is said that, "from 1780 to 1794 they killc^d
within seven miles of Nashville one person in about every ten days. "
Robert Overall was never married. Overall's Creelv, a beaLitifLit
stream in Rutherford County, was named for him. William Overall li;itl
l^een a noted Indian fighter since the foundation of the colony. He was in
the battle at the Bluff and many other encounters with the Indians. lie;
left a family of four sons and one daughter.
Nathaniel Overall died in 1835 and his wife, Annie Thomas Overall,
died in 1844. He was in the battle at the Bluff, April 2nd 1781. when about
seven hundred Indians attacked the fort, which at this time had only thirty-five
men to defend it, some being away to protect other forts. Annie Thomas
was in the fort during this battle and helped to mould bullets and otherwise
assist the men in defense of their lives. She delighted in after years to tell
her children and grand children the thrilling accounts of those perilous times
and of how the women and girls so bravely assisted the men, moulding bullets
even at times taking a man's place at the port holes.
We need not search outside our own state annals to find examples of
the finest heroism. These men were as true patriots as those nearer the
coast who had battled with another enemy to gain freedom for their land.
These had a cruel and treacherous enemy to deal with and their families
were in greater personal danger. Many of these pioneers had been Revo-lutionary
soldiers too, in North Carolina and Virginia, and their lands on
the Cumberland represented the pay they had received for their services.
Nathaniel and Annie Thomas Overall had eight childreni Mary,
Robert, Nace, John, Sally, Abraham, Lorenzo Dow, and James.
Mary, called Polly, was born in 1783 and died in 1849. She married
William Ramsey, Jr. in 1805 and they had ten children. The father of
William Ramsey was William Ramsey, Sr. a native of Mecklenburg County,
North Carolina and a Revolutionary soldier and came to Tennessee just
after the close of the war. William Ramsey, Jr. died in Aug. 1833. Their
oldest child was Eliza who married Wm. Mathes and reared a large family.
The second child was perhaps Ann who married John McKee. She reared
five or six children. The third was Nathaniel Jefferson who married Frances
Young Davis of Davis County, Kentucky. Nathaniel Jefferson Ramsey was
born March 3, 1809 and died June 28, 1871. Frances Young Davis was l^orn
March 16, 1812 and died February 25, 1862. They reared five children;
their eldest^Polly Ann dying in infancy, 2nd William Baxter; 3rd Nathaniel
Preston; 4th Vibella; 5th John Wesley; 6th Ava Amelia. These five all
married and reared families. The fourth child was William Franklin who
married Nancy Knox. They had ten children: George W. H. , James W. J.. ,
David A. K. , B. F. , Granville J. , M.S.T., Robert N. , Daniel B. , Sarah
E. , N. Emilie, Emma J. , and G. F. The fifth child was Nace Preston who
married Polly Ann Davis of Davis County, Kentucky. They reared four sons
and five daughters: Greenville Henderson, Thomas Joiner, Robert Newton,
Mary Frances, William Davis, Gorilla, Rachel Leona, Sophronia and Ira.
The sixth child was Sarah Lucretia who was born March 16, 1815 and died
June 21, 1870. She married first William Elder and had one daughter, Martha,
and two sons, John Summerfield and James Monroe. These all died unmar-ried.
The seventh child was Nancy B. who was born May 16, 1816 and died
D ec. 30, 1891. She married John C . Berry and they had twelve children:
Mary E lizabeth, James L . , Parthenia, Martha Jane, Sallie E . Tennie C. ,
Texas A. , Aurelia, William Robert, Vitula F . , Lucy A . and the 12th died
in infancy. The eighth child was Blackmon Asbury born Soptembcf 20, 1818
and died March 25, 1891. He married Eliza Jett and they had four sons
and tnree daughters. The daughters all married and reared families, but
the sons died when small. The daughters were: Mary Alice, Eliza
Josephine and Susan Ella. The ninth child was Martha who married
Daniel Waddley. They had one daughter Martha who died young. The
tenth child was Pauline Jane who was born April 15, 1825 and died April
22, 1884. She married first Albert Kelly and had two sons William D. and
Albert. She married second Smith, and third Rev. George Johnston.
The second child of Nathaniel and Annie Thomas Overall was Robert
who was born June 11, 1785 and died in 1862. He married his cousin Mary
Espy^and they had twelve children .
The third child of Nathaniel and Annie Overall was Nace. He married
Amelia Davis of Davis County, Kentucky. Nace Overall was a MelhodJsl
Minister, as were two of his brothers. He had three sons and four daughters:
Baxter, Lee Ann, Nathaniel Webb, Robert A., Mary Frances, Elizabeth
and Vistula. Rev. Nace Overall and three of his nephews married sisters.
These were the daughters of Baxter and Mary (Webb) Davis of Davis County,
Kentucky. James G. Overall, son of Robert and Mary (Espy) Overall mar-ried
Rachel Webb Davis; Nace Preston Ramsey, son of William and Polly
(Overall) Ramsey married "Polly" Ann Davis; Nathaniel Jefferson Ramsey,
son of William and Polly Overall Ramsey, married Frances Young Davis.
Perhaps all were of the same type of womanhood as the writers grandmother,
Fanny Davis, a gentle, lovely. Christian, who lived with a song and died
with shouts of praise on her lips. Never having seen her, yet her grand-children
appreciate her influence, and will ever cherish the record of her
life.
"She reaps as she sowed
Lo, this man is her son. "
Two of her sons were ministers and the other and his sisters repeated in
their lives the qualities of their sainted mother and father.
Nathaniel Jefferson Ramsey was born in Rutherford County, Tennessee,
March 3, 1809 and died in Gibson County, Tenn. June 28, 1871. Francos
Young (Davis) Ramsey was born in Davis Co.^ Ky. June 10, 1812 and died in
Gibson Co.^ Tenn. Feb. 25, 1862. They were married August 15, 1828 and
had six children ; Polly Ann (born Sept. 20, 1829, died May 24, 18:;o),
William Baxter (born Feb. 15, 1831, died July 14, 1865), Nathaniel Preston
(bornDec. 22, 1833, died Mar. 13, 1895). Vibella P . (born Aug. 27, 1838,
died Dec. 6, 1871) , John Wesley (born Oct. 7, 1840, died Nov. 4, 1901), Ava
Amelia (born Aug. 16, 1843-yet living NOTE; THIS WAS WRITTI':N IN 1908).
William Baxter married Mary Winfrey Askew^and they had two children:
Henry H. Ramsey (now living at Dawson Springs, Ky. ) and Willie Etta Ramsey,
who died at age thirteen.
Nathaniel Preston Ramsey married three times: first Callie McConnel,
and had one son, Alney Winfrey (born 1862 died 1903) ; second Judith Demaris
Waddy, and had three sons and three daughters^ Robert Waddy, Jefferson
(both living in Memphis Tenn.), Eugene Duncan (living at Clinton, Ky),
Mary Clark (married S. H. Mann and living at Forrest City, Ark. ), Frances
Davis (married Clayton Porter and living Clinton, Ky. ), and Gertrude Mahon
(married living in Baltimore, Md.); third N. P. Ramsey married
Mattie Holmes Waddy. She lives at Clinton, Ky.
Vibella P. Ramsey married Elisha F. Askew and had three children:
Emma, Ava and David.
John Wesley Ramsey married Victoria M. Heard, Jan. 3, 1866. She
was born June 21, 1846, now living in Bedford Co. , Tenn. , at Trenton.
Their children were: Lula Virginia, the writer of this sketch (she married
W. B. McGee of Trenton, Tenn.);Wm. Walter who married Jonm.' Robbins
of Jackson, Tenn. and now lives in Racine, Wise. ; Katharine J'lwc^l 1 Ilainsc^y;
Frances Irene (who married Herbert N. Davis and lives at Trenton, Tenn. ):
Minnie Lee (who married Homer S. Lain and lives at Trenton, Tenn. ); Tommic
Heard (who married Edwin E. Russell of Racine, Wise, and now lives in
Paris, France; Martha Davis (who married Webb H. Herl)ert and lives at
Ruston, La. )
John Wesley Ramsey was a loyal Confederate soldier, sei'vin.o; the four
years of the war. He was an honest upright hristian, beloved by a 1
1 who
knew him. To no man could words be more fitting- -"His life was gentJe,
and the elements so mixed in him that nature miight stand up and say 1o all
the world. This was a man. "
AvaA. Ramsey married J. W. Phillips. Their children died yoimg
except two daughters: lone married J. D. Wrather, :.-vl Doro^ &#8226;
Joyner.
William Ramsey, Jr. who married "Polly" Overall was born in
Alecklenburg County, North Carolina, the date not known to the writer and
died August, 1833 in Rutherford County, Tennessee. He was a Methodist
minister and a very consecrated ": ristian. His father, William Ramsey.
Sr.j was also a native of Mecklenburg County, North Carolina. \\v stM-ved
three years in the Revolutionary War coming to Tennessee just after the
close of the war. The father of William Ramsey, Sr. whose name is not
known to the writer was one of that large company of Scotch- Irish wJio came
from North Ireland by way of Pennsylvania to North Carolina and other
Southern colonies before the Revolutionary War. His sons whose names
are known to the writer were: William, Robert, John, David, James and
daughters, Anne, Maria and Polly.
The fourth child of Nathaniel and Annie Thomas Overall was John who
married a Miss McLin. Some of their descendants live in Gibson County,
Tenn.
The fifth child of Nathaniel and Annie Thomas Overall was Sally who
married John Doak and moved to Texas. She was born September 15, 1800.
The sixth child of Nathaniel and Annie Thomas Overall was Abraham
who married a Miss White. He was a Methodist minister of some note.
His descendants live in Rutherford County, Tenn.
The seventh child of Nathaniel and Annie Thomas Overall was Lorenzo
Dow, born July 8, 1802, a noted Methodist minister and one of the founders
of McKendree Church, Nashville. He died unmarried.
'The eighth child of Nathaniel and Annie Thomas Overall was James^
who married Lucy Butler. Their descendants live in Tipton County,
Tennessee.
Thus we see that three of the sons of Nathaniel and Annie Overall were
ministers, and if any of their descendants have been a dishonor to the name,
it is not known to the writer. That she is able to relate so little of these
brave noble ancestors and Cumberland pioneers, Nathaniel and Annie
Overall, the writer regrets exceedingly; but those who have heard those
thrilling accounts of Indian attacks and slaughter and those tales of pioneer
life, have passed away and left us no written accounts of these things. But
it is with pride we may name them for their courage, their patriotism,
their refinement, their gentle blood, and best of all, for those finer
qu-ilities characteristic of the disciples of the Savior of men.
Lula Vir.iinia ;ia::.Eey ]'.c^&gt;cu
Jackson, Tennessee
February, 1908
Two books have been written on the Overall Family. The first by
^:r.'^. T. 0. Kiger, ^029 Sunbeam Avenue, Chattanooga, Tennessee 37^11
contains about $00 pages and sells for :^15.00. In a letter from Vr,
Eakin Overall, he states that the article by Fxs. Virginia Ramsey
Kcaee on the Overall Family contains two errors. "John Overall Jr.
m:.\rried Kiiria Christa Froman, not Sara Jane"; also, "Eishop Overall
and his wife had no children."
The second book is by Krs. F. Earl Brltton, 133 Kingwood
Drive, Chattanooga, Tennessee 37^12 and is on the family of William
Jefferson Overall. It contains about 250 pages and costs 515.00.
A copy of this book is in the Tennessee Room at Linebaugh Library.
</dc:description>
<dc:description>Printed copy of a handwritten report written by the author in 1908</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>pioneers</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>21 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-16</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication10ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/104</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>