<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Petition of Michael Lorance of Rutherford County for a Revolutionary War pension</dc:title>
<dc:contributor>Lorance, Michael; Herriage, Peggy</dc:contributor>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 11</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1833; 1978</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1830-1839</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>31
PETITION OF MICHAEL LORANCE OF RUTHERFORD COUNTY
FOR A REVOLUTIONARY WAR PENSION
Furnished by Mrs. Peggy Herriage
Pilot Point, Texas
State of Tennessee
Circuit Court, April Term, 1833
Rutherford County
On this 6th day of April, 1833, before James C. Mitchell, one of the Circ\iit
Courts of the State of Tennessee now sitting at Murfreesborough for said
County of Rutherford, personally appeared in open court Michael Lorance,
resident of said county of Rutherford &amp; state aforesidd, aged eighty-three
years, who being first duly sworn according to law, doth on his oath, make
the following declaration in order to obtain the benefit of the act of
Congress passed June 7th, 1832.
That he entered the service of the IMited States, about the month of
Jvme 1780, immediately after the battle of Ramsours, in a volunteer conqpany
which went in pursuit of Col. Brytint tAo had collected a coii?)any of Tories
on the ladkln River in North Carolina. The company of whiggs started from
Third Creek, a branch of the Yadkin, thence down to the Pedee River, thence
returned home. Bryant made his retreat into South CaroLlna. ^plicant can
not recollect the names of his officers in this piirsuit of Col. Bryant, in
^t^ch he served at least one month.
About the month of September 1780 shortly after Gates' defeat, he
again entered seirvice under Col, Davis in Capt. Joseph Dickson's company.
He believes the regiment contained about five con?)anieB. He remembers Cap-tains
Coldwell and Cowen. They rendezvoused about 3 miles below Salisbury,
North Carolina, thence they marched to Charlotte, Mecklenburgh County, thence
to Six Miles Creek where they remained a few days, thence to the Waxaw
settlement in South Carolina, and remained there about two weeks. The Brit-ish
under Cornwallis had left Charlotte a few days before Col. Davis arrived
there and made their way through the Waxaw settlement to Gampden. The
Americans returned home. In this canpaign. Applicant served at least two
months
.
Sometime in Febniary 1781, soon after Morgan had defected Tarlton,
he again entered service again at Batie's Ford on the Catawba River, North
CarolinK under Gen. Davidson in Capt. Cowen'e company. From Batie's Ford,
they marched down to Cowen' s Ford where Gen. Davidson was killed in opposing
the pasjage of the British under Cownwallis. The Amsricans were scattered
at this place &amp; collected again above Second Creek where they destroyed a
bridge to prevent the crossing of the British. The British came to the
place &amp; were fired upon by the Americans. The British went below &amp; crossed
the creek at some ford. The Americans were again dispersed. Under Generals
Davidson and Locke opposing Cornwallis' pursuit after Morgan^ applicant
served at least three weeks.
32
About the first of April, 1781, applicant again entered service under
John Read, Capt,, Daniel Carter, Lieutenant, in Rowan County, North Carolina,
thence they marched to the Congaree River in South Carolina where they
joined Gen, Sumpter in Col. Wade Hajopton's regiment, thence to Orangeburgh
then in possession of the eneny. The British fired on the Americans as they
approached the town, but soon surrendered as prisoners to Sunqpter to the
nvunber of 100 or 150 men. From Orangeburgh the Americans marched in the
direction to Ninety Six, got in three or four miles of that place, when an
express arriving that Gen. Green had left Ninety Six. They changed their
course, crossed Bread River at the fish deun ford, joined Gen. Green. Ap-plicant
then recrossed at the ford with a detachment of about fifty men
under Maj. Rutherford, march in direction to Ninety Six to Saluda River,
thence down the Saluda on one side, while a party of the British marched
down on the opposite side. The Americans crossed the Saluda about two miles
above its mouth, made a circuit and surrounded the eneny at the head of the
Congaree where they made forty or fifty prisoners. Thence they returned to
Sumpter on the Congaree, Joined Green &amp; went down to the Eutaw Springs where
the battle was fought well known in history.
Then applicant under Maj, Moore went to Georgia, swam their horses
across the Savannah about 3 miles below Augusta, thence down to Ebenezer
&amp; Joined Col White, thence down towards Savannah then in possession of the
British. They ranged in the neighborhood of Savannah about three months
but without any engagement. In this campaign applicant served ten months
at least. In all the service aforesaid, he served as a private.
Applicant never received any xjritten discharge from service, and knows
of no person living by whom he could prove his service, nor has he any docu^
mentary evidence whatever to prove the same.
In the several caaqjaigns before mentioned, he was a volunteer, never
seirved except as a private &amp; was always in the cavalry and furnished a horse.
Applicant represents that on account of palsy &amp; inability to speak
the English language intelligibly together with old age &amp; defect of memory,
he fears the circumstances of his services, their duration, &amp; the names of
more of his officers are not so fully set out as the rules of the War De-partment
require. He believes that he served several months longer than he
has stated above. But he could not precisely state the length of his ser-vices
&amp; thereupon does not claim a pension for more than the services before
stated amounting in all to one year, one month, &amp; three weeks to which he
can saXely swear.
As to hla character for veracity &amp; their belief of his services as
a soldier of the revolution, applicant refers to his present neighbors Nace
Overall, Robert Overall, Williaa Northcut, Jordan Williford, Arthur Totty,
Robert Thompson, &amp; James Tucker, to all of whom he is well known &amp; who can
testify as to his character for veracity &amp; their belief of his seinrices
aforesaid.
Applicant was bom in Germany on the 18th of November 17^9, as
appeared from his father's record which applicant brought to America with
him &amp; lost it during the Revolutionary War. Applicant lived in Germany
until he was about twenty-eight years old, when he was sent with a regiment
of Germans over to America to aid the British in subduing their colonies.
33
He landed in New York on Staten Island 3rd of Juno 1777, remained in the
British service about one year, deserted them in Rhode Island, escaped over
to Gen. Sullivan's army as a deserter made himself Imovm to Sullivan who
permitted him to pass on to Pennsylvania, He cade his way to Spring Houoo
Tavern 18 miles from Philadelphia whore he resided 1C ncntho ao a barkeeper.
Thence he moved to Rowan Goimty, North Carolina in 1780 whore ho rooidcd
about seven years &amp; where he was residing when he entered the sorvico of
the United States. The County of Iredell v;as in tho ncantimo laid off &amp;
comprehended his residence. Thence he moved to Mecklenburgh County, North
Carolina, where he lived until the year 1812 when he coved to Rutherford
County, Tennessee where he has ever since &amp; now resides
,
He hereby relinquishes every claim whatever to a pension or annuity
except the present, and declares that his name is not on tho pension roll
of any of the agency of any state or territory.
Sworn to and subscribed the his
day and year aforesaid. Michael X Lorance
s/Win. ? nark
Clerk
We Nace Overall, a clers^nan and Jordan Williford both residing in the
County of Rutherford &amp; state of Tennessee, hereby certify that wo are well
acquainted with Michael Lorance vrtio has subscribed and sworn to the above
declaration; that we believe blm to be oighty-three years old, that ho is
believed &amp; reputed, in the neighborhood where he resides to have been a
soldier of the Revolution, and that wo concur in that opinion.
Sworn to and subscribed s/Jordan Willeford
the day and year aforesaid
s/Vta. ? s/Kace Overall
Clerk
(On the outside of document)
West Tennessee #13820
Michael Lorance of Rutherford Co. in the State of Tennessee
who was a private in the company commanded by Captain Dickenson
of the regiment commanded bj Col, Davis in the North Carolina
line for 1 year, 1 month, and 21 days.
Inscribed on the Roll of West Tenne??see
at the rate of 57 dollars 03 cents per annum
to commence on the Ath day of Maxch, 1631.
Certificate of Pension issued the 22 day of June, 1833
and Vftn. Ledbetter, Murfreesborough
Arrears to the ^th of March $114-, 66
Semi-anl, allowance ending
4. Sept. _28j^
$U3.17
Recorded by: Revolutionary Claim Act, June 7, 1832
Daniel Boyd, Clerk
Book E Vol. 7 PaRe 84
34
State of Tennessee
Cannon County
TO WIT:
Before me Thos. Elkins a justice of the peace in and for the county
aforesaid, this day personally appeared Mary Ford, aged Bisrty-five, v/ho first
being sworn deposeth &amp; saith that she knew llichaol Loranco and Esther Loreince
in Mecklenburg CoTmty emd state of North Carolinao Sho knew then from her
earliest recollection to the time of the death of caid Kichaol vrhich occiired
in Rutherford County seven years ago, tho eighth day of Fobe Iccto (1834)
She remembers the time vrtien they were married in North Carolina ^ They V7cre
married in one half mile of vrtiere affiant was Btc3rlDg at tho tinoo Sho was
at the house of her brother, and taking care of the children vhilo the older
part of her brother's fandly were at tho vjcdding, &#163;ftcr tho wedding v:ac!
over, the married couple and the coiroany camo over to hor brother's to play
and dance. They lived together as man and wifo from tbjit timo till hie
death as aforecald. The time of their marriage sho cannot eznctly remenbcr.
The enclosed list of the ages of their children she believes to bo correct.
She has written her name at the bottom of it, Sho resomboro that tho oldest
child was born in about ten months after the marriagej and affiant v:ac about
ten years old, when they married. Affiant moved to Te:jneBcce abou.t thirty-eight
years since, the said Michael &amp; Esther came out como seven ycT.ro after
that; she has, with that exception, boen living near then all tho timo since
their marriage. The widow Lorance nov; resides in Ru.therford County, como
fifteen miles from affiant. Said Michael was a pensioner of the United
States when he died. /.. _ , E/Mary Ford
Subscribed and sworn before me this 24.th Sept.,
I84.I, and I certify that said Mary Ford is a
person of respect, ability, and worth of credit,
s/Thomas Elkins
Justice of the Peace
State of Tennessee
Cannon County
I, Reain Fowler, Clerk of the County Court of said County of Cannon
certify that Thomas Elkins who has attested the above deposition, is and
was at the time of attesting the same, a justice of the peace for our said
county, diily elected and qualified, that the foregoing signature pixrporting
to be his, is genuine.
The testimony v/hereof I have hereunto
set my hand, and affixed my private
seal, having no seal of office, this
25th Sept. A.D. 184-1.
Reain Fowler
Clerk of County Court
MICHAEL and ESTHER Moore LORANCE'S GM.ldrcn
Jolm loranee vrao bomt September 23, 1787
Anny loroncg was bornt Auguot Jth, 1769
Esther Lorance was bom February 18, 1792
Michael Lorance was bornt October 31, 1794
Eohralm Lorance was bomt April 29, I797
Catharine Lorance was bomt December 16, 1799
Jimmy Ervin Lorance was bomt January 11, 1802
George W. Lorance was bomt August 13, 1805
Mary lorance was bomt January 31, I8O9
s/Mary Ford</dc:description>
<dc:description>A reprint of Revolutionary War soldier Michael Lorance's 1833 petition to Rutherford County courts for a pension from his years of service</dc:description>
<dc:subject>United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1783; Rutherford County (Tenn.); Military pensions</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>veterans</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>9 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-24</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication11ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/148</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>