<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>A history of Milton Tennessee</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Knox, Elsie; Hood, Emil</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 23</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1984</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>18th century; 19th century; 20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>A HISTORY OF MILTON TENNESSEE
By: Elsie Knox and Emil Hood
Milton Tennessee is a small village located in the northeast part of
Rutherford County Tennessee, 14 miles northeast of Murfreesboro the county
seat.
It is located in a beautiful valley about 5 miles wide and perhaps 10 to
12 miles long.
The valley begins in Wilson County Tennessee at the base of the range of
hills known as the Solomon George Hills and extends in a southwest direction
leading to the settlement known as Halls Hill. The greater part of this valley
consists of tillable or cultivating land, a great deal is in Blue Grass and the
balance is timber land. Great improvement has been made in late years toward
improving the crop land by machinery and rotation in crops. It is strictly
a farming community. The residents have always been of an intellegent progress-ive
class of people. They have practiced a Religious and Educational trend for
the past one hundred years.
Most of the residents own their farms and some of the farms have, and
are yet in the same families for the past one hundred years.
Pictures of Milton courtesy of Mrs. Dana Knox Bumpass of Murfreesboro,
and Rucker Raikes of Smyrna.
14
HISTORY OF MILTON, TENNESSEE
1790 - 1800 to 1830
The neighborhoods of where Milton Tennessee now stands, which is now
the civic and social center, began to be settled by immigrants from North
Carolina, Virginia, and East Tennessee about the years of 1790 to 1800.
The first families to locate in this section of Tennessee were William Ray,
Thomas Black, William Doran, John Young, Moses Cranor, David Baxter, George
Peebles, Stephen Roach, Robert Mc Combs, Jesse Alexander, William Donoho,
William Dix, Ephriam Farr, Obediah Cole, Isaac Dill, Martin Armstrong. Of
these William Ray was given a grant of 1000 acres which was in Wilson
County at that time, as Rutherford County did not come into existence until
1803, William Ray's grant was east of Milton and existed in part of the Rev.
John J. Martins farm and later years the Ike Gaither farm. East of the town
of Milton was a tract of land which was a grant to Thomas Black. The residence
was down in the lot some distance from the present house of the Sam Furgasons,
there was a spring back of the old house on a small branch or creek and we are
told that Thomas Black had a still house near the spring suppose he kept the
neighborhood well supplied with good clean spirits. William Doran was an early
settler about 1805 or 1806. He also had a grant of 300 acres of land from the
state of Tennessee signed by Willie Blount Governor at that time. This farm was
southeast of Milton and in later years became the John B. Groom farm. Robert
Mc Combs was also an early resident and was awarded a grant of land. He
probably lived and owned the land where Mr. Jesse DeLay now lives. Anthony Foster
was also one of the early settlers he was on a grant of 640 acres but cannot
locate his home. Some more of the early settlers were Gideon Thompson
(more about him later) , Dr. M.W. Armstrong who was their physician for many
years (he married William Doran' s daughter). The Donoho family was the owner
15
of considerable land in the young days of Milton, their holdings at one time were
800 acres (they were located where Rufus Elrod now lives). He had a son-in-law
named John W. Price, William Barton and David Barton, Rev. Jesse Alexander.
Benjamin Knox another early settler of Milton owned a splended farm west
of Milton of several hundred acres, where the James Pamberton family lived for
many years. He married James Mc Knight's daughter and was the father of five
children; Joseph, James, Frank, Ellen, who married John Dillon, Mary who married
Thomas Vaught.
Rev. Jesse Alexander was one of the early stttlers. He was a minister of
the Presbyterian church and married a daughter of William Ray who entered a
grant of land of 1000 acres just east of Milton. The Rev. Alexander was the
organizer of the first church in, the neighborhood. It was located about one and
one half miles north of Milton on land of Capt. Thomas Black in all probability.
In later years the land belonged to Mr. G.J. Sneed.
The church was Hopewell Presbyterian Church and was organized April 1st 1816**
and the Reverend Jesse Alexander was its first pastor. The first elders were
Ezekial Sharp, William Ray, Zachriars Alexander, Ephriam Farr, Joseph Sharp,
Abner Alexander, and in later years there were added Dr. William Mc Knight,
John H, Baxter, David Morrison.
There was near the church a cemetery, which is still there in the field of
Mr. Sneed. The church building was , we are sure, a log structure as most all
were in those days. We understand that this church building was used in the
early days for school purposes also, of course in those early days there was
nothing but what was called a subscription school, many many years before the
days of free schools as we have today.
The only record we have of a merchandising establishment for the public
was set up by John Young an Englishman who immigrated from Philadelphia, Pa. to
Tennessee about 1800 and located just south of the Solomon George range of hills
** See Rutherford County Historical Society publication # 17
"History and Record of Hopewell Church"
16
in Wilson County, about 3 miles north of where Milton now stands. He erected
a store building in the lot near his house and according to records he continued
in business from 1806 to 1825 and maybe longer. This land was later owned by
James Ewing, after his death, Horace Knight became the owner. The records show
that he dealt in oats, barley, and charcoal then much later he handled some dry
goods and notions.
1820
The records show that in 1820 Gideon Thompson bought forty acres of land
which was the real beginning of Milton. This survey began at the sugar tree
which stood for many years in the lane that leads from Milton to Mr. Jesse DeLays;
it ran east to Woodridge land and north to Milton back to the beginning. This
forty acres comprised what is called the Gin field and where Everett Knight
now owns and lives, he named the road in front of Miss Elsie Knox's home Valley
Street. It seems that he was somewhat of a promoter and in July 1820 he applied
to the Legislature which was then convening in Murfreesboro from (1819 to 1825)
for authority to lay out lots, street and alleys. And this authority was given
him in an act passed July 24, 1820 as follows - Chapter 59
AN ACT : To establish a town on the lands of Gideion Thompson in the
County of Rutherford.
WHEREAS : It is represented to this General Assembly that the public
convenience will be promoted by establishing a town of the land
of Gideon Thompson in the County of Rutherford.
THEREFOR :
Sec. 1: Be it enacted by the General Assembly of the State of Tennessee,
that a town shall be, and is hereby established on the land of
Gideon Thompson in the County of Rutherford, to include such lots,
streets, lanes, alleys, as have been heretofore laid off, or may
hereafter be laid off, by the said Gideon Thompson or under his
direction, and the said town shall be called and known by the
name of Milton.
July 24, 1820 James Fentress
Second session of the 13th p^u^ki
H&#176; USe
general assembly of Tennessee J;*
weaK1
^
v
17
For a short time it seems that Mr. Thompson was moving around pretty fast.
He no doubt erected some new log houses in the new town just established. He
also was busy with the Legislature while in extra session at Murfreesboro and
had them to pass another act, giving the residents of this new village the
right to cast their ballots in the election that was held. The following
act was passed July 26, 1820.
CHAPTER 127
AN ACT : To establish a seperate election in the County of Rutherford and
for other purposes.
SEC. 1 : Be it enacted by the General Assembly of the state of Tennessee,
that hereafter there shall be a seperate election held at the house
of Gideon Thompson, in the town of Milton, in the County of Rutherford,
for the purpose of electing, Electors to elect a President and Vice
President of the United States, members of Congress, Governor of this
State, Members of the General Assembly and Military Officers, and
the said elections shall be held on the same days, under same rules
and regulations, and the returns thereof be made at the same time
and place, and have the same effect that the returns from other
seperate election districts have in said county.
July 26, 1820 James Fentress
Speaker, House
R. Weakley
Speaker Senate
Mr. Thompson's life as a promoter of a growing village in Tennessee was
short lived as he sold his forty acres and two lots as designated in the plans
of Milton as 10 and 11 toa Thomas Pomell, this transaction was dated December
1821. We do not have much record on Mr. Pomell in his operations of building
a town, any way, he disposed of his holdings of this same forty acres and
same boundaries and town lots as designated in the plans of Milton as follows
lots 20-1-3-10-11-12-18-20-22 to Benjamin Morgan February 13, 1830 of South
Carolina who was born 1795, died 1882 in Cornersville Tennessee. He, it seems
from the records, plunged right into the Real Estate business. He first began
to buy all the small and large tracts he could trade for; he also dealt quite
18
a bit in town lot and built houses on these lots, and of course sold houses
and lots. All houses at that date were built of logs, there was no farm
houses and what few of those old houses that are standing today are logs
with an outside covering of popular weatherboarding applied in later years.
The house that Benjamin Morgan (Locust Hill, that is what the family called
it) built where Everett Knight now lives was orginally logs. He and his
brother Harwood Morgan, made many improvement on Milton property. Harwood
Morgan owned and developed what at that time, and for many years afterwards,
was called New Milton. He also laid off lots for sale, he also laid off
the Public Square which still exists today. Harwood also built himself and
family a nice log home, which still exists today. Harwood also built himself
and family a nice log home, which in 1850 became the Bilbro house and still
remains in the family. Harwood Morgan was also a native of South Carolina
born 1798, died near Manchester, Tennessee. It is supposed that he donated
the Public Square to the town of Milton but we have no record to that effect.
The only two streets that we find in the old records are North Street and
Valley Street which began at the creek and ran by the old Warren and Bottoms
houses, store and I. 0. O.F. Hall, and late years by Miss Elsie Knox's house.
North Street began in front of Benjamin Morgans house, (now Everett Knight)
ran to Public Square. Harwood Morgans house (now Bilbro House) many of the
settlers prior to this date and later were (in Milton and on farms) Benjamin
Knox, John S. Woodridge, Robert Mc Combs, William Donoho' , Stephen Roach,
Thomas Powell, Gideon Thompson, Dr. M. W. Armstrong, James H. Cook, Allen
F. Gooch, John L. Moore, William Doran, Anthony Foster, William Dix, William
Barton, Sterling H. Bottoms, David Baxter, Thomas Cranor, George Peebles,
Isaac Johns, Robert W. Gardner, Obediah Cole, John W. Beckwood, Aden Taylor,
Isaac Dill, Peter C. Talley, John H. Baxter, Nathaniel W. David, Dr. William
19
Mc Knight, Henry W. Fagan, James G. Elder, John Bryant, Dennis D. Smith,
Dennis Haywood, James H. Cook, John C. Hood, William B. Byrn, William
B. White, William J. Hooper, John M. Knox, James Knox, B.F. Knox, Samuel
Vaught, Thomas Dill, George Vaught, James Vaught, Thomas Vaught, George
Lorance, Madison Mc Knight, John Selvige, John S. Cook, Donaldson Barker,
Frank Rankin, A.W. Crawley, and many others.
In the year of January 23,1838 the legislature passed an act authorizing
the formation of a company to build a Turnpike beginning at Horn Spring
(now Lavergne) to Jefferson, Lascassas, and Milton.
The commissioners named in the act were Jacob B. Donelson, John C.
Gooch, Ransford Mc Gregor, at Jefferson, James Bioims, James B. Johns,
Andrew Mc Rea at Lascassas, John L. Moore, Benjamin G. Gooch, Allen T. Gooch,
at Milton.
In the year of 1840 the Hopewell Presbyterian Church elders, bought
four acres of land from John S. Woodridge for $60.00 for the purpose of
moving the church from the old location one mile north of Milton to the new
location on the hill east of Milton the deed was made to Jesse Alexander,
Nathanial W. David, John L. Moore, John H. Baxter, and Godfrey S. Newman as
trustees of Hopewell church and Milton Academy and their successors in office.
This church was brick, later years a frame building was erected with a Masonic
Hall overhead. This building remained for many years, and in 1900 a new
building birck veneer erected in Milton on the lot where the Cumberland
Presbyterian church burned down in 1917.
In the year 1850 a petition was presented to the Grand Lodge of Masons
of Tennessee for a lodge at Milton, Tennessee and on August 31st 1850, the
Grand Lodge issued a dispensation for its organization and the following
officers and members were named in the dispensation.
20
Officers Members
Joseph A. Knox, Worshipful Master G. M. Alsup
John W. Sellers, Senior Warden Robert W. Gardner
James G. Putnam, Junior Warden William Putnam
James M. Armstrong
S. W. Talley
In 1853 the Trustees, Henry W. Fagan, A.B. Mc Knight, and J.B. Thomas
of Milton Lodge Independent Order of Odd Fellows #88, bought the store building
on the corner of Valley and North Streets as designated in the plans of early
Milton. We are under the impression that the Lodge had another story built
upon the store building after they became the owners and there for many years
they met for their work in the Lodge. The lower floor was rented for merchandise
and the upper for Lodge meetings.
This program continued for many years, in fact until the building was
moved intact to the business part of Milton, which in later years was the
East side of the Public Square, about where the Milton Bank building was later
built.
The lodge building was destroyed by fire in 1897 and all records of the
Lodge were also destroyed. We have appealed to the I.O.O.F. Grand Lodge for
information on the Milton Lodge but they have informed us that their records
became lost or destroyed and they could not give us any assistance in the
matter. The Lodge building was moved in about 1897 to New Milton by a Mr. Roy
from near Liberty, Tennessee. He only used for this great undertaking in those
days, his son, a small donkey or mule, a winch, and a good supply of large
size grass rope and plenty of blocks. He was about two weeks in completing
the task but he made it all ok. However, it was a wonderful sight to the
residents of the neighborhood at that time.
In the 1830' s Gilliam and Moore were merchants in Milton and Andy M.
21
Alexander came to clerk for them at the age of 18 years. We are sure that
he lived with his Uncle and Aunt, Dr. M. W. Armstrong and wife. While he was
working for Gilliam and Moore two years and another hitch of three years
with James L. Moore. Dr. Armstrong and wife, at this time and for many
years, were residents of Milton and later Dr. Armstrong bought the Harwood
Morgan home, now the old Dr. Bilbro property.
In the early days of Milton, it seems that the first stores of merchan-dise
were located in old Milton as it was called in the beginning. There was
at one time a store building added on to the east end of a dwelling on Valley
Street, which was occupied at that time in 1840's by William B. White, who
was a tailor and merchant in Milton, (now the dwelling of Elsie Knox).
Another store building at one time stood in the southeast corner of Miss Elsie
Knox's garden, also a black smith shop in the plot of ground between the
Knox garden and the corner store at Valley and North Streets.
Later on Harwood Morgan built a store in New Milton on the corner of two
streets, (no name) what is now the property of the Presbyterian church.
Another store was erected across the street where Jack Mathews was located,
but not the same building. The old one was part log and part frame. It
was torn away and moved by Mr. Dill Spain in 1895.
We will try to name some of the early merchants of Milton, Ben Morgan,
W. B. White, Orsuin Alexander, James S. McFadden, P.C. Talley, Williamson
Cosby, Cosby Marshall and Co., Allen T. Gooch, Hooper and Wilson, Gooch and
Mc Knight, Gilliam and Moore, John L. Moore, Robert W. Gardner, A.D. and R.F.
Marshall, A.M. Dillin, W.Y. Posey Sr., S. H. Bottoms.
In later years Dr. Armstrong and wife bought from Harwood Morgan his
home, which is now and has been in the Bilbro family for almost one hundred
years. Harwood Morgan was the promoter of New Milton as it was called in the
22
Erskin Givins in store about 1915
23
olden days. He promoted the laying off of lots and streets. All lots were
numbered in the plans of old Milton and New Milton, where Hugh Hooper lives
was lot No. 12. Mr. Morgan built his residence on lot No. 13 and lot No. 14
was between his home and Mrs. Hattie Sneeds' property. Lot No. 1 was on the
east side of the square somewhere in the realm of Mrs. Sneed to the Medical
Clinic which now stands on the east side of Public Square. Lot No. 4 was
about where John Hogwoods' shop formerly stood.
Some of the later merchants in Milton were (we will try to give them
as they come) James H. Cook, W. B. Smith, Rev. James P, McKee, Morris Goodlow,
John R. Stroop, Lewis Boos, William J. Hooper, Sam B. Cranor, James L. Byrn
and Will Herndon, (Byrn and Herndon) James Patterson and John Rhodes, (Pat-terson
and Rhodes) Thomas J. Duggin, Harris Baird, John E. Grandstaff, C.E.
Robinson and James Rhodes (Robinson and Rhodes), Walter Burnett, Thomas E.
Bell, H.P. Johns, Abner Jones, Emil Hood, Grover Sneed, (Hood and Sneed)
Jeter Hood, William Baxter, (Hood and Baxter) A. P. Givans and son, L.E.
Blankenship, Kennedy Bros., Jack Mathews, Charlie Cherry, W.F. Knight and
Son 1950.
Some of the early physicians or doctors in and near Milton were Dr.
Mc Whirter, Dr. M.W. Armstrong, who was a son-in-law of William Doran, one
of the early settlers. He later bought the Harwood Morgan home and in 1850
sold this home to Dr. B.H. Bilbro. We are deeply under the impression that
Stephen Roach also practiced medicine here.
He bought in 1819 two hundred and two acres of the Thomas Black land
and remained a citizen of Milton for 19 years. He moved to Indiana in 1838.
Dr. William Mc Knight was another early physician, who also married a
daughter of William Doran. He was one of the early elders in Hopewell church.
Some of the early blacksmiths of Milton were James G. Elder, James Bell,
24
J. H. Watts, John E. Sullivan, Thomas Dill, John Selvige, R.H. Rogers,
B. F. Witherspoon, William G. Morrison.
Also in the early days of Milton, about the latter 1830 ' s or 1840,
Dennis Hogwood established a very profitable business of tanning green hides
of cows into leather. He continued in this business for many years and in
his early days he had occasion to be a great benefactor to a young boy 10
years old. He gave him a home in his family and taught him the trade of tan-ning
cow hides into leather. This affinity continued for many years, until
the boy bacame a grown man, and later he decided to go into business for
himself. He opened himself a tan yard in Milton and later married and reared
he and wife, quite a large family, seven girls and five boys.
This boys' name was William J. Hooper, who was the father of the Hooper
family of Milton. His tan yard was located on the western border of Milton,
where Willie Bugg now resides.
Another business man of Milton in the early days was Henry W. Fagan.
He lived for many years and died on the corner of the Public Square, where
Uncle Jacob Herndon lived for many later years.
The old building burned down when Emil Hood lived there in 1913.
In 1874 Donalson Barker, who was administrator of the estate of Henry
W. Fagan, sold to John P. Smith a parcel of ground lying in Milton and de-scribed
as follows: The Fagan house and lot of ground where Mr. Smiths'
father-in-law, J. M. Weatherly, lived for several years and later Jacob
Herndon, the lot of ground where Mrs. Claude Sneed now lives and a vacant
lot between her house and turnpike. In 1875 Mr. Smith sold the lot where
Mrs. Claude Sneed now lives to Morris Goodlow. Mr. Goodlow built the house
where Mrs. Claude Sneed lives, also a store building in the front part of
the lot, about half way between the yard gate and the large gate to drive
into the barn. This building was torn away in 1883, by Mr. Robert L. Smith,
25
who bought the property from Mr. Goodlow in 1881, Mr. and Mrs. Goodlow
planted the beautiful magnolia tree that is standing in the front yard of
Mrs. Sneeds' home. He also included in the building a bay window, the first
one that a great many had ever seen.
In 1885 Milton neighborhood established a Co-Operative Beef Club of
twelve members. The rules were to kill one beef (animal.) every Friday after-noon
for twelve weeks, which was one for each member. After killing, the
carcass was cut into twelve pieces, one for each member, and the cuts would
alternate each week. Their killings would begin the first of July and con-tinue
through the months of August and September. Uncle Jacob Herndon was
the butcher and the rule was for one to kill a beef any larger than 800
pounds. Uncle Jacob received one dollar for the slaughter and cutting up
the beef.
The charter members were:
Dennis Hogwood William M. Byrn
R.G. Byrn Jacob Herndon
John P. Smith John Medling
Dr. A. P. Mc Cul lough W. J. Hooper
D. N. Smith J. E. Allen
Jared Warren Moses Cranor
In the latter part of the 1850's, Milton became very school conscious
and began to make preparations to have better schools and also a suitable
school building.
Mr. William B. Byrn, the father of William Byrn and Green Byrn, learned
through his brother-in-law, Mr. Enoch Jones, of a teacher who had come into
that community, who was a very competent teacher and could be secured. His
name was Jared Warren. So the contact was made, and a contract was drawn
26
With the Rev. Warren. One stipulation that was made by the teacher was that
the neighborhood would build a school building in Milton, that would give
adequate room and also be comfortable to all.
First, a board of trustees was selected in the neighborhood, composed of
Dr. B. H. Bilbro, Dennis Smith, William B. White, William B. Byrn, and George
W. Furgason, who were designated as trustees of Milton male and female Seminary.
This board of trustees proceeded to select a suitable location for the new
school building, and after this was done the purchase was made by the board from
George Furgason for a strip of land where the school now is located, described
in the deed as approximately 2 acres and 32 poles. This land was deeded to the
trustees as above stated and to their successors. The deed was dated November
3, 1857. Purchase price was $122.50 and was registered in the County Registers'
Office September 17, 1860. Witness, James H. Cook, Benjamin F. Knox.
This arrangement continued for a period of three or four years until the
outbreak of the Civil War 1861.
We suppose the school was closed for awhile, but for how long we are unable
to state. After the war we are sure that the board of trustees began to function
in regular form. Up to the year that the county took over the transfer of the
property in 1918 and it has been under County control since.
During the battle of Milton in 1863, a cannon ball passed through the build-ing
entering the western gable end and passed out in the eastern end. The
remains of this episode of marksmanship remained in the building until 1883
when the old building was remodeled and the auditorium was built on the north
side of the old building.
The school adjourned to the Masonic Hall, which was located at this time
above the Hopewell Presbyterian church on the hill, east of Milton. This
arrangement continued for about one year.
27
The school opened in the new building August, 1884 under the management of
Prof. W. A. Peay and wife.
The first building, erected in 1857 or 1858 was a frame building consisting
of three rooms, which ran east to west. After the remodeling in 1883, there
were three rooms with an arrangement made with sliding doors, so that an
emergency room could be arranged if needed. This remodeled building remained
for many years and the school passed under many principals, who were selected
by the board of trustees. We wish we had the old records so that we could name
the board as they came into power, but we have been unable to locate the
secretary's record book.
The names of the board of trustees of Milton Seminary in the year 1889
were:
Rev. John J. Martin, President
Joseph P. Smith, Secretary
R. G. Byrn, Treasurer
Dr. A. P. McCul lough
William J. Hooper
This is the only record we have of the board of trustees, since 1857 -
the date of the first board.
A new brick veneer building was erected on the same old location in 1934,
consisting of five rooms. This is a very modern building and has many facilities
that progress is sure to bring about, cooking, refrigeration, drinking water,
etc.
In the past year the community has erected a splendid gymnasium building
of larger and ample room for entertainments for the school, also for the great
sport of basketball tournaments, etc. All the buildings are now heated by Butane
Gas and are lighted with electricity, thanks to the great progress movement of
T.V.A. by the United States Government.
We are going to include a roster of the names of the men and women who
were principals of this great school, as far as we can secure them.
28
W. H. Turney School 1894
Milton Seminary 1894
29
ozDOzz&lt;
Z
O
hJ
o5 (D O
10
o
&#163;
S
1905.
190C
e:
1 |
05 o &lt;
&#171;" &#8226;,- s &#8226;-&gt;
F=
UJ
X
i_
a:
&lt;
UJ
&gt;- iiS^&#163;s&gt;=^ 3
c
J
'
'
* 2
&#163; 3
3 &#163;
a3 O u x M
c.2
c-u.
1-
&lt; &#163;
5
d in e&#176; o &#167; n h o
eg io
CO
c "^ j 2
r &#187;
*
&#8212; &gt;. Jh CO
% ic u
"o Hi ui
3 "3 ia c:
IS 41 I&#8212;
i
U -Ch -
P 7! &#171;/" -
* O ^ K
P 3 f- - -a &#171; "5. &#163;:&#8226; I
s u 2 = n 'o-5?h pSk^ X ~5
6&gt;U, CJ " e . &#8226;
b- s
Bc&#171;&#171;^
For
tu
r.
A.
P
m
Vau
cKee,
C5 v5
&#171;
"=
ic 9-
'2 cm
&#163; . &lt;*=
-5 ^ -= ^1
&#163;-&#163;&#163;
_- &#171;
rt fab .
- E c-
M E - * &#163; b
O 2
* I
b&#163; _
w !i .i .1
W ^ - -
X | fs!
'&#171;
!? i J
fc&#163; S.
C C
r-j o
d &#8212;
JS o
.5?
X "o
w - c /&#187;; K
&lt; i: n ^ &lt;
&#176;" I &#171;r &#163; u
- " ^ o ~
r&gt;.a S-e &gt;
3 v.
. o O
&#171; C Oh
_&#163; M
&amp; si &lt; -s s
M C
5 " S
a E
i- c = m
r- n . 5-
M
w 5
n: y =
C o &#8226;', .
; &#167; -3 fji!
o 2 __
- J
E
111
&#176; &#8226;&#163; &#8212; &#163;
Announcement of Milton Seminary 1905-1906
30
J 5
3 E
(0 h Z &gt;.
Jt
&#176; m 2
2 - 8 &#163;
2 - s
a u g
.S ,&#163;
&#8226;c . g
*J
E E
SO
T iS
B bfl "&gt;
-J 5
E ft.
" ft.
&#8226;n &lt; .
&lt;0
r E
s IS
1 ei -s
1*1 u - p.
8
E E
? 1
a e
| g
I c s
Sop
B 3 . S E c
I
a &gt;
o ^.
S o
8 if
oo EE ** o
S Z
t 2 S
bl -
s i "i -&#8226; s I
s UIiJ
s b
f
, re u
J= 3 .1
c
*! c 5J
u E SL
U
u c c &#8212;
c -5
"S
re
E
u
"3
JS
u
re
E
V
"3
5
3
o .&#163;
O R
F E
r U J "S J5
S 5
s? o a
??u
J*u.go-g=
i &gt; E y
= &#8212; J! C
R U *S
""
*] j
* &#171; S
2^ u
e c &#163;
t J
c j
.2 * M
3 fc &#167;
= C -a
.5 &#171;
C U &gt; U 5.'
J! ~ ^ &#163; E
.&#8212; **- ft
&#8212; f -
Eo
c Ji &#171;&#171; D
-c o " g
~ &#187; i '5
5 Q3f
&#171; : "S P
15
I
&amp; i
5
I C/}
s r "9 - s
R &#171;S ^ 1 I e
S Z
&#8226;&#163; .2 B
.E I U
3 S _
o E
o
o * B a f
5 &#171; &#171; si ^
&#8226;- - a I
31
Roster of Principals of Milton Seminary School, from 1858 to 1950:
Rev. Jared Warren, 1857 or '58
1861 to 1871
E. G. (Donk) Brown
H.C. (Tip) Alsup
Rev. Enoch Windes
J.B. Phillips
Talley
Jeff Ritchie
Joseph A. Laughlin
M rs. Sinnett Summar
H. B. Northcutt
W. A. Peay
N. D. Overall
Frank Sullivan
E. Brookover
Martin Carter
W. H. Turney
John E. Brandon
E. Sharpe
Walter Martin
David Strickler
B. R. Kennedy
B. H. Lokey
Miss Mary Knott
R. A. Taylor
W. 0. McKee
J. E. Cook
J. F. Pruett
Robert Becton
R. Y. Neel
Clyde Howard
Leslie J. Gould
Miss Angie Haynes
Donnie Baxter
K. T. McCrary 1923-28
Harvey Dodd
Allen Barrett
Alma Lannom (Knight)
Billy Mc Nabb
Grace Delay
Mrs. Sam Turney
The old building and grounds were deeded to the Rutherford County Education
Board in 1918, and the school has been under the control of the County School
Board, and Superintendent of Schools, since that date. The deed was made by the
Board of Trustees and signed by William M. Byrn, W. H. Hooper, D. N. Smith,
Charles E. Robinson, and Moses Cranor.
32
Ml
&#8226;
f^-Q-Z^-^y r5 &#163;3 o nESnHHET
jjJ-M K^ ^liP-^B^ *^ I^^HRHR jH^&#171;m2- ::*
at
Hvl
^z
f
1 fife J IL^l r^
r^(
Br &lt;jAJtt --&#187;a
Milton School - Elsie Knox and
Principal Kenneth Mc Cary on
right of picture
33
REMEMBER? sixty long years ag0' the five young
ladies and five young men shcrvn
above with their teacher composed the graduating class at old
Milton Seminary. The year was 1890. Left to right, those
shown are: Front row&#8212;Jim Rakes, Walter Hood, George Mc-
Cullough; center row&#8212;Miss Fannie Maney, Miss Nettie Hoop-er,
Miss Lou Overall; back row&#8212;George Cranor, Miss Jennie
Hooper, Prof. N. D. Overall, Miss Bettie Elrod and Gilbert But-ler.
George Cranor and George McCullough are the only ones
still living. ((The photograph belongs to George Cranor).
34
Milton School 1908
35
Milton School around 1924
36
John F. Pruett School 1909,1910,1911, &amp; 1912
37
Ewingsville School located 4 miles north of
Milton on Greenvale Road 1911
38
Porterfield school
39
There were, at different times, three drug stores established in Milton,
Morris Goodlow, 1875, Sam B. Cranor, 1883, Author Martin, 1894. All did a
splendid business for many years.
For many years Milton maintained a spring show of Breeding Stock Horses and
Jack Stock. This exhibition was a grand affair for the neighborhood, and was
looked forward to by the young and old. The occasion was placed on the date of
the first Saturday in April. In later years the festivities would wind up in
the afternoon in a real good game of baseball.
Milton has always a \/ery progressive community in all affairs for the bene-fit
of the people and neighborhood.
During the days of the school under Prof. N. D. Overall a yery active
Y.M.C.A. was organized and continued to grow and weilded a great deal of influence
over the young men of the community.
In 1890 the village and community organized a committee to establish a
Public Cemetery for the benefit of the public. A small tract of 1/2 acre was
purchased from Mrs. Fannie Cranor, who was a daughter of Dr. B. H. Bilbro. The
committee proceeded to plot the ground for grave lots, and drew a plot of the
ground and numbered the lots, so that there would be no confusion hereafter of
locating a grave.
The grounds have been enlarged two or three times since, and continue to
grow. In late years the grounds have been under the supervision of Miss Elsie
Knox and she has made a very beautiful place of it.
For a period of 82 years there was but one church in Milton and that was
Hopewell Presbyterian Church on the hill, east of the village.
In the year 1898 the Baptists organized a church at Milton and proceeded
to build a very neat and commodious building in conjunction with the Masonic and
Odd Fellow Lodge. The two lodges occupied the upper story until 1937, when this
building burned down. However, we believe both of the lodges had been suspended
40
Baptist Church about 1910
41
for the lack of required membership before the fire came.
The Baptist congregation proceeded to erect a new building of brick
veneer in 1939 and has become fairly strong in membership.
The Cumberland Presbyterian also organized a church at Milton, and began
the erection of a new church building in the year 1899. This church prodeeded
to worship with a nice congregation for several years and in 1817 it burned down.
However, this church and the Baptist both burned in the night from the force
lightning from the elements on high.
Later on in 1937, Hopewell Presbyterian Church, which stood for so many**
years on the elevated ground east of the village, was torn away and this con-gregation
proceeded to build a new brick veneer Church building on the lot where
the Cumberland Presbyterian Church stood down in the heart of the village.
In 1925 a Church of Christ was built in Milton adjoining the grounds of
Milton Seminary School. They have a nice congregation and worship regularly
every Sunday.
We cannot pass this history up without some mention of the Physicians
who served this community in their blessings and sorrows for many decades.
We mentioned in the beginning of our history that there was in the early days
Stephen Roach, also Martin W. Armstrong, and later Berryman H. Bilbro. There
was also a Dr. McWhirter, who lived south of Milton about two or three miles.
William McKnight was a physician in the early days. In 1860 Thomas King Bostic
located in Milton. In 1870 Robert H. Martin practiced here. In 1870 Allan P.
Mc Cul lough also came to Milton to practice his profession. In 1880 a Dr. Swann
came to Milton and practiced for a while and moved to Auburn, Tennessee. In
1895 James C. Kelton located in Milton to practice medicine. In 1906 J. R. Doak
located in Milton and served the people for several years. He sold his home and
good will to Dr. H. L. Mc Gee who preceeded to attend the sick around Milton until
his death in 19--.
** See Rugherford County Historical Society publication #7
'Minutes of Hopewell Church"
42
A brass band consisting of 10 to 12 instruments was organized at Milton
in the year of 1882 or 1883. They proceeded to practice very regularly for
several years and were able to secure several engagements during this time.
They secured the contract to furnish music at the Rutherford County Fair one
or two years. They finally lapsed into an inactive state, but were reorganized
by Arthur Martin and others in the year of 1892 with a fairly large membership.
But after a few years ceased to exist by removals and lack of interest, etc.
From the records of the U. S. Post Office at Washington, we learn that
the post office at Milton, Tennessee was established on July 3rd, 1824, and Thomas
Powell was the first Postmaster. This Post Office has continued to exist to
the present time with no interferance unless it was during the Civil War in
1861 to 1865.
About twenty five years ago there were two R.F.D. Routes established at
the Milton office, but later one route was discontinued, yet the office still
has one R.F. D. route which serves quite a territory south of Milton.
43
BIOGRAPHY OR HISTORY OF GEORGE PEEBLES AND DESCENDANTS
George Peebles married Thomas Blacks 1 daughter Jane Finney Black at
Winchester Kentucky and in 1812 they came to Tennessee.
They located on part of the Black land on the southeast section and built
them a house there.
Mr. Peebles was a thorough agriculturist. He brought a great variety
of grass seed and many varieties of fruit trees with him to Tennessee. He
and wife were the parents to two children, Martha and Albert. Martha married
William B. White in 1850. Albert died at the age of twenty one years.
Mr. Peebles was a spendid farmer and was quite a live stock raiser and
dealer.
His wife died several years before he (we don't know the date of her death).
He died in the 1870's.
He was honored and known as a very progressive citizen of his day. Before
his death he was the owner of considerable land around Milton, but prior to his
death he divided all of the land in equal shares to his children.
He gave Hopewell church the store building and lot in Milton. But we have
never been able to find a deed recorded for this gift in the Registers Office of
Rutherford County.
Mr. Peebles was the grandfather of the White descendants, who were quite
numerous in the Milton community for many years.
44
BIOGRAPHY OF REV. JESSE ALEXANDER
Rev. Jesse Alexander was an early settler in the community. We have no
personal record of him altho we are confident that he was a native of North
Carolina.
He was an ordaned minister of the old school Presbyterian church and
organized the Hopewell and Stone River churches in this neighborhood, Hopewell
1816, Stones River --. He married a daughter (Nancy) of William Ray, who
was one of the first elders of Hopewell church, by this union they became the
parents of the following children: Mary (Mrs. Thomas Cranor) Martha (Mrs.
James N. McKnight) Nancy (Mrs. James Black) Samuel Alexander (never married)
George Alexander, Gideon Alexander.
A great many decendents of this saintly minister of the early gospel are
still residents of the community where he labored so many years and still worhip
on Sundays and special occasions at Hopewell church.
45
BIOGRAPHY OF CAPT. THOMAS BLACK
He was a native of Scotland, he came to America in the early days and
first located in Pennsylvania. He emigrated to North Carolina and evidently
married there to Martha Polk some relation to James K. Polk. We presune that
he served there in the Revolutionary Way and in later years moved to Win-chester,
Kentucky. From there he came to Tennessee or North Carolina and it is
supposed he received a grant of land, just east of where Milton now stands, of
probably one thousand acres. It included later the Furgason land, Cranor land,
White and Peebles land, and very likely the land where Hopewell church was first
established in 1816. Capt. Black died in the year 1816. He and wife, Martha
Polk, were the parents of the following children. Polly (Mrs. John Doak),
Rebecca (Mrs. Moses Cranor), Jane (Mrs. George Peebles), Samuel Pitts Black.
(Walter Hill married Fannie Sanders), James Alexander Black married Rebecca
Baxter. Capt. Black resided where the Furgasons now live, except in the old house
which was torn away many years ago. It is told that he had a still house at the
spring and in his last will he bequeathed this still and utensils pertaining
thereto to his daughter Polly Doak and husband.
46
SHORT BIOGRAPHY OF STERLING H. BOTTOMS
Two of the most comical people who ever located in Milton was said to be
Sterling H. Bottoms and wife Matildia. They were childless, no one but them-selves
through life. They came to Milton from Wilson County Tennessee in the
1830's. He was an apprenticed shoe maker, and said to be a good one, he
finally bought lots no. 7-8 and the North End of no. 9 as laid out in the
plans of Milton and he and wife Matildia spent their days in the town of Milton
and both died there. It has been told that Mr. Bottoms had splendid trade in
the shoe business for many years in his later days the shoe business began to
decline and he conceived the idea of stocking up his shoe shop with a line of
general merchandise, but this proved a failure in a few years he was badly
embarrassed for finances and had to entail his house and lots to his creditors
to secure the debts made in this last business venture. He and his wife were
worshippers and members of Hopewell Presbyterian church for many years.
In the 1840' s a minister or evangilist came to Tennessee preaching a new
doctrine. He disolved his affiliations with the Odd Fellow Lodge and also the
Masonic Lodge to which he had been a faithful member for years and said that
the New Testament was all that anyone needed to live by. He died about 1870
and Matildia became a widow for many years. Later Uncle Tommie David heard
about her while living at Aubern, and made two trips to see Matildia and they
became one. He, Uncle Tommie was a wood workman by trade and one of the best.
He converted the old shoe shop into a wood shop and enjoyed a splendid trade for
several years and he passed over the river and Aunt Matildia continued to live
right on.
47
</dc:description>
<dc:description>A short history of the Milton community in Rutherford County from its founding in 1790 until current times. Includes four short biographies of prominent citizens appended to the end</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Family histories</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Milton</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>34 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-01; mt2011-02-28</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication23ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/58</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>