<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Lavergne</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Chaney, Shirley</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 6</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1976</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>18th century; 19th century; 20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>58
LAVERGNE
BY
SHIRLEY CHANEY
1
The first property in the area was deeded to Samuel Buchanan in
1788 but had been located in 1785 and signed by Richard Caswell Aug. 1,
1787. The 400 acre tract was located along Hurricane Creek, then Ruth-erford
County, North Carolina. The early 1819 map of Rutherford County,
Tennessee shows the boundaries to extend far into present Davidson
County, and it is easy to see how Donelson and LaVergne have the same
"back yards," so to speak. Both communities could share a few of the
early families settling along Stones River. Samuel's land was on both
sides of the creek north of the present Rutherford-Davidson County
line bridge. The line at this point has been changed numerous times
through various periods of our Tennessee State Legislature. Both
Samuel and John Buchanan were famous Indian fighters and both owned
land in this northwest section of the county.
Buchanan family records state Sam was killed by Indians at the
"Bluff" in 1783, and that he never married. Early Tennessee history
2
accounts such as Ransey, Putnam, Hale and Merritt, and Clayton all
agree he was killed at the hands of Indians but all vary the death
date. Most agree he was killed by 1788, however, none of these could
be accurate since Sam signed a deed transfer in 1784 and was a jurror
3
in 1789. His death occurred in 1793 and his inventory at death left
a widow named Rebecca.
1. Davidson County Reg. Book A. p. 324
2. Hale and Merritt, Vol . 1
3. Davidson County Wills and Inventories, Microfilm #427, Tennessee
Library and Archives, Nashville.
59
Sam was in a field plowing when Indians fired upon him. He ran
while twelve savage pursuers overtook and killed him. The bluff at
which he was killed was at Hurricane Creek and he had been plowing
his own field at his own station when attacked. Sam came into the
frontier wilderness with John, helped settle French Lick, fought
Indians, served several times a juror, bought and sold land, married,
ect. It would seem more likely that he would establish his own inter-est
rather than stay at the Bluff at French Lick, or for that matter
at the John Buchanan Station. His own land along Hurricane Creek
became Samuel Buchanan's station and later Buchanansville.
Official Post Office records show Buchanansville, Davidson County
changed to Mount View, March 8, 1827, then changed back to Buchanan-sville
on January 26, 1837. It was again changed to Mount View, March 1,
1842, then finally to LaVergne, Rutherford County on August 23, 1852.
Unofficially it was given several other names including Rutherford City,
Limestone, and Cedar Point. The man for whom the city was named referred
to the community as Rutherford or Rutherford City. In deciding the date
of establishment for the city seal design, 1803 seemed to be the best
date. Obviously if Sam was killed in 1793, the danger of Indian attack
was still too great to settle in the frontier land. Yet by 1803, ten
years later, the new Rutherford County was chartered and County Court
was held in 1804. Rock Springs Baptist Church was opened July 21, 1804
and its enrollment was of good size. The actual settlement date was
between 1793 when Sam was killed and 1803 when Rutherford County was
chartered.
60
The city was named for Francis Roulhac, born in Limoges, France
March 15, 1767. He was christened at birth: Francois Leonard Gregoire
de Roulhac de LaVergne. When he came to America, he anglicized his name,
shortening it to Francis Roulhac. He was both a doctor and a lavyyer
but practiced neither profession to a great degree. In his younger-life
he preferred a mercantile life, in later years he was happiest
on his farm.
Roulhac had married Margaret Gray of North Carolina. Her sister
had married a Butler who had died or was killed, and she had been given
land in Rutherford County by her father-in-law. The Roulhacs brought
the sister to "Rutherford" and continued on to Montgomery County. A
short time later, "Aunt Butler", as the Roulhac children called her,
asked them to move to Rutherford and she would deed her land to them.
The Roulhacs came to LaVergne in 1822.
Francis knew the importance of sending to and receiving mail from
Europe, the West Indies and eastern United States, all places where
he had connections. He really couldn't have cared less WHAT the city
was named, rather THAT the city retained a post office. Because of this
intense post office concern, the community was named LaVergne for him,
the day Roulhac died. Firestone is located where Roulhac's home once
stood. One of the listed Mount View Post Offices was located a short
distance of Roulhac's home. If he could know what had now come to pass
and the projected plans for the future in Interchange City, he would
be the first to be pleased.
Williams Kimbro and John Hill were two men of means and stature
who probably were the most instrumental in setting a pattern for living
61
in this community. Both men served in County Court, Kimbro's land
was south of the community including the top of a high elevation.
The land was still in the Kimbro family until wery recently when it
was sold for community development. The early roads were cleared,
laid out, and the overseers were responsible men in the area. One
of these roads was a portion of the original Nashvil le-Murfreesboro-
Chattannoga Pike which came through LaVergne about where the present
1-24 highway is located. Of course, its route was changed on more
than one occasion by economic or population needs and post office
site changes.
John Hill, one of the first Magistrates of the County, built
the lovely Nelson home which was recently razed to make way for the
Long-Bell Industry completed early this year. Hill was a son of Green
Hill, the Father of Methodism in Middle Tennessee. Green Hill divided
a 640 acre land grant tract between two of his sons, Thomas and John.
Squire Hill and his wife later moved to another community. Early
court minutes list a good many endeavors by John Hill when he lived
in what was to become the LaVergne community.
During the time Murfreesboro was the capital of the State, ed-ucation
seemed to be the prime interest next to and often interlocking
politics. Dr. James Priestley of Princeton University had come to
the Nashville Academy and was probably one of the greatest forces in
setting high educational standards in Middle Tennessee. His home
was located in what was to become Donelson, and he had several family
members living in the LaVergne community. A granddaughter is buried
in the Mason Cemetery off Hollandale Road. In most of the old letters
62
of the LaVergne Collection, references are continually made to planning
and receiving higher education within a 30-mile radius of LaVergne.
Public education did not come until a century later.
About 1833 the city was laid out by John Hill, son-in-law of
Francis Roulhac and nephew of Squire Hill. He was an enterprising
young man who had a rope and bagging factory in Lebanon. Young Hill
had a store and saw mill near his home which was located where the
Tennessee Farmers Co-op lands are now situated. However, the ear-liest
stores were operated by Joe Kimbro whose store was really a plant-ation
commissary. The Kimbro lands were on a portion of Signal
flountain and surrounding terrain, and the Kimbro store was convenient
to the Rock Springs community as well as to Mt. View, Buchanansvil le,
or LaVergne. The other early store was operated by Benjamin Ferguson
down on the river bend on the former Bob Alexander place. According
to one of the old ledgers that used to be housed in the Hermitage
Museum at Andrew Jackson's home, Jackson bought frequently from
Ferguson. Undoubtedly there had to be trading posts or other early
stores and certainly there was one in Buchanansvil le near the old
Buchanan Cemetery. The old cemetery once served as the city cemetery
and is near the heart of the Buchanansvil le community. The names
of the store owners throughout the time of settlement to a more recent
time would, more often than not, be lost to time.
The late 1840' s and 60's brought a period of time when LaVergne
spawned a lot of doctors. This was due primarily to Dr. James Charlton
who had purchased the old Stokely Donelson tract. His home contained
a post office called Elm Hill and was located north of the LaVergne
63
community. According to verification of a State highway historian.
Elm Hill Pike terminated at the home of Dr. Charlton. As the doctor
made his rounds twice a week in LaVergne, he also carried the mail.
He had a small rock and frame building in the far corner of his front
yard and it was here that young aspiring doctors "read" medicine
under Dr. Charlton.
"Railroad interest was at fever pitch," stated one of the early
Neal letters. It was the railroad that brought economy to LaVergne
in 1852. It was developing into a busy freight stop and was incor-prated
as a city Feb. 28, 1860. The old station was torn down at the
end of World War II, but at the turn of the century it was the gath-ering
place for the young folks. J. R. Park was station agent who
kept the station neat and clean. Brightly colored flowers were
nearly always found around the station. Park lived in the former
John Hill home, Cherry Shade, across from the station and had the
first phonograph in town. This was the obvious reason young folks
delighted in the station.
The old fort where Nathan Bedford Forrest once trained his troops
is now owned by Glen Waldron. It lies south of the old Nashville Pike
but during the War Between the States, it was found just off the Jeff-erson
Pike which continued from the Robert Pope place to the Nolens-ville,
Columbia ect. The King home was located between the old fort
and Signal Knob, a short distance to the south. Its location was one
of the reasons for its being burned to the ground during the v;ar. The
fort was the scene of several skirmishes and traded hands more than
once between Union and Confederate forces.
6^
According to J. T. Dougherty's " Battle of LaVergne ," "General
Braxton Bragg gave orders to slow the Union Army down to avoid a
general engagement until they reached Murfreesboro. This the Con-federates
accomplished quite well. General Crittenden's Corps under
Rosecrans advanced townard Murfreesboro on the Murfreesboro Pike.
On Dec. 26, 1862, he found LaVergne to be a small village with a
desirable railroad depot that could move men and supplies closer to
Murfreesboro. His men moved toward Hurricane Creek but the Con-federate
Cavalry under the Command of mighty Joe Wheeler waited across
the creek with 2,500 men and a battery of 4 gun artillery. Critt-enden
thought he was engaged with at least a division so he sent for
re-inforcements and deployed his men in line for a major engagement.
Rosecrans appeared and thought, too, it was a major battle and sent
for Thomas. After several hours, the Confederates retreated into
the town to take up defensive positions. "Dougherty states the skirmish
became house to house combat as Wheeler's men fired from doorways
and windows.
When the railroad had been built through the town, it became
necessary for the Nashvil le-Murfreesboro Pike to be nearer the rail-road.
This was accomplished by using a portion of an existing road
and the new section of Nashvil le-Murfreesboro Pike ran parallel with
the tracks for a short distance and crossed the tracks on the north
end of the underpass. A Union wagon train under the command of McCook
was progressing toward Murfreesboro with supplies. On December 30,
1862, Wheeler had been making his famed circuitous route when he came
upon McCook' s train. He attacked at the edge of the northwest side
65
6
of the village. An artist sketch depicts a church in the background
thought to be Ebenezer Methodist Church. (Later, the Presbyterian
church used the same foundation.) Burning wagons were scattered in
the surrounding fields on both sides of the present Highway #41 bet-ween
the present Tennessee Farmers Co-op land and the old Sam Buch-anan
Station.
An estimated $1,000,000 worth of supplies was destroyed and
700 prisoners were taken. Again, according to Dougherty's account,
"the work of parol ling prisoners, burning wagons, exchanging arms
and ammunition, and driving off horses and mules consumed the rest
of the day. On the 31st Wheeler continued toward Nolensville burning
a forage train on Rock Springs Road and another wagon train at Nol-ensville
capturing 300 men."
Only a portion of the war history can be depicted here but memtion
7 8
should be made of the Mary Neal King Diary, the story of Kate Lyle,
the account of the October 7, 1862 battle at the Old Fort, the store
9
of Cherry Shade being used as a hospital with its poem written by
Capt. Ira Davenport who was wounded during the Battle of LaVergne,
and the skirmishes along Stones River.
It would be impossible to list all the early families of LaVergne-only
a few are listed and then not in any special order: Kimbro, Hill,
Buchanan, Fly, May, Nance, Williams, Davis, Goodman, Morton, Thompson,
6. Walter Hoover Collection, Smyrna
7. Ernest King Johns Collection, Smyrna
8. Mary Kate, Heroine of LaVergne, Marian Herndon Dunn
9. Charles W. McKay, Attorney, Louisville
66
Carter, Nelson, Mason, Banton, Butler, Roulhac, Charton, Hibbett,
Gooch, White, Mullins (Mulherrin), Neal , Green, Bailey, Stephens,
Mitchell, Hartman, Akin, Austin, Montgomery, Fergus, Tune, Wood, Noe,
Johnson, Finch, Seat, Coleman, Ewing, Cannon, Gregory, Owen, Goodloe,
King, Gowen, Merritt, Ferguson, Gambill, Burt, Cawthon, and others.
Like its sister communities, LaVergne fared badly during the
War Between the States and the reconstruction days were as difficult
there as in any other place. The railroad was probably the prime
factor that kept LaVergne's economy alive and the people's determin-ation
was another factor that kept it going. Education, religion,
and politics prevailed as major concerns of the city.
The first telephone was installed in the Burt home in 1904. The
Mason family, early Middle Tennessee and LaVergne settlers, had des-cendants
with vision and foresight. Although C. I. Mason was pres-ident
of the company. Miss Dora Mason was secretary and probably knew
more of the whole installation of that period than anyone else. The
company was sold to George Kersey and a partner and then later sold
to General Telephone Company. The present dial system was preceeded
by the old wall crank telephones. The receiver was picked up, The
crank turned, and "central" said. Number please." She also gave the
time of day, where someone could be reached on emergency, and other
gems of information. Mary Kersey and Ernestine Fergus were the best
operators in town--they were also about the only operators in town.
In 1925, the city was incorporated again Allen Mason was its
first mayor. Later, electricity was introduced and 0. B. Tucker,
67
father of Mason Tucker of the RUTHERFORD COURIER, was station agent
and was instumental in getting the electricity installed. Most new
things are met with resistance but the reluctance to accept electricity
held fears of instant and costly street lights to the city of LaV-ergne.
Yet progress pushed itself into being and electric lights
came to LaVergne.
The oldest church in LaVergne is the Saint James Christian Meth-odist
Episcopal Church organized by Rev. Columbus Walker in 1870. Two
of its members in 1972 were Mrs. Elizabeth Trimble and Mrs. Bertha
Peebles. Both worked on getting the church history prepared and both
were 94 years of age. The church might well be the oldest black
church in the county. Its location which has remained the same is
near the corner of Highway #41 and Stones River Road. It has an
active program and is an asset to the community.
Jefferson Pike Church of Christ got its start in 1920, on the
Jim Gowen land on Jefferson Pike. Harvey Merritt and Jeff Owens
were instrumental in getting the church started. Will and George
Merritt, twin sons of Harvey Merritt followed in their father's foot-steps
and taught Bible classes in the early church. In 1951, the
congregation purchased an acre of land from Bud Pope and the building
then on the property of Sadie Charlton Herndon was given as a gift.
The building was moved to its present location. Marian Herndon Dunn
has written the church history and the full text is to be published
in the LaVergne history.
Ira Knealand Hibbitt, son of Joseph Hibbett gave the land for the
68
LaVergne Presbyterian Church. Joseph's will divided his land between
his children and Ira's tract contained the "Ebenezer church lot and
Road." From Margaret A. Green's History of the LaVergne Presbyterian
Church, "the first building is described as large and wide a coin-modious
building constructed before the formal organization of the church.
The church minutes relate the rebuilding of the church after a de-vastating
tornado in 1914 on the same foundation. The original church
was established April 16, 1887. In 1969, the original property was
sold and the church relocated on 4 acres of land given by Emmett
Waldron at the corner of Cherokee Drive and Hilltop. The new church
was dedicated Sept. 10, 1972. The church minutes have been taken to
the Tennessee State Library and Archives for microfilming. The found-ation
of the church is thought to be that of the Ebenezer Methodist
Church and that one of its part time preachers was Benjamin Sewell
King, husband of Mary Neal King who kept the Diary in 1862.
The Miracle Baptist Church grew out of Mt. View Baptist Church
on Sept. 22, 1965. The First Baptist Church of LaVergne Sponsored the
new church. Rev. Bob Dowdy was its first pastor. The first worship
sership service was held Oct. 3, 1965, with 75 present in Sunday
School and 107 in worship service. By the end of May 1966, 231 were
enrolled in Sunday School. Dedication of its new building was held
May 5, 1968. The sanctuary seating capacity is about 300. Recently
plans were made to build a new sanctuary of greater size. The church
faces the Highway #41 in the Miracle Heights Subdivision.
LaVergne Church of Christ dates its existence back to beyond
1856. In a letter dated December 3, 1856, Joshua K. Spears reported
69
in the MillenJal Harbinger that the work of the church in LaVergne
was progressing. The first building was near the Davidson County
line at Buchanan Springs. The building was used and destroyed by the
Union Army. The second meeting house was where the old telephone
switchboard was housed. This one burned and since there was such
limited space at this location for hitching horses with wagons and
buggies, Mr. Billy Goodman offered the ground at its present location.
The new building was erected in 1886 nearer the road than its present
building. At the turn of the century, the government paid for the
destruction of the first building and with the aid of this money, the
building was remodeled and moved back to its present site. The church
has grown progressively and helps to support a congregation in Kentucky.
Jon Gary Williams is currently preaching there. The LaVergne Church
of Christ is the oldest continuous congregation in the city--125
years. The property is located on the Old Nasville Highway not too
far from the juncture of the highway and Stones River Road. It is a
fine red brick structure and has ample parking facilities.
First Baptist Church was organized February 10, 1956 and is now
located in Eastwood Subdivision facing the Old Nashville Pike. The
first lot was given by Mr. and Mrs. R. M. Baugh and the first build-ing
was constructed on Greenwood Drive. Rev. J. V. Braswell was its
first pastor. From a very small congregation to one of about 400
members has meant a steady and substantial growth. The building
is most attractive and seats about 400 persons. An education building
adjoins the sancturary and Nathan Hale is presently the pastor of
the church,
I
70
n
The LaVergne Free Will Baptist Church held its first meeting
April 28, 1968 at the home of Mr. and Mrs. Macon D. Green on Sandford
Road. Rev. D. L. Sharp was its first pastor. The growth of the
mission forced the expediency of finding much larger quarters and
the church used the LaVergne Civic Auditorium. The church had pur-chased
a lot on Mason Circle and when Sewart Air Base closed, the
church bought a building and furniture. The barracks type build-ing
has been completely refinished on the inside and bricked on
the outside, and it has made a lovely and important addition to
the community.
The St. Peter Primitive Baptist Church history was prepared by
Mrs. Bertha Peebles and Elder D. J. Carothers, Pastor. The Cumberland
Association of Primitive Baptists was organized by the Lynn Creek
Primitive Baptist Association in 1880. St. Peter Primitive Baptist
Church was first named Stewart Creek Primitive Baptist and was located
at Sand Hill. Their first meetings were held in a county school
-
house in 1896.
In 1918 the church began sponsoring activities to raise money
in an effort to erect a church building and land was purchased form
Mr. and Mrs. Ben Cartwright. It was located near the Jefferson Pike
railroad crossing and at this time the name was changed to St. Peters 's.
In 1943, Sewart Air Base boundary took the property and the church was
moved again. This time it was moved to Sanford Road.
Jefferson Pike Church of God is a relatively new church but it
11. History of the LaVergne Free Will Baptist Church, Charlotte Green
71
is one of the friendliest. Its first few years of existence found
it without a permanent meeting place. It met in a tent for a short
while on land owned by Mrs. Cora Mitchell and was located near Sewart
Air Base. Later services were held at the intersection of Jefferson
Pike and Old Nashville Highway. In December 1962 land was purchased
from Paul Waldron and the church is located on Hill View Drive.
There are only two church histories to be compiled for the city,
county, and state records. These are St. Paul's Church on Sanford
Road and Sand Hill Church of Christ. Mrs. Fannie Belle Paul Taylor
has submitted a fine history of Gilroy Church of Christ which is now
in Davidson County but was at one time in Rutherford County. Mt.
View Baptist Church also in Davidson County has many past and present
ties to the LaVergne community. The church will be asked for a church
history for the 1976 Bicentennial Celebration.
A history of the LaVergne Schools by Shirlie Chaney was printed
in the DAILY NEWS JOURNAL in the early 1960's. Walter King Hoover
included a portion of the history in his SMYRNA, THE CHURCH, THE TOWN
in addition to some good research of other schools. Several small
or one room schools listed were: Rock Springs, Paw Paw, Sinking Creek,
Hollandale, Independent Hill, Sanders School, Tipperary, and Blair
Schools but it would now be difficult to determine where many more
like those might have been. Often school would be held for children
in a neighborhood where the teacher/preacher boarded. In the early
days of county education, schools could be found on the property of
the persons representing school districts. Other schools in the
LaVergne area were located on Sanford Knob, the Johnnie Merritt
72
property, the Will Sutton property, on the Walter Mason farm now
inundated by the waters of the Percy Priest Reservoir, on near the
old railroad depot, another near the LaVergne Church of Christ. In
addition, ther was the Allen and Wallace School for Boys, a prepar-atory
school located behind the "Rock Store" now housing the Glass
Contractors of Tennessee, Inc. The Women's College located across
the street from the Boys school was really more of a finishing
School for girls. It became the LaVergne Academy and like others
in the county was really an equivalent to a secondary school.
County records do not pre-date 1925, and from that period until
1960 there was a slow steady growth. From the 60' s to the present
date, the amount of student enrollment has far out-numbered the pro-jected
estimates. When the students moved to an 8-room new school'
on Stones River Road in November 1961, it housed only six grades.
At the present time it has 550 enrollment, houses K-5 grades, and
is in desperate need of additional space.
12
Walter Hoover wrote, "Throughout this era (1850-1920), down the
dusty roads, through the wood, across the fields trudged the barefoot
children in search of the three R's and a knowledge of history and
the world outside their circumscribed farm-bound lives. Soberly
clad in dull homespun clothing and earring their midday meal in a
bucket or a basket, they walked the miles to the rude and uncomfortable
and poorly equipped one-room schools." These words well describe
the limitations the young people had in those days but there is no
way of telling how many mental business giants emanated from these
12. SMYRNA, THE CHURCH, THE TOWN, P. 259, Walter Hoover
73
humble beginnings.
In 1972 the city again was incorporated and Vester Waldron was
elected mayor with C. A. Chaney and A. C. Puckett as commissioners.
In 1974 Jack Moore and Joe Montgomery were added to the city comm-issioner
offices. Homer Kuykendall is City Manager and Virginia
Frizzell is Secretary. The city was preceeded by the Utility Dis-trict
form of government, however, it restricted itself to the ac-quisition
and management of an adequate water supply.
Interchange City has become an Industrial Park off 1-24 between
Rutherford and Davidson Counties. The land is being developed by
Robert McDowell Enterprises and includes several large companies.
Emniett Waldron who once owned this land used to say, "Its's a good
day, but the best is yet to come!" Francis Roulhac, another previous
owner of the land who is buried atop a hill in Interchange City would
also agree the best is yet to come.
Time has now come to plan for the nation's second birthday and
the LaVergne Bicentennial plans have been set into motion. A census
record is being prepared by A. C. Puckett, Jr., Jack Moore with the
help of the Rescue Squad: a servicemen's roster is being compiled
by the Lion's Club to commemorate all servicemen from LaVergne to
serve their country: Old Timers Day and Homecoming is being planned
by Mayor Waldron and his large committee: a parade is scheduled for
July 1976 with Joe Montgomery and Charles Talley serving as chairmen:
a city park is being planned to provide ample recreation facilities
for the youth of the community: the city's churches are to be hon-
74
ored by having date markers placed at each church: the business
community will have plans for participation in this program with
Jim Bowles of Firestone as chariman. The Men's Club and Home Dem-onstration
Club will plan the 1976 Bicentennial ceremonies.
Victor DeLaVergne, a family descendant and attorney from New
Orleans is to send the city a tree brought from France for the Bi-centennial
Celebration. It will be suggested the city plant a Ma-gnolia
tree in its park every August 23 to commemorate Roulhac and
LaVergne's past, and its promise of a bright future.
</dc:description>
<dc:description>A short history of the town of Lavergne in Rutherford County</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Lavergne (Tenn.); Rutherford County (Tenn.) -- History; Stones River (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>La Vergne</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-15</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication06ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/103</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>