<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Uncle Aggie McPeak's grist mill</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Dillon, Pauline M.</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 10</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1978</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>19th century; 20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>59
UNCLE AGGIE McPEAK'S GRIST hCCLL
Mrs. Pauline M. Dillon
Uncle Aggie McPeak's grist mill was located in Rutherford County,
16th district, on a farm about 1/2 mile north of the Bradley's Creek
Baptist Church on Bradley's Creek and was owned by P. A. McPeak (Uncle
.Iggie) ,
It vfas a two-story wooden building that partly hovered over a thick
rock-cemented sqiiare v;all or sl;iic&amp;-way vd.th gates that could be raised
or lowered at each end to control the flow of the water. This sluice-way
contained the water wheel which was at the end of the mill dam.
This mill dam \!as made up of big thick rock-fence type rocks and covered
horizontally and securely with long wooden planks. The top of the dam
was mrach higher than the banks of the creek and was shaped like the
half of a house top that went sloping downward to the creek bed. The
dam formed a mill pond above the dam which reserved the water for the
power used in the grinding.
On the front of the bizilding was a porch. The patrons came to
mill on horseback vd.th their huge sacks of shelled com behind them and
would unload them on this porch.
Uncle Aggie would then roll the sacks of corn into the mill with
a two-wheeled, steel-tire push wagon or cart, take out the toll corn
with a small red cedar square box measure and pour it into a big unused
hog-scalding box with the other toll corn.
He would take the rest of the sack of com and pour it into a big
60
wooden hopper that was built abovo the big mill stones to be groiind
into Eeal. As tho corn \ras being groimd or crushed between these huge
mill stones, tho meal came out beneath in a little trough onto which
the patron's sack was fastened. Vflien finished grinding, Uncle Aggie,
the dusty miller, removed the sack of meal, tied it securely and the
patron would be on his way. Then came the next patron and so on.
Sometimes the mill stones needed sharpening, and it took a skilled
mill Wright to do the job. The one that came here was on old French-man
by the name of DeHaven who was a traveling mill wright. He came
by once or twice a year and sometimes would stay a week while doing
the job.
Uncle Aggie (P. A. McPeak) died in 1912. After that, his son,
Charlie W, McPeak, probably operated the mill intermittenly for a few
years, maybe until about 1918.
Now the mill is gone, also the mill dam and rock-wall sluice-xmy.
The heavy rains with their high flood waters gradually washed
them away.
There's nothing left of the old mill but the two huge mill stones
\Aich are reserved and kept in memory of the old Ifeicle Aggie McPeak
grist mill that he operated from 1878 - 1912.
Mrs. Pauline M. Dillon
Granddaughter
From Down Memory Lane</dc:description>
<dc:description>Presents a short description of the old grist mill that operated on Bradley's Creek</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>bodies of water; creeks; mills</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Lascassas</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>3 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-16</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication10ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/168</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>