<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Charles Ready, Sr.</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Stacey, Ray</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 26</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1986</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1770-1779; 1780-1789; 1790-1799; 1800-1809; 1810-1819; 1820-1829; 1830-1839; 1840-1849; 1850-1859</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>75
CHARLES READY, SR.
Submitted by
Ray Stacey
Charles Ready, Sr. (b. April 1, 1770 at Salisbury,
MD, d. Aug. 3, 1859 at Readyville, Tenn.) was the son of
Baron and Elizabeth Dulaney Ready of Maryland. His
paternal grandparents were Bryan (Brian) and Catherine Kar
Ready of Maryland and Delaware.
Family tradition held that the original name of
the Ready (pronounced Reedy) family was "McReady" and
that they were a Scottish clan, many of whose members
came to America "on Lord Baltimore's ship" to escape
religious persecution. They were Presbyterians and
settled in Maryland. On arrival in this country they
dropped the "Mc" from the family name.
Recent research has found that there is no "clan
McReady" but, instead, a "Macreadie" family in the
Galloway district of Scotland which is entitled to wear
the Galloway tartan. No doubt this is the ancestral
family of the American Readys.
When Charles Ready was about six years old his
father died and his widowed mother removed with her two
sons to North Carolina to be near her sister and
76
brother-in-law, Caroline and William (Francis ?) Palmer,
whose daughter, Mary (b. 9-4-1773, d. 9-3-1848), Charles
married sometime before 1797. First cousin marriages
were not unusual at that time.
The Ready and Palmer families moved to South
Carolina where they i lived for a short time in the Edgefield
and Fairfield Districts before emigrating by wagon train
to Tennessee in 1797. Charles and Mary Palmer Ready
settled for a short time In Sumner County where their
daughter, Nancy (dates not presently known) and Caroline
(b. 1800, d. 1873) were born.
In 1802 Charles purchased a large tract of land
on the east fork of Stone's River from General Griffith
Rutherford, a part of his Revolutionary War land grant.
This land was at that time in Davidson County, but in
1804 became a part of Rutherford when that county was
formed from Davidson and VJilliamson.
Charles Ready was one of the signers of the petition
dated Aug. 10, 1806 asking for the creation of a new
county, and v/hen the request v;as granted he was appointed
one of the seven members of the first Court of Pleas
and Quarter Sessions, serving as presiding officer.
Soon after taking possession of his land, Charles
built a log home near a large chalybeate spring and set
about developing his property.
77
In 1805 the first railitia companies in Rutherford
County were organized and Charles Ready is listed in
Capt. Alexander McKnight's Co.
In 1816 the Stones River Presbyterian Church was
organized and Charles and his wife, Mary (Polly), were
charter members. Charles served as an elder for many
years
.
In 1811 a Post Office was established on the Ready
property and given the name "Readyvil le . " Chaitles
became the first Postmaster. Also, in 1811, he was
named one of seven commissioners appointed by the state
legislature to choose the permanent Rutherford County seat.
Part of the Ready land was considered as a site. Charles
entertained the commissioners with a lavish dinner at
his home but lost the vote, four to three, to the land
offered by William Lytle, which grew into the present city
of Murf reesboro.
In 1813 Charles Ready built a dam on Stone's
River near his home and erected a mill on the site of
the present Readyville mill.
In the late 1820s bricks, made on the place, were
ready for building "an elegant house," and in the early
1830s construction was completed on the three story
dwelling v/hich was named "The Corners." It housed his
78
growing family, which included ten children, and at times
is said also to have served as an inn for travelers.
Family tradition says that three presidents, Andrew
Jackson, Martin Van Buren, and James K. Polk, were guests
there. For a brief period of time Charles experimented
with growing silkworms in the third floor rooms of the
house and planted mulberry trees on his property to supply
their food. This attempt at establishing a silk industry,
however, proved to be an unsuccessful venture and was
soon abandoned. Otherwise, he continued to prosper and
was recognized as one of the wealthiest and most influential
citizens of the county.
Charles Ready died at his home in his ninetieth
year and is buried beside his wife in the family cemetery
across the road from his home. His obituary in the
"Murf reesboro News" August 10, 1859 speaks of his
accomplishments, his industry, energy, prudence,
honesty and kindness and notes that: "He leaves a
numerous progeny who are scattered over the Southern
and Western States. They will lament his departure
but they will cherish his memory with pride and pleasure."
79
Children of Charles Ready, Sr.
and his wife, Mary Palmer Ready
1. Nancy Ready, dates not yet discovered, m. Joshua
Haskell (1st mayor of Murf reesboro) , known 5 children.
2. Caroline Ready, b. 1800, d. 1873, m. (1) Dr. Benjamin
Hancock, 9/25/1819, known 5 children, m. (2) Enoch
Jones, 1861 (she was his 3rd wife)
.
3. Charles Ready, Jr., b. 12/22/1802, d. 6/4/1878,
m. 5/19/1825 to Martha Strong, b. 3/18/1807,
d. 8/27/1877, known 8 children.
4. Aaron Ready (twin of Charles, Jr.), b. 12/22/1802,
d. 1854 (?), m. 2/23/1830 to Jerusha Sims, children
of this marriage mentioned in will of Charles Ready,
Sr. but not named.
5. Eliza Ready, b. 12/31/1805, d. 3/7/1875, m. Lafayette
Burrus, b. 11/21/1797, d. 11/7/1851, known 13
children.
6. William Ready, b. 1805, d. 11/14/1839, m. 12/13/1832
Isabella C. Burkely, known 2 children.
7. Mary Ready, b. 1/17/1809, d. 3/26/1874, m. 5/16/1827
to James Holmes, b. 2/26/1795, d. 7/5/1850 in
County Donegal, Ireland, 9 known children.
8. Lucinda Ready, b. 12/29/1810, d. 2/12/1830, not
married.
80
9. Susanna Maria Ready (Moriah) , b, 1813, d. 1885,
m. Dr. John Barclay Armstrong, b. 1/20/1819,
d. 12/18/1873, 7 known children.
10. Jane Campbell Ready, b. 4/30/1815, d. 4/15/1876,
m. (1) 7/14/1835 to Dr. William Donaho, i child of
this marriage (?) , m. (2) Peter Coleman Tulley,
b. 11/17/1800, d. 12/16/1884, 8 known children of
this marriage.
This is an incomplete chart. Any corrections or
additions are requested.
Sarah H. Brown
126 N. Sequoia Drive
Springfield, TN 37172
Grandchildren of Charles Ready, Sr.
and his wife, Mary Palmer Ready
1. Children of Nancy Ready and Joshua Haskell
1. Mary Ann Haskell, m. William Porter.
2. William T. Haskell, famous orator, b. 7/31/1818,
d. 3/12/1859.
3. Ellen Virginia Haskell.
4. Martha Lucinda Haskell.
5. Maria Jane Haskell (changed to Jane Maria),
m. Robert Searcy.
81
Children of Caroline Ready and Dr. Benjamin Hancock.
1. Benjamin Hancock, died young.
2. Mary Hancock, m. T. N. Wendell.
3. Harriett Hancock, m. Mr. ? Stewart.
4. Erasmus Darevin Hancock, b. 10/9/1822, d. 12/13/1891,
m. Fannie Dickson Murfree, b. 5/4/1834, d.
12/26/ ?.
5
.
John Hancock
Children of Charles Ready, Jr. and Martha Strong.
1. Charles Edmond Ready, b. 12/10/1830, d. 9/27/1856.
2. Martha 0. Ready (Mattie) , b. 6/22/1840,
d. 11/16/1887, m. (1) Gen. John Hunt Morgan
12/14/1862, m. (2) Judge W. H. Williamson,
1/30/1873.
3. Horace Ready, m. 11/13/1888, Mrs. Ingram B.
Collier nee Louisanna Cushman (he was her 3rd
husband)
.
4. Alice Ready, b. 11/9/1842, d. 9/7/1890,
m. Andrew B. Martin.
5. Ella Ready, m. Leland Jordan.
6. Mary Ready, m. Dr. William Cheatham.
7. Aaron F. Ready, died young.
8. Joseph Strong Ready, b. 2/15/1833, d. 1/29/1846 ?
82
4. Children of Aaron Ready and Jerusha Sims. Number
and names not presently known. They were mentioned
in will of Charles Ready, Sr.
5. Children of Eliza Ready and Lafayette Burrus.
1. Dr. William L. Burrus.
2. Lucian B. Burrus, Arkansas planter.
3. Ophelia Maria Burrus, d. 1856, m. Gen. Joseph B.
Palmer.
4. Robert A. Burrus, merchant, d. Memphis, TN 1879.
5. Francis Marion Burrus.
6. Cassandra Burrus, m. James M. Alexander.
7. Fletcher R. Burrus, b. 9/16/1844, m, 5/30/1871
Hattie Pointer of Pulaski, TN.
8. Lafayette Burrus, Jr.
9. Elizabeth M. Burrus, m. George W. Howse.
10. Dr. Joseph C. Burrus, d. before 1888, Napoleon, ARK.
11. Lucy Burrus, m. P. D. McCullock.
12. Martha A. Burrus, died in young ladyhood,,
very beautiful.
13. Sophia Emma Burrus, m. F. H. Lytle, also a
beauty.
6. Children of William Ready and Isabella C. Burkley.
1
.
Catherine Ready
2
Mary Ready
83
7. Children of Mary Ready and James Holmes.
1. Robert Holmes, b. 4/24/1830, d. 8/24/1835.
2. Charles Holmes, b. 8/8/1831, d. 3/1/1911,
m. (1) Sallie Wade, (2) Fannie Wood
3. Lucinda Holmes, b. 10/3/1833, d. 8/19/1879,
m. James Martin
4. John Holmes, b. 11/20/1835, d. 12/20/1901,
m. (1) Martha Hare, (2) name not known.
5. William Francis Holmes, b. 5/26/1840, d. 2/7/1919,
m. 11/26/1872 Minta C. Hall, b. 4/22/1854,
d. 9/25/1902.
6. James Holmes, b. 11/14/1842, d. 9/2/1864, not
married, died in Confederate Army in battle.
7. Samuel Holmes, b. and d. 4/7/1845.
8. Mary Holmes, b. 4/5/1846, d. 12/21/1921,
m. Capt. Jonathon Nichol.
9. David Edwin Holmes, b. 1/2/1849, d. 10/14/1932,
m. (1) Sallie Enoch Hare. (2) Lula McKnight.
8. Lucinda Ready, no issue.
9. Children of Susanna Maria Ready and Dr. John Barclay
Armstrong.
1. Thomas Temple Armstring.
2. Mary Ready Armstrong.
3. Le Vanda (Van) Armstrong.
84
4. Laura Maria Armstrong.
5. John B. Armstrong.
6. Susan A. Armstrong.
7. Betania Armstrong.
10. Children of Jane Campbell Ready and Dr. William
Donaho, 1 son ?
Of Jane and Peter Coleman Talley.
1. Ada Juliette Talley, b. 9/28/1843, d. 7/9/1916,
m. 1/14/1862 Dr. James Brickell Murfree,
b. 1835, d. 1912.
2. Mary Talley, m. Mr. Spence.
3. Emma J. Talley, b. 7/9/1848, d. 4/29/1920, m.
8/12/1867 Albert Jetton.
4. D. H. Talley.
5. Leslie Talley, b. 1850.
6. Francis Talley, b. 1852.
7. Edwin Talley, b. 1854.
8. Walter Talley, b. 1859.
This is an incomplete chart. Grandchildren may
not be listed in birth order. Corrections and additions
are requested. Some lines have been carried several
generations further.
85
SOURCES
The Goodspeed Historys . Reprinted from Goodspeed:
History of Tennessee, 1886.
Canon County by Robert L. Mason.
Rutherford County Tennessee Cemetery Records , by
Jill K. Garrett and Iris H. McClain.
Bible Records and Marriage Bonds , by Jeanette T. Aclalen.
Bible Records and Tombstone Inscriptions by Jeanette T.
Aclalen.
A History of Rutherford County , Carlton C. Sims, Editor.
The Story of Murf reesboro , C. C. Henderson.
Hearthstones , Mary B. Hughes.
"History of Readyville," Miss Mary Hall, Rutherford County
Historical Society . Publication No. 4.
Tennessee Cousins , Worth S. Ray.
Family papers of Lucinda Holmes Couey and Martha Bone
Crowe
.
Notes from Conversations with David Holmes (1849-1932),
a grandson of Charles Ready, Sr.
Archives of the Presbyterian Church, Montreat, NC
.
Records of The Scotch House, London, England.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Presents a short biography of Charles Ready, Sr., with several pages of genealogical information</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.); Murfreesboro (Tenn.); Morgan, John Hunt, 1825-1864; Ready, Charles, 1802-1878</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Ready, Charles, 1770-1859; genealogy</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro; Readyville</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>11 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-01</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication26ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/127</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>