<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Footprints in the mud and dust at Smyrna, Tennessee</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hoover, Walter K.</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 19</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1982</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>19th century; 20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>FOOT PRINTS IN THE MUD AND DUST
AT SMYRNA, TENNESSEE
By Walter K. Hoover
To the north of the present Smyrna railroad depot by horse and buggy,
about a mile on the now unused dirt road that led to the Jefferson Pike,
the old Gooch and Nelson homes, in the vicinity of where the Hart's Branch
empties into the Stewart's Creek, stood an early Presbyterian Church by
the name of Smyrna. The name Smyrna was derived from a biblical church in
Asia Minor mentioned by the Apostles in their writings in the Bible records.
The families that worshipped here, populated the rich bottom lands
along the Stewart's Creek and Stones River and were first and second gener-ations
of the early settlers.
To the south of Smryna on the Nashville-Murfreesboro stage road or
toll pike was a community known as Stewartsboro. This consisted of stage
stop, post office, blacksmith shops, merchants, etc. Olive Grove M.E. Church
was in this vicinity.
By the 1850 's the Nashville or Mid-Tennessee area was producing many
products-cotton, livestock, wheat, wool, corn and etc. Having no market
except by wagon or boat to New Orleans, the area conceived and built the
railroad to get these products to Chattanooga where an existing railroad
would take them to Charleston, S.C. and the world markets, by ship. Cotton
went to the mills in England and came back as cloth and cotton products.
As the railroad was being completed 1851-1855, it was decided to have
a station between these two communities. Mr. John F. Tucker and brother
Silas Tucker, who owned the land where the present depot is located were
given the privilege of naming the station. They being devout Presbyterians,
and members of this early church, chose the name Smyrna.
In 1855 the railroad company bought a track of land on the east side
of the railroad tracks, adjacent to the depot which was subdivided, laid
off in lots and streets. These lots were soon sold thus forming the town
of Smyrna.
3
In a few years came the smoke, fire and destruction of the Civil War. Most
of the plans and hopes for Smyrna were swept away in the five years of conflict
over, in, and around Smyrna, and the new railroad.
Yet just four years after this ordeal of war, and amid the union domination
of the Tennessee legislature, and the destitute conditions, Smyrna asked for,
and acquired a Charter of Incorporation in 1869.
I have discovered that in 1869-71, Mr. Joseph R. Dillin, a unionist, was
a representative from Rutherford County in the House of Legislature. Mr. Dillin
had a new home completed in 1865-67 known today as the old Tucker house on Oak
Street in Smyrna. This house was not in the Smyrna Corporation limits. The
Brainard Cheneys live there today. The house is a beautiful two story brick
of that period. Joseph had a brother who ran a general merchandise store on lot
number 20, 1855 map. Joseph was a lawyer and the family was apparently quite
wealthy.
The Dillin family left Smyrna soon after the Civil War.
The Senator from Rutherford County 1869-71 was Mr. William Spence. Don't
know where he lived. I wonder how these people related to the new Charter of
Incorporation.
By word of mouth I had been informed that Mr. Joseph Engles had been the
first Mayor of Smyrna, 1869. By evidence of record I knew his son Dr. J. W.
Engles to be the first mayor of Smyrna under a new and different Charter of
Incorporation in 1915. ,
Let me relate to you the circumstances that brought the following evidence
to my attention. Evidence that shows the Engles family took care to preserve
the record book of the 1869 to 1881 City of Smyrna records, only to come back to
light be sheer circumstance.
This book itself, evidently was left in Smyrna by some officer of the Union
Army during the Civil War. It is a large ledger type book seventeen and one
half inches tall, eleven and one half inches wide (when closed), leather bound,
quite shaken or loose, worm eaten, and dirty, yet the contents are still legible.
c(3
&#169;0
laV'Bn^ a[
mn
ma
I&#8212;
I
o
&#8226;paSiBl[DSIQ
&#8226;|B^idso&#163;] nj
&#8226;jjoig naJi^x
&#8226;jB^idsoH ai
&#8226;^U'BduiOQ
I
Mi
"R
^
(See Insert of one of the pages) . So four years after the war when Smyrna needed
the then scarce item of paper material to record the incorporation, and continuing
minutes and records, some one came up with this Civil War record book. It proved
to be an excellent choice.
Never in my memory, or in any records have I discovered any mention of these
records, until in 1968-69 when the Tennessee State Highway Department was purch-asing
right-of-way for Interstate 1-24, in the vicinity of Almaville Road, Will
Neely and wife Ella(Engles) Neely, living on a farm in that vicinity, were forced
to sell and evacuate. Ella was the daughter of our first Mayor Dr. J. W. Engles
of 1915 Incorporation, and, he the son of Joseph Engles first mayor of 1869
Incorporation. Dr. Engles lived with this daughter Ella in his latter years,
having died several years ago.
This Neely-Engles house was located on a knob directly in the northeast
quadrant of the 1-24 Almaville Road Interchange.
Two neighbors, brothers Ellis and Mitchell McGowan, tore down this Neely
house and moved everything remaining off the property. Evidently this book
was part of the remains.
The McGowan brothers being of an early family and still maintaining an old
home place nearby took much of the material there. Their home was across the
branch from the early Brown and later Isam Peebles home. Ellis having married
and living in a new house near by, Mitchell a bachelor remained at the old
home. Mitchell died in 1970, February 28, after which the McGowan house was
not used for a dwelling. Sometime there after several boys prowling through
the old house came upon this old book and secretly brought it to Smyrna where
they lived. Ellis McGowan living nearby, discovered the break-in and made
some attempt to discover who. I am not aware of what else may have been
taken, if any.
The boys not wanting to be discovered, secreted the book, but discovering
the content could not keep quiet. On several occasions one of the boys came
to me, knowning my great interest in Smyrna history, in a feeble attempt to
learn of its value, or to sell it to me.
I never saw the book or knew of its content and for many months. It
disappeared again. Eventually the book was placed in the public library at
Smyrna, where I got my first look at it.
An important piece of evidence of Smyrna history, it is now secured in the
Smyrna Room of the library, microfilmed, pages laminated and available for research.
This story is interesting evicbice of where this book has been for about
one hundred years and how it came to where it is today.
The following is copied from the Acts of the Tennessee Legislature of
1869. Dewit C. Senter, a conservative Republican was governor.
Town of Smyrna.
Officers.
How elected.
Sheriff to hold
election,
etc.
Sec. 19. Be it further enacted that the inhabitants of
the Town of Smyrna, in the County of Rutherford, are hereby
constituted a corporation and body politic, by the name and
style of the "Mayor and Aldermen of the Town of Smyrna",
and by that name shall have perpetual succession; shall sue
and be sued; plead and be impleaded in all courts of law
and equality, and in all actions whatsoever; may purchase,
receive and hold property, real and personal, within said
town, or without, its limits for corporate purposes, and
may lease, sell, or dispose of the same for the benefit of
said town; and may make such contracts for public grounds and
promenades, as may be deened beneficial to said town; they
shall have and use a common seal, and shall change it at
pleasure.
Sec. 20. Be it further enacted, that the officers of the
town shall consist of a mayor, five aldermen, a town constable,
and a treasurer. The mayor shall act and have all the rights
and powers of a recorder, in addition to his other powers
and privileges; he shall be exempt as a juryman, or from
serving on juries. Other officers deemed necessary by the
mayor and aldermen shall be elected and authorized by a vote
of the mayor and aldermen.
Sec. 21. Be it further enacted, that the mayor and aldermen
shall be elected by the qualified voters of said corporation;
that all parties owning property within the corporate limits
of said town, whether actual residents of the town or not, if
said parties are qualified voters, under the laws of the State
of Tennessee; that all officers of the corporation shall hold
their offices for one year and until their successors are
elected and qualified.
Sec. 22. Be it further enacted, that the sheriff of the
County of Rutherford, shall open the polls in said town, on
the 20th day of December for the purpose of electing officers
of the corporation; and shall issue certificates to the parties
receiving the highest number of votes, which certificate shall
become a part of the records of said corporation; and upon the
presentation of such certificates from the sheriff, the party
holding the same shall be sworn as such corporate officer, by
any justice of the peace of said county, to whom the same may
be presented; provided that no person shall be eligible or
qualified as mayor or alderman, who is not a housholder within
and an actual resident of the corporate limits.
Vacancies.
General
powers and
privileges.
Streets, etc.
Buildings,
Taxes
.
Sale of
provision,
etc.
Breaches of
ordinances,
etc.
Sec. 23. Be it further enacted, that all vacancies occur-ing
by death, resignation or removal, shall be filled by a
vote of the mayor and aldermen or by the aldermen, if the
vacancy be that of the mayor.
Sec. 24. Be it further enacted, that the number of alder-man
of said corporation shall be five, who shall, in connection
with the mayor, elect a town constable.
Sec. 25. Be it further enacted, that the mayor and alder-men
shall have power, by ordinance, with the town;
1st. To levy and collect taxes upon all property taxable
by law, for State purposes.
2nd. To levy and collect taxes upon all privileges and
polls taxable by the laws of the State; provided that the poll-tax
shall not exceed two dollars annually, and provided that no
person shall vote in said corporation, who, at the time he
presents his ballot, has not paid his corporation poll-tax for
twelve months last past.
3rd. To appropriate money provided for the payment of
the debts and expenses of the town, by levy of a special tax,
when the same shall be necessary.
4th. To make regulations to prevent the introduction of
contagious diseases into said town, and to prevent and remove
nuisances; to open alleys; to abolish, widen, extend, establish,
grade, pave, or otherwise improve, clean and keep in repair
streets, alleys and side-walks, or to have the same done at the
expense of the owners of the grounds fronting thereto, when
they refuse, after notice, to have the same work done.
5th. To establish, support and regulate a night-watch
and patrol.
6th. To erect a calaboose or lock-up, and regulate the
government of the same.
7th. To provide for the erection of all buildings neces-sary
for the use of the town, and to pass laws making the
injury, defacing, or destruction thereof, a misdemeanor.
8th. To regulate, license and tax auctioneers, grocers,
merchants, and druggists of every description, retailers,
taverns, brokers, coffee-houses, confectionaries, retailers,
of liquors, hawkers and peddlers, livery stable keepers, and
all other matters within the corporation limits; and especially
shows, exhibitions and amusements.
9th. To prohibit and suppress all disorderly and bawdy
houses, houses within, or near proximity to the corporate
limits.
10th. To provide for the inspection and weighing of stone,
coal, measuring of wood, and all other fuel, also hay, corn,
and all other grain; to regulate the inspection of butter,
lard and other provision; and to make such general provi-sions
with regard to the vending of meats, poultry, fish and
vegetable, as well protect the town against impositions, and
preserve the rights of vendees, as well as that of the venders.
11th. To impose fines, forfeitures and penalties for
the breach of any ordinance, and to provide for the recovery
of the same; with full power to imprison offender or offenders
for refusal or failure to discharge or secure, according to
ordinance, fines imposed upon them, either in the county jail
or town calaboose, for a period not exceeding ten days; to
provide for the arrest and confinement, either in the cala-boose
or county jail, of all disorderly persons within
8
the town by day or by night; to authorize the arrest of all
suspicious persons, and the detention thereof, who may be
found violating the ordinances of said corporation.
Violations of 12th. To prevent and punish by pecuniary penalties
the peace, and imprisonment all violations of the peace and disorderly
penalties, conduct, within the corporate limits; and to suppress any
etc. disorderly conduct or unusual noise in any house, or upon
any premises in said town, by arresting and punishing the
parties creating the same. The mayor said town shall have
full power, in his capacity as mayor, and in his capacity
as justice of the peace, to assess fines, render judgments
and issue executions thereon; and the same shall be in all
respects binding, unless the party fined shall appeal to the
Circuit Court of said county, in which case the mayor, in his
capacity as such, or in his capacity as justice of the peace,
shall certify up the papers, which papers so certified, shall
be received in the Circuit Court, or other Superior Court, as
evidence; the usual bond shall be given in all cases of appeal.
Officers to 13th. The mayor and aldermen shall have all the powers and
give bond. enjoy all the privileges usually enjoyed by other corporate
bodies of a similar nature..
Sec. 26. Be it further enacted that all of the officers
of said corporation, who, by law, are entrusted with any of
the funds of said corporation, shalL be required to give bond,
to be approved by the mayor and aldermen of said town.
Boundry of Sec. 27. Be it further enacted, that the Corporation of
Corporation. Smyrna shall be bounded as follows: Beginning in the center
of Hart's Branch, under the Nashville and Chattanooga Railroad
bridge, which is over said branch; thence running up said branch
eight poles; thence parallel with the Nashville and Chattanooga
Railroad in an eastern direction to the center of a county
road, which leads from Smyrna depot to the Nashville and Murfreesboro
Turnpike, intersecting said pike near and east of Old Stewartsboro;
thence on a line perpendicular to said Nashville and Chattanooga
Railroad; thence with the line of J. R. Dillin to the north
bank of Hart's Branch; thence with said north bank of said branch
to the Nashville and Chattanooga Railroad; thence with said road
to the beginning.
Responsible Sec. 28. Be it further enacted, that the Corporation of
for fees. Smyrna shall be responsible to the officer of said town for all
fees due by reasons if inability of the parties to pay said
fees, who have been arrested for violating the coporate laws.
Constable. Sec. 29. Be it further enacted, that the constable of
said town shall have full and complete authority to receive
executions, levy the same, and sell property for the collection
of fines and forfeitures, and shall be liable by action before
any justice of the peace, for any failure to promptly dis-charge
his duties.
Sec. 30. Be it further enacted, that no description of
property shall be exempt from execution for fines or
forfeitures.
Sec. 40. Be it further enacted, that this act shall take
effect from and after its passage.
SMYniSATSAOV
iijoa i'-
'.Post efj^/cf
^A/r ^e&lt;L T/cA/ fie /uses
Thfs Aj^/fjP Aif^Je -Tfe/w
supt/eys //y /y?^ ^y A
^
\,. ^&gt;:-r
' :.,//y
V" '
.'^.^ &#187; ./ /{ M'Mi"H&gt;^"&gt;.*
\
\
\
\
\
T't ''&#8226;&#8226;^""''&#8226;&#187;'
:&#8226;/.}
I, .S,.'&#187;"
',Urx M.&lt;&#8222;in,'.'l
'"^
&lt;.:.: /iSM, &#8226;,n (iiu .V II', III /'iirfor
It I,
\
/&#8226;. &#8226;* 'Kit '': /I. ''Ml \
A ,
1- ^^ ^
\ la ir ' "7&gt;t_,&#8212;:=^&#8212;'^^^-. COTTON HIIL^l Jl.^-- '^&#187;i:,t..J^l.i&#8222;fJi. ^ '"^
\
10
W. O'N. Perkins
Speaker of the House of Representatives
D.B. Thomas
Speaker of the Senate
Passed December 10, 1869
So that the readers may orientate themselves to the life styles of
these times, I offer these thoughts.
These citizens of Smyrna had no telephone, no bathrooms, no automobiles,
airplanes or television, no side walks or paved streets.
They had few neighbors, few schools or churches, few fine clothing or
shoes. Hard work and small pay. Many daily domestic chores to maintain
comfort and survival.
The woods and the fields were intimate, church was the center of
social life. Entertainment consisted of a school box-supper, a traveling
show, a Sunday buggie drive to grandmothers or a visit to a neighbor.
Good books, sewing or needle work, a vegetable garden and canning
food, wood cutting, feeding the livestock, drawing water, making fires,
hogkilling, and harvesting kept them busy. All this is done today be modern
energy and machines.
&#8212;Walter K. Hoover
RECORD OF THE CORPORATION OF SMYRNA COPIED FROM MINUTE BOOK
December 20, We the undersigned judges and clerks appointed to open
1869. and hold an election at Smyrna on December 20, 1869 do
certify that Joseph Engles received twenty five votes
for mayor. James W. Hight twenty five votes for town
constable, R. H. Dudley, J. T. Gooch, J. L. Elder and
J. L. Poynor twenty five votes each for aldermen and
L. B. White twenty one votes for aldermen; Clerks:
J. L. Poynor, L. B. White: Judges: J. T. H. Lenoir,
J. W. Wright, T. J. Reed.
I, John H. Adkerson, Deputy Sheriff of Rutherford County
deputized to open and hold an election in the town of
Smyrna in said county on the 20th day of December 1869
for the purpose of electing a mayor and five aldermen,
do certify that in accordance to previous notice I have
opened and held said elections and that Joseph Engles received
the highest number of votes for mayor, that James W. Hight
the highest number of votes for constable, and R. H. Dudley,
J. T. Gooch, J. T. Elder, J. L. Poynor and L. B. White the
highest number of votes for aldermen. This December 20, 1869.
J. H. Adkerson, Deputy Sheriff
11
On December 20, 1869, J. R. Dlllin, Esquire, qual?,fied the
mayor and aldermen, to witt, Joseph Engles as mayor, John L.
Poynor, R. H. Dudley, J. L. Elder, L. B. White and James T.
Gooch as aldermen. Also J. W. Hight as constable.
December The mayor and aldermen had a meeting on the 22nd of
22, 1869. December and ordained the following laws to govern the
incorporation of Smyrna the mayor being in the chair.
1. Be it ordained by the mayor and aldermen of the town
of Smyrna, that any person or persons who may be convicted
before the mayor for the offense of selling spiritous or
mault liquors, wine or cider on the Sabbath, such person or
persons shall pay a fine in a siun of not less than five or
more than twenty five dollars for each offense.
2. Be if further ordained that any person or persons
who may be convicted of disturbing the public worship within
the corporate limits, such person, or persons, shall be fined
in the sum of not less than ten or more than twenty five
dollars for each offense.
3. Be it further ordained that every person that may be
convicted of being intoxicated and disturbing the public peace
within the corporate limits, shall be fined in a sum of not
less than one or more than ten dollars for each offense.
A 4 Be it further ordained, that any person that may be
convicted of firing within the corporate limits any rifle
or shotgun or pistol, shall be fined in the sum of not less
than one or more than five dollars for each offense.
5. Be it further ordained that any person or persons who
may be convicted of using obscene language or indecent
exposure of person shall be fined not less than two or more
than ten dollars for each offense.
6. Be it further ordained that each and every person
convicted of any offense against the corporation of the
Town of Smyrna, such person or persons shall pay all costs
occuring in the case, and such costs shall not exceed the
cost in criminal offense before magistrate.
7. Be it further ordained that any person or persons convicted
of using language to provoke the breach of the peace shall be
fined not less than one nor more than ten dollars for each
offense.
8. The fines being appropriated for the use and benefit
of the Town of Smyrna.
Attest
Joseph Engles, Mayor and Recorder
December 22. The mayor and aldermen then confirmed the election of
J. W. Hight for town constable, and then proceeded to the
election of a treasurer and two policemen. The elections
12
resulted in the election of J. L. Poynor for treasurer
and H. Hlght and John Hager as policemen. The mayor then
qualified Henry Hight and John Hager for the faithful dis-charge
of their duty. The meeting then closed and agreed
to meet every first and third Tuesday each month.
Attest
Joseph Engles, Mayor and Recorder
January 4, The mayor and aldermen met pursuant to adjournment and
1870. ordained the following laws:
Be it further ordained that any person or persons convicted
of gaming within the corporate limits shall be fined not less
than two or more than ten dollars for each offense, and
forfeit the funds at stake.
A motion was then made and second for the mayor to appoint
a committee of three including the mayor and two aldermen to
draft ordinances to rule the Corporation of Smyrna, to be sub-mitted
however to the vote of the Board of Aldermen for adoption.
The mayor then appointed J. T. Gooch and R. H. Dudley on said
committee.
The following ordinance was then paaed by a by-law. Be it
further ordained that the ordinary parlimentary rules are
adopted for the government of the board of mayor and aldermen.
The board then adjourned till the next regular meeting.
Joseph Engles , Mayor and Recorder
January 11, The mayor and aldermen met pursuant to adjournment there
1870. being no qurorum. No business was called and the board ad-journed
until next regular meeting.
January 18, There being no quorum present, adjourned until next regular
1870. meeting.
February 8, The mayor and aldermen met pursuant to adjournment and
1870. passed the following resolutions: Resolved that James W.
Hight be requested to solicit a subscription of the citizens
of Smyrna, and the neighborhood for the purpose of building
a police station within the said corporation, and to report
at the next regular meeting.
The board then proceeded to the election of one alderman,
there being vacancy by the removal of J. Elder out of the
corporation. Jobe being elected he was qualified as an
alderman.
The board then proceeded to the election of two policeman,
there being a vacancy of one policeman by the removal of
Henry Hight out of the limits of the corporation. Henry
Brewer was elected policeman also George Hight.
Alderman Poynor then presented his account for a docket
for the use of said corporation and the amount of five
dollars was allowed.
13
February 9,
1870.
February 22,
1870.
March 8,
1870.
The board then ordained the following law: Be it ordained
by the mayor and aldermen that any person or persons who may
be convicted of admitting any person or persons not being
connected with the saloon (drinking) into a saloon on Sunday,
within the corporate limits, shall be fined not less than ten
nor more than twenty five dollars for each offense.
The committee to draft by-laws allowed further time to make
report. The board then adjourned until next regular meeting.
The mayor qualified Henry Brewer as policeman for the
faithful discharge of his duty.
Joseph Engles, Mayor and Recorder
The Board of Mayor and Aldermen met pursuant to adjournment.
Mr. George Right refused to serve, the board proceeded to the
election of a policeman in his stead. Mr. B. W. Jackson being
nominated, was elected and qualified for the faithful discharge
of his duty.
The board then ordained the following ordinance: Be it
further ordained that we levy a privilege tax on all merchants,
drinking saloons, grocers, druggist of every description.
Retailers of liquors, hawkers, and peddlers, taverns, coffee
houses, livery sfeables, theatrical and other show, exhibitions
and amusements of five dollars each.
Be it further ordained that we levy a poll on each and every
person entitled to vote in the corporation of Smyrna, for the
office of mayor and aldermen of two dollars on each poll.
Be it further ordained that we levy a tax on all real estate
within the corporate limits of one eighth of one percent. A
resolution was then passed to pay Joseph R. Dillin for the copy
of a certified charter of the Corporation of Smyrna three
dollars being the price thereof.
An ordinance was then passed to appoint a committee of the
aldermen to select the place to build a calaboose, to adopt a
plan of the building, and to give the job of said building to
the lowest bidder and also to make a report on Saturday the 27th,
instant. The board then adjourned until next meeting.
Joseph Engles, Mayor and Recorder
The Board of Mayor and Aldermen met pursuant to adjournment
and passed the following ordinance: Be it further ordained
that any person or persons who may be convicted of peddling
without having paid the privilege tax or any other person
pursuing business for which a privilege tax has to be paid as
a business within the corporate limits, such person or persons
shall be fined not less than five nor more than twenty five for
each and offense.
The committee on building a calaboose made a report that
Mr. James Right agreed to build said calaboose for one hundred
and seventy five dollars, and furnish everything to complete
the building and do it up in workman like style.
Joseph Engles, Mayor and Recorder
March 12, There being an election ordered for a justice of the peace
1870. for the Town of Smyrna by an Act of General Assembly of Tennessee.
In accordance with said Act the election was held in the Town
of Smyrna on March 10, 1870 and the following is a true copy
of the certificate of the judges of said election. We the
undersigned judges and clerks of the etetion this day held in
the Town of Smyrna, Rutherford County, Tennessee for the purpose
of electing a justice of the peace for said town as per special
act of the General Assembly of Tennessee for the election of
said justice of the peace do certify that Joseph Engles received
the highest number of votes cast in this election March 10, 1870.
Clerks: J. W. Dillin, Ger. P. Thayor. Judges: J. P. H. Lenoic,
0. M. Davis.
14
March 16,
1870.
April 6,
1870.
May 17,
1870.
June 20,
1870.
Attest
Joseph Engles, Mayor and Recorder
There being no quorum the meeting adjourned to the next
regular meeting.
Joseph Engles, Mayor and Recorder
The Board of Mayor and Aldermen met pursuant to adjournment.
Motions made and adopted to receive the calaboose and to settle
with Mr. Hight the builder. The town constable reported that
he collected taxes to the amount of seventy four dollars and
eighty cents, and also ten dollars subscription money. Motion
was then made and adopted to pay Mr. Hight any money in the
treasury not otherwise appropriated and the treasurer to pay
the same. Motion was then made and adopted to pay the town
constable five percent of all the collections of taxes and
subscriptions. The board then proceeded to the election of an
additional policeman. The election resulted in the election
of John Lenoir. Motion was then made and adopted to relieve the
building committee and they were discharged from their duty.
Motion was then made to adjourn until next regular meeting.
It was adopted.
Joseph Engles, Mayor and Recorder
The Board of Mayor and Aldermen met pursuant to adjournment.
There being no business of any nature the board adjourned until
the next regular meeting.
The Board of Mayor and Aldermen met pursuant to adjournment.
Mr. Jackson and Brewer having removed to Nashville, the board
elected J. P. H. Lenoir policeman for the next twelve months.
The board then adjourned until the next meeting.
Joseph Engles, Mayor and Recorder
June 20,
1870.
July 20,
1870.
August 20,
1870.
September 20,
1870.
October 20,
1870.
December 10,
1870.
December 20,
1870.
December 20,
1870.
December f',0,
1870.
February 17,
1871.
Mr.J.P.H. Lenoir was qualified as policeman to discharge
his duty for the next twelve months or until his successor
was qualified.
There being no business the mayor and aldermen adjourned
till the next regular meeting.
There being no business the mayor and aldermen adjourned
till the next regular meeting.
Joseph Engles, Mayor and Recorder
There being no business the mayor and aldermen adjourned
till the next regular meeting.
Joseph Engles, Mayor and Recorder
The Board of Mayor and Aldermen met pursuant to adjournment
and passed the following ordinance: that every prisoner guilty
of violating any law of said corporation shall on refusing to
secure or pay his fine be confined in the tovm calaboose not
less than two or more than ten days.
Joseph Engles, Mayor and Recorder
Fines collected for the year 1870: $ 66.50
Assets as per vouchers on treasury and cash
and Hight (constable) $ 66.75
Balance due by recorder
Taxes collected and fines collected for 1870 $ 91.00
Expenses for calaboose, collecting taxes and book $185.10
A copy of charter $ 3.00
$188.10
There being an election held for mayor and aldermen.
Joseph Engles received the highest number of votes for mayor,
R. H. Dudley, John L. Poynor, J. T. Gooch, L. B. White and
J. T. Whitehead for aldermen and R. H. White, deputy sheriff
issued a certificate to that effect, he being the officer
appointed to hold said election.
Joseph Engles, Mayor and Recorder
Mr. Albert Henderson, Justice of the Peace for Rutherford
County, State of Tennessee then administered the oath of
office to the mayor elect for the faithful discharge of his
duty for the ensuing year.
Joseph Engles, Mayor and Recorder
Joseph Engles, Justice qualified the aldermen.
The Board of Mayor and Aldermen organized and proceeded to
the election of a constable and it resulted in the election of
J. W. Hight; they then appointed two policemen. George Hight
and John Hager and they also elected a treasurer, J. L. Poynor.
The Board of Mayor and Aldermen met pursuant to adjournment
there being a quorum present. They proceeded to levy a tax of
five dollars on all privileges and a poll tax of fifty cents
15
16
on each poll and tax on real estate of 1/3 of one percent
for the year of 1871. No further business appearing the
Board of Mayor and Aldermen adjourned till next meeting.
Joseph Engles , Mayor and Recorder
April 25, The Board of Mayor and Aldermen met pursuant to adjournment.
1871. A quorum present and the mayor presiding there being a vacancy
in the office of alderman and treasurer by the removal of John
L. Poynor, Alderman and Treasurer to Nashville. The board
proceeded to elect the alderman, 0. M. Davis being nominated
and was duly elected to fill the vacant term. The board then
proceeded to fill the vacancy of treasurer by electing J. T.
Whitehead for treasurer. Mr. J. T. Whitehead then gave bond
for one hundred dollars for the forthcoming of the corporation
fund that might come into his hands and also Mr. J. W. Right
gave bond for the same amount and same purpose. Joseph Engles,
Justice of the Peace then for Rutherford County then swore
0. M. Davis as alderman for the unexpired term of 1871 viz.
J. L. Poynor resigned.
The board then passed the following ordinance by a full
vote; that public worship in the Corporation of Smyrna shall
close every night at ten o'clock the welfare of the town of
citizens requiring the same. There being no further business
the Board of Mayor and Aldermen adjourned till regular meeting.
Joseph Engles, Mayor and Recorder
December 20, There being an election for mayor and aldermen said election
1871. resulted in the re-election of Joseph Engles, Mayor for the
year 1872 and in the election as aldermen, R. H. Dudley,
J. G. Gooch, 0. M. Davis, J. T. Brewer and John Hager. The
mayor was qualified by A. J. Henderson, a Justice of the Peace,
for the faithful discharge of his duties, the aldermen were
then sworn in for the faithful discharge of their duties. The
board elect adjourned then without delay.
Joseph Engles, Mayor and Recorder
January 15 The Board of Mayor and Aldermen met pursuant to adjournment
1872. and transacted the following business, to wit, to levy a tax
on livery stables, as of one dollar and fifty cents for the
year 1872, also a tax on real estate of 1/8 of one percent
for the year 1872, also a privilege tax of two dollars and
50 cents on liquor shops and merchants and peddlers and a
poll tax of seventy five cents for the year 1872. The board
then elected R. H. Dudley treasurer, he giving bond which was
approved. J. W. Hight was then elected constable for the year
of 1872 and tax collector, he also giving bond for the collect-ion
and paying over taxes which was approved. The board then
appointed J. G. Gooch and Oscar Davis and R. H. Dudley a
committee on streets. No further business appearing the
board adjourned without delay,
Joseph Engles, Mayor and Recorder
February 10, Henry C. Hight tendered his resignation as policeman
1872. and it was accepted.
Joseph Engles , Mayor and Recorder
December 20, There being an election of mayor and aldermen for the next
1872. twelve months held by A. W. Page, C.R.C. and deputy sheriff
on the 20th day of December 1872 and said election returns in
this office by said officer.
The election resulted in the election of Joseph Engles,
Mayor, R. H. Dudley, J. G. Gooch, John Hager, Dabny Carollson
as aldermen. The following is a true copy of the election
returns and the undersigned judges and clerks do certify that
this is a correct return of the election held today for the
purpose herein setforth. J. T. Brewer, John W. Hager, W. B.
Lowry, judges; S. E. Hager, O.S.C. Lowry, clerks.
A. W. Page, Receiver
May 5, The Board of Mayor and Aldermen met pursuant to adjourn-
1873. ment. John S. Ballentine and John Hager having moved away
and thereby being a vacancy of two aldermen the board elected
F. J. Sanders and S. Hager in their stead for the unexpired
term of the ensuing year. Mr. J. W. Hight was elected town
constable and sworn into office by the mayor.
The board then proceeded to levy a tax for privilege and
polls for the ensuing year to wit; on livery stables one
dollar and fifty cents per annum, real estate 1/8 of one
percent; one hundred dollars for liquor shops; merchant and
druggist, peddlers two and 50/100 dollars; poll tax seventy
five cents. The board then elected R. H. Dudley treasurer
for the ensuing year. No further business appearing the
board adjourned until Saturday the 10th of May 1873.
Joseph Engles, Mayor and Recorder
December 20, There being an election of mayor and aldermen for the next
1873. twelve months held by A. W. Page, Deputy Sheriff on the 20th
day of December 1873 and said election returns returned into
this office by said page duly signed by the judges and clerks
who held said elections, to wit, Joseph Engles, Mayor; F. J.
Sanders, J. W. Baker, J. W. Hager, J.R. Britt and S. E.
Hager, Aldermen. We the undersigned judges and clerks and
receiver do certify that the with in is a correct list of
votes polled in Smyrna, Rutherford County for the purpose of
electing a mayor and five aldermen to serve twelve months
and the following is a correct return Signed, S. E. Hager,
0. S. J. Lowry, Clerks; Judges; J. W. Hager, J. B. Moore,
J. W. Hight. A true copy.
Joseph Engles, Mayor and Recorder
December 22, Rutherford County Tennessee. The new Board of M.ayor and
1873. Aldermen met at the office of Joseph Engles, Esq. and after
being duly sworn according to law, transacted the following
business. First, to levy a corporation tax of one dollar on
each poll two dollars and fifty cents on merchants, druggist,
saloons, livery stables, peddlers, theatrical excubations
and one eighth of one percent on the hundred dollars on real
estate. Second, the board then elected J. F. Sanders, Treasurer,
J. W. Hight, Town Constable, Tune and Lenoir, Policemen for
the year 1873 and 74. The board then adjourned until the first
Wednesday in January 1874 for the year 1874.
Joseph Engles, Mayor and Recorder
la
January 20, The board of mayor and aldermen met pursuant of adjournment
1874. and transacted the following business. First, that every
^ livery stable shall have the right to haul in the corporation
and that a dollar of their tax as a privilege shall be for the
use of said wagon and that everybody who wants to haul in said
corporation shall pay a tax of one dollar for such privilege
and that the work on the streets shall be let out to the best
bidder of the day.
Joseph Engles , Mayor and Recorder
December 21, There being an election of mayor and aldermen for the next
1874. twelve months, held by A. W. Page, Constable for Rutherford
County, for the corporation of Smyrna said election returns
was returned into this office by said A. W. Page signed by
the judges and clerks of said election and the following named
persons received the highest number of votes to wit; J. W.
Baker, Mayor and F. J. Sanders, J. G. Brewer, J. R. Britt,
J. W. Hager, S. E. Hager, Aldermen. A. W. Page being deputized
by the sheriff to pole said election. A. W. Page receiver,
D. Tune, J. W. Hight, J. T. Brewer, Judges. J. W. Lenoir,
0. S. C. Lowry, Clerks.
January 1, Be it remembered that on the first day of January 1875,
1875. J. W. Baker was duly sworn in as Mayor of the Corporation of
Smyrna, January 1, 1875.
Joseph Engles, J. P., for the County of Rutherford. We the
undersigned judges, clerks and receiveis of an election held in
Smyrna for the election of mayor and aldermen certify that the
following is the results of said election: for mayor, J. W.
Baker received the highest number of votes. F. J. Sanders,
J. G. Brewer, J. R. Britt, J. W. Hager, S. E. Hager received
the highest number of votes for aldermen.
Signed, A. W. Page, Receiver
Judges: L. D. Tune, J. W. Hight, J. G. Brewer
Clerks: J. W. Lenoir, 0. S. C. Lowry
December 21,
1874.
January 2,
1875.
A true copy.
Joseph Engles, Mayor and Recorder
The new elected board met and were sworn in by Joseph Engles
J. P., for the faithful discharge of their duty for the next
twelve months
,
Joseph Engles, Justice of the Peace for Rutherford County
The following ordinance was passed by the aldermen. Be it
ordained by the board that if any person is convicted of racing
horses in the streets of the Corporation of Smyrna shall be
fined not less than one nor more than five dollars for each
offense. Be it further ordained by the mayor and aldermen
that if any person fails to pay their privilege tax, poll
or real estate tax for the year 1875 by the first day of
June, the mayor shall issue execution to the town constable
who shall proceed to levy the same on property of the deliquent
tax payer and sell the same to the highest and best bidder,
for cash after giving ten days notice at two public places in
December 20,
1875.
December 28,
1875.
the said corporation. And after deducting all the taxes and
expenses allowed by law, he shall pay the residue if any to
the tax payer. The board then elected F. J. Sanders treasurer
of the said corporation for the year 1875. He giving bond of
one hundred dollars for the faithful disbursement of the
corporation funds
.
The board then elected J. W. Right town constable for the
next twelve months and allowed him ten percent for the collect-ion
of the privilege, poll and real estate tax he giving bond
for one hundred dollars. The board elected L. H. Tune police-man
for the year 1875.
The board appointed a committee to employ a force to work
on the streets at the best term they can. The committee is:
F. J. Sanders, S. E. Hager and J. R. Britt and pay for the
work by drawing any money out of the treasurer not otherwise
appropriated. The board then agreed to levy the same tax on
privileges, polls and real estate as last year, except livery
stables which shall be taxed two dollars, running vehicles
included. No further business appearing the board adjourned
until the first Thursday in February.
J. W. Baker, Mayor and Recorder
An election of mayor and alderman was held on the 20th day
of December 1875 by A. W. Page, Deputy Sheriff of Rutherford
County in the Town of Smyrna and said election resulted in
electing J. P. H. Lenoir mayor; John Hager, F. J. Sanders,
Sam E. Hager, J. R. Britt, and J. W. Baker aldermen.
J. W. Baker
State of Tennessee, Rutherford County
J. P. H. Lenoir took the oath of office before Joseph
Engles, Esq. a Justice of the Peace for said county to serve
as mayor of the corporation of Smyrna for the next twelve
months. I certify that J. P. H. Lenoir was sworn in as mayor
of the corporation of Smyrna on the 23rd day of December 1875.
Joseph Engles, J. P. for Rutherford County
19
January 10,
1876.
"NOTE: The preceding minutes to this point have all been
in Joseph Engles hand writing except for the signature of
Mayor J. W. Baker."
Mr. F. J. Sanders, S. E. Hager, John Britt, J. W. Hager and
J. W. Baker, Aldermen elected for the year 1876 were sworn into
office by Joseph Engles, Esq. a Justice of the Peace for the
County of Rutherford. On the same night the Board of Mayor
and Aldermen organized for the transaction of business.
Present, J. P. H. Lenoir, Mayor F. J. Sanders, John Britt,
J. W. Hager, and J. W. Baker, Aldermen. The first business
in order was to elect a town constable for the year 1876.
Mr. J. M. Hight being nominated was duly elected. Second,
the board then livied a tax on all real estate of 1/8 of
one percent on the hundred dollars. The livery stable tax
two dollars, the merchants tax and all other privileges,
two dollars and poll tax one dollar. Third, Mr. F. J. Sanders
was elected treasurer and J. T. Brewer policeman.
20
Joseph Engles - first
Mayor of Smyrna, Tennessee
in 1869. Father of Dr.
J. W. Engles.
^X^^^^M"^''^'^"^'^^^^^^*- ~ - %
Albert Wilkes Page
Mayor of Smyrna, Tennessee
when Charter was lost
in 1881.
Born 1834
Died 1918
1^1
December 23,
1876.
The following ordinance was then passed by a full vote,
that the mayor shall be empowered in case of necessity to
deputize any discreet person of proper age, 21 years, to
make an arrest. The Board of Mayor and Aldermen adjourned
until the first Tuesday in February next and fixed that day
in each month for their regular meeting.
J. P. H. Lenoir, Mayor and Recorder
This is to certify that the above is a correct number
of votes polled at the election held by me in the Town of
Smyrna on the above date and that J. T. Gooch received twelve
votes for mayor for the year 1877. For aldermen the following
persons received the highest vote polled; F. J. Sanders-13,
J. R. Britt-12, J. W. Baker-13, S. E. Hager-12, J. W. Hager-13,
Joseph Engles, Receiver. Clerks: S. E. Hager, W. B. Jarrett,
Judges: J. W. Might, F. J. Sanders, A. W. Page.
21
W. A. Mason a Justice of
State of Tennessee on this
to James T. Gooch and thus
Mayor of the Corporation of
1877. At night the Board o
oath of office was administ
F. J. Sanders, J. W. Baker,
aldermen. When they organi
following business.
the Peace of Rutherford County,
day administered the oath of office
qualified said James T. Gooch as
the Town of Smyrna for the year
f Mayor and Aldermen met and the
ered by J. T. Gooch, J. P. to
S. E. Hager and J. W. Hager as
zed and proceeded to transact the
January 9
,
1877.
The first business in order was to elect a town constable
to serve for the year 1877. James W. Hight was elected with-out
opposition for that position.
Second, the board next proceeded to select a policeman.
John T. Brewer being nominated was duly elected to serve such
for the next twelve months ensuing.
Third, the board then levied a tax of 1/8 of one percent
on the hundred dollars on all real estate, and one dollar
poll tax. The livery stable tax $2.00. The merchant tax and
all other privileges &#8226; to be $2.50, except liquor dealers. Those
who sold by wholesale to pay a privilege tax of $25.00 and
retail liquor dealers to pay a tax of $50.00. The two last
meaning by annum, payable quarterly.
Fourth, F. J. Sanders was elected treasurer for the next
twelve months ensuing.
The board then adjourned until the second Tuesday in
January 1877 and fixed the first Tuesday night of each month
succeeding as the time for holding their regular meetings.
J. T, Gooch, Mayor and Recorder
There being no quorum an adjournment was ordered until the
regular meeting the first Tuesday night in February, next.
J. T. Gooch, Mayor and Recorder
Corporation Record for the year 1878.
April 6,
1878.
September 21,
1878.
1879
July 5,
1879.
July 21,
1879.
22
At an election held at this place today the following
persons were legally elected to wit: A. W. Page was elected
mayor and F. J. Sanders, W. R Jarrett, S. E. Hager, J. R. Britt,
B. B. Gracy were elected aldermen to serve until the 20th
day of December next or until their successors are qualified.
Smyrna, Rutherford County, Tennessee
The Board of Mayor and Aldermen met for the transaction of
business. A. W. Page, Mayor in the chair and the regular order
of business taken. The bond of the mayor and recorder was
read and approved. On motion and seconded. The following
was voted as the rate to taxation for corporation purposes for
the present year, to wit. Privilege, merchant and peddlers-
$2.60 each. Livery stables-$1.25. Druggist-$1.25. Wagons-. 50c,
Polls-$1.00, Realty 1/8 of one percent.
W. B. Jarrett was elected treasurer. A street committee
was appointed consisting of Aldermen Britt, Gracy, Hager, J. T.
Brewer was elected and swocn in as policemen. No other business
appearing the board adjourned to meet again on the 27th,
September 1878.
A. W. Page, Mayor and Recorder
Smyrna, Rutherford County, Tennessee
(NOTE: "This election should have been held December 20, 1878.")
At an election held at this place today for the purpose of
electing one mayor and fi-^e aldermen. The returns in my
office show that A. W. Page was elected mayor and S. E. Hager,
W. B. Jarrett, B. B. Gracy, J. R. Britt and J. W. Hager were
elected aldermen to serve until December 20, 1880, or until
their successors are qualified.
A. W. Page, Mayor and Recorder
Smyrna
At a meeting of the Board of Mayor and Aldermen of the
Town of Smyrna, the following proceedings were had, to wit;
A. W. Page having been sworn in as Mayor and Recorder by J. S.
Gooch, J. P., he then administered the oath of office to the
aldermen elect, except J. W. Hager who was not present. The
regular order of business was taken and on motion and seconded
the following taxes were levied for the present year. To wit,
on realty and personal property 1/8 of one percent. Polls-
$1.00, privilege merchants-$2.00, livery stables-$1.50. The
following aldermen were appointed as a street committee:
Gracy, S. E. Hager, and Britt. W. B. Jarrett was elected
treasurer. By unanimous vote the rules and ordinances posed
by the Board of Mayor and Aldermen on the 22nd day of December
1869 was adopted for the government of the corporation for the
present year by unanimous vote. The first Tuesday night in
each month was adopted for the time of the regular meeting
of the board. No other business coming up, the board adjourned
to meet as above.
A. W. Page, &gt;feyor and Recorder
December 20,
1879.
23
January 3,
1880.
January 6,
1880.
Smyrna, Rutherford County, Tennessee
At an election held at this place today the following
persons were unanimously elected to the office. To wit:
A. W. Page was elected mayor, W. B. Jarrett, S.E. Hager,
J. R. Britt, J. F. Tucker and J. T. Brewer were elected
aldermen to serve for the ensuing term and to these I
have by virtue of my office issued certificates of election.
A. W. Page, Mayor and Recorder
Smyrna, Rutherford County
The Board of Mayor and Aldermen met and the oath of office
having been administered to A. W. Page by J. W. Hall, Esq.
on the 30th of December. A. W. Page, J. P. then swore in the
aldermen elect and the board organized by electing W. B. Jarrett
treasurer. The board then adjourned to meet on the 6th of
January 1880.
A. W. Page, Mayor and Recorder
Smyrna, Tennessee
The Board of Mayor and Aldermen met pursuant to adjournment
with A. W. Page in the chair, and all the aldermen present.
The mayor presented his official bond which was accepted.
(Alderman Brewer in the chair.) The ordinances and laws passed
by the Board of Mayor and Aldermen on the 22nd of December 1869
was then adopted by this board for the government of the Town
of Smyrna for the present year. By vote of the board the survey
of the Town of Smyrna as made by J. J. Neely on the 3rd day of
September 1879 be adopted as the bounds and metes of said town,
and also that said survey and plot be spread upon the minutes
of this board and become a part of the record of said town.
(See Map-1878, page 8 ). J. W. Right was elected and qualified
as town constable for the present term. B. D. Right and J. W.
Lenoir were elected policemen for the present term. Aldermen
Brewer, Britt .and Tucker were appointed a street committee by
unanimous vote of the board. The following vote of taxes was
ordered to be levied for the corporate purposes for the present
year. To wit: on personal and real estate 1/5 of one percent,
poll tax-$1.00, merchants license-$2. 50, whiskey-$2.50, peddlers-
$2.50, shows-$2.50, stables-.$2.50, shooting galleries-$2.50,
wagons or drays-. 50c.
By unanimous vote of the board the 1st Tuesday night in
every month was set for the regular meeting. Nothing further
appearing the board adjourned to meet at the regular time.
A. W. Page, Mayor and Recorder
February 3,
1880.
Smyrna
This being the time for a meeting of the Board of Mayor and
Aldermen of Smyrna but oweing to the inclemency of the weather
no meeting occured.
A. W. Page, Mayor and Recorder
March 2,
1880.
April 6,
1880.
July 6,
1880.
December 7
1880.
December 20,
1880.
Smyrna, Rutherford County, Tennessee
24
The Board of Mayor and Aldermen met pursuant to adjournment
with Mayor Page in the chair and all the aldermen present. A
protest signed by the citizens of Smyrna objecting to the survey
of the town by J. J. Neely was read and ordered spread on the
minutes. Nothing futher appearing the board adjourned for one
month unless sooner convined.
A. W. Page, Mayor and Recorder
Smyrna
The Board of Mayor and Aldermen met at the usual hour with
the Mayor A. W. Page presiding and Aldermen Jarrett, Brewer,
Britt and Hager present. No business appearing for the good of
the corporation, the board adjourned to meet on the next regular
meeting unless sooner called together by the mayor.
A. W. Page, Mayor and Recorder
Smyrna
The board met at the usual time and place with Mayor Page in
the chair and Aldermen Jarrett, Brewer, Britt and Hager present
but nothing appearing for the benefit of the corporation, the
board adjourned to meet again at the regular time.
A. W. Page, Mayor and Recorder
Smyrna
The Board of Mayor and Aldermen met at the regular time and
place with Mayor Page in the chair and Aldermen Jarrett, Brewer,
Britt, Hager and Tucker present. The street committee and the
tax collector both made reports which were received. E. W.
Jarrell was elected to fill out the unexpired term of Hight who
had left the room. Jarrell was then brought in and qualified
as policeman. No other business appearing for the good of the
coipDration, the board adjourned to meet ag^n on the (no date).
At an anular election held in the Town of Smyrna in accordance
with a writ of election issued by R. Ransom, Sheriff of Ruther-ford
County on this the 20th day of December 1880 for the purpose
of electing one mayor and five aldermen to serve for the ensuing
term of twelve months. The certificates of the offices of said
election show that A. W. Page was elected mayor and W. B. Jarrett,
S. E. Hager, J. R. Britt, J. L. Brewer and J. F. Tucker were
elected aldermen. And upon said returns the sheriff issued
certificates of election to the officers elect, which certificates
are now on file in this office, January 4, 1881.
A. W. Page, Mayor and Recorder
January 4, The Board of Mayor and Aldermen met at the usual time. Mayor
1881. Page called the board to order and administered the oath of office
to all the aldermen elect. The oath of office having the same day
been administered to the mayor by J. S. Gooch, Esq, 25
January 6,
1881.
Note.
Note.
Note by W. K.
Hoover
.
The business was taken up in regular order and J. W. Right
was elected town constable. W. B. Jarrett was elected treasurer.
E. W. Jarrell and J. M. Right was elected policeman. The
treasurer was instructed to pay to the parties who had paid a
corporation fine of ? dollars, the sum thus settled by them.
The following rate of taxes was voted and ordered levied for
corporation purposes for the present year. Merchants license-
$2.50, whiskey-$100.00, peddlers-$2.50, shows-$2.50, stables-
$2.50, shooting galleries-$2.50, wagons, drays, carts, and
other vehicles-. 50c, poll tax-$1.00.
And upon all personal property (not exempt) and upon all realty
1/5 of one percent. Aldermen Britt, Brewer and Tucker were
appointed street committee. The mayor was allowed 25c for
each license issued. No other business appearing for the good
of the corporation the board adjourned to meet a^n on the
first Tuesday night in February next, unless sooner called
together by the mayor.
A. W. Page, Mayor and Recorder
At a called meeting of the Board of Mayor and Aldermen all
the aldermen being present the mayor stated the object of the
meeting was to take action on the whiskey license levied on the
4th inst. Whereupon on motion and seconded the board voted to
recend its action in levying said tax on one hundred dollars for
license to sell the same. This action of the board, the mayor
vetoed stating his reasons for this action. Wherefore, upon a
vote the same was passed over the veto and the mayor was by vote
of the board directed to return to J. R. Britt the one hundred
dollars collected by him for said license. No other business
appearing the board adjourned to meet again on the first Tuesday
night in February next unless sooner called by order of the mayor.
A. W. Page, Mayor and Recorder
This called meeting is evidence of conflict between the mayoj:
and city officials.
Rere ends the 1869-1881 records copied above from record book.
Albert W. Page was married to Sallie B. Right February 4, 1874
by the Rev. Mr. Rosser at the Smyrna Methodist Church. This
church was built in 1872. There was no Church of Christ until
1880.
Mr. A. W. Page a highly religious person possibly was disap-pointed
in his inability to control whiskey and the two saloons
in Smyrna, eventually causing the charter of incorporation to
be lost. Mr. Page and the Right family, one of the Right girls
26
being his wife, founded the Church of Christ on Division
Street about this time.
The only evidence that I find about why the charter was
lost or withdrawn is the following petition and a note in
Mr. Page's diary.
1881. From Tennessee House Journal 1881 (Tennessee State Archives)
By Mr. W. R. Jones, a petition from the citizens of Smyrna
protesting against the repeal of the charter of said town.
Referred to the Committee on Incorporation.
To the Honorable Speaker and Members of the House of
Representives of the General Assembly of the State of
Tennessee in session at the Capitol. We the undersigned
boni fide citizens of the Town of Smyrna, Rutherford County
would respectfully represent to your honorable body that
upon information had by us that during your session there
will be presented to you for your consideration a petition
from a few of our fellow citizens praying you to repeal so
much of the Acts of 1869 etc. As refers to the incorporation
of our now thriving little Town to which petition we beg leave
to enter our earnest protest and will endeavor to show by the
following reasons why their prayer should not be heard. 1st.
The petition is signed by two non-residents of the corporation
the others are simply a respectable minority and with but few
exceptions are newcomers falling to realize the maxim vena
vidi visi(note-"I came, I saw, I conquered") they prepose to
rub out and take a fresh start. 2. The petition does not
show in its face the intentional objects for which it was
made-i.e. (Note-"idest" that is). 1st, that is the wish of a
few parties living some miles away that our new citizens may
propetiate securely that these same citizens may have the
consolations that they will thereby avoid the payment of
privilege revenews which all well regulated corporation as
ours impose upon all, who do legitimate business within their
jurisdiction. 3. It will be urged by the friends of said
petition that aside from their prayer they will demand of
you as a matter of duty and right that you repeal our charter
upon constitutional grounds the num&amp;ricallpopylatiQna.haYiQgj
been reduced below the figure required by law.
In answer to this charge we would respectfully show your
honorable body that by the passage of wholesome laws and the
execution of them the town has accomplished a wonderful
change since it became an incorporated town. Our worst enemies
will admit that when our charter was granted our village was in
a sad condition but as soon as the corporate authority could be
organized a happy change was perceptable. We are out of debt
and improvements are going forward as fast as the nature of
the case will admit.
Respectfully submitted
27
January 25,
1881.
Same Day.
Note by W. K.
Hoover
.
Page Diary,
Wednesday,
May 15, 1878.
September 21,
1878.
(A Saturday)
Friday,
February 21,
1879.
L. H. Tune
J, R, Britt
S. E. Hager
J. S. Farris
G. W. Gwyn
J. W. Hager
Entrum Jimerson
J. T. Brewer
E, \J. Jarrell
W, B. Jarratt
D. J. Jarratt
John Hlbett
George Sikes
Sawney Nelson
Abe Drennon
Louis Parks
Raukin Ralston
Peter Allen
Jim Bowen
Henderson Weakley
This petition is hand written. The signatures are by
the same hand writing and same pen.
I suspect that Joseph Engles wrote this in conjunction
with W. R. Britt, the saloon keeper, perhaps others not
wanting to pay privilege taxes. The above minutes show that
A. W. Page, Mayor wanted to tax Mr. Britt one hundred dollars
per year for his saloon.
I did not find a petition by other citizens to do away with
the charter. However, I did find a mention of this in Mr. A. W.
Page's diary to-witt.
"I went to Nashville on the 9:00 a.m. and came back on the
A: 00 p.m. train. While in N. I was at the Capitol and before
a legislative committee and testifed before them why we wanted
to abolish the corporation of Smyrna and am almost certain it
will be done."
"I am still very much dissatisfied with our present situation
and will change it the first opportunity."
Mr. Page moved to Texas soon after this. The reconstruction
period after the Civil War created many social and economic
problems
.
The following quotations from Mr. A. W. Page's diary will
enhance your knowledge of Smyrna history.
"At night I went up to Jarretts Store(meeting place) called
the aldermen elect together and administered the oath of office
to them. After electing J. W. Hight town constable and J. T.
Brewer and J. W. Lenoir policemen we adjourned, (cool and clear)".
"Was at a meeting of the Board of Mayor and Aldermen at night,
at which quite a number of bills were passed for the benefit of
the corporation. Got home at nine thirty o'clock. Cloudy, then
clear and pleasant."
"I think that A. Davis has traded Jo. Engles a track of land
for his Smyrna property. I hope he has and that Engles will
move out of Smyrna at once." (Perhaps where the minute book
was found .
)
Sunday
,
February 23,
1879.
Mdnday
February 24,
1879.
Thursday
,
March 13,
1879.
Monday
,
April 7,
1879.
Saturday,
July 5,
1879.
Monday
July 21,
1879.
Monday
,
August 4,
1879.
0&#163;*
G. S. Ridley was down and he and I went out and looked at &#176;
the former mud hole and corporate lines and etc. "(in streets).
"Rankin Rolston's horse attempted to cross Harts Branch on
the R.R. bridge and it was with great difficulty that we got him
out and off the bridge." (Note-bridge has open space between
cross ties.)
"I had somewhat of an argument with Engles and Mason in regard
to the corporation lines of Smyrna. Loaned Dan Tune 20c."
"I was with the county surveyor W. R. Jones and some others
while they run off the line between J. R. Dillon and Smyrna."
(Note-Dillon lived at "Idler's Retreat" better known today as
the Old Tucker house. Here is W. R. Jones who is mentioned on
face of petition, page 36.)
"While in Murfreesboro I submitted the case of the State vs.
the Corporation of Smyna. I also paid L.S. Tucker $1.20 his
witness fee in the corporation case."
"Was about Smyrna all day. There was an election here for
mayor and aldermen. I was elected mayor and S. D. Hager,
W. B. Jarrett, B. B. Gracy, J. R. Britt, and J. W. Hager was
elected aldermen. J. M. Right and I went to the creek and took
a bath in the evening. We got caught in a shower of rain while
gone."
"There was a meeting of the Board of Mayor and Aldermen of
Smyna. I got a statement from Capt. Fowler, find that the
cost in the case of the State vs. the Corporation is $25.34."
"In company with J. M. Hight and J. W. Hager I went to
Murfreesboro in a spring wagon and was up there nearly all day.
The Criminal Court was in session and I went up to prosecute
R. H. White for buying witness fees, he having reported the
corporation authorities of Smyrna for having a mud hole in the
road in December last. I do this to get even with him. Got
home at 6 o'clock."
Monday,
September 1,
1879.
"I also paid L. B. Fowler $10.00 on our corporation fine...
Jarrett and Britt each paid me $4.70 on the corporation fine.
Thursday, "I was about Smyrna all day. I held the election for constable
August 28, which resulted in 52 votes. J. H. Engles, and 31 votes for J. W.
1879. Lenoir. At LaVergne Engles received 26 and Lenoir 41, making
the majority, 6 votes, a close race. I hope that he will make
a good officer which he will not do if he is influenced by
his father." Etc.
Monday
March 15,
1880.
"I worked for two or three hours on the coporation minutes
book."
Tuesday, "I went to Murfreesboro in my buggie and worked S. E. Hager 's
August 3, horse. While up there I paid J. E. Arnold $5.00 and S. E. Hager
1880. paid him $6.30 that being the balance on the corporation mud
hole fine."
29
Tuesday,
December lA,
1880.
Friday,
January 14
,
1881.
Saturday,
March 5,
1881.
Monday
,
March 28,
1881.
Wednesday,
April 13,
1881.
Monday,
May 16,
1881.
Thursday,
June 9
,
1881.
June 13,15,
16,17
"I was busy all day at work on the corporation. My wagon
and team and two hands were also busy hauling for the corp-oration."
(Note-perhaps hauling rock for streets.) "At
night I was at a meeting of the Board of Mayor and Aldermen.
Dock Brown and Hense Weakley worked for me."
"Was about Smyrna all day-transacted no official business
but wrote on my corporation book for about two hours. The
weather is very bad-rain last night then snow and there is
about two or three inches on the ground."
"There was several drunken men here today but no fighting.
We will soon get rid of whiskey here as the charter of this
town has been repealed and a school house chartered." (Note-this
school was the center section of the Webster house still
standing across the street from Church of Christ.)
"I was deputized to collect the unpaid taxes."
"Before leaving Smyna this morning, the calaboose was sold
and the treasurer of the Town of Smyrna, W. B. Jarrett was
instructed to pay the proceeds out on the fine and cost in
the case of the State vs. Corporation of Smyrna." (Note-by
W. K. Hoover. To this day, to the best of my knowledge
this log calaboose is still contained in the Will Ross house
at the corner of First Street, on 1855 map, lot number 26,
page 2.)
"I also collected $7.00 due me by the Corporation of Smyrna,
amount paid to criminal court in the mud hole case." A note
by W. K. Hoover. Look on page ^-1878 map. See lake near
depot. This lake originally extended under the buildings on
the west side of Front Street. When Smyrna excavated along
this street to install water mains the ditching equipment
was stopped about three or four feet deep by railroad cross
ties, placed solid together to hold up the roadway. They had
to be chopped into to install the water pipes in 1936.
I have seen boys fishing from a crosstie raft in summer and
party's skating on ice in the winter. This lake was ^drained
and filled with cinders by the railroad about 1920,
"I am making arrangements to leave for Texas within the next
two weeks but I find it a difficult matter to collect any money
due me now."
He writes of his preparations to leave for Texas. "While
in Nashville on the 18th, I bought our railroad tickets to
Dallas, Texas. Paid $42.65 for two and one half tickets."
(End of diary quotations.)
Mr. Page's diary continues on for many years but this ends
his connections with the office of Mayor of Smyrna. He came
back to Smyrna after several years in Palerm, Texas. He later
moved to Lebanon, Tennessee where he worked and died.
30
Mr. Page's diary spans many years before and aftej^ he ewe to gmyrna.
There are many details of history, name of people and happenings in and
around Smyrna, noted in this important diary. A photo-copy of Mr. Page's
years in Smyrna from his diary is presently in Thurman Francis, Jr. High
School Library along with Walter K. Hoover's historical files and is
available for research there. (Net available to check out.) The complete
original diary is at Vanderbilt University, Nashville, Tennessee. This
was taken from page family records, by Ellen Swink.
A. W. Page was a very devout Christian attening Sunday
School each Sunday and Church if there was a service in
the community. Around 1870 Page, Bill Dunnaway, Bill
Gooch, Levi White and Miss Cora Holloway went to West
Tennessee to hear Alexander Campbell preach. An invi-tation
was extended Campbell to come to Smyrna and preach
at a meeting. Campbell accepted and the meeting was held
at the Page home. Page led the singing for this meeting
which he followed by becoming song leader. With a new
congregation and no meeting house they met in the Page home.
Ann Eliza Page furnished the unleavened bread for the
weekly observance of the Lord's Super until her death.
In 1872 he ventured into a new field. . .politics. Was
elected magistrate for his district. On April 1, 1978
was appointed a delegate to the convention in Nashville
to nominate Supreme Court Judges. Was also elected tax
accessor for his district.
On the 6th of April, 1878 was elected Mayor of Smyrna with-out
opposition. This position he held until the charter was
rendered in 1881. Page didn't approve of drinking and his
actions led to the discontent which caused the charter to be
rendered.
31
Early Store - First Street at Tank Street, 1855 map, lot
23. Across Tank Street is blacksmith and buggy shop.
Note - unpaved street.
Note by W. K. Hoover.
It is now only sixteen years since the cessation, of the
turmoil, of the Civil War, which happened on and through this
vicinity. The despised federal domination and the reconstruction
period was just beginning to relax. Money, business, livestock,
labor (slaves) and the old southern plantation life style had
gone. Federal taxes were a burden. These things had their effect
on the loss of the Charter.
&#8226;^S
32
The pit., .(ire of your company is respectfully
solicited at a Picnic to he given in Buchanan's
Grove, 7 miles west of Murfreesboro^ near the
terminus of the Wilkinson Cross Roads Pike,
on Thursday, August 10, 1870.
COMMUTES OF INVITATION.
Db. J. J. Ruck KB,
E. Hendkkson,
J. T. Patton,
W. H. Washington,
a W. Hicks,
J. W. Smith,
Henby Obeooby,
H. H. Hicks,
Sam. Buchanan,
A. B. Harding,
C. H. Sanders,
J. M. Butler,
T. E. Smith,
P. N. OVEKALL,
J. B. Hicks.
U. H. Smith,
L. C. Edwards,
Jno. Beesley,
J. L. McQbeqob,
MANAGERS.
Wm. Beesley,
R. R. Hall,
J B. Batey,
G. W. Howse,
A. W. Blackman,
J. F. Jenkins,
J. S. Hicks,
ly. J. S.MITH,
H. Kino.
D. Anderson,
Jno. Kino,
W. A. Vawtee,
D. J. Jarratt,
H. N. Hicks.
J. E. Manson, Jr.,
A. M. Edwards,
D. Beesley'.
W. M. Smith,
Mrs. V. A. Vawteb,
" J. W. Smith,
" J. S. Hicks,
" L. J. Smith,
" A. W. Blackman,
LAST MANAGERS.
Mrs. W. M. Smith,
" H.H. Hicks,
D. Beesley,
J. F. Jenkins,
" C. H. King,
Mnti. J. W. Ross.
MH.S. 8. E. Buchanan,
" J. E. Manson, Jr.
" R. K. Hall,
" H. Ubeoory,
'&#8226; Wm. Beesley,
H. H. Davis,
FLOOR MANAGERS.
T. O. Butler, E. F. Haynes
BfUSIC MANAGERS.
J. L. Smith,
JUUSIC BT JORDAN JUcGOWAA^S J/.4.VX).'SW
A social affair. (See 1878 County map.)
^ ^ yj^ -#^^&#171;x^'~^
/r&gt;^ L.^'ejL rh.^4z/s ^-,^&gt;....*^ ^
7
All
Smyrna
people
of this
period.
i^j=5 -
33
-^y^ P^ l^/f^ i^^^^*-t^-^ &lt;f .^^^L-^ f yl^f^..,gfh&gt;"2-^ f/U^ -^/^/^a:,'^^^^
r^; ;^&lt;i-^ -^ . ^.
/^ -^2^ Jf^^c}^ /^r^'JO
-c^ ^iL^-,:^^ (^ i\
^je^ AiTf-^ ^ .^sf^ . y
Stud service for grey mare with interest and Justice Peace fee.
Collected (on back) in 1874.
(More foot prints)
&#8226;^^'-^ 4/-^ -aW
SMYRNA BUSINESS DIRECTOTY OF 1860-POPULATION 500
Presbyterian Church
Masonic Lodge
Five Stores and One Hotel
R. H. Dudley-Postmaster
J. C. Brothers-Justice of the Peace
James Hlbbett-Constable
Green Sanders-Justlc* of the Peace
C.Benning-Boot and Shoe Maker
W. H. Burkett-Dealer In Wines and Liquors
Thomas Cook-Brick Mason
C. R. and I. A. Dlllln-General Merchandise
S. A. Downer-Butcher and Tailor
R. H. Dudley-Dry Goods, General Merchandise
Elliot and Rolston-Carpenter , Sashes, Doors, Limber
Thomas Fox-Taylor
P. F. Hager-Blacksmith
Hager and Burke tt-Llvery Stable
G. B. Harris-Depot Agent
A. G. Henderson-Real Estate Agent
James Hlght-Carpenter, Stone Dealer
W. G. Howell-Stoves, Tin, Ironware
R. P. Johnson-Boot and Shoe Maker
J. H. Simmons-Grocer
Benjamin Tompklns-Pump Maker
Silas Tucker-General Merchandise
John's Saloon(1870)
34
35
Early Dillon Store - Hibbett Store at time of this
picture. Todays 108 Lowry Street - Regal Furniture.
Lot 20, 1855 map.
""t^-
Lookinfj north on todays Lowry Street - First Street
at Jefferson Street on 1855 map, Smyrna, Tennessee,
Lot 21.
36
SZ^&lt;^^^._^&lt;^^m^^i^J^mk&#177;&#163;. ^iD^^t^ y^&gt;S
^Z^x^^^^^L^Q^^^^^^&gt;&lt;s3U&lt;iW8^*^-&lt;:^'&#8364;J^
^-^-^^ -^^&#171;-r!'-i'^f&gt;-4^^e^^C..je-^^'
l^^e^-*&amp;&lt;i^^&amp;;. ^ ^^/^. ^Z^ - ^ l^^f^^^^u&amp;p
*&lt;^-x^t
:^.4f&gt;^
James S. Cannon collected rent from I. L. Davis, sworn to
before Joseph Engles Justice Peace. (On back) collected by
A. W. Page April 10, 1873.
37
SMYRNA BUSINESS DIRECTORY OF 1876-77-POPULATION 300
Presbyterian Church
Methodist Church
White and Colored Free Schools
J. F. Sanders-Postmaster
H. B. Baker-General Store
J. R. Britt-Hotel Proprietor
Dr. B. B. Gracey-Physician
L. B. White-Depot Agent
S. P. Black-Miller
Rev. J. B. Chapman-Presbyterian
T. J. Sanders-Genral Store
Rev. G. W. Winn-Methodist
3S
^ - ^ &gt;^^^^^ /r^ r /-^//
/
/^!&gt;
C y/^.^'-'j^
L. Davis's estate owed this account to Dudley and Ross Store,
since 1868. Mr. Dudley affirmed before Joseph Engles, Justice
Peace that the bill was due and correct. Paid by administrator
February 10, 1872. (Receipt on back.)
39
Early Railroad workers at Smyrna, Tennessee, Notice small
track rail, old handcar.
^.oading loss at Smyrna, Tennessee with mule power and
boom Dole. Notice small railroad car, depot.
40
SMYRNA BUSINESS DIRECTORY 1880-POPULATION 250
W. B. Jarrett-Postmaster
S. P. Black-Physician and Miller
J. R. Britt-Saloon
G. W. Crossthwaits-Physician
J. W. Davis-Physician
B. B. Gracey-Physician
W. L. Davis-Mill
G. W. Gwynn-General Store
W. E. Hager-General Store
William Hibbitt-Blacksmith
W. B. Jarrett-General Store
A. W. Page-Magistrate and Livery Stable
T. J. Read-Blacksmith
G. W. Tune-General Store
H. J. Warmouth-Physician
(Note the decrease in population)
41
Time and the elements have eraced all trace of the physical footprints
made by these many citizens of yesterday. Perhaps some of these prints remain
under the pavements that preserve them. The citizens of Smyrna today do not
make footprints in the mud and dust, they move about in gas guzzlers on paved
streets while the concrete farmers use pick-up trucks.
Life becomes more complex with each generation and more people to generate.
Economics and science increasingly project us into a deminishing world and
into the castness of space, beyond this small sphere.
As you travel across the parade grounds of your life, you will Inevitably
leave prints and impressions that others will study and follow. By what still
water will you lead them to their tomorrows? What are your hopes and aspirations
for your siblings?
1. Tennessee State Archives
2. 1869-1881 Smyrna Minute Book
3. A. W. Page Diary
A. History of Smyrna, W. K, Hoover
5. Page Family Records
6. Lucket Davis Family Papers
Note to reader: For further research or information on early Smyrna, Tennessee
examine
:
1. History of The Town of Smyrna
2. Hardeman's Mill
3. Hart's Spring on Taylor's Trace
By: Walter K. Hoover</dc:description>
<dc:description>A short history of Smyrna, Tennessee, with pictures and documents</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>community histories</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Smyrna</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>41 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-08</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication19ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/146</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>