<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Bibliography of Rutherford County historical sources found at Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:title>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 39</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>199?</dc:date>
<dc:description>BIBLIOGRAPHY OF RUTHERFORD COUNTY HlSTORICAL SOURCES FOUND AT
TENNESSEE STATE LIBRARY AND ARCHIVES
Historical and Genealogical Information
BIBLIOGRAPHY OF TENNESSEE LOCAL mSTOKY SOURCES : RUHTERFORD COUNTY
Rutherford County in General
Baskin, Robert W History of Blackman community. Mur&amp;Teesboro, the author, 1986. 132 pp.
Baumstark, Michael E Recreational demand study for Rutherford County. MTSU thesis. 1971. pp.
Biographical directory, TN General Assembly, 1796-1969 (Rutherford County, Preliminary #6). Nashville,
TSLA, 1968. 63 pp.
Borden, Elizabeth. "Blacksmith lore: Joe Hansberry, master blacksmith." TNFolklore Sac. Bull 50 (1985),
pp. 10-21.
Davis, Charlene J. The geology of the LaVergne quadrangle, TN. Vanderbilt U. thesis, 1959. 32 pp.
Dowden, M.L Seasonal costs of producing &amp; marketing cream in Rutherford County, TN, 1947-48.
Knoxville, TN Ag. Exp. Sta., 1949- 35 pp. (its Rural research series monograph #250)
Dowden, M.L. Seasonal costs of producing &amp; marketing fluid milk in Rutherford Countv-, TN, 1947-48.
Knoxville, TN Ag. Exp. Sta., 1949. 35 pp. (its Rural research series monograph #242).
Downen, M.L. Seasonal costs of producing &amp; marketing milk for manufecturing purposes in Ruther-ford
County, TN, 1947-48. Knoxville, TN Ag. Exp. Station, 1949- 38 pp. (its Rural research series monograph
#246)
Flood insurance study: Rutherford County, TN, unincorporated areas. "Washington, D.C., FEMA, 1983. 40
pp.
Flood insurance study: Rutherford County, TN, unincorporated areas (rev Oa. 17, 1989). Washington,
D.C., FEMA, 1989. 42 pp.
Frow Chips. Vol. 1, Sept. 1971-. (monthly) Rutherford County Hist Soc.
Galloway, Jesse J. Geology &amp; natural resources of Rutherford County, TN. Nashville, TN Di^: Geo!., 1919.
81 pp. (its Bulletin #22)
Geoige Peabody College for Teachers. Division of Surveys &amp; Field Services. Public schools of Rutherford
County, TN; a survey report. Nashville, 1958. 223 pp.
Glass, ET "Sketch ofHenry Rutherford." .4/iM 5 (1900), pp. 225-229.
Goodspeed's history ofTN (Rutherford County, pp. 810-940, 1019-1076). Goodspeed, 1886.
Page 49
Goodwin, Sarah J., et al., comps. Westbrooks, WiHiams &amp; related Smodiennans of Rutherford County
TN, with histories ofMidland Conununity, Oak Grove School, Old Leb Church. Murfreesboro, Ruther-ford
County Hist. Soc., 1984. 306 pp.
Greene, Samuel. Availability of education to Negroes in Rutherford County, TN. Fisk U. thesis, 1940. pp.
Hankins, Caneta S. Hearthstones: the story of Rutherford County homes. Murfreesboro, Oaklands Associa-tion,
Inc. in cooperation with the Center for Historic Preservation at MTSU, 1993- 107 pp.
A history of Rutherford County schools to 1972. Murfreesboro, Rutherford County Retired Teachers Assn.,
1986. 2 vols.
Hoflfechwelle, Mary S. "Organizing rural communities for change: the Commonwealth Fund Child
Health Demonstration in Rutherford County, 1923-1927." THQ (Fall, 1994), pp. 154-164.
Houston, Gary B. A survey of the legal needs of the poor in Rutherford &amp; Cannon counties, TN. N.p.,
1967.29 pp.
Hughes, MaryB. Hearthstones: the story of Rutherford County homes. Murfreesboro, Mid-south, 1942. 68
pp. (reprinted, I960, 69pp. ;fifteeri additionalhomes are added in the second edition)
Hughes, Travis H. The geology of the Gladeville qpiadrangle, TN. \^derbilt U. thesis, I960. 35 pp.
Intercultural contact: the Japanese in Rutherford County, TN [videocassette]. Knoxville, UT, 1986. (1
videocassette, 29 min.)
Ivey, John B. Geology of Cedars of Lebanon State Park &amp; vicinity, Wilson &amp; Rutherford counties, TN.
VanderbUt U. thesis, 1950. 52 pp.
Jacobs, Ludle F. Duck River \^ey in TN &amp; its pioneers. N.p., 1968. 124 pp.
Jarman, Brenda S. "Ailin' animals: folk treatments collected in Rutherford County, TN." TNFolklore Soc.
Bull 4i (1978), pp. 55-65.
Jarmon, Laura C. Arbors to bricks: a hundred years ofAfrican-American education in Rutherford
County, TN, 1865 to 1965. Murfreesboro, MTSU Div Cont. Studies &amp; Pub. Ser, 1994. 144 pp.
Mrkeminde, Patricia B. 'The confessions ofYWllis Mayberry." TNFolklore Soc. Bull 30 (1964), pp. 7-21.
Laniers, Doris, ed. "Mary Noailles Murfree: an interview." THQ 31 (1972), pp. 276-278.
Lokey James L. History of dairying in Rutherford County, TN. Geoige Peabody College thesis, 1937. pp.
Lowe, Ma^eJ. "The murder ofManroe Bynvun." TNFolklore Soc. Bull. 20 (1954), pp. 9-13.
Lowe, Maggie J. "An old ballad composer of the nineties." TNFolklore Soc. Bull 19 (1953), pp. 83-94.
Luebke, B.H. Farm real estate situation in five areas ofTN, 1941-1944. Knoxville, TN Ag. Exp. Sta., 1945.
52 pp. (its Rural research series monograph #185)
Page 50
Middle TN State College. History of Rutherford County. Murfreesboro, MTSC, 1939- 52 pp.
Miller, Clarice. Central Christian Church early history. Muifreesboro, Rutherford County Hist. Soc., 1986.
Ill pp. (Rutherford County Hist. Soc. Pub. #27)
Miller, Julia C. The status ofwomen in industry in Rutherford County. MTSU thesis, 1969. pp.
Mooers, Charles A. The soils of Rutherford County. Knoxville, IN Ag. Exp. Sta., 1924. 27 pp. (its Bulletin #
130)
Muse, Luda S. Salem Methodist Church, Rutherford County, TN, 1812-1975. Nashville, TN Societ)^
NSDAR, 1976. 51 pp.
Mustard, Harry S. Cross sections of rural health progress: report of the Commonwealth Fund Child
Health Demonstration in Rutherford County, TN, 1924-1928. NX Commonwealdi Fund, 1930. 23 pp.
Nashville MSA, 1980-1987: an economic analysis. Nashville, TN Dept. Emp. Sec, 1988. 55 pp.
Ordanbadian, Reza. Rutherford County: a study in onomastics. Auburn U. dissertation, 1968. 250 pp. (place
names)
Kttard, Homer P Legends &amp; stories of Civil "W^ Rutherford County. George Peabody College thesis, 1940.
132 pp.
Pittard, Mabel, comp. A history of Rutherford County in pictures. Murfreesboro, Rutherford County Hist.
Soc., 1990. 128 pp.
Pittard, Mabel. Rutherford County. Memphis, MSU Press, 1985. 137 pp.
Puckett, Liz. "Stories firom the tack room." TNFolklore Soc. Bull 46 (1980), pp. 45-83.
Ransom, Robert G. The history of medicine in Rutherford County, TN. Murfreesboro, Rutherford
County Historical Society, 1985. 5 vols. (Vol 1: Introduction &amp; overview ofthe history ofmedicine in the
county; Vol 2: Biographies ofnineteenth centuryphysicians; Vol 3: Biographies oftwentieth centuryphysi-cians;
Vol 4: History ofRutherford Hospital (now the Middle TNMedical Center);Vol 5: History ofRutherford
County Health Dept.)
Ross, Robert M. Grade A milk producers in Rutherford County, TN. Problem A; Characteristics ofRuther-ford
County Grade A milk producers &amp; their farms; problem B; Management practices of Rutherford County
Grade A milk producers; problem C: Factors influencing dairy management practice adoption by Rutherford
County Grade A milk producers, (three relatedproblems in lieu ofthesis. UT, 1966. 155pp.)
Rutherford County Historical Publication. Vol. 1, 1973-. (quarterly) Rutherford County Hist. Soc.
Rutherford County home demonstration: plan ofwork, 1940. Murfreesboro, Home Demonstration
Clubs, 1940. 39 pp.
Salmon, Lourene. "The tale of the mysterious barrel &amp; other 'haint' tales collected in Big Springs." JN
Folklore Soc. Bull 37 (1971), pp. 59-72.
Page 51
Sims, Carlton C, ed. A history of Rutherford County. Murfreesboro, n.p., 1947. 236 pp. (reprinted, 1981)
SoU survey, Rutherford County, TN. \X^hington, DC, US GPO, 1977. 95 pp.
Southern Assoc, of Colleges &amp; Schools. Visiting Comm. Evaluative study made in Rutherford County
Central High School, Murfireesboro, TN. Murfreesboro, 1951. 106 pp.
Spence, John C. The annals of Rutherford County. Murfreesboro, Rutherford County Hist. Soc. (vol. 1, 1799-
1828 (1991), 265pp.; vol. 2, 1829-1870 (1991), 306pp.)
Spence, John C. A diary of the Civil War. Murfreesboro, Rutherford County Hist. Soc., 1993. 164 pp.
Stanfield, Eli2abeth P "Selected social correspondence of Miss Eleanor HardinJackson of Rutherford
County, 1861-1865." TNfolklore Soc. Bull 41 (1975), pp. 9-18.
TN Dept. Transportation [county maps] issued periodically
US Geol. Sunney [topographic maps] issued periodically Quadrangles: Lavergne, Gladeville, Vme, Smyrna,
\(^terhill, Lascassas, College Grove, Rockvale, Murfreesboro, Dalton, Readyville, Chapel Hill, Rover, Fosterville,
WebbsJungle, Beech Grove, Deason.
US Soil Conservation Service. Soils interpretations, Rutherford County, TN. Nashville, Mid-Cumberland
Council of Governments, 1977. 37 pp.
^Jf^ker, Watson E Ten years of rural health work, Rutherford County, TN, 1924-1933. NX Commonwealth
Fund, 1935. 82 pp.
Walker, "Watson E &amp; Caroline R. Randolph. Influences of a public health program: fifteen years in Ruther-ford
County, TN, 1924-1938. NX Commonwealth Fund, 1940. 106 pp.
Weeks, Terry Heart of TN: the story &amp; images of historic Rutherford County. Murfreesboro, Rutherford
County Chamber of Commerce, 1992. 205 pp.
West, Carroll V "The money our fathers were accustomed to": banks &amp; political culture in Rutherford
County, TN, 1800-1850." Wm. &amp; Mary College dissertation, 1982. 245 pp.
EagleviHe
Dyer, Minnie E The history of Eagjeville. Eagleville, n.p., 1972. 158 pp.
Griffiih
Rutherforcl County Bicentennial Comm. GriflSth: a bicenteimial publication. N.p., the commission, 1976. 60
pp.
LaVergne
Flood insurance study: city of LaVergne, TN, Cheatham County. ^X^hington, DC, EEMA 1983 19 pp
Page 52
Miihtte Tennessee State University
MTSU. BuUetin. Vol. 1-12, June 1911-1923; NewSer., Vol. 1-2, Aug. 1923- Apr. 1925; [3rd sen] Vol. l-,June
1925-. Frequenq' varies, (flumesfor 1911-25 issued by the university under its earlier name-. Middle TNState
NormalSchool; 1925-30, Middle TNState Teachers College; 1930- 43, State Teachers College; 1943-65, Middle
TNState College; 1965- , Middle TNState University)
MTSU magazine. Vol. 1, no. 1, Mar. 1993-. (monthly). MTSU.
Nunley, Joe E. The Raider forties. NX Vantage Press, 1977. 115 pp.
Kttard, Homer. The first fifty years. Photography by Dr. Bealer Smotherman. Murfreesboro, Middle TN State
College, 1961. 273 pp.
Pittard, Homer P Middle TN State College: its historical aspects &amp; its relation to significant teacher
education niovenient.Geoige Peabody College dissertation, 1957. 471 pp.
Woodmore, Thomas B. Up the winding stairs. Murfreesboro, the author, 1984. 168 pp.
Murfreesboro
Amette, Charles B. From Mink Slide to Main Street. Murfreesboro, the author, 1991. 244 pp.
Amette, Charles B. The history of the East Main Church of Christ. Murfreesboro, the author, 1988. 436 pp.
Bell, Ed. The lonely people &amp; their strange ways. Selections compiled &amp; edited by Robert Lasseter. Mur&amp;iees-boro,
n.p., 1951. 166 pp.
Donaldson, John G. Murfi-eesboro annexation study. Knoxville, MTAS, 1958. 42 pp.
Edwards, Charles D. &amp; Lin2y D. Albert. Master plan for recreation, Murfi-eesboro, TN. Nashville, n.p., 1952.
56 pp.
Flood insurance study: city of Murfreesboro, TN, Rutherford County. Washington, D.C., FEMA, 1983. 18
pp.
Flood insurance study: city of Murfreesboro, TN, Rutherford County, (rev. June 2, 1994). Washington,
DC, FEMA, 1994. 1 v
Henderson, C.C. The story of Murfi-eesboro. Murkeesbotx), News-Banner, 1929. 145 pp.
Howse, Elisabeth O. Flowers for Grace. N.p., Mrs. Granville S. Ridley, Jr., 1972. 152 pp.
Llewellyn, Ralph M. "Others have labored" : a sesquicentennial address on the early history of the First
Presbyterian Church, Murfi-eesboro, TN, Sunday, Apr. 29, 1962. Murfi-eesboro, n.p., 1962. 25 pp.
Murfiieesboro Regional Plan. Comm. School survey &amp; plans for city of Murfreesboro, TN. Murfi-eesboro,
n.p., 1948. 31 pp.
Page 53
Mutual Realty&amp; Loan Company: Handbook of Murfreesboro &amp; Rutherford County, TN. Murfteesboro,
Homejoumal Print, 1923- 128 pp.
Pitcard, Homo*. Pillar &amp; ground. Photography byArchie King, et al. Murfreesboro, First Baptist Church, 1968.
166 pp.
US Army Corps of Engineers. Flood plain information study, Murfreesboro, TN, West Fork Stones River,
Lyde &amp; Sinking Creeks. Main report Prepared for the dty of Murfr-eesboro &amp; Rutherford County Plan.
Comm. by the US Army Engineer District, Nashville, Corps ofEngineers. N.d., 1965. 32 pp.
Weatherford, Sally E. "Profile of a Murfreesboro quilt maker &amp; her craft." TNFolklore Soc. Bull 44 (1978),
pp. 108-114.
White, Robert H. 'TN's fovir capitols." ETHSP 6 (1934), pp. 29-43. (reprinted in TN old &amp; new, vol. 1, pp. 319-
332.)
Oaklands
Hemdon, Joseph L &amp; Mary L. Oehriein. Historic structures report, Oaklands Mansion, Murfreesboro, TN,
for the Oaklands Assoc., Inc. ^W^hington, D.C., Building Conservation Technology, 1978. 57 pp.
McBride, Robert M. "Oaklands: a venerable host, a renewed welcome." JHQ 22 (1963), pp. 303-322.
McConnell, Vii^inia, et al. Oaklands, a look at its past. N.p., 1987. 33 pp. (in partialfulfillmentfor the
requirementsforHistoric Preservation 433, TSU)
Sam Davis Home
Baird, Mary R., comp. Home ofSam Davis, Smyrna, TN: a state shrine of a southern scout, under man-agement
of the Sam Davis Memorial Association, Smyrna, TN. Smyrna, the compiler, n.d 48 pp.
Meredith, Owen N. "The Sam Davis home." THQ 24 (1965), pp. 303-320.
Smyrna
Baird, Mary, comp. A history of the First Baptist Church of Smyrna. N.p., 1954. 22 pp.
Coleman, Nell E., comp. A history of the Smyrna Methodist Church, 1872- 1955. N.p., 1955. 88 pp.
Flood insurance study: town of Smyrna, TN, Rutherford County. V^hington, D.C., FEMA, 1982. 17 pp.
Floods in Stewart Creek &amp; Harts Branch, Smyrna, TN. Nashville, US Corps ofEngineers, Nashville District,
1976. 32 pp.
Hoover, \^ter K A history of the town of Smyrna, TN. Nashville, McQuiddy, 1968. 559 pp.
Nissan Corporation
Egerton, Jolin. Nissan in TN. Smyrna, Nissan Motor Manufecturing Coip., USA, 1983. 127 pp.
Page 54
Hammer, Joshua. "Stretching their productivity as well as their limbs, auto- workers in TN goJapanese.
(Nissan truck assembly plant in Smyrna.)" People Weekly 66 (Oa. 24, 1983), pp. 38-41.
Springs, Ricardo. Pilot case study: the decision by Nissan Motor Manufecturing Corp. USA to build a
light truck assembly plant in Smyrna, TN. Washington, D.C., US Dept. Transp., 1981. 78 pp.
Tokyo in TN. [videocassette]. NX Caroiosel Films, 1983. 1 videocassette, 16 min. (a segmentfrom the television
program 60 Minutes)
Woods, Mike. "A look at Smyrna: the Nissan impact." A/&amp;. Man. 66 (fune 1984), pp. 3-5.
Battle ofStones River/Stones River National Battlefleld
The Batde of Stones River. N.p., Eastern Acorn Press, 1987. 55 pp. (articles originally appearing in Civil War
limes Illustrated)
The Batde of Stones River. Jamestown, \A, Eastern Acorn Press, 1991. 55 pp.
Bearss, Edwin C. "Cavahy operations in the Batde of Stones River." THQ 19 (I960), pp. 23-53, 110-144.
Bickham, William D. Rosecrans' campaign with the fourteenth army corps, or the Army ofthe
Cumberlands: a narrative of personal observations with official reports of the Batde of Stone River.
Cincinnati, OH, Moore, Wilstach, Keys &amp; Co., 1863- 467 pp.
Byrne, Stephen C. An archeological survey of the visitor center addition &amp; parking lot expansion.
Stones River National Battiefield, Rutherford County, TN. Tallahassee, FL, National Park Service, Southeast
Archaeological Battlefield, 1990. 12 pp.
Comstock, Rock L. Museum prospectus for Stones River National Military Park. N.p., 1959- 119 pp.
Cozzens, Peter. No better place to die: the batde of Stones River. Chicago, U. EL Press, 1990. 281 pp.
Fitch, John. Annals of the Army of the Cumberland: comprising biographies, descriptions of depart-ments,
accounts of expeditions, skirmishes, &amp; batdes; also its police record of spies, smugglers, &amp;
prominent rebel emissaries. Together with anecdotes, incidents, poetry, reminiscences, etc. &amp; official
reports of the battie of Stone River. By an officer Illustrated with steel portraits, word engravings, &amp; maps.
Philadelphia, J.B. Lippincott &amp; Co., 1863. 671 pp. (various editions)
Hascall, Milo S. Personal recollections &amp; experiences: concerning the Batde of Stone River. Goshen, IL,
Times Pub. Co., 1889. 22 pp. {apaper read by request before the Illinois Commandery ofthe Military Order of
the LoyalLegion ofthe US, at Chicago, R., Feb. 14, 1889)
Horn, Stanley F. The Batde of Stones River. N.p., Eastern Acorn Press, 1983. 15 pp. (firstpublished in Civil
War Times Illustrated)
Logsdon, David R. Eyewitnesses at the Batde of Stones River. Nashville, the author, 1989- 82 pp.
McDonough, James L. "The last days at Stones River: experiences of a Yank &amp; a Reb." THQ 40 (1981),
pp. 3-12.
Page 55
McDonough, James L. Stones River: bloody winter in TN. Knoxville, UT Press, 1980. 271 pp.
Murfnee, Mary N. [pseud. Charles E. Craddock]. Where the battle was fought. Boston, Osgood, 1884. 423 pp.
(fiction)
Phisterer, Irederick. The regular brigade of the Fourteenth army corps, the Army of the Cumberland, in
the batde of Stone River, or Murfireesboro, TN, from Dec. 31st, 1862, to Jan. 30, 1863, both dates
inclusive. N.p., 1883. 30 pp.
Rosecrans, William S. Report on the Battle of Murfireesboro, TN. Washington, DC, US GPO, 1863. 571 pp.
Stevenson, Alexander F. The Batde of Stones River near Murfireesboro, TN, Dec. 30, 1862-Jan. 3, 1863...
Boston, MA, J.K Osgood, 1884. 197 pp.
Taylor, Martha S. Shiloh, again!: the story of Stones River &amp; the Batde of Murfireesboro, TN. Huntsville,
AL, the author, 1989. 50 pp.
Thruston, Gates P Personal recollections of the batde in the rear at Stone's River, TN. Nashville, Brandon,
1906.21pp.
US National Park Service. Denver Services Center. Draft general management plan &amp; drafit development
concept plan for Stones River National Batdefield &amp; Cemetery, Murfireesboro, TN. Denver, CO, National
Park Service, US Dept. of the Interior, 1979. 145 pp.
Vance, Wilson. Stone's River, the turning-point of the Civil ^^. NX Neale Pub. Co., 1914. 72 pp.
Willett, AnnWA history of Stones River National Military Park, MTSC thesis, 1958. 155 pp.
Womack, Bob. "Stone's River National Military Park." THQ 21 (1962), pp. 303-317.
Versailles
Nance, R Fred &amp;JohnWNance, comps. The history ofVersailles, tenth district, &amp; its people.
Murfreesboro, Rutherford County Hist. Soc., 1983. 303 pp.
Page 56
</dc:description>
<dc:description>Lists the resources available for historical and geneaological research pertaining to Rutherford County housed at TSLA at the time of publication</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Tennessee State Library and Archives; geneaological research</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>8 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-01-25</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication39ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/9</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>