<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Some biographical sketches from "History of Macon County, Illinois"</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Smith, John W.</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 19</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1876; 1982</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>19th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>113
Some Blogrsphical Sketches
from "History of Macon County, Illinois"
by - John W. Smith 1876
BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCHES of EARLT SETTIERS
JESSE AUSTIN was bom May 3, I8I8, in Rutherford county, Tenn.,
and moved to Macon county in I83IJ was married in 181*7 to Catharine
Faris. Of their seven children -
NANCY E. was bom July 2, I8U8; died 1853. JOSEPH H. was
bom Feb. 16, 1850. ROSETTA A. was bom Sept. iM, l85l, and""was married
to Vfci. C3etts, March 2Ui 1870." WILLIAM I. was bom JuOy 16, I853.
MELLI3SA E. was bom Axigust 25, 1862. ELIZABETH was bom April 2, 1865.
MARY J. was bom Oct. 3, 1857
NEWTON N. BAKER was bom in Lincoln county. North Carolina,
February 28, l803; moved to Rutherford County, Term., when he was eleven
years old, and moved to Macon county in I83O and settled 5 miles east of
Decatur; was married to Tabitha J. Hodge in 1835, and died May 27, 1872.
His wife was bom in Orange coxmty. North Carolina, in I81I;, who came to
Illinois in 1829, and settled in Sangamon county, remained one year and
then removed to Macon coimty; she is still living in Decatur. Of their
children -
AM2I H., was bom in l836j was married to Anna White, in 1867,
and is now HvLig in Decatur. MARY C_., was bom in l839j was married to
S. C. Davis, in 1857, and is still living in this county. JOSEPH N.,
was bom , and is now living in Decatur. JAMES W., was bom ~
,
also living In Decatur.
*"
DAVID DAVIS was bom in Lincoln county. North Carolina, May 2, 1798.
At the age of 17 he emigrated to Rutherford county, Tennessee, In I828
he came to Illinois and settled in this county. At the age of 23 he had
the misfortune to become paralyzed in his lower extremities, and through-out
his long life he walked with great difficulty. Notwithstanding this,
he was ever energetic, and gathered a handsome conqjetence for himself,
and provided liberal means for beneficent charities. He died August 19,
1875. He was once county treasurer and one of the judges of the first
election held in Macon county. He was married to Mary Martin September
28, 1825, who was bom in Rutherford County, Tennessee,November 15, I806.
Of their children -
ISARKTJA C. was bom Aiigust 17, l826j was married to Michael C.
Rozzell, November U, 181*5. WILLIAM M. was bom January 11*, l831j was
married to S. J. Nicholson March 23,"1851*. SYLVESTER C. was bom June 8,
1834; married to Mary C. Baker, September 3, 1857. FlTLTON Z. was bom
August 29, 1835; married to Emma Eichinger, September 3, 18^5. MARY P.
was bom January 11, I838; married to Hiram G. Wheeler, October 11, lF55.
ELIZABETH E. was bom September 6, I8I4I; married to John Rucker, December
28, 1058; died January 2U, I862. JOHN L., was bom December 22, l8ii2;
died April 26, I865. TRAUGHBER L. was bom March 2, 181*5; was married
to Mendosia Houseman, September 25, 1873. MARILLA A. was bom January 2,
181*7; was married to Thcanas J. Odor, September 28, 1869.
116
JOHN McMENNAMT was bom March 10, 1793, In Rutherford County, Tenn.,
and came to Macon cotmtiy in October, 1826, with his brother-in-law,
James Ward. He removed to Texas in 1839, and died there. Of his children-
JOHN H. was bom in iSll;, in Tennessee, and has been constable
in Macon county for 20 years. His wife died some 25 years ago. He had
two children -
OEORCffi. who died a few years ago, and Dr. B. F. Mc
MEaJNAMI, now of Moiiltrie county. ~
~
LUCINDA (now Martin} who reside ix Harristown township.
THDMAS H. READ was bom February 2k, 1798, in Charlotte county,
Virginia, and died on the first day of September, l87li, in the city of
DecatTir. His father moved from Virginia to Rutherford county, Tenn,,
when Thomas was quite young. In the spring of I83I the Doctor moved
from Tennessee to this county; was married on the 2lith of August, I836,
to Elizabeth Allen, of Loudon county, Virginia, who was bom on the Uth
of August, 1812, and came to Macon county in 1835. Names of children -
JULIA E. was bom September 8, 1837, and died October 21, l837.
JOHN N. was bom August 11, I839. MARY S. was bom March 22, I8I4I.
ANNIETh. was bom February 2, I8I43, and died Aiigust 2h, I86U. JAMES A.
was bom May 26, I8ii6. EMMA F. was bom August 31, ISI^S. SUSIE C,
"
was bom January 12, I83I.
"" "
JAMES SANDERS. There are but few old settlers of the county who do
not reioember "Uncle Jimmy Sanders." He was one of the noted men, and al-most
every one knew him, by reputation at least, for an area of a great
many miles. He was bom in Spartanburg county, S. C, Jxxne 15, I8OO, and
Was taken on a packpony when very small, to Rutherford county, Tenn.,
irtiere he remained until he was grown. In 1823 he married Polly Wilson,
who was bom in North Carolina in 1797, and died in Christian county. 111.,
in 1866. In the year I829, he removed with his family to Illinois, where
he has remained ever since. On his arrival in Illinois, he says he had a
wife, five children and an "old plug of a wagon, three old plugs of horses,
one good mare, (^ cents in money. The money he had in his pocket with
his shot and bullets a short time after his arrival, which he accidentally
lost, and was thereby "broken up." Mr. Sanders was a man of most powerful
constitution, and his strength and endiurance were probably not excelled
by any man in Central Illinois. On the day of Ifticle Joe Stevens' wedding,
Mr. S., in a general trial of strength among those persons present, took a
piece of lead, 75 poiinds in weight, in each hand, and raised them on a level
with his shoulders, and then passed them around straight in front until
they touched each other. At one time he had been sic for some length of
time, and when he had sufficiently recovered to walk to the blackberry
patch, he gathered his hat full of blackberries, and then sat down and ate
them all. He returned to the house and said, "Polly, I have eat a few
blackberries and feel better."
He was known far and wide as a good rail-maker, and would go as far
as 15 and 20 miles and make rails for parties at 25 cents per hundred, or
37^ cents in trade, which he regarded as a very liberal price. He was a
man that possessed a great many pecviliarities, a particular mention of
which, wotild extend this sketch quite too far. He relates to-day, with
pride, as one of his greatest achievements, the fact that he at one time
in a wrestling match, threw down * Abe Lincoln, who had thrown the bully
117
of the countiy-. Of Mr. Sanders* children -
KIJM was bom in 1823, and now resides in Kansas. JOHN,
their second, died in the Mexican war. J.AMES B. died in 185U. JANE ,
wife of Prestly Travis, resides in Christian county. PBTBR H., PEGGY,
MATIIDA . BETHANY and AMANDA, are dead. FRANK, the youngest ^lild, was
bom in March, 18U5, and married Annis Hollingsworth, with whom Uncle
Jimmy now resides.
* NOTE: It win be remembered in this connection, that Mr. Lincoln,
wh&#171;i he first came to Illinois, was a resident of Macon county, and he and
Ifr. Sanders were great cronies and friends. Ifticle Jim says that they
spent many Sundays together fishing in the Sangamon, and were often to-gether
at bamraisings, house-raisings, fox=chases and wolf-hunts. At
these early gatherings, when Mr, Lincoln was an awkward gangling boy,
he was often called upon, \rtien the work was through, for a Jackson speech,
and he seldom failed to respond. I'bc. L.'s father was a Jackson Democrat,
and his son grew \3p in that faith, and has made a great many Jackson
speeches in this county. He afterwards changed his politics and became a
Whig of the most pronounced type, which incensed his father no little.
Mr. Lincoln commenced his law stiidies in this co\inty vmder the following
circumstances: He had gone to "Uncle Billy Wamick*s" to see one of the
girls J but in going, his shoes not being good, he got his feet frost-bitten,
and was unable to return home. He remained there for a week or ten days
under the medical treatment of Old Mrs. Wamick, and while so doing became
greatly interested in reading the statutes and a few other stray volumes
of law-books, which, no doubt, afterwards materially determined his course
in adopting his profession. It was reported in the newspapers during the
campaign of i860, that }fr. Lincoln in his early day was a great rail makerj
but Mr. Sanders says that while it is true that "Abe" did make some rails,
yet they were few in number. Mr. Sanders also relates the circumstance
by which Mr. L. ceased to be a resident of this county, which is this: A
man by the name of Offit purchased a few himdred hogs, and Mr. Lincoln
and his step-brother, John Johnson were employed to assist in driving the
hogs to market at Beardstown. When they had disposed of the hogs they in-vested
the money in groceries, which consisted, as IMcle Jim says, of "sod-com,"
spvai-cotton, sugar and coffee, powder and lead, etc., the greater
part of wUch were brought back as far as Salem, where they started a
grocery, and Mr. Lincoln was left in charge of the goods, to keep store.
This was the last of Mr. Lincoln's personal history in connection with
this cotntyT Mr. Sanders' last interview with Lincoln was but a day or so
before Lincoln's departTire for Washington. As they were separating-whlch
proved to be their last-^. Sanders said, "Now, Abe, don't do any wrong."
Mr. Lincoln replied, "I will not, if I know it."
JOHN SMITH was bom June 28, 1796, in Rutherford county, Tennessee;
where he married Margaret Wilson, who was bom at Guilford C. H., North
Carolina, July 25, 1801. They removed to Illinois about 1829 or &#187;30, and
settled at Mt. Zion, where he died, a few years since, loved and respected
by all who knew him. Of their children -
MARY J. was bom November 10, 1822; died at 18. GEORGE A. was bom
J^ril 6, 1825; "died July 29, 1873; married Elizabeth Wilson and as second
wife Martha Wilson. LOUISA C. was bom May 2, 1829; married Rev. J. C.
Smith. CANDOR R. was bom November 17, 1832; died at 13. NANCY M. was bom
November 20, 1837; married W. S. Parr.
~
118
ROBERT SMITH, &amp;. , was bom In Guilford cotmty. North Carolina,
September U, 1782. His father removed to Tennessee, near Nashville,
about the year I603, and remained there about a year, and removed to
Stones River, near Murjdireysborough, where he remained \mtil his
death, in I830. Mr. Stodth r&#171;noved to Illinois in I828, and located
in Sangamon county, where he remained until the spring of I828, when he
came to Macon county, where he settled about six miles south-west of
Decatur, and died in 1855. His father ^ose name was also Robert, was
engaged in the Revolutionary war, and was taken prisoner in North
Carolina. Robert was with Jackson in the battle of New Orleans. His
first wife was ELenor Wilson, irtio died in l82l;j he afterwards married
Jane Allen, vho now lives in Mt. Pleasant, Iowa. His children were -
Andrew W., Nancy, Robert, Vfci. C. and Margaret; all by
his first wife.
ANDREW W. SMITH was bom in Rutherford county, Tennessee, November
25th, 1806. He married Elizabeth Biankenship, who died in I83I.
afterwards married Rebecca R. Smith, Jssiuary 28, l836j &gt;*o died in
November, 1875. He was a member of the old county commissioners coitpt
for several years, and was engaged in the Black Hawk war; he was with
the conpany of rangers that went out from Macon county, towards the head
of the Sangamon, in the viclni-ty of Cheney's Grove. He died in October,
1875, just one month previous to the death of his wife. Of their
children -
ELIZABETH M. J. was bom March IM, 1832; she married Jos.
Trobaugh, and now lives' in Texas. ALEXANDER A. was bom November 25,
1838; was married to laiira Jacobs, October 77 I869. He now resides in
Wheatland township. ABIGAIL E. was bom July 30, l81iO} was married to
B. G. Heniyj tAio now lives on the Lewis Ward place. MARGARET A. was
bom September 5, l814^j was married to Nelson Odor, October 6,"l868j
now living in Wheatland township.
WM. C. SMITH was bom in Rutiierford county, Tennessee, July 5, l8l9,
moved to this cotnty in I828, from Sangamon county; married Leacy J. Pope,
February 17, 181+2, who was bom in Wake county. North Carolina, October
25, 1819. Of their children -
JOHN W. was bom February 9, I8I43; married Mattie J. Weekly,
September 1, 15*68; now resides in Decatur.
GEORGE R. was bom October 2, l8lil;; died November 17, 181+5.
WTTJ.TAM B. was bom January 5, I81i7; married Elizabeth Goff , July 2, 1867;
now lives in Wheatland township. ROBERT H. was bom November 27, 181+9;
married Belle Wilson, September 23,1875; now resides in Blae Mound town-ship.
SARAH E. was bom February 5, 1852. JAMES M. was bom March 20,
1851+. DANIBL~C. was bom March 2l+, 1857; died September 23, 1857.
LEWIS B. WARD was bom in Logan county, Ky., January 17, I809, and
removed to Illinois in I819, and moved to Macon county in I82I+. On the
23d of December, I83O, he married Elizabeth VJalker, who was bom September
8, 1813, in Rutherford county, Tenn., and became a resident of Macon
county in l829; died June 7, 1852. Of their children -
US
ALFBED was bom October 16, I83I. MARY J. was bom November
18, I8335 married S. B. N. Vaiighan. ELTZABETH was bom March 13, l836j
married Woodson Parker. ROBERT was bom June 13, I838. CAROLINE was
bom November lit, I8I4D; married J. B. Moore. HARRgTT was bom November
26, lQl^h. REBECCA was bom November 2?, I8U6. LEWIS J. was bom Feb-ruary
26, 18U8. NANCY A. was bom May 15, 1852; died September 28, 1853.
Mr. Ward was married a second time to Matilda Parker, who was bom
August lii, 1832. He sold his farm in Macon county in the fall of I876,
and removed to Girard, Kansas, prior to which he was the second settler,
in point of arrival, residing in the county. From him we derived most
of our information in reference to the Ward family and Ward settlement.
He fixes the dates of the erection of the first houses in the county in
the following order: 1st, WLlliam Downing' s, south of Sangamonj 2d,
Leonard Stevens', in Stevens' creek; 3d, Abraham Sprague's, just south
of fair-groTind; Uth, Hubble Sprague's, on the inside of the present fair-ground
inclosure; 5th, William King's, a short distance south of the
fair-grounds. Mr. Ward says the first mill in Macon cotmty was on Stevens'
creek, and was built t&gt;y William King in I826, ;rtiich was afterwards owned
by and known as Renshaw's mill; also, that the first hotise in the limits
of the old town of Decatur was just north of Priest's Hotel, and was built
by Reuben Miller, who sold out to James Renshaw, in which the first store
Was kept. He also states that the first school house in the county was
on the old Widick place, now owned by P. M. Wickoff, three and a half
miles southwest of Decatur, and was erected in 1825, and the first school
teacher was "Frozen" Taylor; and that the second school house was on
land now owned by W. C. Snith, erected in I828, in which one Nelson, "a
little Yankee," taught. At this school house Abraham Lincoln went to
singings and spellings. In the spring of I826 Mr. W. raised 1,800 pounds
of cotton in Macon county.
D. K. WILSON was bom March 27, 1825, in Rutherford county, Tennessee;
came to Macon county in 1835, and was married to Mary J. Dickey, February
25, I81i5, who was bom July 31, 1827, in Florence, Alabama, and came to
Macon county in 1829. of their diildren -
SAMUEL was bom April 17, l81|6; was married to Eveline Dresback
In September, 1868, and died January, 1877. MARGARET C. was bom December
17, I81t7; was married to S. B. Betz in March, I869. EIJZA J. was bom
October 8, 181*9; died April I6, I866. ANDREW was bom Septanber 1, l85l;
was married to Ella Bundy April 13, 1875, who was bom April 26, 1859, in
Piqua county, Ohio; came to this county in 1875, and died December 15, I876.
SARAH A. was bom October 25, 1852; was married to R. J. Ross December 9,
187U. MARY E. was bom January 17, 1858; was married to Marian Ranabarger,
February 27,~l876. ZARITHA M. was bom December 3, 1859. WILLIAM A. was
bom December 8, I862. JOHN' W. was bom April 27, 1865; died September 17,
'67. GEORGE W. was bom July 28, I868.
BENJAMIN WILSON was ainong the early and prominent citizens of Macon
counly, and came here in 1827, and was one of the county commissioners
who assisted in the county organization. He held the position for a great
many years. Ife was bom at Guilford Court House, in North Carolina, and
removed then to Tennessee, and afterwards to Illinois. He married JANE
WARNICK in the state of Tennessee, who was a sister of "Ifticle Billy" War-nick,
the first sheriff of the county. Their children were, POLIY,(see
120
Sanders,) RACHEL, (see Hill, J PEGGY SMITH, (see John Staith,; ROBERT.
NANCY. HANNAH , (see Blankenship,; and -
JOHN WILSON was bom in Rutherford county, Tennessee, in 1813,
came to Illinois in 1828, and was married to Nancy VHLlson, March 1, 1832,
who was bom July 6, I8l3, in Greene county, Tennessee, and became a
resident of Macon county about I83O. Of their children -
BENJAMIN T. was bom Augtist 19, I836; died February 5, 185U.
MARY A. was bom October 23, 1833, and married JOSEPH M. DAWSON, who was
bom ^ril 5, I828. Of their children -
John A. was bom July 8, 18^3. Thomas M. was bom
April"'6, 1855. Nancy A. was bom January 19, 18575
died December 29, 1857T Luella B . was bom August
U, 1859. C. E. was bom Januaiy~l8, I863. Edwin P.
was bom December 17, l861i. Oscar W. was bom ""
April 26, 1867.
WILLIAM WIEELER, Sr., was bom in Virginia about 1790, and married
ELIZABETH HAYS, who was bom in the sane State. Mrs. W. died about I836,
Mr. W. in 1866* Their children were, James, Stacy, Henry, William Jr.,
Elizabeth, Raleigh, Burton, Larkin and Nathaniel. Mr. Wheeler and family
removed to Illinois and settled in Macon county, in I828.
JAMES WHEELER was bom in South Carolina in 1799, and died in 1867
.
His wife was Margaret Mayberry.
STACY WHEBLER was bom about I8OO, and married William Christopher,
and died about I83I.
HENRY WHEELER was bom in I80I, in Tennessee, and was married in
Tennessee to Mary Y. Braden, who was bom January ii, I800. Of their
five children -
ELIZABETH E. was bom May 7, I826; married David Brett; died I86I+.
SAMUEL R. was bom August I6, 1827; married Jamima Abrams, who was bom in
1828, in Illinois. mUJME. was bom October 23, l828j married Ellen
Frazee; he died 1875. NANCY'j. was bom January 9, I83OJ married Samuel
Woodward, first husband; Mason Packard, second husband; now resides in
Califomia. ANDREW J. was bom January 16, 1832; riiarried N. E. Cox, who
was bom in Scott coamty, Illinois, 1837.
WILLIAM WHEELER, Jr., was bom on the 28th of Dec, I809, in Ruther-ford
county, Tennessee; was married Oct. 27, I83I, to Sarah A. Ward,
(daughter of Jerry Ward,) who died in August I869. Mr. Wheeler has been
prominently connected with the affairs of the county, and has been re-peatedly
elected sheriff, assessor and collector. Of their 10 children,
but two are living, viz: -
MARY E. , who married Thomas Inscho, now resides in San Jose,
Califomia; and Lewis Cass. ANDREW M. died in &#187;69; CALVIN R.died in '61;
LUCINDA K. died in '63T"'"T7TlIJ:aM L. di&#187;d in '66; HENRIETTA^died in '62;
JAMES C.'died in '51; Thomas Bo died in infancy, and ALICE died in 187U.
la
ELIZABETH WHEEIER was bom In 1831, and married Winiam Ward, the
father of Franklin and Hiram Ward, well known in the county.
RALEIGH WHEELER was bom in I8l3, and died in I83li} his first wife
was Rebecca Travis, and second Mary Fields.
BURTON WHEELER was bom in l8l5, and resides in Motatrie county,
Illinois.
LARKIN WHEELER was bom in I8l7j died in I838.
NATHANIEL WHEELER was bom in l8l9; died when young.
IRA WARNICK was bom in Tennessee, Augst 7, 1823j he moved to this
cotinty in 1825, and settled at the place afterwards knovm as the William
Wamick place, and has ever since resided in this countyj was married to
Julietta Priscila Burke, J^ril 17, 181;3, who was bom in Kentucky, June
30, 1822, and came to this county in l8Uu. Of their nine children all
of which are now living -
JAMES W. was bom April H, 1814!^, and married Ann E. Stevens,
September lU, I869. ELIZABETH E. was bom May 10, I8U6; and married
Edward Hill. ARTHUSA D . was bom August 6, I8U8. THOMAS T. was bom
December 30, 1851, and was married to Mary E. Lynch, in February, l87li.
NANCY C. was bom February I8, 1853, and married S. P. Falconer, Sept.
18, 1873. MAJOR M. was bom March 13, 1855- HaiRIETTE L. was bom
December 10, 1&#171;57T JULIETTA A. was bom September 27, lH"60. mA G.
was bom March 7, 18^1+. " ~
WILLIAM WARNICK, was bom in 1781;, in North Carolina, and married
_, who was bom the same year. He removed from North Carolina to
Rutherford County, Tennessee, and thence to this county, in 1825. He
was the first sheriff of Macon county after its organization, and held
the office from 1829 to I835, and was also re-elected again for two
years, in I8U0. He was in the Black Hawk war, and participated in the
famous Stillman's defeat, where he received a slight flesh wound., He
was also captain of the rangers, during the same difficulty. It was Mr.
W. \rtio, as sheriff of the county, whipped Redmon and W/att, by order of
the court, giving them 39 lashes apiece. This was the only punishment of
the kind ever inflicted in the county. Mr. W's father, James Wamick, was
from Ireland, landing in New Castle, August 15, 1758. Their children were
JOHN, MARGARET . POLLY (first wife of Joseph Stevens; . JAS.,
LUCTODA, BETSY (married John Taylor), CLARK . IRA . ROBERT , SARAHl^arried
Benj. Taylor; now dead.; Ifr. W. died February 12, 1855.
</dc:description>
<dc:description>Reprints of selected biographical sketches from a work published by John W. Smith in 1876; includes information on prominent Rutherford County citizens with ties to Macon County, IL</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.); Genealogy; Macon County (Ill.); Family history</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>9 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-08; mt2011-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication19ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/35</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>