<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>My years at Linebaugh Public Library: 1947 - 1962</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Parsons, Myla Taylor</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 26</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1986</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949; 1950-1959; 1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>101
MY YEARS AT LINEBAUGH PUBLIC LIBRARY
1947 - 1962
by
Myla Taylor Parsons
One day in late spring of 1947 Healer Smotherman,
Superintendent of Rutherford County Schools, asked me if I would be
interested in giving up teaching to do full time library work.
He told me that there was quite a bit of interest in the community
in regard to establishing a public library.
The question naturally came as a shock, for I had thought
that I would be a teacher for the rest of my working days. I
told Dr. Smotherman that I would need time to think before I could
give him an answer.
For the last three years I had been the English teacher
and librarian at Christiana High School. Previous to this time I
lad taught in the elementary school at Christiana and in other
schools in Rutherford County. I had taken a few courses in
library science at Middle Tennessee State College. At the time
Dr. Smotherman mentioned the library possibility, I was enrolled
in library science at Peabody Library School, working toward a
library degree.
After thinking about the pros and cons of taking the
library job and after discussing it with my family, I decided I
would accept the offer. Little did I know what was ahead for me.
At that time I didn't realize how valuable my teaching experience
would be as background knowledge for library work.
102
A Statement, written by Robert Lasseter in an editorial in
the Rutherford Courier in 1942, was undoubtedly responsible for
the establishment of the public library. In his article Mr.
Lasseter lamented the fact that this area was without a public
library.
After reading the article Mr. Henry T. Linebaugh, who, as
a poor boy grew up in Murf reesboro, and later went to Florida and
became wealthy in real estate, made a gift of $5,000 to the City of
Murfreesboro toward starting a library. His only stipulation was
that the library bear his mother's name, Mattie V. Linebaugh.
A City Library Board was appointed, and in order to have
Rutherford County participate in the program a County Library
Board was also appointed, thus having a joint library board. The
City, County, and County Board of Education cooperated with the
state regional program in establishing Linebaugh Public Library.
In addition to lending books to the library the Regional Library
placed deposit stations of books in various areas of the county.
On September 1, 1947 I assumed my duties as librarian of
Linebaugh Public Library. The nucleus of the library was the
Rutherford County School Circulating Library, which was housed on
the second floor of the Rutherford County Courthouse. Previous to
this time Mrs. Katie Lee Peyton had been responsible for checking
out books to the county teachers. She was also the caretaker of
the Rutherford County textbooks. My first responsibility was to
catalog the school library books.
103
If we had inquired of the American Library Association in
regard to requirements for starting a public library, we would
have been told that we didn't have sufficient resources for
undertaking such a task. We knew very well that we couldn't meet
standards when it came to budget, staff, building and books.
However, with the determination of a few dedicated people, we did
undertake the task, and we did succeed.
In the meantime the old Hale home on Central High School
Campus (now Middle School) was being renovated in order to house
the library, which moved to its new quarters the latter part
of 1947.
From the $5,000 Linebaugh funds the Library Board decided
to use $2,000 for furnishings for the new quarters, and $1,500
for books.
After the library moved to the Central High Campus,
Alberta Spence joined our staff as a volunteer worker. She worked
with us for quite some time before we had the funds with which to
pay her a small salary. We were very fortunate in having someone
with Alberta's qualifications. She was a graduate of Middle
Tennessee State College, an excellent typist, an avid reader, and
a person with business experience. I shall always be grateful for
the contribution she made to the library.
The next important step was to prepare for a formal
opening. Much of the renovation was done by the Rutherford County
school maintenance personnel. Shelving, tables, and chairs were
built by the Trade School. Shelves were painted a light blue and
104
lined with red. Three rooms were made ready for the opening &#8212; the
adult reading room, the children's room^ and the conference room.
We were especially proud of the conference room, which was
furnished with red sofa and chairs. My sister. Carmine Jones,
made the blue striped drapes for the windows. The circulation
desk was in the front entrance hall, which had steps that led to
Mrs. Peyton's apartment. Mrs. Peyton decorated the steps with her
beautiful African violets.
We were proud of the books we had acquired. Some were
purchased, others were donated. With these books and the borrowed
books from the Regional Library we were beginning to look like
a library.
On April 1, 1948 we had the formal opening of Linebaugh
Public Library. Invitations were sent to organizations, schools,
libraries, governing bodies, both local and state, as well as to
many individuals. Mrs. W.H. Westbrooks was in charge of the
hostesses for the occasion. They served refreshments to more than
600 people who attended. The library received many compliments
for its homelike atmosphere. It was decorated with many gift
flowers, sent by clubs, schools, and individuals. The register
showed that many important people from the surrounding areas were
our visitors.
We were pleased that the Linebaugh Family recognized the
opening of Linebaugh Public Library. Mr. Lasseter received a
congratulatory letter from Julia Linebaugh King (Mr. Henry T.
Linebaugh's daughter) and a telegram from Henry T. Linebaugh, Jr.
(Mr. Linebaugh, Sr. had died a few years earlier)
.
105
The library was catching on. Much interest was being
shown by clubs, organizations, and schools as well as by
individuals: Beta Sigma Phi Sorority gave a picture for the
children's room; the American Association of University Women had
a silver tea with the proceeds going for books; Publisher, James
G. Stahlman, gave sixty volumes of history; the Craddock Study
Club gave nine volumes; the Stephens Music Club held a pilgrimage
with proceeds going for books on music; the Business and
Professional Club gave money for books.
One of the most interesting donations made to the library
was a map of Rutherford County (1878), showing prominent places
and names of property owners. Mr. Otho Cannon gave the map,
which had hung in his office in the courthouse. The State Library
and Archives did the laminating. The map attracted much attention
on the opening day.
I was invited to visit clubs and organizations to give
book reviews. I never declined the opportunity to publicize the
library. As a result I was giving book talks and reviews rather
frequently. I felt that was a way to sell the library. Our
citizens had to be told again and again that they now had a
library. Many times I was asked to explain our facilities, how
we operated with the schools, with the Regional Library, etc.
The library never lacked for publicity. Bob Lasseter, who
was editor of the Rutherford Courier, did a splendid job. Hardly
a day went by that there wasn't library publicity in the paper.
He realized we were responsible for selling the library to our
citizens. When I went home at night, my family would ask, "What
106
did Mrs. Parsons say today?" Bob would quote me on one thing or
another concerning the library. There was no mistake about it, if
a person read the paper, he knew we had a library.
By the end of the year the library had grown tremendously.
The circulation for the year was over 40,000 books, including
circulation to schools. There were over 1000 registered
borrowers. For a county that previously had no library these
figures meant something.
I was away from the library during the summer months of
1948 to finish my work at Peabody. After I received my library
degree, I was ready in earnest to take up where I left off.
In the fall of 1948 we began story hour for the
youngsters. Dr. Emily Calcott's class in children's literature at
the college conducted this hour for several weeks. Later practice
teachers from the training school took charge.
One of the most interesting pieces of publicity the
library experienced was the two page article written by
Dr.Calcott, entitled "They Like to Read." The article was published
in the "Tennessee Teacher". Dr. Smotherman purchased 1000 copies
for distribution to the schools. Miss Martha Parks, Director of
Regional Libraries, purchased 1000 copies for distribution to
regional libraries. Miss Parks also sent copies to library
extension workers in other states and to the American Library
Association school and public library officers.
In 1951 Dr. Calcott wrote an additional article, entitled
"So you Want an All County Library", featuring Linebaugh Public
Library. The article was published in the magazine, "The Nation's
107
Agriculture". As a result of the article the library received a
complimentary letter from Mrs. Margie Malmberg, Director of
American Library Association office.
In May 1950 the library was fortunate in receiving a
bequest of approximately $30,000 from Mrs. Emma Weitzel, a
Murfreesboro native. I shall never forget the day when a library
patron mentioned that he had heard that the library had been
remembered in a will. You can imagine my excitement. I rushed to
the telephone to inquire of Mr. Lasseter what he knew concerning
the story. He had also heard the story and believed it to be
true. $30,000 was a great deal of money to a library that had
been operating on a "shoe string".
In those early days the library had many distinguished
visitors. Mrs. Frances Cheney, a professor from Peabody Library
School, came to see us before we had our formal opening. She
walked from up town one cold winter day. It was good to see her,
for she gave me encouragement, which I needed. She visited again
on our opening day.
Dr. and Mrs. Henry T. Linebaugh, Jr. of Jacksonville,
Florida, while on a business trip to Nashville, drove to
Murfreesboro to see the library that his father was instrumental
in starting. Dr. Linebaugh remarked that he could not pass up
the opportunity.
Mr. Henry Linebaugh, Sr.'s nieces. Miss Cathryn Trainer
and Mrs. Anne Monahan of Overland, Missouri, made a point to stop
overnight in Murfreesboro in order that they might visit the
library the next day.
108
Dr. S. R. Ranganathan, President of the Indian Library
Association, included Linebaugh Public Library in his visit to
Middle Tennessee schools and libraries,
Mr. Jack B. Spear, Public Library Supervisor of New York
state complimented our organization. He followed his visit with
a letter.
Adelaide Rowell, author of "On Jordan's Stormy Banks", the
story of Sam Davis, autographed her book when she visited
the library.
Nora Buest from the United States Office of Education
remarked after visiting the library that Linebaugh Public Library
was one of the outstanding small libraries of the South.
Mrs. Julia Linebaugh King, daughter of Mr. Henry
Linebaugh, and her husband. Dr. Joe E. King of Birmingham
expressed their pleasure in seeing what had been accomplished.
Mrs. King followed their visit with a complimentary letter.
By this time we felt that the library was making progress.
The citizens, for the most part, knew that Rutherford County had a
public library. Our greatest need was more books for the shelves.
The big question was how could we get them. We knew the budget
would not permit very many purchases. Mr. Lasseter and I had many
discussions concerning the matter. These discussions led to the
beginning of our present memorial book program. Never in our
fondest dreams did we think the program would reach the success it
has today. The same procedure used for the first memorial book is
still used. We are proud of the results. The program was and
still is a success.
I believe I am correct in saying that the library owes res
tremendous growth to the success of the memorial program. We knew
that books would go a long way toward answering the problem.
A library cannot have a good circulation without those needed books
to circulate. We can truly say, "This was the beginning of
something big".
The memorial book program story spread to many area of the
country. Many libraries asked for detailed information as to the
procedure used in beginning a similar program. We sent them a
sample of our printed card, used to send to the family of the
deceased, the method of selection of books, and the procedure for
publicity, etc. We always added a note saying: the program
entailed a great deal of work, the librarian needs to be
professional and dedicated to the cause, and that we were fully
convinced that the program was a "life-saver" for a small,
struggling library.
The time had come when the library had outgrown the
quarters on the high school campus. The board decided to purchase
the old Elks Club building on Spring Street. Funds from
Mrs. Weitzel's bequest were used for this purpose. The library
was closed for moving on August 14, 1953.
Any kind of moving has its problems, and the moving of
a library is no exception. I'm sure every librarian works out
special procedures. With the assistance of Alberta Spence and my
brother, James Taylor, we were able to get the new place in order
for business by September 9 with open house a month later.
mehauqh Library
ctinii on E&#187;st Main sl.'eesi m a buiicjm^j forrnerSy part sf the c-fd '(&#171;r-&gt;'8&#171;i^i-- C(^i&gt; o&#171; -&gt;3- vVo'r!?o {^ ss^t
P-^COf-fi-S show {hAt hyrcireS', of R^;h&gt;"-fO!-ci &lt;,Oiiniia&#171;S are !.iSiri&lt;; tiif- fvfOiS &#187;y f.f-/ o -j5!?&gt;! Mr), V ,i^
P &lt;i&gt;'i-^ Sm% a&#171;:ry&#171;s&gt;:i z% hbrafian since ts? &#163;!ps")if&lt;g of the V&gt;b&lt;-&#187;.r&gt;f. /"^-^ '''. f "'"' ^&lt;
Mrs. AAylo Parsons,
top right, wos
limebaugh's first
librarian, I
111
It was good to have more room. The location of the
library up town had its advantages. The attendance and
circulation increased considerably. The Elks Club building lent
itself well for our furnishings. The red sofa and chairs seemed
to belong in front of the fireplace which held sycamore logs. Dr.
Goodman gave a picture and brass urns with which to decorate
the mantle.
The garden clubs have always been friends of the library.
They planted shrubbery in front of the building and planted petunias
in the urns on the front porch, for which we received
many compliments.
The library was still being operated with a minimum amount
of funds. It was a struggle to survive, but with the cooperation
of city, county and Rutherford School system, the library
continued. It's difficult to believe that the library received
only $4,350 from the Rutherford County Court for 1953. Every year
from the beginning representatives from the library have asked the
court for additional funds. Without the persistence and selling
abilities of people like Bob Lasseter, Baxter Hobgood and Tillman
Haynes, Jr. the library would have long since closed its doors.
In those early days there were many people who gave their
services to the library. Harriet Haynes (Mrs. James B.) was one
who made a contribution that will always be remembered. She
conducted story hour during the summer months. The children
adored her. With her rich background and her special talent, she
could entertain the children for hours. She should have had
10
renumeration tor her services, but the library had no funds witn
which to pay her. This was Harriet's way of helping the library
get on its way.
The library welcomed groups to use the library for exhibit
and committee meetings. Art and historical exhibits were held
frequently. We wanted the citizens to feel that the library
belonged to them. Among the groups who held meetings were people
interested in the following activities: Garden Club Pilgrimage,
Charity Circle Chorus, fashion shows. Delta Kappa Gamma Teacher
Society, League of Women Voters, Symphony Concert, D.A.R.,
U.D.C. and others.
Many people have valuable books in home libraries. After
many years they may decide to either discard or give their books
to a library. I was invited to examine several collections.
Some of our most valuable books came from this source. In a
community with the cultural background that Murfreesboro has, you
will find many a gem in someone's attic. In those early days we
could not afford to turn down these offers. A library that has an
adequate budget may not afford the time it takes for such an
undertaking. There are many books in these collections that the
library cannot use, but in many instances valuable books are
discovered. Some of the books in the Tennessee Room came from
this source. For example, books by the following authors were
located: Mary Noailles Murfree, Will Allan Dromgoole, Andrew
Lytle, etc. Valuable books on the Civil War period were found.
It was good to find one of Ed Bell's books, "Fish on the Steeple"
11
113
ELKS CLUB BUILDING
(out of print) in someone's discarded collection. Later I found14
other copies of Ed's "Fish on the Steeple" and his "Tommy
Lee Feathers".
I am indebted to my brother, James Taylor (deceased), in
assisting me in checking the above books. We did this work at
night after working hours. His ability as a history teacher was
very helpful.
Publicity continued to be of most importance to the growth
of the library. Without question the local newspaper contributed
a great deal. One of our first bits of advertising was the
placing in bold type on the front page of the paper, usually in
the lower corner, the question, "Have You Read?" Under the
question was the name of the book - a different book each day.
This device caught on rapidly. Ethel Womack volunteered a column,
"It Seems to Me". Later Lady Brown wrote a column,
"At Linebaugh". These two writers not only listed and discussed
interesting books, but they also informed patrons as to what was
going on at the library. There could not have been better
publicity than the frequent listing of memorial books, with name
of book given, name of donor, and name of person for whom the
book was given.
The library was not air-conditioned in those days.
A group of patrons organized a "Library Auxiliary". The first
project was to air-condition the library. Mrs. L.A. Slaten
(deceased) was chairman, and Mrs. Cornelia Davidson was treasurer.
The library was air-conditioned in July 1957.
12
On April 1, 1958 it was time for a ten year anniversary.
The library had come a long way. These had been years of
struggle. The important result was that the library had survived.
The budget was now a little more than $10,000.
For ten years Smyrna Community had a deposit station for
books, administered by the State Regional Library. The community
decided they needed more than a deposit station. The Library
Board agreed. Katherine Haynes Walkup (Mrs. William T.) was an
important force behind this project. Katherine, a former
librarian, and native of Smyrna understood the needs of the area.
After making necessary agreements and arrangements with the
governing bodies involved, it was decided that Smyrna would become
a branch library of the Linebaugh Public Library system. With a
few of Linebaugh's books and the Regional Library's books a
library was started, housed in an old residence.
Mrs. Jimmie Webster was the first librarian, with Mrs. Mary Carter
as the assistant.
After a short while Smyrna Public Library had open house.
The community was most enthusiastic. Many of the citizens came by
to show their appreciation. Mr. and Mrs. Brainerd Cheney,
residents of Smyrna, presented several books on the occasion.
By 1960 the library was outgrowing its quarters. When we
moved to the Elks Club building, we thought we had space for many
a day, but how mistaken we were.
In the meantime the Post Office building on College Street
had been vacated for a new building on West Main. Bob Lasseter,
always alert when it came to the needs of the library, suggested
to the board that it might be possible to obtain the building for
115
13
116
the library. As a result contacts and correspondence began with
members of Congress and other influential people. This work was
not in vain, for in 1961 the General Service Administration gave
the building to the area to be used for a library.
I shall never forget the day when Bob and I went over to
the Post Office building to survey the possibilities. Previously
I had seen only the entrance portion of the building in front of
the service counters. How surprised I was to see the amount of
space available. My dreams began. I was late going to sleep that
night, for I was thinking about all the possibilities.
Remodeling began shortly. The board gave me permission to
purchase furnishings for the new quarters - shelving, tables, card
catalog, etc. It was quite interesting to plan for the different
areas - reading rooms, children's department, stacks, etc. John
Carter, Remington Rand's representative^ had many sessions with me.
For quite some time I had been anxious to change our
circulation system. We had outgrown the procedure we were using.
Syd Shinn, the Regional Librarian at that time, and I visited many
libraries throughout the state, observing the various systems. AS
a result we decided to use the library card system - an individual
card for each patron. This system was installed shortly after the
library opened for business at its new location.
When I began the project at the Post Office, I had no idea
that in a short time I would be leaving the library. When one has
given himself to his work as I had at Linebaugh, he is not aware
14
. . . ... 117
when he is over-extending himself. On visiting my doctor I was
told that I needed to make my work day shorter. When there was so
much to be done, I couldn't see how I could heed the advice.
At this time there was a vacancy in the reference
department at Middle Tennessee State College. After much careful
consideration and after many talks with my family, I decided I
would resign at Linebaugh and take the job at the college.
Linebaugh Public Library had become an important part of
my life. Could I give it up? Yes, I must for my best welfare.
I rationalized that I was leaving a library that was well on its
way. It was considered by authorities to be an excellent small
library, with a memorial book program that had not been equalled.
I resigned from Linebaugh Public Library on June 30, to
begin work at Middle Tennessee State College Library on July 1,
1962. A few days before I left the library, the Board gave a
lovely dinner in my honor at the Student Union Building on MTSC
campus. They presented me a charm bracelet, depicting the facets
of the Linebaugh Public Library program. When I accepted the
bracelet, I made this remark, "Linebaugh will always be an
important part of my life."
Mrs. Briley Adcock, who was finishing her library training
at Peabody was employed as the new librarian. Alberta Spence, my
assistant, would be the acting librarian during the interim.
When the college library closed between quarters, I came
back to Linebaugh to assist in the new registration and install
the new card system.
15
118
Linebaugh Public Library had four homes while I was
librarian. The library was moved from the Courthouse in 1947 to
the Old Hale home on Central High Campus, to the Elks Club
building in 1953, and finally to the Post Office building where it
has been since 1962. It is still growing, and at the present time
needs additional space.
I have never regretted that I told Bealer Smotherman on
that day in 1947 that I would be the librarian for Linebaugh
Public Library. In spite of all the vicissitudes that came our
way, I enjoyed it all. At the end of my work I felt that we had
accomplished something for which the community was proud.
There were many people who gave me much assistance and
moral support. I must say, "Thank you" to the following:
Bob Lasseter, whose optimism gave me the courage to carry on.
Tillman Haynes, Jr., whose kind words of appreciation, I shall
never forget.
Baxter Hobgood, who made me feel that I was a good librarian.
James W. Taylor (Bill), my brother, who helped me when I
couldn't help myself.
Alberta Spence, whose untiring efforts helped us put the
library on "its feet".
Bealer Smotherman, who was the first to ask me to be librarian.
Mrs. Katie Lee Peyton, who gave all she had to the library's
early efforts.
My daughter. Fay, who knew I was at the library if she didn't
see me at home.
Other members of my family, who took care of Fay while I was
taking care of the library.
AND
All the citizens of Nurfreesboro and Rutherford County, who
believed in me and encouraged me to believe in myself.
16
</dc:description>
<dc:description>Memoir of Myla Taylor Parsons, who helped found Rutherford County's Public Library system</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.); Public libraries</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>21 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-01; mt2011-02-02</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication26ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/12</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>