<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>A view of the battlefield of Stones River</dc:title>
<dc:creator>C.Y.S. [unknown]</dc:creator>
<dc:contributor>Brigance, Fred</dc:contributor>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 8</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1865; 1977</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>A VIEW OF THE BATTLEFIELD
OF STONES RIVER
From the New York Times, Sept. 2, 1865
Furnished by Fred Brigance
Murfreesboro, Tenn. , Friday, Aug. 25, 1865
Murfreesboro, the old capital of Tennessee, is another of the many places
aboiHiding in this region of no special note in themselves, but made famous
by the rebellion. A recent visit to it I found singularly interesting, and hav-ing
gathered some facts, and acquired some information which will be of
interest, I think, to sundry readers of the TIMES, I shall make the record
for their particular benefit.
The city may have had a population of 6, 000 or 7, 000 before the war,
though it looks now as if this figure were a very liberal estibate. It is a
terribly war- scratched place. The destruction of property in it and around
it has been immense. All peaceful and profitable industries have been for
dreary years rudely broken in upo.i, and the old town wears the appearance
of having lain long in a trance, and now slowly awakening from it to find
its beautiful and valued things ravished aw.y by the spoiler during the sway
of its profound lethargy.
The town is spread over considerable space, and all that space, wi1h tJic
buildings of various kinds occupying it, betokens the terrific ravages of war.
What these particular ravages are, have been too often told to need
repetition. Fences torn down to the naked and unsightly stumps, buildings
more or less dismantled- -these are only a part of the defacing work that
war delights in. The state house of a former day, stands in the centre of
the Murfreesboro square- -a substantial, dome-crowned edifice within wiiich
Tennessee legislators were wont to expound laws and make them; and, though
a structure no way striking arthitectually or esthctically, looked upon in
its palmy day, no doubt, as a wonderful creation. Military offices have for
months and months been found here, and Uncle Sam's bayonets have bristled
and do still upon its porticoes and along its courts. Its firm stone fence,
as it once was, capped with iron railing, has all crumbled away. And its
whole appearance with surroundings, seems to exclaim if this be the c-ondi -
tion of the city's heart what must be that of the body and extremities ?
The aspect, in fact, is sharply military. Compassing the place for a dJs
lance of seven miles is a scries of lunettes, redoubts earthworks, &amp;( . , in
form starshaped, and all filled to do yeoman's execution- -the complement
of guns for the whole number being sixty -six- -on such daring assailants as
may call forth their slumbering energies. This has been done at several
memorable periods; by WHEELER in Octobcn" of 1863, and again in September
of 1864. On the first of lhese occasions, this marauding cavalry leader
lay around the town tor two days and a half, and on his second visit rc^mained
seven days, being driven off both limes with loss.
FORREST tried hJs hand nc xt in concert with flOOD. lie arrived before
Murfreesboro and the day after the battle of Franklin, and remained here
some twenty days. Tht&gt; programme was for FORREST to take Murfreesboro,
while HOOD should 1ak&lt;^ Nashville. Gen. THOMAS slightly disappointed the
latter in his darling scheine. Gen. MILROY baffled the attempt and efforts
of the former. The battle of the Cedars, fought in sight of Murfreesboro,
in which MILROY repulsed FORREST, having more than twice the number
of the former, capturing many men and two 22- pounders, proved that all
FORREST'S plans in this quarter would come to naught. Accordingly, after
HOOD'S defeat before NashvilJe, FORRE.ST abandoned the ground here and
joined in a retreat which, in the case of the worse-bafnod HOOD, bccamo
little less than a disastrous rout. During all the period of FORRFOST'S stay
about Murfreosboro, skirmishing was going on daily at some point of the Jin&lt;^s.
Shells from 1he rebels' batteries occasionally flew into the city. Several
buildings, among them the State- House, bear the ugly marks such as these
gentle missiles are wont to make.
The State- FIousc (as it was before the capital was renvwed) has other
incidents connected with it that illustrate the rebellion. JOHN MORGAN,
of raiding memory, married here, in 1862, a daughter of Judge READY,
formerly member of Coiigress and long among the most influential and pro-minent
of citizens. After the interesting ceremony, the happy pair held a
public reception in one of the legislative chambers, at which numbers of
the officers and men or MORGAN'S command, and citizens generajly, were.
present with their congratulations, and wishes for the long life and happiness
of the newly wedded. In spite of the wishes, the liie of MORGAN did not last
long, and Mrs. M. is a widow at her father's house.
At the breaking out of the rebellion, a citizen named WINSHIP ascended
to the top of the State- House, and iia his newfledged rebel zeal, tore down the
Stars and Stripes floating from the staff there, and put the secession rag
in its place. When the news reached Murfreesboro of the fall of Richmond,
this man was compelled to go to the top of the capital , and on the very spot
where he had, four years before, committed this indignity upon the nation's
flag, to unfurl the banner of the victorious and free, and for half an hour
to keep it waving in view of shouting and rejoicing crowds that filled the
grounds below. It was a fitting punishment for a felon deed.
After the surrender of l.ee's army, a fine liberty pole, 15 6 feet in height,
was erected in the State- House groujads, and a splendid flag, raised by gen-eral
contribution, was lifted to the breeze amid the acclamations of an
enthusiaslic multitude. Judge READY, Chaplain RARNSHAW and Squire
BURGER made addresses in honor of "that standard sheet" thus propitiously
unfurled, and destined to "float forever"
.
Murfreesboro had nine hospitals after the battle of Stone River, the number
being afterward reduced to Ihree or four, and now reduced to one, contain
ing about 100 patients, occupying the Soule Female Seminary. The churches
used for this purpose are most of them now in condition to be opened for
Divine service, several of them being so employed. Nearly every minister
of the town was rebel, the only exception I have heard being Prof. PENDl&gt;ETO^
, who taught in the Union (Baptist) University here. He was from Ohio, and
is now returned there. Th(; rebel pastors fled when the Union occupancy
began, and their church(&gt;s were, of course, closed- -those, at least, that
the government did not occupy. Several of these churches are now opened
under Union auspices.
Rev. Dr. PRETTIMAN, formerly Missionary to Bulgaria, (Turkey) is
recently come as a missionary to the Methodist church in this place, and has
commenced operations with very encouraging prospects. He found around
him here some thirty earnest members of his own order from the North, and
with these his foothold will be firm at once. He is moreover a gentleman of
culture and of pleasing mai-mcM-s, and withal an excellent preacher. Rev.
78
Mr. ANDREWS, sent by the General Assembly of the Presbyterian Churc-h,
has been laboring here about four wec^ks. He, too, finds a considecabje
number of Northern Presbyterians, ready and anxious to hold up his hands,
and promote his reconsi meting Christian work. Rev. Mr. DUNN, sent
hither by Ihe Baptist Home Missionary Soeiety- -and here some three weeks -
is also ministering in his sphere, with fair prospeets of usefulness. Jn fact,
the religious interest in the 1own has been utterly prostrated and paraly/.cnl
for upward of three years and but for the aid thus rendered from the Norlh,
a long time must have elapsed without any serious attempt, from this quar-ter,
to build up what thc^ rebc^lJion has so disastrously thrown down.
This place indeed was one of the rebel str-ongholds. It has fought the
Union, with "teeth, nails, claws, beak, wings" as Carlyle expresses it,
and only succumbed through sheer force. Of course its sanctuaries shared
from the fatal effects springing from such insane fury. The beautiful houses
that the fathers built others must now occupy, and will, till a better and
truer spirit possesses Ihe minds of the former worshippers.
There was a flourishing college here before the rebellion, combining theo-logical
and medical courses of study, with purely literary, and belonging
to the Baptist order. It stands just on the outskirts toward the south, a
commodious, well-built structure, in the midst of grounds that must once
have been extremely beautiful. The Union and rebel lines hemmed it in on
either side, and the result is, that all around it is defaced and mutilated,
the building itself being rifled of its windows and doors, and presenting other
evidence of the scars and gashes it received from its exposed situation.
A heavier loss than this was the one sustained by its library, which, consisting
of 13, 000 volumes, is now reduced to the beggarly account of 700- the rest
being scattered and lost beyond recovery. This going into rebellion for a
theory is very costly, as well to literature as to religion and humanity.
I was struck with the number and extent of the cotton fields about Murfreos-boro.
The County of Rutherford always stood high as cotton county, but this
year it surpasses itself. Major STUBBLEFIEI.D, District Attorney at
Nashville, a long resident oJ" ihe State, and familiar with its agriculture,
informed me lately thai Teimessee would raise more cotton this season than
for any one year for twenty years past. This statement was confirmed by
what I saw and heard her(^. The crops were looking finely, though the Jong
dry and hot spell had begun to pinch Ihom a little. A reliabJe gentleman told
me that at and about Murfreesboro not less than a hundred Northern men had
a hand this year in cotton crops, with good prospect of success. Major
JOHNSON, who leased a farm of Mr. MANEY for several years to grow coi-ton
on, realized, it is sajd, $90,000 by his crop last season. Two Pennsyl-vania
companies are at work in the same business near by, and others, like
them, have been tempted to strike in by the high price of cotton, and the
comparatively low figure at which cxcelJent land may be rented. This will
explain the large aggregate yield expected this year, and will point to what
the coming year will be likely to unfold in this business. It is certain that
Tcnnesse&lt;- holds out rare inducements for peopJe from without to embark in
an enterprise which promises to render large returns to capital and industry.
79
1 rode out to the famous Stone River Battlefield two or three miles distant
from, the town. I had noticed a square, unadorned, limestone monument,
close by the railroad tract, as I passed the spot several times before, t
know it stood near where the hottest battle raged, and brave men feiJ fast..
On visiting it J found it to be erected by the survivors of the brigade com-manded
by Col. HAZEN, since Major-Gen. HAZEN his immediate promotion
being the result of meritorious services on this great day. This monument -
rather a heavy piece of work- -recounts the gallant exploits of this brigade;
has the names of its officers who fell inscribed on it, and records, in some
well-turned sentences, the honor due by the country to the noble men- -the
heroes of Shiloh also- -who sealed their devotion to it with their blood.
Several small stones close by contain the names of private soldiers who fell
upon that spot. The trees standing all round display in abundance hugh gashes
and limbless trunks, the effect of the crushing artillery. The very spot was
shown me, close to the tomb, where Gen. Ilosecrans Adjutant- GeneraJ gal-loping
to execute an order had his head taken clean off by a cannon ball, the
body being carried several yards before it fell from the horse. He was an
accomplished officer and a man of great personal worth. Here, too. Gen.
VAN CLEVE, distinguished at the battles of Mill Spring and Perrj^ville, was
wounded and borne off the field, to recover , however, for the fight at
Chickamauga, where less success attended the Union arms. The General Is
now the commandant, honored of all who know him- -of the Middle District
of Tennessee, with headquarters at Murfreesboro.
Advancing along the railroad northwai-dly a couple of hundred rods, and
looking across it toward the east a similar distance, a gentle wood- crowned
eminence appears, on which ROSECRANS massed his batteries among the
trees and awaited the coming up of the rebel battalions under BRECKINRIDGE,
certain that the day was won and the Yankees irrecoverably routed. Here
the fate of the battle hung suspended and the bloody day was to be decided.
On came the vivacious, shouting masses, from the direction of Stone River,
little suspecting the terrible r(;ception in store for them. On they came, in
the attitude of vanquishers and pursuers. They had broken and pushed back
the Union lines; they had only to follow up and make assurance of victory
doubly sure. Suddenly, eighty cannon opened upon the advancing columns,
pouring their deadly missiles into the very midst of the dense array. The
stock was tremendous- the carnage was awful. From BRECKINRIDGE'S own
repoiH to the rebel authorities, 2, 000 of his men fell there in the space of
twenty minutes. To advance in the face of this fearful and deadly hail was
impossible. The tide was checked on the spot, then pulled back. The lines
just before so confident fell back, broken and dispirited, beyond Stone River,
leaving him whom they thought discomfited master of the field. It was a great
achievement, and productive of great results. Upon the brows of the commandi
and his gallant army the laurels won that day will remain green so long as
history can embalm the noble deeds of a nation's heroic sons.
Those who fell here dc^serve well that special honor should bo paid to their
remains. This is about to be done. Sixteen acres were set apart by Gen.
THOMAS about a year ago for this pious purpose. The tract is where tiie
80
hottest battle raged for a part of the time, one side of it resting on Ihe rail -
road, in plain sight of the muHitudes who wJIJ pass and repass it on Ihal gri;at
line of travel . The opposite side rests on the A-lurfreesboro pike. From (&gt;ach
of these p&lt;-)ints the ground slopes gradually upward. On the top a monumeni Tf)
feet high will be erected, from appropriate designs not yet completed. Cen-tering
in the square on which the monument is to stand, are twelve avenues
running up from the outer circle. Along these will be ranged th(&gt; various lots
to receive the remains of the honor&lt;^d deed, each State having a suitable lot
appropriated to it for the interment of the dead belonging to it, as far as
they can be identified. A wall 4 1/2 feet high by 2 1/2 feet thick, built of
granite, will surround the cemetery, While the two main entrances fronting
the railroad and the pike, will be under high arches finished with suitable
emblematical devices. A fine quarry near at hand will furnish the granite
for the walls as well as for the monument, and superb gravel for the avenues
is also near at hand. From the One Himdreth and Eleventh Regiment U. S.C.T.
quartered here, four squads of twenty-five men each, have been detailed
to perform all the work with competent masons to superintend and direct
them. These men are now at work, getting the grounds in readiness for those
who are to sleep here after being removed from where they are resting now.
It is believed that upwards of 8, 000 of our soldiers fallen in battle in the
various engagements around JVIurfrecsboro, as well as at Stone River, will
be interred in this cemetery.
The whole work is under the special superintendence of Rev. W. P^/arnshaw,
for two years sole Chaplin at Murfreesboro, previously Chaplain of the Forty-ninth
Regiment Pennsylvania Volunteers and present at nearly every battle
in the Peninsula campaign. He is an intelligent, laborious and efficient officer,
and will give his earnest and constant attention to the important work which
Gen. THOMAS has intrusted to his care. He intends to make the spot every
way, worthy of its noble occupants so that when kinsfolk and friends visit
it, or strangers are drawn to the consecrated ground, they may find it every-thing
that affection or patriotism could desire, as the best resting place of
the loved and heroic men who died that their countx^y might live. C. Y.S.
</dc:description>
<dc:description>This arrative from the New York Times discusses the condition of Murfreesboro and the Stones River Battlefield post-battle.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Forrest, Nathan Bedford, 1821-1877; Morgan, John Hunt, 1825-1864; Murfreesboro (Tenn.) -- History; Ready, Charles, 1802-1878; Rosecrans, William S. (William Starke), 1819-1898; Stones River (Tenn.); Stones River National Battlefield (Tenn.); Stones River, Battle of, Murfreesboro, Tenn., 1862-1863; Union University (Jackson, Tenn.); United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Breckinridge, John; cotton; monuments &amp; memorials</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>11 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-01</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication08ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/76</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>