<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>The Sanders family of the old first district of Rutherford County</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Farrar, Christine Sanders</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 6</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1976</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>18th century; 19th century; 20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>80
THE SANDERS FAMILY OF THE OLD FIRST DISTRICT
OF RUTHERFORD COUNTY
BY
CHRISTINE SANDERS FARRAR
After 1766 when Uriah Stone, with his hunters and adventurers,
found the rich bottom lands along the river which now bears his name,
many families from all sections of the country came to settle in what
is now the first district of Rutherford County, Tennessee.
Among the early settlers were the names of Sanders, Weakley,
Donelson, Lannom, Burnett, Nash, Buchanan, Ridley, Wright, Carter,
Smith, Barnett, Bodily, Freeman, Smart, Goodwin, and others.
Stories of the "Long-Hunters" and "Indian Fighters" handed down
through generations leads one to believe many may have come exploring
before returning to bring their families, such is the story of the
Sanders Family.
A two room log house still stands on the Fate Sanders road about
one half mile from Couchville Pike was supposedly built in North
Carolina By the Sanders '-if true they were here before Tennessee was
a State.
Among the earliest Land Grants were 640 acres on Stones River
opposite the mouth of Stewarts Creek to Robert Weakley 1793, which
became part of the Lafayette (Fate) M. Sanders lands which the Fed-eral
Government acquired in 1966 from his daughter, Christine S.
Poole Farrar for the Percy Priest Lake. Earlier owners had been
J. H. Charlton and Asa Houston Sanders, father of Fate Sanders and
son of Isaac. An 1805 Deed of 640 acres from John Donelson to Isaac
*LAFAYETTE (FATE) MORTIMER SANDERS
*ANNIE GOODWIN SANDERS
o4/
MOSES R. BUCHANAN
l^sH^'tflU ^Hl^^^^v
The Buchanan Mill (picture circa 1915) - Was
located behind the old Sewart Air Force Base
property and near the Youth, Inc. installation
*A Sanders child appeared in each of the
two pictures
.
Excerpt from Moses Buchanan's Obituary
"In 1820, Mr. Buchanan settled on a
magnificent farm, lying on Stone's River,
in Rutherford County. He built in that
year Buchanan's Mill, which is still
standing. On Stone's River, then a
navigable stream, Mr. Buchanan built
the first lock and dam at his mill ever
constructed in Tennessee." The
Daily American , May 30, 1887
81
and Luke Sanders was one of the first Deeds to the Sanders family.
They with Thomas, Elisha, William and Cornelius were the forefathers
of this later known as the "Sanders District". In 1850 there were
140 Sanders' in this Community and men by other names were married
to Sanders women.
Even though this was a fertile farming area the pioneer had
to be knowledgeable in many fields such as tanning leather, making
shoes, spinning and weaving cloth, cabinet making, carriage building
and carpentry. There were cotton gins, saw mills and grist mills.
Blacksmith shops, for making the many required implements necessary
in farming, were a part of e^ery community.
The six sons of Isaac and Mary Sanders were land owners and
farmed on a large scale in the community. They were Thomas, John
H. , Isaac Jr., Wiley, William Meredith and Asa Houston.
Isaac Sanders Sr. seems to have been the financier of his family.
He was the Executor of his fathers estate in North Carolina and surety
on many bonds of other members of his family. His plantation of sev-eral
hundred acres was divided among his sons. All were farmers in
the first district during their life time with the exception of Wiley,
who with his wife, Martha Hart, moved to a farm on Jefferson Pike at
Stewarts Creek where he operated a saw-mill also. Martha was drowned
trying to save a wash-woman who had fallen in the creek. Wiley Sanders'
second wife was Virginia Rucker and he with his two wives are buried
in the garden of their house which is now the center of the Smyrna Golf
82
Course.
The home of Thomas Sanders, oldest son of Isaac and Mary, was on
Stones River at Spring Creek where a grist mill was operated by water
power. Later a stave and hoop mill was operated by steam power where
a Mr. McKennon lost his life by getting a leg caught in a shaft. The
old home still stands and was occupied by a son, Isaac Summer Sanders,
until his death in 1915. Isaac Summer Sanders married Mary Jane
Richmond, daughter of Dr. John Richmond of Wilson County.
It was after the Civil War that Daniel Thomas, son of Isaac
Summer, went to Texas in search of cheap land but finding it was too
expensive at 50t per acre in Lamar County, he returned home and op-erated
a general merchandise store across from the mill, and named it
Lamar. It was here that one of the earliest Post Offices for the
first district was established. Mail was brought in from Walter Hill
and Mt. Juliet. The other Post Office was "May Eller", located in the
store of Wm. M. Wright on Couchville Pike across from the farm of his
father-in-law, John H. Sanders. Mail was called for at these two loca-tions
until a delivery route was sent out from Smyrna, Tenn. for some
sections and from Mt. Juliet for others.
Daniel Thomas Sanders with his wife, Almeda Word, moved to Nash-ville
when his two daughters, Dora and Callie, became librarians at
Vanderbilt University. His son, Daniel, became a Pharmicist, and
grandson. Dr. Dan, is now a well-known Pediatrician. Another son of
Daniel Thomas was Epps Richmond Sanders who operated the farm with his
grandfather, Isaac Summer Sanders. The mill was operated by a brother-in-
law, Edward Weston and later by Geo. Patton who met and married
83
Miss Betty Welch. Their sons are James W. Patton, Prof, of History at
the University of N. Carolina and George A. Patton, a large land owner
in the Fellowship community and a building contractor now living in
Nashville.
Dr. Robley Elwood Sanders, son of Isaac Summer, lived and prac-ticed
medicine in this community until he married Miss Annie Randolph
and moved to Walter Hill. Another son, John Richmond Sanders, married
Mary Frances Jones and moved to a farm near Smyrna, Tenn. and had
three daughters. Isaac Summer Sanders, Jr. married Lucy Emaline
Sander and lived across Stones River from his father's farm.
Charlie Lenord Sanders, son of Isaac Summer Sanders, married Mrs.
Annie Bonds and moved to Dallas, Texas. The Rutherford Parkes Library
at Castle Heights School in Lebanon, Tenn., was given by his son-in-law
of that name.
Thomas Marion Sanders, third son of Thomas and Mary Lannom
Sanders, married Martha Gregory and moved to a farm north of Smyrna on
the Nashville Highway. He was named for his grandfather Thomas and
Gen. Francis Marion, the "Swamp Fox" of the American Revolution, under
whom he fought. Thomas Marion was a Confederate soldier quartermaster
Tenn. Volunteers.
A son of Thomas Marion Sanders was Dr. Evander (Van) Sanders,
Surgeon at Protestant Hospital, Nashville, for many years. He died
from an infection caused by a needle prick in his hand.
Leonard Sanders, another son of Thomas Marion Sanders, married
Clara Northway and operated the farm with his father. Thomas Gregory
Sanders, another son of Thomas Marion Sanders, married Frances Kimble
84
and is living in Sarasota, Florida at age 94 years.
Wm. Meredith Sanders, fifth son of Isaac Summer Sanders, with his
wife, Margaret Barnett, and thirteen children, operated a large farm
on Stones River between Stewart and Spring Creeks. They lost five
children during the 1850' s with typhoid fever, and his wife died in
1863. His second wife, Mrs. Sophia A. Martin, gave him his fourteenth
child and a step-daughter. He was also guardian for the nine minor
children of his brother, Thomas, who had died at age 45. Yet he was a
prosperous farmer, a churchman, and his name often appears on legal
documents which made him active in many businesses. He and his
brother, Asa Houston, were well versed in law. They were Masons, mem-bers
of the Mt. Juliet Lodge #379 and later transferred to Smyrna
Lodge where A. H. Sanders was on the Building Committee in 1872.
One son of Urn. Meredith Sanders, John Gerome, and a grandson,
James Franklin Sanders, became Baptist Ministers, lived on farms in
this community, and served as Pastors of Fellowship Church on differ-ent
occasions. Another son, Andrew Franklin, who married Martha
Lemmons, lived east of Sanders Cemetery. Their home still stands.
Isaac Sanders, Jr., born in 1807, married Sallie Mitchell. Their
two sons, William and Mortimer, were killed in the Civil War. Their
old home, owned by Oscar Mount, recently burned.
Asa Houston Sanders, born 1822, was the youngest son of Isaac
(b.l772) and Mary. He married Christine Clemmons and bought from J. H.
Charlton the acreage formerly granted to Robert Weakley, opposite the
mouth of Stewarts Creek along Stones River. He was a courageous and
prosperous farmer, recognized for his leadership in civic, political.
85
and church affairs. He served as guardian and executor for many, and
his name appears on legal documents of Rutherford, Wilson, and
Davidson counties, indicating his knowledge of law. Through his ten
children the names Goodwin, Mason, Bell, Edmondson, Malone, and Guill
were added to the Sanders Colony. Three sons, Isaac Franklin, who mar-ried
Tennessee Goodwin, Thos. H., who married Sallie Bell, and Isham
Harris, who married Lenora Sanders, moved to Nashville where they oper-ated
a feed and grain business. William L. married Sallie L. Sanders
and lived in the Fellowship community as a farmer and trader.
A daughter of Asa Houston Sanders, Frances Jane Sanders, married
Wm. Newton Mason, a judge of Rutherford County for 46 years. Another
daughter of Asa Houston Sanders, Josephine, married Thomas Pinkney
Edmondson, a teacher at Walnut Grove, Rockdale, and other schools.
Lafayette Mortimer (Fate) Sanders, youngest son of Asa Houston,
followed in his father's footsteps exercising civic, business, and
political leadership. After his father's death he bought the interest
of the heirs in the lands of Asa Houston Sanders and added other
adjoining acreage as it was sold through the years, making him one of
the largest landowner in the county.
Lafayette married Annie Ladocia Goodwin. Their children were
Andrew Hollis, C. Goodwin, and Christine. Goodwin died while a
student at Vanderbilt University. Hollis married Anne Baskette and
lived on and operated the farm he inherited from his parents.
Christine married Adam Johnson Poole, Jr., and they operated the
adjoining farm she had inherited, until the Federal Government
acquired the entire acreage for the Percy Priest Lake in 1966. This
86
is now the Fate Sanders Recreation Area. During World War II these
farms were used for "Food for Freedom" and Army maneuvers. In 1943,
U. S. Secretary of Agriculture, Claude R. Wichard, issued this family
a "Certificate of Farm War Service". In 1908, Fate Sanders was instru-mental
in getting the first bridge across Stones River which bore his
name, and was used until the Threet Bridge was completed across the
lake a few hundred yards upstream in 1967. The first telephone in
this community was a Nashville phone through LaVergne, Tenn., built by
Fate Sanders in 1907, and in later years electricity was brought into
this First District by a right-of-way given across his farm. He
bought the first automobile in that district in 1908 - a seven passen-ger
Overland.
In 1869, Dr. Benjamin Franklin Guill moved to this community
from Mt. Juliet. He married Sal lie A. Sanders, daughter of Asa
Houston, and bought the farm adjoining her father's, formerly owned by
Wm. Meredith Sanders, where he lived as a practicing physician until
his death in 1894. Dr. Guill served two years as an Infantryman in
the Civil War before he was transferred to Hospital duty in Richmond,
Va., June 1863, by Gen. Lee, where he was paroled out of service in
May 1865. Dr. Guill was a charter member of the Smyrna Medical
Society in 1876. He had two sons, Hugh Hayes and Clarence Gardner
Guill. Clarence moved to Union City, Tenn., after his father's death,
with his mother and her second husband. Dr. J. B. Adkerson. Hugh mar-ried
Cora Jones and they lived on the Guill farm many years before
moving to Smyrna where he was Postmaster. They later moved to Texas
on account of his health. Their one son, Benjamin Hugh, served with
87
the Army in the Pacific during W. W. II and was later elected to the
81st Congress as the first Republican from Texas in twenty-five years.
He nominated Richard M. Nixon for Vice-President in 1953. He served
as Executive Assistant to Postmaster General Arthur E. Summerfield
from 1953 to 1955 when he was appointed to the Federal Maritime Board
where he served until 1960. Ben Guill is now a lobbyist for the
National Automobile Dealers Association and lives in Washington with
his wife, the former Marjorie Buckler from Pampa, Texas, and two sons,
Hugh Buckler, serving with the U. S. Army in Vietnam, and Benjamin
Allen, a student at Princeton.
John Buchanan, later known as Major John of Buchanan Fort, with
his father, brothers, and two sisters, joined James Robertson and John
Donelson at Ft. Nashboro in 1780 even though tradition tells us the
Buchanans were at French Lick in 1779. Major John was a District Sur-veyor,
a courageous soldier, and contributed greatly to the transforma-tion
of the wilderness into a great state. Due to his services and
explorations he was in a position to secure most anything in the new
territory he desired; therefore, he became one of the largest land-owners
in this section. In 1789 John Buchanan was granted 640 acres
on the narrows of Stones River, Grant No. 1030, which later became
part of the First and Second Districts of Rutherford County. It was
here that he and his brother-in-law, Moses Ridley, built the first
Mill near the narrows of Stones River. In 1808 another Grant No. 655,
to John Buchanan and Moses Ridley, was for 274 acres on the East
border of the former 640 acres. In 1817 a Grant No. 14152 was to John
Buchanan for 127 acres East of the 274 acres grant, joining Elisha
88
Sanders near the Sanders Cemetery. It was in 1806 that John and Sarah
Ridley I'.uchanan's son, Moses Ridley Buchanan, was born. He married
Sarah Vincent Ridley, daughter of James and Anne Hamilton Ridley, in
1827 and inherited this land at his father's death in 1832. He built
the first lock and dam ever constructed in Tennessee and operated a
Mill at this site in connection with farming. Moses Ridley deeded his
half interest in the 274 acres to his nephew and namesake and moved to
the Smyrna dred where the Sam Davis Home, a State Shrine, is now
located. Moses Ridley Buchanan was one of the county's wealthiest and
most influential citizens, possessed with all the qualities which make
a man lovable. The liberality which he displayed all through his life
was something remarkable. To him a prominent, wealthy gentleman liv-ing
in Nashville, at that time, owed his start in business to a $3,000
loan from Mr. Buchanan. A violin, said to be 200 years old and the
first one brought into Tennessee, was owned and played by Moses R.
Buchanan. He loved music and dancing, and great was the hospitality
in the home he built in the early 1800' s for his wife, Sarah, and four-teen
children. A beautiful plot by the river, shaded by giant oaks,
was known as the "Buchanan Picnic Grounds" and many were the invita-tions
sent to neighbors and friends by carriers on horses "Requesting
the honor of your presence".
But when the Civil War came his slaves were freed, provisions
taken, land stripped, and cotton gin burned leaving him unable to oper-ate
a plantation. He sold his mill and farm, with the exception of
500 acres his daughter, Sarah Anne, lived on with her second husband,
John B. Goodwin. Her first husband, Thomas J. Mabry, Jr., died in
89
1855. These 500 acres were passed down four generations to Christine
Sanders Poole, who owned it at the time the Federal Government pur-chased
it for the Percy Priest Lake, which is now "Pooles Knob Recre-ation
Area".
S. H. Miller bought the Moses Ridley Buchanan property for his
heir, Elizabeth (Lizzie) Miller Jones, who with her husband, Amzi
Jones, took possession of the home and operated the mill for many
years - thus the origin of the name "Jones Mill Road" which at present
leads from the Nashvil le-Murfreesboro highway near LaVergne, north to
the old home standing on a hill overlooking the Percy Priest Lake at
the location of Youth Incorporated.
Moses Ridley Buchanan celebrated his 81st birthday in April 1887,
one month before his death at the home of his daughter, Nancy, and her
husband, Andrew B. Vaughn, with whom he had lived for the past several
years. On this occasion he played his violin for his many friends,
relatives, and great, great grand children.
In part this is the account of his death in "The Daily American"
May 30, 1887.
"At his home in Franklin yesterday mo'^ning surrounded by his
friends and relatives, Moses R. Buchanan, well-known to almost every
man, woman, and child in Middle Tennessee, passed away. Peacefully as
a child sinking to rest, and contented, his spirit took its flight
from the body which had been its home for more than four score vears,
to seek a deserved rest after a life which had been as useful as it
had been long. Perhaps no man in Tennessee had so extensive a connec-tion.
It has been a common saying that everybody was kin to Buchanan
or Buchanan's wife. He was greatly loved by all who came in contact
with him. His heart was as tender as a woman's to any aooeal for
symoathy, though brave as a lion when danger appeared. In the 1820's
Mr. Buchanan settled on a magnificent farm lying on Stones River in
Rutherford County where he built Buchanan's Mill, which is still stand-ing.
The deceased leaves eleven children, six daughters and five sons,
all living in the State. One of the daughters is the wife of County
90
Judge Caldwell. The remains will be brought here this morning on the
8 o'clock accommodation and be taken out to Mill Creek Cemetery on the
Murfreesboro Pike, where according to his request he will be laid by
the side of his wife. Dr. Strickland will conduct services at the
grave.
"
Other heirs who inherited lands in Rutherford County at the death
of their father. Major John Buchanan, were Nancy Mulherrin, 1169 acres,
who later married Jackson Smith, and Henry R., 1120 acres, who never
married.</dc:description>
<dc:description>A history of the Sanders family and related surnames in Rutherford County</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Family history; Genealogy; Rutherford County (Tenn.) -- History; Sanders, C. (Cornelis), 1921-;</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Fellowship; Smyrna</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>23 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-15</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication06ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/163</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>