<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Mt. Olivet and Hoover Gap Methodist churches</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Powell, Margaret</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 26</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1986</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>19th century; 20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>86
MT. OLIVET AND HOOVER GAP METHODIST CHURCHES
by
Mrs. Margaret Powell
Methodism swept into the Southeastern basin of
Tennessee like a tidal wave in late 1790 or 1800. There
were people anxiously awaiting this new religion that
assured anyone v/ith a place to worship and would have a
preacher sent by a district superintendent. People
worshipped in brush arbors, homes, and schoolhouses
.
This new form of church government was formulated by
John Wesley, "Father of Methodism." He refused to have
the movement called Weslyism. But since the system was
so Methodical, it soon became "Wesleys Methods or
Methodism." It was J. W. Cullum a preacher in 1871 v/ho
said, "Christianity was Methodism on Horseback," as so
many of the preachers or "circuit riders," as they were
called, had to ride horse back, because of the bad roads
or lack of roads. Some churches were almost inaccessible,
even then but if they were on their circuit the preacher
got there, rain, sleet, cold or whatever. Sometimes their
shoes would freeze in their saddle stirrups.
As early as 1812 church houses were being built in
Rutherford County. I don't have any record of when the
87
church at Big Spring was built, only a tiny dot on the
1878 map indicated the spot where the Methodist Episcopal
Church stood--I don't know when nor why it was moved to
Manchester Highway, with an access road to Big Spring road.
Presumably the Big Spring church burned, as so many
buildings did, leaving no records. The new church was
built majestically--"Big and Wide" high on a hill and
appropriately called Mt. Olivet.
Mt. Olivet was in Murfreesboro District and on
Hall Springs Circuit with the parsonage located at Noah,
on Manchester Highway between Beech Grove and Manchester.
Most circuits had at least 4 churches but the preacher
was available at all times for funerals and to preach
any place the people called for him.
While Rev. Cullum was occupying the parsonage, he
with some help built a brick cistern for their water
supply. The building required 3,400 bricks, 3H barrels
of cement and 2 barrels of lime and cost $44.87. It
was built about 1890. I don't know how long it was used.
I dimly remember our church donating money to have
water installed in the parsonage sometime in 1920.
I have often heard my grandfather tell of the huge
crowds and the big revival meetings that were held in
Mt. Olivet. Sometimes the meetings lasted all night with
preaching, singing, shouting, and people would go into
trances. The revivals were very emotional and congre-gations
expressed joy in their salvation, each in his own
way. After all they came to America to worship for
freedom; and worship they did.
I grew up in this church and thinking back can
remember the many things I enjoyed there. The card class
that "Miss'Mol ly" Baugh Pate taught. We had to memorize
our golden text, sit still and listen, holding our
pennies in our hot little hands. I remember the excite-ment
of the box supper, dreading and hoping some one nice
would get my box. The ice cream suppers v/ith cake walks
held as friendly get togethers and to augment finances.
The Christmas tree, huge in our eyes all a glitter
with tinsel in the candlelight and loaded with all sorts
of interesting looking packages while excited youngsters
hoped and waited with bated breath for the program to
be over and Santa would hand out the gifts.
Then in June "Children's Day" would be a big
event with all the Sunday School participating--boys
with scrubbed faces, hair sleeked down, in white shirts
and knee pants. The girls with curls, bows, ruffled
dresses and baby doll patent slippers would march, sing
and speak our pieces with outward calm and inward
89
quaking and oh what a relief it was when it all was over.
It was a pretty event--children for once all dressed up,
and on their best Sunday behavior, the church too was
all dressed up and decorated with flower arrangements.
There was a closeness in this group of people who worked
for common good. Many and varied were their talents and
each was willing to share and do what they could.
Visiting the sick and caring for the elderly was done as
a matter of fact. There were no florist shops to call
and have flowers sent to sick or shut-in. Home grown
flowers were used and since "Miss Annie" McKnight as
she was affectionately called had a "green thumb," lots
of flowers, and a knack of arranging them, she was
called on often to furnish flowers (in season) on all
occasions. There was always flowers on Sunday and extra
ones on special occasions. I've often wondered how
many flowers she had given to others, bouquets, and potted
plants for old, sick or shut-ins and on so many occasions
hearts that grieved were lightened by the wreaths of
"Miss Annie" flowers covering the cold clay on a loved
ones grave.
Quarterly conferences were held once a year in
each church. The delicious "basket dinners" were looked
forward to&#8212;a just reward we felt after a long sermon and
90
91
a lengthy business session. I remember a few times Uncle
Dave Macon would come and bring his banjo and entertain
after lunch under the big shade trees.
Singing Schools were often held in summer and well
attended. This picture of one group taught by George W.
Sebren was held in 1915. I have attempted with the help
of Mrs. Mary Price Snell and Mrs. Pearl Marlin Smith to
name them. I'm not 100% sure and apologize for any
mistakes we made. It v/as a long time ago and only a few
are still living.
Names on Pictures
1. Mary Epps
2. Margaret Powell
3. Mabel Fox
4. Pauline Allman
5. Sue McKee
6. Mr. G. W. Sebren, teacher
7. Smith Webb
8. Hall Webb
9. 0*Brien
10. 0. B. Hendricks
11. Pearl Marlin Smith
12. Aileen McKee Hatchett
13. Mrs. Allen
14. Irene Hoover
15. Mary Price Snell
16. Willie Mai O'Brien
17. Mary Lou Hendricks
18. Mrs. Annie Hoover
19. Mrs. Lillie White
20. Ida Hoover Williams--Rev. John Mark Williams' mother
21. Mrs. Margaret Webb
22. Mattye Ida Hoover O'Brien
23. Elizabeth White
92
24. Mrs. Corrine Hoover 43
25. Mrs. Annie McKnight 44
26. Hoover 45
27. Andrew Price 46
28. Lizzie Hayes Haynes 47
29. Luther Hayes 48,
30. Rose Smotherman 49
31. Mr. B. G. White 50
32. Virginia O'Brien 51,
33. Mr. Hendricks 52,
34. Mary Hoover 53,
35. Mr. Hoover 54,
36. Dr. Allen 55,
37. Mattie Lou Hoover 56,
38. Willie Hendricks 57,
39. Allie McKnight Hoover 58,
40. Mattye Hayes Maxwell 59,
41. Bettye Mai Allman 60,
42. Dovie Biggers 61,
Effie Davis
Willie O'Brien
Walter Price
Edward Hendricks
Kirk Webb
Elmer McKnight
Hugh O'Brien
Tommye Lee Haynes
Jimmy Cristman
Bob Lynch
Mr. Pheonix
Silas M. Hoover
Eugene Hoover
Murphy Haynes
Sam Insell
Johnny O'Brien
Mr. Stem
Jim Webb
Partial Membership
I don't have a record of all the members but some
that were on Sunday School report are given.
Mr. and Mrs. Tom Allman
Jim Broyles
Willis Drake
Marlin Hoover--Marvin
Le Grand Hoover--Irenej Nettye Lou
Joe Hoover--Travis , Ida Lee, Eunice
John Henry Hoover&#8212;Allice, Eve, Ada
Eugene Hoover
Harvey Hoover&#8212;Forney, Eugene, Palmer
Will Kelton
John McKnight--Kirby , Allie, Elmer, Margaret
W. J. Fox
W. J. Fox--Henry, Mabel, Evelyn
Chip Lee
Frank Mankin
S. F. Pheonix
Porter Carter&#8212;Arnold, Aubra
Ashton Pruitt
Robert Bugg&#8212;Hubert
93
Some of the Sunday School Superintendents
Eugene Hoover Silas Hoover
Kirby McKnight Margaret McKnight
Teachers
Miss Mattye Baugh Pate D. F. Tribble
Andrew Todd Marvin Hoover
Allie McKnight Mrs. Will Maude Kelton
Mrs. Corrine Hoover
Organist and Song Leader
Mrs. Marvin (Allie) Hoover, organist
Silas Hoover, song leader
Membership fluctuated as people moved in and out
but in the main Mt . Olivet maintained a good congregation
until one cool windy day in March sparks from the big
old stove hit on the soft shingles and soon the roof was
ablaze with no hope of extinguishing the blaze. With
no ladder going up in the attic and one fire extinguisher,
it was useless. The high wind kept the fire swept up
and toward the back and we, working madly, were able to
save most of the hand made pews, organ, pulpit, song
books, and pulpit chairs which were stores for future use.
We were a desolate group as we stood and watched our loved
church tumble down. The next thing on the agenda was
what to do. Cedar Grove Methodist invited us to their
94
church as did Hoover's Gap Protestant Church so each
family went to the church nearest them and our once
strong church was weakened by division.
The two separate congregations at Hoover's Gap were united
as one when the three Methodisms were unified as one also. Upon
reconstruction of the highway in 1936 this building was
razed and the present one erected. In June of 1936 the
congregation moved into the new building using pews,
organ, etc., saved from Mt. Olivet. They reorganized
and became known as Hoover's Gap Methodist Church having
sixty-one members. This church contributed two men to
the Methodist ministry--Rev. Leo Parker, now in Texas
his wife's home state, and Rev. Harry Agee who will be
installed at Hohenwald, Tennessee this year. Both have done
well in their ministry.
After we had settled in^ we decided to add some
Sunday School rooms and asked conference for help, which
was denied. However, we built them and carried on the
best we could, losing our young people to distant jobs.
We were moved from Bell Springs circuit to Cedar Grove,
without our consent. We disagreed with the district
superintendent on several occasions and for several
reasons. Just before Christmas 1960, we received a
letter from District Superintendent telling us that when
conference had met in June our church was declared
95
"Abandoned" and that he was sending our letters of
membership to the church he deemed nearest us. That
didn't qo too well and so v/e decided to remain as we
were using lay speakers until we could do better. Some
of our speakers were Ralph Sutton, Tommy Carter, Terry
Spence, Bro. Baker, Eslene Macon, Virgil England, and
0. C. Robinson. In fact Terry Spence and Virgil England
served as regular minister for a time until in 1978 we
persuaded 0. C. Robinson to be our preacher. He has
been with us ever since, and his wife has taught a
class, led in singing and helped in every way. We are
a small hard working group seemingly not making big
waves, but still keeping the church door open. We're
known as Hoover's Gap Interdenominational Church and
welcome all and sundry to worship with us. We have
Sunday School and preaching every Sunday.
This is a list of ministers as nearly as I can
compile it after the church was moved from Big Spring to
the Highway.
John R. Reagin, Oct. 1887-1888
R. E. Alford, 1888-1889
J. W. Cullum, 1889-1890
John R. Thompson, 1890-1891
O. P. Hill, 1891-1895
G. W. Blanton, 1895-1896
S. M. Keathley, 1896-1897
M. P. Wood, 1897-1898
J. W. Cullum, 1898-1900
G. W
B. T
E. E
G. B
S. D
J. K
0. H
J. T
R. H
M. B
John
E. M
A. L
96
Nackles, 1900-1901
Smotherman, 1901-1903
Varner, 1903-1904
McPeak, 1904-1905
Plant, 1905-1906
Lee, 1906-1910
Lane, 1910-1914
Parsons, 1914-1916
Skelton, 1916-1920
Williams, 1920-1922
C. Crigqer, 1922-1923
Harrell, 1923-1926
Hodge, 1926-1931, District Superintendent
Irvin McDonough, 1931-1932
N. O. Allen, 1932-1935
R. C. Moore, 1935-1939&#8212;Havvkins
G. Thomas Reed, 1939-1940&#8212;Cook
Hugh Parsons, 1940-1942
W. L. Burden, 1942-1945
0. N. Jones, 1946-1947
Virgil Tipps, 1947-1950
Allen Brown, 1951-1953
Ralph Koolmay, 1954-1955
Bobby Davis, 1955-1956
Carl Felkner, 1957-1958
Howard Haynes, 1959-1960
Carl Cantrell, 1960-1961
James McGlothin, 1965-1966
Kenneth Miles, 1966-1967
Harold Edwards, 1967-1968
Wayne Caldwell, 1968-1969
Donald Erickson, 1970-1971
Virgil England, 1972-1975
Terry Spence, 1978-1979
0. C. Robinson, 1978-1984
I'd like to close with J. W. Cullum's favorite little
This is a difficult world indeed
And the people are hard to suit.
The man that plays the violin
Is a bore to the man with the flute.
And I myself have often thought
How much better it would be.
97
If everyone I knew would only agree, v/ith me.
But since they v/ill not the very best way
To make this world look bright.
As never to mind what people say
But do what you think is right.
?t
J.W. Cullum
98
99
^ jQ
(J J3
oa OS
^ &#8212; &gt; =5
CO &gt; l/l E
&#8226; O +-&gt; nD
s: o c &#8212;
&#8226;
ic a; &#8212;
'
&#8226; s_ &#8212;
&lt;
&gt; (13 n3 &#8212;
H
Qi I&#8212;.-^^
iOO
Mrs. Mattye Baugh Pate Silas M. Hoover
Martin Hoover
Luke Rawling standing</dc:description>
<dc:description>A history of two Methodist churches in Murfreesboro, including a list of pastors and several images</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>churches; Methodism</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Hoover; Murfreesboro</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-01</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication26ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/153</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>