<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>East Main Church of Christ local history</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Roberts, Carol</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 22</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1984</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>19th century; 20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>EAST MAIN CHURCH OF CHRIST
LOCAL HISTORY
DECEMBER 12, 1983
CAROL ROBERTS
East Main Church of Christ has for many years been an active group
in the Murfreesboro community. The congregation has been helpful in
establishing other congregations in the area. The East Main congre-gation
was one of the original groups developing out of the Restoration
Movement of the early 1800 's. The Movement was an effort to bring
Christians back to a closer relationship with New Testament teachings.
Using no creeds but the Bible, this simplified form of worship first
developed on a large scale in Kentucky. Barton W. Stone was one of the
first preachers to emphasize only the New Testament teachings rather
that specific laws of the Presbyterian church. Because of this he
was censored like many other preachers of the time. As a result Stone
was one of the first Restoration preachers to come into Tennessee from
Kentucky.
The earliest Christian Church in Rutherford County was on the
banks of Overall's Creek near the Beesley Primative Baptist Church.^
Alfred Blackman, a prominent elder of East Main Christian Church during
the 1860's, and his wife worshipped with this congregation after being
baptized by Barton W. Stone in the fall of 1812.^ This shows that the
Restoration Movement came to Rutherford County sooner that originally
thought. Some thought that the Church originated with Alexander
Campbell's work in Middle Tennessee, but by the time Campbell came to
52
Tennessee the Rutherford County congregations were well established.
The congregation worshiping at Overall's Creek merged with a group
worshiping in Murfreesboro. This congregation began worshiping to-gether
sometime in April of 1832.
One of the earliest preachers in Rutherford County was Fred E.
Becton, Jr. He carried on correspondence with Walter Scott, the editor
of The Evengelist . a journal devoted to discussion of Restoration
activities. Two letters in particular explain the earliest beginnings
of the congregation. The letter of May 5, 1832 says, "We were opposed
by the Presbyterians with a sacramental occasion; the Methodists locked
us out of their building after having first given us permission to
5 occupy it." A letter of April 30, 1832 explains where they worshipped.
"The sheriff of this county. Col. Crockett, kindly offered to us the
spacious room of the courthouse." The congregation also met at King
College, when the college was located at the present site of Middle
Tennessee Electric Company. By August of 1832 the congregation had
doubled in membership from eleven to twenty-one worshipping in the
Q
courthouse.
The congregation wanted a permanent place of worship so they began
looking for another meeting place. In the early months of 1833 a lot
numbered 59 was purchased in Murfreesboro by Fred Becton for fifty
9
dollars. The land was deeded to the elders of the congregation,
Peyton Smith, George Morris, William Smith, and others. The building
was on the west side of the West Main Street Bridge on the banks of Lytle
Creek. Meetings or week-long revivals were held in larger halls
usually in surrounding schools such as King College and Union University. ^^
53
Prior to the Civil War feelings were strong for or against slavery.
Another preacher during the early 1830's was Tolbert Fanning, a young
man 22 years old. Fanning was strongly opposed to slavery. At that
time slaves and slave owners worshipped together at the Christian
Church. The slaves usually sat in the back of the building and some
12
of the household slaves sat with the families. One week a prominent
member of the Church sold a slave, and member of the church, at public
auction; the slave was sold, taken to Mississippi, and never heard from
again. The sale of the slave angered Fanning to the point that his
next sermon was a condemation of the slave owner for selling his
13
brother away from his family.
Fanning 's sermon caused enough conflict in the group that the elders
fired Fanning, and the slave owner had him arrested for inciting slaves
to revolt. Charles Ready, a prominent lawyer of Rutherford County,
14
volunteered his services to Fanning, and won the case for Fanning.
However Fanning was not rehired by the congregation, and never preached
in the area again. Yet he went on to become a very famous Restoration
preacher in the Nashville area, and also was the State Secretary of
15
Acriculture for several years.
In 1860 plans were made to develop a new building. To begin they
bought the house and lot on the corner of East Main and South Academy
from Mr. Robert McLane and Mr. W. W. Ross for $1800.00.^^ The trustees
of the property were the elders at the time, among them Alfred Blackman,
one of the earlier church members in the county. Mr. Blackman paid
the majority of the cost of the land. In the August 1860 Millennial
Harbinger Alexander Campbell made mention of a handsome brick meeting
54
house in Murfreesboro that was 78 feet long and 45 feet wide, a build-ing
built in "good taste and speaks well of the Brotherhood." The
congregation did not use the building on East Main for very long be-fore
the Civil War came to Murfreesboro, and the church would be very
involved. During the battle of Murfreesboro and afterward the building
was used as a Confederate hospital as were other building along East
18
Main, thus causing services to occasionally be interrupted.
The Civil War is the base for various memories for members of
East Main. The most common memory was that among several Federal troops
worshipping with the congregation, James A. Garfield attended services
quite regularly, and often participated in them. Garfield tended to
sit near the front during services. As a little girl Mrs. Ben Johnson
remembered that anytime he spoke or led the singing, he left his gun and
sword on the pew. The girls were fascinated by the weapons and would
peek over the back of the pew at the sword and gun as if there was a
19
magical spell on them. Also the girls' parents always warned the
children to be friendly, but not to be too friendly because he was a
Yankee. After all, the Yankees were responsible for the mess and problems
around Murfreesboro.
As a result of Garfield making acquaintances with the congregation
20
members, he sent the church a communion set as a gift of appreciation.
This set consisted of a silver decanter and four silver goblets, and
was for several years a point of disagreement. Some members appreciated
the gift, some felt that it was very inappropriate to accept a gift from
a Yankee who had helped govern their city. Thus strong disagreement
continued for several years. So rather than disagree over a gift from
21
a Yankee, the set was given to a congregation in Christiana. The
55
set has passed on through several congregations then to Mr. A. N.
Miller. Mr. Miller then sold the set to Dr. George DeHoff in 1954.^^
As a result of several transfers, the set now consists of the decanter
and two goblets.
Before the Civil War there were not enough preachers to fill all
the jobs, so many congregations had to share preachers, but as the
churches grew there were more men becoming preachers. After the Civil
War the East Main congregation grew so much that it felt it could
afford to hire a full-time minister. It also tended to be on better
financial terms so in 1866 the Christian Church paid $2,000.00 to Alfred
23
Blackman for full title to the deed of the Property. According to
wills filed by Blackman, he planned to will the property to the church,
but the church felt it was obligated to Mr. Blackman to repay the debt
rather than leaving it unpaid. Blackman' s executor was his son-in-law,
24
William B. Lillard, who was also an elder at the Christian Church.
In 1900 the congregation felt the need for a larger building, for
which it would need more land. The elders were able to buy from Mr.
and Mrs. T. B. Fowler a 10 foot section on the west side of the build-ing.^^
The old building came down and a new more modern building was
built in its place. The new building was very attractive and had Roman-
?fi
esques Revival characteristics popular in the late 1880's and '90's.
The displayed characteristics were semicircular windows and door openings,
brick corbeling around windows, elaborate barge board designs in the
brick along the gables of the building, finials on each gable, and a
bell tower with unique corbeled chimney stacks. Some of these chara-cteristics
can be seen on the building today.
The new building had impressive stained glass windows on each
56
side of the building. Each of the stained glass windows represent a
Bible event; for example, the sheaves of grain represent the story of
Ruth, and the lillies represent the Resurrection. Each window is
different, no two are alike with the exception of the colors used,
those colors being rose, yellow, blue and shades of green.
The building itself was built in a rectangular shape, and was
made of bricks fired in the county. The main entrance of the building
was below the bell tower on the east corner. Its design was solid up
to the roof line, then it changed into four corbeled chimney style
stacks to create the bell tower.
On the interior of the building, the podium and pulpit were on the
south end facing towards East Main Street. There is evidence that the
floors were flat with pews running east-west and facing south.
This building well served the purpose of worship of the Christian
Church for 20 years. In the early 1920's several things led to necessary
changes. The main reason being that the congregation wanted to add a
baptistry to the building. For some reason the baptistry would not fit
on the south end where the original podium was, so plans were made to
add it onto the west side of the building. There seems to be no dis-agreement
over the new placement of the baptistry.
Renovation plans started in 1920 by purchasing the Fowler house
and property on the west side of the building from the Fowler relatives
28
for $10,000.00. On the new property a wing of approximately 15 feet
in width and the same length as the original building was built. The
exterior was built in brick to match the original brick. The addition
changed the roof line, and the bell tower was removed to make the
entrance area flush with the main wall. In the new wing another
57
entrance was built giving two entrances on East Main Street, making the
facade look balanced on each corner.
On the interior the stained glass windows were removed from the
original west wall and built into the new exterior west wall. The open-ings
left by the windows were made into doors into the new wing. In
the center of the new wing a baptistry was built. The baptistry had
a movable rear wall for seating in sight of the pulpit for overflow
crowds. The west wing has often been used for overflow crowds simply
by opening the doors and raising the rear wall of the baptistry. As
a result of the change in the baptistry and extra seating space, the
pews were rearranged in a semi-circle to face west with the pulpit
being in the front of the baptistry. Thus the changes were basically
necessary for the growth of the congregation rather than building another
building so soon after the original building was built. With growth
came the need for easy access to a place for baptism.
The building has changed very little since the remodeling of the
'20's. Additions have been made behind the church for an educational
wing. This additional was made in 1958. The house bought from the
Fowler's in 1920 was made into a home for the minister and his family.
Minor changes were made in 1950's in the matter of electric lights and
the additional of air conditioning.
The electric lights were simple light bulbs hung from the ceiling.
on
They were part of the building in 1900. In 1951 the preacher, Dr.
George DeHoff, had visited Germany. He bought back pictures of German
churches, and in the pictures were ideas for new light fixtures. Mc-
Fadden's of St. Louis took the pictures and made light fixtures for the
30
auditorium. These lights have added to the character of the building,
and remain as part of the building to the present.
58
It was also during the 1950 's that East Main became the second
31
church in Murfreesboro to install air conditioning. Dr. DeHoff re-members
that where other changes and renovations did not cause conflicts,
the air conditioning caused some real problems. Many members told DeHoff,
"Why it's the Lord's weather and we shouldn't do anything to mess with
such things." To which DeHoff replied, "What about the heating system
32
in the winter?" "Oh well, that's different," they said. Thus air
conditioning was soon added and made the 1900 building a new and up-to-date
building.
The building has changed very little in appearance since 1920's.
It still can be recognized by the pictures from the early 1900' s. Yet
the building has taken on new characteristics as each new generation
worships together there. Many famous preachers have worked with the
East Main congregation, as well as famous visiting preachers. Alexander
Campbell was a guest speaker on several occasions during the 1830' s.
He admonished the group for not meeting every Sunday. The preacher of
the time was concerned with this problem simply because they did not have
33
a meeting place in which to worship. Other famous preachers during
the early years were David Lipscomb, J.W. Mc Garvey, T.B. Larimore, and
J. Petty Ezell. These men preached throughout Middle Tennessee, establish-ing
many other congregations as well as helping strong congregations
-54
such as East Main."
David Lipscomb, who came down from Nashville to conduct meetings,
came quite ofter despite the fact that he was a close friend of Tolbert
Fanning, a former preacher of the Christian Church. J.W. McGarvey once
considered the East Main congregation as one of the strongest groups in
35
the Middle Tennessee area. T. B. Larimore was a very powerful preacher
59
of the early 1900' s whc stressed strict Biblical direction to the
congregation, J. Petty Ezell will always be remembered for his
remarks in a sermon not long before his death. "The Bible is the book
I lived by, loved and preached by, and am ready to die by." Mr. Ezell
died in a bus accident returning to Murfreesboro from Crossvile, Tennessee,
where he had baptized a friend.
The history of East Main has not always been pleasant. Besides
being locked out of meeting places in the 1830's, there were problems
in the very early 1900' s. These problems were the same type of those
throughout the congregations of Christian Churches in the South. The
most prominent problem concerned centralized authority over local con-
07
gregations. Some congregations wanted to work through a centralized
missionary society, while others wanted to support missionaries by indiv-idual
congregations. This is when the congregation at East Main and
Academy assumed the name of East Main Church of Christ rather than
Murfreesboro Christian Church.
According to several different preachers' correspondence, East Main
has a strong influence on society in Murfreesboro, with prominent citi-zens
as faithful members of the congregation. Such compliments were
given to the congregation by preachers such as Barton W. Stone, Alexander
Campbell, Fred Becton, J. W. McGarvey, B.D. Goodpasture, and George DeHoff.
Many of these men had the opportunity to compare East Main with other
congregations where they had previously worked or held meetings.
The congregation has always been willing to help other congregations
become established in other neighborhoods. In 1929 it helped the Westvue
church of Christ build a building, and approximately 50 members from
East Main began worshipping there. In 1939 East Main built a building
60
on State Street, at that time segregating the congregations in Murfreesboro.
Then in 1947 East Main helped North Boulevard church build a building on
38
Tennessee Boulevard. It has become a sort of tradition that whenever
East Main becomes overcrowded it helps local neighborhoods that do not
have a congregation to establish a new congregation. It seems to be
more effective than building a new building every few years at East
Main and South Academy.
The church has always had its main goal of letting God's work show
in their lives as a result of their actions. The congregation functions
in many ways to help the community, from teaching the Bible, to quilting
quilts for those who might need them. They also help in the local nurs-ing
homes and have study classes for men who would like to be better
39
preachers and teachers of the Bible.
The East Main congregation has also helped in foreign lands such
40
as Poland and Ghana helping to feed the hungry of those lands. They
hope always to continue these programs of the church as best possible
for the benefit of those less fortunate.
East Main has had a long and full history. The change in properties,
evolution of the building, and stories of many members all lead to an
interesting study. The congregation has always put special effort into
helping the community of Murfreesboro, and it strives to follow the New
Testament as it did when it was established in the early part of the
1830' s in the Restoration Movement. The East Main church is also very
proud of its distinguished history in the Murfreesboro community.
61
East Main Church of Christ from 1920 's to the present
62
&#171;i&#187;ws&#187;&#171;"&#8212;
"
' ii'iimig^ ff^^* _^
East Main Christian Church Circa 1910
photo furnished by Mrs. Homer Harris
63
ENDNOTES
1
B.W. Stone and John Rogers, The Biography of Barton Warren Sto ne.
(Cincinnati: J. A. and M.P. James, 184/j p. 67.
2
History of Beesley Primative Baptist Church, "(Murfreesboro,
Tennessee.
)
3
William Lipscomb, "Death Notice," Gospel Advocate , (July, 1872).
4
Walter Scott, "Correspondence," The Evangelist, (August, 1832),
p. 189.
^Scott, (May, 1832) p. 142.
^Scott, (April, 1832) p. 140.
Interview with George W. DeHoff, DeHoff Enterprises, Murfreesboro,
Tennessee, 22 November 1983.
^Scott, (August, 1832) p. 189.
9
Maury, Williamson, Rutherford, Wilson, Bedford, and Marshall
Counties of Tennessee , (Nashville: Goodspeed Publishing Company, 1887)
p. 837.
1
1
Alexander Campbell, Millenn ial Garbinger, Louisville: (March, 1855)
,
p. 145.
^ ^DeHoff.
^^Ibid.
14
Bill Lewis, "Church's History Reflects Serious and Lighter Moments,
Murfreesboro: Daily News Journal , Murfreesboro, (May 29, 1983), p. 8.
^ ^DeHoff.
1 fi
Rutherford County Deeds, Deed for East Main Christian Church,
November 5, 1860, Book 11, p. 476.
^^Campbell, (August, 1860), p. 478.
^^Goodspeed, p. 837.
19
'^DeHoff.
20
^Lewis, p. 8.
21
^'DeHoff.
64
23
Rutherford County Deeds, Deed for transfer of title from Alfred
Blackman to the Chirstlan Church, 5 December 1866, Book 14, p. 388.
24
Esquire Alfred Blackman, "Last Will and Testament", 25 November 1870,
25
Rutherford County Deeds, Deed for transfer of land from Sally J.
Fowler to the Christian Church, 4 May 1901, Book 1,p. 421.
John J. C. Blumenson, Identifying American Architecture , (Nashville-
American Association for State and Local History, 1982), p. 43.
^''oeHoff.
28
Rutherford County Deeds, Deed for transfer of title from Mr. &amp; Mrs.
George Cranor to East Main Church of Christ, 20 October 1920, Book 64
p. 255.
29
Sanborn Map Company, Murfreesboro Tennessee June, 1907, p. 13.
30
^*^DeHoff.
^^Lewis, p. 8.
32
"'^DeHoff.
33
Campbell, (February 1833), p. 90.
34
Robert Hooper, A Call to Remember, (Nashville: Gospel Advocate,
1977) p. 6-7.
^^DeHoff.
3fi
Russ Shelley, "Ministers' Children Recall Memories", Daily News
Journal, Murfreesboro: (29 May 1983), p. 9.
37
Robert Hooper, Crying in the Wilderness , Biography of David
Lipscomb , Nashville: David Lipscomb College, 1979, p. 85.
38
"East Main As a Landmark", Daily News Journal, Murfreesoboro:
(April 1952).
39
Russ Shelley, "East Main Ministers With MANY Programs," Daily
News Journal : Murfreesboro (29 May 1983) p. 7.
Ibid.
65
BIBLIOGRAPHY
Blackman, Esquire Alfred. "Last Will and Testament." 25 November 1870.
Blumenson, John, J.G. Identifying American Architecture . Nashville:
American Association for State and Local History, 1982.
Campbell, Alexander, ed. Millennial Harbinger . (February 1833).
Campbell, Alexander, ed. Millennial Harbinger . (March 1855).
Campbell, Alexander, ed. Millennial Harbinger . (August 1860).
DeHoff, George W. DeHoff Enterprises. Murfreesboro, Tennessee, Interview,
22 November 1983.
"East Main As A Landmark." Daily News Journal . Murfreesoboro:April 1952.
Henderson, C.C. The Story of Murfreesboro. Murfreesboro: Murfreesboro
News Banner, 19^9.
"History of Beesley Primative Baptist Church." Murfreesboro Tennessee.
Hooper, Robert E. A Call to Remember. Nashville: Gospel Advocate, 1977.
Hooper, Robert E. Crying in the Wilderness, Biography of David Lipscomb .
Nashville: David Lipscomb College, 1979.
Lewis, Bill. "Church's History Reflects Serious and Lighter Moments."
Daily News Journal . Murfreesboro: 29 May 1983.
Lipscomb, William, ed. "Death Notice." Gospel Advocate. Nashville: July
1872.
Maury, Williamson, Rutherford, Wilson, Bedford, and Marshall Counties
of Tennessee. Nashville: Goodspeed Publishing Company, 1887.
Rutherford County Deeds. Deed for East Main Chirstian Church. November
5, 1860. Book 11.
Rutherford County Deeds. Deeds for transfer of land from Sally J.
Fowler to the Christian Church. May 4 1901. Book 41.
Rutherford County Deeds, Deed for transfer of title from Alfred Blackman
to the Christian Church. December 5 1866. Book 14.
Sanborn Map Company. Murfreesboro, Tennessee. June 1907.
Scott, Walter, ed. The Evangelist.
66
Shelley, Russ. "East Main Ministers With Many Programs." Daily News
Journal . Murfreesboro: 29 May 1983.
Shelley, Russ, "Ministers' Children Recall Memories." Daily News
Journal . Murfreesboro: 29 May 1983.
Stone, B.W. and Robers, John. The Biography of Barton W. Stone .
Cincinnati: J. A. and M.P. James, 1847.
67
SOURCES USED FOR ADDITIONAL STUDY BUT NOT CITED
Atkisson, Ed. Architecture and Significant Structures in Murfreesboro
Between Court Square and Academy on Main Street . Tennessee
Architecture: March 1983.
Sims, Carlton, ed. A History of Rutherford County . Carlton Sims: 1947.
Murfreesboro Newspapers: Central Monitor and Daily Rebel Banner
68</dc:description>
<dc:description>A history of the contributions of the East Main Church of Christ to the Murfreesboro community</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>churches, Church of Christ</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>17 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-02</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication22ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/161</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>