<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Central Christian Church early history</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Miller, Clarice</dc:creator>
<dc:contributor>Woodfin, Virginia Black; Riggs, Kathrin Kerr</dc:contributor>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 27</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1986</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>19th century; 20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>CENTRAL CHRISTIAN CHURCH
EARLY HISTORY
Compiled by
Virainia Black Woodfin, Kathrin Kerr Riggs
and Clarice Miller
Written by
Clarice Miller
Virginia Woodfin Clarice Miller
Compilers of the
History of Central Christain Church
Kathrin Riggs
It
What a calamity it might have been! The church with
the dome at the corner of East Main Street and Maney Avenue,
as it is often identified, was found to be structurally
weakened in early January 1986. It was in imminent danger
of collapsing, dome and all, under the stress of wind,
storm, fire, weight, and age. In this year of 1986 it will
be seventy-four years old.
The arrival of the Reverend James Blair, as new
minister to this congregation, the first of January 1986 was
followed almost immediately by the alarming discovery of the
danger. The energetic, dedicated minister set about closing
the church building. Meetings were held first at Woodfin's
Chapel, then in the Educational Building located on the
church property. Work was begun on the repairs to the
damage. After the structural wooden trusses and frame work
(the ribs) of the dome were thought to be sufficiently safe,
the congregational meetings were held in the basement of
the church, or Fellowship Hall, as it is called.
Using these smaller quarters brought the members into
a more informal service. A spirit of "togetherness"
prevailed along with a concerted effort to help with the
repair work in the sanctuary, where more water damage had
been discovered.
It was in Fellowship Hall on March 16, 1986 that
installation services were held for the Reverend Blair, his
Church must meet elsewhere
after building found unsound
By JOHN HOWZE
Newt Journal Staff Writer
A local church congregation will
hold services at the Woodfin Funeral
Chapel on Tennessee Boulevard for
the coming two weeks after it was
discovered its building is structurally
unsound.
"We had a man go up into the attic
to change a light bulb, and he saw the
rafters were twisted and said some-thing
wasn't right," said Rev. Jim
Blair, who heads the Central Chris-tian
Church at 404 E. Main St.
"One of the main rafters was three
feet out of line, and the two next to it
were each out of hne by a foot," Blair
said.
The church called John A. Hughes
and Associates, a Nashville
engineering firm, which examined
the building and declared it unsafe to
hold services.
In addition to twisted rafters, the
company found many rafters and
side beams which had split open as
the warped rafters placed undue
stress on them.
'They told us the church could
literally fall down," said Blair,
"especially during the service when
we have that loud organ music."
With 300 members. Central Chris-tian
needed a meeting place and
Woodfin Chapel was suggested. The
funeral parlor agreed to host the
Sunday morning service for the
coming two weeks.
ONJ pKoto by Jim Dovit
CLOSED FOR REPAIRS &#8212; The Rev. Jim Blair of Central Christian
Church holds a sign he will ploce on the church's door telling members
that services w/lll be held at Woodfin Funeral Chapel until warped
ceiling beams are repaired.
Repair Work Underway
fr f r r r Ti^-
wife, Joyce and daughter, Shirley. The congregation, family
and friends of the Blairs were well aware of the awesome
spectacle in the sanctuary above them; gloomy, dusty,
plastic covered pews and organ pipes, a jungle of
scaffolding and boarded up stained glass windows all under a
cloud of grey plaster dust. The beautiful pre-Easter
installation service was touching and inspirational as if
the above sanctuary were new and gleaming as the day it was
finished in 1912, and the day of dedication at the meeting
of the Tennessee Convention of Christian Churches the
following September 20-24, 1913.
CHRISTIAN STANDARD
"October 11, 1913, Tennessee Convention"
The annual convention of the Tennessee disciples
was held in Murf reesboro, September 20-24.
The convention proper was preceded by the very
successful dedication of the charming new $30,000
house of the Murf reesboro brethen. With the aid of
the master dedicator, George L. Snively, the house,
which had been used since the preceding December,
was formally set apart to the work of the Lord,
freed of debt through the cash and pledges secured
before and on the day of dedication. Moreover,
enough more was raised to provide for organ and
possibly the purchase of a parsonage. In short, the
Murfreesboro brethren demonstrated a firm belief in
the success of the cause in their beautiful city.
With such preparation the brethren of Murfreesboro
and their many friends proceeded to make all visitors
doubly welcome. Their every provision for conveni-ence
could not but be appreciated by all the
visitors. . . .
In the afternoon and evening of Monday the Christian
Woman's Board of Missions auxiliaries held their
sessions. Some excellent reports were made and the
officers re-elected. The best feature of their
program was the inspiring address of H. J. Derthick,
recently of Livingston, Tenn. and now of Indianapolis,
Ind. He set forth clearly and sympathetically the
great work that is being done among the people of
Livingston by the aid the C.W.B.M. has given them in
their earnest search for education. He showed that
these people merely need help; that they are ready
and anxious to do their part. The women have a
habit of setting forth a live worker to report their
work first-hand. . . .
The Board of Trade of Murf reesboro showed the
visitors their joy in the convention and in their
city by means of an auto trip in all points of
interest about the city.
The music of the convention was under the direction
of H. C. Boblitt, of Cincinnati, O. and was responsible
for much of the enthusiasm of the sessions.
Showing as it did a genuine interest in the cause
of New Testament evangelism, the Tennessee Convention
has been surpassed by none in its repor^ of work done
and its prospect for future attainment.
Again in another church related newspaper the
following account is given:
' THE CHRISTIAN-EVANGELIST
October 23, 1913
Tennessee State Work
Jas . T. McKissick, Cor. Sec'y.
We have just closed a great year's work in
Tennessee, as the following report shows: Places
aided, 120; days worked, 4,870; sermons, 3,640;
baptisms, 994; otherwise, 786; total, 1,780; new
churches, 15; Bible schools, 13; amount raised,
$11,832.09, as against $10,009.37 last year.
Several new houses have been dedicated: Union
City, Murf reesboro. Knob Creek, Lutts, Elkanah and
Well Sprinq have about completed their houses of
worship.
To the current members of Central Christian Church
who feel it is their church home, and especially the three
remaining life members who were, although at an early age,
present at the dedication in 1913, namely Virginia Black
Woodfin, Kathrin Kerr Riggs and Clarice Miller, this
appalling event instigated a series of memories and
questions. How and why did this organization of the
church, the purchasing of the property and the construction
of the building with the dome, come about?
Dr. Herman Norton, dean of the Disciples Divinity
House at Vanderbilt University and professor of American
Christianity in the Divinity School, in his book Tennessee
Christians , tells the history of the Christian Church
(Disciples of Christ) in Tennessee, which was a pivotal
state in the origin, development of the movement, and
finally the merger of the religious forces led by Barton
Stone and Alexander Campbell. Much controversy and related
events finally cleared the way for a new religious group,
the Churches of Christ. Later, the two groups go their
separate ways as the author documents the resulting
development of the Christian Church, following the teachings
of Barton Stone.
On February 11, 1889, the Missionary Society was
organized at Woodland Street Christian Church in
Nashville. . . . The organization was the culmination
of sentiments set in motion by a few new members
sympathetic to missionary societies. . . . The
women of Woodland Street asked the elders to take
charge of the missionary program. . . .
The group that met in Chattanooga, October 6-8,
1890, constituted themselves as the "state Missionary
Convention of the Christian Church of Tennessee."
An historical sketch in the Christian Church
directory when Reverend Roy Hulan was pastor dated 1972:
Central Christian Church, Murf reesboro, Tennessee,
is one of some five thousand congregations which make
up the Christian Church (Disciples of Christ) com-munion
numbering in the neighborhood of 2,000,000
members, and a part of a movement begun in the early
1800 's which is today the largest body of church people
indigenous to the American soil. Men like Alexander
Campbell, Barton W. Stone, Walter Scott and John
Smith are looked to as the early leaders. The Churches
of Christ and the Christian Churches (independent) are
two large bodies of church people with the same
heritage
.
Alexander Campbell preached in the Methodist Church
in Murf reesboro in 1833. About a dozen citizens were
so impressed by his message on church unity and
restoration of New Testament practices in the church
that they organized the Murfreesboro Christian Church,
purchasing property near Lytle Creek. The congrega-tion
grew, and in 1858 located on the corner of
East; Main and Academy Streets. During the Civil War
Federal forces occupied Murfreesboro and Col. James A.
Garfield, later president, was placed in charge of
the troops. He was an ardent^member of the Christian
Church and sometime preacher.
Several congregations in Tennessee began supporting
the work of the Missionary Society, as they became interested
and the movement continued to grow.
Following the Civil War the movement grew, but
soon differences of emphasis and interpretations
began to divide the members. By 1906 an official
break came about. The Churches of Christ became a
separate movement emphasizing immersion as the only
form of baptism acceptable, denying the validity of
organizations such as missionary societies as being
unscriptural , and decrying the use of musical instru-ments
as aids to worship. The independent Christian
Churches are also adamant about missionary organiza-tions
and immersion, but do use the musical instru-ments
in church worship. These three would probably
number a total of some 5,000,000 adherents, all a
part of the Campbell Stone heritage.
The year 1907 witnessed some notable attainments.
Contributions from congregations for state missions
reached the astounding figure of $17,528. For all
missionary enterprises, the churches gave $24,303.
The Permanent Fund was at $16,179.
To make the separation even more distinct and clear
cut, the State Convention which met at Vine Street
October 7-9 (1907), voted to change the name of the
organization from the Tennessee Christian Missionary
Convention to the Tennessee Christian Missionary
Society. . . .
Before the delegates left Nashville, they learned
that the 500 member congregation at Johnson City had
just dedicated the "best church building in the state."
In it was a new $2,500 pipe organ, and Andrew Carnegie
had given $1,000 towards its purchase.
The 1908 Convention which met in Chattanooga,
October 26-29, received reports that the recommenda-tions
of the previous year had been carried out to
the extent funds would permit. Fourteen churches were
getting mission support.
The above mentioned church directory continues:
In 1908 a small group of members withdrew fellow-ship
from the original church in Murfreesboro and
established what is known today as Central Christian
Church on the corner of Main and Maney. There were 61
charter members of whom Mrs. Eugene Black is the only
livinq one at this date in 1971. Mrs. James Barclay,
sister of Alexander Campbell and wife of our first
missionary, helped to turn the first spade of earth
at groundbreaking ceremonies on May 8, 1911.
The Convention for 1909 was held at Murf reesboro,
September 20-23. The Christian Church at Murf reesboro
had come into existence a year earlier, when 50
persons withdrew from the Church of Christ. By the
time of the Convention, the congregation had grown to
150 and was meeting regularly in a rented building.
Prospects for a church building of their own brightened
when convention delegates pledged $6,000 towards its
construction
.
In spite of new opposition, the program of the
Christian Church in Tennessee experienced steady
progress. By the time of the State Convention in
October 1913 at Murf reesboro, where a new $30,000
edifice was dedicated as a part of the Convention
program, the State Society had five full-time
evangelists in the field. The delegates were told that
since its beginning the Society hadgbeen responsible
for establishing 150 congregations.
Again in the Church directory of 1972 the following
explains further the purpose and, aims of Central Christians.
This church is a local congregation of the Christian
Church (Disciples of Christ) , and was founded in 1908
for the purpose of promoting Christian Unity among the
followers of Christ here. It is affiliated with the
Christian Church in Tennessee, regional manifestation
of the church with headquarters in Nashville, and with
the United States and Canada manifestation (jg the church
with headquarters in Indianapolis, Indiana.
The records of Central Christian Church members report
that sixty-one persons withdrew from the Church of Christ in
1908, which at that time was Main Street Christian Church.
10
In researching this history of the early Christian
Church at Main and Maney, it is found that there are many
different versions and statistics which are given in hopes
that a more accurate picture may evolve.
The Central Christian Church which was first named
"Central Church of Christ," was organized August 1908, with
the name "Central" referring to the fact that the
Missionary Society of the Christian Churches following
Barton Stone's teachings, were in favor of centralizing the
Missionary Movement of the Churches of Christ.
Hattie W. Noel, one of the early members, wrote a
history of Central Christian dated September 27, 1963. In
it she says:
Central Christian Church of Murf reesboro, Tennessee,
was organized in August 1908 with 61 members, first
worshiping in the Cumberland Presbyterian Church, East
Main Street, which has since been wrecked and replaced
by the 1st National Bank of Murfreesboro building.
In October of the same year (1908) Brother R. E. Moss
was called to minister to the congregation. In May
1909 Brother Ira. M. Boswell of Chattanooga was
called in a revival service when 35 members were added
to the church, making a total membership of approxi-mately
100.
In 1909 the State Convention met with the church
and during convention week about $7,500 was raised with
which to begin a new church building. Among those
making large gifts to the building fund were B. B.
Kerr, E. H. Tatum, C. B. Ragland and James R. Jetton.
Brother Moss served the congregation two years.
Brother Everett Smith was called to minister to the
congregation in February 1911. At the time he received
this call he was State Sunday School Superintendent,
11
and upon suggestion of the State Board, accepted the
call to Central Christian Church and continued his
Sunday School work by correspondence. At the time
Bro. Smith came to the church, there were 85 member
&#8212;
a loss of some 15 members, some of whom had decided
to return to the Main Street church, from which this
group had broken away. Plans for the new church
building got under way promptly after Brother Smith's
coming. The sum of $6,000 was borrowed from the State
Board .to be added to the building fund. The church
trustees empowered to borrow the money were E. H.
Tatum, Clifford Love, B. B. Kerr and C. B. Ragland.
Mr. Ragland was chairman of the building committee and
Mr. Kelly Poff was the builder. The architect was a
Mr. Combs whom Brother Smith described in a letter
to me as "the dapper little fellow with whom I had
quite an argument as to the size of the baptistry."
It was always too small, but I couldn't convince
Mr. Combs of that fact.
May 8, 1911, was set apart as the day to begin
the work of building the new church. The cornerstone
was laid with appropriate and impressive ceremonies,
a spirit of reverence, love, and devotion to a cause
sprung from sincere conviction seemed to permeate
the entire proceeding. On this occasion Mrs. Barclay,
daughter of Alexander Campbell, was present and she
and Mrs. W. R. Jones, senior member of the congregation
and known to the congregation as "Mother Jones" were
permitted to move the first shovels of dirt. Among
other articles placed in the cornerstone were a Bible
and a picture of Brother and Mrs. Everettt Smith and
their baby, Beatrice.
Brother Smith set to work to obtain a pipe organ
for the church and was successful in securing a gift
from Mr. Andrew Carnegie for its purchase. His gift
covered practically the entire cost of the organ,
a Hillgreen and Lane. Mrs. Clifford Love was organist
for the church for many years, carrying over into
Brother Gray's and Brother Elliott's ministry.
12
{ mi. EVERETT S. SMl'l'H
Dr. Everett S. Smith's seven year ministry at
Central Christian began in the Cumberland Church and
continued through and beyond the construction of the
building at 404 East Main. He was remembered by all who
knew and loved him with reverence for many years.
13
Miss Frances Love, later Mrs. Eugene Black and
mother of Virginia Black Woodfin, was the longest living
charter member of the Central Christian Church at her
death at age 92. She is shown here in her graduation dress,
Mr. Eugene Black served for many years as elder
and Treasurer of the Central Christian Church.
14
Three charter members of Central Christian Church.
Seated: Mrs Aubrey Cook (Cookie) ; standing left to
right: Kathrin Kerr Riggs, Frances Love (Mrs. Eugene
Black, Gladys McCarty (not a chartered member)
15
16
THE KINGS BUILDERS.
THE KING'S BUILDERS.
,...^^&lt;J&#187;-
CHILDREN OF OUR MISSIONARIES IN SOUTH AMERICA.
M&#171;&#171;mr&#171;t Bun&#171;a-. J&#187;rvi&#171; Burner. Philip Burner. Ewmrt Wyle, Alwin Wyle.
CO O "&#171;
o &#187;s
If
3"
&#171; a
5 8
i; cu C 0)
n ^ &lt;v bi) ra 2 o &gt; u &lt;u
a "^ 03 S " -r
u Sis sn
&#8212;_ OaaO ^I-ao " U O Ih
^' o x; ^ ^
S 11" -5 u
a &gt;&#187;^^ TO a
O O T- 5 o
o 'Si a O rt
a&#163;&#176;s"
&#8212; Cii Ufe,fc,fc,i, 0[i,c^;&#8222;
3 t^
3 T- I
-a t&#171;
U ??!
4) &gt;, C -^
5 &#176; M 1X1 c u
rt ''. g a o ~
is
2 &#176;
^Tt
= J3 a 5 3 ^
&lt;a - - 2 T3 J;
CQ
&#8226;::CQ
ii &#167;:? a
a
S a
.^ u. N
a73 &lt;a o a
" 7= p , rt &#163; S a M &#163; &#171; &#163; fe
; 2 o &#8226;- '2
-: a a a a
tjfe,fc.b.fc,
I 1-^
"In 5
.5 Jj o u X! ^
&#8212; &#176; -c ^ t: -
a T cs e 3 a
J
-; w - (u a W
i2 &#171; .&#176; tU! rt I
" " &#8212; -^ A &#8212;
&#163;5:^55-0
^ s "
= a aas
5&#163;fe&#163;2&#163; .
'-'
&#163;1. U. Cl. Ck Cf ^
a. " 3 M
aaJT o !
? _ 3T3
&#8212; w 3 T *;
T3 3 &#171; I &#171;
"- &#167; 3
agaiw
o a o d, &#163;S&amp;55
= "a&#171;a
O&#171; rf&#176;e f2'" rt&#174; rp** &#8226; &amp;. U&lt; fe. fc, k.
&#171; 5
17 &#8212; c]
3 2
&#8226;Sod--
'*" k.
n5^
&#8222; o 1; aH ^a
0, ^ r o -30
I .53^"^
" rt S &#171;-^
3 0, 3 r ^ Oj
-3 S &#163; S 'f "
r &lt;u a a R 3 2
CJ &#8212;- &#8482; flJ " flJ fl.
2 t c -S S = -c
* 1. 2 a) 11
&#163;&#8226;5 o'-o " = n
9 c-
O
I
ra O
,^ " t- *
I &#171; ^
&#176; = t
-
cU B l- -3 " - M o m-a r I. a o
T3 0) ^ - 0; &#176; -r Ma tB. - 3 &gt;, -3 ^ &#8212; .3 n &#8226;" " 01 S 'J t- O'
5 S &#8212; a' u I"
- a5 * &#171;&#187; m O' &#8212; o ^ ja &#8212;
j3 ^ g =&#171; o &#187;^ J,
rt ja I- a* S -o
a i S bJ : f
to I,
ftj 1 ttj 3
Q 4&#187;
&#8226;^~J &#163;
&#8226; S55
&#187;&#8226;&#171;
^5
f.
a.
5 a **
x: &#8226;
^ G ? JX
ja .:&lt;: &#171;
'y u &#171;
a:
&#171; ~
h. a-a X!
;^
a /'. 2 3
&#171; S
"&#8226;S ^
25^ &#8226;3
s .&#171; M
ja .ad ja ^^^^
5 &#171;
S "^ &gt; 41 o
&#171; " S &#163; ^
(a S" ** " ^
o 5 f. J=
V- S3Ca)Oa
a 2;
&#163;&#8226;&#163;
&#8226;-. w i &#8226;o &#171; &#8222;. ^ ^ ^'&#176; a
2 g " 3 "^ S - -
gili'*Oj3&#8222;5'-'.
&lt;a a B*
&#8226;OJ3&lt;uffl-r;S'S.a
&#171;5 "-o 9 s-o" "&#8226;
Mj:-5oo)&#8212;.oa&#171;_o
&gt; o o o g
{ S K X ^ = B &amp; ^ ^ H Ci p: ^ tS
2 J
u 1
N a
5 J
O -J
So
a g
0) O)
I J3 g 0&#187;,
Sg'
;&#171; 3
it* 3 3 &#8212; &#8212;-.
&#171; O i2 o Ja
555 &#8226;3o_&#163;S =So3SS
fcfefc .2fr?ia
o3 909
3 3 D
2 &#171; a
Si' 2 38
K &#163; a 3 1
a 3 o
S-3
0&amp;
aas
a a c
11 11 &#171;
vo aanc
&#8212; a o jj a
&#174; &#187;&gt;
a
"&gt; *&gt; S o
i^ fc. u h O
"3 oi Ji" o X V i-rt
3 &#8212;. o
(tt I. Wl^
fca&lt;^^
e a s &#171;_
la 01 I.
g-f &#171; =
j5 o 4* ti a
* S S a a
&#171; 3 g .^ '"^
^ &#8226;a o, 4j 1*^
= &#167;&#167;aa
&#171;&#163;&#163;&#163;&#163;
Ufe,[k,fe,[i,
a; BJ a
4) _^ a O
ja ^ &#187;-! T
::^ I a
a a a o
p ^ I. ee
t- 4) c
5S&#163; &#176;
-s
18
CHARTER MEMBERS
OF
CENTRAL CHRISTIAN CHURCH
AUGUST 1908
Mrs. W. R. Jones
Mrs. H. H. Kerr
Mrs. T. B. RDtter
William T. Love
Miss Fannie Love
Miss FranJde White
Miss Lil Jetton
Miss Ida Richardson
Mrs. J. R. Burton
Dr. aixi Mrs. Enoch H. Jones
Mr. and Mrs. Ed H. Tatuin
Mr. and Mrs. Charles B. Ragland
Mr. and Mrs. Qifforxj Love
Mr. and Mrs. W. L. Logan
Mr. and Mrs. A. D. Wharton
Mr. and Mrs. J. R. Jetton
MAJ. and Mrs. J. D. Richardson
Mr. and Mrs. Wharton McLencre
Mr. and Mrs. Dnmett Batey
Mrs. Leland Jordan
Miss Letitia Jordon
Mrs. Tom Crichlow
Granville Sullivan
Mrs. George Bock
Mrs. G. B. Giltner
Mrs. Charlie Cooc
Miss Maude Earthnwn
Miss Diina Earthnan
Mr. and Mrs. J. T. Ott
Mr. and Mrs. S. B. Tidwell
Mr. and Mrs. John Sullivan
Mr. and Mrs. C. M. Pifer
Miss Bessie Smith
Miss Cuma Vaught
Miss Dolly Smith
Frank Smith
Mrs! Dnmett Crockett
Mrs. Mary Wood
Mrs. B. J. Hayes
Mrs. Mary Smith
Mrs. Amanda Lamib
Mrs. Vander^iff
Mrs. T. M. King
Harry W. Kerr
Winston Burton
B. B. Kerr
19
Virginia Black Woodfin has a list of the sixty-one
charter members. Her mother, Mrs. Frances (Miss Fannie)
Love Black saved the list, which was most fortunate, because
many of the church records had been lost.
The congregation was meeting in the Cumberland
Presbyterian Church building at the corner of East Main and
Spring Street where the First National Bank is found today.
Members were engaged in finding property and a builder for
their church building, as well as the financing.
While meeting in the Cumberland building the work of
the Missionary Society was being emphasized and a Junior
group was organized.
Kathrin Kerr Riggs had a book her sister, Elizabeth,
used while in the Junior Missionary society. It is dated
January 1909 and is called "The Kings Builders." Included in
this issue is a picture of the Juniors of Murf reesboro,
Tenn., "who contributed $5 or more each to the work last
year." In it are familiar names, such as Elizabeth Kerr,
Mary Brian Giltner (who is now Mrs. B. Martin), and Idaline
(Ida) Richardson, as shown.
The young people's work had its beginning before
the separation from the old church. Like most other
new organizations, it had its ups and downs,
completely disbanding on one or more occasions.
This Junior Work, as it was then called, was begun
by Miss Hattie Jones, daughter of Mr. and Mrs. W. R.
Jones, who after recovering from a severe attack of
typhoid fever and believing that it was through God's
20
answer to her prayers that her life had been spared,
felt she must enter actively into God's service as a
thank offering for her recovery. Two other young
women of the congregation she brought to her aid.
Misses Ida Richardson and Mimmie Holmes. They met
with the children on Sunday afternoons, prior to the
organization of what is now the Central Christian
Church, in the homes of either the leaders or the
children and carried on their work and study. Miss
Jones died soon after the organization of this work.
It was later carried on very successfully under the
leadership of Miss Frankie White. Among those who were
members of the Junior Band were Elizabeth and Katherine
Kerr (Mrs. Deery Riggs) , Ruth Batey (Mrs. Chas. T.
Battin) , Ready Batey (Mrs. Marion Logan), Mary Brine
Giltner (Mrs. Bob Martin), Margaret Ragland (Mrs.
Will Ragland), and Mary Lawrence Ragland (Mrs. Frank
Godchaux) . Later on. Miss Jeanette King took over
the work, devoting a great deal of time and effort
to the organization. She, having known personally
some of the missionaries, including Dr. and Mrs. Hardy
who went from Vine Street Christian Church, was capable
of making the studies very interesting. This work
later became known as Christian Endeavor, and is now
known as Christian Youth Fellowship.
Clarice Miller remembers the anniversary date of
her parents' marriage; Miss Myrtle Poff to Mr. Albert B.
Miller, on December 10, 1910. In her memoirs Mrs. Miller
says she and her husband joined the Christian Church
early in 1911, and since she had been sprinkled in the
Cumberland Church and then changed her membership to the
First Presbyterian upon their merger, she wanted to be
baptized. The Christians were using the Baptist Church
baptistry for this purpose until they built their own
church.
All of the Poffs took part in the march from the
Cumberland to the Presbyterian Church, one block north
21
on Spring Street on October 1906 when the two churches
14 merged. They had one minister who served both
congregations
.
According to Dr. Ernest Hooper, retired history
teacher at M.T.S.U., in his article, "History of First
Presbyterian Church," Mr. John T. Woodfin, Chairman of the
Cumberland Sessions, wrote a letter to the Presbyterian
Chairman proposing the merger. John T. Woodfin was the
father-in-law of Virginia Black Woodfin, and grandfather
of John T. (Bubba) Woodfin. After "a called meeting of
the session (Presbyterian) was held in Dr. Murfree's
office . . . and a joint meeting of the Elders and
Deacons . . . , the two congregations decided on the
merger ,.16
.
Included in a film strip. Reel I, of the "History
of Presbyterian Church" the names of the minister,
deacons, elders and their families from the Cumberland
Church who joined that day of the merger, October 6, 1906,
were: John T. Woodfin, Deacons: G. K. (Kelley) Poff,
and family, Miss Myrtle Poff, J. F. Poff, Julia A. (sic)
Poff, Abbie (Addie sic) Poff, and Floy Elizabeth Poff.
Kathrin Kerr says her mother, Mrs. H. H. Kerr, was
also a member of the Cumberland Church. Clarice
remembers Mrs. Harry H. Kerr as a beautiful woman of regal
bearing who reminded her of the Queen of England. Others
22
found the same resemblance, Kathrin remembers. Her father,
Mr. Harry H. Kerr, was Mayor of Murf reesboro. He had
fought in the Civil War and therefore was much older than
Kathrin 's mother, who was his second wife.
A lot at the corner of E. Main and S. Maney Avenue
was found and the trustees proceeded to purchase it. The
deed is self-explanatory. It is observed that the original
lot went south from Main Street to Vine Street. Dr. E. H.
Jones and wife sold to Clifford Love, et al trs. (Trustees).
The trustees of Central "Church of Christ" were Clifford
Love, Chairman, C. B. Ragland, B. B. Kerr, and E. H.
Tatum. The property was sold to these Trustees and their
successors, thereby making them the owners of the property.
They and their successors were the only ones who could
buy or sell Church property, and that only with the two-
1
8
thirds majority vote of the whole congregation.
A copy of the deed follows:
23
mrxxxxxxxxxxx)cxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxxx)oaxxxxxxxjrA;;. /xxxxxx
iljl m
Or. S. H. JftitM k wlf*
ro) dcbd'
Clifford Lot* &#8226;&#171;&#187;!&#187;&#8226;,
Stat* of T&#171;nn&#171;s&#171;*&#171;( Ruthorforrt County: Pc? cnrt tn oon-
&#8226; Irtorrtlon of tho mw of iUty-fl** hundrod ($6500.00) rtoU&#171;ri
paid *ivl to bo paid %a follows; two hundrod and fift)r(t2S0.00)
dollar! thlo day paid, eaah In han't tho racalpt of ctiloh la
-loraby aoknewladgad and on* proHlasory nofof *T*n data h*r*wlt
fc tfrtir
-^^
In th*a&#171; of tw onty-tao huwli-od &#187;n^ fifty (|2230.00) dollars, rtu* on or b*for* aay th*
lit, 1910, wlUtowt lnt*r*at, *x*eut*d by th* hw&gt;*lnaft*r na&#187;*&lt;1 truat*** .and payabla to
tha ordar of Or. B. H. Jonas and'thr** prolasory not** of OTon dat* h*r*wlth In th* aun
of en* thouaand (|1000.00) doUara oaeh, du* on or bofor* th* 1st day of May 1911% 12
ami 13 raapaotlTaly, with Intaraat at tha rata of six p*r-eant fro&#187; Kay th* 1st, 1910
untlll p*ld, azooutad by tha b*r*lnaft*r namad truataaa and Myabl* to tha ord*r of th*
said Dr. B. H. Jonas aw( tha aaauivtlon of on* thouaand dollars ($1000.00) du* Mlaa
Kllleu^ being on* of tha d*f*rr*d payaants on tha h*r*lnart*r d*aorlbad proparty pur-ehaa*
d by &#187;. R. H. Jonas from Rlehord Baard, w*, h*&#187;* this d*y bargaln*a ajuJ sold and
do haraby tranafar and contray unto Clifford I&#171;o**, 0. B. Ragland. B. fl. Karr and E. H.
TatuB, Tmstaaa for tha eantral Churah of Chrlat at llurfr**sboro, Tmnasa** and thalr au&#187;^
eaaaora (or aueh truataaa *a u^ h*r*lnaft*r b* aalaetad by tha oon0r*iit*tlon of aald Churah
to fill any vacancy In tha aald board of trustoas) tha fellowln,&lt; dasorlbad prep&#171;rty, lo-
&#8226;atad In tha 6th Ward, In tha City of llurfraasboro. In th* IJth Clrll Dlatrlet, Rutharford
County, Taim*aa*a and Mr* partloularly boundad and daaarlbad aa follow:
Baglnnlng at tha Horthwaat oorn*r of Mro. W. Y. Billot '8 lot on Bain 8t. and running
'South with aald Kra. W. Y. Elliot 'a Wast llaa JIO faat to tlna St.; thane* with vin* St.
13c I f**t to Vanay's A&#187;*.; th*no* Bast 152 &amp; t&#8212;t to ti a baglnnlng, b*la&lt; th* aaM prop-
&#8226;rtypur*h***d by DP. E. H. Jon** fro&#171; Richard Baard and raglatarad In Boofc #*1, pag* 380 _
&#8226;f th* laglatar'a Offle* of Rutharford County, T*nn**aaa.
To hara aad %c hald tha said lot with all th* l^ro&#187;*Mnta th*r*on and tha appurt*&#187;o&#171;4
thM&gt;*unto balon&#171;int&lt; to th* aald truataaa and tb*lr auaoaasori ferovw. 1
&#8226; &#187;9r&#187;nMH thst &#8226;&#8226; ara lawfully salaad of said proparty and hvn &#187; good and 1&#171;|^
vltfA %&#8226; aanra^'th* *&#171;m and that it la &#8226;nlnaaabarad, aiaapt tha &#8226;&#187;&#8226; tfewMWd (tlOOO.tO)
&#171;&#171;U&#171;va &#8226;*&#8226;&#8226; tafwrad to &#171;m1 aasuaad ly aald truitaaa, iMwatt MUg paid aa &#171;^ &#171;IB^
MMMMd &#171;*lUra (IIOOO.OO) &#171;( U&#171;i W&#187;% M* BMlglMMlBMrt SMf a^ *m
420 2
*^/' - &gt;^?^
2h
'^!Z^^^^S^^:r7. .:!! ''rLrJl^. j.. a,a.c.c^^L,sL/^^&#8364;.j^.
'M
wy
cl&#171;ll&#171;r&#171; ($1000.00) du* Rlohard B&#171;tfd uA en&#171; proaltaory not* of en* theuaMUl 4oIl*r* \
($1000.00) d)!* Mlii RtfuoB, botb b*lng balane* of purohM* inon*y on a^d lot, and 4
rir* hvmdr*d and fifty dollar ($330.00) aortga^ia to B. L. Rldlay, truataa, rat^latarad In
Book L.L , pad* t^BS of th* R*({lat*r'a Offle* of Rutharford County, T*nn*aax*, all of vtilch
*xc*pt th* en* tbeuaand dollara ($1000.00) to th* said Hiss Klllouiih, will b* paid off and
dlaohargad &#171;iti*n th* abev* mentioned not* of tii*nty-t&#171;o hundrod and fifty ($2250.00) dol-lars
du* on or before nay, let, 1910 Is paid to the said Dr. E. {&lt;. Jon**. And a* will
warrant itfut for*v*r d*f*nd th* tltl* th*r*to to th* said trustees and th*lr suoe*ssors,
at&lt;alnst the. lawful claims of all persons, whomsoever.
The said trustees and their suocessors, as above described, are eapowerad to sell any
or all of the above deeorlbei' property at any tlae, provided they are so authorlr.ert by
a aajorlty vote of the said conMSagatlen at a rehnilar open &#8226;*tlng.
It Is futhsr agr**d and understood that a lien is hereby expreisly retained on said pray
erty to eecure the payaents or the above deeerlbed noten, possession to be given Uay the
let, 1910. In wltn*** wh*r*of &#8226; hav* h*r*unto 8*t our hands this th* 19ti , day of
Haroh, 1910. E. H. JOnas.
Pannl* P. Jon*s.
STATE OH TENNK3SF.K&#8212;RUTHKRVORD COUNTT.
Personally appeared before me Jai.es D. Richardson Jr., a Notary Public Ir. and for said
Coxinty and State, the within naaed E. H. Jones and wife Urs. Panr.le P. Jones the bargainors
with whom I a personally acqualntad, and who ao)cnowledt{ed that they executed the within
deed Instrument for the purposes therein oontdnrd. And Kannle P. Jones wife of the said
R. H. Jonee, having appeared before de, privately and apart fron. her husband, the said
Panr.le P. Jonea aeknowledKOd the execution of said paper to hav^ be- n done by her freuly,
voluntarily, ant unlerstandlngly without compulsion or constraint fror, her said husband
and for the purpoees therein expressed. Witness my hand and official seal, (SFJIL) at
Murfreeaboro, Tennesaee this 19, day of Uareh 19IO.
Jeaee D. Richardson Jr.
Notary Publlo.
Noted Maroh 29th at 10 A. U. IjlO. Registered March 29th 1910.
^
25
John B. Woodfin
S ^3(0 3 9
&#167;
I
2" I
I ,
^1 ^sa I I
s 4 H o "&gt;
&#8226;JO
00 00 g P p^
I q2&gt; I
6?^
Wiiim
Sis I Sf| I
^5^&#167; -
S-BS
&lt;
8
n
o p oO &#187; &#187; &#187;
o o o
O&lt;0i (Xi
r*^^'**"* '
e32
^ &#171;ii;
i.. ^^^_, ____
5&#176;
...J a &#171;
27
Searching for a builder for their church, the
Christians engaged Bell Brothers and Company, located on
west Main Street where the old post office was. Their
lumber yard was located over by the railroad according
to Mr. Sam Ogilive. The Bell brothers were W. R. Bell, Jr.,
senior member, James G., and Cliff&#8212;according to James
Bell of Bells Drafting and Drawing Company on Lytle Street,
their nephew. He did not know or remember much about the
company.
In an interview with John Shearron, son of Gilbert
Shearron, one of the partners in their company in the new
building across the street, where Sterchi's Furniture store
is located now, told Clarice that Mr. W. R. Bell, Jr., was
the architect of Central Christian Church, and drew the plans
and specifications. Mr. Kelley Poff was superintendent of
the construction, working with Mr. W. R. Bell and inter-preting
specifications. Mr. John Shearron also told about
an older black man, Willie Franklin, who, as a young boy,
worked for Bell Brothers and had worked on the church.
Clarice called Willie and asked him to come to the
Central Christian Church and answer some questions. He
was a tall, very slender man about eighty-five years old.
At first he was a little slow remembering, but warmed
up to the subject as the questions came.
28
"Did you work for Bell Brothers when this church
was built?"
"Yes'm, I was just a boy, but (a friend) (sic)
took me to the job and Mr. W. R. said he would try me out.
I worked for Bell Brothers off and on as long as they
were in business. They said they would take care of me."
He was driving a nice second hand car.
"Did you know Mr. Kelley Poff?"
"Yes'm, I know 'em."
"Was he a good man?"
"Yes'm, he's a good man; yes'm."
"Was he the superintendent of the builders?"
"Yes'm, thats what he was."
"Did he do the work? Did he stay here on the
job all the time?"
"No'm, he didn't do the work. He tole us what to
do. He didn't stay all the time, but came by to check
on it."
"Was he building another house?"
"I don't remember."
Mr. Poff was building his home on Spring Street
which he designed and which was finished in March 1912.
It still stands at 827 N. Spring Street. This was the
house where Clarice spent the first four years of her
life with her mother and dad on one side of the house and
29
Aunt Emma and Uncle Kelley on the other side. The front
porch stands out in memory because the bannisters across
the front were solid stucco, as was the house, with toe
holes at the bottom and a concrete slab across the top for
flower boxes. The bannisters were designed so that people
passing along the street while the ladies were sitting out
on the porch sewing, drinking tea, etc. could not see their
ankles! There are many houses in Murfreesboro with this
same design--Uncle Kelley used to point them out as they
drove around town.
"Willie, what kind of work did you do on the Church?"
"I helped the brick layers, and poured concrete."
"Did you know Mr. Addie Poff? He was a brick layer,
and he was Kelley Poff's young brother?"
"Yes'm, I helped him and the others."
"What is that foundation made of? Is it rock or
concrete?"
"Thay's rocks with concrete on top of 'em."
"Where did they get the rocks? Did they come
from the quarry?"
"No'm, they cut 'em out of the ground out around
Lascassas Pike."
That is in the area of the Flat Rock which marks
the center of Tennessee. There is a stone marker
surrounded by a fence and a plaque explaining the rock
30
which is the exact center of Tennessee; one of Murf reesboro '
s
landmarks
.
"Willie, did you go up on the roof?"
"No'm, they wouldn't let me. It was too high."
"Willie, how deep do those rocks go down into the
ground?"
"'bout four or five feet. I hoped build the court
house in Woodbury. I got some of the pictures of that.
And I holped build the big house down here."
John Shearron said he had worked on the James K. Polk
Hotel at Main and Spring where Mid-South Bank is now
located.
"Who were the other Bell brothers, Willie?"
"Mr. Cliff, and Mr. Shearron, and Mr. Hooper,"
Clarice remembers Aunt Emma and Mrs. Cliff (Cuma)
Be^l were good friends. Mrs. Kelley Poff's name appeared
19
in the 1917 list of members of the Woman's Club. The
Club had evolved from a literary club called "The Helen
Hunt Jackson Reading Club." Several members of Central
Christian were among those listed. The Kelley Poffs
had become quite prominent since his success as a contractor
designer'-draf tsman of many homes in Murf reesboro. During
the 1920 's they went to Fort Worth, Texas, where he again
became quite successful. He first built his own home
there. They returned in the early 1930 's, and again he
31
became an independent contractor. Many Murfreesboro homes
were designed and built by Mr. Kelley Poff. He was both
deacon and elder of Central Christian as was Mr. J. F.
Poff, his father, who in his later years received the honor
of being made the first honorary officer (Elder) in the
Church's history. Church members fondly called him Daddy
Poff. He was an artist with wood; but that is another
story.
To continue the interview with the surprisingly
intelligent, elderly Willie Franklin, who was still tall
and slender at this late age:
"What else did you do for Bell Brothers?"
"I worked the yard hauling lumber, sand, gravel."
"Where was that "yard?"
"Down there by the railroad. It came here by
train.
"
"Did Bell Brothers make the brick and tall columns
for Central Christian?"
"I don't remember that."
Inspectors, repairmen and church members found the
free standing columns were made of metal cut in inter-locking
sections which were held together by the weight of
their capitols and the pediments they supported. The
pediments on the west and east sides corresponded to the
transcepts of ancient Cathedrals.
32
Willie Franklin
(worked on Central
Christian as a boy)
33
Kelley Poff's house
on N. Spring Street
where Clarice spent
her first four
years
.
The same design
of the porch
bannisters across
the street--designed
by Kelley Poff.
3^
Mr. and Mrs. Kelley Poff about 1912
35
Mr, and Mrs. Albert Bridges Miller and Clarice
Mr. &amp;. Mrs. Kelley Poff in front of their home in Fort Worth, TX, 1920':
36
Half columns built into the thick walls were
massive masonry covered with the buff colored bricks which
were used in the entire upper walls. These thick walls
on the outside, as well as in the basement, gave support
and upward thrust to support the roof and dome. Mr. John
Herrod, current building committee member, described an
arch that was uncovered during repairing the basement walls.
Arches such as this were found in cathedrals built
centuries ago. The keystone and upward thrust of these
arches counteract the gravity of downward pull of the
roof and dome. He estimated the weight of the huge dome
at about 2,500 pounds, not very heavy for its size, because
of the thin skin of galvanized sheet metal. He stated the
building was in surprisingly excellent condition. A fire
caused by lightening in 1975, and water damage in putting
out the fire, began a process of slipping of the chords
out of the trusses holding up the roof. Later rain and
storms continued the damage.
Mr. Herrod also told of the iron frame work in
the floor of the sanctuary, which makes the ceiling of the
basement. The sanctuary floor beams fit into these iron
"saddles" or cradles, and are not nailed in. No nails
have been found in these floor beams. Could this device have
been used to give in to the slight movement in expansion
and contraction of the building? Could it have been a
37
pre-conceived notion of steel reinforced concrete of modern
times? Colonial cabins were sometimes built with puncheon
floors in which logs were split and laid on the foundation
in such a manner. Mr. Hollis Westbrooks told of these
floors in the book. The Mayor's Dream by Clarice Miller.
Some of the walls in the basement were several feet
thick, adding to the support of the building, as told by
Clarice's Uncle Kelley Poff. These walls were made of
concrete, as was the floor of the basement.
On the outside of the church the bricks were not
painted but were made that buff color by adding pigment
before they were fired.
The corner stone at the northwest column at East
Main and South Maney did not rest on the ground. It is
above the thick rock wall with concrete on top, on which
the buff colored bricks were laid. Inscribed on this
original cornerstone was "Central Church of Christ A.D.
1912." After the parent church members changed their name
to "Main Street Church of Christ," the new church members
changed their name to "Central Christian Church." The
two pictures show the two names at Central.
Kelley Poff could never be hurried in erecting a
building. He said many times, "A building needs time to
settle." It took some two years to have Central Christian
far enough along in construction for the congregation to
38
begin meeting in it in December 1912. It was begun in
May 1911, as stated in the historical sketch in the program
for the Silver Anniversary of the building dated May 1937.
The architecture of the church building was quite
different from the parent church building or any other
building in Murf reesboro. In contrast to the Romanesque
types found locally. Central Christian had a pleasing
combination of oriental Byzantine (dome) and the Greek
classical order of columns.
In an art appreciation class at Middle Tennessee
State College in 1939, Miss Hester Rogers, well known and
loved art teacher, now deceased, said the dome on Central
Christian Church was more like the dome on the earliest
Christian Church, still in existence, St. Sophia in
Istanbul, Turkey, than any other modern church she had
20
seen.
St. Sophia or Hagia Sofia, Church of the Holy
Wisdom, was built between 532 and 537 (A.D., sic)
. . . . The plan is basically an inscribed Greek
Cross. . . . The plan is basically an inscribed
Greek Cross. . . . The hall has the typical Byzantine
Church centre: four piers at the corners of the
square rising in circular arches to support the
central dome. . . . The thrust from the dome is
taken partly by the semi-domes on the east and west
axes, but mainly by the massive buttresses . . .
built into the outer walls of the aisles and linked
by arches to the four central piers. They were
built of bricks roughly 60 centimeters . . . and 5
centimeters thick with mortar joints nearly as
thick. . . . The early dome was too weak and
collapsed after about twenty years. Its successor
was built slightly higher. ^^
39
Greek architecture achieved its finest form in the
clear statement of the developed temple which' Kad
such a profound influence on later western European
architecture. Greek enthusiasm for mental and
physical culture found expression in the sculptural
qualities of its architecture .22
The Greek orders of architecture were found in the
columns and monuments. The simplest column, the Doric
with its plain capitol; the Ionic, with its rams horn
capitol; and last, the Corinthian with decorative capitol
of papyrus leaves and flowers and flated columns.
Two of the Greek orders were used in the design of
Central Christian.
In contrast to the rounded domes and arches of
Byzantine architecture are the pointed vaults and flying
buttresses of the Gothic cathedrals, such as Amiens
23 begun in 1220 as shown here.
In the design of Central Christian, the arch of
the hemispherical dome is repeated in the sanctuary.
Rounded arches are found over the organ pipes made of dark,
polished wood with Ionic columns, and over the marble
baptistry with Ionic columns including the ram's horns.
The arch over the baptistry has a large keystone
easily visible. The keystone of any arch is the triangular
shaped stone, no matter what size, at the top. It holds
the arch in place taking the outward and upward thrust
from the columns below, the surrounding walls and the base
support.
40
s
,** -.1' ^A. ..^
^
Free standing columns and Pediments
41
Half Columns and Thick Stone Foundation
42
Ground rocks and concrete
^3
Original cornerstone in the
foundation
The later sign when
the name was changed
44
The Dome Rests on a Square Base
^5
Arches over Organ Pipes
Baptistry Marble Arch with Ionic Columns&#8212;Pews before
Renovation, chairs used now
46
Amiens Cathedral. Begun 1210. The
cutawiy portions reveal the rib vaulting
of the nave which transmits the load onto
piers by means of the pointed arches.
Flying buttresses brace the upper walls of
the nave, the upper walls of the chancel
(on the right), and the south transept.
The west front is on the left.
In contrast to the domes and arches of Byzantine-Greek
architecture in the Gothic architecture.
&#8226;^/&#187;*rjon-(rJ&#187;&#163;-
^7
Fig. 67 (above) . l'..ulu&lt;m. Vi.w ..[ cMciior. Rome.
View of i,ucri.,r. l.-oking toward apse. I.tanhul. Turkey;
^" ^'"''"'"'^
' ""'^'&#8226;' '"'''"'&#8226;
V V
48
C
&#8226;H
T)
C
ro P
CO
&gt;1
0)
3
ao
w
^9
L,,,^ ^^^^^J
Doric order.
i6
^
50
i,&#187;.-&#8222;w&#187;...-^4J
Ionic and Corinthian Columns on Central Christian Church
IS'
51
Again rounded arches were built into the choir
railing, and the pews were arranged in a semi-circle or
ampitheatre around the pulpit. A downward sloping of the
floor resulted in providing an excellent view even from the
back pews. Rounded "corners" of the church on both lower
sides and ceiling aided in reflecting of voices. Singers in
the choir observed the excellent acoustics, since the
ceiling overhead there is also rounded. Many visiting
speakers, as well as the congregation, remarked about this
25
phenomonen.
Pews are so constructed that the gradual sloping
or decline of the floor was not noticeable when people are
seated. The contrast was evident when using chairs while
construction was underway.
On the outside of the church Ionic and modified
Corinthian columns support the pediments.
In his book. Understanding the Arts , by Bernard S.
Myers, he notes.
The dome presents many similar problems and.
limitations (as the Gothic-Vault) with its constituted
pointed arches constantly exerting outward thrust as
a result of weight imposed upon it as well as its own
weight. A thrust that would cause it to burst unless
the strain were relieved in some fashion. . . .
(half domes, massive walls, flying buttress) The
dome is employed to cover either a circular or a
square building. The hemispherical vault, or dome,
may be seen in the Roman Pantheon as well as the
Byzantine Church of (St.) Hagia Sophia. . . . Fitting
52
the top of this cylinder to the lower portion of the
hemisphere presents no difficulty (as in the Pantheon
in Rome) since both are circular in shape. There
are many instances however, in which the lower part
of the building is square (such as Central Christian
Church) . To provide a complete and enclosed roof
for it, the circular dome has been used, and special
architectural devices had to be developed to fit the
two shapes together. The most important of these
devices is the spherical pendentive, as seen in Hagia
Sophia.
However light in weight a dome may be (and
often special efforts are made to limit its weight)
,
it still constitutes a formidable weight for the walls
to support. In Hagia Sophia, two sides of the building
are buttressed, or supported, externally by the
addition of pairs of heavy stone piers which lean
their weight against the walls. (Not flying
buttresses but masses of stone.) The other sides are
reinforced by placing smaller half domes below this
slngl&#171;i one. From here a number of lower vaults take
over the weight, ^Qtil it is finally grounded at the
base of the walls.
The dome at Central Christian has a frame work of
carved wooden ribs covered by a skin of galvanized sheet
metal, according to engineer inspector, Logan Hickerson
of Murf reesboro. It is supported by two longitudinal
trusses and two latitudinal trusses forming a square. The
metal skin for the dome is constructed of graduated metal
strips, wider at the bottom than the top of each. They
are fitted onto the hemispherical shape in strips from a
wide bottom to the point at the top. The skin of mental
is nailed to the surrounding square.
The outer walls at Central were reinforced by
masonry columns, which can be easily observed from the
53
outside. Masonary columns were used since reinforced con-crete
had not yet been invented. These thick outer walls
with brick veneer above a stone and concrete foundation
sank deep into the ground forming the basement or "Fellow-ship
Hall." Three or four foot thick walls were used in
the basement to give the support and upward thrust needed
by the roof and dome. The capitols of these half columns
are modified classical Corinthian.
To better understand the construction of the roof
and dome, the report of the findings by inspectors after
the bent beams were first discov-ered, along with pictures
taken in the attic, are given at this point. The report,
and pictures illustrating it were supplied by Floyd Wilson,
of State Farm Insurance Company and David Kious, chairman
of the Financial Committee.
January 28, 1986
5^
ENGINEERING REPORT D0157
STRUCTURAL EXAMINATION AND EVALUATION
CENTRAL CHRISTIAN CHURCH
400 EAST MAIN STREET
MURFREESBORO, TENNESSEE
SUMMARY
Extreme deflection in the primary wood truss framing members
of tnis structure has aeveloped over a period of many /ears.
No significant additional motion in these members has oci,m,--
fed since repairs were accomplished after a fire event in
the attic about qleven years ago.
The affected members can be realigned and repaired, however,
the methods required for this work may be very dangerous if
not accomplished with great care and under the supervision
of persons who are experienced in construction methods to be
used.
In our opinion, the structure, in it's present condition,
poses a significant hazard to persons and property. We
recommend that this structure not be used for meetings, and
that it be closed to public access until appropriate repairs
are accomplished.
I. INTRODUCTION
An engineering investigation was initiated on January
22, 1986, at the referenced site for the purpose of
examining and evaluating the cause of reported bowing and
sagging in primary framing members of the roof. The color
photograph's included with this report were taken during the
course of inspection.
II. BACKGROUND INFORMATION
This structure was built in 1912. According to in-formation
provided by others, a fire was caused in the at-tic
area by a lightning strike about eleven years ago. Re-pairs
were made to the structure at that time.
Recently, extreme bending as well as sagging has been
reported by persons who observed the attic area. Inspections
have also shown severe sagging in the roof and in the
sanctuary ceiling. As a result of these observations, the
building has been taken out of use due to public safety
concerns
.
III. OBSERVATIONS OF FRAME DAMAGES
Figure 1 at the end of this report shows the general
layout and location of photographs taken during our in-spection.
Overall views of the building are shown in
photographs A, B, F, and G. The building in constructed
using load bearing exterior masonry walls with wood trus-ses
as primary roof framing.
55
56
Substantial sagging has occurred at the roof ridge both
in front of and to the rear of the dome section. At the
front, we estimate a drop in ridge elevation of about 1.0
feet. At rear the drop is estimated at about 1.5 feet, The
amount of the displacement is demonstrated in photographs C
and H. A peripheral inspection was conducted of the
building for the purpose of determining the amounts and
locations of any relevant settlements. In general, we found
no indication of settlements which could be causative to the
extreme deflections which are present in the roof framing.
All of the exterior walls are plumb and plane. The
only cracking of structural consequence was situated at the
front entrance door. This problem with cracking has been
present for many years arid^ has been patched in the past.
The cracks at this location are localized at the doorway and
do not affect the remainder of the structure.
A number of cracks are present around the structure at
the level from ground to the base of the windows. These
crack patterns are generally vertical, and situated at to
bottoms of window openings. There are no construction
joints in the exterior walls for the control of expansion
and contraction motion. The pattern of cracks aroumt tl..."
perimeter of this building are the result of differential
expansion and contraction in the masonry materials relate
the changes in temperature and moisture content.
According to information provided, a new roof covering
was installed about six months ago. Our observation
indicates that the roof covering was relatively new as shown
by the photographs. The joints of the roof to vertical wall
sections do not appear to have been flashed. Photograph D
demonstrates that the joint was apparently closed by trowel-led
mastic.
An inspection of the interior of the sanctuary revealed
notable sagging in the ceiling, especially toward the rear
area of the building. Also, substantial damage has been
sustained in the plaster ceiling and walls due to leakage.
Leakage stains observed in this area appeared to be quite
aged.
Access to the attic of the building was made through
ports in the ceilings at the rear of the building. Our
observations of the walls and ceilings at the area around
these ports demonstrated longterm leakage problems.
The photographs taken during inspection of the attic
are referenced in the photographic layout as Photographs K
through PP. Multiple photographs are presented for desig-nated
points L, S, and CC. These extra photographs show
close-up views and are lumped together for simplification of
the sketch.
There are eight lateral trusses which support the
entire roof and transfer load to the masonry walls. The
-3-
57
58
second through the sixth trusses from the rear wall support
two longitudinal truss-type members. These longitudinal
truss-type members support the framing for the dome and the
dome support walls. For our reference, we have designated
the lateral trusses with the letters A through H. The two
longitudinal members we designate as 1 and 2. Two wall
sections support the dome walls which we designate as B1 and
El . These references are show on the layout sketch.
Primary truss members A and B have spread about 2
inches since original construction. The spreading is
present at the bottom junction of the inner lattice chords
to the base chord. Typical spreading motion is shown in
photograph L2 and S2. These openings have not changed in a
period of many years. The oresence of the fiberqlflss
insulation in these openings indicates that the openinas
were present at the time that the attic was insulated. In
our opinion, the spreading as observed in trusses A and B
most probably developed very soon after load was first
applied to the new roof at the time of original
construction.
As shown by photographs and PP, very significant
longterm leakage has been sustained in the roof. Also, the
wood decking material has been severely damaged at several
points, apparently by "stepping through" during roofing
operations. We recommend that these damages be repaired to
prevent early failure of the roofing.
-4-
59
We observed no rotting in any of the primary framing,
however, longterm roof leakages has caused deterioration of
parts of the ceiling joists as shown in photograph T.
The roof trusses in the front of the building (F, G and
H) are not damaged. All of the chords appear to be straight
and true and the material is in secure condition.
Truss members C and D have effectively failed. The top
chords of these trusses are leaning toward the front of the
building. The peak has dislocated 21 inches with respect to
the bottom chord plane. The extreme deflection of these
members is shown in photographs U, W, Z, and BB.
Truss member E has developed a reverse skew so that the
peak has not been displaced laterally. This peak is shown
in photograph II. In this member, the left top chord has
bowed toward the front and the right top chord has bowod
toward the rear of the building. The condition is
demonstrated in photographs FF and KK.
The longitudinal truss-type member has sustained severe
damage at several points due to overload. The most
significant damage was located in member 1 at the
intersection with truss C. At this point, the top chord of
member 1 was virtually crushed by applied loads.
Close-up view of the top surface of the insulation
blanket at the center of the new wood repair area is shown
in photograph CC4. At this location, and in the surrounding
-5-
60
area, the top surface of insulation was covered with many
pieces of charred wood from the previous fire event. All of
the top surface of the insulation material appeared to be
smoke stained.
Photographs CC1 and CC2 show the connection of the- .new
wood replacement framing to the charred top chord of truss
D. Close-up observation was made of this joining. The new
wood was toe nailed to the truss chord. There was no
bending of the nails or distress in the wood to indicate any
relative motion between these wood members since instal-lation
of the new wood.
As shown in photograph CC2 , the upper part of the new
wood is in contact with the top of the truss chord. This
demonstrates that the vertical location of the top chord of
truss D has not moved since installation of the new wood.
Also, the angle of cut for the new wood to the top chord
shows no relative change in location of the truss member
since the new wood was installed.
IV. COMMENT ON POTENTIAL FIRE HAZZARD
Improper placement of fiberglass insulation has boon
made in this attic space. Very high temoeratures were felt
by touching the sides of the light fixture enclosures In
this area. As shown by photographs LI, N. V, DD, and JJ
,
insulation material completely encompassed maxiy Q^ thpse
fixtures. Such placement of insulation prevents proper
-6-
61
dissipation of heat and results in raoid and dangerous cise
io temperature. In some wood materials, auto ignition can
occur with sustained temperature of around 400 degrees F.
At the area shown in photographs CC1 through CCS and JJ
the insulation on an electric wire had been damaged by- heat
from the previous fire event. This insulation damage is
shown in photograph CC3 and CCS. This damage does pose a
significant fire hazard, especially at the contact point
with a metal part of that truss member.
V. ANALYSIS OF CAUSE OF DAMAGE SUSTAINED
Truss members C, D, and E are completely unbraced
between the longitudinal members 1 and 2. Truss members A,
B, F, G, and H are provided lateral restraint by fastening
to the roof purlin and wood decking material.
Lateral support of wood in the compression chords is
critically important for stability. Without lateral bracing
the compression chords will tend to buckle out &#169;f the plane
of the truss.
As these members bent out of their load axes, they
ceased to be capable of functioning as load bearing members
of the trusses. Over a period of many years, truss member C
and D ceased to carry design load. Load was transferred to
truss E resulting in direct overload. Truss member E also
failed due to compression of the unbraced top chords as
described above.
-7-
62
Loading from the center portion of the roof, especially
the dome, was designed to be carried by trusses C, D, and E.
In there present condition, these trusses have ceased to be
supporting members and are effectively additional dead load.
Support of these trusses, and of the central portion of
the roof is being transferred to truss members B and F
through members 1 and 2. A substantial load distribution
also transfers load to the masonry walls.
VI. CONCLUSIONS
Deierioration &lt;^f. the primary roof trusses has occurred
over a period of many years due to inadequate bracina of the
top chord of the central trusses.
VII. RECOMMENDATIONS
We recommend that the damaged truss members be
realigned and repaired. Where wood chords have been bent
extremely, reinforcement plates should be installed by
through bolting. In the longitudinal members 1 and 2, tne
top chord should be similarly reinforced where distress has
occurred.
Realignment of each truss can be accomplished by
drawing from the base chords of adjacent trusses. After
reinforcement and realignment of the trusses has been
accomplished, the top chords of the center trusses should be
secured permanently by continuous runs of bracing. This
63
bracing should be run to and securely fastened to the wall
sections Bl and El
.
Purlin connections to wall section Bl and El , appear to
be by nailing to the sheathing material only, except at the
right side of wall section El . (Refer to photographs' Q and
MM) . We recommend that additional framing be added to more
securely support these sections of roof.
After completing repairs of the primary framing, the
sanctuary ceiling can be adjusted by leveling the bottom
chord of each truss if necessary.
It is recommended that all fastening, whether temporary
or permanent, be done using screws. Hammer driven nailing
and all other vibration causing tools, etc, should be
avoided. Heavy equipment or materials should not be placed
in or on the envolved sections of roof. Work should be
accomplished with as few men as practicable. The center
area, under the dome, should be avoided by workmen until the
primary trusses are secure.
*****
-9-
^ 64
=a
-^ j&#163;.
\
s\l
K^
I ;&#8226;-
Q V
[&amp;-
&#8212; rIV ?/,
'
I
^
&lt;.fA.
J
:Ji&#187;^
LI
S2.
67
68
XI
69
70
^Mm^^^^^^i^ 71
&#171;4?*.*.-
Wfs^:
fiSf^\ ^&#8226;*&#171;
3k?-* "r^. i'*"
II,
m.
jj.
73
When the congregation began meeting in the church
building in December of 1912, and the dedication ceremonies
were held in September 1913 preceeding the State Conven-tion
held in the building, much activity in missionary
work, church, Sunday School and youth organizations
continued with renewed vigor.
Again quoting Hattie Noel's "History," "The church
became permanently identified with the State and National
work. Dr. and Mrs. E. H. Jones were regular attendants at
most of the National Conventions with the pastor, Everette
Smith. Dr. Jones was chairman of the board for many years.
Mr. E. H. Tatum was secretary and Mr. Emmett Batey,
treasurer.
"
During Dr. Everett Smith's seven years ministry,
which began while the congregation was meeting in the
Cumberland Church, many memorable happenings stand out in
the minds of the three remaining members who were present
for the dedication.
Not one of the three will ever forget the little
red chairs for children in Sunday School. They were placed
in rows in front of the adult chairs. Miss Elizabeth Kerr
was Sunday School teacher for Virginia and Clarice. The
bunch of grapes drawn as circles on a sheet of paper for
each child, just had to have that purple grape stuck on
in place each Sunday until it was full. She didn't dare
27
miss going, the grape would be empty.
74
No one could ever forget the delicious aromas in
the basement as one entered down the steps from Maney
Avenue at Thanksgiving and Bazaar, and Christmas; turkey,
dressing with sage and onion, cocoanut cakes and ambrosia.
The delicate lace and satin craft work, embroidery,
tattinq and crochet work; whole sets of baby clothes were
displayed and used as a fund raising project. Kathrin
remembers her mother, Mrs. Harry Kerr , stood at the
entrance door to accept reservations.
At Christmas the tingling smell of the Christmas
tree filled with gifts and goodies for children, sent
chills up their spines. Santa was there, and often
Mr. J. F. Poff or Virginia's uncle Clifford Love, played
the role to perfection.
Kathrin went to Mission Band for the Juniors with
her sister, Elizabeth. One time they said to Katherin,
"Get up and sing for us." Since they didn't say sing
"Jesus Loves Me," she sang a popular song, much to everyone's
delight
.
In the summer, church picnics were held out in the
country. Again the fried chicken, potato salad, caramel
cake and watermelon not only remembered but tasted in
retrospect
.
At least some of the stained glass windows were
donations made by families. The name "Potter" was
75
76
77
remembered on one of them. Clarice found in the Poff
family Bible a letter edged in black announcing the death
of &#8226;
Mrs. Frances Potter Jones, Funeral from Central
Christian Church tomorrow (Saturday) morning,
December 12, 1925 at 10:30 o'clock. Services by
Dr. Ernest Elliot. Interment at Evergreen Cemetery.
The following friends will serve as pall bearers:
Honorary&#8212;Dr. J. R. Gott, C. B. Huggins, R. H.
Harrison, E. C. Batey, J. R. Jetton, J. F. Poff.
Active--Sam Hirshbrunner , Clifford Love, J. R.
Williams, Thomas Brackin, Eugene Black, Dr. J. A.
Scott.
Woodfin and Moore in charge.
Murf reesboro, Tenn., December 11, 1925.
Another letter edged in black was for the daughter of
Mr. and Mrs. George W. Haynes , December 22, 1910, with other
families names.
All three of the children, Virginia, Kathrin and
Clarice remember Katherine Love playing the organ. There
was no electricity and the pumping of feet was amazing,
but what lovely music! Mrs. Everette Smith brought tears
to the eyes of little Virginia Black, and Clarice thought
she looked like an angel when she sang "The Ninety and Nine."
The Ninety and Nine
There were Ninety and nine that safely lay
In the shelter of the fold.
But one was out on the hills away
Far off from the gates of gold.
Away on the mountain wild and bare
Away from the tender shepherd's care
Away from the tender shepherd's care.
78
Lord thou hast here the ninety and nine
Are thev not enouqh for Thee?
But the shepherd made answer, this of mine
has wandered away from me.
And although the road be rough and steep
I go to the desert to find my sheep,
I ao to the desert to find my sheep.
But none of the ransomed ever knew
How deep were the waters crossed.
Nor how dark was the night that the Lord passed through
Ere He found His sheep that was lost.
Out in the desert He heard its cry
Sick and helpless and ready to die.
Sick and helpless and ready to die.
Lord, whence are those blood drops
All the way that mark out the mountain's track?
They were shed for one who has gone astray
Ere the shepherd could bring him back.
Lord, whence are thy hands as rent and torn?
They are pierced tonight by many a thorn.
They are pierced tonight by many a thorn.
But all through the mountain, thunder riven
and up from the rocky steep there arose,
A glad cry to the Gate of Heaven,
Rejoice I have found my sheep.
And the angels echoed around the throne.
Rejoice for the Lord brings back His own
Rejoice for the Lord brings back His own.
Rejoice for the Lord brings back His own.
Elizabeth Clephane Ira D. Sanky
From the book loaned by Buleah Rowlette, The Shape
of Adam's Rib , by Lorraine Lollis, we read:
The First officers of the Christian Woman's
Board of Missions set up shop in Indianapolis. The
president, Maria Jameson recording secretary, Sarah
Wallace; and treasurer, Mrs. O. A. Buraess, all lived
there; and the corresponding secretary, Caroline
Neville Pearre, was in the process of moving there.
This, believe it or not, explains the fact that
79
Indianapolis is today the city of the international
headauarters of the Christian Church (Disciples of
Christ) . The oriainal constitution of CWBM named
the above officers plus a vice-president from each
of the nine states represented and twelve managers
as the Executive Committee, but stipulated that
five should be a quorum for the transaction of
business
.
It was an organization of laywomen, all amateurs,
for whom winnina the world for Christ became the
grand passion of their lives. To leave no doubt
about their purpose, they used the word missionary
.four times in Article II of the first constitution:
Its object shall be to cultivate a missionary
spirit, to encourage missionary effort in our churches,
to disseminate missionary intelliaence, and to se^gre
systematic contributions for missionary purposes.
The program for the celebration of the Christian
Church buildina, October 17, 1937, "Commemorating the
Building and Twenty-Five Years of Continuous Worship,"
reveals an historical sketch and names of those who had
been members for the twenty-five years, on that Silver
Anniversary/ 1912-1937, as well as others who came later.
The program brings to a close the early history of
Central Christian Church.
... .SILVER. ...
ANNIVERSARY
80
J
I &#165;
i
*
l^&lt;3P&gt;^|
COMMEMORATING
THE BUILDING AND TWENTY-FIVE YEARS
OF CONTINUOUS WORSHIP
CENTRAL CHRISTIAN CHURCH
MURFREESBORO, TENNESSEE
*^jg^i
OCTOBER -17, 1937
-J
\\ &lt;:^LL(j&#163;:% cyT&gt;^2.ni(j&#163;%&#177;axu r
SILVER MEMBERS
Present Resident Members
Twenty-Five Years
In Central Christian Church
Mrs. Emma Arnold
Mr. and Mrs. Eugene Black
Mrs. Emmett Crockett
Mrs. Charles F. Cox
Mrs. Aubrey Cook
Miss Emma Earthman
Miss Bessie Green
Mr. and Mrs. Sam Hirshbrunner
Mrs. R. L. Jones
Mr. J. R. Jetton
Miss Jeanette King
Mrs. Harry Kerr
Miss Elizabeth Kerr
Mrs. A. H. McLean
Mr. and Mrs. Albert Miller
Mrs. W. B. Noel
Mr. and Mrs. J. F. Pott
Mr. and Mrs. Kelly Poff
Mrs. John Pierce
Miss Ida Richardson
Mrs. Deery Riggs
Dr. and Mrs. J. A. Scott
Mr. and Mrs. John Sullivan
Miss Bessie Smith
Miss Frankie White
82
C c^iLuEX CITjtnuLVEtiaxL
tl }
COMMITTEES
RECEPTION
Mrs. John Woodfin Jr., Chairman
Mrs. Deery Riggs
Mrs. Eugene Black
Mrs. Kelly Poff
Mrs. R. A. Nausley
Mrs. David Renaker
Mrs. Cecil Elrod
Mrs. John Tarver
Mrs. Earle Rees
DINNER
Mrs. J. A. Scott, Chairman
Mrs. Aubrey Cook
Mrs. T. A. Moore
Mrs. H. E. Cranford
Mrs. Florence Funk
Mrs. S. H. Wood
Mrs. Hattie Noel
Mrs. A. H. McLain
Miss Elizabeth Kerr
Miss Mary Roberts
DECORATION
Miss Bessie Smith, Chairman
Mrs. C. C. Baker Miss Clarice Miller
Mrs. Earle F. Rees, Chairman
Miss Margaret Hitt, Co-chairman
PROGRAM
Mrs. Marshall S. Burns, Chairman
Miss Ida Richardson. Co-chairman
Dr. T. J. Golightlj Mr. and Mrs. Kelly Poff
PUBLICITY
Mr. C. C. Baker, Chairman
Mr. T. T. Martin, Co-chairman
INVITATION
Mr. Kelly Poff
11:00 A.M.
Mr. Sam Hirshbrunner
Dr. R. A. Nausl&#187;y
Mr. Eugene Black
Dr. J, A. Scott
Mr. T. .A Moore
3:00 P.M.
Jesse Waller
Cecil Elrod Jr.
Orbry Moore
Mr. David Renaker
Mr. Aubrey Cook
s^^^;?*&#174;
83
j
&lt;^iL(js,x c::/f-nnLLT&#163;x&#177;a%Li It
HISTORICAL SKETCH
&#8212;of&#8212;
THE CHRISTIAN CHURCH
The Christian Church is strictly a Restoration movement. This
movement had for its beginning in America the turmoil of the re-ligious
frontier of tha American pioneer days. The first Christian
Church organized and ?et up in this country was Brush Run Church
at Brush Run, Pennsylvania, in 1814. This movement has a rich
heritage. The first movement started with an OKelley, a. Methodist
minister in Virginia. Another with Abner Jones, a Baptist minister
in Vermont, and a third movement growing out of the Great Revival
of Kentucky with Barton W. Stone through three movements un-known
to each other and in different parts of the country were alike
in taking the Bible as their only rule of faith.
The Central Christian Church was organized in August, 1908 with
61 members, first worshipping in the old Cumberland Church. The
construction of the present Cliurch building was begun in May, 1911,
being completed in 1912, at a cost of $37,000.00, every dollar of which
has been paid. Tlie present membership is 160. The first pastor called
was R. E. Moss, 1908; following was Everett S. Smith, 1911, serving
seven years ; J. Gross Boone, who served the Church less than one
year died with Flu and Pneumonia ; fourth pastor, A. Preston Gray,
July, 1918 to April, 1923; following him was E. W. Elliott, 1923 to
1929; then H, M. Sippel, September. 1929 to September, 1932. Rev.
Marshall S. Burns, the present pastor, called November, 1932. All
visitors find a ready welcome at all services.
&#187;&#163;*$^^
af
NOTES
"Christian Standard." October 11, 1913. pp. 32-33.
Copy supplied by Christian Disciples of Christ, Historical
Society, Nashville, Tennessee.
2 "Christian&#8212;Evanaelist." October 23, 1913. p. 18.
Supplied by Christian Disciples Historical Society,
Nashville, Tennessee.
3 Herman Norton, Tennessee Christians , Reed and
Company, Nashville, Tennessee, 1971, Jacket description.
^Norton, p ,. 193.
"Central Christian Church Directory. ]972. Roy
Hu]an, pastor, p. 1.
Church Directory, 1972, p. 1 , par. 3.
Norton, pp. 220-223.
Church Directory, J972, p. 1, par. 4.
^Norton, pp. 2 24, 233.
Church Directory, 1972, p. 2-
1 1 Clarice Miller, after much research.
] 2 Hattie W, Noel, "History of Central Christian
Church," September 27, 1963, pp. 1-2.
Noel, p. 3.
14
C. C. Henderson, Story of Murf reesboro . The News
Banner Publishinq Co., @ 1929, p. 134
.
Rutherford County Historical Maqazine,
Publication No. 14, p. 27.
1 r
Rutherford County Historical Maqazine, p. 27.
Film Strip, Reel I, "History of Presbyterian
Church," Loaned by Dr. Ernest Hooper.
1
8
See Constitution and By-Laws of Central Christian
Church.
85
19Rutherford County Historical Society Publication,
No. 26, Winter 1986, p. 63.
20 According to Clarice Miller who was in the class.
21 Georqe Mansell, Anatomy of Architecture . A. &amp; W.
Publishers, Inc., NY, 3 1979, p. 45.
22Mansel 1 , p. 16
.
23 Mansell, p. 106.
24 Clarice Miller, student and teacher of Art.
25Miller, from observation and listening to
Kelley Poff.
2 6 Bernard S. Myers, Understanding the Arts .
pp. 108-110.
27Miller, from observation and Kelley, Poff.
28Lorraine Lollis, The Shape of Adam's Rib .
Dethany Press, @ 1970, p. 41.
</dc:description>
<dc:description>Presents a history of the Central Christian Church. Includes information on architecture, notable people, and important dates, with several appendices</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.); Murfreesboro (Tenn.); Christian Church (Disciples of Christ)</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>87 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-01; mt2011-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication27ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/38</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>