<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>On the home front: the effect of the civil war on Murfreesboro, Tennessee</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Chatham, Debbie</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 39</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1996</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869; 1870-1879; 1880-1889;</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>ON THE HOME FRONT: THE EFFECT OF THE CIVIL WAR
ON MURFREESBORO, TENNESSEE
For those ofus who have been blessed to live in the United States in a time ofrelative peace and prc)sperit&gt;^
it is hard to imagine the hardships feced by those living during the Civil War era. This was a time when the people
had very strong beliefe regarding states' rights, abolition, and secession. Aneighbor might oppose secession, while
you fevored it. A friend might be an axid abolitionist, while your brother might feel it is his God-given right to
protect those people he feels are inferior by allowing them to live and work on his property' as slaves. These strong
beliefe, and the emotions they generated, eventually erupted into a war so devastating that it would take the
economy of the South many years to recover 130 years later, the emotional eflfects of the Civil War have not
completely disappeared.
Those men who fought in the battles ofthe CrvQ War had to iace ph&gt;'sical and emotional hardships, hunger,
and death. However, theywere not the only ones who suffered, for the civilians ofthe South who were left at home
on the ferms and in the towns, the suffering was intense. They might not have had to face going into battle, but
they quite often did not knowwhere the next meal was coming from or howtheywere going to pay the mortgage
or the taxes. These same individuals also worried about their loved ones whowere fighting. Family and fiiends left
at home did not knowwhether thefr men would come home fixam the war. Many ofthem worked in the hospitals
and saw the death, disease, and carnage ofwar from a very personal viewpoint. Citizens also did not knowwhom
they could trust. Those who lived in federally occupied territory could be reported to the Union troops as an
enemy by their neighbors or their slaves. Martial law ^-as in place in many areas. Schools were closed, courts were
dosed. One could be thrown in jail for the slightest thing, and quite frequently residents were not allowed to leave
thefr town. Life in the South would never be the same again, and the small town ofMurfreesboro, Tennessee, with
its surroimding countryside in Rutherford County is such an example.
Murfreesboro was founded on land given to the Lytle Family as land grants for service in the Revolutionary
War.^ By I860, the town of Muifeesboro had grown to 1,671 white people and 1,190 African-Americans. The
surrounding Rutherford county contained 14,743 white people and 13,174 African-Americans. Most of the citi-zens
were fermers, - with the average improved acreage of farms in Rutherford approximately 100 acres. The
average cash value of these farms was between $5,000 and $12,200.^ Murft-eesboro was beginning to have a
thriving business district, including a hardware store, a jewelry store, a book store, a livery stable, a carriage shop,
and even a distillery^ This community was growing, and the years between I860 and 1870 would have been
extremely profitable for its citizens if it had not been for the outbreak ofwar.
Rutherford County\^'as originally loyal to the Union. When the question ofsecession arose in Tennessee, the
county voted against it. One local newspaper, the Rutherford Telegraph, was published by a staunch Unionist, R.
S. Northcutt. In his newspaper, Mr. Northcutt stated, "Under the drcumstances that now exist, there is no cause
whatsoever for disunion, and he that favors it can be gailty ofnothing short oftreason to his country" Mr. Northcutt
ended up leaving Murfreesboro and going North at the outbreak of war. He became a brigadier general in the
Federal army.' The feelings ofthe people ofMurfreesboro and Rutherford County began to change as theywatched
four of the states bordering Tennessee leave the Union. By 12 April 1861, when the first shots were fired at Fort
Sumter, and when Lincoln ordered the blockade of all ports of seceded sutes, Murfreesboro and Rutherford
Countywere ready for secession. When the matter came to a vote inJune 1861, Rutherford County voted 2,392 for
secession with 73 against. Six of those who voted against secession were from Murfreesboro. Many men were
ready to leave immediately to join the Confederate Army Two companies of the 2nd (Bates) Tennessee Infantry
Regiment, formed 6 May 1861, were made up of men fixam Rutherford County Three companies of the 18th
Tennessee Infantry Regiment, organized 11 June 1861, were irom Rutherford County The colonel v^lio formed
this regiment wasJoseph B. Palmer, a fawyer bom in Murfreesboro. By the end of the war, had been promoted to
brigadier general.''
Although most of the citizens' sympathies fay wth the South, there were stiU people w+io were very much
opposed to secession and the formation ofthe Confederacy The pastor ofthe Baptist church in Murfieesboro, Dr.
James Madison Pendleton, \iolently opposed sfaven^ and strongly supported the Union. His outspokenness upset
Page 10
many members of the church who then refused to attend services. Some of his enemies even threatened to hang
him. By Oaober 1862, Dr. Pendleton decided that Muifeesboro was no longer safe for him, and traveling sepa-rately
from his wife, he left town.""John C. Spence, owner of the local hardware store, bitterly opposed secession,
however, his feelings began to change as the war continued.^
The excitement generated by the thought of war hit Murfreesboro immediately as men left to join the
Confederate Army John C. Spence stated, "The boys were vigerous [sic] and stout, anxious for a fight, feeling
satisfied they could whip five Yankees, unwilling to engage less than three at a time." Camp life, made them
courageous, defiant and devilish. He also wrote offriends and families making frequent visits to see the boys, "like
making trips to 'mecca'," bringing back 4 pieces of shell and cannonballs "to astonish the natives at home, as they
may never see such things in Rutherford." Howwrong Spence was when he wrote that the natives might never see
the war and "war not such a mighty bad thing after all. Not likely lasting over ninety days at most."'
The time had come when all had to help in the war effort and show patriotism, even if they were not
comfortable with the war. As word arrived in Murfi-eesboro that the Confederate Armywas viaorious at the battle
ofManassas, the citizens feft excited that their "boys" were there, "helping to make the 'Bull run' in Virginia"'&#176; They
formed a Home Guard, and in the fall of 1861 established a Confederate hospital, using Union University for this
purpose. The women in town formed a sewing society for the hospital, and others gathered things suitable for a
soldier's clothing. Crops were good that season, and the town felt confident that the war would not last long, but
things were about to change. The war would not end in three months."
In February 1862, General Grant and the Union Army were on the move and heading into Tennessee. On
February 5, with the use offour ironclads and three wooden gunboats. Grant landed 15,000 troops several miles
below Fort Henry 'While flooding and heavy rain slowed Grant and his troops, the Union flotilla fired 18 guns into
the fort. The Confederate troops could fire back with only nine guns. Realizing that the situation was hopeless, the
fort's commander sent his 2,500-man garrison to Fort Donelson, while he remained behind with one artillery
company as a delaying tactic against the gunboats. Before Grant's troops could airive, the fort's commander and
his few remaining troops surrendered. After his success at Fort Henry Grant moved on to Fort Donelson. Al-though
Fort Donelson did not fall as easily as Fort Henry the result was the same. Grant's troops captured Fort
Donelson. Within a few days the Confederate GeneralJohnston evacuated Nashville, making it the first Confeder-ate
state capital to fall. Much ofTennessee came under Union military control.'^
On 10 March 1862, the UnionArmy took formal possession ofMurfreesboro, lowering the Confederate flag
and replacing it with the Union flag. The soldiers then began repairing the roads and bridges leading back to
Nashville. The Union forces imposed martial law on the area, and began house-to-house searches to collert guns
and ammunition. The Union forces also arrested many citizens, and according toJohn C. Spence, arrested them
for some "pretended" cause. The military also stated that some residents were disloyal subjects ofthe United States
and demanded that they take an oath of allegiance. Those who could avoid taking the oath of allegiance did,
unless it was necessary in order for them to cany on their business.
With the arrival ofthe Federal troops, residents ofMurfreesboro and the outlying area started complaining of
soldiers stealing food from their gardens, smoke houses and poultry yards. There were also small skirmishes in the
country and whenever one would occur, the military government would arrest the nearest citizens and bring
them to town. Quite often these citizens were sent to NashviUe and put in the penitentiary When they were
released, they had to enter a bond and security for their future good condua.^' One example of this was written
ofin The Union Volunteer, a Union newspaper printed in Murfreesboro. The 20 May 1862, issue ofthe newspaper
stated.
On Saturday the 10th instant, some despicable villains [sic] attempted the assassination of
Col. Parkhurst and Capt. O. C. Rounds by firing upon them as they were riding along a
public street. The affair occasioned a large amount ofexcitement, in town and in camp, and
culminated on last Monday in the arrest of twelve citizens, known secessionists, to be held
as hostages for the good behavior of their fellow citizens . . . They were dispatched to
Nashville on the cars last Tuesday noon.
The outcome of this attempted assassination was another search of all homes and the confiscation of 200
firearms.'-'
Page 11
The citizens became afi^aid to speak out or voice their opinions. One clergyman "quietly omitted at Sunday
services the customary prayer for the Confederacy" and a week later, with numerous Federal soldiers in atten-dance,
"preached a sermon more in accordance with their feelings than of the Southern portion of his congrega-tion."'''
Not only were they afraid to speak in front of their neighbors, but also in front of blacks. A Murfreesboro
giii whose family hid some escaped, disguised rebel soldiers in June 1862, confided in her diary that she felt
obliged while in her slaves' presence to pretend that the soldiers were Yankees. In July 1862 she wrote, "I don't
trust the negroes now They have too much ofthe yankees about them, to suit me."'' Not long after this, the arrival
ofColonel Nathan Bedford Forrest and his cavalry excited the townspeople who hoped that things were going to
change.
During the early morning hours of 13 July 1862, Forrest and his men slipped into town, galloped up East
Main Street, and then one division veered offto attack the Union forces bivouacked at Oaklands, the Maney femily
mansion taken over by Colonel Duffield. The Confederate troops were pushed back, but not before seriously
wounding Colonel IXiffield. Two other Confederate battalions captured the entire Seventh Pennsylvania Regi-ment.
Colonel Forrest then approached the courthouse, where Union forces were deployed at the windows on
two floors. Confederate forces took the building, and other Union soldiers stationed around the town surren-dered.
Using several tricks to convince the Union army that he had a significant number of troops under his
command, Forrest convinced Colonel DufBeld to surrender, along with the Third Minnesota, which was holding
its position west of Murfireesboro. Forrest then destroyed all of the nontransportable stores and several miles of
the Nashville and Chattanooga Raifroad track. Then he and his cavalry unit, along with about 1,000 Union prison-ers
and several hundred wagons, moved out of town. Confederate oflBcers in Knoxville accepted the Union
prisoners and the captured supplies."'After the fighting was over, soldiers gathered the wounded and dead. They
prepared coflBns, and buried the dead, both Union and Confederate. The Union wounded were taken to the
hospital, but the Confederate woimded were placed in the homes of the citizens of the town. Four days later the
Union army returned to MuiiBieesboro. '"Their quiet return depressed the white residents ofthe town, but had the
opposite eflect on the blacks.
One Ohio oflScer traveling to Murfijcesboro with his regiment wnate,
at every plantation negroes cam [sic] flocking to the roadside to see us. They are the only
friends we find. They have heard ofthe abolition army the music, the banners, the glittering
arms. . . [and they] welcome us with extravagant manifestations ofjoy. They keep time to the
music with feet and hands and hurrah 'fior de ole flag and de Union,' sometimes following
us for miles.
When the troops and the excitement had passed, however, the slaves returned home, picked up their hoes,
and went back to the fields.'^The blacks ofthe town were realistic enough to know that things could change. Until
the war was over and one side viras the definite dinner, they were afi:aid to accept the fi^eedom the Union soldiers
were ofiering them. Some slaves did disappear, but most remained loyal to their masters until they were certain
that they were truly fi:&#171;e.
Over the next few months. Union troops would come and go in Murfireesboro, as would Confederate
troops. By December, Gen. Braxton Bragg and his army had established themselves outside Murifreesboro along
the Stones River. This was a period of social activity for the wealthier residents of the town. Mattie Ready, the
daughter of prominent citizen Charles Ready married Gen. John Hunt Morgan. Many of the Confederacy's mili-tary
elite attended the wedding, including Generals Braxton Bragg, John C. Breckinridge, B. J. Cheatham, WJ.
Hardee, and the "Fighting Bishop" Leonidas Polk, who performed the ceremony"A wedding was a rare occur-rence
by late 1862.
Rutherford County went fi-om 171 marriages in 1859 to only 47 marriages in 1862. This was a decrease of
approximately 264 percent. This trend downward continued in 1863 with only 40 marriages. With the uncertainty
ofwar, most couples delayed their marriages until after the end of the war. In 1865, the year the \^'ar ended, the
number of marriages increased to 1,739- Although many of these marriages are attributed to blacks who finally
had the opportunity to marry, there were still a significant number ofwhite couples who married. It was not until
1870 that the number ofweddings dropped back down to a level one would consider normal for the size of the
county-"
Page 12
The wedding ofMorgan and Ready and a grand ball on Christmas Eve, sponsored by the First Louisiana and
the Sixth Kentucky regiments, were the last social events in Murfreesboro for quite a while. On 3 1 December 1862,
the Army ofTennessee and the Army of the Cumberland began to fight one ofthe bloodiest battles of the CivilWar
at Stones River, a few miles outside Murfreesboro.
The Confederate troops struck first, catching the Union soldiers at breakfast. The fighting continued over
four da&gt;'S, and when it was done. General Rosecrans and the Union Army had narrovdy won the battle, with
General Bragg and his troops being forced to retreat. Bragg lost more than a third of his troops to death, wound-ing,
or capture. Rosecrans was almost as hard liit with 31 percent casualties.-' With Bragg's retreat, Union troops
occupied Murfreesboro for the rest of the war. Rosecrans's army surrounded the town for the next six months,
and converted churches, schools and other public buildings, as well as some homes, into hospitals for the wounded
ofboth armies. At this time, several leading citizens of the town fled the city with Bragg's army and Federal oflicers
took over their homes. The Union soldiers then built Fortress Rosecrans, which served as a supply depot for Union
operations in Tennessee and Georgia." With this last arrival ofUnion forces, life became even more difficult for the
local residents. Union soldiers traveled through the county stripping all the secessionists" farms and redistributing
the goods to Unionist femilies. Farmers did not know whether it was worth it to plant crops because soldiers
stripped the fields dean. Farm animals also disappeared. By 1864, a group of Rutherford Count}' residents de-scribed
their land that year as one "where crime of every grade unrebuked, runs riot at noonday where there is
neither safety for the person or protection for the property ofthe citizens. "-^ Both white and black citizens suffered
with food shortages. A Rutherford Countywoman wrote in 1864, "There simply was not enough food and fuel to
go around. Times hard and tight everything sells high . . . eatables very scarce and price high."-^ Residents and
soldiers pulled down fenceposts for fuel. Some wounded soldiers were forced to lie on fenceposts, as the hospi-tals
had run out of cots. Soldiers died and were buried every day but now there were no coffins Soldiers were
being buried in their blankets. The appearance of refugees made conditions even worse. John C. Spence was
exceedingly vocal in his opinion of these individuals when he wrote,
the tovwi was infested with a class of people fi-om different portions of the country known
as refuges, [sic] This class were generally below the negro, but like the negro making their
appearance, men and women half dad, with a half dozzen [sic] tow head children, having
small bundles of dothing about the house-hold, stock, a dog or two, to make up the family
Such making their appearance in town, telling a pitiful tale. Every thing they had was taken
fi-om them by the Rebels, often telling their house burned, they turned out ofdoors. These
like the negros, come to be fed, lie about and do nothing, claiming to be Union, and had
come for protection.
These refijgees, often found at the local Baptist church, received rations, cooked in the street, and slept on
the church floor. The town was also frustrated because other so-caUed "Union refugees " were in town to avoid
conscription. These individuals aaed as loyal informants to the Yankees, watching the local citizens and informing
the Yankee soldiers of anything they felt would help them. The informants would often be abusive to the local
citizens, and the local citizens would ignore them.-'
Life continued in this manner until the end of the war, when Murfi-eesboro had to deal with other problems,
such as the Ku Klux Klan and carpetbaggers. For the white citizens, dealing with newly-fi-ee blacks was also
considered a problem. Another serious situation for Murfreesboro, and indeed for the entire South, was worthless
Confederate money Former leaders of industry were now impoverished.-^'
Confederate soldiers slowly returned to Murfi-eesboro, finding conditions in the to^Ti extremely depressed.
They began arriving in July only to discover that Union soldiers or fi-eed slaves had torn down, burned, or taken
over many homes. Planting had not been done, and it was now too late to plant crops for that season. Those
buildings and homes that were still standing had been stripped dean of belongings. The difficult job of rebuilding
the South began in earnest.
Farmers began rebuilding their fences and trying to replace their farm animals with those sold by the Federal
Government at public auction. Cattle and hogs were still scarce, due to soldiers slaughtering many during their
occupation.-" In I860, Rutherford County had 10,308 horses, 4,348 mules and asses, 6,249 milch co'ws, 23,133
sheep and 64,877 swine. The value of all livestock in I860 was $2,1 15,432.00.-** Ten years later, and five years after
Page 13
the end of the war, Rutherford County was not able to equal these numbers. Rutherford County had approxi-mately
20 percent fewer horses, 20 percent fewer mules and asses, 6 percent fewer milch cows, 35 percent fewer
sheep and 94 percent fewer swine. The value of livestock in 1870 had decreased by $595,493.00.-''
The war also greatly affeaed the value of real estate and personal property Although the total number of
acres of improved land in Rutherford County was almost identical in I860 and 1870, the assessed value of real
estate was significantly diflFerent between I860 and 1870. In I860, the census valuation ofreal estate for the county
was $15,759,758.00. By 1870, that valuation of real estate had dropped to $6,020,57500, a decline of almost 10
million dollars and approximately 161 percent Even more extreme was the diJBference in the value of personal
property In I860, the valuation of personal property for Rutherford County was $17,835,603.00. By 1870, that
valuation of personal property had dropped to $1,055,297.00.
In comparing some individual families living in the Murfreesboro area, apparently life was so hard in Mur-fi-
eesboro that many families left the area. Of 148 families tracked from I860 to 1870, only 69 families, less than
one-haU^ were still in the county in 1870. Most ofthe families who left Murfreesboro were tenant farmers who had
no reason to stay in an area being destroyed by war. The 69 families who remained owned 642 sfaves, real estate
valued at $911,160.00, and 12 personal property valued at $1,019,767.00 in I860. By 1870 thefr real estate value
improved to $922,015.00, but their personal propertyvalue had decreased to $329,550. There were a few families
who greatly increased their real estate value during this 10-year period; however, 50 percent of the families
decreased the value of their real estate.
For many more years, Murfreesboro would continue to struggle with the trials of rebuilding homes, busi-nesses,
and the town. There would be the problems of carpetba^ers coming in to make money ofi'the devasta-tion
of war. The Kii Klux Klan created problems that had to be handled. There would be political problems for
years as the radicals and conservatK'es fought for the Negro vote and learned to live with disenfranchisement,
where many former Confederates were not allowed to vote. Their biggest problem, however, would be learning
to accept that their former slaves were their equals. In TheMonitor newspaper dated October 7, 1865 the editor
wrote,
Experience has proved that negroes are not equal to white men, and all attempts to place
them on a footing of social and political equality vvill fail, and will prove injurious to both
white and black.*"
One hundred years later there were still people in the South who were unwilling to accept Afi-ican-Americans
as their equals.
Although Rutherford County and the rest ofTennessee avoided many ofthe worst aspects ofthe Reconstruc-tion
period by being readmitted to the United States on July 24, 1866, it would be almost 35 years before the
people of Rutherford County would truly be able to say they were experiencing the type of growth they had
achieved during the prewar years.*' War is hell on all those who are involved in it, but it was especially so to those
"on the home front".
End Notes
1. Mabel Pittard, Rutherford County, edited by Robert E. Corlew (Memphis: Memphis State University Press,
1984), 28-29.
2. Population ofthe United States in I860 (Washington DC: Government Printing Office, 1866).
3. Steven YAsh, Middle Tennessee Society Transformed, 1860-1870: War and Peace in The Upper South, (Baton
Rouge: Louisiana State University Press, 1988) 6-7.
4. Mabel Pittard, Rutherford County, edited by Robert E. Corlew (Memphis: State University Press, 1984), 64.
5. ibid., 66.
Page 14
6. Tennesseans in the Civil War: a Military History ofConfederate and Union Units unth Available Rosters of
Personnel: (Nashville: Civil War Centennial Commission, 1964) 176, 212, 434.
7. Mabel Pittard, Rutherford Comity, edited by Robert E. Corlew, (Memphis: Memphis State Universit}' Press,
1984) 59.
8. John C. Spence, The Annals ofRutherford Cowity, vol. 2 (Murfreesboro: The Rutherford County Historical
Society, 1991) v.
9. ibid., 149.
10. John C. Spence, TljeAnnals ofRutherford County, vol. 2 (Murfreesboro: The Rutherford County Historical
Society 1991) 152.
11. ibid, 153-155.
12. James M. McPherson, Battle Cry ofFreedom - The Civil WarEra, (New\brk: Ballantine Books, 1989) 397-
403.
13. John C. Spence, The Annals ofRutherford County, vol. 2, (Murfreesboro: The Rutherford County Historical
Society 1991) 158-160.
13. The Union Volunteer (Murfreesboro). 20 May 1862.
14. Stephen V Ash, Middle Tennessee Society Transformed, 1860-1870: War andPeace in the Upper South,
(Baton Rouge: Louisiana State University Press, 1988) 102.
15. ibid., 127.
16. Mabel Pittard, Rutherford Count}', edited by Robert E. Corlew, (Memphis: Memphis State University Press,
1984) 68-72.
17. John C. Spence, Tlye Annals ofRutherford County, vol. 2, (Murfreesboro: The Rutherford County Historical
Society 1991) 177.
18. StephenV. Ash, Middle Tennessee Society Transformed 1860-1870: War andPeace in the Upper South,
(Baton Rouge: Louisiana State University Press) 106.
19. Mabel Pittard, Rutherford County, edited by Robert E. Corlew, (Memphis: Memphis State University Press,
1984) 72.
20. Edythe Johns Rucker XXIiitley, with an index by Gary Parks, Marriages ofRutherford County, Tennessee.
1804-1872 (Baltimore: Genealogical Publishing Company 1981) 149-240.
21. James M. McPherson, Battle Cry ofFreedom - The Civil WarEra, (New York: Ballantine Books, 1989) 580-
582.
22. Mabel Pittard, Rutherford County, edited by Robert E. Corlew, (Memphis: Memphis State University Press,
1984) 75-77.
Page 15
23. Steven V Ash, Mj&lt;^/e Tennessee Society Tran^ormed 1860-1870: War andPeace in The Upper South, (Baton
Rouge: Louisiana State University Press) 154, 163.
24. ibid., 92.
25. John C. Spence, TheAnnals ofRutherford County, vol. 2, (Murfreesboro: The Rutherford County Historical
Society 1991) 191-194.
26. Mabel Pittard, Rutherford County, edited by Robert E. Corlew, (Memphis: Memphis State University Press,
1984) 90.
27. John C. Spence, The Annals ofRutherford Cowtty, vol. 2, (Murfreesboro: The Rutherford County Historical
Society 1991) 252.
28. Agricultural Census oiThe United States in 1860 (V&gt;^hington D.C.: Government Printing OflBce, 1866.)
29. Agricultural Census oiThe United States in 1870 (Washington D.C.: Government Printing Ofifice, 1872.)
30. The Monitor (Murfreesboro). 7 Oaober 1865.
3 1
.
Mabel Pittard, Rutherford County, edited by Robert E. Corlew; (Memphis Memphis State University Press,
1984) 91.
Bibliography
A^icultural Census ofthe United States in 1860. \^^hington, D. C: U. S. Government
Printing Office, 1866.
Agricultural Census ofthe United States in 1870. "W^hington, D. C: U. S. Government
Printing Office, 1872.
Ash, StevenY.Middle Tennessee Society Transformed, 1870-1870: Mir andPeace in the
Upper South. Baton Rouge: Louisiana State Uni\'ersity Press, 1988.
McPherson, James M. Battle Cry ofFreedom The Civil War Era. NewYork: Ballantine
Books, 1989.
TheMonitor (Mmfreesboro). 7 October 1865.
Pittard, Mabel. Rutherford County, edited by Robert E. Coriew Memphis: Memphis State
University Press, 1984.
Population ofthe United States in 1860. Washington, D. C: U. S. Government Printing
Office, 1866.
Population ofthe United States in 1860. Washington, D. C: U. S. Government Printing
Office, 1872.
Spence, John C The Annals ofRutherford County, vol. 2. Murfreesboro: The Rutherford
County Historical Society 1991.
Page 16
Tennesseans in the Civil War: a Military History ofConfederate and Union Units with
Available Rosters ofPersonnel. Nashville: Civil War Centennial Commission, 1964.
The Union Volunteer (Murfreesboro). 20 May 1862.
Whitley EdytheJohns Buckex. Marriages ofRutherford County, Tennessee, 1804-1872, with an
index by Gary Parks. Baltimore: Genealogical Publishing Company 1981.
This article was written by Debbie Chatham in April 1996, as a research paper for a Civil Wkr History course she
was taking at Brigham Young University She sent a copy to Gilbert J. Backland, Chief of Park Operations at
Stones River National Battlefield here in Murfreesboro. He then forwarded a copy to our Historical Society
along with his recommendation for its publication in our armual journal. We are grateful to both of them for
making this article available to our Society
Page 17
</dc:description>
<dc:description>Describes the effects of the Civil War in Murfreesboro, Tennessee, including battle history, economic hardships, and race relations</dc:description>
<dc:subject>United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865; Stones River, Battle of, Murfreesboro, Tenn., 1862-1863; Murfreesboro (Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro;</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>8 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-01-25; mt2011-01-26</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication39ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/1</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>