<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Abstract of wills from Rutherford County, Tennessee</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Daniel, Susan G.</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 23</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1984</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1820-1829</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Abstract of Wills
from
Rutherford County, Tennessee
by
Susan G. Daniel
Publication No. 17 contains the abstracts of wills from Record Books 1 &amp; 2
Publication No. 19 contains the abstracts of wills from Record Books 3 &amp; 4
Publication No. 21 contains the abstracts of wills from Record Books 5 &amp; 6
67
ABSTRACT OF WILLS FROM RUTHERFORD CO., TN RECORD BOOKS 7
RB = Record Book DOW = Date of Will P = Proved in Court
R = Recorded in Record Book s = son/sons d = daughter/daughters
W = witness Ex = Executor/Executrix gs/gd = grandchildren
N = Named but relationship not given L = landowner mentioned
1. RB 7, p. 83-85 - Heartwell Bass, DOW: 26 Sept. 1826
P: Sept. 1827 "portion of my late Father and that portion of
his estate coming to me before the death of my mother..."
Wife: Sarah Bass d: Mary A. Bass [unmarried] "... a good
English education" Ex: Friend, John R. Mason of Limestone Co.,
AL and "my brother in law" Stith Richardson of Rutherford Co., TN
W: Wm. Ledbetter, Coleman Jackson
2. RB 7, p. 93 - Andrew McCaib, DOW: 25 May 1828
Wife: Polly McCaib "my children": Andrew, John, Nancy, Harvy,
Alexander, Julyan, Joseph, Iby McCaib d: Polly s: James
Exs: Wife and son, Andrew W: Jesse Stovall, John D. Stovall
3. RB 7, p. 93-94 - James Bell, DOW: 26 May 1828 R: 1828
s: Elisha Bell "a one hundred dollar note on Richard Burgess"
d: Sally Deloach, Elizabeth Bell, "rest of my daughters received
when the[y] left me", Marget Tennison, Mary Bell, Nancy Emeline
Bell d?: Ester Hollis s: William Bell "tract formerly
belonging to Anderson Coulter", Samuel Bell "tract .. .lying on
north side of the east fork of Stones River late purchased of
Nicholas Cornatzor . .also eleven acres and half which I bought of
James Cherry lying on the same side of the river", Lewis Bell
Wife: Susannah Bell W: Joseph Soape, Azia Coulter
4. RB 7, p. 95 - Ransom Hogwood, DOW: 9 Aug. 1827
"being sick" d: Martha Wife: Betsy "all my children"
"my sons" Exs: Capt. William Smith and Fredrick Batte
W: John Nance, William Batte
5. RB 7, p. 100-101 - Sarah Crutchfield, DOW: 5 May 1826
R: 1827 gs: Samuel Thomas Beavers gd: Harriet Gowen
d: Delila Beavers, Polly Gowen s: John Crutchfield, Charles
Crutchfield Exs: Abram Beavers, Robert Burnett W: Rb
.
Dreury, Robert Burnett, Thomas Neely, Andrew M. Johnson COD: 7
May 182 6 [changed bequest to grandson]
6. RB 7, p. 271-275 - William Lytle, DOW: 24 Nov. 1825
s: William Franklin Pitt "tract of land whereon I now live NE
corner of Col. Archibald Lytle' s large survey of 7200 acres
running W with the commissioners line 326 poles to Stones river
thence up the river to the mouth of Lytles Creek thence up said
Creek untill it intersects the eastern boundary line of Col John
Thompson's track thence with his E boundary line to the E corner
of said John Thompson's track and the NE corner of a tract owned
by David Williams thence S with said David Williams line to his SE
corner thence E to the eastern boundary of the original tract
68
thence N to the southern boundary of Murfreesboro thence W with
the southern boundary of the [?] to the SE corner thereof thence N
with the western boundary of said tract to the NW corner of the
range of lots laid off and sold by me lying along the north
boundary of said town thence east with the northern boundary of
said range of lots to the NE corner thereof thence S to the Bennet
Smith lot on the eastern boundary of Murfreesboro thence E to
Doctor James Maney line, thence N with his line to William Maneys
and David Dickensons corner thence W with the Commissioners line
to the beginning except two lots of one half acre each where the
Methodist Church stands which I have conveyed to John Lytle the
[?] William. . .also. . .Lot 53 in the town of Murfreesboro .. .brick
house stands in which Lock and Spence now have stores... Lot
65... Lot 83 where Sandlin now teaches school... Lot 76 where Robert
Smith has a stable... Lot 82 which three last lots was in the range
of lots which I sold north of Murfreesboro with the buildings
improvements..." "also... in Wilson County [TN] granted to me by
the state of North Carolina for my service right by grant bearing
date the 10th day of Sept. 1787 which was originally for 3840
acres... also in Wilson County... S of Cumberland river opposite the
town of Cairo... 176 acres being the place originally owned by
Richard Brewer .. .purchased at Sheriff's sale" "also to my son
William Franklin Pitt... I now own lying in what is called Western
district in Tennessee west of Tennessee river except one tract con-taining
same upwards of 900 acres which I give... to my Grandson
William Lytle Foster" Slaves to son, William Franklin Pitt:
Jesse, Perry, Frank, Hannah, Mill, Grace and her two children to
wit Gaston &amp; Delia George Eriser Watsten Mariah &amp; her child, Fanny
Adeled &amp; Phillis and increase d: Julia Margaret Nichols "land...
Rutherford County [TN] supposed to contain near 600 acres... NE
corner of a tract formerly owned by John M. Tilford thence S with
the eastern boundary of said tract to the NW corner of the tract
now owned by John Lytle thence E 2 56 poles to the E boundary line
of Archibald Lytles service right survey thence N with the E
boundary line of said Archibald Little survey so that by running a
due W line at staik the beginning thence a direct line to the
beginning. . .also. . .a house and lot in the town of Murfreesboro
known in the plan of said town by Lot 9 being the brick house and
lot on which John Watkins now lives..." Slaves to daughter,
Julia M. Nichols: Jim Henrietta, Silva, Flora Tom Matilda and
Minerve and. . .increase Slave to son, John Lytle: boy, Stephen
"now in possession of John M. Tilford... of my daughter Nancy
Tilford wife of John M. Tilford" "to my Grandson William Little
Foster a tract... west of Tennessee river containing a little
upwards 900 acres I am not able to describe" "to my sister in
law, Margaret Taylor .. .negro girl, Levina daughter of Mariah and
after the death of said Margaret Taylor I give... to my son William
F. P...." "to Elders of the Presbyterian Church in Murfrees-boro...
a lot of ground lying immediately N of the lot I give to
said Church upon which the Church is erected and extending N to
Bennett Smith's lot of ground being the piece of ground lying E of
the town of Murfreesboro between the eastern boundary of said town
and M. Murfrees field and Bennett Smith's lot and the Church
69
Lot..." Exs: my nephew, William Lytle of Nashville; my friends,
Samuel P. Black and Saml . Anderson W: Jont. Currin, David
Wendell
7. RB 7, p. 277 - Philadelphia Haynes, DOW: 15 Nov. 1828 P:
May term 1829 Brother: George Haynes "one negro boy named
Allen... also one bond on John Haynes for $300... one half of my
Legacy in the estate of John Haynes dec'd in the State of Virginia
Charlotte County" N: Eliza Ann Redmand daughter of George
Redmand and Keziah his wife "give. . .negro girl...Masy"
N: Martha Jane Redmand daughter of George Redmand and Keziah his
wife "give... negro boy named Neptune" N: Rebecca Susan
daughter of said George Redmand and Keziah his wife "negro boy
named Edmund" Exs: Creed T. Thompson and James Sanford W:
Richard Vaughan, John B. Niscan (?)
8. RB 7, p. 278 - James Taylor, DOW: 15 Oct. 1828 P: February
term 1829 "weak state of body" Wife: Deborah Taylor "to my
beloved Mother" EX: Adin Taylor W: Adin Taylor, Samuel Denny,
C. R. Davis
9. RB 7, p. 278-283 - James J. Maxwell, DOW: 18 Dec. 1828
P: January term 1828 [1829] "low state of health" Wife: Jane
"with a small exceptance to my father" Slaves to wife: Cait,
Wax, Ned, Harry, Zed, Hetty, Mariah &amp; her three children, Rose
Solomon and Peter "as my wife is in a pregnant situation"
"my brothers and sisters and the heirs of John Maxwell deed my
brother" d: Naomy L. Maxwell "tract of land I now own in
Bedford County containing 250 acres known by the name of the drake
tract... also eith negroes Sandy, big Fan, Sam Little Mary, George
Ann Harriett and Charles also the Clay bank filly and two cows and
calves that I got from Mary Brothers..." "to William A.
Maxwell one negro woman by the name of Mary" Brother: Robert
Maxwell "one negro girl...Feby" Brother: Jesse Maxwell "one
negro boy named Billy" Sister: Lidda Adcock "one negro man
named Tomy" Sister: Nancy Maxwell "one negro girl named
little Fan... then to Amanda Marchal daughter of a Elizabeth
Martial which child is said to be an illigitimate child of mine"
"my Father and mother have fifteen acres of land E of the Cave
Spring... the land between the widow Miller's line and the Creek
and up the creek to the fence of the old land. . .negroes Charles
and big Fan" "to William Maxwell and his wife Elizabeth
Maxwell..." Exs: Robert Miller and Stephen Linch Guardian:
Azariah Kimbro "for Naomy L. Maxwell and Catharine M. Gowan
Guardian for Wife: Robert Miller Guardian for unborn child:
Stephen Linch W: Isaac J. Miller, Wm. W. Miller
10. RB 7, p. 283-284 - Evander Mclver, DOW: 11 Sept. 1828 P:
November term 1828 Wife: Matilda C. Mclver "real estate in
Western district" d: Maria M. Mclver (not yet 14 years) "my
plantation &amp; tract of land known by the name of the Smith place"
"to my dear father I give all my books and papers ... " Brother:
John Mclver Ex: "friend and brother Daniel Graham" W: Henry
Couper, James Read
11. RB 7, p. 284-287 - Willson Yandell, DOW: 8 Nov. 1826 P:
January term 1828 s: Dr. Lunsford P. Yandell "education abroad
which has cost me much... negro man Burwell .. .negro girl,
Caroline..." d: Eliza Becton "when she married two negro woman
Nelly and China... a note on Littleton Williamson .. .with Tho.
Shearwood. . .negro girl for a nurse called Mary..." Wife:
Elizabeth "Betsy" Yandell "my children severally come of age or
marry" Exs: "brother, John Yandell ... son, Lunsford P. Yandell...
son in law, Dr. Fredrick E. Becton" W: William Wasson
COD dated 19 June 1827 - s: Henry Yandell and Burton Yandell
"receive a good English education" W: William Wasson, Edwin
Rogers
12. RB 7, p. 287-289 - Richardson Booker, DOW: 8 Mar. 1827
P: July term 1827 Wife: Nancy D. Booker Slaves to wife:
Lucy, Ralph and Henry "My four children": George R. 0.
Booker, Efford D. Booker, Sally A. Booker, William A. K. Booker
"my Executors restore to Jack Covirly (a free man loned to me)"
Exs: "Friends" Walter Keeble and William P. Booker W: John B.
Morris, John G. Keeble
13. RB 7, p. 289-290 - Eden Donnel (verbal will), DOW: 21 Oct.
1828 P: November term 1828 "in the presence of Jesse
Alexander and Mary (Polly) Weatherly" "my mother" "my wife"
"my children. . .my son have a liberal education and my daughter a
good English education"
14. RB 7, p. 290-293 - Thomas A. Oden, DOW: undated in his own
hand Sworn statements by Burwell Ganaway and Samuel Campbell
that he died 1 February 1827 Wife: Chloe Oden "eldest daughter
of Samuel Adams of Logan County, [KY] " "my children": Katharine,
John, Mary, Martha and Amanda Ann Oden [possibly other children,
see: sworn statement] "I give and bequeath to Lydia R. Oden
and her daughter Leah Oden, each of them one dollar."
15. RB 7, p. 294-295 - Mathew Whitfield, DOW: 6 Sept. 1823
P: April term 1827 Wife: Levina "three of my children":
Benjamin, Mary and Mathew Exs: Wife and son, William Whitfield
W: Hugh Robinson, Jane Robinson, Levina Robinson
16. RB 7, p. 295-298 - Moses Bellah, DOW: 2 Oct. 1827
P: August term 1828 Wife: Elizabeth s: John Bellah "tract
of land I own... 190 acres... not more than 170 in the lower end of
the tract whereon he lives .. .negroes , Jerry and Peter" d: Nancy
Gibson "negroes, Rit and Henry" s: Samuel Bellah "negroes,
Isaac and Ellison" gs : Moses Gibson gd: Elizabeth A. Bellah
(daughter of son, John) "my three children: John, Nancy and
Samuel" Exs: sons, John and Samuel W: James G. Henderson,
Ephraim L. Jetton, John W. Jetton COD dated 2 Oct. 1827: "two
old negroes, Harry &amp; Lucy
17. RB 7, p. 298-299 - Drury Vaughan, DOW: 28 Jan 1826
P: July term 1827 s: William B. Vaughan "land and plantation
where on I now live containing 230 acres... one negro man named
71
Squire and. . .Mager . . .one negro woman named Fanny also her four
children named Nancy, Nicea, Nido and Naomi" s: Peter Vaughan
"negro man named Thos . . . .Gabe . . .boy named Burwell" d: Betsy
Matthews "negro man named Henry... girl named Patsey"
d: Mildred Nelson "negro man named Squire, Jr.... woman named
Dilcea" d: Nancy Lenoir "negro man named Sam. . .woman named
Sillar" gs : John P. H. Lenoir "one negro boy named Guy"
gs : William H. Palmer "one negro woman named Bittey . . .girl named
Betsy" "my five children and William H. Palmer" Exs : William
B. Vaughan and Peter Vaughan W: Wilson Yandell, John Hoover
18. RB 7, p. 300-301 - Thomas Dickson, Senr., DOW: 24 Feb. 1822
P: January term 1828 Wife: Abegail Dickson s: Edwin Dickson
(probably the youngest), Asahel Dickson, John Dickson, William
Dickson, Thomas Dickson, James Dickson, Ezekiel Dickson, Alexander
Smith Dickson, Joseph Rankin Dickson d: Elizabeth Canon,
Aramanta Canon Exs: "my sons and trusty friends, John Dickson
and Thomas Dickson" W: Theophilus A. Cannon, Alfred Strapp,
James Finney
19. RB 7, p. 302 - Elizabeth Home, DOW: 5 June 1828
P: November term 1828 "being weak and feeble" Youngest
son: Simean Home [not yet 21 years] "negro woman Litta. . .thirty
and one half acres of land lying in the State of Georgia on
Commissioners Creek Jones County" Ex: son, Josiah Home
W: Daniel W. Bantan and Jesse Bloodworth
20. RB 7, p. 303 - William Tombes, DOW: undated P: August
term 1829 Wife: Susannah Tombes "one sorrel mare to be well
taken care by Emanuel Tombes" Ex: son, Emanuel Tombes
W: Lewellan Williams, James Sanford, William Nance
21. RB 7, p. 303-304 - Deborah Elliott, DOW: 5 March 1829
P: August term 1829 s: James, William, John, Alfred, Stockard
d: Eleanor, Catharine, Mary Grandchildren: Deborah and Jas
.
Elliott Stockard Ex: son, John Elliott W: John MacGowan,
Thos . MacGowan
22. RB 7, p. 305 - Polly Dickson, DOW: 11 January 1828
P: August term 1828 d: Lucinda Emaline Dickson "my four
boys": Jackson Carroll [Dickson], John Haywood [Dickson], Franklin
Holland [Dickson] and Thomas Samuel Smith Dickson Ex: Stephen
Roach W: Pierce G. Noland, Lewis Noland
23. RB 7, p. 306 - Hugh Shearwood, DOW: 26 Sept. 1827
P: August term 1829 "being weak in body" Wife and Executrix:
Nancy Ann W: Benjamin Ransom, Deveraux Jarratt
24. RB 7, p. 306-307 - Ann Butler, DOW: (verbal will - she died
24 Sept. 1828) P: November term 1828 "died without heirs of
her body" "all her property and estate being wholly personal in
the state of Tennessee she had in possession to be given to Eliza
M, wife of Major Andrew McKee" "...real or personal which she had
or might have in the state of Virginia .. .to .. .namesake Ann Hodge
of the state of Virginia" W: Thomas C. Hoskins, Jr.
72
25. RB 7, p. 307-308 - John Greer, DOW: 17 February 1826
P: January term 1828 "being of an old age" Wife: Debby Greer
d: Lotty "at the time of her removal to the western district"
d: Polly Crouse, Elizabeth s: Stephen Greer gd: Debbyan
Battle Ex: son, Nathan Greer W: Spill C. Haskins, M. M.
Haskins
26. RB 7, p. 308-312 - Daniel Elam, DOW: 1828 P: February term
1829 Wife: Jane/Jean Elam Slaves to wife: Isham, Mary,
Winney, Lucy and Winney's child, Lawson s: Edward Elam "a
negro man named Davy s: William Elam "a negro boy named Harry
s: John Elam "a negro boy named Ned" s: Robert Henry Elam
"a negro boy named Charles s: George Foster Elam "a negro boy
named Isaac d: Elizabeth Elam "two negroes named Jenny and
Sarrah" "I give to my four children Lewis Wills Elam, H.
Jetton, Emilly now Emilly Stuttings . .
.
" d: Nancy Molloy
gs: "Daniel Jetton a son of my daughter Henrietta Jetton"
Ex: son, Edward Elam W: David Wendell, Samuel Anderson
27. RB 7, p. 312-313 - George Taylor, DOW: 11 July 1827
P: October term 1827 Wife: Jerusha "my sons": William
Taylor, Eden Taylor, George Taylor, James Taylor and Leonard
Taylor d: Jane Taylor, Sally Taylor Exs : Adin [Eden?] Taylor,
wife, Jerush Taylor W: Andrew McKee, Nathaniel Greer, John C.
Hayse, Ephraim Farr
28. RB 7, p. 313-314 - Thomas Beasley, DOW: 18 June 1828
P: August term 1828 Wife: Sally Slaves to wife: Charles; big
Lucy; "old woman named Nancy" gs : "Thomas, son of my daughter,
Rebecca Coleman" s: William Trustees: Robert Williams and
Joseph Burnett Exs: son, William Beesley, Robert Williams and
Joseph Burnett W: Creed T. Thompson and Pleasant H. Mitchell
29. RB 7, p. 315-317 - William Foster, DOW: 24 August 1825
P: August term 1828 eldest s: James "135 acres lying in
Bedford County on the waters of Alexanders Creek... 80 acres of
land being the west end of a 200 acre tract lying in Rutherford
County and a part of a thousand acre tract that formerly belong to
David Vance..." second s: William "120 acres... east end of a
200 acre tract lying in Rutherford County on the waters of the
west fork of Stones River being a part of 1000 acres tract that
formerly belonged to David Vance..." youngest s: Guynn [sic]
"tract of land whereon I now live being 257 acres lying in
Rutherford County on the waters of the west fork of Stones
River... one negro boy named Frank" "to sons... James and William
one negro man named Bob" "my four daughters": Anna, Polly,
Nancy and Betsey "profits from my four negroes, Peggy, Buck,
Hannah and Addison" Exs: two sons, James and William and son in
law, George W. Mallard W: Thornton Mallard, George Clanton, J.
Y. Mallard
30. RB 7, p. 317-319 - William Rowtan, DOW: 22 October 1827
P: August term 1829 Wife: Mary Rowtan "my eight children":
John Rowtan, Polly Wood, Owney Walls, Elizabeth Hancock, William
73
D. Rowtan, Rody Wrather, Nancy Hunt, Peyton Rowtan Exs : wife,
John Rowtan, William D. Rowtan, Peyton Rowtan W: Wm. W. Searcy,
Beverly Randolph, william Smith, John Smith
31. RB 7, p. 319-320 - William Sledd, DOW: 7 October 1827
P: October term 1827 "all property .. .sold my negro girl Mariah
and her two girl children Sally and Eliza excepted. . .back to
Virginia under care of friends... my children also" Children:
John M. Sledd and Elizabeth Sledd EX: Isaac H. Overall
W: George L. Lachland, Richard Thomas
32. RB 7, p. 321-322 - John Doak, Senr . , DOW: 17 May 1824
P: November term 1828 "in a bad state of health" Wife: Peggy
Doak d: Uppy, Elizabeth, Patsey, Mait, Isabella, Polly s:
Joseph Doak "Nancy Weatherly is to have a dress of calico or
bombazette, Robert Doak's daughter Nancy a dress of calico or
bombazett . . . son, Joseph Doak's daughter..." Slaves: Harry and
his wife, Leah to have freedom Exs: Samuel P. Black, Abner
Weatherly W: Robert Shepherd, William Shepherd
33. RB 7, p. 322-324 - John Thomas, DOW: 8 October 1828
P: November term 1828 s: Peter James Thomas "tract of land
whereon I now live purchased of Jesse Reed... negro boy Charles
about seven years..." s: John Hartwell Thomas d: "heirs of
deceased daughter Mildred Tyus Vaughan[,] William and George"
s: Lewis Green Thomas d: Rebecca s: Theos . W. Thomas
d: Ann d: Susannah d: Mary H. Harris "negroes Holland and
Andrson. ..sold" "the following named children (to wit) Lewis
G. Thomas, Rebecca Loyd, Theophilus W. Thomas, Ann W. Sutton,
Susannah R. Lowe, .. .heirs of Mary H. Harris, as I expressly wish
that John H. Thomas and the aforesaid heirs William and George of
my daughter deed. Mildred Vaughan have no more of my estate..."
Exs: Leonard F. Sims, Theophilus W. Thomas W: Daniel Keith,
Lemuel Reed, Jesse Wood
34. RB 7, p. 324-326 - Martha Penn , DOW: 23 January 1828
P: May term 1828 "being in a low state of health" s: William
Penn d: Franky Banks, Ruth Finny, Martha Wallise s: George
Penn d: Luvenea Penn "one black woman slave called Sally and
all the children she may have from this date..." "equally
divided between William Penn, the children of Betsey Banks one
share for she is dead, Joseph Penn, Franky Banks, Ruth Finny,
Martha Wallese, Josiah Penn, Jacob Penn and George Penn"
"whereas I have two small children to be sold... my children may
purchase..." Ex: "trusty friend William Penn" W: Theos. A.
Canon, Ota Cantrell, Thomas Dickson
35. RB 7, p. 326-328 - James Mathes, DOW: 30 June 1826
P: 2 April 1829 "a true full and complete copy from the record in
Jefferson County, Kentucky [apparently P: July 1827]" Wife:
Marium Mathes "ten children": Sarah Huchison, Caty Mathes,
William T. Mathes, Rebecca Mathes, Anna O. Mathes, Polly Mathes,
Rachel Mathes, Heller Mathes, James H. Mathes, Betsey L. Mathes
Ex: wife W: Henry Mathes, Thomas Hutchison
74
36. RB 7, p. 329-330 - Mary Randolph, DOW: 17 March 1827
P: July term 1827 "my two grandchildren": Peter Randolph, Sarah
Randolph "heirs of my son, Peyton Randolph dec'd." Slaves to the
grandchildren: Hilsey and her child, Fanny "heirs of my son
Beverly Randolph": Mary Elizabeth Randolph, Lucy Randolph, Sally
Randolph s: Harrison Randolph Ex: son, Beverly Randolph
W: John McGregor, John C. Harris
37. RB 7, p. 333-334 - Anthony Clark, DOW: 30 June 1826
P: October term 1827 "being weak in body" Wife: Susanna
Clark s: William Clark, Walter Clark, John Clark, James Clark,
Robert Clark, Anthony Clark d: Franky Clark, Sarah Clark
sons in law: William McClure, James Glenn, Robert Bigham, John
Stephenson Exs : John Clark, James Clark, Robert Clark, Anthony
Clark W: John Clark, Robert Bigham
38. RB 7, p. 334-336 - James Johnson, DOW: 20 January 1826
P: May term 1828 Wife: Arebelow Johnson Slaves to wife:
Randal and his wife, Tenor and her child Adalina s: Joseph
M. Johnson, "seven beloved daughters": Sintha Ann Johnson, Rhue
Johnson, Nancy Johnson, Sarrey Rolland/Rowland [husband, Benjamin
Rolland], Susanna Gavott, Rebecca Whight [White], Mildred Foster
Slaves: Timothy, Cith, Edy, Darks and Alfred Exs: James
Higgins, Larkin Johnson, Senr . W: George Her, Isaac I. Miller
39. RB 7, p. 336-337 - Nancy Wood, DOW: 8 November 1824
P: August term 1828 "negro boy George is to choose his master
among my legatees" Legatees: Lucy Staton, Juriah Dixon, Samuel
Wood, Keziah Dixon, William Wood, James Wood, Nancy Dixon,
Elizabeth Gutridge W: Eli Bell, James W. Dickson, Lucinda N.
Dickson, Lucretia K. Dickson
40. RB 7, p. 337-338 - Eleanor McKnight, DOW: 3 May 1825
P: January term 1828 Slave: Rachel "to be sold" d: Jane,
Abby, Peggy s: James, David, John M. Sister: Jane Andrew
Exs: sons, James and John M. W: Alexander Orr, Benjamin Knox
41. RB 7, p. 338-341 - Catharine Morton, DOW: 22 September 1826
P: July term 1827 gd: Mary Ann A. Anthony, Elizabeth V. Gooch,
Martha M. Morton, Cicelia H. Morton, Catharine Lytle, Nancy Lytle
gs : Joseph Morton, William Lytle, Curator of negroes:
Th. S. Anthony s: Joseph Morton, dec'd d: Tabitha Lytle,
dec'd "four children now alive": Judith Edwards, Sarah Searcy,
James Morton, Lucinda Newsome [husband, William Newsome] Slaves:
girl, Julia to Mary Anthony; girl, Liney to Elizabeth Gooch; boy,
Wilson to Grandson Joseph Morton; girl, Sylvia in estate of son,
Joseph Morton dec'd; boy, Silman to grandson William Lytle; girl,
Rachael to granddaughter Catharine Lytle Ex: son, James
Morton and son in law, William W. Searcy W: Jacob Payne, James M.
Smith
42. RB 7, p. 341-343 - Thomas Norman, DOW: 28 July 1827
P: January term 1828 Ex: brother, James D. Norman Wife:
Martha B. Norman "negro girl, Charity" "until my oldest child
75
comes of age" Slaves to be hired out: man, Isaac; boy, Lewis
"a piece of land I bought of Daniel Taylor" W: James Jones,
William B. Jones, Little Berry Crook
43. RB 7, p. 343-346 - John Bowman, DOW: 12 Sept. 1824
P: February term 1829 Wife: Margaret Bowman s: Alexander
Bowman "tract of land on which we live containing as I suppose
about 350 acres..." d: Peggy Bowman "tract .. .beginning at the
bank of the Creek direct opposite the fence dividing the meadow
from the field which Thomas Dunn rents this year running with that
fence a SE direction .. .to the corner of the new ground next Henry
Threats... 85 acres" d: Prisulla Freeman, Betsey Ransom
Exs : Wife; son, Alexander Bowman; George Morris W: Ezekiel
Hazlet, Whitcoat Tarpley, B. F. Hazlet
44. RB 7, p. 347-348 - William Rawlings, DOW: 18 November 1826
P: August term 1827 Wife: Sally Rawlings Children: Polly
Fulks, Nancy Rawlings, Matthias H. Rawlings, Piety Rawling, John
W. Rawlings, Joseph A. Rawlings, Neffee Rawlings, Lewis J.
Rawlings, Fanny Rawlings, William W. Rawlings Exs: Wife and
Martin Hoover, Senr. W: John Rawlings, George Uselton Jr.,
Christopher Hoover
45. RB 7, p. 348-349 - Benjamin McFarlin, DOW: 6 December 1828
P: February term 1829 Wife: Elizabeth L. McFarlin Slaves to
wife: man, Alfred; girl, Nelly "my five children": Robert B.
McFarlin, Sarah N. McFarlin, Eliza Y. McFarlin, Benjamin P.
McFarlin, Elizabeth McFarlin Exs: Wife and John C. Berry
W: Joseph Youree, James D. Hamilton
46. RB 7, p. 349-350 - John Sage, dec ' d of Williamson County,
TN, DOW: 22 May 1826 P: October term 1827 "being old and
infirm" Wife: Polly Sage s: Jesse Sage, Thomas Sage, Travis
Sage Exs: Wife and son, Jesse Sage W: Meriman Landrum,
T. C. Nash
76
RB 7, p. 36-37
This Indenture made the twenty second day of May in the year
of our Lord eighteen hundred and twenty eight
Witnesseth, that Thomas Doughlass, son of Bodham Doughlass, aged
seventeen years ten months and twenty two days, by and with the
consent of the said Bodham Doughlass his father hath, of his own
free and voluntary will paced and bound himself apprentice to
James McDowel of the county of Rutherford and state of Tennessee,
carpenter and house joiner, to leave the arts, trad[e]s, mystery
and occupation of a carpenter and house joiner; which he the said
James McDowel now usith, and with him as an apprentice to dwell,
continue an serve from the day of the date here[in] untill he has
completed his twenty first year during all which time the said
apprentice his master well and faithfully shall serve, his [ ]
keep his lawful commands gladly do and obey; hurt to his master he
shall not do nor wilfully suffer it to be done by others, but of
the same to the utmost of his power, shall forthwith give notice
to his said master; the goods of his said master he shall not
wast[e] or lend to any without his consents; at unlawful games he
shall not play, nor frequent taverns, doggerys, or houses of ill
fame, he shall not commit fornication or contract matrimony nor
shall he at any time depart or absent himself from this said
master service without leave; but in all things as a good and
faithful apprintice shall demean himself toward his said master
during said term. And his said master for and in consideration of
the sum of one dollar to him in the said trade of a carpenter and
house joiner, which he now usith with all things thereunto
belonging, shall and will teach and instruct, or cause to be
taught and instructed af [t]er the best way and allow unto his said
apprintice, meat, drink, washing, lodging and apparel both linen
and woollen, and all other things fit and necessary for such an
apprintice, during the term aforesaid. And the said master at the
end and expiration will give unto his said apprintice a sum of
[ ] and a suit of clothes extra of decent homespun (Janes)
In witness whereof the said parties have hereunto set their hands
and affixed their seals the date first above written.
Thomas 1
^. Doughlass (SEAL)
James McDowell (SEAL)
Bodham [ 1
f .Doughlass (SEAL) mark) ^
TEST
A Fowler Done by consent,
77
</dc:description>
<dc:description>Abstracts of wills from Rutherford County record book 7, housed at the Rutherford County Archives</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.); Wills; Rutherford County (Tenn.) -- Archival resources; Public records</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>11 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-01; mt2011-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication23ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/36</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>