<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Hardeman's mill</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hoover, Walter K.</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 5</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1974</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>18th century; 19th century; 20th century;</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>SJ^
Hardeman's Mill - This replica was reproduced by Walter
King Hoover from random descriptions of the mill house.
It is positioned at the exact original site. Inset shows
the Constant Hardeman grave marker. Abandoned Hardeman
cemetery lies on Stewart's (Stuart's) Creek near the
southeast limits of Smyrna, Tennessee.
Gregory Mills - A sales transaction form of Hardeman Mill's
^
HARDEMAN'S MILL
BY
Walter K. Hoover - 1974
An abandoned cemetery with a few legible grave markers,
a mill house foundation, and a large stone mill dam are all
that remain of a once important family, and a prosperous
business. The mill is located on Stuarts Creek at the
southeast city limits of Smyrna, Tennessee, and was earlier
known as the Hardeman's Mill, later Black's Mill, and still
later as Gregory's Mill.
This area today is owned by the Percy Priest Lake
Recreation Department and is maintained as a public picnic
area accessible by paved streets and a parking area. It is
a lovely spot where one could relax, examine the old dam and
water race, contemplate the efforts, hopes and successes of
the many citizens and slaves who passed this way in years
gone by. Perhaps you could better approach your tomorrows
if you could for a few hours sit in the cool damp shade of
this historic site and contemplate the rushing waters that
eternally hasten by. My father took me there when I was a
boy, and I have returned often.
Constantine (1) Hardeman (2) was born January 3, 1778,
in North Carolina, and died August 27, 1850, at his home
(1) I find Hardeman, Hardiman, Hardaman.
(2) I find Constentine, Constantine, Constant, Constance
and various spellings.
-55-
adjacent to this site (see map) . Constant was the fifth
child of Thomas Hardeman and Mary Perkins. He married Sarah
Marr in 1799. Sarah died in 1823 leaving twelve children:
Thomas, John Marr, George W. , Constant Hardin, Lent, Susan
Perkins, Agatha Ann, William Miller, Mary B. , Sarah E.,
Matilda, and Cornelia. To a second marriage between 1827 -
1829 to Mary (no last name) born 1778, died Feb. 22, 1859,
there was one daughter, Levinia, born 1830, died 1848. Con-stentine,
his second wife Mary, and Levinia are buried in
the family plot east of the mill site across the creek and
above the bluff on the property now owned by J. L. Ross.
Evidently most of these children went on westward to
Texas, Arkansas, etc.
Not finding any early Hardeman land records in Ruther-ford
County, because there was no Rutherford County at that
time, I go to Davidson County Archives and find several land
records of Thomas Hardeman. I find an indenture dated
August 25, 1800, showing that Constant bought from his father,
Thomas, for two thousand pounds (English money) , three hundred
acres and six hundred acres, both described in the same
indenture, in what was then Davidson County, Tennessee, on
the waters of Stuarts Creek.
This land was part of a twelve hundred acre grant to
Mose Shelby, a North Carolina grant before Tennessee was
created.
The Town of Jefferson was by 1800 an organized community,
and Constant no doubt came in through that community.
-56-
Constant, a citizen of some prominence and a resident of
Davidson County, in the year 1803 at age twenty-five years,
did in his own handwriting, draw up the petition which
requested the Legislature to create Rutherford County. This
new county was to be drawn from parts of Davidson and William-son
Counties. Many of the residents of this area are evidenced
by the two hundred and fifty six signatures on the petition,
Hardeman being the first to sign. Thus Rutherford County
began, by Act of the Tennessee General Assembly, October 25,
1803.
There were one thousand one hundred and forty-one heads
of families in the new county as indicated by the 1810 census.
These were mostly scattered along the Stuarts Creak area (1)
and the Stone's River area centered around Jefferson and
Stuartsboro, there being no Murfreesboro at this time. (2)
I cannot determine any exact date when Mr. Hardeman
built his mill or his home, but rather suspect that by 1820
the mill was in operation and his permanent home was built.
I find many documents of land sales and purchases, division
of large land holdings to new settlers and children; many
slave purchases and sales; of lots that Hardeman bought in
the Town of Jefferson; and of the railroad coming through
his property in 1850.
(1) Stewarts Creek - Early maps and documents show Stuarts
Creek rather than Stewarts. I cannot determine why it
was named either.
(2) See Publication No. 3, Rutherford County History Society,
1974.
-57-
Census records show in the Hardeman household:
1810 - 3 males under ten years; 1 male 26-45 years (himself)
2 females under ten years; 1 female 26-45 (wife)
seven slaves
1820 - 2 males under ten years; 2 males 10-15; 1 male
26-45
3 females under ten years; 2 females 10-15 years
1 female 26-45
12 slaves
1840 - 1 male 50-60; 1 male 60-70; 1 female 10-15
2 females 20-30; 1 female 50-60
Male slaves under ten, two 10-20, three 24-36, one
over 36
Female slaves, one under 10, one 55-100, agricul-tural
slaves three, two slaves in manufacturing (Mill)
1850 - Constentine Hardeman - age 72 - Farmer 12,000 -
Real Estate Born in N. C.
Mary Hardeman - age 61 Born in N. C.
Susanah Morton - age 58 Born in N. C.
James Morton - age 29 - Farmer Born in TN.
Charles Sneed - age 19 - Student Born in Ala.
Robert Morgan - age 18 - Student Born in TN.
Gilbert Morgan - age 15 - Student Born in TN.
The Hardeman house sat on the east side of Stuarts Creek
and south of the mill, which was across the creek. A bridge
about forty yards above the dam provided access to the mill and
was the public road at that time (see map) . This home was a
-58-
large frame house about sixty by forty feet, two and one-half
stories. A staircase in the entrance hall ran to the third
floor ballroom. Four large rooms were on the first floor and
two on the second floor, each off the center hall and staircase.
There was a small covered front porch. The lumber in the house
was hand- sawed and hewn. The house corners were each hewn to
turn an angle of 90&#176;, from one log and each ran to the third
floor. Braces to these corners were mortised and pegged.
Rafters were red cedar poles hewn on one side. Sheeting was
boards of log width, with shingles of red cedar. Chimneys at
each end were built inside the house, with closets on each
side of the fireplace downstairs. Walls were plastered through-out.
Floor beams were 12 x 15 inch timber and floor joists
were 4 x 12 inches, all hewn by hand.
This house description came to me from Ira McDonald whose
father, John McDonald, owned the property in 1910. Ira helped
to take it down. The lumber from the house was bought by Ben
Dodd. His son, Horace Dodd, relates to me that he helped to
take it down and haul it, with wagon and team, to the Ben Dodd
home, which is still standing as the James Gambill place today,
off the Rocky Fork Road. This Hardeman House was also the Joe
Black Home in the 1870 's - 1880' s.
Early grist water powered mills in the area were Buchanan's
or Jone's Mill, on Stone's River at the northern edge of
Rutherford County. Crosthwait ' s , or the Davis Mill, was at
Jefferson on the east fork of Stone's River as were Brown's
Mill at Lascassas, the old mill at Readyville and Hall's Hill
-59-
Mill at Halls Hill. On the west fork of Stone's River were
Ward's Mill at Florence, Ransom's Mill at Murfreesboro and
Elam's Mill on Elam Road. Sanders on McKennon was on Spring
Creek - Alsup Mill on Fall Creek a mile east of Silver Hill -
a mill I cannot name is said to have been just south of old 41
highway on Overall Creek. An old map shows a mill on Stuarts
Creek, just south of today's 1-24 on the old Dillon place.
Maps show a mill at Walter Hill near the Thomas C. Black place,
and where the present dam is. I do not know which was the
earliest.
*
Hardeman's Mill and the Readyville Mill were different
in that all the above mills were built adjacent to the dams
which diverted the water directly into the power wheel or
turbine. The Hardeman and Readyville Mill dams diverted the
water into a canal or flume which ran several hundred yards
to the mill house and flowed back into the river or creek on
the opposite side of the mill house as it meandered back.*
Mr. Hardeman no doubt having great need for a source of
power to accomplish the needs of his rural society, daily
studied the possibilities of Stuarts Creek in his area, and
selected the site where the proper fall and curve of the creek
made this possible.
Water power is the power obtained from water by its fall
from a higher to a lower level. The real agent is gravity,
the fluid itself being the agent through which the action of
gravity is transmitted to the prime mover. So the dam, the
canal and water gates were arranged to control the water flow
or fall.
*See photos on page 75
-60-
Mr. Hardeman having determined these possibilities, set
about, with slave labor, to quarry the huge stones for erection
of the dam and mill house foundation. Excavation for the dam
footings and digging the canal to the mill house all had to be
done with mules and hand labor. Bricks for the mill house had
to be moulded and burnt. As the mill house went up, timbers
had to be taken from the forest and sawed into proper size
and length, a project that could not be accomplished in a
few days.
The dam is 75 to 100 feet long, 10 to 12 feet high and
3 to 4 feet thick. The park service of Percy Priest did some
repair about 1972 to the dam. Over the years the water had
washed out the dirt banks at each end.*
The mill house was two-story brick above a rock foundation
about 54 feet long and 4 feet wide. Under the first floor
which was some four feet above ground level, the rock foundation
had open arch-ways for ventilation and access and was some six
feet space under the floor where the main shaft and belt wheels
sent the power into the mill from the water turbine or wheel.*
The water wheel was not the old picturesque wooden wheel
with water spilling over the top. This was a turbine type, with
the wheel laying down flat and the power shaft in a vertical
position. The fins or veins in the wheel part were arranged
so that water spilling in from the top center, propelled the
sloping fins or blades as it passed and spilt out around the
bottom outside. This was a very popular type power turbine in
*See photos on page 75
-61-
America about 1810. (See water wheels in any good encyclopedia.)
It is reported that "the first water powered mill in Rutherford
County was built in 1799, (then Davidson County.) By 1830,
there were twenty mills in operation."
The machinery in the mill house elevated the grain to
the upper floors and as it came back down through the milling
machinery, which were grinders, sifters, and blowers, the
flour or meal was caught in large bins, from which it was
dispensed to customers or sacked for storage. It would be
interesting to know where Constant got this machinery and water
wheel and how it was transported, over what routes, into this
undeveloped area.
Many years passed, joy and prosperity reigned, a family
was raised and educated as the farm and mill operation continued.
Hardeman evidently operated his mill until the time of his
death on August 27, 1850.
Ira McDonald remembers having been told by his elders,
who were neighbors of Hardeman, that the creek flooded, and that
Mr. Hardeman went to the stable to get his horse out of the
rising waters, where the horse kicked him and killed him. The
tale of a flood in August, a dry month, makes me a little
skeptical, but is handed on as folk history.
A list of articles sold at the residence of the late
Constent Hardeman on the 26th day of September, 1850, shows
that his farm and mill operation was vast. This list included
horse drawn farm tools, augers, planes, axes, frows, saws,
harness, gears, shafts, shingles, guns, saddles, cooking
-62-
utensils, buggies (one fine carriage sold to Charles Lewis
Davis, father of hero Sam Davis, for $452.00), horses, mules,
hogs, cows, sheep, corn, flax wheel, wagons, chains, ten
slaves, and his investment in the Nashville-Murfreesboro and
Shelbyville Turn-pike Company. Since he was 72 years old,
which indicates that he may have been retired at this time,
it is believed he rented the grist mill and saw mill for at
least two months prior to the sale, or they could have been
rented since his death.
The neighbors and friends who attended and bought at
this sale are listed and include many that are lost in the
history of the area: Reed, Ward, Ralston, Farris, Ballentine,
Bennett, Wade, Sneed , Cash, Goodman, Hicks, Haynes, etc.
John C. Gooch, father of Col. John S. Gooch of Civil War fame,
was the administrator of this estate. However, he died before
the estate was settled, and the court appointed Mr. Charles
Lewis Davis to take his place.
In 1882 on November 1, John M. Hardeman of Texas conveyed
to his brother, Thomas Hardeman of Mississippi, all of his
interest in their father's estate including the sale of the
land in Rutherford County where-on he resided at the time of
his death and which was sold for partition, by decree of Circuit
Court of Rutherford County. Also included was his undivided
interest in that tract of land which was assigned as dower to
Mary Hardeman, his widow. This was the home place during her
lifetime. John Marr also transferred his interest in land
in Obion and Weakley Counties at this time to Thomas. This
-63-
document does not indicate why the interest was transferred,
but does show that the mill was sold or partitioned at Constant's
death.
Mary Hardeman, widow, having died in February of 1859,
nine years after Constant and still holding the home place
as dower, is believed to have sold to Charles Lewis Davis the
mill site; because, in April of 1859, Charles L. Davis sold
the mill site containing seven and one-third acres to Mr. or
Dr. Thomas C. Black, father of Dr. Sam P. Black and Joe M.
Black. The record book of this date was destroyed by the
Federal soldiers while they were occupying the court house at
Murfreesboro. It is possible that Charles Lewis Davis deeded
this to Thomas C. Black as administrator and never owned it.
Thomas C. Black owned and operated the mill during the
Civil War, or War Between The States as the U.D.C. prefers to
call it. This was a hectic period for any business operation
in Middle Tennessee. Likely the operation was closed down
and all supplies, machinery, tools, livestock and grain, even
labor, including slaves, were consumed or disrupted by the
Federal soldiers. Occupation of the business by the Federals
could have been possible.
It appears that the war had its effects because in 1869,
four years after the war, a partnership was formed between Dr.
Thomas C. Black and his son. Dr. Sam P. Black, for the purpose
of rebuilding and operating the mill.
Dr. Samuel Pitt Black was born April 10, 1838, near
Walter Hill. At an early age he began the study of medicine
-64-
with his father, Dr. Thomas C. Black. Sam graduated from the
Medical College of Nashville and practiced with his father. He
was appointed Assistant Surgeon of the Nashville Hospital where
he did not remain long because of a tubercular condition. He
served in the 4th Tennessee Cavalry Company as a private and
was transferred to the Medical Department of East Tennessee.
Dr. Sam's name appears in the minutes of the Smyrna Medical
Society in 1876. He was a brother to Miss Kate Black Ward.
He was a Democrat and a Mason. Sam was never married.
The part of the property on which the old Hardeman house
was located, eleven and three-quarter acres, was evidently
bought by Henry Gregory and S. H. Miller from the Hardeman
Estate sometime after Mary's death in 1859 (books destroyed).
This is assumed to be true for in 1873 the two above owners
sold that tract of land to Dr. Thomas C. and his son, Sam P.
Black.
This partnership continued until the death of Dr. Thomas
Black in May of 1878, when by decree of the Chancery Court,
that Dr. Sam P. Black, by paying to the estate of his father
the sum of two thousand cash and four thousand seven hundred
dollars, claims and assuming the liabilities of the mill
business, became the sole owner.
I cannot determine why in 1882 John N. Hardeman of Texas
still had an interest in his father's homeplace. However, we
must keep in mind that this was the period of the Civil War,
military government, and reconstruction.
-65-
Sam P. Black ran the mill, after having acquired his
father's interest in 1878, until 1885-88. Here I insert a letter
from Tom G. Sanders dated October, 1974, from his home in
Sarasota, Florida, a response to my request for information.
Mr. Tom is 96 years old, was born and raised at Stewartsboro
and Smyrna. He was a man of great character.
"I was born February 9, 1878, and when I say
something happened which I was a certain age you
can figure what year it was.
When I was 5 or 6 years old (1883-1884) his
boiler exploded. He had a steam engine to supple-ment
the water power when the creek was low. My
father wanted to see the extent of the damage,
and took me with him the morning after the
explosion. Dr. Sam was at the mill when we arrived
and took us around the mill showing us the damage.
He remarked that it just blew it to atoms. It
was the first time I had ever heard the word
"atom," and it made an impression on me that
lasted. The mill was quite a wreck and it was
reported that after the explosion someone went
into the mill to find Dr. Sam, and they said he
was scrambling out from under a pile of bricks
and other trash and was heard to say; Heckl it will
kill all my cats. He had some five cats that he kept
in the mill to keep down rats and mice.
-66-
A stub of the boiler went across the road
and killed a young mule or cow at No. 7. I think
he had' a negro to fire the boiler and I don't
remember whether he was killed or not, if he
was killed he was the only one.
I don't think that Dr. Sam made any effort to
remodel the mill, and it stood a wreck until W. H.
(Bud) Gregory bought it which was about the time
I was 13 or 16 years old." (1891-1894)
When I was 18 to 21 years old (1896-1899) I
visited Miss M. B. McDonald pretty regularly on
Sunday nights, and usually rode horseback and
went by Blacks Mill and forded the creek at the
mill at No. 6., so I know the bridge at No. 8 was
not built or the road opened from No. 3 to No. 4
until after 1900. I don't know when it was opened
for I was away from the Smyrna community. There
was a path and foot bridge, or log, across the
creek at No. 3. The path was from No. 4 to No. 3
and people used it when the creek was up or when
they were walking and had no way to ford the creek.
The Mill was located at No. 1 and the mill race at
No. 2. This is all from memory and of course is
liable to be far from right, so excuse the errors."
"T. G. Sanders"
W. H. (Bud) Gregory did not buy the mill at this time as
Tom Sanders suggested, because I find a deed dated September 5,
-67-
1888, showing that Sam P. Black, now owning all of the Hardeman
mills and home property, and the mill still not repaired after
the boiler explosion, sold the mill and real estate to his
brother, Joe M. Black, W. E. Ward and C. A. Ward for $2,500.00,
payable in three notes at 6% interest. This consisted of
three tracts: (1) the Hardeman Mill site 7 3/4 acres; (2)
the Hardeman home place, 11 3/4 acres,, bought from Henry
Gregory and S. H. Miller in 1873; and (3) 2 1/3 acres which
was a part of the old Academy Lot. The Academy Lot was an
effort of the Cumberland Presbyterian Church to establish a female
academy and church in 1837, a story in itself.
In 1892 after Joe Black, Will Ward, and Charley Ward
had repaired and operated the mill four years, they sold it
to W. E. Ward for $3,000.00, still the three tracts, about 21
acres.
Now in 18 94, Henry Gregory conveyed to W. E. Ward a
nearby tract of 94 acres. Ward paid Henry Gregory $2,000.00 and
conveyed the Black Mill property as part payment for the 94
acres. So Henry Gregory got the mill in a land trade January 1,
1895, the day of possession.
One year later on January 1, 1896, W. H. Gregory and wife,
Ida S. Gregory, sold the mill property to a LeRoy McKennon.
The same year, October 27, 1896, for a $500.00 profit he sold
the mill back to Gregory. I cannot determine who LeRoy McKennon
was or why he deeded it back to Gregory a few months later.
Mr. Preston Ford remembers that the old water race was repaired
by the Gregorys in 1906-1907 by walling it up with stone.
-68-
Mr. Robert Heath, son of Henry Heath, born on the Mayfield
Ross place near the present Enon Springs Road Bridge, remembers
that Mr. Henry Heath and his brother, Cal Heath, worked for
Charley Ward, both mill and farm vrark. Henry ran the mill by
day and Cal by night. One night Cal had indulged in a portion
of strong drink, and while his glee was abounding, he put a cat
on the fan-sifter while in operation. The cats unsuccessful
attempt to liberate itself, disrupted the operation sending
clouds of dust and ground wheat all over the place. Mr. Henry
Heath, suspecting trouble, had gone back to the mill to check
things and told of this incident.
The Gregory's ceased to operate the mill around 1916-1^17,
the time of the First World War. Mr. W. C. Fvans was the last
miller to operate the mill. At this time no flour was made, only
meal. One reason for this is that R. 0. Davis and his brother,
Sam B. Davis, had built a large modern steam operated flour
mill on the railroad in Smyrna, where they produced the famous
"Sarah Davis" flour in great quantity. The steam engine had
been moved to the Sam Hager Cotton Gin in Smyrna. The old
boiler was used for a road culvert near the Oscar Mann place
on Enon Springs Road. Evans came into Smyrna and operated a
gasoline powered mill at Hager and Second Street.
Al and Watt Gregory evidently operated the mill at inter-vals.
Dodson and Overton Gregory used the mill house for a
broom factory. They had raised a large quantity of broom corn
on the bottom land at the east end of what is now Rice Circle
in Smyrna
.
-69-
An attempt to salvage the brick in the old mill house
ended in the destruction of it. The bricks after some 100 years
were not good enough to be reused. Eventually the old machinery
was hauled away for scrap iron. The vertical shaft turbine or
water wheel was removed and taken to Wards' nill for use there.
On the 12th day of September, 1919, W. H. Gregory and
wife, Ida, sold about 13 acres for $2,000.00 (reserving the mill
and road leading to it) to James T. Seward. At this time the
old Sam Black house was still standing, and Seward had just
married, evidently planning this for his home. James Seward
was a brother to our Walter Seward. James, however, never
moved there and about a year later sold the tract to B. S.
Flowers for a $500.00 profit on November 17, 1'520. On the same
day that Seward sold to Flowers, B. S. Flowers resold for a
$250.00 profit, the 13 acres, to Lon S. Mayfield. Marginal
notation on this deed to Mayfield shows that Mayfield 's title
was cleared in 1929 by J. R. Miller, who was connected with
the Smyrna Bank and Trust Company at that time.
Mayfield being a carpenter by trade, tore down the old
Sam Black house and built a modern frame house. He lived there
with his family until his death. This house was moved across
Enon Springs Road and is there today. This moving occurred
when Percy Priest bought- the- rioperty for a park in 1967 or 1968
Lon Mayfield having lived here for about twenty years and
his children married and gone, turned the property over to his
son, Bovel Mayfield. The deed stipulated that Bovel would pay
a small loan to a Sam Hall and that Mr. and Mrs. Lon Mayfield,
-70-
now in their retiring years, would retain possession until the
death of survivor.
In 1934, w. H. Gregory died intestate and his widow passed
away in 1951. This left H. W. Gregory and Ida Bell Paxton
their only heirs-at-law. They sold the old mill site contain-ing
about 8 acres on Stuarts Creek in 1951, thus bringing back
together the old mill site of 29 acres, to Bovel Mayfield who
held the surviving land on December 3, 1951. (Price not evi-denced)
On the 5th day of May, 1967, Bovel Mayfield and wife.
Bertha, along with Mrs. Girtie Mayfield, widow, holding dower,
sold the property to the Government. The improvements
untimately cost the Government $35,000.00.
So the dreams of Constant Hardeman and all his efforts
after about 100 years lay idle and in ruin, washed and eroded
by flood waters and the elements, viewed only by an occasional
fisherman, or local boys, who in the summer, swam and played
in the nude. Cattle and stock grazed here peacefully making
paths through the undergrowth.
So the evolvement of man, and the elements that surround
us, have brought this scene along the Stuarts Creek almost
back to where it was when Mr. Hardeman first viewed it in his
youth.
The rains continue, the soft winds still blow, the forest
and fields still react to the seasons that follow, each in their
appointed order. Man continues to pursue his physical and mone-tary
needs, as society rushes on to the moon and the universe
beyond
.
-71-
All these people have added much to our today. It is
my hope that, when we are written about, the efforts and
pursuits of our lives will be listed as charity - not as
sounding brass.
-72-
SOURCES EXAMINED
1. Davidson County Tennessee - indenture Aug. 25, 1800.
2. Walter K. Hoover historical collection.
3. Memories of local citizens.
4. On site observations.
5. Rutherford County Tennessee - Deed Book H, Page 422
6. " " " - Appointed Administrator-list
of sale
7. " " " - Deed Book 5, Page 681
8. " " " - Deed Book 19, Page 121
9. " " " - Deed Book 30, Page 220
10. " " " - Deed Book 33, Page 280
11. " " " - Deed Book 35, Page 225
12. " " " - Deed Book 37, Pages 144
and 584
13. " " " - Deed Book 62, Page 473
14. " " " - Deed Book 64, Page 304
15. " " " - Deed Book 69, Page 21
16. " " " - Deed Book 87, Page 79
17. " " " - Deed Book 109, Page 597
18. " " " - Deed Book 175, Page 142
19. T. G. Sanders, Sarasota, Florida
&#8226;73-
MEMORIES OF HARDEMAN'S MILL
Preston Ford
"I have seen rats running running over the
roof of the old mill house, so I am sure that
the roof was not tin."
"There were grain bins under the first floor
for storage."
"The steam engine power belt went into the mill,
to the water wheel shaft, through the archway in
the foundation at the west rear of the mill house
(see photo) . At one time there was a shed that
housed the boiler and steam engine, adjacent to
this archway."
Allen W. Gooch
"As I recall it, on the east side of the dam
there was a concrete pillow, on the top of which was
inscribed, (My Fishing Place - W. H. Gregory)
.
This was evidently finger marks made by Mr. Gregory,
at a time of repair of the dam."
"I recall when I was a boy 11 or 12, of going
to this mill with Mr. John F. Tucker, who took a
turn of corn to exchange for meal."
"I went hunting on the mill property with John B.
Hager, and just west of the mill house we found a
covey of quail in a canebreak. This was the first
time I ever saw cane growing wild."
Walter King Hoover
"There are two other graves in the Hardeman
cemetery that have not been mentioned. (1) Peterfield J,
January, Oct. 16, 1836; May 5, 1846. (2) Constant P.
son of M. H. and M. J. January; Feb. 15, 1848, Age
11 mo. , 25 days.
"
"There are two mill stones in the front walk
at the Henry Davis home at Stuarts Creek, and old
Nashville-Murfreesboro Turnpike, the Davis and Gregory
families were related, which leads me to believe that
these came from this old mill."
-74-
S. Richmond Sanders
"About 1919-20 local boys having a zesty
interest in the old swimming hole, wore permitted
by Dodson Gregory, to move a large round millstone
(a topstone) from the Gregory Mill site to "Calls"
or Kale's Hole. This favorite swimming place is some
100 yards below the Sam Davis Home on the Stewart's
Creek. The seclusion, smooth rock bottom, and about
four feet of water provided a delightful place for
naked boys."
"Jimmie Moore, Leslie and Clarence Wright,
Robert Dayton, John Richmond Jones, and I loaded
the stone on an old four cylinder Chevrolet skeeter
which brought it into Smyrna, where the old skeeter
quit running. Not to be outdone, they hitched
up a buggie, transferred the stone and by going
through the fields, got it to Kale's Hole. They
placed it on a wooden platform just above the water
level, where it remained for thirty or forty years."
"Hundreds of local boys, over several generations,
will recall the joy of their youth, when they recall
Kale's Hole and jumping off this stone."
"The stone was moved by Mrs. Media Sinnott to
102 Crescent Ave. in Smyrna, and is there in the
back door terrace today."
"Leroy McKennon was the miller at Jones Mill,
before going to Sanders Mill or McKennons Mill on
Spring Creek. He also was the McKennon who bought
the Gregory's Mill."
The mill dam - It has changed little since its
construction by Hardeman. The top of the dam
once was topped by a log to prevent debris from
chipping away the top layer of stone. The canal
angled away to the right.
Water flowing through a central gate to the right
was channeled into the canal to the mill house.
In the foreground was once the dirt creek bank.
This canal connected the mill house with the dam.
Once walled with stone, the man-made channel still
carries water past the mill house site.
Remains of the mill house foundation - The power
shaft from the turbine-type wheel went into the
mill through the stone archway. The wheel was
positioned in the channel at the bottom of the
picture.</dc:description>
<dc:description>A history of Hardeman's Mill on Stuart's Creek</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Cemeteries; Family history; Rutherford County (Tenn.) -- History</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>mills; family businesses</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Smyrna</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>45 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-15</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication05ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/164</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>