<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Young man John Esten Miles went West</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Sloan, Gene H.</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 16</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1981</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>19th century; 20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>YOUNG MAN JOHN ESTEN MILES WENT WEST
-Gene H. Sloan
Among the distinguished Murfreesboro natives vdio played prominent
roles in the "Winning of the West" was John Esten Miles, who filled many
inqjortant political and business leadership posts in the early history of
New Mexico,
His distinguished career included the Govemor of New Mexico, United
States Congressman, Chairman of the State Democratic party, newspaper
publisher, merchant, farmer and rancher.
He was bom in Murfreesboro July 28, l880, the son of James Manuel
and Frances Elizabeth (Howland) Miles. His father, Louis Miles was bom
In McMinnville in 1861, and is believed to be a descendant of Thomas Miles,
a lieutenant in the Revolutionary War. His mother was the daughter of John
and Mary Howland. According to family tradition the Howland 's were descendants
of a Mayflower family.
Like his parents, John E. Miles received formal education in Tennessee
Public Schools. His father was a trainer of horses and thus acquainted with
farm work. From an early age John Esten always maintained an interest in
horses and farming.
In 1901 he went to Bonham, Texas to work on a ranch of an uncle. In
1905 he moved to Magnum, Oklahoma, and the following year to Quay County,
New Mexico. There, forty miles from Tucumcari, he continued in farming and
ranching. In 1916 he made his first political race and was defeated for
county commissioner. He bou^t a general store at Endee, in Quay County.
This he sold in 1920 after a successful race for county assessor.
Miles first went to Sante Fe in 1921 to serve as secretary to the
State Tax Coninission, a position he filled until 1925. In 1927, he
35
John E. Miles
established a tax agency in the city, but in 1931 he rejoined the Tax
Commission as secretary, this tine serving imtil 1938* In January 193U
he also served as chief of the Internal Revenue Office at Albuquerque,
resigning In July of that year. At that time he was elected Chairman of
the New Mexico State Democratic Central Committee.
In 1927-28 Miles became interested in the newspaper business and for
a tine published the New Mexico Democrat in Sante Fe and the Independent
in Las Vegas.
In 1935 he returned to the office of secretary to the State Tax
Commission, holding that position until he was elected Governor in 1938.
His term ran \mtil 19U2 and in 19U2-Uli he was chairman of the New Mexico
Public Service Commission. In 19hh Miles was elected Commissioner of
Public Lands, serving in that office from 19U5 until 19U8. In the general
election of that year he was successful in his candidacy for the United
States Congress. After two years in Washington he returned to Sante Fe in
1950 but was defeated in his bid for Governor.
In 1951 he went to Denver, Colorado, to serve as enforcement officer
for the Office of Price Administration. When he returned to Sante Fe in 1952
he entered with a son, J. Wade Miles, in the management of the Chrysler
agency. In 1953 he disposed of his interest in that business to become
president of the New Mexico Book Depository, Inc. This corporation serves
as the center for the distribution of text books used in the public schools of
New Mexico.
During his career Governor Miles had been active in the Kiwanis Club
and the Lodge of Benevolent and Protective Order of Elks, He had been
reared in the Christian church.
Miles made his last atteirpt for state office in 1956, at the age of
71. He was defeated when he ran for Commissioner of Public lands.
A contenporary of Miles describes him as weighing about I8U pounds,
36
with black hair steaked with grey over twinkling blue eyas. "Throu^out
hla lifetiiBS he prided himself on loyalty to the Democratic party and on
his word being his bond." His slowness to act steraned from careful con-sideration.
He was a gifted 'conqjromiser,* according to a longtime friend.
Senator Manviel Sanchez.
In reviewing his own contibutions Governor Miles took pride in pro-viding
others a better education than he had. He saw that teachers salaries
were raised, that teacher pension laws were enacted, that the school bus
system was standardized and laid the ground work for permanent registration
laws and the stabilizing of state financing.
Miles was married to Susie C. Wade in June 1906 by Judge Jarrett Todd
in Magnum, Oklahoma. They were the parents of tan children. A summary of
the work of these children was supplied by the family to the Rutherford
County Historical Society. Two sets of twins, Floyd Preston and Lloyd
Weston, and Franklin Everett and Jessie Evelyn were bom to the family.
Jessie Evelyn Miles died in infancy. Seven children reached maturity,
"THE FtHn.Y OF GOVERNOR JOHN E. MILES"
1. Peggy Frances (TheLna) Henrie, 111 Columbia Dr. S. E., Albuquerque,
New Mexico, 87106. Bom August 8, 1909, has two children, eight
grand -children, one great-granddaughter.
Retired: Worked 23 years with Atomic Energy Commission and the
Sandia (Corporation) Laboratories.
2. Mildred Lorraine Adams, 5803 W. State Ave., Glendale, Arizona 8$301.
Bom August 16, 1911, has two children, five grandchildren, and one
great-grandson, &#187; r. j
Retired: worked 25 years with the Glendale Schools Health &amp; Food
System.
3. J. Wade Esten Miles, Rte 2, 521B #75, LaVillitas de Santa Fe, Santa
Fe, New Mexico, 87501. Bom June 19, 191i4, has three children and
five grandchildren.
Employed: Real Estate, formerly Ranched, owned Miles Motors,
Public Land Commlsaicn and associated with N. M, Horse-racing.
U. Annie Margurite, born June 19, 1916. Deceased.
37
5. Floyd Preston Milosj, 2U00 Baylor So., Roawell, New Mexico, 88201
Bom Aug\i3t 29, 1919, has two cWidren
Employed: Captain and District Commander, New Mexico State Police,
Roswell, H. M.
6. Lloyd Weston Miles, Box J488, Springer, New Mexico, 877U7.
Bom August 29, 1919, has two children and one granddaughter.
Presently emp. Police Chief of Springer, formerly enployed New
Mexico State Police, City Police Judge, Farmington, N, M,,
New Mexico State Bureau of Revenue, Security Officer for
Santa Fe, Downs Race Track., Retired Lt. Col. DSA &amp;
National Guard.
7. MaJ. Oen. Franklin Erorett Miles, P. 0, Box 506l, Santa Fe, N. M.
87501, bom Jan U, 1923, has six children and four grandchildren.
Enployed. Adjutant General, State of New Mexico, Head of New
Mexico National Guard.
8. Jessie Evelyn Miles, bom Jan. h, 1923. Deceased.
9. Edna Irene Green. P. 0. Box 373, Columbia Falls, Montana. Bom
July 7, 1925, has three children. Formerly enqjloyed as Court Reporter,
New Mexico Supreme Court.
10. Baby boy, birth and decease dates not available.
George Hooper (1866-1910) married the widow of James Monroe Miles in
November 189$. Following his death Mrs. Hooper and her dau^ters lived in
Murfreesboro before moving to Oklahoma City "about 1916."
The two daughters were Wattie Dean (Mrs. W. D. Carter) and Colera
(Mrs. H. A. Gardner) of Bartlesville, Oklahoma. Mrs. Carter had two daughters
Mrs. Reed Barker and Mrs. V. C. Mcintosh, both of whom live in Chicago. Mrs.
Gardner has one dau^ter Mrs. Fred Dimit of Tulsa, Oklahoma.
In addition to his two sisters Governor Miles had one brother, Clarence
Miles, who is deceased.
Mrs. Hooper later married E. H, Eakle in Oklahoma, whom she survived.
According to Mrs. Laurelee Helgason (wife of a grandson) James Monroe
Miles, Sr., had emigrated to Texas where he married Pearl Chancellor in 1889.
There were eight children bom to this union.
Mrs. Helgason lists these children of Monroe and Pearl Chancellor
Miles as Fred Fellow, Melviji, Louise, Olive Mae (Bobbye), James Marvin,
38
Monroe J Pearl and &#163;arl. Monroe Miles &gt; Jr. is a minister in Houston^ Texas.
Earl Miles and Mrs. Bobbye Miles Fisher live in the Shreveport, La. area,
Fred Fellow and Melvin Miles both died in Infancy.
Mrs. Helgascn states that Monroe Miles always maintained his interest
in horses and that he lived in Springfield, Mo. following his seccxid
marriage from 1899 until 1908. He later lived in Shreveport, Louisiana
xintll moving to Vicksburg, Mississippi about 1919 or 1920, In Vicksburg,
he and hie wife ran an "eating place." Monroe Miles died in Vicksburg,
Mississippi June 7, 1933.
Governor Miles made his last visit to Murfreesboro in 19^1 to attend
the graveside services for his mother. Dr. Ernest Hooper, a nephew of
George Hooper, recalls Governor Miles, acconpanied by his two sisters coming
to Evergreen Cemetery under highway patrol escort. Mrs. Frances Elizabeth
Howland Miles Cooper was buried on the Ed Hooper lot in Evergreen cemetery.
Her funeral services had been conducted in the House of Representatives at
the State Capitol in Sante Fe, New Mexico.
Mrs. Peggy Frances (Thelma) Henrie, eldest child of Governor Miles,
wrote that, "in spite of his great love for his adopted State he was always
proud of being from Tennessee."
Miles continued his interest in the problems of agriculture after his
retirement from public life. He owned and operated a farm near Santa Cruz
where he grew chili beans, com, alfalfa and maintained an orchard.
In a biographical sketch in the Historical Encyclopedia of New Mexico
a concluding paragraph reads; "As Democratic State Chairman, as Governor of
the State, as an individual, John Miles built a reputation for integrity,
fairness and honesty that reflects great credit not only on the man but
upon the State he so ably represented."
Governor Miles died in a rest home in Sante Fe, New Mexico, October
10, 1971. Final rites wore conducted in tiie rotunda of the New Mexico State
Capitol. 39
The Sante Fe Journal recorded the life and times of Governor Miles
in langhthy, profusely illustrated news stories, features and editorials.
His eulogy was given by the Reverend Monroe Miles, a half-brother and pastor
of the Albuquerque d Sombra Christian Church.
"His life is a reminder to us of some of his ideas and ideals,"
declared the Rev. Monroe Miles, Jr. in paying tribute to his half-brother.
"The most characteristic salient of his life was his loyalty. . .loyalty to
his party, loyalty to his state....loyalty to his citizenship, his friends
and to his family."
There were two pages of tributes to the Governor in the newspaper on
the day of his funeral. "Most of those remaining who fought the political
wars of 20 and 30 years ago, both with him and against him, were present
to pay their last respects."
Among the statements of these great, near great and representatives
of the citizenship of New Mexico were such succinct but revealing assertions
ass
"He was a man who didn't know how to quit."
"Re was a man you could trust."
"He was a man who was kind and gentle."
"At 21 he was a homesteader at Eiidee and spent five years in inproving
his land."
"I've known hira since I was a boy and he would stop by to visit with
my dad. Hs had that touch with the common man."
"Although he was on the other side of the political fence, I considered
hira a close personal friend. He was a great American"&#8212;Governor
Tott Bolack
"Governor Miles was the last of the old breed. He was a man of great
integrity and strong, very pronounced views"&#8212;Former Governor David Cargo.
The editorial of the Sante Fe Journal on the day of his burial read
in part;
New Mexico laid her Mr. Democrat to his final rest
Monday. Funeral rites for John E. Miles were sijTq)le.
Uo
For the final tins auch a aenrlee was held In the
rotCBoda of the State Capitol with both State and
National flaga at half naat.
QraTeslde serTlces were as siupla at Meotorlal
Oardens, the casket was carried by his grandaons
between an honor guard of National Quardamen)
State Police and the New Haxico Mounted Batrol.
His fallow citizens prqperly bestowed on him the
honorary title:
"Mr. Democrat of New MaxLcol"
Authors Notet
Where was the residence of Jamea Monroe (or Manuel) and Francea
Elizabeth Miles? One aource Indicates that James Monroe Milea was a horae
trainer and that the family lived near the old fair grounds.
Children and half-sisters of Governor Miles have been helpful in
sullying information about Governor Miles and his descendants but inform-ation
concerning the 17 years of John Eston Milea life in Murfreesboro
appears vague and often contradictory. Wb are especially indebted to Mrs.
Peggy Frances Ifenria, oldest daughter of Governor Miles, Mrs. H, A. Gardner,
a surviving sister, Dr. Ernest Hooper, a member of the MTSU faculty, Mrs,
Baxter Hobgood, Mra. Lauralee Helgason of Louisiana, the New Mexico State
Historical Sociely, Murray Miles, information director of the Tennessee
Farm Bureau, and the editor of the Historical Encyclopedia of New Mexico.
la
Governor John Esten Miles
Mrs. H.A. Gardner
Miles' Sister
Mrs. W.D. Carter
Miles' Sister
These two sisters were also born in Murfreesboro
But emigrated to Oklahoma "about 191 6".
</dc:description>
<dc:description>The story of John Esten Miles, a Rutherford county native who became heavily involved in politics in New Mexico, serving as governor and chair of the State Democratic Party, among other positions</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Miles, John E; Rutherford County (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>New Mexico</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>17 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-15;mt2011-02-17</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication16ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/53</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>