<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>A country store (1912 - 1914)</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Mankin, Jack</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 11</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1978</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1910-1919</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>36
A COUNTRY STORE (1912-1914)
(Selection from Jack R. Mankin's "Autobiography" written for his
children in which he describes his brother's store and offers
some nostalgic impressions of life as he remembers it in the
surrounding communities of Mankinville and Dilton.)
When I was a child--some eight or nine years old&#8212;Papa
bought a country store for my older brother Hendrick to run,
Ilendrick being at that time about nineteen or twenty years old.
The store was located on the Manchester Pike at the corner of the
little country road that wound and meandered through the farms,
across the branch, on to cross Lytle Creek and finally to end in
the Bradyville Pike at Dilton. On its winding way it passed the
2
"Walker place," where I was born, and by Cousin Oscar's,
although his house set far back from it and was anproached by a
long driveway. At the road end of his driveway was one of the
most fascinating inventions my young mind had ever seen, namely,
a "patent gate." It had long arms sticking out on each side of
two tall posts and dangling from the arms were ropes that could
be reached from the buggy seat. When one of these ropes was
pulled, wonder of wonders, the gate opened! Aladdin's magic lamp
was no more improbable or exciting! After driving through and
stopping, the other rope was pulled and the magic gate closed
itself. If children in this day are thrilled and awed by rockets
and computers, I was just as thrilled and awed by this wonderful
"*" Dr. John Benton Mankin (1860-1926).
Mr. Oscar Mankin.
gate. The road passed by Frank Overall's place and the church
where I grew up before losing its identity in the Bradyville Pike.
But back to the store. It was a long, narrow, and high
wooden building sitting up on cut stone piers. It had a porch,
or unloading dock, all the way across the front. The front door
was in the center of the platform porch, and a large, heavily
shuttered window was on each side of the door. I think the width
of the store was twelve feet and the length was fifty feet. It
was divided into one large room at the front, which was the store ,.
proper, and a smaller room on the rear for storage. Somewhat
more than halfway back in the store proper was a large, pot-bellied,
coal-burning stove. This was the social center of the
farming community during the winter, that is, for the older male
members. The women were too busy with their interminable work to
have any time for socializing. That would have to wait until
Sundays, the summer "protracted meeting," and possibly hoq-killing
time.
The store, facing the west, was about one-fourth mile north
of where we lived--an easy walk, but a dark, cold one on a winter
night. Of course there were no street lights&#8212;there was no
electricity nearer than "town," which was about four and one-half
miles away.
As one entered, he viewed the store from a central aisle.
There were shelves up to the ceiling on both the north and south
The Dilton Church of Christ.
2 Murf reesboro, Tennessee.
38
walls, running about two-thirds of the way back. In front of the
shelves were two heavy wooden counters on each side of the center
aisle with a narrow passageway between them and between them and
the shelves. The counters were hollow where heavier items, such
as buckets of candy, were stored under them. Part of the tops of
the counters were taken up v;ith glass show cases displaying the
most enticing articles and those that were particularly attractive
which might stimulate sticky hands and lead to shoplifting. By
and large, however, the people were honest and did not need to be
deterred from stealing by glass cases. Inside the cases were
cookies placed there maybe with some intent of keeping flies off
of them, but more likely to keep samplers' hands off, for sampling
and eating on the spot was not stealing. Most of the residents of
the community did not bother much about flies at this time. The
cases displayed pocket knives, fishhooks and lines, spools of
thread, chewing gum (not Long Tom, it was out of date by this
time), papers of pins, needles and thimbles, rick-^ack, bias tape,
boss balls, and other small items. Of course, V7hat excited my
child's mind was the candy, the chewing gum, and cookies.
No description of this country store would be complete if it
omitted the "punch board," a gambling device that was quasi-legal
at that time though later banned by law. It consisted of a board
about twelve by sixteen inches with holes about one-half inch
apart each direction, making a total of about 660 holes. Each
A small ball of darning thread that came in a ball about
an inch in diameter in black, white and brown.
39
hole had a roll of paper in it with a number on it. Both sides of
the board were then covered over with a colored paper. On the
front side, as I remember, there v;ere three colors across the
board. One was for 25C punches, the next and larger for 10&lt;?
punches, and the third and largest for 5&lt;;: punches. Below it in a
show case were the enticing prizes which could be won. The top
prize was a handsome watch perhaps worth $25 at retail price.
It was of course among the numbers in the 25&lt;: punches. I can't
remember all the prizes, but they were attractive and desirable
and calculated to whet the greed of the prospective customer.
The merchant had a chart, which he kept out of sight, of all the
winning numbers. Of course, like all gambling devices, they were
rigged to pay a profit to the "house."
When anyone came in the store, particularly males, this
attractive display of wanted items and the punch board on top of
the show case fairly shouted, "Stop. Try your luck. You might
win a watch or a ten dollar bill." This subtle salesmanship along
with an inherent desire to get something for almost nothing broke
down the resistance of many and they would lay dov;n their money,
the merchant would give them the punch for punching out the
numbered paper, and then the agonizing decision as to which one
(within the chosen and paid for color) to punch haa to be made.
After due deliberation, the punch was made, the paper unrolled
and the number checked against the merchant's list. If it was a
winner, the prize was taken out of the shov/case and delivered at
once. If it was a loser, as most of them were, he had a lesson
in economics to the effect that wealth comes from productive work
40
and not from chance. At the same time the merchant had reinforced
his knowledge that, as Barnum said, "A sucker is born every
second.
"
Eventually all the punches were gone, all the prizes given
out, and the merchant pocketed a neat profit from a minimum of
effort and risk.
Most of the merchants in these country stores had a trace
of New England skepticism about them and this led them to "ring"
the coins they received in payment. At this time all the coins
above the nickel were made of silver and if dropped on a hard
surface would give out a clear, bell-like tone. The proprietor
on receiving a silver coin, particularly a dollar or half dollar,
would flip the coin in the air and let it fall on the hard coun-ter
top. If it "rang true," which most of them did, he accepted
it and put it in the cash drawer; if it didn't "ring true," he
refused to accept it. This was a routine thing and no local
customer took it as a challenge of his honesty. Of course, this
test, while it is probably more needed now than then, would be
worthless at the present. Our modern, "two faced" coins have
about as much music about them as a frog landing in thick mud.
The ring they make is a dull "plunk"&#8212;still another instance in
which beauty and romance have fallen victim to "progress." Alas,
how much we sacrifice on the altar of practicality.
Under the counter on the north was the cash drawer. Cash
registers were not yet in vogue, at least, not in the boondocks.
Under the drawer were several keys like typewriter keys. If one
P. T. Barnum
41
pressed the right combination of these keys, the spring-loaded
drawer would slide open and ring a bell. Presvimably this was to
warn the proprietor if an unauthorized person was "dusting" the
till.
In the shelves on the north wall and behind the show case
was the drug section, loosely defined. It held patent medicines
such as Cardui, Beef Wine and Iron, Sloan's Liniment, Sarsaparilla
,
Black Draught&#8212;what an awful dose it was. It was a finely ground
black powder made of roots, barks and vegetable matter, and was ^
used as a laxative. Also, there were Doan's Kidney Pills, Calomel,
Castor Oil, Iodine, and small bottles of turpentine&#8212;which was
used as an antiseptic. Two other drugs that are nov/ rigidly
controlled were paregoric and laudanum, both of which
contained opium, the latter in considerable amount; but then
anyone who claimed to have a toothache and who had the money or
the credit could get them. Presently drug useis would probably
look on those as the good old days, although the merchant, as a
matter of principle and also because he personally knew all his
customers, would probably have stopped short of selling any of
them a dangerous amount. And by the same token none of them ever
considered taking it by force. In those pre-World War I days,
force was a little-used item. Both the merchant and the customer
had a mutual respect for each other. That was one of the features
of "the good old days" I would like to have back.
I failed to mention that on that drug shelf was vermifuge,
which was one of, if not the vilest tasting concoctions ever devised
by man. If we could just make every politician whose words and
42
acts get us into wars take two doses of vermifuge before he
threatened, I believe it would usher in the golden age of peace!
Its merits were alleged to be that it would rid children of pin-worms.
I guess it would, but there must surely be some easier
way. Aunt Louella"'" gathered Philip and me up one day and gave us
a dose of it. The memory still puts a bad taste in my mouth.
Next to the medicine section was the tobacco. There was a
great variety of smoking, chewing tobacco, and snuff. Among the
chewing varieties I remember Brown's Mule, Spark Plug, and Picnic
Twist. The first two were plug tobaccos, that is, tobacco leaves
treated with molasses and pressed into sheets. And near them
stood the inevitable tobacco cutter to cut as much off a plug as
the customer wanted. As I remember about a fourth of a plug of
Brown's Mule sold for a nickel. I guess the plugs were scored to
indicate where to cut. Picnic Twist, though, was a different
breed of cats. It was pure tobacco twisted into a twist that
looked like an overgrown periwinkle. It was dry and strong.
Some advanced tobacco users crumbled it up and smoked it in their
corncob pipes. When one got to the place that he could use Picnic
Twist, he had arrived, because his system must be almost saturated
with nicotine before he could stand it! While it may not have
been as strong as I described, it nonetheless had a tendency to
separate the men from the boys! If my memory serves me right.
Papa chewed Brown's Mule very sparingly. Then there were the
snuffs in nickel and dime cans. There were two brands, Bruton's
Mrs. Welcom H. Mankin.
A3
and Garrett's Scotch Snuff. They were probably both made by the
American Snuff Company in Memphis. Snuff was used, if at all,
by the women who before this time had given up smoking pipes and
had not yet got to cigarettes. My Grandmother Hendrick dipped
snuff; Mother did not. Most of the men smoked or chewed, or both.
But cigarettes were in high disfavor with the older men; they
called them coffin tacks, and subsequent research indicates they
were just about right. As for cigarettes, those shelves did not
hold any ready rolled. They were beginning to catch on in town,
but the country people who smoked cigarettes at all rolled their
own, partly, I guess, because they were cheaper. There was a
rather strange notion among the cigarette smokers that it was the
paper, specifically cigarette paper, that was harmful, not the
tobacco. To get around that, they rolled them in pieces of brown
or white paper sacks, which added three or four times as much paper
as the very thin cigarette papers. Some few of the more audacious
owned a book of L.L.F. cigarette papers. Whether it was because
they were not socially approved or because they were illegal, I
do not know, but they were kept pretty well concealed. I think
Hendrick generally used L.L.F. 's. The initials were locally
reputed to mean "last leaf first." Actually, I think they were
the initials of the French firm that made them. Among the ciga-rette
tobaccos that were on the shelves were Bull Durham (way out
the most popular), R.J.R., and Prince Albert. The first two came
in little flattened cloth bags; the third in a red tin, as I
presume it still does. Of the pipe tobaccos I can only recall
Our Pride, which came in a round cloth bag with a red and white
label, and Tuxedo, and Prince Albert, which were packaged in tins.
u
Really experienced cigarette rollers could roll one in one hand
after the tobacco was poured in the paper, including striking the
kitchen match (Diamond brand, no less) . I learned how to roll a
very presentable cigarette, but I never advanced to become a
one hander!
Among the other tobacco supplies were some cheap cigars.
The one that fastens itself on my memory was Virginia Cheroots
or "threefors," meaning three for a nickel. The box had a picture
of a big sow rooting and under it cheroots. Even in those days
of cheap products and cheap labor, I can't imagine that three for
a nickel cigars could have had much quality. They could probably
just as well have been named "El-Ropo." It is likely that
Fleur-de-Melba and King Edward also graced the shelves and touted
their virtues at five cents each, which were treats for the more
affluent only. Pipe smoking and cigar smoking were not considered
to be harmful; they had not yet been associated with lip, throat,
and tongue cancer. Today they are still regarded as less harmful
than cigarettes, but not helpful to the health.
But back to the drug shelves. There were bottles of Grove's
Tasteless Chill Tonic guaranteed to cure malaria. And it probably
would, too, if one could stand the taste for sufficient time to
take enough doses. Little cans of Gray's ointment were there.
The ointment was supposed to liG a specific for boils. It was as
black as axle grease and had a peculiar odor. It was almost as
adhesive as glue. Aspirin had not come into vogue and there was
little or nothing to console one with a headache, but, fortunately.
45
there were not many headaches either. I suppose the more
leisurely pace removed the tensions that now cause us so many
pains, or rather, the tensions never built up to the point of
pain.
Immediately behind the drug and tobacco shelves the groceries
began. There wasn't much rhyme nor reason about the arrangement;
soap and spaghetti might be side by side. But there was sure to
be found somewhere in the shelves cans of sardines (cheap American
variety which sold for five cents). Nigger Head Oysters, Club
Salmon in tall cans, pork and beans, bottles of pepper sauce, a
meager selection of spices including black and cayenne pepper,
maybe whole cloves, allspice, stick cinnamon, and whole nutmegs.
Since country people canned their own fruits and vegetables, not
many of these were sold. There were round cardboard boxes of
Quaker's or Mother's Oats (not the quick-cook kinds, for they had
not appeared yet), Kellogg's Corn Flakes, Post Toasties, sometimes
Grape Nuts and Cream of Wheat. Grits came as hominy flakes in
large burlap bags lined with a cotton bag. They sat against the
counter in the center aisle along with one or two hundred pound
bags of coffee (whole beans), a hundred pound bag of sugar, from
which the merchant dipped it with a scoop and weighed it for the
customer in a small paper bag. On second thought, I believe the
sugar was kept in a bin under the counter. Large bags of dried
beans&#8212;pinto, navy, and maybe large butter beans&#8212;sat along the
counter in the center aisle on the north side. The south side
^ Acetanilide was used by some for headaches but occasionally
induced unpleasant side effects. It was never popular like
aspirin or some of the other present-day pain relievers.
iV6
of the aisle was taken up largely with kegs of nails, staples,
and horseshoes, some opened, some unopened. You might think that
rats and mice would bother these bags that were sitting on the
floor. The fact is that they probably did, but no one worried a
lot about it, unless it was the merchant who lost a little of his
wares and who had to clean up the mess.
There wasn't much of an assortment of soap; usually to be
found was Octagon, Fels Naphtha, perhaps Ivory for the elite,
and Grandpa's Wonder Tar Soap that the women prized highly for
washing their hair. It came in a yellow cardboard box. The bar
was rounded and was almost as black as tar. It lathered freely,
having a tantalizing odor of pine tar. Along with the soaps were
Faultless Starch and cans of Merry War Lye, used variously for
making your own "lye soap" and for putting in pig swill, presum-ably
to rid them of intestinal worms; but, I suspect, given just
because we had always done it this way! It certainly makes one
have a high respect for a pig's innards to think that it could
stand a dose of lye! Along with these items too was Twenty Mule
Team Welding Borax, used by the housewives as a water softener
and by the nearby blacksmith as a flux in welding iron, which was
to me then, and still is, an amazing process.
Conspicuously missing from this section, as compared to a
modern grocery, was toilet paper. The law of supply and demand
prevailed here, for there simply wasn't any demand for it. The
people used sheets of old Sears cataloas, newspapers, or even
sometimes freshly shelled corn cobs. You might infer from this
that people were tougher then than they are now. If you did.
Kl
your inference would be totally correct. They were tougher both
physically and morally.
On the back counter on the north side sat the cheese cutter.
It was a circular platform some fourteen inches in diameter with
a heavy knife hinged over it. The platform could be rotated a
fixed distance at a time. This amount of arc represented the
value of a nickel's worth of cheese, which was a segment of the
circle of the cheese. The cut of cheese was wedge shaped. If a
dime's worth was wanted it could be ratcheted twice, or multiples
for another multiple nickel's worth. The cheese itself was about
fourteen inches in diameter and five inches thick and of little
better quality than the kind we now describe as mousetrap cheese.
A cheese this size came in a wooden box of the same shape. The
cheese itself weighed about fifty pounds. I didn't bother about
it at the time, but I suppose the ratchet was adjustable to take
care of the varying price of cheese. When not in use the knife
was left standing vertically and the hoop (the box the cheese came
in) was placed over the cheese on the cutter platform. I suppose
that the purpose was to keep the mice from getting their share.
Flies probably got their share off the standing knife. As far as
I remember, no one ever bothered to take the knife off and wash
it, but I also never knew of any case of illness being traced to
the cheese cutter.
On the center end of this same counter was the indispensable
roll of wrapping paper in its stand with a guide to tear the paper
off by. Most things were not prepackaged and had to be either
wrapped and tied with string or put in a paper bag and tied with
ifi
string. There were no staplers and no tape. Cellophane and
polyethelene had not even been dreamed of at that time. The
string was on a ball or spool in a container on the ceiling and
the end of the string hung down so that it could be reached.
Some of the string, I remember, had a red thread and white thread
twisted together; other was all white.
In addition to the burlap bags of beans, coffee, and hominy
flakes, in the middle aisle there might be a barrel of apples in
season or even a box of oranges. If this seems awfully crowded
to you, just remember that there was seldom, more than one or two
people in the store at a time except for the "hangers-on," who
were either sitting around the stove in the winter or on the front
porch in the summer. The porch, which jutted out almost to the
road, was a good place to see who was passing and what they were
hauling and to enjoy good-natured talk about them. There wasn't
any continual flow of traffic as there is now; there was an
occasional buggy carrying one or two people, a tew farm wagons,
and sometimes old man Ab Wharton walking along with his hands
clasped behind his back and his wife following some five or six
steps behind him. Many of the people who passed were Negroes
who often heralded their approach by singing, particularly at
night. We almost knew them by their voices, most of which were
rich and melodious.
Behind the northeast counter there was a barrel of salt pork.
It was, I think, taken from the jowls of the hogs and was almost
Not his real name.
49
pure fat. This must have been the same kind that the army bugle-call
ditty referred to as "porky, porky, porky, without a bit of
lean." It was a staple among the poorer people who could not
afford to raise their own hogs. I don't remember what it sold for
per pound, but I would guess not more than ten cents, perhaps even
less. This salt pork, hominy, and corn bread, along with dried
beans, were the main constituents of the diet of the very poor.
There were no food stamps, no welfare programs, no subsidies. In
those days, except for a little help from the somewhat better off
neighbors, you were on your own, and if worst came to awful worst,
it was the poorhouse for you. There were several people in the com-munity,
both whites and blacks, who had a daily battle with the wolf
at the door. It is almost superfluous to say that tuberculosis was
rampant among them and that the death rate was inordinately high.
They were caught in the poverty syndrome and there was very little
hope of ever getting out. Let it be noted, however, that not many
of them were ever suspected of stealing. By and large, they
accepted "what can't be cured must be endured," and suffered with
a dignity that puts to shame our modern complaining. And suffer
I'm sure they did, sometimes being actually hungry. In the Dilton
neighborhood, there were one or two cases of pellegra, which is
specifically a disease of dietary deficiency.
Sometimes in the winter months when hogs were being killed, the
merchant might have "a few sets of bones" for sale at ten cents a
set. A set consisted of a pair of ribs and a backbone. He might
also have some fresh faces and jowls which, I think, sold for ten
cents each. This fresh meat was a welcome addition to the diet of
the very poor and furnished them some much needed protein and
50
vitamins. A novelty, and maybe even a revolting kind of novelty,
in this and other country stores was the sight of rabbits hanging
by a string from a hook in the ceiling. The merchant had bought
them from local hunters for ten cents each and sold them, I guess,
to the more affluent for about twenty to twenty-five cents each.
They had been "drawn" (innards taken out), but the skin and head
were still on them. H. K. Mankin and J. B. Preston used to be
local nimrods who picked up a little spending money this way.
No doubt they invested a substantial part of it in Bull Durham,
while most of the rest went for jellybeans. The older, married
hunters used their rabbits to supplement the families' diet. It
should be noted that a shotgun shell sold for about three cents.
But they didn't always use a shotgun. Often they would kill them
while sitting with a .22 rifle. The shells for it cost about
one- half cent each. When there was a snow on the ground, they
would track them to their burrows and kill them with a club.
Under the northeast counter was one or more stands (50 lb.
metal cans) of hog lard which the merchant had bought from local
farmers and which he sold retail to those who did not produce
their own. There was also shortening manmade from cotton seed
oil which the local people called compound lard. Generally speak-ing,
only the poor would use it as it was considered of inferior
quality and sold at a cheaper price. Some of us have lived to
see that position reversed, since pure hog laid doesn't find
much of a market now. Then, as now, it had a tendency to get
rancid as weather warmed.
51
Considerable of the business of the country store was carried
on as barter. Women would bring in eggs and butter or chickens
and trade them to the merchant for staples such as coffee, sugar
and flour, thread, and calico. We children, too, engaged in
barter with the local merchant as from time to time we could
wangle an egg from our mothers. With almost drooling anticipa-tion,
we would rush to the store with our egg to trade it for
some goody we wanted. But just what goody? There were so many
enticing choices. There were chocolate drops, jellybeans,
cookies, fishhooks, and boss balls, and we just had one egg to
spend, worth roughly one cent. The merchant waited understand-ingly
while we wrestled with this momentous choice. Finally we
decided, the deal was completed and we went away as happy as if
we had made a shrewd deal on a new Rolls Royce. The merchant
usually gave us more than value received. He was our neighbor
and friend, not just a dealer and salesman.
Frequently, too, some adult would bring in a live hen and
trade her for some staple such as sugar, coffee, or lard. Ready
cash was scarce and barter took its place. The merchant had a
coop outside the back of the store that he kept the chickens in
until he took them from time to time to sell to the poultry
wholesale dealer in town.
Part of the business was done on a credit basis also.
Things would be charged until the fall crop was gathered when
the customer and the merchant would have a settlement. If one's
credit was questionable, he would have to get some more acceptable
person, usually a landowner, to "stand" for him, that is.
52
guarantee payment. The poor then, as the poor have always been,
were "on the short end of the stick, " and occasionally there was
a grasping merchant who would gouge them. Hendrick was not that
kind. He had more of a tendency to be softhearted and let them
gouge him, for often his outgo was more than his income. Busi-nesses
do not prosper that way, nor did his, but I venture to say
that he laid up a lot of shekels where "moth and rust doth not
corrupt nor thieves break through and steal." I doubt seriously
that he ever knowingly cheated anybody, but I don't doubt that he
gave long weight to the poor.
To the east of the counter toward the back of the store,
there was a barrel of vinegar lying in a cradle with a wooden
spigot in it. Vinegar was drawn out into the customer's jug or
jar.
Somewhat near the northeast corner of the store was a hanging
platform to hold the cloth bags of flour and meal. The purpose,
of course, was to keep thfe rats and mice off it, not necessarily
for sanitation but to keep them from gnawing holes in the bags
and wasting the contents. A customer might be more concerned
about the bag's being a half pound short than he was about any
germs the rat or mouse might distribute; anyhow, cooking would
kill the germs!
There was some variety of flour but small quantities of each.
Flour came in twenty-four and forty-eight pound bags. I only
remember the name of the one brand that Mother used. Dainty, I
think it was, made by Ransom's mill near Murf reesboro. I believe
there were both plain and self-risina flours. Mother used plain
53
flour and made her biscuits (which we had twice a day) with
buttermilk and bicarbonate of soda. The meal&#8212;the brand escapes
me&#8212;came in twenty- four and forty-eight pound cloth bags also.
The bags were prized for making cup towels and underwear for us
children after the printing had washed out.
Among her other duties, Mother made underwear and shirts for
us. When I think of all the things she did, it makes me ashamed
of what we call work now, nor is it any surprise to me that she
wore out and died in sixty-two years. There was no electricity
nor much gasoline to lighten her load. She did have a gasoline
iron that gave her a desperate headache nearly every time she
used it, probably from carbon monoxide fumes. It was a cantan-kerous
piece of equipment as temperamental as a movie actress.
When it was good, "it was very, very good, and when it was bad
it was horrid!" I doubt seriously that Underwriters' Laboratories
would put their seal of approval on one now, and probably didn't
then. But in the summertime, as bad as it was, I guess it was
better than heating the wood-burning kitchen stove to heat the
sadirons to do a big family ironing including shirts, sheets, and
table cloths. Incidentally, she kept a green cedar bough to put
the iron on occasionally to keep it from sticking to starched
clothes so badly. I suppose the heat extracted oil or wax from
the cedar needles. Country people were not botanists, but they
knew many practical things about trees and herbs.
Across the back wall of the store, hanging on hooks or pegs,
were work harnesses for horses and mules. Among them were trace
chains, collars, hames, hame strings, clevises, backhands, curry
54
combs, and maybe singletrees and doubletrees. Other farm items
were kept in the back storage room.
In addition, the back room contained the coal oil (kerosene)
barrel with a hand-cranked pum.p on it. Coal oil was one of the
necessities of life in those days before electricity reached the
rural areas. We had at our house a metal, one-gallon can with a
small spout to get our supply of kerosene in. It could be poured
from the can directly into the lamps without benefit of a funnel.
Since the small spout didn't have a cap, the merchant would
usually stick a potato on it so that I would not slosh it out as
I carried it home. Other people got theirs in a glass jug with
a cork in it for a stopper. They also had a loop of heavy cord
or small rope attached to the handle to carry it by. I suppose
carrying a gallon of oil by one finger for a mile or two got
rather tiresome.
The shelves on the south side toward the back were devoted
to shoes, men's and women's and children's. They were mostly
work shoes. The men's shoes were high top, lace-up, with hooks
about halfway. As I remember the women's shoes, they had eyelets
all the way up and reached almost to mid-calf. No ankle was
going to be exposed to public view! The clothes then not only
protected the property; they also obstructed the view.
Immediately to the west of the shoe shelves were the dry
goods. The selection was not impressive. It consisted of
several different calico prints, maybe some ginghams, unbleached
and bleached domestic, some Indian head, hickory stripes for
shirts, overalls, work socks, garters, black ribbed cotton
55
stockings in weights for women and boys in short pants, elastic
banding, spools of thread, safety and straight pins, hairpins,
huck toweling and various other kindred items. The wants of the
community had not been whetted to such a keen edge by advertising
as they have been now; therefore, the canny merchant stocked
accordingly. Somewhere along this side of the store was sole
leather and "sprigs," which the industrious bought and used to
half-sole their own work shoes. I often thought how unfortunate
it would be if a piece of this sole leather got mixed in with the
Brown's Mulel They looked somewhat alike. The half-soling jobs
were crude, but they served the purpose and postponed the day of
judgment on buying a new pair of shoes, a momentous decision to
make.
It is nearly impossible for us to envision now the tran-quility,
the sense that tomorrow was going to be very much like
today, the slowness of the tempo of living, the simple pleasures,
the almost all pervading calm that enveloped those days,
especially before World War I. We who lived in those days and
now have the long perspective needed to assess them can't help
but conclude that 1914 was a turning point in history. Life
before that time and after it are almost as different as life on
separate planets would be. ^s one example, violer.ce was rare and
was frowned upon by all but those who committed it, and the
punishment meted out for it was both swift and harsh. Divorce,
too, was looked upon almost as a scandal and divorcees were not
glamorized. Shoplifting was practically nonexistent.
56
One of the simple pleasures I remember with nostalgia was
the mournful, sweet sound of the steam locomotive whistles in the
dead of night. When we lived at the Gamewell place there was a
switch on to a sidetrack of the N.C. and St. L. Railroad about a
mile and a half from our house, and in the still of night we
could clearly hear the whistles. Remember, there wasn't much
background noise, for there were few automobiles and most of them
went to bed at dark; there were no radios, no televisions, and
for all practical purposes, no airplanes, so it was quiet when
night fell except for an occasional passing wagon or buggy in the
early hours or the lilting, half-happy, half-sad voice of a Negro
singing as he walked along the pike. So, late at night&#8212;I think
about midnight--when the Dixie Flyer passed through, the freight
that met this fast passenger train from Chicago to Jacksonville
at that siding had to get off. We could hear it coming to a halt
while the switchman threw the switch, then a short toot from the
tenor pitched whistle, then the puff puff puff &#8212; puff &#8212;
puff &#8212; puff - puff - puff of the steam exhaust as the locomotive
labored to get the heavy train moving again, the low rumble of the
moving train then when it got on the switch (siding) , the clangor
of car couplings bumping together as the brakes were applied,
then silence while the freight lay there waiting for the Dixie
Flyer to pass. It usually wasn't a long wait until the Flyer
came roaring and clacking and its deeper-throated baritone whistle
sounding out an "all's well" to the waiting freight as it
thundered by and was soon gone. Then the freight with two short
toot- loots began its laborious chuff chuff chuff --
57
chuff -- chuff - chuff - chuff as it started, then a slowing of
the chuffing as it slowed for the switchman to throw the switch
and run and catch the caboose then faster chuff-chuff-chuff-chuff-
chuff until the individual chuffs were lost to the growing
roar as the train gained speed. It didn't have far to go, though,
until it came to the Rucker crossing and there the engineer really
expressed himself on the whistle, almost playing a tenor solo with
the W-H-0-0, W-H-0-0, WHOO, W H O with a
diminuendo toward the end of the last WHOO trailing off into the
still night as clear as the note of a violin and as plaintive as
the wail of a banshee. It was a thrilling pleasure that younger
generations have been deprived of. "Progress" drove the steam
locomotive to the bone yard, the raucous diesel horn displaced
the melodious whistle, and music gave way to noise. Perhaps
Longfellow had the tenor-pitched steam whistle in mind when he
wrote "and the night shall be filled with music" at least, he well
could have. I'm sure efficiency has been increased by the change
from steam to diesel, but the soul went out of railroading with
the demise of the steam whistle. Shall man live by efficiency
alone or is there some nobler goal? Is it necessary to swap
beauty for ugliness in the name of progress? The passing of the
steam whistle is typical of the passing of many of those charms
that set the pace of peace and calm which prevailed in the entire
community.</dc:description>
<dc:description>A selection from the author's autobiography that describes his brother's country store and his impressions as a child in rural Rutherford County</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Family history; General stores; Memoirs and biographies</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>local history</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Dillton; Mankinville</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>43 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-24</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication11ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/138</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>