<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>The Air Force base: Smyrna, Tennessee 1942 - 1978</dc:title>
<dc:creator>King, Adeline</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 12</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1979</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949; 1950-1959; 1960-1969; 1970-1979</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>THE AIR FORCE BASE
By Adeline King
SnQnrna, Tennessee
1942 1978
When the Nazi laind and air forces invaded Poland in September 1939 and the
Low Countries in May 1940, followed by their many months of blitz bombing of the
British Isles, the United States recognized the imminence of our country's in-volvement.
The interest in and development of the long-range, four-engine
bombing aircraft was immediate and imperative; therefore, bases with adequate
rtinway length and strength, with trained maintenance crews, with adequate instruc-tion
and training of pilots for such aircraft was of first priority.
To provide enough pilots, foxur-engine schools had to be established, to
which pilots would come after completing requirements of advanced flying schools.
The B-24. four-engine, heavy bomber was the first to be sent to Smyrna for the
training of pilots. The B-17 Flying Fortress, also a heavy, four- engine aircraft,
followed immediately; and the base at Smyrna was the fore-runner of all four-engine
training fields in the country.
It was necessary to find locations for such bases &#8212; flat land, no extremes
in climate &#8212; and Middle Tennessee was in early consideration. It is believed
that the late Senator Kenneth D. McKellar recommended this section of ths State
as a possible site. The final selection for this first base was made from the
following locations: DeRidder, Louisiana; Jackson, Mississippi; Greenville,
South Carolina; and Smyrna, Tennessee. A four-man site selection board, led by
Colonel W. S. Wuest, came to Nashville in September 1941 to meet with officials
of the State, Nashville Chamber of Commerce, and Major 0. E. Walsh, Chief Engi-neer,
U. S. Corps of Engineers, Nashville, to make an investigation of the recom-mended
site.^ They spent four days checking out the area, and filled a subsequent
report to the Air Force authorities in Washington, recommending the use of the
1 Walter King Hoover's History of Smyrna, pp. 540-541
Rutherford County site.
In November I9UI, a delegation of Tennesseans, led by Governor Prentice
Cooper, and comprised of: Mayor Thomas Cvimralngs of Nashville; Roscoe Beale,
Manager of the Nashville Chamber of Commerce; Mayor William T. Gerhardt of Mur-freesboroj
Rutherford County Judge John D. Wiseman; Dr. J. S. Lowry of Smyrna;
Brennus Huggins, President of the Marfreesboro Chamber of Commerce, went to
Washington to sponsor and urge the selection of Smyrna as the site of the new
base. In Washington, the group was accompanied and supported by Tennessee's
Senators Kenneth D. McKellar and Tom A. Stewart and U. S. Representatives from
Middle Tennessee, J. Percy Priest and Albert Gore, Sr. They were given audience
with General H. H. ("Hap") Arnold of the U. S. Army Air Force and other officials.
No definite commitment was made at the time, but the delegation was not discour-aged.
"Major requii^ments of a well-appointed air base were considered ajnply
filled in the Smyrna location." ' It was adjacent to the tracks of the N. C. &amp;. St.
L. Railway, and
"The topography of the proposed site was exceptionally suitable and readily
adaptable to the establishment of a major air base. The surrounding territory
offered no hill masses that might be considered detrimental and, on the other
hand, considerable areas of flat lands for emergency landing are well distributed
in the vicinity of the site. Surrounding lands offered ajnple space for expansion
of the field and cantonment areas. "^
On December 10, 19id, the final approval was given to the State of Tennes-see.
In order for land acquisition to begin, the State Legislature gave official
authoriaation in House Bill No. 669 (by Ragon &amp; O'Dell), Chapter 16^ of the Public
Acts of I9J4I, which specified, as follows:
"AN ACT TO AUTHORIZE THE STATE OF TENI&gt;IESSEE, acting by resolution of its
Funding Board, to issue and sell its interest-bearing coupon bonds in an amount
1 Hoover's History of Smyrna, p. 5U2
i Maxwell Field AFB Historical Division, History of Sewart Air Force Base
19iil-1958, p. 2
3
not to exceed One Million ($1,000,000) Dollars for the purpose of providing fiinds
to acquire lands in the name of the State for the purpose of State and National
Defense, and providing for the lease of said lands by the Governor to the United
States Government or to the proper department thereof to be used as a part of the
National Defense Program, and providing for the application of any rental received
from the United States Government to the payment of said bonds and the interest
thereon."
This bill was passed on February 11, 19Ul, John Ed O'Dell, Speaker of the
House of Representatives; Blan R. Maxwell, Speaker of the Senate; and approved on
February 15, 19Ul, by Prentice Cooper, Governor of the State of Tennessee.
(Note; For brevity's sake the very long bill has not been quoted in its
entirety; but copies are available for verification.)
The Governor of Tennessee, Prentice Cooper, made official announcement of
the final authorization for the base in the following statement, issued January 1,
19142:
"After having spent considerable time making investigation as to possible
sites for the location of air bases for use during the present war emergency, the
United States engineers representing the War Department, have selected as one of
the sites about thirty-three hundred (3,300) acres north of the N. C. &amp; St. L.
Railroad in Rutherford County near Smyrna, Tennessee, and have asked the State of
Tennessee in cooperation with the City of Nashville, the City of Murfreesboro,
Rutherford County, and Smyrna, promptly to acquire this site and lease the same
to the Federal Government for the use of an /iir Base. The United States Engineers'
Office at Nashville, representing the War Department, advises that work will begin
on this site within 30 days.
"While this is short notice, we aire sure that everybody concerned fully
realizes the importance of taking prompt and immediate action to the end that this
1 House Bill 669, Ragon and O'Dell, Chapter l6ii. Public Acts of Tennessee,
I9UI, Par. 1
h
3ite may be acquired and turned over speedily to the federal government for use in
the present war emergency. We are in the midst of war for which vast and extensive
preparations must be made. Sacrifices on the part of every American citizen are
called for , and we are sure the public will respond whole-heartedly to the call of
our government.
"There are approximately 35 separate tracts of land comprising this site of
3300 acres which mast be acquired. Some of these tracts of land have been in the
same family for approximately 100 years. The citizens of this area are making
their homes on these farms. Of course, they did not like to have their occupancy
interfered with, but we know that they are all patriotic American citizens, that
they will realize that wherever these bases are located the ownership of the land
at such sites must be interfered with. We know the good citizens of Rutherford
County and especially those who will be affected immediately will be aa patriotic
as any other citizenship in any other locality of any state.
"It is our purpose to see to it that the owners of these various tracts of
land are paid the full value for the same and that as little hardship as possible
will be brought about to them; but, in view of the fact that this land must be
acquired speedily for immediate use of the United States Government, this state-ment
is made public to the end that the owner of each tract of land in the area
involved may know at the first possible moment the intention of the State and the
cities associated with it to acquire this land at once and the intention of the
federal government to occupy it within about 30 days from this date. We hope and
believe that everybody involved will accept the situation cheerfully and cooperate
to the end that the project will go forward without delay.
Prentice Cooper
Governor of Tennessee
Thomas L. Curamings
Mayor of Ilashville
Jno. D. V/iseman
Judge of Rutherford County" 1
1 Hoover's History of Smyrna, pp. S^k-^SS
s
In summary, according to this statement by the Governor, the State of Ten-nessee
was to acquire from local owners the acreage necessary and then lease it
to the Federal Government for $1.00 per annum, renewable for a period of 2$
years. According to this statement also, approximately 3,300 acres, comprising
approximately 35 land tracts, would be acquired.
"A survey fixing the tract boundaries was established and the Register of
Deeds of Rutherford County applied certificates of title ownership to the attorney-general's
office, vrtiich supervised the task of land acquisition and purchase.
"Five Murfreesboro attorneys were appointed during the first week of Janu-ary
19ii2 by Attorney-General Beeler to prepare abstracts of title for the property
to be acquired, "^-
"A special committee, composed of Robert G. Lipscomb of Murfreesboro, Willis
Haynes of Nashville, and C. W. Phillips, Commissioner of Highways and Public
Works in Tennessee, was appointed on 25 January 19U2 to appraise and purchase
the necessary land.
"The State of Tennessee was the sole purchaser of the air base property.
Governor Cooper issued an executive order 30 January 19U2, authorizing fiscal
officials of the State of Tennessee to make an appropriation of $300,000 from
State funds for the purpose of acquiring the site for the bombardment base.
However, it was found necessary to appropriate additional funds.
"The Nashville Tennessean stated on 19 March 19U2 that the estimated land
acquisition costs were going to reach a total of close to $1400,000.
"In a letter by Henry C. Foutch, Assistant Attorney-General of the State
of Tennessee, to F. V. Kuhn, Office of Area Engineers, Smyrna Mr Base, dated
b June 19l;2, a summary of the history of land acquisition indicated that forty-two
tracts plus a few condemnations represented the total land acquired.
"In a letter dated 8 August 19U2 to Gwen W. Hughes, Attorney for the U.S.
Engineers, Y.M.C.A. Building, Nashville, Tennessee, Mr. Foutch reported that the
Map shovdng area of Sewart Air Base
aSd"lailS{^J^15^"'^"^ ^""^ &#176;f the houses
7
land acquisition costs at that date had already aggregated some $367,932.07, plus
$5,(536.96 expenses for an estimated price of 4&gt;138.3U per acre for 2,6i49 acres. Tt
is the consensus of opinion that, in comparison with the existing land values, the
prices paid for the land averaged a full and fair compensation.
"The State was able to acquire nearly all the tracts by direct purchase. How-ever,
a few unwilling sellers took their claims to court; these titles were subse-quently
acquired by condemnation proceedings, pending fixing of sale values by the
court and jury.
"Generally, a spirit of cooperation prevailed among all interested parties
and the entire task of land acquisition was efficiently disposed of for the State
under the direction of Attorney-Genercil Beeler and his first legal assistant.
Henry Foutch M 1
A story in the Nashville Tennessean for February 1$, 19^4 2, stated that, as
of that date, 126U acres had been acquired at a cost of $169,303.20 for the Army
Air Corps Bomber Base at Smyrna, about one-half of the projected $300,000 to
cover the 3,300 acres.
According to the records of the Register of Deeds Office, Rutherford County,
the following land owners transferred their property to the State of Tennessee:
Owner No. Acres
J. R. Palmer and wife 95.0
George T. Fergus and wife 2U. 28
J. N. Bamett and wife 81;.
5
Mrs. Johnnie T. Hibbett (3 tracts) 83-5
2ii.5
131.58
Mrs. Johnnie T. Hibbett (2 tracts) 98. U9
7.5
Hubert H. Johns and family 1U5.U8
W. E. Gibbons and wife 82.^
J. R. Sanders and wife 169.0 &amp; 85/160
W. R. Coleman and wife
1 Hoover's History of Smyrna . pp. 555-556
5U.96
W. R. Coleman and wife (7 tracts)
John Edmonds on
Mattie B. Edmondson and husband H. R. Edmondson (2 tracts;
John Edmondson
Mattie B. and Henry R. Edmondson
John, Mary, and Annie Edmondson
Henry R. Edmondson and wife
Amanda K. Rucker and husband
Mrs. Hal Edmondson Hughey
J. W. Dodd and wife
Mamie, Susie, and John Chapnan
Carrie Mary Davis Potter and husband
Joe R. Aldrich
Louise and Annie Ella Aldrich
J. T. Lewis and wife
John Butler and wife
Brad Buchanan and wife
J. B. Peebles and wife
Media Davis Sinnott
Charles L. Davis and wife
Media Davis binnott
Charles L. Davis and wife
Ross Buchanan and wife
Ben Cartwright Estate
Jemima R. Ridley et al.
George Hays' heirs-at-law
(2 tracts)
3.7
2.9
2.0
78.3
U.i;2
59.7
A. small Parcel
77.5
7.5
Uo.o
67.39
100.0
110.96
80.0
80.0
(2 tracts) 100.0
10.0
(2 tracts) .25
Acreage not stated
U or 5
(3 tracts) 30. Ui;
2.0
1.0
2.0
87.5
11.0
5.0
12.0 approx.
Acreage not stated
1.0
9
Kathleen Charlton Hill 161^.0
J. 0. Lester and wife 98.0
James Gooch estate 2.0
H. L. Overall and wife, and C. D. Moss III 65.8
Robert Weakley and wife U3.5
Jesse Merritt estate .75
Jennie Coleman Dunn and husband S. R. Dunn (2 tracts) .89
Perpetual easement over l.b acre
Mrs. 3. M. (Josephine) Weakley and family 8U.0
pastor and Trustees of Primitive Baptist Church .$
Pleas Smith's heirs-at-law I9.8
James H. Moore ( Avigation Easement Contragt
)
8.t
Mrs. B. B. Gracy, Sr. (Avigation Easement Contract) (2 tracts) 18,
5
&#8226; U
"Not more than 50 acres were wooded. The area contained six farm houses,
eighteen farm buildings, and sixteen miscellaneous buildings of small value."
By March 19U2, the contracting firm of VJolfe and Michaels (Memphis), with
the U. S. Corps of Engineers, had made considerable headway in the demolition of
houses and farm buildings, the bulldozing of trees and fences, in burning accumu-lated
logs and debris from the demolition, in the eradication of any farm pro-ducts
in storage (a barnful of Mr. John Edmondson's lespedeza, a money crop, was
poured out and scattered by bulldozers). There was not sui'ficient time to allow for
salvage of anything on the acquired landj it had to be cleared quickly for instal-lation
of runways and erection of buildings.
"Despite the generally level nature of the site, some grading was necessary,
especially on that portion which had been earmarked for the landing field, in
order to make it wholly suitable for the purpose intended. That involved excavat-ing
some 200,000 cubic yards of rock and moving approximately 2,U00,000 cubic
yards of dirt. Seven miles of concrete pipe were used in the construction of
1 Hoover, Walter King, History of Smyrna, p. 5Ul
Map of Sewart Air
ase and part of Smyrna
11
the drainage system."
People poured into Smyrna, Ifcirfreesboro, the surrounding areas^ looking for
jobs and places to live, seeking places to eat. A small town of approximately
U97 inhabitants was swamped. Temporary housing had to be found; the Meadow
lawns Apartments were constnicted; public eating places were up-to-then non-existentj
the new Sam Davis Grill was the first to open, and the price of a
steak "slcyrocketed" to the unbelievable cost of $1.10.
Large underground fuel storage tanks were installed in the area where
once had stood the old First Presbyterian Church, an oblong red brick struc-ture
surrounded by heavy-branched shade trees under which the hitching racks
stood waiting for Sunday mornings. Incidentally, the bricks of the old church
were acquired by and moved to the Sam Davis property to be reconstructed into
the present Jane Simmons Tea Room. Another note of local interest: The
father of the Chapman family, one of those whose property was purchased for
the Base, had come to the area as the first pastor of the Presbyterian Church.
A spur tract from the N. C. &amp; St. L. Ry. line was laid to bring into the
property fuel cars, military supplies, and other equipment. Before this was
accomplished , it was necessary to bring in the new underground tanks by truck
from the main railway line. The tanks were shipped to the rail siding on flat
cars. To unload, a truck was set alongside the flat car; another truck hitched
onto the ropes encircling the tank and pulled it over onto the first truck.
"Other work of a general nature relative to the site included the con-struction
of a permanent water storage and distribution system; of a sewage
system and disposal plant; of an outdoor substation and electric distribution
plant; of 12 miles of paved roads and streets; of h miles of railway track,
counting the spur leading to the area and various houselines; of h bridges,
including one railroad and three vehicular structures.
1 Maxwell Field AFB Historical Division, History of Sewart Air Force Base
19U1-1958, p. ^
"The remaining major structures and installations originally planned for
:;myrna Army Air Field may be noted conveniently under the following headings:
..lirfieldj Cantonment] Training; Recreational and Vfelfarej and Hospital. Most
of the buildings concerned, incidentally, were of the mobilization type con-struction,
designed for wartime use only and a maximum duration period of 10
years.
"Airfield
a) Three runways, two of concrete construction and the other an
asphalt- concrete combination, all 300 feet wide and 5,500 feet long.
b) A triangular concrete parking apron with its base 3,700 feet in
length and the two legs 2,600 feet each.
c) Five concrete taxiways.
d) One large hangar for base operations and four smaller ones for
squadron use, all with concrete aprons and flood lighting.
e) An airdrome traffic control tower.
"Cantonment
a) 51 enlisted men's barracks, with a total capacity of around 3,b00.
b) 23 officers' barracks, with accommodation for approximately 1,000.
c) A VJAC's barracks.
d) 8 mess halls.
e) 2 cafeterias.
f
)
A post administration building.
g) h group operations buildings.
h) 12 squadron operations buildings.
i) 6 warehouses.
j) A quartermaster building.
k) A commissary.
1) A finance building.
m) Ik supply buildings.
13
n) A fire station,
o) A guard house,
p) A detention barracks.
"Training
a) 2 ground school buildings.
b) A link trainer building.
c) A bombsight storage building.
d) A bomb trainer building.
e) A photographic laboratory building.
f) A skeet range.
"Recreational and Welfare
a) Ik day rooms.
b) 2 post exchanges.
c) A general recreation building.
d) A theater.
e) 2 chapels.
f) An officers' club.
g) A post office.
"Hospital
a) An administration building.
b) 7 wards, with a total bed capacity of 207.
c) 3 barracks.
d) An infirmary.
e) A dental clinic.
f) An officers' quarters.
g) 2 nurses' quarters,
h) ' mess hall.
i) A recreation building.
Mr
"Over a period of time, the operation of the Army Air Field clearly re-vealed
the need for an expansion of its facilities. Before the end of V/orld .Jar
II, therefore, the following additional units v;ere constructed there at Smyrna:
a) A sixth hangar; b) tv;o more operations buildings; c) a bom.b approach train-ing
building; d) a gymnasium (with a swimming pool, an archery range, and a
track field in an adjacent outdoor area; e) a theater and recreation hall for
colored troops; f) two bowling alleys; g) two civilian housing units; and h)
two guest houses, one for officers and one for enlisted personnel. Early in the
summer of 194^, moreover, the authorities at Smyrna obtained jurisdiction over two
auxiliary airfields. One v;as the V/illiam Northern Field at Tullahoma, Tennessee,
and the other was Campbell Army ^Ur Field at Glarksville."^
In addition to Wolfe and Michales Company, the Foster and Creighton Company,
Nashville, was a major contractor in the base construction, with a weekly payroll
of about .^90,000.00.
Traffic increased on all roads, paved and unpaved. Families evacuated from
their homes (some of them second and third generation residents of their lands)
moved to other places in Rutherford County or into other counties. By 1951, a new
four- lane expansion of the existing two-lane coinciding Hif^hways 70-South and .'J was
completed to accommodate the Snyrna-to-Mashville and oiryrna-to-I'hirfreesboro traffic
of workers and rilitary personnel.
In the six months from January 1, 194^, to July 19'';-^, the runways, han,^ars,
supply and en~incering buildings, barracks, etc., v;ere constructed; plunes viere
moved to the base; early squadrons of len arrived; and the crew-training school
was activated and ready for the E-24 and P-17 pilot trainees.
Colonel ctanley &#165;.. Umstead and Colonel Troup Killer, Jr., i;ere the .'iTT'" Air
j'^orce officers first desif;nated to set up lour-enr^inc sci;oclG in the United States;
and they were sent to Gm^.Tna /iri.:y :^.v Corps Base (later oi.yrna kvrrr .dr Base;
later, Sr^^/rna Air Force Base), as Smyi^na was the first one activated in the country-
1 r^xwell i'ieli /iFB Historical Division, iiistory of G'^wart aIv Force Base,
19/J-1956, pp. 2&#8212;5.
15
Colonel Umstead was subsequently named Base Conuriander, and his residence (and that
of many, if not all, succeeding base commanders) was the brick bungalow beside
.^tewarts Creek vacated by Mrs. Media Davis Sinnott (her property had been a part
of Louis Davis' original land holding; he came to Middle Tennessee in the early
iSOO's from Virginia, and was the father of Sam Davis, local Confederate hero).
Many civilians had been employed in the construction of the Air Base; and
many were employed there during the 18 years of its operation. One of the largest
civilian groups during World War II was housed in the central hangar, the Base Oper-ations
Hangar, on the line. This hangar was the center for the military engineer-ing
staff, the civilian aircraft maintenance chief, trained aircraft inspectors,
skilled workmen and women in various shops; an extensive Aircraft Technical Order
Field (hundreds of volumes covering every physical item of an aircraft structure,
with revisions coming in daily), shops for the repair and reconstruction of an air-craft
(shop for engine change, for sheet metal repair, for electrical and electronic
work, for propeller repair, for radio and communications equipment maintenance, for
parachute repair and repacking, and numerous others). Some of the civilians had
been turned down for military duty; some were over-age, with sons in the service;
one man had been in the Navy and had lost an eye at Pearl Harbor; another man, in
the Parachute Shop, Mr. Burns Hiillips, Sr., Murfreesboro, had a son on active and
dangerous duty in the South Pacific with the Marines; and Mr. Phillips declined to
take a day off as long as his son was on active duty.
"The AAF Combat Crew School was opened officially on h July 19U2. When class-work
began two weeks later, 32 B-2U's had been flown in from Albuquerque
There were 1|8 students in the first class, while a total of 700 reported for the
seven classes during the year 19h2. Training was restricted to the B-2U aircraft
until near the end of November when the scope of the work was broadened to include
the B-17 Flying Fortress as well. Transition training in the B-l? was discontinued
at Smyrna in March 19h3 and transferred to Lockbourne Air Base at Columbus, Ohio." 1
1 Maxwell Field Report, p.
6
16
Crews were, by the end of 19U2, flying their four-leg patterns of touch-and-go
over the area. It was often a difficult adjustment for young pilots just out
of two- engine schools to make, to fly the more complicated and heavier four-engine
aircraft. Once, when a plane came in from the flying pattern, preparing
for a touch-down landing and immediate take-off, a young hand reached the wrong
toggle switchj and, instead of lowering the flaps as the plane came down near
the runway, he raised the landing gear; and the bottom of the big craft scraped
the runway, suffering extensive skin and structural damage. There were crashes
on -md off the Base, some major, some minor, with loss of men and airplanes.
The researchers and writer have not been able to verify exactly how many planes
from the Base were involved in fatal accidents, or how many men lost their lives
in these accidents. From publications of the Murfreesboro Daily News Journal
for the period from May 25, 19h3, through January 12, 1955, the following records
have been obtained:
The first crash after the Base was opened, in vrfiich there were fatalities,
occurred on May 25, 1953, at 1:35 p.m., when a B-2U came down 5 miles north of
the Base. In this tragedy, 3 officers and h enlisted men lost their lives. The
accident occurred in a small clearing on the Campbell farm and was witnessed
and reported by civilians. The men who lost their lives were:
Capt. Stuart K. Oliver, instructor trainee, from St. Paul, Minn.
(stationed at Smyrna '2 months); survived by his parents, his wife,
and his 7-month-old daughter;
2nd Lt. Charlie P. Harris, 21, student pilot, Franklinton, N. C;
2ndLt. Samuel E. Fennegan, 21, student pilot, Fairmont, N. C;
Corp. vailiam N. Clayton, 19, aerial engineer, MempMs, Tenn.;
Pfc. James P. DeRasha, 20, Roxbury, Mass.;
Pfc. Harold J. Linane, 31, Natick, Mass., survived by his wife and
hi a mother.
Pfc. Thomas F. Monahan, Jr., 20, Mnto, New Brunswick, Canada.
17
Two days after the Base's first fatal crash, another occurred on May 21, 19U3,
9:^''' p.m. Six men lost their lives, another txro were injured, when their plane (B-2U)
crashed about 1,000 feet south of the Field when returning froi.i a navigational
training flight. The plsme hit telephone lines, cutting off local comraunications,
caught fire, and was destroyed.
The 2 men who survived were thrown clear and not seriously injured. They were:
2nd Lt. Anthony J. Demetrakopulos, 23, student pilot, Pittsburg, Gal.j
Pfc. David N. Lawson, 27, Louisville, Ky.
The 6 men who were killed were:
2nd Lt. Thomas N. Arrington, 21, pilot instructor, Di:d.e, Ga., survived
by his parents;
2nd Lt. Donald E. Cochraji, 2h, student co-pilot, Mt. Olive, Miss., sur-vived
by his wife Marie
j
Pvt. James K. Blanchard, 28, flight engineer, Hammond, Ind., survived
by his wife and his parents
j
3gt. Jajnes R. York, 2l|., student aerial engineer, Dante, Va., survived
by his parents]
2 other officers aboard were killedj but, as they were from another base,
their names were withheld from the press pending positive identi-fication.
On July 10, I9I4.3, at 2:00 a.m., 3 officers and 2 enlisted men were killed
when, on n routine training flight, their B-2U crashed near Nolensville, Tenness-see,
about 8 miles southeast of the Field, exploded, and was destroyed. The men
\-jho died wei^:
Capt. Donald H. Riggs, 32, flying instructor, Glendale, Gal, survived
by his wife, 2 children, and his father. (Capt. Riggs ;-ras formerly
in the RGAF prior to entering the U. S. Army in 19U2)j
2nd Lt. William H. Garlington, 28, student pilot, Raleigh, N. C., survived
by his wife and his mother;
2nd Lt. Oarroll G. Gettings, 25, student pilot, Danvers, Mass., sur-vived
by his wife and his parents;
Corp. Edward C. Kozuta, UO, flight engineer, Buffalo, N. I., survived
by his mother;
pfc. John D. Lynch, 22, student engineer, Cambridge, Mass., survived
by his mother.
18
On July 12, 19h3, about U:00 a.m., in a wooded section 2 miles southwest of
L.:n.7rna, a B- 2ii on a routine training flight, crashed. Four men aboard were
killed, all unmarried. They were:
2nd Lt. Arthur H. Hunt, 2^, pilot, Lima, Ohio;
2nd Lt. Paul J. Holly, 23, co-pilot, Fairview, N. J.;
Pfc. James E. Cureton, 22, student engineer. Liberty Hills, S. C;
Pfc. Raymond Levlne, 23, flight engineer, Dorchester, Mass.
A B-2U Liberator crashed and burned about 8 miles northeast of the ^ield
about /.:30 p.m.. May 2, 19hh. An explosion followed, and 5 fliers (2 training
officer.'.;, 2 student officers, and 1 enlisted m.an) were killed instantly. They
were:
2nd Lt. Joseph W. Johnson, San 'Antonio, Tex.;
2nd Lt. Francis R. Stoikovdtz, Paris, 111.;
1st Lt. John W. Strickland, Jefferson, Ga., Assistant Base Operations
Officer;
Ist Lt. Aaron R. LaReau, 'Turfreesboro, Tenn.;
Pvt. Ivan P. Jones, flight engineer, Lindley, N. Y.
On May 12, I9I4.U, at the Field, 1st Lt. J. 'w. TIarshall, 2h, residing in liur-freesboro,
was killed instantly when, after alighting from his combat training
plane, he either slipped or walked into a moving propeller.
On &#8226;, routine training flight, A B-2U crashed at 8:1+5 a.m.. May 12, 19/^5, two
iniles from V/illiam Lorthem Field, Tullahoma, Tenn. V/hen the story was published,
tho identities c.f the 3 men -board who lost their lives ^^fere not revealed.
On '.pril 1?, 19it6, about 2:31 p.m., the pilot of a B-25 ferrying plane was
burned and killed in the crash of his aircraft about 1 2 mile northwest of the Base.
He was Capt. Charles J. Anderson, Carbondale, 111. His co-pilot, Capt. Joseph T.
Hendrickson, Jan &#171;ntonio, Tex., was injured, sustaining multiple cuts. They had
just taken off from the Smyrna Base; developed engine trouble, tried to return to
the Base, overshot the landing strip, and crashed.
19
On January 12, 195^, thirty-seven of the thirty-nine men aboard a G-119 Flying
^oxcar were able to parachute to safety as their pilot held the plane aloft. How-ever,
the pilot, Capt. John Raspet, Jr., 30&gt; from Mt. Clemens, Mich., and co-pilot,
1st it. Ross N. Richards, 30, from Jacksonville, Fla., were killed when the plane
crashed and burned. The 37 who bailed out safely at about 6,000 feet were 3U
paratroopers and 3 crew men. The accident occurred at Lamar, Tenn., near Jeffer-son
oprings, Rutherford County, soon after takeoff on a flight to blmendorf AFB,
'laska.
4ccording to the story in the Daily News Journal , "One eye witness, Krs.
Claude Cox, whose home x^ras about $ miles from the site vjhere the big plane went
down, said she vjas sweeping off the porch when she heard the plane, ohe said,
'Tt sounded funny. Then I saw the flames. It was right in front of me.'
"Mrs. Otis Gavin said she was inside her house quilting when 'T heard the
awfullest roar. It sounded like it was coming through the house. ' 6he and her
son rushed outside to see the plane 'hit the ground and burst into a big fire.'
"Another eye witness, C. V7. Russell, was unloading coal from hib truck
when the plane hit. He said 'it went into a nose dive and,when it struck, there
was a great mushroom of fire and smoke that reminded me of pictures of atom bomb
tests .
&#8226;
"Houston Gavin, 17, said he ran to the scene of the crash, but 'it was in a
big way of burning when I got there.'"
There may have been other fatal crashes during the existence of the Base
oi)erations, but these recorded are the ones our researchers have found.
oome of the pilots and airmen trfio had trained at omyma later carae back
al'ter combat duty in the European theater. One of the first B-2ii,'s assigned to
.jnij'ma during the first year of operation, a lumbering clumsy giant, served in
m.-iny bombing mJ.s3ion3 in Europe, also returned to Smyrna after combat, vnth
&#8226;..1../ h/ii.i.ifi v'M-.i,ory rtiarki ri!',, oti it-j fat oides as proof of its service abroad.
20
"By January 19h3, the transition training of ferrying crews had ended at
;:niyrna Amy Air Field. V/ith the emphasis shifted to regular transition pilot
training in four-engine aircraft, the school was renamed the Army Air Forces
Pilot Transition School (Four Engine). Thereafter until the end of Vforld War [T,
it took pilots from the advanced flying schools and taught them to fly the B-2U
(and, as noted, the B-17 also, through March 19h3) .... The Transition bchool
prepared the trainees directly for operational training units, the link between
amyrna and actual combat."
In the course of that first year, groups came to the Base from many places
for training &#8212; from Australia, from Canada, from Yugo-Slavla (the lant king of
'/"ugo-Glavia, a teenager named Peter, was here at the Base for a tine accompanied
by his guards and associates), and possibly from other countries. Assigned to the
Base for a short time in 19^3 in the radio and communications squadron, George
Putnrin, radio announcer from New york City, served as an enlisted man. He has been
in Los Angeles for a number of years, still serving as radio and television an-nouncer
for the NBC network.
Many entertainers came to the Base during those early years. The Field movie
house ran two shows a night, with first- run movies, at a minimal entrance charge,
local civilians (with passes) were permitted to attend. They enjoyed the sing-alongs
of the nearly all-male audience, especially when one-half of the room would
sing "falsetto". Another amusing GT trademark at the movies was th.^t triey hissed
the villian, cried and whistled at the heroine, booed the hero, and cheered loudly
for the director's n.ame.
The local marching band was made up of excellent musiciansj their mascot was
a huge dog named AL5AB, who strode haughtily alongside the band when marching. Sgt.
Karl Baker of the band developed a fine dance band, and a weekly dance was held in
the Gym and enjoyed by large crowds. Three men from this band married ^myrna girls
(bgt. Earl Baker married oara Batey; Sgt. Joe Everett married Ann Hartj ogt. Robert
Brown married Libby King).
I M.'ixwoli Field AFB Hibtory of Sewart Air Force Base, 19U1-1958, p. 6
21
"The 76th Flying Training &gt;ang was activated with headquarters at Sm,vTna Army
ir Field in August 19h3- One of the 22 flying training wings in the ArirQr Air
Forces, the 76th had as its function the coordination of the activities of the
several four-engine pilot transition schools in the AAF Southeast Training Com-mand.
"Having been suspended id.th the formal surrender of Japan in \ugust 19hS,
all major training activities at Smyrna Army /'ir Field ceased altogether before
the end of the year. The Field was transferred from the AAF Training Command to
the Tactical Air Command in March I9U6. As of June 19hl , it was put on the 'in-active
list'. A year later, however, it was given a 'standby status' and vras
activated with the designation of Smyrna Air Force Base on 8 September 19U8.
Colonel Hoyt L. Prindle became the first Commanding Officer of the Base and of the
Ninth Air Force's 31i+th Troop Carrier VJing when it was activated there on 2 Novem-ber
19hQ.
"For several months after it was activated, the 3lUth Troop Carrier Wing
existed largely on paper. . . .Vfi.th the gradual increase in the number of per-sonnel
assigned to the Base (the total population exceeded U,000 in 1955), all
existing facilities were in use and additional ones were in demand. . . .Since
most of the buildings had been constructed for wartime use only and planned for
a relatively short period, continuous repair work was necessary to keep them in
usable condition.
"New construction at Smyrna A.ir Force Base following its reactivation in-cluded
four more warehouses (1953) j a Little League softball park (1953) J five
additional squadron operations ouildings (19^6); and another fire station (1956).
The latter year also saw the culxnination of a long-delayed plan to convert the
base heating facilities from coal to gas. In 1956, the Air Force announced thi
it would acquire from civilian owners the VJherry Housing Rroject, consisting of
oOO units." 1
1 Maxwell Field AFB History of Smyrna Air Force Base, 19U1-1958, pp.6--10
22
The list of Commanding Officers, or officers in charge of the Base, follows,
with year of entry on duty, and the unit commanded by each:
-;;- Colonel Stsmley M. Umstead
Colonel lUchard Ballard
Colonel R. Baez, Jr.
Major Frank L. Fenn 19ii7 Base Inactive House-
19k2 Smyrna AF3
19U5 II II
19ii6 11 II
19li7 -
keeping unit
Colonel Hoyt L. Rrindle
Colonel Marvin L. Mcliickle
19l;8 3lUth Troop Carrier VJing (H)
During his tw&#169; brief absences
(TDY in Japan and Korea in
1950, and when hospitalized
in 1952, Col. Korman Van
Sicklen .-.md Col. Viilliam H.
DeLacey served as temporary CD's.
19^k 3lUth Troop Carrier VJing (il)
Col. V/illiam Letd.s, Jr.,
served 3 weeks on TDi.
3llith Troop Carrier Viing (M)
839th Air Division
Colonel Adriel N. Williams 1956
Colonel Charles V/. Howe 19^7
Colonel f.Lbert V. Andreas 1958 " " "
Brig. Gen. Frederick J. butterlin 196O " " "
Colonel L. F. Tanberg 1962 " " "
Colonel Williajn G. Moore, Jr. I963
Brig. Gen. Ernest C. H-rdin, Jr. I965
-"- Colonel William H. DeLacey I966
Colonel Oliver L. Duncan 1967
Colonel Wayne Matson 1967
-"- Deceased
Note: The above-named were the senior commanders and, through 1956, were called
Base Commanders. IThen the 839th Air Division was formed in 1957, there was also
a separate "Base Commander" xj'ho took care of the housekeeping details and answered
to the Division Commander. These were:
Colonel E. R. Bane &#8226; 1957
Major Allen Sewart, Jr.
Air Base Namesake
u
Colonel C. R. Phillips
Colonel G. ? . Franklin
Colonel Joseph Sullivan
Colonel W. F. Brown
I960
1962
1965
1967
According to Walter Hoover's History of Smyrna, the following is a record
in chronological order the activities and.'or operations on the Base fron July
19U7 to July 1963:
July 19i|7 Base de- activated. Housekeeping unit only.
August I9U8
March 25, 1950
June 1950
November 5, 1951
Base re-activated. 313th Troop Carrier Wing moved
here from Texas.
Base was given permanent name Sewart Air Force Base,
in honor of Major Allan J. Sewart, Jr., Louisiana,
who was killed in 19^2 over the Solomon Islands. His
widow and daughter, his parents, a brother, I,t. Col.
Harold Y. Sewart, stationed in England, were present
for the dedication. A plaque, mounted on a block of
native Tennessee stone, was unveiled and became a per-manent
part of the Base. (Note: These details are
taken from the Maxwell Field AFB History of the base.)
Many local people felt that the Base should have been
named in honor of Lt. V/illiam D. Neely III, who was
killed in 19U3 over North Africa, because he was the
fourth generation of his family who had lived on land
acquired for the Base.
C-119's were moved in by the 3lUth Troop Carrier V/ing
for crew training for combat in Korea; after combat,
the crews returned to the Base.
A quit-claim deed was issued by the State of Tennessee
to the United States Government, executed as of that
date by Governor Gordon Browning, secretary of State James H. Cummings, and
&#8226;.ttomey-General Roy Beeler. From that quit-claim deed, here is an excerpt:
"VJHEREAS, by virtue of Chapter I6U of the Public ^cts of 19lil, the Legislature
of the State of Tennessee authorized the acquisition of certain property located
in Rutherford County, Tennessee, to be used as an air base, formerly known .ind
designated as Smyrna Air Base and presently knoim as Sewart Air Force Base, com-prising
approximately 2, 6I42 acres of land; and
"VJHEHEAS, by virtue of Chapter I6U of the Public Acts, the Legislature of
the State of Tennessee authorized the issuance of bonds in the amount of One
25
Million ($1,000,000) Dollars to defray the cost of acquisition of said land to-gether
with all other incidental expenses as well as another military installa-tion
known as Camp Forrest. Said military installations were leased by the btate '
of Tennessee to the United States of America for the s\im of One ($1.00) Dollar per
yearj and
"'i/ffiEREAS, the Honorable Gordon Browning, Governor of the State of Tennessee,
on 2 March 19k9, formally notified the United States that the State of Tennessee
was interested in the Sewart Air Force Base being made a permanent air force in-stallation
by the Federal Government and, if said proposal was acceptable to the
Federal Government, the State of Tennessee would take such action as may be neces-sary
to accomplish the desired aimj and
"'iVHEREAS, the Legislature of the State of Tennessee, by virtue of the auth-ority
contained in Chapter 103 of the Public Acts of Tennessee of 19h9, as
amended by Chapter 103 of the Public Acts of Tennessee of 1951, authorized the
conveyance of the property comprising the Sewart Air Force Base, formerly known
as the Smyrna Air Base, to the United States of America^
"ISDW, -THEREFORE, this quit-claim deed of conveyance, made and entered into
this the $th day of November 1951, by and between the State of Tennessee, acting
by and through Gordon Browning, Governor, and by, through, and with the approval
of Jajnes H. Cummings, Secretary of State, and by Roy H. Beeler, Attorney General,
pursuant to the provisions contained in Chapter 103 of the Public Acts of Tennes-see
as amended by Chapter 31 of the Public Acts of Tennessee of 1951, the State
of Tennessee, according to the method provided by Chapter 130 of the Public Acts
of Tennessee of 1937, quit-claims to the United States of America all of the inter-est
of the State of Tennessee in and to the following described property; but it is
specifically covenanted and stipulated that this conveyance shall be effective to
vest in the United States of America only such titles as the State of Tennessee
has and possesses in the premises hereinafter described, without warranty by .-ind
on the part of the State of Tennessee, and that the following described property
26
is conveyed subject to existing easements for public roads and highways, for
public utilities, for railroads and pipe lines, or other existing easements."
(Note: For brevity's sake, the long descriptions of the three parcels described
in this quit-claim deed have not been quotedj but a copy of the deed is available
for verification.
)
The 5l6th Troop Carrier Group, equipped vdth H-19
helicopters, was brought to Smyrna. To that date,
the only such unit.
The 513th Troop Carrier Group was activated here
for crew training in C-123's.
C-130's Hercules, supplanted the C-119's and C-123's.
The Base was reorganized as the 839th Air Division.
The 513th Troop Carrier Wing was de-activatedj the
U63rd Troop Carrier Wing was transferred here from
Ardmore, Oklahoma. At that time, Sewart AFB was the
only operation.al C-I30 training base in the United
States.
The USAF Advanced Flying School was activated to be
operated by the kh^nd Combat Flying School, respon-sible
for training on all models of the C-I30.
The U63rd Troop Carrier Wing was moved to Langley Air
Force Base, Virginia. The $l6th Troop Carrier
Vfing's operational control was transferred to Dyess
Air Force Base, Texas.
6Uth Troop Carrier Wing was activated.
The above was redesignated as the 6iith Tactical Air-lift
Wing
As of this date, a quit-claim deed was completed be-tweerjthe
United States of America and Rutherford
County, Tennessee, for the transfer of the Air Base
property from the ownership of the Federal Govern-ment.
This deed was prepared by the Regional Counsel,
General Services Administration, Region k, Atlanta,
Georgia, (Warren G. Moody, Chief, Property Division,
Property Management and Disposal Service).
Quoting from Page 21 of the Quit-Claim Transfer Deed, "the property hereby
conveyed has heretofore been declared surplus to the needs of the UIHTED STATEo
OF AMERICA, is presently under the jurisdiction of the General Services Adminis-
Early 1955
November 1955
Early 1957
October 1957
December 1, 1958
July 1, 1962
July 1963
March 7, 1966
May 1, 1967
December 31, 1971
27
tration, is available for disposal; and its disposal has been authorized by the
'dministrator of General Services."
The opening passage of this quit-claim deed is quoted herewith from Page 1
of th^t docuinent:
"THIS INDENTURE, made this the 31st date of December 1971, beti-reen the
UNITED oTATES OF AMERICA, acting by and through the Administrator of General
.Services, under and pursu?Jit to the povjers and authority contained in the pro-visions
of the Federal Property jnd, Administrative Services Act of 19h9) ap-proved
June 30, 19h9, (63 Stat. 377), as amended, and regulations and orders
promulgated thereunder, party of the first part, and RUTHERFORD COUIlTf, a politi-cal
subdivision of the State of Tennessee, party of the second part.
"^iflTNESSETH:
"That the party of the first part, for and in consideration of the sma of
T\-IO MILLION TEN THOUSAND AND I'O 100 DOLLARS ($2,010, 000.00) to it cash in hand
paid, the receipt of x*ich is hereby acknowledged, doth by these presents remise,
release, and forever quit-claim unto the said party of the second part, its suc-cessors
and assigns, all those tracts or parcels of land, with improvements
thereon, -md certain interests and facilities as more particularly set forth
below, all situate, lying --nd being in the cth Civil District of Rutherford
County, Tennessee "
This detailed document plus notp.rization, covers 22 pages. It describes
the various tracts and parcels of land and includes the following: Main utility
lines; flowage easements; railroad spur line; water, power, and telephone lines;
water treatment plant; pumping station; sewage treatment plant.
On Page 3 of the document, there is this reservation statement:
"RESERVING unto the LTJITED STATES OF ATIERICA, its successors and assigns,
perpetual rights for the use and benefit of the public in its use of the said
28
airport, a right of flight for the passage of aircraft above the horizontal sur-faces
over the real property hereinafter described, together vrith the right to
cause in such airspace such noise as may be inherent in the operation of aircraft,
now known or hereinafter used, for the navigation of or flight in the said air-space
for landing on, taking off from, or operating at the airport; the party of
the second part, for itself, its successors and assigns, does hereby agree that
it will not erect nor permit the erection or growth of any structure, tree, or
other object into the airspace above the horizontal surfaces of the property des-cribed;
there is reserved unto the UNITED STATES OF AMERICA, its successors and
assigns, the continuing right and easement to take any action necessary to prevent
the erection or growth of any structure, tree, or other object into the airspace
above the horizontal surfaces described. . , . , to mark or light as obstructions
to air navigation all structures, trees, or other objects that may extend above
such horizontal surfaces, together mth the right of ingress, egress from, and
passage over the land described for such purposes."
(Note: Tn the interest of brevity, the lengthy quit-claim is not included in its
entirety in this record; but a complete photostatic copy is on file in the Ruther-ford
County Historical Association files and available for reading and study.)
A report from the UoAF Historical Division and the Maxwell Field Research
Branch has provided the following information about the annual cost outlay in the
peak years of the Base's operations, along with data on population .md housing
statistics there:
FACTS AND FIGURES ON SEWAKT 'PAreHECK'
Monthly civilian-military paycheck $1.75 million
$21 million annually, of which approximately 4517.5 million was spent in
local communities.
Annual contracts and local purchases &#8212; $8.5 million
Value of Sewart aircraft &#8212; $225 million
Value of Base real estate -- $U3 million
29
FIGURES ON POFULATICM 'J^D HOUSING
Population ;
Militaiy Strength -- approximately 5,000
Civilian Strength -- approximately i;20
Military, Civilian, and Dependent Strength -- approximately 1^,000
Housing ;
Wherry Housing &#8212; 600 Units
Officers; 1 bedroom - 20 Airmen; 1 bedroom - 80
2 bedroom - 50 2 bedroom - 150
3 bedroom - 98 3 bedroom - 200
U bedroom - 2
Capehart Housing &#8212; 8? units
Officers; 3 bedroom - 3h Airmen: 2 bedroom - 20
U bedroom - 1 3 bedroom - 32
Trailer Court &#8212; 76 spaces
Officers and airmen in BOQs and barracks -- approximately 2, $00
Air Force families residing off-base (Rutherford and Davidson Counties &#8212; approximately 2,500
FACTS AND FIGURES ON SEV/ART 'PArcHECK'
1. Recurring expenditures which are relatively fixed from year to year as of
1 April I96I4:
a. Pay and allowances of civilian employees, inactive
reservists, and the Tennessee Air National Guard .j;3,382,000
b. Payments to transportation carriers for shipments
of military material and household goods 570,000
c. Payments for utilities and communications 505,000
d. Contractual laundry, education services, and
repairs to equipment 171,000
e. Rental of computer system lUii,000
f. Purchase of supplies, equipment, subsistence, and
POL products 1,970,000
g. Military personnel housing rentals 3,It56,000
Total ;}&gt;10,198,000
30
Carried Forward $10,198,000
2. Recurring expenditures, but not in fixed amounts each year:
a. Contractual repairs and modifications to existing
real property 990,000
b. Construction of new facilities 1,700,000
Total 2,690,000
3. Pay and allowances to military personnel, excluding
Item l,g, above 17,608 ,000
GR,'.ND TOTAL $30,U9fc,000
After title of the Base property was transferred to Rutherford County as of
December 31, 1971, the Rutherford County-Smyrna Airport Development authority was
set up for immediate leasings of parcels or sections of the property and or
buildings to prospective lessees. Varying types of small and larger companies
and industries began moving in in 1972.
As of April 1978, companies and businesses operating on the Base property
were, as follows:
RUTHERFORD CaJNTY-S^mlNA AIRPORT DEVELOPMENT
Al J. Durham, Director
Industries Owners or Contact Persons
Airport EXXON James P. Warren and John Coffey
All .'Uaerican Liquidators Hickman Duncan
Better Build Aluminum Co. L. M. Hoffett
Browlow Manufacturing Co. Clinton Brownlow
Capitol International Airways, Inc. Mack H. Rowe
Carrier Corporation !&#8226; B. Hilton
Gilbert Tank Service, Inc. Randall, James, and Alvin Gilbert
Centerline Manufacturing Co. Buford T. Perry
Clover Garden Products 0. B. Elliott
G\iston Coach Interiors Rankin Arnold and Stanley E. Knight
31
Fiborking, Inc.
Hytec tjorporation
Tiiternation.nl Drugs
Tnperi-^-1 Meats
Kr-ne Industries
I'^aiden Craft
Mid- Cumberland Conununity '.ction Agency
Parthenon Enterprises
lat's T. V.
Pete's Bait Shop
Polymer Technology
Pro Travel Bag
Ray's Fabric bales
banford Span Joist
:.myrn3 Country Club
...paulding Fibers Co.
'iangent Tool &amp; Die Co.
Tom ' s , 'upply
^.orro Bait Co.
Bob Larson
Peter W. Lufkin
Lonnie Smith
Bobby Gene Spivey
J. A. Putlak
James C. Epps
Patrick Wade
John Davis
G. E. Patterson
C. S. Murphy
Don Dundius
John R. Tillman
H. Ray Emmanuel
Frank Davis
Jim Vfalls
Lee Rake
David M. Saunders
Richard B. Johnson
Stan Sloan
(Total Employment -- Approximately 1,800)
MET ROPGLITAiN NASHVILLE AIRPORT AUTHORITY
(Smyrna Airport Tenants)
Col. Steve Fitzhugh, Director
:^een Bee Restaurant Mel Corum, Manager
Capitol International Airways, Inc. Jesse ^tailings. President
:-^l eetline Products Jim He]. ton, Manager
i-Kislc City International Airways, Inc. Bob bpivey. Manager
Hei] ^.tuaker Joe Butts, Manager
32
iitones River Air oervice Ed Lowe, Manager
K. G. Plastic Equipment Co. Ken Gil jam, fi'.nager
Iridon, Limited Lynn l^/urzel. Manager
Golf Club House Jim Hale, Manager
Tennessee Adhesive t&gt;hirley Farmer, Manager
safety Equipment Company Jack Morton, Manager
"lational V/orm Growers Exchange Jerry Meyers, Manager
Tennessee Aruy National Guard Colonel James F. Mc3ride, Manager
(Total Employment &#8212; Approximately 160)
STATE OF TENKESbEE
LEAHMING RESOURCEo CENTER
COMPREHENSIVE VOG-REH' BTLITATTON CEIiTER
(Total Employment -- Approximately U50)
A total of approximately 2,000 persons, employed in approximately h?) busi-nesses
or operations, were based here as of April 1978. Twenty-six years after
Dulldozers removed all evidences of a farming life style and construction of a
1 arg&#171; airfield and military installation had begun, the area is again engaged
in civilian activities of business and industry.
Going much farther back in history, the area was once wilderness and home
of native Indians. It is not known how long the Shawnee tribe m :de it their home
(they were here when the French explorers came in the late ]600's and early lyju's
and named the present Cumberland River with their French word for :.hawnee). In
the late 1700's, settlers were pushing westward from the original colonies and
buildin-g their cabins. The area became private property through large land grants
in the early iSOO's, becoming a home place for many families for the next hunared
years, a rural farming community, landmarked by n-'ijnes like "the Chapman Place,"
"the :'elson place," "Goochland," "Liberty Hill," etc.
In 19li2, the cycle changed with the acquisition of this land for use as a
bc.se for *raining crews for four-engine aircrafL; and, fin-lly, returned to pri-
33
vate use in 1971- These approximately 3,300 acres of land have been used in
various ways during the cycles of occupation; and .all its occupiers h'?.ve left
indelible influences on past and present generations.
Over its 29 years of activity here, the Base has brought many changes to
the community and surrounding areas. Tt brought growth in business, in home con-struction,
in the development of the school system (In the 1930's, both elementary
&#8226;:.nd high school classes were housed in the old "Rock dchool" on College ,'jtreet,
with a probable total of 1^0 pupils; in the 1970' s, four new buildings, plus two
old buildings and the John Coleman School were full and overcrowded.), and in the
general business environment.
Many fine rsid permanent relationships were developed between local people
and newcomers who had moved here and lived here for a number of years. Many of
those temporary residents came to call it home and decided to live here perman-ently
^Jter retirement from active duty.
The direct national use of the property has been discontinued, but the
tern "The Base" will long be a part of the local vernacular.
and
3U
ACKWOWLEDGMEM'S
Adeline Kin;;; wishes to acknowledge and express appreciation for the respon-sive
and generous help from a large number of people in her preparation of t-.is
ti.Tterlal on the Air 3o.se at Srayrn?., 19U1--1970.
To ;'!r3. Gladys McCarty, rfurfreesboro, Tennessee, who waj. eniployed in tnc
Go"irri?nd Section at the Base for most of its existence; to the Honorabj e Albert
Gore, Jr., U. &#163;. Congressman from the Uth District of the otate of Tennessee,
;iis office staff J to the Office of the National Archives, Washington, D. C, to
llr. James Koobler, Director of /jr-chives Gection, State of 'lennessee; to V.v . James
.i. Eastman, Jr., Chief, Research Branch, the Albert F. oimpson Historical Research
Center, iJGAF, Maxwell Field, Alabama; to V/alter King Hoover, author of the History
o: umyrn."; to the Daily Lews Journc-1 , hurfreesboro, Tennessee; to Yt . Gene ..loan
M-.d I iss o-usan Garter, Ilurfreesboro, who researched the Daily Je-.vs Journal files
for the period; to Dr. H. D. Riley, Ch^.ldren's Hospital, Oklahoma City, Oklahonr.,
loriner officer at .;ewarb AFB; to Mayor Sam Ridley, Mayor of Smyrna; to ..Ibert J.
Durh^i:", Director, Rutherford County- ,-yrn: Airport Development; t,o '-a^s :'artha
&#8226;/right and the Regibter of Deeds Off&#177;ce, Rutiierford County; to i^rn^sL King Johns,
;;iio i,aiked her into compiling this material and h. s done a considerable amount of
tht. research.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Presents the history of Sewart Air Force base in Smyrna, Tennessee</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.) -- History; United States. Air Force</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Sewart Air Force base; World War II</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Smyrna</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>67 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-01</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication12ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/139</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>