<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Rutherford County Historical Society publication no. 12</dc:title>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1979</dc:date>
<dc:description>Digitized by the Internet Archive
in 2010 with funding from
Lyrasis IVIembers and Sloan Foundation
http://www.archive.org/details/publication12ruth
S3.50 The Copy
Rutherford County
Historical Society
PUBLICATION N0.12
%
^&#8226;^i&#187;^
Fatal Crash At Sewart
Winter 1979
MURFREESBORO. TENNESSEE 3^130
The Cover
The cover of Publication Nvunber 12 Is by James Matheny of Murfreesboro . This
Publication has an article on Sewart Air Base and the drawing on the cover shows the
heroic action of two Sewart pilots on January 12, 1955. Their C-119 transport plane
had just taken off with a load of paratroopers when engine trouble developed. The
two pilots held the plane long enough to allow the paratroopers and crew to bail
out. Capt. John Raspet Jr. and his co-pilot 1st Lt. Ross N. Richard did not have
time to get themselves out and died when the plane crashed.
Sewart Air Base is now closed as an Air Force base, but the men and their fami-lies
contributed much to Rutherford County and will always be remembered in our
history. We gained a large number of former airmen at Sewart as permanent citizens
upon their retirement.
The Rutherford County Historical Society is grateful for the work of the authors
of these articles in Publication Number 12. We would also like to say thanks to our
County executive Ben Hall McFarlin and Miss Susan Jones for their help in getting
this publication into a published form.
The Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society are not copyrighted.
The Society beleives the History of Rutherford County belongs to everyone, however we
would appreciate anyone reprinting the material to give the authors and the Society
credit.
RUTHERFORD COUNTY HISTORICAL SOCIETY
PUBLICATION NO. 12
Published by the
RUTHERFORD COUNTY HISTORICAL SOCIETY
OFFICERS
President Mr. Robert Ragland
Vice-President Mr. William Walkup
Recording Secretary Miss Loiiise Cavrthon
Corresponding Secretary and Treasurer Miss Kelly Ray
Publication Secretary Mr. Walter K. Hoover
Directors &#8226; Dr^ Robert B. Jones III
Mrs. Dotty Patty
Miss Aurelia Holden
Publication No. 12 (Limited Edition-350 copies) is distributed to
members of the Society. The annual membership dues is |5.00 (Family-$7. 00)
which includes the regvaar publications and the monthly NEWSLETTER to all
members. Additional copies of Publication No. 12 may be obtained at $3.50
per copy.
All correspondence concerning additional copies, contributions to
future issues, and membership shoixld be addressed to:
Rutherford County Historical Society
Box 906
Murfreesboro, Tennessee 37130
For Sale
THE FOLLOWING PUBLICATIONS ARE FOR SALE BY THE RUTHERFORD COUNTY
HISTORICAL SOCIETY, BOX 906,Murfreesboro, Tennessee 37130
Publication #1, 2, 3, 4, 5, and B: Out of print
Publication # 6: Link Goiranunity;Lavergne; Fellowship and the
Sanders family. $3.00 + $.50 postage
Publication #7 : Hopewell Church; Petition by Cornelius Sanders
for Rev. War Pension. $3.00 + $.50 postage
Publication # 9: History of Dilton. $3.50 + $.50 postage
Publication # 10: I864 Diary; Peter Jennings; Henderson Yoakum;
Early Methodist Church; and Overall Fam. $3.30 + $.50 postage
Publication # 11: State Capitol; Ben McCulloch; Petition of Michael
Lorance; A Country Store; and Soule College
$3.50 + $. 50 postage
1^40 Rutherford County Census: With index $5.00 + $.50 pOstage
Deed Abstract of Rutherford County 1^03-1^10 $10.00 + $.50 postage
Griffith ; Illustrated bi-centennial publication $2.00 + $.50 postage
Commemorative Plates;
Plate # 2: Tennessee College in Murfreesboro $5.00 +$1.00 postage
Plate # 3: Rutherfoiid County Cojirthouse 1900 $5.00 +$1.00 postage
Available From William Walkup,202 Ridley St , Smyrna, Tennessee 37167
Rutherford County Map IS7S : shows land owners $3.30 + $.50 postage
Cemetery Records of Rutherford Caunty.
Vol. 1 : Northwestern third of county and part of Wilson and
Davidson Counties, 2 56 cemeteries with index and maps.
$10.00 + $.50 pstage
Vol. 2 : Eastern third of Rutherford and the western part
of Cannon County. 24I cemeteries with index and maps.
$10.00 + $.50 postage
Vol. 3 ; Southwestern third of Rutherford County. 193 cemeteries
with index and maps
ALSO AVAILABLE FROM MRS. FRED BRIGANCE,1202 SCOTLAND DRIVE,MURFREESBORC
Tennessee 37130:
Marriage Records of Rutherford County 1^51-1^72 $10.00 no postage
79-14182
QUERIES
IMPORTANT: Publication of queries in this column is free to all members aa
space permits. Each query must appear on a full sheet of paper which must be
dated and include member's name and address. Please type if possible. Queries
should give as much pertinent data as possible, i.e. approximate/actual dates
of birth, marriage, death, etc. Queries must refer to RUTHERFORD COUNTY,
TENNESSEE FAMILIES and immediate connections. Address all correspondence re-lating
to queries to the Society, P. 0. Box 906, Murfreesboro, Tennessee 37130.
No. 1 HARRI3-GUNN Wiley William Harris b 1808 N. C. m Catherine GUNN, appear
in Coffee Co. 1850 census. First son William Lafayetta Harris b
11-10-1853 m 5-13-1858 Martha Jane ALLEN (according to their Bible)
buried Evergreen Cemetery, Murfreesboro. 2nd son John Wesley HARRIS b
1835 TN m Hannah KEY native of Gibson Co., Ind. John Wesley HARRIS
vfritten up in 'History of Gibson Co;inty, Ind. (19K). "Mr. Harris
member of Baptist church . . . family been prominent in the various
localities where its members have lived, and was among the early settlers
of Harrisburg, Dauphin Co., Penn." Need parents of Wiley William HARRIS
and Catherine GUNN (her mother ? CHARLES ) . Lillian Brown Johnson. 307
Mayfield Drive. Smyrna. TN 37167 .
No. 2 ALLEN-JOHNSON Benjamin Franklin ALLEN b 1815 TN m 8 Aug 183^ Jane
JOHNSTON (Johnson) Rutherford Co., TN. Appear in Coffee Co. 1850 Census.
Need parents of Benjamin Franklin ALLEN and Jane JOHNSTON (father Thomas
or Tommie who lived to be nearly 100 and died after 1885). Lillian Brown
Johnson. 307 Mayfield Drive. Smyrna. TN 37167 .
No. 3 BROWN-ROWLAND Lucy ROWLAND b 1808 TN m 12-20-1836 James A. Brown in
Rutherford Co. Lucy had brothers Littleberry, John and William ROWLAND.
Need ROWLAND parents from Virginia. Lillian Brown Johnson. 307 Mayfield
Drive. Smyrna. TN 37167.
No. 4 RAWLINGS (Rollins) - Wm. Rawllngs left will Rutherford Co. 11/18/1828,
Inv. taken 1830 and final payment to heirs on 5/1 /l 84.8. Wife Sarah
Rawllngs and friend Martin Hoover administrators. Sarah still alive
5/I/I848, not seen on 1850 census. Believe to. b. in Virginia and Sarah
In Tennessee. (Was Sarah a HOOVER ?) Children;
Polly(Mary) mar. John D. Fulks 9/8/1 824(need birth/death dates)
Nancy mar. Pleasant Jacobs 8/I9/I829 (Need birth/death dates)
Mathias( Martin H. ?) mar. Louisa Blair 6/3/1834- ? and Polly T. Hoover
3/2^/1842 ?
Piety(BETTI) mar. Archibald Fulks (After Nov. 1828-need marriage/birth/
death dates)
John W. , mar. Elizabeth Brooks 3/3/1837 ? and Martha Bailey 4/19/I843 ??
Joseph M. (John Marshall ?) mar. Martha c184,6 (was she a
Hoover? census shows a MARY HOOVER living with them through
1870 census)
Neffie(Nannie Neffle) mar. \lm. B. Man}d.n c1845? (need exact mar. date, etc.)
Levds J., mar. Elizabeth Hoover, 9/91838(need birth/death date)
Fanny, mar. James Allman, cl845(need mar. date/blrth/death)
Vfci. W., mar. Rebecca Trlbble, 3/5/1845
1820 Rutherford Co. census shows:
Wm. Rawlins - 410010 31010 (mar. Sarah- see above ?) ) BROTHERS ?
John Rollins - 200010 00100(mar. Sarah Hoover, 7/31/1817 ??) )
I would appreciate/exchange any info on any of the above. Rawlings
may have been from Brunswick Co. Va. Daniel Rawlings, b. c1774
Brunswick Co. Va., mar. Clarissa Barnes and he d. 12/27/1845 in
Rutherford Co. Tenn. Clarissa still alive living near Smyrna in
5/26/1871 when she applied for widow's pension for services of Dan-iel
Rawlings in War of 1812, She was living in home of Nancy/Jackson
Smith in I860. Children of this couple are unknown, could be parents
of early Rawlings men.
1830 inventory of estate of Iffa. /Sarah Rawlings shows: 13 slaves by
name; 6 horses, 1 mule, 7 cattle, 26 sheep, 16 hogs, 27 pigs, 1 wagon,
1 gun and other tools, 7 beds with clothing, 1 cupboard/furniture, 1
clock, 1 table and furniture and other necessary things and kitchen
furniture.
Joseph M./Martha . Rawlings(see above) had the following children:
Robert S. (I842-I919) mar. Joanna Fairfield c1879, bur. Bedford Co.
Tenn. (Civil War)
Dawson, b. 0I849&#8212;not seen on 1880 census - need any info
M.T. (female) b. c1852, gone by 1870 census(did she mar. BenJ. Hoover ?)
Christopher H., b. c1854, still living at home 1830 census. Need any info.
JOSEPH SiiUIRE, b. IO/5/I856, mar. widow Virginia (Prater) Fox 3/IO/I886,
moved to Bell Co. Texas in 1890's, d. IO/I 6/1923 (My Great Grandfather)
Sarah, b. c1858, not on 1880 census. Need any info.
Thankful, b. I86I, mar. Joseph Larkin Pinkston 12/6/1877, d. I925 Ruther-ford
Co.
John W., b. CI863, alive on 1880 census. Need any info.
William, b. c1867, gone from 1880 census. Need any info.
Ada, b. 9/2/1870, mar. c1888 J.M. Wood, d. 7/28/1898, bur. Miller Gem.,
Christiana.
Ify Great Aunt; Pearl Rawlings b. I/IO/I89I near Murfreesboro is dau. of
Jos. S. St Virginia Prater Fox Rawlings and tells me she can remember hearing
about the Yankees burning the house &amp; everything in it &amp; leaving "Grandma"
standing in the yard with nothing left but a pair of little boy's "britches"
in her hand. Was "Grandma" a Prater or Rawlings? Families lived Big Spring/
Millersburg/Hoover's Gap area. Would appreciate any info concerning this
war time incident.
Mrs. C. L. Neill. Box 103. Pharr. Texas 78577
PRAT(h)HER - Phillip Prater II and Susannah Hubbard mar. 7/l6/l775 Guilford
Co.NC. Phillip d. 1798 Pendelton Dist., S.C., Susannah remarried to. Ham-mond
and d. I848 Pickens Dist. S.C. - one of their children was Phillip
Prather III, b. c1778, mar. Elizabeth Mayfield (cISOO ?) and died in
Rutherford Co, Tenn. 10/27/1855; probably buried in Big Spring area.
Elizabeth Mayfield Prater also d. 1850-60. Children:
Austin, b. c1801(?) mar. # 1 , #2 Martha ir/oodfln 12/24/18^9
and # 3 Harriet Brinkley 8/26/1 856 (Austin not seen after 1850
census-gone Missouri?)
Cella(Sarah) b. c1802(1860 shows b. Ky.?),mar. Herod(?) Burks (When ?)
Polly said to have mar. Newman
Susan mar. Nelson Green not seen after 1860 census
Jeremiah, b. c1805, mar. Margaret Miller 11/17/1827 and Jane Baird
4/1 5/1867 ? - Said to have gone to Missouri, (where in Missouri ?)
Madison nothing known about this man, not seen on census-died young?
Ellzabeth(Betsy), b. c1822,mar. J.H. Freeman 12/20/1 84.6, had Minerva S. 18^7
and died?
Aaron, b. c1812, mar. Mary Fulks 3/8/l84.5(was he in Clark Go. Ark. in 1854?)
Thomas, b. c1815, mar. Cela(Sarah) Jacobs 8/27/1837 not seen after 1860 census.
Melinda, b. c18l6, mar. Hance Mayfield 9/16/1835, not seen after 1860 census
Elijah, b. c1817,mar. Cynthis Hail 3/5/1837, not seen after 1870
Phillip Jackson, b. 7/20/1820, mar. # 1 Lavinia Brothers, #2 Isabella Kelton
9/U/1854
John A., b. c1 824, mar. # 1 Martha Zumbro 11/8/1843, # 2 Sarah F. Moore
1/5/1856-7.
Monroe, b. c1826,mar. # 1 Caroline Knox 8/27/1847, #2 l-fery Fox ? when? and
married # 3 Margaret Growder 2/6/1867. Not seen after 1870 census
DAVID, b. c1829 mar. Mary Elizabeth Moore 11/24/1857, d. after 1880 census.
(was she a sister to Sarah F. Moore who mar. John A. Prater ??)
William, b. 1832, died at 15 yrs. in 1847.
DAVID PRATER/Mary E. Moore were my Great Great Grandparents. They were
alive on 1880 Rutherford Co, census. Would like to know of biirial place/
tombstone, etc. Family tradidion states that when David was a tiny baby a
bad storm/tornado came up and his mother held him in her arms so tight that
she squeezed his chest out of shape. Children !
Sallie A., b. Dec. 1859, mar. James H. Eads 1881 (where) d. May 191S(where ?)
Virginia Elizabeth(l^ Great Grandmother) ,b. 1 /I O/I &#163;62 , inar . # 1 Joseph Fox
9/15/1879 and # 2 Joseph Sire Rawlings 3/10/1886, she d. 5/23/1950
Bell County, Texas.
Margaret (Maggi e) , b. 1865, mar. J.T. Honeycutt, d. Bell County, Texas.
Mary E., b. 1868, mar. Millard Hicckey nothing known
Udora A. (Dora) b. cApril 1870, mar. Sam Brown nothing known
1-fcrra Dell, b. 10/18/1872, mar. Lewis Dewitt McRae 3/24.1 9U, d. 1/19/1953
at Chattanooga.
Need info as to parents of Mary E. Moore who mar. David Prater. Believe her
mother may have been Elizabeth. Father possibly James Moore ? Would appre-ciate/
share any info on any of above people, ^frs. C. L. Neil, Box 103, Pharr,
Texas 78577
I cannot place the following people in my family lines, would appreciate
any info:
GERMAN D. RAV/LINGS/SARAH M. JONES, 5/25/1 84S mar. in Rutherford Co.
Jajaes L. Rawlings, a Justice of the Peace in 1816
John Rawlins to Sally Hoover, 7/31/1817
Thomas McFarland to Nancy Rawlings, 6/18/1817
Joseph Rollins to Susan Keel, II/I7/I864
James Rollins to Anna Dowell, 6/6/1867
John Johnson to Mariah Rollin, 12/22/1829
Benjamin Rawllngs to Sarah Johnson, 8/1 6/1 81
9
Mrs. C. L. Neil. Box 103. Pharr. Texas 78577
No. 5 I am seeking the parents of Palexina NORTHCUTT (b. ca 1810 Tenn) who married
George W. LORANCE 6 March 1834 in Rutherford County, Tennessee. I believe
her mother was Margaret ? (b. ca 1785 NC), living with LORANCE
family In 1850. Could Palexina 's father be John NORTHCUTT, Rutherford Co.
1810 census (maybe dead by 1820)?
Also desires information on Thomas K. ALLMAN/ALMOND (b. ca 1785 Va.) and
wife Elizabeth ? (b. ca 1786 Va.); their son, Thomas ALLMAN (ba. ca
1825 Tenn), his wife and children: Thomas B. married Maggie FOX, Martha Jane
married James H. FORD, Sarah F. married John G. FORD and Mary Ann married
Ephraim L. MILLER. The three girls moved to Fannin Co., Texas with their
families, believe Thomas B. remained in Rutherford County. I'frs. Jack Her-riage.
Route 2. Pilot Point. Texas 76258.
No. 6 WEBB: I have an 1873 letter from Madison H. WEBB, Fosterville, Rutherford
County, Tenn. to a cousin, Isaac Blackman WEBB in Farmers Branch, Tex., in
which he gives the latest news and locations of many family members. Kiadi-son's
father was Benjamin, his mother, Elizabeth ^iJhiteside REEVES. Madison's
wife was Jane Elinora ELAM and their children were Maggie M. SUTTON, Frank R.,
Jim, Anderson Miller, and Louella MANKIN. Will exchange information. Mrs.
George F. Davis. 5752 Oak Cliff Drive. El Paso. Texas 79912.
No. 7 CROWDER, ROBINS: Seeking parents of Philip CROWDER who served in War of 1812
from Rutherford County and lived near Readyville. Born 1780 in Virginia,
Philip married Charlotte ROBINS b. 1783 in South Carolina, probably Green-ville
Covuaty. Philip and Charlotte moved to White County, Illinois, then
Pike County, Illinois, and Philip died Yolo County, California, after 1850.
Their children were Nancy b. 1807, Robert b. ca 1811, Massa b. 1812, Asa b. a
1816, Susan b. 1821, John, Philip b. ca 1825, Stephen, Mary Ann, Elroyra, and
perhaps Stephen and John H. Philip's youngest brother was Elisha Alexander
Crowder b. Virginia 1784., died Rutherford County 184.2. Mrs. Charles H. Fay
5A03 Beverly Hill Lane. #1. Houston. Texas 77056.
A member of our society is a genealogist: I-Irs. Lalia Lester
1307 W. Northfield Blvd.
Murfreesboro, Tennessee 37130
Tel.: (615) 896-9089
FOREWORD
If variety is the spice of life, the Publication No. 12 of the
Rutherford County Historical Society is a fitting intercalation to an
afterpiece for Publication No. 11 and an exordium for Publication N0.I3.
This edition of the historical records of Rutherford County contains
an Apostle John-like account of one who "saw and heard and touched" those
associated with the establishment and mission of Sewart Air Force Base.
Adeline King:, a member of the civilian staff of the Smyrna installation
from its inception until 1952, has compiled a significant factual record
interpreted with the keen insight of those incidents that make a story
readable.
Ernie Johns has supplemented "The Smyrna Air Base" chronicle with
a record of the major tragedies resulting in casualties on the Base as
recorded in contemporary accounts.
Virginia Gooch Watson has added to the significance of the Smyrna
narrative with the story of Goochland , a typical Rutherford County plan-tation
from its founding by Dr. John C. Gooch to the time that the en-gineers'
bulldozers pushed down the mansion walls to start the major
runway for Sewart Air Force Base.
For those related to the pioneer families the extensive and labor-ious
work of Sue Daniels in compiling the Index of Wills for Rutherford
County wills from I803 through 1883 is of inestimable research value.
Just as the articles in this volume provide an interlude between the
legend of Ben McCulloch, the nostalgic Country Store , and the factual
record of Murfreesboro as the State Capital and the journal of Soule
College in Publication No. 11, it will serve to whet the literary appe-tite
for such stimulating reading as Mabel Pittard's The Coleman Scouts
(another Smyrna-related epic), an eye-witness account of Forrest's raid
on Murfreesboro, a tome on new stones in the City Cemetery, and other
features scheduled for Publication No. 13
.
Gene Sloan
TABLE OF CONTENTS
History of Smyrna (Sewart) Air Base 1
by Adeline King
Goochland 35
by Virginia Gooch Watson
Index to Some Actual Wills of Rutherford
County. Tn 1^02-1^52 53
by Susan Garretson Daniel
Index of Publication Number 12 SB
Index for Publication No. 12
BB
Adams 61-83
Adcock 61
Adkerson 77
Aldrich 8
Alexander 77
Alford 54-70-74
Allen 83
Ambrose 49
Anderson 18-61-70-77-83
Andress 22
Anthony 61
/trmstrong 61
Arnold 2-30-70-83
Arringioa 17
Ashican 61
Atkinson 77
Baes 22
Baker 20-61
Baird 70-83
Ball 83
Ballard 22-70
Bane 22
Barkley 70
Barksdale 61-70
Barnes 83
Barney 77
Barnett 7-61
Baskette 77
Barr 61
Barton 61
Bass 61-77-83
Batey 20-61-70-83
Baugh 83
Beale 2
Beasley 61-70
Beaty 71
Beazley 83
Heeler 5-7-25
Beesley 61-77
Becton 83
Bell 61-77-83
Bellah 61
Bennett 77-83
Benson 83
Benton 38
Berry 61
Bigham 83
Biles 61
Binford 83
Bingham 70
Birthright 61
Bivins 83
Black 61-83
Blackman 61-83
Blackwood 70-83
Blackmore 77
Blanchaxd 17
Blanks 61
Blanton 61
Boles 70
Booker 61
Bone 77
Bonnewell 83
Booth 70
Bowman 61-62-70-83
Bracken 83
Brady 77
Bradford 70
Braley 62
Brandon 70
Brantley 83
Brittain 77
Brooshire 62
Brothers 62-70-83
Brown 20-24-70-77-83
Browning 24-25
Brownlow 30
Bruesch 55
Buchanan 8-36-54-62-77
Buckner 62
Burlason 62
Burnett 62-70
Burns 62
Burrus 62-77
BiH-t 77
Burton 70
Butler 6-62-83
Butts 31-70
Caffy 83
Cain 62
Caldwell 83
S9
Calhoun 70
Campbell 16
Cannon 70-77
Carlock 77
Carlton 77-83
Carnahan 62
Carter 34-62
Cartwright 8-77
Cason 62
Gates 83
Chapman 8-11
Cheatham 62
Childress 62-77-83
Chisenhall 62
Chism 70
Christy 84
Claiborne 84
Clardy 84
Clark 84
Clayton 16-77
Cochran 17
Cock 70
Cocke 64
Coffey 30
Coler,ian 7_8-70-S4
Collier 70-84
Cone 84
Condon 77
Cook 70
Cooke 70-71-84
Cooper 2-3-4- 5-6&lt;
Coppage 84
Cortuii 31
Cotter 62
Coulter 77
Council 84
Coimcill 84
Covington 62-71-84
C0XI9-7I
Craner 84
Cranor 84
Crawford 62-71-77
Creson 77
Crocker 77
Crockett 84
Crosthwait 62-77-78
Crouse 78-84
Crutchfield 62
Gurami.ngs 2-4-24-25
Cureton 18
Currin 71-78
Dameron 62
Danl el 58-78 "
Davidson 62
Davis 8-15-31-62-71-84
Deen 62
Dejarnett 62-84
Delacey 22
Dellinger 78
Dement 71-78
Demtrakppulos 17
Denton 78
DeRusha 16
Descart 62
Dickinson 63-71
Dickson 63-71
Dill 63-71
Dillard 71
Dinney 71
Doak 63
Dodd 8-71
Dodsen 84
Donald 71
Donnell 63-71
Donoho 63
Doran 71
Dovan 63
Downing 84
Duffer 84
Dunaway 71-78
Duncan 22-30-63
Dunn 9_71_78_S4
Durham 3CU34
Earwood 63
Eastman 34
Eaton 78
Edmondson 8-9
Edwards 63-71
Elam 59-63
Elliott 30-63-C4
Ellis 78
Elrod 71-84
Emmanuel 31
Engles 52
Eppes 63
Epps 31
Espey 63
Evans 71
Everett 20
Pagans 63
90
Fagg
Fan
Farmer
Farr
Farris
Faucett
Fenn
Fennegan
Fergus
Ferguson
Field
Finch
Finney
Fitzhugh
Fleming
Floyd
Fly
Flynn
Ford
Forkner
Fosset
Foutch
Fowler
Fox
Franklin
Freeman
Fulk
Fulks
Fuller
Fults
Gans
Gambill
Gambrill
Gannaway
Gardner
Garlington
Garmany
Garrett
Garrison
Gatlin
Gavin
Ga'jway
Gentry
Gerhart
Gettings
Gibbons
Gibson
Gilbert
Giljam
Gill
Glllaspie
Gilliam
63
63
32-78
71
71
78
22 -
16
7
5^
71
63
78
31
71
71-78-84
84
63
63
71
54
5-7
63
78
24
63-78-84
78
71
7i1
63
71
78
78
63
17
53
78
63
63
19
63
78
2
17
7
63
30
32
78
78
64-71
Gillmore
Gooch
Good
Goodlett
Goodloe
Goodman
Gore
Gracy
Grant
Gray
Green
Gregory
Gresham
Grigg
Hale
Hall
Hallibvirton
Hallyburton
Hamilton
Hampton
Hancock
Hardin
Harding
Hannah
Harris
Harrison
Hart
Hartwell
Hayes
Haynes
Hays
Heath
Hedgepath
Heise
Helton
Henderson
Hendreckson
Hibbet
Hicks
Higgenbetham
Hill
Hilton
Hinton
Hodge
Hogg
64
9_36_38-39-40
41-43-46-47-48
4.9_ 50-51-52-53
54-55-56-64-84
64
71
71
64-72-S4
2-34
9
78
50-?4
64-78
64-72
78
64
32-72-84
64-78-84
78
78
64
64
78
22
78
72
16-64-72-78
72
20-64
72
64-72
5-64-72-78-84
&#163;
78
64-84
72
31-78
56-64-C4
18
7-54-64
84
72
9-64-84
30
41
78
36-72
91
Hogwood 64
HoIden 78
Hollars 58
HoHowell 84-85
H0II7 18
Hoobler 34
Hooper 59
Hoover 24-34-72-78-85
Hord 78
Home 64
Ho skin 64-72
House 72-79
Howe 22
Howse 72-85
Howell 64
Hubbard 72-79
Huff 79
Huggins 2-64
Hughes 5-58-85
Hughey 8
Huhta 58-59
Hunt 18-64-85
Hutcheson 64
Ivie 64-79
Jackson 85
Jacob 72
James 64-72
Jameson 79
Jamison 79
Jarmnn 79
Jarratt 64-72-79-85
Jenkins 72-79-85
Jetton 72-79
Johns 7-34-43-4A-46
52-56^64-72-79
Johnson 18-31-64-72
Jones 18-65-72-85
Jordan 65-79-85
Keas 65
Keeble 65-72
Keel 85
Keeling 79
Kelton 65-72
Kerby 85
Kerr 85
Keys 65
Killough 73
Kimbro 36-65-79-85
Kimbrough 38
Kindrick 65
King 1-20
Kinnard 41
Kirk 65-73
Knight 30-65
Knox 17-65-85
Kozuta 17
Kuhn 5
Lamb 85
Landsberger 85
Lane 65-73
Lanier 65
Lantern 73
Lalleau 18
Lark 73-79
Larson 31
Lasater 85
Lawrence 73-85
Lav/son 17
Layne 73
Lean 73
Leatherman 85
Ledbetter 65
Lenoir 79
Lester 9
Lewis 8-22-65-79
Levine 18
Li Hard 73
Linane 16
Lindly 4.7
Lindsey 73-79
Lingow 79
Linster 79
LipsGonb 5
Loftin 65
Long 85
Love 73-79
Lov;e 32-65-79
Lowry 2
Lufkin 31
Lynch 17
Lyon 73-79-25
Lytle 65-73-79-85
tiarby 73-79
92
MacGowan 73
Fiacklin 65
Mallard 79
Malone 73
Maney 79
Manning 65
Manor 73
Manson 85
Marable 65-7&gt;79
liar shall 18-73
Martin 65-73-85
Mason 65-73-79
Mathis 65
Mason 79
Mat son 22
Matthews 73
Maxvell 3-65
May 73-85
MayField 73
Meadows 73
Mendelsohn 58
Merritt 9-79
Meyers 32
Miles 73-79
Miller U-65-73-79-85
Mitchell 73-79-85
Moffett 30
I'iolloy 79
Monahan 16
Montgomery 65-73
^body 26-65
Moore 9-22-55-65-66-73-'
80
Morgan 80
Morris 66
Morrison 47-55
Morton 32-41-66-73-80
Moseby 66
Moss 9
1-killins 66-73
Murfree 73 y
M\irphy 31
Muse 73-80
Ijyrick 80
McAdoo 80-85
McAlhatton 66
McBride 32
McCaib 66
McCarty 34
McClaran 85
McClusky 52
McCoy
McCrary
McGullock
McDaniel
McDowell
McElhatten
McElroy
McEwen
McFadden
McFarlin
McGill
McGregor
McHenry
Mclver
McKee
McKeen
McKellar
McKnight
Mclfeirray
McNeil
McNickle
Nance
Neal
Neely
Nelson
Newman
Nickolas
Nickols
Nickson
Nisbett
Nivins
Noe
Norman
North
Northcott
Northcutt
O'Dell
Oden
Oliphint
Oliver
Ott
Overall
Owen
Palmer
Parish
Parker
Parks
Parrish
Patrick
Patterson
Paul
66
80
73-80
85
80
80
73-86
66
73
66-86
66
54-66
66-86
66
80
66
1-2
54.-66-73-80-86
48
86
22
eo-86
54-80
24-51-52-56
35-36-66-73-74-80
74-86
66
86
66
80
74
80
64-66-74-SO
66-SO
74
74-86
2-3
66
74
16
86
9-66-80-86
86
7-4C
66
66-74-80-36
66
80
66
31-66-80
67
93
Peak 7^-80 Richardson 67
Richey 56
Pearcy 86 Richards 19
Peebles 8 Ridley 8-34-44-52
Peek 74 67-81-86
Ridout 81
Penn 67 Riggs 17
Perry 30 Riley 34
Peter 20 Ring 81
Robb 81
Petty 80 Roberson 67
Roberts 67-81
Peyton 80 Robertson 67-86
Phelps 86 Robinson 67-86
Phillips 5-I5-24-74.-8O Robison 74
Rogers 67-74-S6
Pierce 80 Rosenfeld 86
Pitts 74 Ross 74
Poe 67 Roulhac 74
Pointer 86 Rovfe 30
Posey 74-86 Rovfland 86
Potter 8 Rowlet ^ 74
Powell 67 Rowlett 81
Price 67-74 Routon 67
Priest 2 Rucker 8-67-74-81
Prindle 21-22 Russell 19-86
Pritchett 80 Rutledge 74
Puckett 67-74-80
Pullen 67 Sagg 67
Putlak 31 &#8212;Sanders 7- 52-74-6 1-86
Putman 20 Sanford 86
Saimders 31-38-39
Ragon 2 Sercy 67-74-81
Rainey 67 Seat 67
Seward 74
Rake 31
Ralston 80 Sewart 24
Ralph 86 Sharpe 67
Randolph 67-80 Shelton 86
Rankin 67-74 Sherwood 67
Rajisoia 67-74-81-86 Ship 67
Short 86
Raspet 19
Rather 46 Sikes 81
Siranon 11
Rawlings 67 Simnons 81
Read 67-74-81 Slii55son
,
34
Ready 81 Sims 74-86
Reed 86
Reeder 81 Singleton 74
Reese 74 Sinnott 8-15
Reeves 81 Slack 87
Raid 86 Sledd 67
Revel 67 Sloan 31-34
Rhodes 49-81 Siaart 81
94
Spivey 31 Umstead 1 4.- 15-22
Smigh 29-31-67-68-74-75-81-S7 Underwood 68
Sraothernan 81-87
Sneed 75 Yandike 68
Span 87-75 Van Sicklen 22
Spain 75 Vaughan 68-75-81-82-87
Spence 68-75-81 Vaught 68-S7
S tailings 31 Vincent 75
Standridge 75
Stansel ^1 Wade 31-75-C2-87
Statham 68 V/alker 68-75
Staton 75 V/alden 87
Statui.i 75 Waller 68-75
Stegar 81
Stewart 2-68 Wallis 68
Still 68 Walls 31
Stockerd 68 VJalpole 75
Stoikowltz 18
Walsh 1
Stovall 87 Ward 54-68-75-C2
Strickland 18 Warren 30-68
Stroop 87 Washington 68
Stroup 68 Watkins 75-82
V/atson 35-53
Sublett 81
Sugg 6S V/eakley 9-53
Sullivan 2^-68 Weatherly 68-69
Summers &#163;7
Webb 75
Sundius 31 Welch : 69-75-87
Sutterlin 22 Wendal 55_75-&#163;;7
Suttle 87 West 69
Sutton 68 White 75
VJhitfield 69
S',;an 81 l-Jhitnel 69
Svank 81 VJhoberry 69
Wigger 69
Tanberg 22
Tarplej 81 V/illiams 22-38-69-75-82
Taylor 36-68-81 V/illiamson 69
Tennesson 68 'Wills 75-82
Thacker 68-75
Thomas 68 Wilson 39_ 52^-69-75
Thoiiipson 68-75-81-87 Windrov; 69-87
Thorn 75
Thiorinan 75 Winn 69
Tilley 68 Winsett 82-87
Tilljnan 31 Winston 82-87
Tinch 81 Wiseman 2-4
Todd 81
Toiiipkins 87 Witherspoon 76
Travis 87 Woraack 87
Traylor 75-87 Wood 69-82
Trimble 81
Tucker 75-81 Woods 76
Turner 81 Vfoodson 87
95
V/orke 76-87
Woolridge 82
Wrather 82
Wright 34^69-76-87
i/uest 1
Wurzel 32
Yandell 69-76
lardley 76
learwood 69
York 17
Youree 69-76
Yous 69
DATE DUE
-
catloud '"""""""*'
Call Number
T
976.857
R9^1p
V.12
79-litl89
Rutherford Coimty Hist. Society
AUTHOR
Publication
TITLE
"~~
LIBRARY
MIDDLE TENNESSEE STATE UNIVERSITY
MURFREESBORO. TENNESSEE
^^H MIDDL
3 3082 00527 7032
'(
HIGHSMITH # 45220
Js'^7^7/
'KiUt'SJiSitti;?.
</dc:description>
<dc:description>This volume contains several articles, each of which is treated separately in this collection and can be searched individually</dc:description>
<dc:description>History of Smyrna (Sewart) Air Base -- Goochland -- Index to Some Actual Wills of Rutherford County, Tn 1802-1882
</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.); United States. Air Force; Rutherford County Historical Society; Wills</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Sewart Air Force Base</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Periodical</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>222 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-01; mt2011-05-20</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication12ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/69</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>