<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>The role of Stone's River in the early exploration, trade, and settlement of Rutherford County, Tennessee</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Lawson III, Samuel J</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 18</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1981</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>18th century; 19th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>B9
THE ROLE OF STONE'S RIVER IN THE
EARLT EXPLORATION, TRADE, AND SETTLEMENT
OF RUTHERFORD CODNTT, TENNESSEE
Samuel J. Lawson III
August 1981
90
PREFACE
When one examines a contemporary map of Rutherford County, it will
come to hia attention that there are two prominent features on the face
of the county, ie., Interstate Highway 21* and Stone's River. Both the
highway and the river have many things in common. Today in 1981, the
highway is a route both to the market and from market for many goods
leaving and entering Rutherford County. Besides being a route for trade
and commerce, Interstate Highway 2k also serves as a major transportation
route for people travelling through the area. Obviously, the movement of
people and trade goods through the county means an increase in the area's
economic well-being. The benefits of Interstate Highway 2k are well
known to the residents of today's Rutherford County.
Years ago, the traffic of people and commerce into and out of the
Rutherford County area came via Stone's River. The river served in much
the same capacity as Interstate 2k does today. The river supplied a "Natural
Highway" by which the county's produce was sent to market and by which
commercial items were brought into the county. The river traffic of those
days also brought an economic prosperity along with new settlers.
People coming into the area were from different ethnic backgrounds
and thus contributed many cultural treasures to the area's heritage. Follow-ing
the course of the river, many Rutherford County settlers found new
homesteads along its banks. Thus the river gratly influenced the pattern
of settlement in the county. These various pioneer settlers had different
needs which directly effected the supply and demand for goods as well as
91
the types of goods transported over the Stone's River trade route.
As Interstate Highway 21* provides today's area residents with both
transportation and trade connections to the remainder of the United States,
Stone's River also gave earlier Rutherford Countians outside connections.
The Stone's River flows into the Cumberland River which in turn flows into
the Ohio River, thus giving access to the Mississippi River. This gave
river traffic connections to the great trade centers of New Orleans,
Natchez, Vicksburg, Memphis, Cairo, St. Louis, Cincinnati, Vheeling,
and Pittsburgh. Thus the benefits of the navigation of Stone's River
were well known to the people of Rutherford County in previous tines.
It becones evident that the Stone's River afforded Rutherford County
with a portion of the great Mississippi River tradition of river life and
transportation. This is a notable aspect of the area's history which has
previously been either forgotten or ignored.
The following account of the river's role in the early exploration,
trade and settlement of Rutherford County is presented with the hope that
present-day residents may begin to understand the past greatness of Stone's
River and its importance to the county.
92
DESCRIPTION
The Stone's River is a prominent tributary of the Cumberland River
and has a drainage of 921* square miles. The Vest Fork and the Middle Fork
are in Rutherford County in their entirety. The East Fork originates in
a large mineral spring near Woodbury in Cannon County, flows across the
northern half of Rutherford County, and joins the West Fork after the latter
has received the waters of the Middle Fork. The Main Channel, formed by
the union of the East and West Forks, continues a general northwestward
course through the remainder of Rutherford County to enter Davidson County.
The river continues its northwestward drainage, passing through Donelson,
and empties Into the Cumberland River near Neely's Bend. The distance from
the mouth of Stone's River to its East Fork origin in Cannon County is
approximately 82 miles if measured along the meanders, however the distance
straight across the land from mouth to origin is only hh miles. Thus it
is easily seen that the river is filled with bends and meanders. The actual
meander length for the Main Channel is 38.6 miles, East Fork U6 miles, and
West Fork 25 miles.
The point at which the East Fork and the West Fork join became the site
of the town of Jefferson, the first county seat of Rutherford County. Jeff-erson's
location at the forks of tine Stone's River resulted in the later
development of the town as a river port. Just one mile downstream from Old
2
Jefferson was Jefferson Springs, a popular summer resort of the 1920's era.
A brief look at a county map reveals that the Walter Hill community
is located on the East Fork about 5 miles east of the site of Jefferson.
It can also be seen that 9 miles further upstream is Bradley's Creek, on the
93
banks of which is located the village of Laacaaaas. The village is
adjacent to the river. Bran farther upstream is the village of Ready-ville
which is located at the juncture of the East Pork and the Rutherford/
Cannon County line, Hurfreesboro is the only town of considerable size
on the river and is located about 15 miles by river fro* Jefferson up the
West Fork. The famous Civil War battle of 31 December 1862 and 2 January
1863, centered around the river on the northwestern edge of Marfreeaboro.
However the greatest feature that the map Shows along the course of the
river is the Percy Priest Reservoir. This man-made lake was created in
1966 by the United States Army Corps of Sigineers. The river waa impounded
by a dam located 6.8 miles from the mouth of the river adjacent to the old
Stewart' a Perry bridge and formed a U2 mile long reservoir when the waters
were backed up. The lake today is extensively used by loca"1 residents for
boating, fishing, swimming, camping and other forma of recreation.
94
Figure 1 i Map of the Stone's River
drainage area
95
EARLT EXPLORATION AND SETTLEMENT
Stone' 6 River first appears In written history about 167U when
French explorers who penetrated the interior of Tennessee froa the
Illinois country, encountered the Shawnee Indians. The Shawnee at
that time were located along the Cumberland River with a large settle-ment
near present-day Nashville. Stone's River was within the hunting
grounds of the Shawnee. These hunting grounds were the object of great
controversy among the Indians. They were coveted by both the Chickasaw
and the Cherokee. The matter came to a violent conclusion in 171U. About
1710, a French trader, Jean du Charleville, from Crosat's colony at New
Orleans, established a store or trading post "on a mound on the west side
of the Cumberland River, near French Lick, in the Shawnee country," near
the present site of Nashville. As a result of the hunting controversy,
in 171 h Charleville and a party of Shawnee were attacked and killed by a
band of Chickasaw. During the ensuing conflict, the combined force of the
Chickasaw and Cherokee forced the Shawnee to retreat north of the Ohio River
and vacate the Central Basin of Tennessee.
The early French explorers referred to the Cumberland Basin area of
Tennessee as the land of the "Chaouanon" River. Translated this meant
"Shawnee River" which is known today as the Cumberland. The French were
also the first permanent settlers of European origin in the Middle Tennessee
area. Martin Chartier, a deserter from the LaSalle expedition on the
Mississippi River, married a Shawnee woman and subsequently settled with
her people at their settlement at French Lick (present-day Nashville) and
resided there about 3 years. Between 1692 and 169U, a group of the Piqua
96
Shawnee moved eastward into Pennsylvania to join others that had pre-viously
removed there from the western areas and Chartier accompanied
these Piqua Shawnee. Later, he returned with his eon, Peter, and settled
again at French Lick. Perhaps it was due to the influence of Chartier
that French traders had worked and hunted in the Cumberland Basin since
about 1685.*
The next Frenchman to settle in the Nashville area was only the
vangard for an influx of explorers that came into the area in the late
1760's. Jacques-Timothe DeMontbrun, a French Canadian fur trader, began
to operate in the Nashville area during the mid-1 760' s. DeMontbrun came
to Tennessee from Kaakaskia, Illinois and eventually brought his wife and
settled in a cave on the Cumberland River near the mouth of Mill Creek in
present-day Davidson County. Records show that DeMontbrun used the "natural
highway" of the area in his trading. He ascended the rivers of the area
many times and used "a large boat" with 6 or 8 hands and thus hunted and
trapped for many years in the region about Nashville. It is highly probable
that he used the Stone's River as an access to the rich hunting in the
Rutherford County area.
Shortly after DeMontbrun' s arrival in the area, parties of long hunters
from Virginia crossed the Appalachian Mountains and began to explore and
hunt in Tennessee and Kentucky. Cne such group was headed by Colonel James
Smith. Among the men that accompanied Smith was a man named Uriah Stone.
When the party had reached the Cumberland Basin, the hunters separated to
hunt and explore. The year was 1766, when Uriah Stone discovered a blue-green
stream emptying into the Cumberland River. He followed the stream
97
southward to a point where it divided into two rivers, one fork to the
east and one to the west. After re-joining Colonel Smith's party, Stone
7
told then of the river and thus the hunters called it "Stone's River".
1 few vears later, in 1768, Lieutentant Thomas Hutchins of the Royal
Engineers, British Amy, was eoanaissioned by his government to survey the
topography and hydrography of the western frontier. Included in his
survey area was the Cumberland Basin of Tennessee. Hutchins accomplished
his mission in part through the construction of a boat which was to be used
as a transport for the engineer surveying party. The result was the Gage,
an "armed galley" which was converted from a bateau at Kaakaskia, Illinois.
Hutchins 1 "gunboat" had 2U oars and carried a crew of 35 men. In 1769* at
the conclusion of his survey work along the Cumberland River, Hutchins'
group scouted out the lower reaches of Stone's River. The results of the
expedition, in the form of descriptions and maps, were published in London
in 1777. The published map, based on Hutchins' information designated the
Cumberland River as "Shawanoe River", after the Shawnee Indians, and Stone's
8
River as "Fish Creek".
The Stone '8 River in the 1760's was a different river than it is now.
It may have flooded occasionally in seasons of extreme rainfall, but it
appears that the river had a uniform flow because the soil was deep and
covered with grass and forests all along the river's meanders and tributaries.
9
The water is thought to have been deep and swarming with fish.
Uriah Stone returned to the area in 1 770 with a group of 1 long hunters
including Kasper Mansker. At the end of their hunting in Middle Tennessee,
the hunters met on the Cumberland River, near the mouth of Stone's River,
93
Figure 2: Drawing of a Colonial
British Scouting Vessel similar
to that used by Lt. Hutchins
99
and built two boats and two trapping canoes. These were loaded with furs
and bear neat. The group found a deserted boat which they added to their
"flotilla" and later moved down the Cumberland River. They planned to go
to Natchez to dispose of the goods and purchase much needed supplies, ill
went well until they reached the mouth of the Cumberland, tfcen the group
stopped in order to render some spoiling meat into oil, they were overtaken
by a mountain man, John Brown, and 25 of his followers who promptly robbed
10
Stone's party of 2 guns, some ammunition, salt and tobacco.
The years 1768-1769 saw the birth of commercial transportation on the
rivers of Middle Tennessee in the area of the Central Basin. Joseph Holl-ingsworth
was employed by a trading house in Philadelphia to come to the
Cumberland Territory and supervise the killing of game and the packing of
meat in casks for the New Orleans market and the garrison at Fort Chartres,
Illinois. Hollingshead's hired hands worked an area of 300 miles along the
Cumberland River and employed 20 pirogues to transport goods. No doubt
this enterprise exploited the Stone's River area.
Early use of canoes and pirogues had been made by the Indians of the
region. The Shawnee were famed for fine canoes. These canoes were actually
"dug-outs" made from single logs. The Caribbean Indians called them "piraguas";
a term adopted by the Spanish and later by the French and English as the
"pirogue". Using the Indian method of construction, a 20-foot pirogue would
require h days to make. Indian war parties at times used pirogues which
held over 20 warriors. The largest of this type craft were approximately
50 feet long and 5 feet wide and could carry 30 men or an estimated 50 tons
of cargo. These large pirogues were steered with an oar at the stern and
100
propelled with either poles or paddles. The craft also could be "com-partmentalized"
for cargo when small bulwarks, made during construction,
divided the hull into spaces h to 6 feet long. This is the same craft that
was adopted and used by the early English and French fur traders. Pirogues
were used for rapid transport of salt to settlers and transport of cargo to
12
trading posts.
Figure 3: Pirogue
Jabob Sandusky, a Pole, took a cargo of skins and tallow down the
Cumberland River to New Orleans in 177U* He is creditted as being the first
white man to make such a voyage. He probably was indeed the first man to
establish a new pattern for the exportation of products from the Cumberland
Basin by showing the relative ease of following the downstream current of
the rivers to the Mew Orleans market, rather than hauling goods overland.
DeMontbrun also carried hides and tallow to Mew Orleans by boat in 1776.
Ill
101
Sandusky's route to the New Orleans market was to become "standard
operating procedure for the exporters of the Cumberland Basin for many
years to come.
A few years after Sandusky's voyage, Rufus Putnam arrived with a
party of settlers at Marietta, Ohio. Putnam's landing was not significant
for navigation as his cruise was. Putnam travelled in the galley Adventure.
This vessel was U7 feet long, 12 feet wide with a curved, raking bow and
the lines of a coasting boat. Such a craft was not unusual, but quite
similar to the vessels used by the military and was patterned after a "ship's
boat" or shallop. A shallop is described as a "shoal-draft keel vessel
having a bluff bow and a square stern" with dimensions similar to those of
Putnam's Adventure . Although this Instance was not out of the ordinary,
it was a shadow of what was to come. The shallop-type vessel was of course
a keel vessel which made it markedly different from craft that had been
used previously. It's most outstanding characteristics are its stability
and streamlined design. The Indian pirogue was a much more primitive craft.
The French bateau was more like the shallop/keel vessel but did have several
major differences. This kind of craft was a keel-less, flat-bottomed boat
with ends tapering to points, built of planks. Small vessels of this type
were called skiffs. The bateau was propelled by oars, setting poles, or
square sails and was steered by means of either an oar or a rudder. 18 or
20 rowers were employed to man the crew. The vessels were often equipped
with an awning or wooden shelter for a cabin in the rear. The halcyon days
of the bateau were between 175U and 1790. Bateaux built during the American
Revolutionary War were described as UO feet long, 9 feet wide, and 32 inches
102
deep. Both the bateaux and the keel-type vessels were to beooae fore-runners
of later river craft.
1779 and 1780 saw the plans and schemes of James Robertson and John
Oonelson begin to take shape and be put Into action. These sen were the
motivators behind the Cumberland Settlements in Tennessee and became the
"founding fathers" of the settlements. Reams of material has been written
concerning this because of its great Impact on Middle Tennessee, but this
colonization project also had a tremendous effect on navigation and Stone's
River in particular.
The expedition to settle the Cumberland River area around the old
French Lick in today's Davidson County had direct bearing on the settlement
of Rutherford County. The caravan of settlers came by two different routes
with Robertson leading one group overland through Kentucky from the Watauga
settlements of East Tennessee, and Oonelson setting out from Fort Patrick
Henry on the Holston River. Donelson was to lead a flotilla of over 1*0
flatboats loaded with settlers down the Holston River to the Tennessee past
present-day Chattanooga into Alabama over Muscle Shoals back into Tennessee
then into Kentucky to the mouth of the Tennessee River on the Ohio River.
From this point, the flotilla was to travel upstream to the mouth of the
Cumberland and thus up that stream to the bluff near French Lick at present-
17
day Nashville.
The Donelson voyage marked the introduction of 2 new ideas. First,
the mass transport of settlers by water transportation. This was something
that had not been tried before, but nevertheless seemed to set the style
because later many western settlers began to travel by water when this means
103
of transport was available. Second, due to his success, Oonelson ushered
In the era of the flatboat, When it became the major vehicle of river
transportation. But In a much more direct way, Donelson was to Influence
what was to happen on the Stone's River when he later would be personally
involved in the settling of pioneers along its banks.
Flatboats, like those used by Donelson, were in use on the western
rivers as a means of transportation by 1?80 and no doubt sooner. The craft
retained its importance in transportation until its use peaked in 18U6-18U7-
Thereafter the use of flatboats declined until the American Civil Mar put
an end to its use.
18
rVc^
Figure ht Family Flatboat
104
A typical flatboat could be described as a simple affair looking lite
a flat-bottomed box with a shed-like shelter built over the interior cargo
space for the protection of either the cargo or the passengers and crew.
Flats used by the government in the 1790's were 12 to 1li feet wide and U5
to 50 feet long on the average, although the sizes of flats in general were
varied. Burdens varied according to size, with the average flatboat hold-ing
between 1*0 and 50 tons of cargo. The steering aboard a flat was done
via a 30 to l*0-foot oar that was pivoted in a forked stick to the roof or
to a porthole in the stern. Two or more sweeps similarly pivoted on the
sides were used to keep the boat in the current. The boat's crew demanded
19
2 men and a steersman.
The flatboat was essentially a downstream craft and was generally float-ed
downstream to the desired destination and upon arrival was broken up.
After being broken up, the timber thus attained was then used for other
construction purposes or sold for a profit by the boat owner. The average
flatboat used by a settler's family was 30 to 1*0 feet long. When the cost
was calculated, the flatboat could have been relatively expensive for a pioneer.
Estimates place the cost between $1 .00 and $1 .25 per foot, thus with cable,
20
pump, etc., the vessel could cost approximately $50.00 total.
In 1780, John Donelson's flotilla landed at Cedar Bluff near the French
Lick and met Robertson's settlers to begin the task of settling the area of
present-day Nashville. Tradition tells that "Timothy'' DeMontbrun paddled
down the river in his canoe to greet the new residents. However, Donelson
made only a short stop at the Bluff, staying Just a few days without unload-ing
his flatboat, the Adventure. After seeing the pioneers were safely
105
arrived and getting along well, Donelson and his family boarded the
Adventure and set out upon the Cumberland River pushing her against the
current. Upstream they came to the mouth of Stone 1 s River. Upon reach-ing
this point, the vessel was pushed up the Stone's River about U miles
and landed on May 1st, 1780 in a large meadow of white clover. The site
became known as "Clover Bottom", the name it still carries today. Donelson 's
group built cabins and Ranted crops of corn and cotton. By 1783, the
21
settlement became known as "Stone's River" or "Donelson's Station." The
river's history had entered into a period of pioneer settlement.
At this same time in 1783, the State of North Carolina began the survey-ing
of the lands that were to be given in grants to the soldiers for their
service during the American Revolutionary War. These surveys included the
Stone's River drainage area. In 1786, North Carolina issued these land
grants and some of these such as the grants to Samuel Wilson, Hardy Murfree
and Archibald Iytle were located deep within the area now known as Rutherford
County. Due to troubles with the Indian tribes of the area during the
1780&#187;s and 1790's, it is thought that most Rutherford County pioneers made
22
no permanent settlements in the county until about 1795.
Nevertheless, Donelson's settlement at Clover Bottom evidently began
a movement to settle the banks of the Stone's River and its tributaries.
William Stewart of Fife-Shire, Scotland, had arrived in Middle Tennessee
with Donelson's flotilla. In 178U, Stewart came to Stone's River and settled
on the eastern bank near the site of the later built bridge on Stewart's
Ferry Road about 7 miles upstream from the mouth of the river. By the spring
of 1788, about 23 miles further upstream according to the deed records of
106
Davidson County, in which portions of today's Rutherford County wore
located, John Bowen and Robert Spotswood Russell apparently had residences
23
along Stewart's Creek, a tributary of the Stone's River. This area of
Rutherford County has been referred to as a fertile area and probably
played a large part in the production of produce to be sent to market.
Statistics show that in 1788, the settlers of Kentucky and Tennessee sent
$22^,000 of produce down the rivers to New Orleans. Sandusky's earlier
voyage to the New Orleans markets had not been in vain. When the Mississ-ippi
River was opened "free" to American trade by a treaty between Spain
and tile United States in 1792, commerce with New Orleans markets rapidly
increased.
During the first two decades of the Cumberland Settlements, goods had
been imported by wagon from the East. These goods were purchased in
Philadelphia or Baltimore and brought over the Appalachian Mountains on
pack horses. Wagons were sometimes used. However at an early date, the
wagons were hauled from Philadelphia to Pittsburgh, where they were
transferred to flatboats and floated down the Ohio River to the Cumberland
River thence to the Nashville area. This early import trade used overland
transportation although the export trade of Middle Tennessee was from the
25
beginning almost exclusively a water-borne commerce.
Settlers were moving into the area of present-day Rutherford County
by 1795. Samuel Wilson resided temporarily at the forks of the Stone's
River in 1 788-1 789. During this time he planted Rutherford's first corn
crop. Wilson later erected a permanent settlement at Wilson's Shoals on
the Stone's River near the National Cemetery about 11* miles up the West Fork
107
from his first residence. Wilson and Nimrod Menifee settled this area
about 1797* About the sane time, settlers were constructing their home-steads
on Stewart's Creek. This party of pioneers included Owen Edwards,
Thomas Nelson, William Atkinson, Thomas Howell and John Etta. Cver on the
East Fork, Thomas Rucker was locating his home near today's Veterans Admin-istration
Hospital. By 1799, William Iytle set up his abode on the West
26
Fork in present-day Murfreesboro.
The significance of these pioneers' movements and settlement patterns
is that they are bound up with Stone's River. Carlton Sims summed up the
situation by saying that "the most important stream of immigrants into the
27
county (Rutherford) came up Stone's River from Davidson CCunty." Some of
these moved up the East Fork, while others moved up the West Fork. The
majority seemed to have followed the West Fork, erecting homesteads on
Stewart's Creek, Overall Creek and Iytle Creek. By following the river's
course and the dates of settlement, one can easily see the pattern of develop-ment
in Rutherford County's early history. Beginning with Done 1 son at Clover
Bottom in 1780 to Stewart in 1781*, three miles further upstream and on to
Wilson at the forks of the river in 1 788, the settlements reached 38 miles
upriver in about 8 years. After another 10 years, they reached to Murfrees-boro
on the West Fork and to Lascassas and beyond on the East Fork, so that
28
by 1800, Readyville was being established.
1800 was a year of change in the river history of our area. The hunting
era on the frontier was gradually being replaced by the agricultural era
with the increase in the number of pioneers raising crops. Cotton was the
major export product of the Cumberland Basin with tobacco taking second place.
103
rr*J"*?
:kny.
"-5
ft^xsixxA- syr^uasTKck-** rx&gt; &lt;*- &lt;*&amp;lcA QaM- erry- tnx.
&lt;&amp;cvn$fimltLSlIXA^tfl
ci-^ii -..
Figvire 5&#187; Survey map of the 1 78U grant
of William Stewart on Stone's
River
109
Ifade and commerce were becoming acre water-borne. The Mississippi River
had been opened for comaere e and the freight rate for wagon transportation
was at $10 per 100 pounds. The rate for water transport was $6.75 per 100
pounds of goods. Practical business sense dictated a turn from land trans-port
to water transport for trade. The Cumberland Basin area was exporting
the "productions of the country" by boat downriver to New Orleans and was
receiving goods from Philadelphia via Pittsburgh and the rivers. Flatboat-men
would upon their arrival at New Orleans sell the cargo as well as the
29
boat and would then return home along the Natchez Trace. However, the most
significant development was the introduction of a river craft called a
"keel-boat".
Figure 6 j River Scene Showing
A Flatboat and Two Keelboats
110
The keel-boat seems to have developed as a combination of the military
galley or shallop-type vessel and French bateau. These vessels were created
in order to both ascend and descend rivers due to their stream-lined con-figuration.
The ordinary keel-boat was between U0 and 80 feet long, 7 to
10 feet wide with a shallow keel and was sharp at both ends. The vessel's
loaded draft was about 2 feet, rendering it well adapted for use in shallow
river water. The mid-section of the boat was usually covered in part by
a cabin or cargo box that had an inside clearance of about 6 feet. All
around the gunwales ran a cleated footway, 12 to 18 inches wide, where the
crew walked while poling the boat upstream. At the bow were seats for rowers
used when the boat was propelled by U to 12 oarsmen. The steering was done
by means of a long oar pivoted at the stern and extending 10 to 12 feet
beyond the boat. This "rudder" was operated by the steersman, who was usually
the boat's captain, sometimes called the boat's patroon. The burden of the
keel-boats ranged between 15 and 50 tons, but usually it was less than 30
tons. If the boat was covered by a cabin extending the total length of the
vessel, it was called a "barge".
Figure 7: Barge
Ill
In June of 1809, the Nashville newspapers announced the arrival of a
typical fceelboat/Wge in the following Banner. "Arrived at this place
(Nashville) on Saturday last, the elegant barge Mary Anne, Capt. Sprigg,
27 days from New Orleans, burthen 57 tons. This barge is 87 feet long and
upwards of 15 feet wide...Built at Cincinnati at a cost of $11 00... is now
completely equipped with masts, Spars, and rigging, and is an excellent
sailer. She is worked by 22 hands... amount of freight was upwards of $5000."
Not only were keelboats propelled by setting poles and oars but when
conditions were favorable and the situation warranted, sails were employed.
The Tennessee Legislature, on 13 November 1801, declared Stone's River
to be navigable "to the main West fork" of the river and thus the river was
protected by the law for navigation. This act began a new phase in the
32
history of the river.
31
112
COMMERCIAL NAVIGATION
Once Stone's River was declared navigable, many Individuals quickly
grasped the chance to get ahead in this new business of water-borne commerce.
One of Nashville's enterprising merchants, John Coffee, got into the
business as early as 1803. Coffee owned several barges and fceelboats which
he employed in the New Orleans trade. The names of two of these, the
Resolution and the Adventure, have been preserved. However, the earliest
record of Coffee's involvement is found in his personal papers. The record
consists of the bill of lading of the boat Child which is dated 2 March 1801
.
The destination of the Child was New Orleans and her cargo included salt-
33
petre, pork, corn, cotton, tobacco and slaves. Goods brought up to the
Cumberland Basin from New Orleans consisted of those things not easily obtain-
31*
ed locally such as sugar, coffee, and various groceries.
John Coffee was later to do business on the Stone's River, but local
residents had already begun, starting almost immediately after the river
had been declared navigable. It soon became evident that the chief port
on the river was to be Jefferson. This was mainly due to the town's
advantageous location at the forks of the river. About this time a local
interest was started at Jefferson in the way of freighting the commerce
of the community to New Orleans by way of Stone's River and the Cumberland,
which awakened an interest in the community for river travel. Many people
envisioned the Stone's River as becoming an important artery of commerce.
Then in 1803, Moses Ridley and John Buchanan asked permit of the State to
build a mill dam on the river about 10 miles downstream from Jefferson. The
leading citizens of Jefferson held a public meeting and dispatched a resolution
113
of protest to the General Assembly t
"That If our Honorable, the Senate and House of
Representatives, do not think it expedient to
secure to us the navigation of Stones river,
according to a former law, and in opposition to
certain petitions to legalize obstructions in
the navigation of said river, we will be forced,
again to think our rights infringed, and our
interests disregarded. Wherefore, your memorial-ists
respectfully pray, that your honorable body
will take into consideration our peculiarly
critical situation, and by rejecting all petitions
to obstruct the navigation of Stones river to the
town of Jefferson."
The State allowed the construction of the mill dam, but required that the
builders install navigation locks to facilitate the safe passage for all
vessels. The locks were specified to be at least 67 feet long and 16 feet
wide. Ridley and Buchanan built both the dam and the lock at a location
on the Stone's River that is now located under the waters of Percy Priest
Lake. The site was later known as Jones' Mill and was approximately 28
miles from the mouth of the river.
Just as with any settlement that developed along the rivers of Middle
Tennessee, Jefferson began to send an incresing number of boats down Stone's
River to eventually reach New Orleans. William Nash owned a trade-store in
Jefferson about 1803. lesh's store sold dry goods, groceries, gunpowder
and lead as well as whiskey. Nash was at this time exporting ox-hides, wolf-scalps,
deer skins, deer "saddles'', 'coon skins as well as farm produce,
grain and meat to New Orleans via flatboat. These boats took a month or
more to complete the journey. Gtods coming into Jefferson were purchased
largely in Pittsburgh and brought to Jefferson by river. Nash was not the
only pioneer making use of the river's "natural highway". The Tennessee
114
General Assembly received a petition on 26 August 1803 requesting that the
navigation of Stone's liver be kept open iron Cumins Mill to the mouth of
37
the river in order to carry produce to market. Cummins Mill was located
on the East Fork near Providence Church in today's Walter Hill community.
38
1803 also saw the creation of Rutherford County on the 25th of October.
By this time, John Coffee, George Poyzer, Christopher Stump and Messrs.
Rappier, Turner, Spriggs, et. al. became the leading men of the keelboat
business in Nashville. The principal export items of Nashville included
tobacco, corn, indigo, hogs, horses, flour and cotton. But Nashville was
not alone, Jefferson was also exporting produce. The flatboat Kitty, John
Smith, Master and tie flatboat Salley McGee, James K. Benson, Master, arrived
at New Orleans on the first of May 1805, with cargoes of corn. The corn
had been shipped by Mark Mitchell from Jefferson on Stone's River. Later
in 1807, the settlement near Cummins Mill sent a flatboat carrying a 1*0 ton
39
cargo of farm produce down the river to the market in Nashville.
Figure 8: Flatboat
115
In the spring of 1805, John Coffee joined with Andrew Jackson and
John Hutohlngs as business partners and formed the firm of Jackson, Hutchlngs
and Company. The firm owned and operated the Jackson store at Clover
Bottom near the Lebanon turnpike bridge over Stone's River. The store sold
some items that had come from Philadelphia, where Jackson had purchased them
in 1801*. He had the merchandise sent by wagon to Pittsburgh and from there
by boat to the mouth of the Cumberland River where they transferred the goods
into John Coffee's keelboat. Then Coffee brought it back to Clover Bottom
on Stone's River. The items included whiskey, wine, brandy, nails, bottles,
alum, sulphur, silk, linen, broadcloth, needles, thread, paper pins, buttons,
UO
combs, barrels of salt, sugar, flour, bacon, bar iron, shot and gunpowder.
The business enterprise at Clover Bottom also received merchandise from
New Orleans. Records of the Port of New Orleans indicate that the barge
Relief , a large keelboat, Willis Wright, Master, departed there on 8 May 1809
1*1
bound for Stone's River with cargo for Jackson, Hutching s and Company.
Coffee also managed a boatyard at Clover Bottom for the firm. The boat-yard
filled many contracts for the government and private individuals. Perhaps
the most famous incident connected with the boatyard involved Aaron Burr.
Jackson authorized Coffee to build 5 flatboats and purchase one keelboat
for Burr. This took place in the latter part of 1805 and early 1806 during
the time of Burr's conspiracy, and as a result, Burr received only two
flatboats. The boats were built out of trees cut off Clover Bottom. The
construction took place in an area adjacent to an oak tree near Jackson's
store on the west bank of Stone's River just downstream from the Lebanon
Pike bridge.
116
Commercial traffic on Stone's River steadily increased over the years,
even after the county seat of justice was moved from Jefferson to Murfrees-boro.
By 1815, Stone's River traffic included 'rafts, flat-bottomed boats...
barges, keelboats and other craft." Commerce on the river became so
substantial that on 28 September 1815* the State established a state
inspection station "on the banks of Stone's River," at Jefferson. This
facility's personnel inspected agricultural goods. The inspector was to
issue certificates of inspection to the shipmasters and to brand the barrels
of goods, after they passed an inspection for quality, with the word
"TENNESSEE". Shortly after the passage of this act by the General Assembly,
Walter Kibble requested permit to construct a warehouse in Jefferson to aid
in the inspection of export commodities. The Rutherford County Court granted
his request and thus established a system of inspection for tobacco, flour,
hemp, pork and other items for exportation. The court also appointed William
W. Searcy, William A. Sublett and George Simpson as inspectors.
B.M. Hard, Tennessee State Commissioner of Agriculture in 1889, recalled,
"...years ago I have seen cotton loaded on flatboats at Jefferson, the old
county seat of Rutherford, floated down Stone's River to the Cumberland and
thence to New Orleans."
In 1816, Stone's River had a newer facility on its banks. A rafting
ground was operated by Abram Maury DeGraffenread at that time. The area
used by DeGraffenread was located on the west bank of the river just north
of the mouth of Hurricane Creek approximately 18 miles from the mouth of the
river. DeGraffenread owned 320 acres of land in the area and was apparently
cutting timber off the land in order to build and launch rafts at the river
117
Timber rafts as a means of transport had been widely used prior to the
Revolutionary War and for many years afterward. It was a standard practice
for an immigrant family to purchase a timber raft and float to their
destination and after arrival, they would sell the timber at a profit.
Another use of timber rafts was a simple means of getting timber to sawmills
and markets in order to be sold. DeOraffenread's rafting ground was
adjacent to Brooking Burnett's mill and the Methodist meeting house. From
such an advantageous location! Defraffenread could have engaged in either
rafting transports or commercial timber rafting. The exact business con-ducted
at the rafting ground is not known. DeGraffenread only operated
the rafting ground for a short time from 181U until selling the property
in 181 9 after his removal from Tennessee to Alabama.
Figure 9* Raft
During this decade, Jefferson continued to flourish as a river port
of considerable importance. Along the river banks at the foot of Main
Street were Jefferson's wharves where many barges and flatboats were loaded
11$
and unloaded. Many boats were also built there. Boats from Jefferson ran
from there to Nashville during these years navigating both upstream and
downstream . Several of these craft measured 70 feet In length. Due to
lower water levels in the river, the larger boats descended the river once
a year, while the smaller craft could make the trip during three-fourths
of the year. Although these vessels were involved in regular commercial
trade and transportation, many local residents were involved in an active
fur trade with merchants in Nashville via small boats and pirogues.
The decade of the 1820's was one of great interest in navigation and
the residents of Stone's River and its area were no exception. On 26 July
1820, the General Assembly legally extended the navigation of the West Fork
from Jefferson to Samuel Bowman's mill. Present-day Nice's Mill about 6
miles upriver from Jefferson, is thought to be located on the Bowman Mill
site. The Assembly passed a law on 26 November 1825, which effected Stone's
River navigation in both Davidson and Rutherford Counties. This act im-posed
a $50 fine on all those obstructing the river and applied the money
thus obtained to the improvement of the river. These were only the beginning
of developments for Stone's River during this time.
Records of the Tennessee Legislature reveal that in 1803, 1815, 1819,
1820, 1831 and 1832 laws were enacted that authorized the construction of
mill dams on Stone's River. As part of the law, each dam would incorporate
a navigation lock to insure the safe passage of watercraft. This was the
means that the Assembly used to maintain an open navigation of the river.
However, the residents interested in the river's navigation saw many threats
to their interests via mill dams and other obstructions. Perhaps this view
119
of threats to navigation was the impetus behind the long battle to prevent
obstruction of the river. This battle was the underlying cause of the
legislation of 1827. This was "an act to authorize lotteries for the purpose
of opening and improving the navigation of Stone's River...from the junction
of the east, and west forks, of said river at Jefferson, Rutherford county,
to its confluence with Cumberland River . " Section I of this act listed the
names of the Rutherford County men that were appointed as managers to draft
a scheme for the lottery effecting the Stone's River. These men were:
Glover W. Banton, Burwell Perry, Eliaha Sanders, Thomas
Shaw, Theophilus Sharp, Islah Faris, Samuel Watldns, John
Hoover, William Alford, Henry Ridley, John M'Griger, John
Knight, Lewis Watldns, William Lannum, Robert Freman, John
Martin, Brooking Burnett, William P. King, Edward Gregory,
William Bouman, William Sneed, Robert L. Weakley, John M.
Sharp, Moses Ridley, David Wendle, James C. Moore, George
A. Sublett, William W. Searcy, James Martin, John C. Clements,
Ota Cantrell, John Parks, Baker Wrather, William H. Smith,
Isaac Sanders, Joel H. Barton, Moses G. Beavers, Absolem
Gleaves, James Ridley, William Stewart, Joseph Kimbro, James
Sharp, Constant Hardeman, Matthew M'Lanahan, Edwin Sharp,
Samuel P. Black, Robert Jetton, Samuel Anderson, William
Robb, and Russell Dance.
This lottery was designed to raise $30,000 as specified in the legislative
* U8
act.
The most significant event of the 1820's era in the history of Stone's
River navigation took place in Jefferson, At this locale, several local
boatbuilders teamed together with Constant Hardeman and laid the keel for
a steamboat. This was done in the wake of the arrival of the first steam-boats
in Nashville during 1819* These steamers had come from the Ohio River.
No steamers had been built at that time in the Cumberland Basin. Hardeman
and tie Jefferson residents saw the advantage of having a steamer on Stone's
River and thus conceived the idea of building their own steamer. When the
120
hull of the vessel was built and completed, it was floated down the river
to Nashville for outfitting with a steam plant and other equipment. The
steamer was described as being about 100 tons burthen. Hardeman's vessel
was the first and only steamer ever built in Jefferson and probably was the
first steamer ever built in the Central Basin area of Tennessee. The vessel
reputedly made many trips between Jefferson and Nashville , however some
accounts say that the river proved to be too shallow for steamboat navigation.
Today, it is suspected that Hardeman's steamer became the Emerald and was
U9
employed in the Nashville trade.
Steamboating became the rage and by 1825, $1% of all the freight in the
west was reaching the New Orleans markets via steamers. Nashville had be-come
a steamboating center by 1821 and steamers were reaching New Orleans
from Nashville in 22 days as compared to 87 days one-way for a keel boat.
However, steam navigation was restricted to relatively short periods of
high water thus rendering the outlying districts, such as Rutherford County,
dependent on either keelboats or wagons for their import trade. The decade
of the 1830 '3 also brought the construction of turnpikes leading to and from
Nashville. Rutherford County was thus connected in 1831 to Nashville via
the Nashville, Murfreosboro and 9ielbyville turnpike. This enabled farmers
to more easily get produce to market by wagons going into Nashville. To add
to the situation, 1830 ushered in a railroad fever that enveloped the people
in the county. All these factors combined to push river traffic into a
50
period of sluggish activity.
The two decades between 1830 and 1850 were periods of relative inactivity
for commerce along Stone's River. Jefferson's fur trade with Nashville was
121
dying out. Some goods such as grain were rafted to Nashville for the steam-boat
trade, but the majority of import merchandise was hauled into Jefferson
by wagons, pack-horses and mules from Nashville. Then in 181*7* the rail-road
was constructed through Smyrna and Jefferson's freight was hauled there
for shipment. Thus a gradual change was beginning to take place. The river
was embarking on another phase of its history.
On the 7th of November 1853, the Rutherford County Court sent a petition
to the General Assembly concerning the navigation of Stone's River. The
petition was protesting some previous requests to the Assembly to enact laws
for the obstruction of the river. The petition informed the Assembly that
the navigation of Stone's River was a "natter of great Importance to the
citizens of Rutherford County." In the continuing information contained in
52
the petition, the river is called "a great highway to market." Thus the
petition tells of the river's rising new industry, ie., the floating of
cedar timber rafts to the sawmills and lumber markets of Nashville and else-where.
Figure 10: Keelboat as represented
on the Tennessee State Seal
122
THE TIMBER RAFTING ERA
According to Dixon Merritt, Wilson County historian, the timber industry
in the Cumberland Basin began in the 18U0's when a Englishman named Hiram
Drennon brought a colony of lumbermen from East Tennessee. Drennon's workers
set out by cutting red cedar timber along Falls Creek In an area that today
is covered by portions of Wilson and Rutherford Counties. Cnce the timber
was cut, it was rafted down Falls Creek to Stone's River. From the river,
the rafts could then be taken to Nashville. By 1853, cedar timber rafts that
floated down the river had Increased Rutherford County's commerce by $50-100
thousand per year. From the heart of the red cedar belt, the old river port
of Jefferson was chosen as a rendezvous for the rafts and as a staging area
for raft construction and launching. The rafts were floated downstream every
spring and fall during periods of high water. In the 1850's and 1860's, logs
were piled up on the East Fork near the confluence with the West Fork at
Jefferson and here rafts were built and launched. There probably was another
similar staging area at the mouth of Falls Creek about 5 miles downriver
from Jefferson. When the raftsman floated the rafts to Nashville and had
53
sold the timber, many walked back home to the Jefferson area.
Logs for these rafts of timber were cut between 10 and 16 feet long.
The average Cumberland River raft was 200 feet in length and a single tier
in width. Large rafts were 2 or 3 tiers in width and about 250 long, although
lengths and widths were variable. Average rafts were manned by a crew of
5 men and a pilot. Of these, 3 men were assigned to the bow oar and 2 men
to the stern oar. The pilot was generally called "the captain" and the crews
123
Y^CsOJ7t7&amp;c&#163;jci4^ /urgr 7j&amp;iJyej~/xa/i &lt;?/~fS2,o
fse.tis of/but* /ocjs'
^ \?rfor7ct&amp; t / " rxr/c fJieK)
.y-^ - ^ ~&gt; - .y y
'Uari Di J
1p^-&#8212; usoc?rt bow
U7S/1 po/e-
Figure 1 1 : The Days of River
Rafting
124
were referred to as "river rats". Perhaps one of the best known of Stone's
River's raft captains was Captain Jack 0. Lannom. Captain Lannoa in 1886
had been rafting on the river for over 30 years. Lannoa 's rafting days
were known as those in which the river was "famous for the nuaber of rafts
Sh run down it.""^
There is a "knack" in steering a raft and in the way they are launched
,
landed and tied up. Therefore the pilot and crew had to be aware and cautious
while rafting, because it was dangerous business. Stone's River was a very
hazardous river due to the high rock bluffs in the turns of the river. If
the raftsmen lost control of a raft in a turn the current could force the
raft into the rock bluff at a speed high enough to cause a crash. If the
craft crashed into the bluff, not only would the raft break up and the logs
be lost but lives could be lost as well. Raftsman Tom Arnold of Rutherford
County's Fall Creek area, was known to have been in such a crash, however
none of the crew were injured. His raft was broken up, logs lost and he was
forced to swim for his life as huge logs crowded around him in the river's
current. Another such accident involved a death. During an early spring
raft trip, Robert Green Lannom died in 1860 as a result of his raft breaking
up near Jones* Mill on Stone's River. Lannom drowned while attempting to
reach safety. Jones' Mill is presently the site of Youth, Inc. camp on the
55
Percy Priest Lake about 28 miles from the mouth of the river.
Huge quantities of Stone's River red cedar was shipped to Louisiana,
Mississippi, Illinois, Indiana, and Ohio. Many of the mansions in Cincinnati,
Ohio were built of Stone's River cedar. The industry grew steadily from the
18U0's but the Civil War temporarily stopped the exportation of timber rafts.
125
After the war, the timber Industry catapulted to reach huge proportions.
In 1882, about 11*00 rafts had tied up on the river at Nashville. At the
close of the year, the Nashville sawmills handled lumber valued at
$3,372,000. By 1881*, the twenty mills In Nashville handled 86,165,000 feet
of lumber. Between 1900 and 190U, it is estimated that the total lumber
handled by the Nashville mills exceeded 100,000,000 feet, ie., a gross annual
income of better than $8 million. With Stone's River red cedar timber rafts,
Nashville became one of the outstanding hardwood lumber centers of the
56
United States.
One of the most unusual uses of the Stone's River cedar was that use of
trees taken from the cedar lands along present-day Percy Priest Lake. These
trees were floated down the river to be used as telephone poles. Many were
floated to Nashville where they were made Into rails for the street cars
57
pulled by mules.
Rafting was done during periods of high water and thus was greatly effected
by the weather. Weather conditions have always had an influence on the
river and they have always been an Important part of the river's history.
126
THE WEATHER AND THE RIVER
Stone's River, like other rivers, has had problems in the past due to
certain weather conditions. Heavy rains have increased water levels thus
resulting in floods, freezes in winter have caused ice gorges and flooding
during thaws, and droughts have created periods of low water or in severe
cases, almost no water at all. An excellent guage for many such events are
the records of weather conditions and the resulting effects concerning the
Cumberland River at Nashville. Logically, whatever occurred on the Cumberland
likely happened on the Stone's River.
Droughts are generally caused by lengthy periods of no precipitation.
There are a few recorded instances of very low water. Local newspapers
announced that in November of 1818, the Cumberland River at Nashville was
"too low to be navigated" by steamboats. The next November, the Cumberland
was very dry. That year the newspapers were publishing the fact that the
river was the lowest it had been since 1781*. One reporter wrote, "There is
not enough water in several places to float an empty boat..." The Stone's
River must have also experienced these same periods of low water. One example
of low water on the Stone's was in 1805, when Jackson, Hutchings and Company
could not bring their keelboats down the river because there was less than
, 58
18 inches of water in the channel.
Winter freezes probably caused more dangerous situations for steamboats
and keelboats than for the residents along the banks. The worst freeze on
the Cumberland was in 1832 when wagons were able to cross the ice at Nashville
for 2 entire weeks. The river was again frozen over in 1856 and again in
1872. Later freezes occurred in 1876, 1893, 1905, and 19U0. Due to the
127
simple fact of extremely cold weather, Stone's River must hare indeed
59
frozen over just like the Cumberland River.
Large amounts of rainfall increase the amount of water runoff and
thus can cause flood conditions. The flood stage of the Cumberland River
at Nashville is UO feet. The Cumberland has experienced waters higher than
this level in 1808, 1815, 1826, 181*7, 1850, 1862, 1865, 1867, 1882, 1886,
1890, 1902, 1912, 1915, 1927, 1928, 1935 and 1937. The highest of these
was the 1927 flood which was a record breaker. This particular flood crested
at 56.2 feet in Nashville. However, the 1902 flood was the record breaker
for Stone's River. The record high water of 1902 was followed by another
period of almost record high water in 19U8. La the 1902 flood, about 11
inches of rain fell in 2U hours during a storm that covered an area from
Nashville to McMinnville. The downpour continued for a total of 38 hours.
This storm occurred between March 26th and March 29th, 1902, however the
high water continued on into the month of April. At the public square in
the village of Jefferson, the high water created an island of the hilltop
there. Nashville newspapers carried complete reports on the flood's effects
60
in Rutherford County.
The following contemporary accounts describe the catastrophe that
came to Murfreesboro and Rutherford County in 1902 as a flood.
"At Murfreesboro the water was 3 feet deep on the tracks
at the passenger station...A bridge 30 feet in length
Just north of the passenger station was washed out. It
was hit by a floating house. The Salem turnpike county
bridge was washed away and against the railroad structure
between the passenger station and freight station and both
passed on down the stream... Train No. 5 leaving Nashville
yesterday afternoon at 3:30 P.M. for Chattanooga is tied
up at the National Cemetery 3 miles north of Murfreesboro.
123
The train is due at Murfreesboro at li&#187;U8 P.M. and
almost reached the railroad bridge across Stone's
River about 2 miles north of the depot, when it ran
into high water. The Engineer said that he could
not go through and . . . .backed the train to the National
Cemetery to telephone back to headquarters for orders...
When they left the telephone to return to the train
they found that the water had risen in a long depression
between them and the railroad tracks and that the train
was standing in water about 2 feet deep. It was 3 or
h hours before the water had subsided sufficiently for
them to get back...but as far as can be learned it is
almost certain that 10 bridges over Stone's River have
been washed away.... The bridge over Stone's River on
the Hanson Pike has left its moorings and washed against
the railroad bridge j where the current is rapidly
beating it into pieces and endangering the railroad
bridge. The Franklin road bridge, the Salem turnpike
bridge are also reported as wrecked. Part of Ransom's
Mill on Stone's River is gone and two bridges are re-ported
washed away on the Woodbury pike. It seems that
the rainfall was general throughout the county and that
both forks of Stone's River are higher than ever known
in the history of the county. Indeed the height to
which both forks rose has staggered the oldest inhabitants
beyond the power of comparison. The waters stood for
several hours over the counters in the stores in Readyville
on the East Fork of Stone's River. The West Fork washed
away Dr. Elam's mill and swept the post house off its
foundations. The bridges over the Shelbyville, Salem,
Franklin, Manson and Nashville pikes are gone. The East
Fork has washed away the Lascassas bridge, the Pierce's
Mill bridge, the Readyville bridge, the Burton bridge and
The Woodbury bridge. The Cripple Creek bridge on Woodbury
pike and tie bridge on the Manchester pike are the the
only bridges of any consequence left in the county....
Lewis' mill near Jefferson was completely ruined, and not
a great distance away the store house and dwelling of T.E.
Bell was lifted from its foundations and carried away by
the flood. Mr. Drak's barn near Walter Hill was washed
away....Damage will be from $250,000 to $300,000."
These were the contemporary newspaper accounts of the flood from the
Nashville point of view. No doubt the Murfreesboro newspapers carried more
detailed accounts, although these have not survived.
129
CONCLUSION
In 1853, the Rutherford County Court petitioned the Tennessee General
Assembly concerning the Stone's River. The petition Indicates that the
turnpikes seened to hare diminished river commerce. Railroads no doubt
played a great role In switching commercial transportation route thus putting
and end to river trade. This seems to be more of the truth behind the
demise of river traffic rather than lower water levels in the river or the
removal of the county seat of justice from Jefferson to Murfreesboro. The
traffic and trade along Stone's River fell victim to the "progress" of the
advances in the technology of transportation. But even so, the petition
reminds one that the "navigation of said Stone's River....being a matter of
of great Importance to the citizens of Rutherford County... (provided) a
great highway to marfeet.** As such, the commercial developments of river
transportation and the like caused economic prosperity and thus caused the
county to greatly flourish. In addition, many settlers and pioneers as well
as later residents followed the "natural Highway" of Stone's River into the
county. In the final analysis, Stone's River has played an enormously im-portant
role in the development of Rutherford County.
130
NOTES
John Gerald Parchment, "A Lixnnological Study of Stone's River,
Tennessee** (PhD dissertation, Vanderbilt University, 1961), p. 9, 11.
2
Parchment, p. 13,16.
3
Richard M. Ketchum, ed., The American Heritage Picture History of
The Civil War (New York: American Heritage Publishing Co., Inc., I960),
p. 283, 28U, 289; Leona Taylor Aiken, Donelson, Tennessee t Its Landmarks
and History (Kingsport, TN: Kingsport Press, Inc., 1968), p. 117.
John R. Svranton, The Indian Tribes of North America, Smithsonian
Institution, American Bureau of Ethnology, Bulletin # 1U5 (United States
Government Printing Office : Washington, D.C., 1952), p. 227; Byrd Douglas,
Steamboatin' on the Cumberland (Nashville, TN: Tennessee Book Co., 1961),
p. xii; Charles A. Miller, The Official and Political Manual of the State
of Tennessee, 1890 edition, (The Reprint Company, Publishers: Spartanburg,
S.C., 197U), p. 8; Stanley J. Folmsbee, Robert E. Corlew, and Enoch L. Mitchell,
Tenne ssee i A Short History (Kncxville, TN: University of Kncocville Press,
1969), P . 32.
Douglas, p. xii; Svranton, p. 227; Lei and R. Johnson, Enginners on the
Twin Rivers: A History of the Nashville District, Corps of Engineers, United
States Army (Nashville, TN: U.S. Army Engineer District, 1978), p. 6; Folmsbee,
Corlew, and Mitchell , p . 32
.
6
Douglas, p. xiiij Aiken, p. 1QU, 105.
7
Ursula Smith Beach, Along the Warioto: or a History of Montgomery
County, Tennessee (Nashville, TN: McQuiddy Press, 1961*), p. 13; Parchment,
p. 13; Carlton C. Sims, ed., History of Rutherford County (TN) (Murfreesboro,
TN: Carlton C. Sims, 19k7), p. 7.
8
Johnson, p. 1-u.
9
Parchment, p. 17.
10
Beach, p. 13.
11
Douglas, p. xiil-xiv.
12
Beach, p. 55; David B. Guralnik, ed., Webster's New World Dictionary
of the American Language, Second College Edition (New York: Simon and Schuster,
1980), p. 1081*; Johnson, p. 6-7; Herbert Quick and Edward Quick, Mississippi
Steamboatin' : A History of Steamboating on the Mississippi and Its Tributaries
(New Tork: Henry Holt and Company, 1926), p. 8-9.
131
13
Douglas, p. xiii.
1
^Aifcen, p. 104-105.
Quick and Quick, p. 12-13j William A. Baker, Sloops and Shallops
(Barre, MA: Barre Publishing Company, 1966), p. 129.
16
Leland D. Baldwin, The Keelboat Age on Western Waters (Pittsburgh,
PA &#187; University of Pittsburgh Press, 194u, p. 42.
17
Baldwin, p. 1 48-1 53
.
18
Baldwin, p. 47.
19
^Baldwin, p. 47-48.
20
Balthasar Henry Meyer, ed., History of Transportation in the United
States Before 1860 (Forge Village, MA: Murray Printing Company, 1948 3, p. 97.
21
Aiken, p. 104, 308.
22
Sims, p. 11, 12.
23
'Aiken, p. 225J Davidson County, Tennessee, Register's Office, Deed
Book A, p. 166, 210.
Tfeyer, p. 100.
25
Aiken, p. 80j Stanley John Folmsbee, Sectionalism and Internal Im-provements
in Tennessee, 1 796-1 8U5 (Knoxville, TN: The EasTTfennessee Historical
Society, 1939), p. 14-15.
26
Sims, p. 1 83 Goodspeed Publishing Company, History of Tennessee, with
sketches of Maury, Williamson, Rutherford, Wilson ."Bedford and Marshall Counties
(Nashville, TN: Goodspeed Publishing Company, 1886), p. 811.
27
Sims, p. 17.
28
Sims, p. 11, 17, 18, 19.
29
Thomas Perkins Abernethy, From Frontier to Plantation in Tennessee:
A Study of Frontier Democracy (University, AL: University of Alabama, 1967),
p. 199, 200, 20lj Meyer, p. 103j Folmsbee, p. 15-16.
30
Baldwin, p. 44-45; Abernethy, p. 199.
Samuel Anderson Weakley, Cumberland River Floods Since the Settlement
of the Basin With Special Reference to Nashville, Tennessee 11 (Civil Ehgineer
thesis, Vanderbilt University, Nashville, TN, 1935), p. 26.
132
32
"Determination of Navigability for Stone 1 a River, Including East
and West Forks", Waterways Management Division, Operations Division,
Nashville District Engineers, United States Army Corps of Engineers, Nash-ville,
Tennessee, 15 April 1975. (hereafter cited Navigability Report.)
33
Douglas, p. 11 j Gordon T. Chappel, "The Life and Activities of General
John Coffee," Tennessee Historical Quarterly I (191*2) i 127.
3k
John D. Barbae, "Navigation and River Improvement in Middle Tennessee,
1 807-1 832a" (M.A. thesis, Vanderbilt University, 193U), p. 10; Douglas, p. 17,
18.
35
Goodspeed, p. 833; Johnson, p. 2U; Interview with Ernest King Johns,
Rutherford County Historical Society, a^rna, Tennessee, 9 July 1981, in
reference to the photograph of the mill site in Rutherford County Historical
Society Publication No. 6, p. 80.
36
Goodspeed, p. 833} Kevin Markuson, "A History of the Town of Jefferson,
1803-1813", Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 17 (Summer
1 981 ) , p. 3j John R. Bedford, "Tour in 1807 Down the Cumberland", Tennessee
Historical Magazine 5 (April 1919): U0-U1
.
37
Goodspeed, p. 837.
38
Goodspeed, p. 813.
39
Johnson, p. 15} Sims, p. 222.
U0
Gordon T. Chappel, "The Life and Activities of General John Coffee",
Tennessee Historical Quarterly I (191*2): 128; Aiken, p. 78, 79, 80.
U1
Navigability Report
ii2
Gordon T. Chappel, "The Life and Activities of General John Coffee,"
Tennessee Historical Quarterly I (191*2): 128; Aiken, p. 81-82, 9U-95.
U3
Act of Tennessee, 28 September 1815 cited in Navigability Report;
Rutherford County, Tennessee, County Clerk's Office, County Court Minute Book
I, p. 120.
^Navigability Report
1*5
Rutherford County, Tennessee, County Court Clerk's Office, County
Court Minute Book I, p. 115; Rutherford County, Tennessee, County Register's
Office, Deed Book K, p. 221; Deed Book M, p. 2*76.
Goodspeed, p. 833; Sims, p. 222; Interview with Everett Waller, Smyrna,
Tennessee, 15 July 1981; 1853 petition of Rutherford County Court cited in
Navigability Report; Markuson, p. 38; Ed Bell, " Rising Water to Banish Old
Town," Rutherford Courier . Snyrna, Tennessee, 17 August 1967.
133
^ 7Acts of Tennessee, 26 Jul/ 1820 and 26 November 1825 as cited in
Navigability Report.
wBarbee, p. 42 j Acts of Tennessee 1827 (Knoxville, TNi State Printer,
1827), Chapter CLU, p. 133-131.
*J*.7QBell, Rutherford Courier, 17 August 1967j Sims, p. 222j Goodspeed,
p. 833 j Douglas, p. 19; Barbee, p. 64; Embree, ed., The Western Boatman,
Vol. I, No. 3 (May 1848) courtesy Tennessee State Library and Archives,
Nashville, Tennessee.
Barbee, p. 29, 21*, 13; Folmsbee, p. 15, 16, 17; Baldwin, p. 66;
Goodspeed, p. 816; Sims, p. 222.
Interview with Everett Waller, Smyrna, Tennessee, 15 July 1981.
52 Q
1853 Rutherford County Court petition as cited in Navigability Report.
Navigability Report; Interview with Everett Waller, Smyrna, Tennessee,
15 July 1981; Douglas, p. 236.
54
Douglas, p. 236; Navigability Report.
-'-'Douglas, p. 237| Interview with Everett Waller, Smyrna, Tennessee,
15 July 1981; Interview with Ernest King Johns, Rutherford County Historical
Society, Smyrna, Tennessee, It August 1981; James W. Pattern, "History of the
Lannom Family", Chapel Hill, North Carolina, 1968, courtesy of Ernest King
Johns, Smyrna, Tennessee.
5 Navigability Report; Douglas, p. 234, 235.
57
Aiken, p. 338.
5
Weakley, p. 31-32; Aiken, p. 81
.
59
Douglas, p. 373-371*.
Douglas, p. 373; Interview with Everett Waller, Smyrna, Tennessee,
15 July 1981; Weakley, p. 11, 12, 11*6.
61
Weakley, p. 149-150.
62
1853 Rutherford County Court petition as cited In Navigability Report.
134
ILLUSTRATION CREDITS
Figure 1i from map "State of Tennessee", Scale 1 i500,000, United States
Department of The Interior, Geological Survey! Washington, D.C.,
1959.
Figure 2: from frontspiece, Larry E. Ivers, British Drums on the Southern
Frontier t The Military Colonization of Georgia, 1733 - 'JU9.
Chapel kill, NC&#187; University of North Carolina Press, 197U.
Figure 3i from p. 1U-15, Transportation Economics Division, Tennessee
Valley Authority, A History of Navigation on the Tennessee River
System . Washington, D.C.i United States Printing Office, 1937.
Figure U&#187; from Library of Congress print, p. 15, Nicholas Perkins Hardeman,
Wilderness Calling t The Hardeman Family in the American Westward
Movement. 1?56 -T9OO . Kncxviile, Ttl: University of Tennessee fress,
WT.&#8212;
Figure 5: from p. 18q Leona Taylor Aiken, Donelson, Tennessee; Its Landmarks
and History . Kingsport, TNi Kingsport Press, inc., i960.
Figure 6: from p. U3 , Leland D. Baldwin, The Keelboat Age on Western Waters.
Pittsburgh, PA 1 University of Pittsburgh Press, 19UL
Figure It from p. 1U-15, T.V.A., History of Navigation on the Tennessee River
System .
Figure 8* from p. 1M5, T.V.A., History of Navigation on the Tennessee River
System .
Figure 9: from p. 14-15, T.V.A., History of Navigation on the Tennessee River
^System.
Figure 10: from the SEAL OF THE STATE OF TENNESSEE, shown on the cover of
Jesse Burt, Your Tennessee . Austin, TXi Steck-Vaughn Company,
1974.
Figure 11 1 from p. 42-45, Eric SLoane, A Museum of Early American Tools.
New York 1 Ballantine Books, 196U.
13 5
BIBLIOGRAPHY
Abernethy, Thomas Perkins. From Frontier to Plantation in Tennessee: A
Study in Frontier Democracy . University, AL: University of Alabama
Press, 1967.
Acts of Tennessee 1827 . Knoxville, TN: State Printer (1827).
Aiken, Leona Taylor. Donelson, Tennessee: Its Landmarks and History .
Kingsport, TN: Kingsport Press, Inc., 1968.
Applewhite, Joseph Davis. "Early Trade and Navigation on the Cumberland
River." M.A. thesis, Vanderbilt University, 19U0.
Bacon, H.P. "Nashville's Trade at the beginning of the 19th Century."
Tennessee Historical Quarterly 15 (1956): 30ff.
Baker, William A. Sloops and Shallops . Barre, MAi Barre Publishing Company,
1966.
Baldwin, Leland D. The Keelboat Age on Western Waters . Pittsburgh, PA:
University of Pittsburgh Press, 19U1
&#8226;
Barbee, John D. "Navigation and River Improvement in Middle Tennessee,
1 807-1 83U. M M.A. thesis, Vanderbilt University, 193U.
Beach, Ursula Smith. Along the Warioto: or a History of Montgomery County,
Tennessee . Nashville, TN: McQuiddy Press, 196U.
Bedford, John R. "Tour in 1807 Down the Cumberland". Tennessee Historical
Magazine 5 (April 1919): UOff.
Bell, Ed. "Rising Water to Banish Old Town." Rutherford Courier , Smyrna,
Tennessee, 17 August 1967.
Burt, Jesse. Your Tennessee . Austin, TX: Steck-Vaughn Company, 197U*
Caruso, John Anthony. The Mississippi Valley Frontier: The Age of French
Exploration and SettTement . New York: Bobbs-Merrill Company, Inc., 1966.
Chappel, Gordon T. "The Life and Activities of General John Coffee."
Tennessee Historical Quarterly I 09U2): 125ff.
Davidson County, Tennessee, County Register's Office, Deed Books
"Determination of Navigability for Stone's River, Including East and West
Forks." Waterways Management Division, Operations Division, Nashville
District Engineers, United States Army Corps of Engineers, Nashville,
Tennessee, 15 April 1975.
136
Douglas, Byrd. Steamboatin* on the Cumberland . Nashville, TN: Tennessee
Book Company, 1 961
.
Embree, D., ed., The Western Boatman . St. Louis, MO: Union Job Office,
Vol. I (May 1BU8), No. 3.
Folmsbee, Stanley John. Sectionalism and Internal Improvements in Tennessee,
1796 - 18lig . Knoxville, TN: The East Tennessee Historical Society, 1939.
Folmsbee, Stanley J.j Robert E. Corlewj Enoch L. Mitchell. Tennessee: A Short
Historjr. Knoxville, TN: University of Enoxville Press, 1969*
Qoodspeed Publishing Company. History of Tennessee, with sketches of Maury,
Williamson, Rutherford, Wilson, Bedford and Marshall Counties . Nashville,
TN: Goodspeed Publishing Company, 1666.
Ivers, Larry E. British Drums on the Southern Frontier : The Military Colonization
of 0eorgia1~T733 - 17U9 . Chapel Hill, NC: University of North Carolina,
Johns, Ernest King. Rutherford County Historical Society. Smyrna, Tennessee.
Interview, 9 July 1981 and h August 1981.
Johnson, Lei and R. Engineers on the Twin Rivers : A History of the Nashville
District, Corps of Engineers, United States Army . Nashville, TN: U.S.
Army Engineer District, Nashville, 1978.
Ketchum, Richard M., ed., The American Heritage Picture History of the Civil
War . New York: American Heritage Publishing Company, Inc., 1960.
Marfcuson, Kevin. "A History of the Town of Jefferson, 1803 - 1813." Rutherford
County Historical Society Publication No. 17 (Summer 1981), Murfreesboro,
Tennessee.
Meyer, Balthasar Henry. History of Transportation in the United States Before
1860 . Forge Village, MA: Murray Printing Company, 19U8.
Miller, Charles A. The Official and Political Manual of the State of Tennessee .
(1890 edition) reprinted. Spartanburg, SC: The Reprint Company, Publishers,
1972*.
Parchment, John Gerald. "A Limnological Study of Stone's River, Tennessee."
PhD dissertation, Vanderbilt University, 1961
.
Patton, James W. "History of the Lannom Family." Chapel Hill, North Carolina,
1968. (Typewritten.)
Quick, Herbert and Edward Quick. Mississippi Steamboatin ' : A History of
Steamboating on the Mississippi River and Its Tributaries . New York:
Henry Holt and Company, 1926.
137
Rutherford County, Tennessee, County Clerk's Office, County Court
Minute Books
Rutherford County, Tennessee, County Register's Office, Deed Books
Sims, Carlton C. History of Rutherford County (TN). Murfreesboro, TN*
Carlton C. Sims, 1%7.
SLoane, Eric. A Museum of Early American Tools . New York: Ballantine Books,
196U.
Stewart's Ferry Reservoir Map, Stone's River, Tennessee, Cumberland River
Watershed. Nashville, TN: U.S. Engineer Office, 19U5.
Swanton, John R. The Indian Tribes of North America . Smithsonian Institution,
American Bureau of Ethnology, Bulletin No. 1U5. United States Government
Printing Office: Washington, D.C., 1952.
Transportation Economics Division, Tennessee Valley Authority. A History of
Navigation on the Tennessee River System . Washington, D.C. : United States
Government Printing Office, 1937.
Waller, Everett. Smyrna, Tennessee. Interview, 15 July 1981.
Weakley, Samuel Anderson. "Cumberland River Floods Since the Settlement of
the Basin With Special Reference to Nashville, Tennessee." Civil Engineer
thesis, Vanderbilt University, 1935.
</dc:description>
<dc:description>Analysis of how exploration, trade and settlement in early Rutherford County were influenced by the Stones River, a major geographic landmark in the area</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Land grants--Tennessee--Rutherford County; Murfreesboro (Tenn.); Stones River (Tenn.); Tennessee, Middle;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Uriah Stone</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>49 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-15; mt2011-02-17</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication18ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/51</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>