<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>The Crowders of Readyville, Tennessee</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Crowder, Clyde R.; Fay, Mrs. Charles H.</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 8</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1958; 1977</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>18th century; 19th century; 20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>63
TPffi CROWDERS OF READYVILLE, TENNESSEE
Brief excerpts from a manuscript written about 1958 by Clyde R. Crowder
(1882-1961) of White County, Illinois. These excerpts are followed by com-ments
by Mrs. Charles H. Fay who has researched the Philip Crowder fam-ily
for several years.
"The first of my ancestors of which I have any knowledge came from
England to Virginia in early Colonial days. This ancestor was either my
great grandfather or my great- great grandfather. But I am under the
impression that my uncle Elisha Crowder said that he would have been my
great grandfather.
"Assuming that he was my great grandfather, I will say that he had
seven sons, the youngest of whom was my grandfather whose name was Elisha
Alexander Crowder who was bom in Virginia in 1784 and who died in
Rutherford County, Tennessee in 1843 in the month of October about three
weeks before my father was bom. I shall relate the cause of his death as
father and my uncles related it to me, which was confirmed by a very old
man who was born and raised in Rutherford County, Tennessee, and who
know about it. His name was Henry Glasscock.
"Grandfather had the reputation of. being the strongest man in Rutherford
County in which he lived at the time of his death. Grandfather was a black-smith
as many of the older Crowders were. One day a man rode up to grand-father's
shop and said to him, "I miderstand that you are the strongest man
in Rutherford Covuaty". He also stated that he was said to be the strongest
man in his county. He challenged Grandfather to a trial of strength of toeing
a line and throwing an anvil backward over their head. The one that threw
in the farthest was to take the honor of being the strongest. Grandfather
64
threw last, and threw the anviJ ten feet farther than the other fellow. In pnr-forming
thJs feat of strength, he ruptured a blood vessel inside and bird lo
death with an internal hemorrhage one year to a day from the time h(^ threw
the anvil, dying at the age of fifty-nine years, which was three wt^oks before
my father was bom. Henry Glasscock's story told to me in. 1903 was sub-stantially
the same as told to me by my father and uncles.
"In mentioning that my grandfather was the youngest of seven sons,
will say that the oldest was named Philip Crowder. He was a soldier in the
Revolutionary War. Sometime after this war, he moved to Kentucky and
lived there until 1844, in which year he moved to Sangamon County, Illinois.
He later died in this county and was buried there. On the South side of the
old capitol buildings m Springfield is a metal tablet set in the masonry on the
outside contains his and several other names of Revolutionary Heroes who
are buried in Sangamon County. The Hlinois Historical Society says that
he had several children. Seventeen as I remember. Mitchell and George
Hiinsinger, now deceased, but who lived around Burnt Prairie, Illinois,
were related through their mothers to Philip Crowder.
"My grandfather's brothers all lived to be very old men ranging in
age. I am told, from 80 years to 109 years. He perhaps had sisters, but
T know nothing of them.
"My grandmother's maiden maiden name was Sarah Black. She was
known by many as Aunt Sally Black. She was related to a former United
States Commissioner of Pensions by the natne of Black. Grandfather and
Grandmother Crowder had eight sons and three daughters as far as I know,
and of which 1 shall speak. All of them were born in Tennessee and so far
65
as I know in Rutherford County near Read&gt;n/iJ]e. I shall namc^ th(^m as nearly
as possibJc ac:cording to their agt&gt;, but i ain sure that sumo wjM not bc^ cor-recMy
p)act-d. Stc^phcn was the oldest, ioJlowcd by Geor-gc. Eljsha Alexander,
Abigail, William, Crockoit, Nathaniel Green, Ann, Susan, Robert, and John
R. - my father.
"John Rick Crowder was born in Rutherford County, 27 October 1843.
In joining the Union Army in 1861 or J862, he gave his year of birth as J844,
which was an error on his part. Thus, in the War De^partment files at
Washington, 1844 is given as the year of his birth. He never tried to have
it changed as his discharge papers gave it that way and it might have inter-fered
with his pension.
"Shortly after Henry Clay's compromise of 1850, people from the
North and South begin to immigrate to the Kansas- Nebraska territory, in
the spring of 185 2, my father's family including his mother and his brothers
and sisters set out from Tennessee in a Conestoga wagon drawn by oxen I'or
ihis territory. They travelc&gt;d Nor-lh, across Tennessee and Kentuck)' to
Colconda, Illinois, where t'ney crossed the river. They planned to take 1he
old stage route which ran through Vienna, Old Mount Pleasant, Jonesboro,
into Missouri through Cape Girardeau, Jackson, and on to Independence,
Missouri. These piac^es wc&gt;rc only vjllages al this time.
"Upon arriving at Jonesboro, they found two c-ousins who wcn-e bro-th(^
rs that had conu&gt; a lew months earlier from Tennessee. These brothers
had also started to Kansas; but, upon arriving at Jonesboro, learned that
the Illinois Central Railroad was to begin building its road through therc^ the
next year. They decided to stop awhile and work on this railroad.
66
They did stop because grandmother was ill, and the boys vvorl&lt;ecl on Ihe roi)-
road when it began. Only two of lather's brothers ever- wcmt any larthct- west.
Those two, Stephen and George, after several years had passed, wcni on into
Missouri, around Hartsville and Carthage. The two cousixis ai' whom I spoke
finally settled near Laclede. Missouri. One of these two cousins, .Fohn,
became the father of General Enoch Crowder of World War 1 fame. General
Enoch Crowder, second cousin to my father, was not only a mjljlary man,
but was a lawyer, diplomat, and an export on mondary matters. He is said
to have been responsible for the get up of the draft law used in World War I.
Upon retiring from public life and the Army, he went to Chicago, became a
member of a law firm where he remained until his death which occurred
during the middle or later 1930's My two oldest daughters talked lo Gen&lt;^ral
Crowder while he was a member of his Chicago law firm, and he confirmc^d
what I have written about his father, his uncle, himself, and our relationship.
"When father's family left Tennessee, the family owed some debts.
Uncle William and Uncle Nathaniel, or Nat as he was called, remained in
Tennessee to work and pay these debts. They worked and paid the debts
and then walked from Tcumessee to Illinois. This was, 1 think, in the autumn
of 1852.
"Grandmother Crowder died in 1852 or 1853. Two or three of the boys.
Uncle Steve. Uncle Gcmrgc^ Uncle Eljsha, and probably Aunt Abigail were
married liefore comint; to Illinois. Aunt "Abe" as she was called, mar-ric^d
a Crowder, his name not known to me. He was only slightly related, if any,
lo her.
67
to her.
"Uncles William, Crockett, NalhanJel, Robert and lather wore in the
Union Army of the Civil War.
"My father, John Rice Crowder, was born in Rutherford County,
Tennessee, near a smaU place caJled Readyville on October 27, 1843. He
was bom three weeks after his father, Elisha Alexander, died. Having never
seen his father, he was supposed to have power to cure the thrush which small
children have in their mouths. ] have seen people bring babies for ten or
fifteen miles to him, so that he could blow in their mouths. 1 saw him do
this many times. It always cured them.
"Uncle Nat possessed power to stop blood on people or animals, also
the power to cause warts to go away. He said it was by faith. Unc:le Nat
was a very good man and also a preachc^r. He was very well read in the
Bible.
"The Schools to which father went were built of logs. I think he told
me that h(i never got beyond ihe second grade. When he entered the Union
Army in 18 62, he could scarci^ly read ar.d could not write enough to send let-ters
home. A Mr. Henry Plater who was in the Army and was a former
teacher taught him how to read and write. This lack of education is due
largely to the fact that he had to mnke his home among his older bt-olhers
while he was growing up. In later life he could read and write quilc well.
He read newspapers and the Bible. He kept ciuitc will informed on news of
the day.
"
68
Comments by Mrs. Charles H. Fay, 540o Beverly HJll [.ano, Ap1.. 1, Houslnn.
Texas 7705 6:
Tlnving been born December 5, 1883, iVIr. Clyde Rufus Crowder- was
about 75 when he wrote all he remembered of his Crowdet- for-ebearers. All
the information he gave whic-h I have checked is essenlially factual. The
names of the children of his father's brothers and sisters have been deleted
but will be provided to anyone interested.
The 1850 Rutherford County Census shows this family in household No.
695 as follows:
Sarah Crowder F. age 44, born South Carolina
Abi Crxjwder F. age 25 " "
George Crowder M. age 22, born in Tennessee
Elizabeth " F, age 16
Acey R. " M. age 14
"
Nathaniel " M. age 12
Robert " M. age 11
John " M. age 6
"
William Crowder was age 19 born Tennessee in the home of Mathew F.
McElroy, age 35, born Virginia, visit No. 711.
Rutherford County Marriage Records confirm that Stciphen Crowder
married Mary A. Rodgc&gt;rs on 25 July 1844 and George G. Crowder married
Sarah F.. Boyd on 9 .January 1849. No record is at hand to substantiate Mr.
Crowdc^r's affirmation ihat his Ifncle Elisha and probably Aunt Abigail wex-e
also married bc^forc moving to Illinois.
The story of Cousin John is sk(^tched by David A. Fockmiller's "Enoch
II. Crowder, Soldic&gt;r, I ,awyer and Statesman. " Enoch's father was John
Herbert Crowder, IV, born 18 March J831 near Marysville in Union County,
Ohio; and his luicestors moved from Dinwiddle County to Mecklenburg County,
Virginia, to Baltimore, Maryland, then Ohio, and Van Buren County, Iowa,
69
before settling in Grimdy County, Missouri. The stay in Jon(\shor-(), Illinois,
is not mentioned.
The statement that Philip Crowdcr was the eldest of his grandialiu^r's
six brothers is undoubtedly true. However, he assumed that this Philip was
the Revolutionary War Sergeant when in fact he was the Philip Crowder born
1780 in Virginia who fought in the War of 1812 from Rutherford County,
Tennessee.
The Revolutionary War soldier, Sgt. Philip Crowder who was born
7 April 1760 in Amelia Couiaty, Virginia, and died February 1844 in Sangamon
County, Illinois, was the third son of Abraham Crowder (surgeon) born 30
August 1730 in Bristol, Priaco George County, Virginia, and his wife,
Frances Tucker born 1730 in Amelia County. When Philip was five the
family moved from Amelia County to Mecklenburg County, Virginia. Philip
was still there when ho enrolled in the Virginia militia, first as a substitute
for his bnjthcr, William, and later for several enlistments of his own. By
his first wife, Susan Parish, whom he marric^d in Mecklenburg County,
Philip had five children. He stated in his pension application that he moved
in 1785 to Rutherford County, Noi-th Carolina; in 1791 removed to Greene
County, Ktmtucky; and in 1830 removed to Sangamon County, Illinois. Mean-while
he had ten more children by two other wives, Rachel Saunders and
Sally Chandler. His children are named in Power's "History of the p:arly
Settlers of Sangamon County, Illinois."
Walter R. Sanders' book on the John Chandler family states that Philip
Crowder was a licxmsed preacher on the Baptist Church.
Although Philip did no1 mention it in his pension application, he
70
probably lived in fiardin County, Kentucky, for a time, and at least three
of hia children were married therc^ between 1806 and 1809. It doc^s not appear
that this elder Philip Crowder ever lived in Tennessee.
Now we shalj look at the yoimger J'hilip who did live in Rutherford
County, Tennessee. The Third Census of the United States in 18J0 published
in the Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 4 shows Philip
Crowder 26 to 45 years old as head of a household in Rutherford Comity.
The eldest female in the fome is age 16 to 26 (Philip's wife Charlotte was 67
in 1850 census of Pike County, Illinois while Philip was 70).
On 2 January 1851, Philip Crowder in Pike County, Illinois, applied
for bounty land (under the act passed 28 September 1850) because of his
service in the War of 1812 whiJe a resident of Rutherford County, Tennessee.
He said that he was a private tti tha company commanded by Captain George
Barnes in the second regiment of Tennessee's militia commanded by Col-onel
Carroll; that he was drafted m Rutherford County on or about 1 Nov-ember
1815 for a six months term and was honorably discharged at Columbia,
Tennessee about 1 April 1815. He had sold the discharge subsequently for the
moTtthly pay due him. His descendants have often stated that he was with
Andrew Jackson at the Rattle of Mew Orleans, and histoi-y shows that Major
General William Carroll was indeed at the Battle of New Orleans.
Philip Crowder had marriecl Charlotte Robins in South Carolina,
possibly in Gre(&gt;nville County, about 1806.
Before^ 1830 this Crowder family moved to White County, Illinois.
Their daught(^r Nancy born 14 October 1807, in South Carolina, married
.17 Sept. 1828 Jolin Hunsinger (1806-1877) m White County; and another daughter,
71
Massa, born 20 May 1812 married 27 Scptomber 1830 Adam C. Ilunstngcr
(1807-1873), brother to John. Mr. Clyde R. Crowder mentioned George T.
Hiuisignerthe youngest son and 12th of 13 children of John and Nancy lluj-isingrr
and Mitchell Hunsinger who was the seventh of 16 children of Adam C. and
Massa Hunsinger.
While residing in While County. Charlotte Crowder was a member of
the Regular Baptist Church at Mount Pleasant in Burnt Prairie Township;
and many of the descendants of the above two daught(&gt;rs are members of that
church today.
After 1840 Philip and Charlotte moved to Pike County, Illinois. It was
here that daughter Susan born 8 March 1821 in Rutherford County married
20 January 1845 Jacob G. Bowers; and son Philip born 1825 in Tennessee
married 7 April 1845 Maria Bowers. The Bowers family had come from Ohio.
In 1849 Jacob Gusler Bower went to California on a prospecting tour,
having crossed the plains with a large expedition. He first located in
Trinity County and for a time successfully mined in the Cow Creek country.
Be returned to Pike County via Panama in 1851 and duriag the spring of 1852
he and his wife and three children in a wagon drawn by oxen joined a large
train of emigrants and crossed the plains in safety. They stayed in Hangtown
(now PJacerville) for a time, but later that same year moved to Yolo County
and purchased 320 acres of land. Mr. Bower died on 8 July 1894 and his widow
Susan, lived until 1902. They are burje;d at Mary's Chapel cemetery in Yolo
County with several of their descendants on the same ]ot . On an adjoining
Jot is the government headslonc of Philip Crowder showing he was in the
72
2nd Tennessee Militia of the War of ]812. Even though I he History of Yolo
County by Tom Gregory docs not state this, Philip Crowdor must have fol-lowed
his daughter, Susan to California where he died. There is no ht^adsiotio
for Philip's wife, Charlotte, who may have died in Pike County before Philip
started to California, but no stone has been found to date in Pike Coimty
for her. As already noted, she was still living when the 1850 census was
taken in Pike County.
This younger Philip Crowder apparently did not learn to write since
his signature always appears with an "x", and he did not have a deed to any
land in the various places we know he lived. The search has not been an
easy one for this man born Virginia, married in South Carolina, who fought
in the War of 1812 from Rutherford County, Tennessee, moved to White County
Illinois, then to Pike County, Illinois, and who is buried in Yolo Coimty,
California.
REFERENCES
David A. Lockmiller, Enoch H. Crowder, Soldier, Lawyer and Statesman
(Columbia: The [Tnivcrsity of Missouri Studies, 1955)15-17.
.lohn Carroll Power, History (&gt;&#163; Ihe Early Settlers of Sangamon County,
Illinois . Centennial Rcco rd (Spriiigfield: Edwin A. Wilson^ Col, 1876)
237-240.
"
Walter R. Sanders, The .lohn Chandler Family of Green and Taylor Counties,
Kentucky(1947) 7-8.
Henry G. Wray, Comp. , "Population Schedule of the Third Census of the
United States 1810, Rutherford County, Tennessee, "Rutherford County
Historical Society Publication No. 4 (Fall, 1974) 50.
Tom Gregory et al. History of Yolo County, California (l^os Angeles:
Historic Record Company, 1913) 693-695.
73
MAP OR PLAT OF THE FIRST LOTS IN THE TOWN
OF MURFREESBORO
Along about 1927, while searching titles for various parties, I dis-covered
that the P lat of the Original Plan of the City of Murfreesboro, was
never recorded, or at least, did not appear in any book in the Register's
office. Thereupon, I began looking in spare time through the early books
in that office, and discovered that Lot No. 1 was at the N. W. corner of what
is now West College, and North Front Streets, and Lot No. 70 was in the
Old City Cemetery
Looking through the books page: by page, since many of the indexes
had been destroyed, I got the information needed to prepare a plat of the
property, donated by Col. William F. Lytle, to the City of "Murfreesbo rough"
Miss Martha Wright, presently employed in the office of the Register
of Deeds for Rutherford County, now has a replica of the plat which prepared,
and she has added further information as to other additions to the C ity of
Murfreesboro.
You are at liberty to make any use which you may desire, of the plat
which I made and which Miss Wright now has.
Howell Washington
74
ORIGINAL PLAN OF THE TOWN OF MURFREESBOROUGH
AS LAID OFF IN 1818 BY CAPTAIN WILLIAM LTTLE
LOTS 1-130
120 121 122 121 '
108 109 no 111
NOTES;
1. This map Is not drsvn to scale. The size of the
numbered lots may vary according to location.
2. Lots 1-70 were researched and platted bv ROWEU,
WASHINGTON, Attorney -at -Law, ^{u^freesbo^,
Tennessee,
3. Lots 71-130 were added iji I976 after further
research by the RUTHERFORD OOUMTY RKGISIER'S
OFFICE.
4. Fbr further reference, see Deed from William
Lytic, Sr., to the Commissioners of &gt;turfreesboro,
recorded in Deed Book H, page 385, R.O.R.C.,
Tennessee.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Excerpts from Clyde Crowder's 1958 research are followed by comments from Mrs. Charles Fay, who also has researched the Readyville branch of the Crowder familiy</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Family history; Genealogy</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Crowder family</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Readyville</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>23 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-01</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication08ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/137</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>