<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Methodists and Murfreesboro in the mid-nineteenth century</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Brookshire, Jerry H.</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 10</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1978</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1840-1849; 1850-1859; 1860-1869</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>61
METHODISTS AND MURFREESBORO IN THE MID-NINETEENTH CENTURY
by Jerry H. Brookshire
Murfreesboro and the nation experienced a critical and fascinating
period during the three decades of the 184.0's-60*s: the late antebellum
era, Civil War, and Reconstruction. The conditions during this period can
be partially revealed through studies of the various facets of life at the
time. This paper vdll examine one such aspect &#8212; Methodism in Murfreesboro -
with particular emphasis on membership patterns as affected by slavery,
Civil War, and Reconstruction.
Some brief introductory comments about the Methodist organizational
structure may be in order. The Methodist Episcopal Church had a quadrennial
General Conference. The church was divided into many subgroupings , called
"conferences," most of which were the size of a state or portion of a state.
Each conference held a yearly meeting called the Annual Conference; the
Tennessee Conference usually met in October. A conference was divided into
districts, over which were presiding elders (district superintendents)
.
Then there was the local charge or circuit, consisting of one or more
chvirches, and to which would be appointed a pastor(s). In the Tennessee
Conference, appointments were usvially changed every year.
In 1844.-1845 a major split in the Methodist Episcopal Church occurred;
the ch\irch throughout most of the slaveholding states formed itself into
the Methodist Episcopal Chxirch, South, and the remainder throughout the
nation continued with the original name. Slavery was one significant issue
62
which brought about this split, and directly involved in this separation
were several men closely associated with Murfreesboro Methodism.
Methodism in America had struggled with the problem of slavery for
many decades. The 1784. conference which organized the Methodist Episcopal
Church for the newly independent United States forbade slave trade or ^
ownership by members and established a procedure for the gradual emancipation
by Methodist owners. At first, most preachers and laymen took this provision
seriously, but over the next three decades the General Conference gradvially
modified its anti-slavery position and even provided some local options by
Annual Conferences on the issue. In the Tennessee Conference there were
some heated debates, especially in 1819, but generally by the 1820's ^
slavery was becoming tolerated for several reasons. Throughout the south
the cotton economy was growing and slavery was becoming more pervasive,
and particularly in Tennessee, Methodists were evolving from "frontiersmen"
to more settled, more affluent people. Some preachers in Tennessee were
Harrying into slave-owning families, and moreover, some of the most vocal,
anti-slavery preachers were recognizing the change and were moving to non-slave
states.^ Following the 182A General Conference, the position was
that Methodist laymen could own slaves, but that slavery was considered an evil and an
official within the church could neither buy and sell slaves nor own slaves
(unless the law in his state prohibited emancipation), and even this
provision was not enforced.
Two important secondary sources on the chiirch separation are the per-tinent
sections of William Warren Sweet, The Methodi st Episcopal Church and
the Civil War (Cincinnati: Methodist Book Concern Press, 1912) and Emory
Stevens Bucke, gen. ed., The History of American Methodism . 3 vols. (New
York: Abingdon Press, I964.).
^oda Lee Kennedy, "The Methodist Church in Tennessee, 1 800-1 82i;"
(Thesis, George Peabody College, 1929), pp. 59-62.
63
Within the United States during the 1830's and 18^4.0' s, abolition
jnovements became significant. Slavery became a very controversial issue
among Methodists, although the aboUtionists gained little support in the
1836 and I84O General Conferences. In the early 18.^0' s, the anti-slavery
movement grew stronger, and the issue at the \^UU General Conference pre-cipitated
a split in the church.
The General Conference met in New York in May and June of 18/W.. All
four delegates from the Tennessee Conference are associated with the Mui-- ^
freesboro church. Robert Paine had been its first pastor two decades
earlier, Thomas Madden bec&amp;me its pastor six years later, and A. L. P.
Green was twice the presiding elder (district superintendent) of the Mur-freesboro
district. John B. McFerrin was never assigned to Murfreesboro,
but he often preached there on special occasions and was a close relative
of later pastors there; McFerrin edited the Southwestern Christian Advocate
located in Nashville and used it in 18iW.-4.5 to print letters and articles
by himself and others which strongly favored the separation of the church
3
and which criticized northern Methodists."^
The 184-4 General Conference experienced a heated debate which centered
arotmd Bishop James 0. Andrews of Georgia, who through marriage and inheri-tance
became owner of a few slaves in a state in which emancipation was
illegal. One motion at the General Conference proposed to remove him as
bishop since he owned slaves; the amended version which passed 110 to 68
retained him in office but suspended him from performing any duties as
bishop while he continued to own slaves. All four Tennessee delegates
^Lewis McCarroll Piirifoy, Negro Slavery ; The Moral Ordeal of
Southern Methodism . 18^4-1861 (Lake Junaluska, N.C.: Association of
Methodist Historical Societies, I966), pp. 81-82.
voted vdth the minority, and Green spoke passionately during the debate.
The long debate was not on slavery itself, for most delegates considered
Slavery a sin; that debate, as well as an earlier one at the Conference,
centered on the power of the General Conference to interfere in areas
affecting the duties of bishops. In fact, even after the split in the
church, the Methodist Episcopal Church included slave-holding states
(border states), and only in 186-^ did its General Conference prohibit slave
ownership by members.
At the 18^ General Conference, following the defeat of the southern
position on the Andrews case, McFerrin's motion was passed that a "Committee
of Nine" devise a method for a possible division of the church if Annual
Conferences in slave-holding states chose to form their own organization.
Paine chaired the committee and then explained and defended its "Plan of
Separation" in the resulting debates. The General Conference accepted it
5
before adjournment.-'
Delegates from the southern Conferences then continued to meet for
another day in New York and agreed that their Annual Conferences should
determine their positions on separation and appoint delegates to a special
convention in Louisville in May 18^5- The Tennessee Annual Conference
later in 18U strongly supported separation^ and sent to Louisville ten
men. Four had attended the 18U General Conference and had signed the call
for the Louisville convention; of the other six, five are associated with
Murfreesboro as pastors or presiding elders: Fountain E. Pitts, J. W. Hanner,
^History of the Organization of the Methodist Episcopal Church , South,
vlth the Journal of Its First General Conference (Nashville: Publishing
House, Methodist Episcopal Church, South, 1925), pp. 95-96, Ul-U^- This
is a collection of pertinent documents.
^Ibid., pp. 101, passim .
^Ibid., pp. 182-85.
65
Joshxia Boucher,' Robert L. Andrews (its then presiding elder), and Ambrose
F. Driskill (Andrews' successor the next year). At Loudsville, Paine and
Pitts served on the important Committee of Organization and all ten voted
with the overwhelming majority to create a separate church, the Methodist -^
Episcopal Church, South.
Slavery and the relationship of white and black members within the -'
church was a crucial concern for the Methodist Episcopal Church, South.
Its first General Conference strongly recommended that there not be sep-arate
black congregations (called African missions or colored missions) -jf
within districts; rather, blacks and whites should belong to the same
congregations and worship together even though there would be segregation
in seating. Most supporters of that arrangement considered it better spir-itually
for blacks and whites alike (many clergymen stressed the equality
of souls) and also financially (for whites would have to support the "mis-sions")-
Despite that appeal, many churches and districts did not follow
that pattern. In antebellum Murfreesboro, where about half of the members ^
of the Methodist church were slaves, the worship arrangements for the blacks
varied throughout the period.
At times, apparently there were joint worship services by the two
races, for the old church building (constructed in 1823 ) and the new one
Boucher had signed a vigorous protest following the 1819 Annual
Conference for its refusal to admit on trial to the clergy a slave-owner.
John B. McFerrin, History of Methodism in Tennessee . 3 vols. (Nashville:
Southern Methodist Publishing House, 1869-73), 3: 160-161
.
^Organization . . . M. E. C . South , pp. 239, 24.8, 262-63.
&#176;Piirifoy, Negro Slavery, pp. 14.6-14.7.
^History of Tennessee . . ..Rutherford . &#171; &#187;. (Nashville; Goodspeed
Publishing Co., 1886), p. 84-0.
66
which replaced it in 184,3'''' each had a gallery for slaves. Even so, most
services were separate according to G. T. Henderson, once its pastor and a "
long-time Murfreesboro Methodist during this period. Henderson wrote that
"negroes worshiped in the ^^8233 church every Sunday afternoon at 3 o'clock,
with Thomas Hartwell as their preacher," and in the 18^3 building, the "base-
1
2
ment was used by the negroes for general services and Sunday school purposes."
For most of this period, the whites and blacks were considered part of
the same "congregation," whether or not they actually worshiped together.
For other years, though, they were separate congregations. For the first
time in the official chiirch membership records, in October 184.5 no blacks were
listed on the Murfreesboro chiirch rolls; they and blacks from other churches
in the vicinity were in the "Stone's River African Mission" circuit. Al- ^
though that special circuit continued (with some interruption) until the war
years, from 184.7 iintil 1853 the Murfreesboro membership records again included .
both whites and blacks. In 1853 the pastoral assignment specified a "Murfrees-boro'
and col'd mis," indicating that there were two separate congregations "
sharing the same pastors. -^ The next year (1854) the two races were separated
into different charges with the creation of the Rutherford colored mission," "
vrtiich lasted only one year and whose preacher was Elisha Carr. For the next
Carlton C. Sims, ed., A History of Rutherford County , ^turfreesboro,
Tenn.: Carlton C. Sims, 1947] p. 196.
1
2
C. C. Henderson, The Story of Murfreesboro (Murfreesboro, Tenn.: News-
Banner Publishing Co., 1929), p. 131. Sims states that the basement was
"sometimes used for Negroes." Ibid.
"^There is no indication whether T. W. Handle or his assistant Abraham
Overall had specific responsibility for the black congregation.
67
three years (1855/56-1857/58) whites and blacks were listed in the same Mur-freesboro
congregation, but the next two years (1858/59 and 1859/60) Kurfrees-boro
was again an all-white congregation, and its blacks were included in the -
Stone's River African Mission. During the remaining two years (1860/61 and
1861/62) before the va.T interrupted, whites and blacks were again listed in
the same congregation (the 1862 membership figures recorded 24.3 whites and -
267 blacks). ^"^
Apparently in antebellum Murfreesboro, only occasionally did the blacks
and whites worship together in segregated seatings; the pattern was separate :4
worship services, especially by the 1840's. The constant separating of the
two congregations during the two decades before the Civil War indicates that
these were probably merely organizational or administrative changes and that
the races worshiped separately even when technically part of the same congre-gation
(or "station" or "church").
Preachers assigned to black congregations were white. A glimpse into "^
the worship services is fo\ind in a series of essays on Elisha Carr, who served
about half his ministry in black missions, including one year in Murfreesboro.
He disliked what he considered excessive or feigned emotionalism of blacks
diiring worship; he also was reputed once to have carried pebbles to throw at
those who slept during services. He believed he understood the "black character,"
""^The information found above in this paragraph is from the various
Tennessee Annual Conference reports in the yearly Minutes of the Annual Con-ferences
of the Methodist Episcopal Church, South . .
.
(Nashville: Southern
Methodist Publishing House) . Unfortunately, figures on membership totals may
not always be accurate, especially on black membership when at times "round
niunbers" seem to be used. Black membership in Murfreesboro in the IS^O's and
1850's generally ranged between 130 and 180. Since the Annual Conference
usually met in October each year, a church year is from October to October.
Membership figures are supposedly for that time of year; however, if whites and
blacks are listed in the same congregation then, that does not necessarily in-dicate
they were part of the same congregation for the entire preceeding year.
&#8226;^No information has been located on Thomas Hartwel] though most likely
he, too, was white.
68
and he preached to them to end their faults, be honest, and obey their mas-ters.
His views on blacks may have been very sirailiar to his friend, A. P.
L. Green, a slave-owner preacher vrtio believed the system of slavery under
good masters was beneficial to blacks for he felt that they were inherently
17
incompetent to control themselves. Jithin the black I'lurfreesboro congre-gation
were some members who had leadership positions and preached some sermons.
The postwar black congregation was listed as having four Qblack^ "local
preachers"; the pastor, Braxton James, had been such a preacher there while a ^
, 18
slave .
The Civil War came to middle Tennessee and Kurfreesboro in 1862. In y
late February, the Confederate army abandoned Nashville, and Murfreesboro be-came
the temporary headquarters of General Albert Sydney Johnston before he
moved south to fight and die at Shiloh in April. The Federal army took control
of Murfreesboro from the spring imtil the autumn of 1862, though possession was
temporarily interrupted by Forrest's raid in July. In the autumn, General
Brajcton Bragg' s Confederate army withdrew from its campaign in Kentucky to &gt;kir-freesboro
in anticipation of an attack on Nashville. Instead, the Federal
forces advanced from Nashville and defeated the Confederates in the Battle of
Murfreesboro (or Stone's River, December 30, 1862 to January 2, 1863). Bragg's
army was forced back tov;ard Chattanooga, and the Federal army occupied Murfreesboro
""^A. L. P. Green, "The Rev. Elisha Carr." The Home Circle 7 (July I860):
28-29. William M. Green, "Pleasant Recollections of Rev. Elisha Carr," The
Home Monthly 4 (February, ^krch, April, and M^y 1868): 88-90, 111-13,
154-56, 219-21.
17 "
William M. Green, Life and Papers of A. L. P. Green , ed. T. 0. Summers
(Nashville: Southern Methodist Publishing House, 1877), pp. 167-68. Future
research into slave ownership and views on slavery by Murfreesboro Methodist
laymen and other preachers could prove rewarding.
^&#176;Minutes of the Annual Conferences of the Methodist Episcopal Church. .
.
,
(New York: Methodist Episcopal Church), for 1866, pp. 258-59&#171; From the records,
it is not clear v/hether or not James was included in that number of "local
preachers." See also James' obituary in the same publication, 1885, p. 342. y
69
thereafter. The Union forces built the massive Fort Rosencrans to protect
its major supply depot there and maintained effective control over the city
and its people.
The Murfreesboro Methodist church and the entire Tennessee Conference
was greatly disrupted by the war and enemy occupation. The Annual Conference
of October 1862 met in Cornersville, which was accessible and not in Union
&#8226;hands, and then it did not meet again until three years later, after the war
was over. Because of the confusion and uncertainty, practically no changes in
pastoral appointments were made at that 1862 conference. Actually, many pul-pits
were not being filled, for almost one-fifth of the clergymen of the
19
Tennessee Conference were serving in the Confederate army. Many others
left this area for Confederate controlled territory or remained "quietly at
home"; A. L. P. Green in 1869 asserted that Federal troops "arrested and sent
off to prison a considerable number of the Methodist preachers in Nashville
20
and its vicinity."
In 1862 George L. Staley was reappointed as the Murfreesboro pastor, but -
there is no evidence as to how long he continued to serve, since Conference
21 records were not kept between October 1862 and October 1865. Reappointed
as his assistant in 1862 was E. J. Allen, a "supernumerary" preacher who had
been the assistant in Murfreesboro since 1857 and who continued to serve within
the district as an assistant pastor in the postwar period. Allen was apparently
22
a permanent resident of Murfreesboro, and perhaps he led the congregation
19
Carter, History of the Tennessee Conference , pp. 14,7-51
.
^Green, Life and Papers of A. L. P. Green , p. 508.
21
*^' Information gathered by &gt;fertha Ison, "Traveling Connection, Murfreesboro
First Methodist," 1: 90. No obituary exists to shed any light on the question.
^^See Minutes . . . J^.E.C . South for the appropriate years.
70
during much of the war period. G. T. Henderson, a former Murfreesboro pastor
and by then a permanent resident and a publisher in Murfreesboro, served as a
Chaplin in the Confederate army until "disabled by rheumatism . . . near the
close of the war." He then returned to the niinistry, and though it is not
23
clearly stated, he may have led the local church toward the end of the war.
There is not, thus, any solid information on whether or not the Methodist
congregation had an ordained minister during the last two and a half years
of the war.
The Civil War and Reconstruction affected church attendance and member-ship,
both of whites and blacks. Ore obvious feature was that some members
served in the Confederate army^ and thus were not in l-iurfreesboro during
part of the war. Another is that overall white membership seriously declined
beginning with the report of October 1861: 1859 (278), I860 (308), 1861 (251),
1862 (2.;3), 1863 and 186^ (no records), 1865 (229), 1866 (215).^^ One may
only speculate as to the causes of that decline: reduction of religious in-terest,
economic disruption, social instability, etc. Other features involving
membership and attendance were political controversies, loss of the church
building during much of the war, black members forming their separate congre- -/
gation(s), and the Methodist Episcopal Chvirch's attempt to establish a second,
and rival, white church in Murfreesboro.
At least one member withdrew from the church in a very passionate and
controversial dispute over loyalty to the Union or the Confederacy. Most of
^^This portion of Henderson's "obitviary" was written by him. Ison,
"Travelling Connection," 1: 27-32.
^This obvious generalization is based on a few pertinent biographical
sketches, especially foiind in Goodspeed's History ...Rutherford.. . , pp. 1019-
76, and ibid.
&#8226;"Minutes . . .M.E.C. . South , appropriate years.
71
the white members of the church strongly supported the Confederacy. One who
did not was James M. Tompkins, a prosperous farmer and merchant and successful
county political figure; he had served in several political positions, in-cluding
one term (1855-57) as a member of the General Assembly. In December
1861 he was elected a city alderman, and when in 1-lay 1862 the Federal author-ities
in Murfreesboro required all officials to take a prescribed oath, he -^
was one of the few who did; those who did not were removed from office. The
remaining aldermen then elected him mayor, a post he held for several months
until the war conditions ended the municipal and civil government. His polit-ical
activities were very unpopular in Murfreesboro in that chaotic year of
1862; he even had two sons in the Confederate army. This tension was re-flected
in the Murfreesboro Methodist church, where he was a member and a
steward. The controversy became so intense that he withdrew his membership
from the church that year, and although he expected to re-enter the church
later on, he finally decided against that and in 1868 joined the Cumberland
Presbyterian church.
Worship service was fvu-ther interrupted by the war as the congregation
lost control of its building in 1862. As with many other large, sturdy,
brick structures in Murfreesboro, the Methodist church building vras taken over
as a hospital, first by the Confederates and then by the Union which held it
until 1865. The structure was severely damaged, and in 1873 it was so com-pletely
remodeled that it was rededicated. For at least part of the time that
^^James M. Tompkins, "Memoirs of James M. Tompkins ( 'V/ritten by Himself')"
and Homer Pittard, "Occupation ^ilyor: The Honorable J. M. Tompkins,"
Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society 2 (Winter '&#8226;973),
pp. 32-36, 30-31; Biorrraphical Directory , Tennessee General Assembly, 1796-
1967 (Preliminary, No. 6) Rutherford County (Nashville: Tennessee State
Library and Archives, (19S8), p. 57; and biographies of two of his sons
(Robert and Albert G.) in Goodspeed's History . . .Rutherford . . ., pp. 'Ob/-
68. The blurred Tompkins memoirs have dates which may be read as 1882 and
1888 or 1862 and 1868; the latter are obviously correct since he died in 1870.
Tompkins wrote this memoir for his children to explain his actions to them.
Apparently he was deeply concerned about the religious controversy, for he ends
with that topic and he wrote this memoir only four months after he decided to
join the Cumberland Presbyterian church.
72
the Methodists were vdthout their building, they used the still incomplete
27
but "less damaged" Cumberland Presbyterian church for Methodist services.
A similar problem affected the black members. A history of a black Methodist -
church founded after the Civil War states that during that war, the blacks
worshiped in some of their houses, in the basement of the Methodist church
28
building, and finally in the Primitive Baptist church.
By the end of the war there was the new question of membership of now
freed black Methodists. Throughout the south, there was by the whites the
general acceptance of separate black congregations, with their own officials
and often their own [blackj pastors. Most white Methodist leaders hoped that
these black congregations would remain within the Methodist Episcopal Church,
South; special circuits and African missions were established or continued. -
The white Methodist leaders believed that the ending of slavery did not mean
that they should end their concern for aiding and perhaps controlling the
religious development of blacks. But black membership fell drastically,
especially as individual blacks and often entire congregations joined the
(independent) African Methodist Episcopal Zion Church, or the Methodist Epis-copal
Church which sent "missionaries" to the south to serve both whites and
blacks. To counter or reverse this loss of membership, the Methodist Episcopal
27
Based nainly on Goodspeed's History. . .Rutherford . . . , pp. 837, 839-4-0;
also J. B. McFerrin, History of Methodism in Tennessee , 3: 34-7 (on his dedicating
the building), and C. C. Henderson, Story of Murfreesboro . p. 131 (on its retiirn
to the congregation in 1865).
^^hkttie D. Bracy, "The Development of the Negro Church in Rutherford
County" (undergraduate paper, Tennessee A. and I., 1944-), p. H. One of her
sources is a now lost work by Mrs. J. P. McClellan, "History of Key Memorial
Methodist Church," [n.p., n.d.^. The sequence of the locations of worship
is as given by Bracy, but one may wonder if not the loss of the church building
to the Methodists caused the black members to then worship in various houses
and then finally in the Primitive Baptist church.
73
Church, South, made an unsuccessful attempt to merge with the African Methodist
Episcopal Church in 1866. Then in general recognition that most blacks wanted
complete control of their own church organization, the Methodist Episcopal
Church, South, helped sponsor in 1870-71 the establishment of the Colored ^--
Methodist Episcopal Church. ^"^
In 1865 in the Kurfreesboro district (of the Methodist Episcopal Church,
South), an attempt was made to include all black members (200, obviously an
estimate) within one "African mission" circuit attached to a white circuit.
30
This failed, and from 1867 on there were very few black members, some having
joined the Colored Methodists, the African Methodists, or the Methodist
31
Episcopal Church.
By the end of the war, the black Methodists in Murfreesboro were no ^
longer associated with the Methodist Episcopal Church, South. The Methodist
32
Episcopal Church sent a northern missionary to Murfreesboro in 1865, but
the local black congregation was at first independent. It soon became affil-iated
with the African Methodist Episcopal Church, which ordained as elder
its local pastor, Breixton James. In October 1866, the Methodist Episcopal
Church held the founding meeting of its Tennessee Conference in Murfreesboro.
Probably while in town for the event, W. H. Pearne (presiding elder for the
33 Memphis district and a missionary to the south from a New York conference)
^Hunter Dickinson Parish, The Circuit Rider Dismounts ; A Social History
of Southern Methodism . 1865-1900 (Richmond: Dietz Press, 1938), pp. 163-76.
^^Minutes . . .M.E.C. . South, appropriate years.
^''Sims, Rutherford County , p. 189.
^^See footnote 42.
33Minutes of . . .M.E.C. for 1866 (pp. 258-59 for the Tennessee Annual"
Conference, and p. 89 for Pearne, a missionary from the V/yoming Annual Con-ference
in New York state)
.
74
preached to that local black Methodist congregation. He offered aid to the
chirrch, including aid to build a chapel (and probably to help pay the pastor &#8226;"
and help develop a Sunday School). All but eleven of the congregation of
about sixty to seventy agreed to join the Methodist Episcopal Church. The
eleven who renained as African Methodists were the nucleus of the future ^
Allen's Chapel; the bulk of the congregation which joined the Methodist
Episcopal Church later became Key Memorial. At this October 1866 Tennessee
Conference, the local minister, Braxton James, was "appointed" to the Mur-freesboro
"second charge," located in the Nashville Mission District. ^^
The Methodist Episcopal Church obtained for the congregation a lot for
the church building, and federal government allowed it to dismantle the Fort -^
Rosecrans commissary and rebuild it for its church, which was used until
about 1880.^^ A northern Methodist missionary to New Orleans about this
time explained and defended the Methodist Episcopal Church activities in the
south, esjiecially because blacks needed financial support for church buildings
and educational programs. By 1867, the Radical Murfreesboro newspaper,
Freedoms Watchman, noted a flourishing Sunday School at the "colored congre- ^
gation of 250 students and 24 teachers.-^' The church building was also used
for a school, its teacher being first a missionary from the north, then the \6
pastor, Braxton James, and later employees of the public school system.
^"^Ibid., and Bracy, "Negro Church in Rutherford County," pp. 14-15, 30.
In describing the Pearne visit, her sources gave the date as 1867; the
Minutes . . M.E.C. indicates 1866.
^^Bracy, "Negro Church in Rutherford County," p. 15.
3^L. C. Matlack, "The Methodist Episcopal Church in the Southern Slates,"
Methodist Quarterly Review 54 (January 1872): 103-27.
^'^November 17, 1867.
3&#176;Bracy, "Negro Church in Rutherford County," p. 15.
75
The local church was active in other ways too, for in 1867, a brush arbor re-vival
greatly increased its membership, apparently both through new members
and by regaining some others who had been members while slaves."^
The Methodist Episcopal Church also tried to create white congregations
in the south. During the war, the Federal government allowed its pastors
(missionaries from the north) to take over some buildings of the Methodist
Episcopal Church, South, in occupied cities,^ a practice which was stopped -
when the war ended. Although one of Nashville's Methodist churches experi-enced
this,"* the Murfreesboro Methodist church did not. Northern mission-aries
were sent to Murfreesboro. The Ohio Annual Conference in October 1865
listed one of its pastors, Wesley Prettyman, as a missionary to Murfreesboro,
but if he did actually come to the town, he failed to establish either a
black or a white congregation. In October 1866 he was assigned to Atlanta.
A white congregation was organized in Miirfreesboro during or just prior to the
founding/ meeting in the town of the Tennessee Conference of the Methodist
Episcopal Church in October 1866.'^^ The pastor of this "Murfreesboro first
charge" for its initial two years was Amasa A. Brown, a missionary from the
-^^Ibid. Bracy mentions a "hundred conversions and two hundred added to
the church." This increase (though not the base number) coincides generally
with the records for appropriate years in Minutes of . . .M.E.C. which listed
1866 U2U members), 1867 (500), and then 1868 (650 members).
^ Street, Methodist Episcopal Church and the Civil War, pp. 98-99.
^ McFerrin, Methodism in Tennessee . 3: H9-50.
^^Minutes of . . . M.E.C. (Ohio Conference in 1865, Tennessee Conference
in 1866).
^^Freedorns Watchman . November 30, 1867, states it was organized "a ^
little over a year ago."
76
North West Indiana Conference who moved on to the Kansas Conference in 1868.'^
The church had "many obstacles. to contend against. "^^ One was the lack of a
\
U(y
church building; it held its services in McFadden's Hall. The most important
problem was membership. V/hite Methodist Episcopal churches in southern states
were expected to serve northern Methodists who were in the south and local
LI
Methodists who opposed the church separation two decades earlier. Apparently
there were few of either in Murfreesboro,^&#176; for the church soon died. The
membership figures were as follows: in 1866 when founded (40 members, 3 pro-bationers,
and 1 local preacher), 1867 (48, 47, and 2), 1868 (26, 1, 0),
1869 (21, 0, 0), and thereafter no pastor nor membership figures were given
49
and no mention of the church was made after 1871
.
The Civil War thus had a tremendous effect on the Methodist organization
in Murfreesboro. The Methodists in antebellum years, while divided into black
^Minutes of . .-.M.E.C. for appropriate years and annual conferences.
When Brown was mentioned as the Rutherford County SuperintendenL of Publi;;
Schools, he was described as a "Negro Methodist Episcopal minister" in Ihrtha
McCullough Bouldin, "A Decade in Rutherford County, 1865-1875" (Thesis,
Middle Tennessee State University, 1973), p. 24. No source was given, but it
seems incorrect considering his past and future assignments as well as his
Murfreesboro pastorate for the white congregation.
^^Freedoms Watchman , November 20, 1867.
^^Ibid. Also, listed were "0" buildings in the Minutes of . . .M.E.C.
for the appropriate years.
^ Mat lack, "The Methodist Episcopal Church in the Southern States," p. 106.
^ One nay speculate if Tompkins was a member. He left the Methodist Epis-copal
Church, South, in 1862 and finally joined the Cumberland Presbyterian
church in August 1868. It was the autumn of 1668 that the white Methodist Epis-copal
Church seemed to be failing; its membership was only half of the October
1867 figure, and also its missionary pastor left for a northern conference.
^"Minutes of . . .M.E.C. for appropriate years. Freedoms Watchman , ".&#8226;. ^'\
1867, fully displayed its bias by claiming that the membership was "almost the
average equal of any of our city churches."
77
and white congregations, were within the sane church (l-'iethodist Episcopal
Church, South), shared the same building, and often were within the same "charge"
and shared the same pastor. Shortly after the war there were at least four con-gregations:
a small black African Methodist Episcopal Church (future Allen's
Chapel), the larger black Methodist Episcopal Church (future Key Memorial),
the struggling and soon terminated white Methodist Episcopal Church, and the
white Methodist Episcopal Church, South. That latter congregation ("First
Methodist") did experience some reduction in its white membership, which
averaged about twenty percent lower in the first five postwar years than in
the five years preceeding the war, although by the next decade its membership
surpassed its prewar numbers. Though long lasting, not all the divisions
within Methodism in the mid-nineteenth century were pernanent. In 1938 the
Methodist Episcopal Church, South, and Methodist Episcopal Church me^^ged.
This again brought I-lurfreesboro's white Methodists and most of its black
Methodists into the same denominational structure while still maintaining
separate congregations.
50
Minutes of . . . M.E.C. . South for appropriate years.
</dc:description>
<dc:description>Describes membership patterns of the Methodists in Murfreesboro during the 1840s - 1860s</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>church congregations; Methodism</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-16</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication10ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/107</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>