<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Deed abstracts on Stones River from deed books A, B, C, D, E, F of Davidson County, Tennessee 1784 - 1806</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Johns, Ernie K.</dc:creator>
<dc:contributor>Vaughn, Edna Rhea</dc:contributor>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1981</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1780-1789; 1790-1799; 1800-1809;</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>MIDDLE TN STATE UNIV.
3 3082 01682704 9 acts
on
Stones River
from
Deed Books A, B, C, D, E, F
Davidson County, Tennessee
1784 - 1806
by
&#163;. K. Johns
1981
976
.857
R931 p Rutherford County Historical Society
V. 38 Publication No. 38
Deed Abstracts
on
Stones River
from
Deed Books A, B, C, D, E, F
of
Davidson County, Tennessee
1784 - 1806
by
E. K. Johns
1981
Ml Su Library
Middle Tennessee State University
Murfreesboro, Tennessee 37132
Rutherford County Historical Society
Publication No. 38
10-028S3
Deed Abstracts
on Stones River
from
Deed Books A, B, C, D, E, F
of
Davidson County, Tennessee
1784 - 1806
by
E. K. Johns
1981
Officers
President Nell Blankenship
Vice President Jerry Gaither
Program Co-Chairpersons Bob &amp; Pat Sanders
Recording Secretary Ed DeBoer
Treasurer Mary Cox
Publication No. 38 is distributed to members of the Society. The
annual membership dues are $ 15.00 per family, which includes the
annual publication and the monthly newsletter, Frow Chips, to all
members. Additional copies of this and other publications may be
obtained by writing to the Society.
Rutherford County Historical Society
P. O. Box 906
Murfreesboro, TN 37133-0906
&#169;2000
Foreward
Rutherford County was originally part of Davidson County, Sumner County, Wilson
County and Williamson County. The land records of Davidson County contain many
deeds on Stones River some of which near Donelson are still in Davidson County. The
records ofdeeds on the east and west forks of Stones River and Falling, Stuarts, Cripple,
Overall, Bradley, Big Hurricane and Hart Spring Creeks are mainly now in Rutherford
County.
This information was taken from two rolls of microfilm records in the Tennessee
State Library. Many of the first land grants are recorded but not all. Some of the early
grants may be in Greene County records. Other early grants can be found in Sumner,
Wilson, Williamson and Rutherford County records. Some of the grants were not regis-tered
until after Rutherford County was formed in 1803. Some of the grants were regis-tered
in Davidson County and state that they were in Wilson County at that time.
This information may be of some use to researchers of early Rutherford history
and its people. A copy has been placed in the County Registers Office and in Linebaugh
Library.
One puzzling item in the land grants that cannot be explained is the grant numbers
in the Davidson County records do not all match up with the grant numbers in the book.
North Carolina Land Grants in Tennessee 1778-1791 bv Cartwright &amp; Gardiner, 1958.
Many times the Davidson County number is one ahead of the book number. Also only
the land owners names appear in the index of this paper.
E. K. Johns
Editor's Note
Many interesting facts came to light as this book was being typed. Not too familiar
measurements were used such as: a pole is 16'/2 feet; a chain is 66 feet or 100 links; 80
chains equal to 1 mile; a link is 7.92 inches. Trees were often used as landmarks. Some
trees that were native to the area in 1784-1806 are extinct now or are called by other
names. It was interesting to read about the trees which still flourish in the Stones River
area today. Many of the streets and roads today have the same names as the early
landowners in this area. Preemptors listed at the back of this book are those first settlers
who were landowners before Tennessee became a state. You may find one person's
name listed several times in the Index. That name may be spelled several different ways
as well as abbreviated, but the editor did not feel she had the right to change the spelling
from the original transcript. It was also interesting to learn that the most popular first
name of the early landowners was "John.''
Edna Rhea Vaughn
i?t/CK
KuTrieRrc^D County
Survey 1&amp;| 3
Digitized by the Internet Archive
in 2010 with funding from
Lyrasis Members and Sloan Foundation
http://www.archive.org/details/publication38ruth
Deeds on Stones River
from Davidson County Deeds
Volumes A, B, &amp; C 1784-1796
Lardner Clark March 7, 1785 page 5
North Carolina Grant No. 248 to Robert Martin, Corporal, Lardner Clark, as-signee
ofRobert Martin, is granted 420 acres on Stones River lying between Col.
James Armstrong's military claim of 7200 acres and Stones River. Beginning on
Keneday's west boundary at a black oak &amp; dogwood, then west 120 poles to Col.
Armstrong's east boundary to two dogwoods &amp; a hickory then north along
Armstrong's line 180 poles to a large branch in all 402'/2 poles to a stake, then
east 120 poles to a stake, then south 402 !/2 poles to the beginning. Surveyed for
Lardner Clark by Robert Hays, D.S., June 13, 1785. Military Warrant No. 1029.
Grant dated March 9, 1785.
Archibald Lytle page 43
North Carolina Grant to Lt. Col. Commandant (?) granted 7200 acres on Stones
River on the west fork. Beginning at a mulberry &amp; two dogwoods on Old East
Line and runs south 134 to a cherry tree, then east 6 poles to two black oaks then
south 6 poles to two cherry trees, then west 6 poles to a white oak then south
1391 poles crossing a small creek to a walnut &amp; tliree ashes, then west 496 poles
crossing Stones River 270 poles more to a stake, then north 1531 poles crossing
Lytle Creek to a white oak, dogwood, &amp; black oak on ye old east line, then west
with said boundary 326 poles to Stones River, then south up the river 74 poles to
an ash, then west 320 poles to a walnut &amp; mulberry, then north 74 to a dogwood
&amp; elm on the east line then west with the line to the beginning. Surveyed by
Robert Hays March 11, 1785, in consequence of Military Warrant No. 1. En-tered
March 2, 1785.
Thomas Cox February 19, 1788 page 112
North Carolina Grant No. 81 to Thomas Cox, one of the guards to the commis-sioners,
for laying offthe land for the officers and soldiers. Thomas Cox is granted
640 acres on main west fork of Stones River. Beginning at two white oaks and
south west corner to Samuel Wilson's preemption, then south 320 poles to three
walnuts, then east 320 poles crossing the said river to a stake, then north 320
poles to said Wilson's corner, then west with his line 320 poles to the beginning.
Surveyed for said Cox March 12, 1785 by R. W. Pollock, D.S., and Benj. Watkins
and Jonathan Robertson in consequence of a warrant No. 149, located and en-tered
January 16, 1784 in the preemption office. Dated October 8, 1781.
Thomas Cox February 19, 1788 page 112
North Carolina Grant No. 43 to Thomas Cox, commissioners guard. Thomas
Cox is granted 320 acres joining his 640 acre tract on the upper side. Begiiming
at three small walnuts corner to his 640 acres, then south 160 poles to two wal-nuts
and mulberry, then east 320 poles to a large ash &amp; white oak, then north 160
poles to the other corner of his 640 acre survey, then west with his boundary 320
poles to the beginning. Surveyed by Wm. Pollock D.S. &amp; Jonathan Robertson
1
and Benj. Watkins March 9. 1785. Located &amp; entered January 17. 1784. in the
preemption office. Dated October 8. 1787.
Samuel Bucchanan February 26. 1788 page 128
North Carolina Grant No. 324 to Samuel Bucchanan for the services of Col.
Martin Armstrong, surveyor. Samuel Bucchanan. assignee of said Armstrong .is
granted 400 acres on the west waters of Stones River. Beginning at a white oak &amp;
dogwood Cornelius Ruddle "s west boundary, south with said line 180 poles to a
white oak &amp; dogwood, then east with said Ruddle's line 105 poles to a dogwood,
then south 120 poles to an elm. Then west 220 to an ash. then north 300 to a
cedar, then east 188 poles to the beginning. Surveyed April 5. 1786, by John
Buchanan. D.S. &amp; Cornelius and William Mulheim, chain carriers, located De-cember
5. 1785. Grant dated Aguust 1. 1787.
Green Hill March 1. 1788 page 135
North Carolina Grant No. 229 to William Walten private. Green Hill, assignee of
William Walten. is granted 640 acres on Stones River on the Big Hurricane.
Beginning at a lynn northeast comer of Nancy &amp; Elizabeth Rearden runs north
through the Big Hurricane 427 poles to a dogwood, then west 240 poles to a
hackberry. then south 427 poles to a dogwood &amp; hornbeam on said Rearden"s
line, then to the beginning 240 poles. Sun eyed August 6. 1785. by John Buchanan
D.S. - EphriamNo. 1067. located June 2, 1785. Grant dated March 7. 1786.
Lardner Clark March 3. 1788 page 142
For ten pounds for each 100 acres. Lardner Clark is granted 640 acres on Hurri-cane
Creek. Beginning at a sugar tree on Green Hill's west boundary and runs
south 226 poles crossing a fork of Hurricane Creek to a dogwood &amp; hornbeam,
then west 452 poles to a mulberry, then north 226 poles to a log on the Big
Hurricane, then east 452 to the beginning. Surveyed June 1. 1784. by John
Buchanan. D.S. - Ephraim McLane &amp; William Morrow S.C.C. in consequence
of Warrant No. 573. located July 6, 1784. Grant dated April 17. 1786.
Lardner Clark March 3. 1788 page 142
North Carolina Grant No. 648 to Mordica Holman private, Lardner Clark, as-signee
of said Holman. is granted a tract of 640 acres on Stones River on Hurri-cane
Creek. Beginning at a honey locust &amp; elm Capt. James Bradley's north
boundary, then east with said line 320 poles to a popular being corner to said
Bradley, then north 320 poles to Henry (Charron) south boundary', then west
with said line 320 poles to a stake. Then south 320 poles to the beginning. Sur-veyed
by John Buchanan D.S. - Samuel McMurray &amp; James Mulherin S.C.C.
February 1, 1786. in consequence of Military Warrant No. 1661. located Sep-tember
9, 1785. Grant dated December 8. 1787.
JohnCaffrey March 4. 1788 page 145
For the sum often pounds for each 100 acres, Jolm Caffrey is granted 640 acres
on Stones River on both sides of Stoners Creek and about three miles of Stoners
Lick. Beginning at a sugar tree, white oak &amp; ash on the north side of said creek
then north 226 poles to a white oak, then east 452 poles crossing two branches to
a white oak, black walnut and cedar then south 226 poles to a white oak, dog-wood
&amp; ash crossing said creek, then west 452 poles to the beginning. Surveyed
by John Buchanan D.S. - Hugh Henry &amp; Win. Donald S.C.C. on April 4, 1785, in
consequence of Warrant No. 284, located &amp; entered in the Preemption office
February 14, 1784. Grant dated April 17, 1786.
William Stuart March 8. 1788 page 157
North Carolina Grant No. 169. For the sum often pounds for each 100 acres
Win. Steward is granted 640 acres on the east side of Stones River and south of
the Public land which includes Stoners Lick. Beginning at a large black gum and
white ash in the line of the Public survey, then south poles to a hickory on the top
of cliff at the bank of Stones River up Stones River according to several mean-ders
to a black oak on the northeast bank of the Buffalo Ford, then north 566
poles to a white dogwood and two poplars 72 poles east of the southeast corner
of the public survey. West 425 poles touching the comer two white oak saplins.
of the public survey at 72 poles, &amp; along this line to the begiiming. Grant dated
April 17, 1786.
Moses Shelby March 10, 1787 page 159
North Carolina Grant No. 67 to Moses Shelby, commissioner guard, granted
1200 acres on Smart's Creek. Beginning at four mulberry trees above a spring
mnning into the west of Smart's Creek. Then east 400 poles crossing Stuart's
Creek to two hickories. Then north 480 poles to a red oak &amp; walnut. Then west
400 poles to a hickory &amp; sugartree. Then south 480 to the beginning. Surveyed
by John Buchanan D.S. June 9, 1785, in consequence of a Warrant No. 242,
located February 6. 1784. Grant dated October 8, 1787.
Evan Shelby March 10. 1788 page 160
North Carolina Grant No. 44 to Evan Shelby, commissioners guard. Evan Shelby
is granted 1200 acres on Stewards Creek. Beginning at three hickories running
west joining Moses Shelby's northeast corner at 120 poles, continues with his
line to a sugar tree and hickory at 520 poles, then north 369/2 to a poplar and
mulberry, then east 520 poles to a stake, then south to the beginning. Surveyed
June 9. 1785. by John Buchanan D.S. in consequence of Warrant No. 241, lo-cated
&amp; entered in the Preemption office February 6. 1784. Grant dated October
8. 1787.
Samuel Wilson March 10. 1788 page 160
North Carolina Grant No. 39. For the sum of ten pounds for every 100 acres
Samuel Wilson is granted 640 acres on Stones River. Beginning on the bank of
Stones River, then west 61 to a mulberry, then south 320 poles to a white oak
then east crossing Stones River at 123, cornered on a hickory at 320 poles. Then
north cross Singing (Sinking) Creek at 312 poles, cornered on an oak at 320.
Then west to the beginning crossing Sinking Creek at 1 1 poles. Surveyed Janu-ary
22&#171; 1785, by John Buchanan D.S. in consequence of a Warrant No. 29, lo-cated
&amp; entered in the Preemption office December 22. 1785. Grant dated April
. 1786....
John Mulherin March 11, 1788 page 162
North Carolina Grant No. 5. For the sum often pounds for every 100 acres John
Mulherin is granted 640 acres on Overall Creek. Beginning at a black walnut
being the southeast corner of William Overall's preemption. Running south 360
poles to an oak. then west crossing Overall Creek at 124 poles, continued to an
ash at 283 lA poles, then north 260 poles to a post oak. Then east joining said
Overall's southwest corner at 57 poles and crossing the creek at 243 poles and
continues to the beginning at total of 2831/2 poles. Surveyed January 20. 1785. by
Jolin Buchanan. D.S.. in consequence of a Warrant No. 1 1, located &amp; entered in
the Preemption office December 26, 1783. Grant dated April 17. 1786.
John Foreman March 12. 1788 page 165
North Carolina Grant No. 85. For the sum often pounds for every 100 acres John
Foreman is granted 640 acres on Mill Creek. Beginning at a poplar miming south
crossing a branch of Mill Creek at 150 poles continued to a dogwood at 320
poles, then east 320 poles to a sugar tree, then north 320 poles to a hickory
crossing a branch of Stones River at 300 poles, then west to the beginning cross-ing
a small branch of Mill Creek at 300 poles. Surveyed July 28. 1784, by John
Buchanan D. S. in consequence of a Warrant No. 309. Located &amp; entered in the
Preemption office February 20, 1784. Grant dated April 17, 1786.
JohnBowen March 12. 1788 page 166
North Carolina Grant No. 65 to John Bowen. heir of Moses Bowen, a commis-sioners
guard, is granted 320 acres on Stuart's Creek, a branch of Stones River.
Beginning below Ins improvement at a large white oak running south 160 poles
crossing the creek twice to a sugar tree &amp; elm. then west 320 poles crossing to a
hickorv and ash. then north 160 poles to a hickory &amp; honey locust, then east 320
poles to the beginning. Surveyed by Robert Russell D.S. April 13. 1785. in con-sequence
of a Warrant No. 326. located &amp; entered in the Preemption office March
20, 1784. Grant dated October 8. 1787.
William Overall March 12. 1788 page 167
North Carolina Grant No. 166. For the sum often pounds for each 100 acres
William Overall is granted 640 acres on Overall Creek. Beginning at a black
walnut 200 yards north of the falls and runs east crossing Overall Creek at 86
poles continued to a white oak at 146 poles, then south 452 poles to a black
walnut, then west crossing the creek at 58 poles continued to three cherry trees at
226 poles, then north 452 poles to a mulberry, then east to the beginning. War-rant
No. 131. located &amp; entered in the Preemption office January 15. 1784. Grant
dated April 17. 1786.
Reading Blount April 22. 1788 page 191
North Carolina Grant No. 14 to Reading Blount, major. Reading Blount is granted
4800 acres between the east &amp; west forks of Stones River. Beginning at Col.
Shelby's south boundary line at two hickories and dogwood, then west with
Shelby's line 132 poles to Bushnell's Creek, the same course continued in all
1250 poles to a hickory, dogwood &amp; red oak. then south 656 poles crossing a
small creek to a walnut, then east 1250 poles to an ash, then north 656 poles to
the beginning. Grant dated March 10, 1786.
Stephen Cantrill April 26. 1788 page 207
North Carolina Grant No. 64 to Stephen Cantrill, a commissioner's guard, is
granted 640 acres on Steward's Creek, a branch of Stones River. Beginning at
126 poles east of said creek at a stake, running west 3210 poles crossing the
creek to a hickory &amp; dogwood, north 320 poles to a hackberry &amp; hickory, then
east 320 poles crossing the creek to an ash &amp; mulberry, south 320 poles to the
beginning. Surveyed April 12, 1785, by Robert Russell, D.S., in consequence of
a Warrant No. 203, located January 29, 1784. Grant dated October 8, 1787.
William Bowman April 26, 1788 page 209
North Carolina Grant No. 220 to William Bowman, assignee of John Callihan, a
private. William Bowman is granted 640 acres on Stones River between Stones
River and Farmer's Creek. Beginning 800 poles south from Col. John Armstrong's
southeast corner. Beginning at a Mulberry, walnut &amp; honey locust, then south
280 poles to an elm &amp; dogwood, then west 366 poles to a stake then north 280
poles to a stake, then east 366 poles to the beginning. Surveyed by Robert Hays
D. S. July 15, 1785, in consequence of a Military Warrant No. 877, located March
9, 1785. Grant dated March 7, 1786.
Robert Spotswood Russell April 28, 1788 page 210
North Carolina Grant No. 25. For the sum of ten pounds for each 100 acres
Robert Spotswood Russell is granted 640 acres on the west fork of Steward's
Creek. Beginning 20 poles below his improvement on the creek, running south
20 poles crossing the creek to a red oak &amp; dogwood, then east 320 poles crossing
the creek twice to a stake, then north 320 poles crossing the creek to a hickory
and persimmon, then west 320 poles to a elm &amp; red oak, then south 300 poles to
the beginning. Surveyed by said Russell, D.S., in consequence of Warrant No.
400 on April 12, 1785, located and entered April 6. 1784. Grant dated April 17,
1786.
Samuel Hays April 28, 1788 page 210
North Carolina Grant No. 35. For the sum of ten pounds for every 100 acres
Samuel Hays is granted 640 acres on the north side of Stones or Clover Creek, a
branch of Stones River. Beginning at a Spanish oak on the north bank of the
creek corner to the land surveyed for Stones Lick ninning along the line of said
land west 162 poles to a large white oak on corner of Col. John Donaldson's,
then with said Donaldson's line north 325 poles to a hickory and hackberry. East
368 poles to three small poplars, south 169 poles crossing Clover Creek twice to
a sugar tree and ash on the north bank thereof, down the same with the meanders
to the Warrant No. 205, located January 29, 1784. Grant dated April, 1786.
Jacob Castleman April 28, 1788 page 211
North Carolina Grant No. 576. Jacob Castleman, assignee of William Price, pri-vate,
is granted 640 acres on both sides of Stoners Lick Creek joining Stewarts
preemption on the north. Beginning at a black gum ninning east 230 poles to a
sugar tree and dogwood, then north 445 poles to a honey locust and elm, then
west 230 to an ash &amp; elm, then south 445 poles to the beginning. Surveyed Sep-tember
18. 1786. by Moses Shelby in consequence of a Military Warrant No.
951. Grant dated September 15, 1787.
Timothy Acuff April 28. 1788 page 212
North Carolina Grant No. 179. Timothy Acuff, assignee of Richard Evans, a
private, is granted 640 acres between Smart "s and Fanning Creek. Beginning at
Col. James Armstrong's northeast comer at a hickory, black oak &amp; walnut, then
west 320 poles to a red oak. Then north 320 poles to a stake. Then east 320 poles
to a stake, then south 320 poles to the beginning. Surveyed by Robert Hays, D.S.,
in consequence of a Military Warrant No. 1223. located March 8, 1785. Grant
dated March 7, 1786.
Eusebius Bushnell July 18. 1788 page 218
North Carolina Grant No. 626. Eusebius Bushell &amp; William Dobbins, assignees
of William Davis' heirs, are granted 640 acres lying on Moses Shelby's west
boundary line. Beginning at said Shelby's southwest corner at three mulberries,
then north 400 poles to a walnut on Shelby line, then west 256 poles to a stake
then south 400 poles to a stake, then east 256 poles to the beginning. Surveyed
by Edwin Hickman, D. S.. in consequence of a Military Warrant No. 1625. lo-cated
July 21. 1785. Grant dated September 15. 1787.
Bushnell &amp; Dobbins July 19. 1788 page 218
North Carolina Grant No. 623. Eusbius Bushnell and William Dobbins, assign-ees
of Jos. Williford, are granted 640 acres on a branch of Stones River by Bushnell
Creek and on Major Blount's east boundary line at Bushnell" s southwest corner
of a 1000 acre No. 1660. Beginning at a mulberry, walnut &amp; oak, then south 279
poles crossing Bushnell Creek to a walnut and three big red oaks, then east 367 Vi
to a stake, then north 279 poles to a walnut, then west 3671/2 poles to the begin-ning.
Surveyed September 1. 1785 by Robert Hays. D.S., in consequence of a
Military Warrant No. 1667, located September 1. 1785 . Grant dated September
15, 1787.
Bushnell and Dobbins July 19. 1788 page 219
North Carolina Grant No. 624. Eusebius Bushnell and William Dobbins, assign-ees
of Daniel Jacobs. Sgt.. are granted 1000 acres on Stones River. Beginning
Col. Shelby's southeast corner at an ~ walnut, and oak. then east 370 poles with
Capt. Montflorence's line to a walnut, then south 432 poles to a stake, then west
370 poles to a mulberry, then north 432 poles to the beginning. Surveyed by
Robt. Hays September 2. 1785. in consequence of a Military Warrant No. 1674.
located July 24. 1785. Grant dated September 15. 1787.
Bushnell and Dobbins July 19, 1788 page 219
North Carolina Grant No. 634. Eusebius Bushnell and William Dobbins, assign-ees
of John Beaver. Sgt.. are granted 1000 acres on Stones River. Beginning at
Col. Isaac Shelby's southwest corner a large hickory, red oak and dogwood,
miming then north 320 poles to a walnut on said Shelby's line, then west 500
poles to a stake, then south 320 poles to a stake, then east 500 poles to the begin-ning.
Surveyed by Ed Hickman in consequence of a Military Warrant No. 1669,
located July 25, 1785. Grant dated September 15, 1787.
Bushnell and Dobbins July 19, 1788 page 220
North Carolina Grant No. 632. Eusebius Bushnell and William Dobbins, assign-ees
of Alanson Summons, Sgt, are granted 1000 acres on Stones River. Begin-ning
at Col. Shelby's south boundary line, a dogwood and hickories, then east
370 poles crossing a small creek to said Shelby's southeast corner to a double
walnut and oak. Then south 432 poles to a stake, then west 370 poles to a mul-berry,
walnut and ash. then north 432 poles crossing Bushnell"s Creek to the
beginning. Surveyed September 6, 1785, by Robert Hays, D.S.. in consequence
of a Wilitary Warrant No. 1660. Located July 25. 2785. Grant dated September
15, 1787.
Bushnell and Dobbins July 19, 1788 page 220
North Carolina Grant No. 629. Eusebius Bushnell and William Dobbins, assign-ees
of Capt. Mathew Wood, are granted 1622 acres on the east fork of Stones
River. Beginning at Col. Isaac Shelby's northwest comer at a large red oak and
hickory, running east with Col. Shelby's north boundary 648'/2 poles crossing
Stones River to a walnut on said Shelby's line, then north 400 poles to a stake,
then west 648 !/2 poles to a stake, then south 400 poles crossing Stones River to
the beginning. Surveyed September 7, 1785, by Edwin Hickman in consequence
of a Military Warrant No. 572, located July 25, 1785. Grant dated September 15,
1787.
Bushnell and Dobbins July 1 9, 1 788 page 22
1
North Carolina Grant No. 625. Eusebius Bushnell and William Dobbins, assign-ees
of Jacob Givins, a private, are granted 640 acres on Stuart's Creek. Begin-ning
at Capt. Moses Shelby's southeast comer on the east side of said creek at
three hickories, then north 400 poles with said Shelby's line to a mulberry, then
east 256 poles to a stake, then south 400 poles to a red oak, then west 256 poles to
the beginning. Surveyed by Robert Hays, D.S.. in consequence of a Military
Warrant No. 686, located July 25, 1785. Grant dated September 15, 1787.
Bushnell and Dobbins July 19,1788 page 22
1
North Carolina Grant No. 627. Eusebius Bushnell and William Dobbins, assign-ees
of John Ward, a fifer, are granted 1000 acres on both sides of the main west
fork of Stones River. Beginning at Col. Isaac Shelby's northwest comer at a large
red oak and hickory, running north 640 poles crossing Stones River to a walnut,
then west 500 poles to a stake, then south 640 poles to a stake crossing Stones
River, then east 400 poles to the beginning. Surveyed by Edwin Hickman in
consequence of a Military Warrant No. 1677, dated Septmeber 1, 1785. Grant
dated September 15, 1787.
Bushnell and Dobbins July 19, 1788 page 221
North Carolina Grant No. 630. Eusebius Bushnell and William Dobbins, assign-ees
of Henry Cole, a drummer, are granted 1000 acres on Stones River. Begin-
ning at Col. Isaac Shelby's northwest corner at a large red oak and hickory,
running south 320 poles to a walnut on said Shelby's line, then west 500 poles to
a stake, then north 320 poles to a stake, then east 500 poles to the beginning.
Surveyed by Edwin Hickman, D.S., in consequence of a Military Warrant No.
1665, located July 25, 1788. Grant dated September 15, 1787.
Bushnell and Dobbins July 19, 1788 page 222
North Carolina Grant No. 635. Eusebius Bushnell and William Dobbins, assign-ees
of private Isaac Hill, are granted 228 acres on Stones River. Beginning at
Major Blount's northwest comer at a hickory, dogwood and red oak. then west
200 poles to a walnut, then south 18214 poles to a stake, then east 200 poles to a
mulberry on Major Blount's west boundary, then north 18214 poles to the begin-ning.
Surveyed by Robert Hays, D.S., in consequence of a Military' Warrant No.
1689, located July 25, 1785. Grant dated September 15. 1787.
John Blackamore July 29, 1788 page 243
Indenture made May 16, 1788, for the sum of 500 pounds Eusebius Bushnell and
William Dobbins have sold 1000 acres to John Blackamore on the east fork of
Stones River. Beginning at Isaac Shelby's northwest corner a large black oak,
running north 320 poles to a stake, then west 500 poles to a stake, then south 320
poles to a stake, then east 500 poles to the beginning.
Hardy Holms October 6. 1788 page 250
North Carolina Grant No. 232. Lt. Hardy Holms is granted 2560 acres on Fanner
Creek on Stones River joining the upper lines of the preemption, running up the
creek on both sides. Beginning at a dogwood and elm then west 80 to Farming
Creek, crossing said creek and continuing west 60 poles to Col. James Armstrong's
southeast comer, continuing west with Armstrong's line, in all 412 poles to a
honey locust and two liickories. then south 800 poles to a stake, then east 412
poles to a stake, then north 800 poles to the beginning. Surveyed March 17,
1780. by Robert Hays, D.S.. in consequence of a Military Warrant No. 212,
located February 9. 1784. Grant dated March 14. 1786.
William Blackamore October 27. 1788 page 257
Indenture made October 7, 1788. For the sum of 100 pounds Eusebius Bushnell
and William Dobbins have sold William Blackamore 640 acres on Moses Shelby's
west boundary line. Beginning at Shelby's southwest corner at three mulberries,
then north 400 poles to a walnut on said Shelby's line, then west 256 poles to a
stake then south 400 poles to a stake, then east 256 poles to the beginning. Land
granted Bushnell &amp; Dobbins by patent dated 15, 1787.
John Rice October 27, 1788 page 258
Indenture made August 13.1788. For 100 pounds Eusebius Bushnell and Will-iam
Dobbins have sold 640 acres on a branch of Stones River known as Bushnells
Creek and on Major Blount's boundary line and at Bushnell's southwest comer
of a 1000 acre survey No. 1660. Beginning at a mulberry and oak. then south 279
poles crossing Bushnell's Creek to a walnut and three red oaks, then east 36714
poles to a stake, then north 279 poles to a walnut, then west 367% poles to the
beginning. Land granted to Bushnell &amp; Dobbins as assignees ofJoseph Williford,
a private, by patent dated September 15, 1787.
Witherel Latimore October 27, 1788 page 259
Indenture made September 3, 1788. For the sum of 57 dollars Eusebius Bushnell
and William Dobbins have sold 228 acres to Witherel Latimore, land located on
Stones River. Beginning at Major Blount "s northwest comer at a hickory, dog-wood
and red oak, then west 200 poles to a walnut, then 182 1/2 poles to a
stake, then east 200 poles to a mulberry Blount's west boundary line, then north
182!/2 poles to the beginning.
Benjamin Joslin October 29, 1788 page 259
Indenture made October 7, 1788. For 200 pounds Eusebius Bushnell and Will-iam
Dobbins have sold Benjamin Joslin 1000 acres on Stones River. Beginning
at Col. Isaac Shelby's northwest corner at a large red oak and hickory, running
north 640 poles crossing Stones River to a walnut, then west 500 poles to a stake,
then south 640 poles crossing Stones River to a walnut, then east 500 poles to the
beginning. Land granted to Bushnell &amp; Dobbins by patent dated September 15,
1787.
Charles Homer November 6, 1788 page 260
Indenture made November 5, 1788. Isadore Skerrett of Davidson County for 300
pounds has sold Charles Homer of the town of Windsor, Bertie County, North
Carolina, 640 acres on the east fork of Stones River above the first line run by
the Commissioners in 1783. Joins Capt. Welch's survey on the east and was
granted Isadore Skerrett for the sendees of Timothy Zralott, a private. Also that
other tract of land on the north side of the east fork. Beginning at a beech tree
marked RW, the northeast corner of the above tract, granted for the se\ice of
Zachariah Zralott, a private, to Isadore Skerrett containing 640 acres.
John Bush November 13, 1788 page 262
North Carolina Grant No. 546. John Bush, Lt., is granted 914 acres on Stuart's
Creek. Beginning at a white oak on the Commissioner's Line, then west with
said line 480 poles to an ash, then south 304 poles to a stake, then east 480 poles
to a stake, then north 304 poles to the beginning. Surveyed by B. Wra. Pollock,
D.S., March 14, 1785, in consequence of a Military Warrant No. 216, located
February 17, 1784. Grant dated September 15, 1787.
John Bucchanan December 1, 1788 page 268
North Carolina Grant No. 41. John Bucchanan, assignee of Col. Martin Armstrong,
surveyor of lands allotted officers and soldiers, is granted 200 acres on the west
side of Stones River about four miles above the old station. Beginning at an elm
and black oak on the bank of the river about thirty yards above the fish dam, then
down the river with its meanders 460 poles to two sugar trees and a hickory
opposite the lower end of an island, then south 160 poles to a stake, then east 80
poles to the beginning. Surveyed by John Bucchanan for himselfMarch 2, 1786,
in consequence of service right of said Armstrong, entered (December) 6, 1785.
Grant dated October 8, 1787.
9
Abm. Riston. Jno. &amp; Elisha Rice December 8. 1788 page 270
North Carolina Grant No. 306. Abraham Riston. John Rice &amp; Elisha Rice, as-signees
of Moses Simpson, a private, are granted 640 acres on Stones River.
Beginning on the west bank of Stones River at a sycamore. John Bucchanan'
s
southeast corner, then west with said line 2621/2 poles to a black oak being said
Bncchanan's southwest comer, then south 390 poles to an elm. then east 262 '/s
poles to a stake, then north to the beginning. Surveyed by John Bucchanan March
10. 1786, by virture of a Military Warrant No. 2055. located December 7. 1785.
Grant dated June 13. 1787.
Abm. Riston. Jno. &amp; Elisha Rice December 8. 1788 page 274
North Carolina Grant No. 296.Abraham Riston. John Rice &amp; Elisha Rice, as-signees
of William Harris, a private, are granted 640 acres. Beginning at a large
white oak on the East bank of Stones River opposite to the Mill Dam Rock, then
east 320 poles crossing Stones River twice to an ash and elm on the east bank of
said river. Then north 320 poles to a mulberry, then west 320 poles to a stake,
then south to the beginning. Sun eyed March 10. 1786. by John Bucchanan.
D.S.. in consequence of a Military Warrant No. 2129. located December 7, 1785.
Grant dated June 13. 1785.
Abm. Riston, Jno. &amp; Elisha Rice December 8. 1788 Page 274
North Carolina Grant No. 294. Abraham Riston, John Rice &amp; Elisha Rice, as-signees
of Dougall McConnough. a private, are granted 640 acres. Beginning at
an ash and elm on the east bank of Stones River, being comer to two surveyed
claimed by John Rice &amp; Co., then east 226 poles to two black walnut trees, then
south 452 crossing Stones River to a black oak. then west 226 poles to a stake,
then north to the beginning. Surveyed by Jolm Bucchanan. D.S.. on March 10.
1786. Grant dated June 13. 1787, Warrant No. 2142. Located December 7. 1785.
Abm. Riston. Jno. &amp; Elisha Rice December 9. 1788
North Carolina Grant No. 297. Abraham Riston. Jolm Rice &amp; Elisha Rice, as-signees
of Samuel Griffin, a private, are granted 640 acres. Beginning at a large
white oak on the east bank of Stones River opposite the Mill Dam Rock, then
east 320 poles to an ash and elm on the east bank of Stones River, then south 320
poles to an elm, then west 320 poles to a stake, then north 320 poles to the
beginning. Surveyed March 10, 1786. by John Bucchanan. D.S., inconsequence
of a Military Warrant No. 3037. located December 7. 1785. Grant dated June 13,
1787.
Hampton &amp; Hay January 16, 1789 page 280
Indenture made June 20, 1788. Eusebius Bushnell and William Dobbins for 598
pounds, sixteen shillings have sold David Hays and Adam Hampton the follow-ing
tracts of land:
All the tract lying on the waters of Stones River being a military claim of 1000
acres, the Warrant No. 1669, located July 25, 1784.
Another tract on Stones River of 1000 acres, the Warrant No. being 1660,
located July 25. 1784.
Also 1000 acres on Stones River, Warrant No. 1674. located July 17. 1784.
10
Another tract of 640 acres on Stones River, being another military claim,
Warrant No. 1686, located July 25, 1784.
A tract on south side of Cumberland joining Brant &amp; Tatum lines contains
640 acres Warrant No. 1664. located August 13, 1784.
A tract on the east fork of Stones River of 1622 acres Warrant No. 572, lo-cated
July 25, 1784.
A tract on Hickman Creek of 1000 acres. Warrant No. 1696, located Septem-ber
1, 1784.
In Sumner Co. on Cumberland River near Virginia line of 640 acres Warrant
No. 1682, located August 13, 1784.
A tract of 1000 acres on Stones River Warrant No. 1665, located July 25,
1784.
Also 1/2 of lot 9 in Nashville.
Isaac Shelby January 19, 1789 page 285
Indenture made January 9. 1789. Laurence Thompson has sold to Isaac Shelby
1000 acres on Stones River for four hundred pounds. Beginning at Isaac Shelby's
southeast corner of a 5000 acre survey a double walnut and oak, then east 320
poles with Capt. Montfait's line to a walnut, then south 432 poles to a stake.
Then west 320 poles to a mulberry, north 432 poles to the beginning. Said land
was granted to Eusebius Bushnell and William Dobbins, grant dated September
15,1787.
Samuel Deason January 19, 1789 page 286
Indenture made January 1, 1789. James Borley has sold Samuel Deason 100
acres for 100 pounds lying on the south side of the Cumberland River, near the
Stone Lick. Beginning at a red oak running north 26 degrees west 150 poles to a
white oak, then south 64 degrees west 87 poles to a pile of stones, then south 26
degrees east 66 to a white oak, then north 64 degrees east 126 poles to the begin-ning.
Laurence Thompson January 20. 1789 page 287
Indenture made January 9, 1789. Eusebius Bushnell and William Dobbins for
the sum of 200 pounds have sold to Laurence Thompson 1000 acres on Stones
River. Beginning at Col. Isaac Shelby's southeast corner at a double walnut and
oak. then east 370 with Capt. Montford's line to a walnut, then south 432 poles to
a stake, then west 372 poles to mulberry, then north 432 poles to the beginning.
Land granted to Bushnell &amp; Dobbins by patent dated September 15, 1787.
John Rice January 21, 1789 page 291
Indenture made January 21, 1789. Abraham Riston has sold for 386
pounds 1/3 part of nineteen tracts containing 3860 acres.
Tract # 299 1000 acres
Tract # 294, 295, 296, 297, 306, 309 640 acres each
These seven tracts were obtained with the date June 13, 1787.
Alexander Cowan, Esq. January 22, 1789 page 295
Indenture made July 14, 1788. John &amp; Elisha Rice have sold to Alexander Cowan
11
of Hartford Co., Maryland, 1280 acres for the sum of 220 pounds. Lying in two
tracts and granted by Patent Nos. 296 &amp; 297 to Abraham (?) , John Rice &amp; Elisha
Rice dated June 13. 1787. (See pages 1 1 &amp; 12 of this typed copy for description
of boundries.) .... if any of the lands mentioned shall befoul of older surverys so
that a loss shall be sustained John and Elisha Rice oblige to make up any differ-ence.
John Donaldson February 5. 1789 page 298
North Carolina Grant No. 209. For the sum often pounds for every 100 acres
John Donaldson is granted 640 acres between Cumberland and Stones River.
Beginning at an ash on the public line, then along the same east 226 poles to
Samuel Hay's corner, white oak and ash. then along his line north 452 passing
his comer and along Nathaniel Hay's line to a hickory and three dogwoods on
the said line, then west 112 poles to a red oak and sugartree on a branch, then
down the same as it meanders to an elm. then west 26 poles to an ash. and then
south 452 poles to the beginning. Surveyed by John Donaldson. D.S., agreeable
to a Warrant No. 327. Entered March 3, 1784. Grant dated July 10. 1788.
Willaim Donaldson February 5. 1789 page 299
North Carolina Grant No. 204. For the sum of ten pounds for every 100 acres
William Donaldson is granted 640 acres in the forks ofbetween Cumberland and
Stones River. Beginning at a red oak on Stones River, then north along John
Donaldson's line 345 poles to a white oak and red oak on Cumberland River,
then down the same as it meanders to the mouth of Stones River, then up Stones
River as it meanders to the beginning. Surveyed by John Donaldson March 22.
1786, agreeable to Warrant No. 620. located November 13, 1784. Grant dated
July 10. 1788.
John Donaldson March 11. 1789 page 306
North Carolina Grant No. 203. For the sum often pounds for every 100 acres
John Donaldson is granted 640 acres on the south side of the Cumberland River.
Beginning at John Donaldson's comer a hickory and three dogwoods on Nathaniel
Hays' line, then along Donaldson's line west 112 poles to a red oak and sugar
tree on a branch, then down said branch as it meanders to an elm. then west 56
poles passing said Donaldson's comer to an ash. then north 440 to an ash in
Stockly Donaldson's line, then along his line east 102 poles to two elms in Lewis
Robard's line. Then along his line south 80 poles to an elm. West 160 to Hugh
Hay's comer locust and elm. then along his line and Nathaniel Hay's line south
360 poles to the beginning. Surveyed for himself by said Donaldson March 6,
1786. Warrant No. 742, June 3. 1785. Grand dated July 10. 1788.
Ambrose Jones March 12, 1789 page 307
North Carolina Grant No. 791. Ambrose Jones, assignee of Daniel Ray. a pri-vate,
is granted 640 acres on the east side of Stones River. Beginning 20 poles
above the mouth of the second creek above the mouth of Stuart's Creek that falls
into the said river on the east side at a while oak and black oak on the bank of the
river, running up with the meanders of the same to the lower end of a large island
to two white ash trees then 352 poles to a cedar, then north 315 poles to a stake,
12
then west 206 poles to the beginning. Surveyed by William Nash, D.S., January
20, 1788. Warrant No. 2740, located January 8. 1788. Grant dated July 10. 1788.
Thomas Armstrong April 28, 1789 page 325
North Carolina Grant No. 164 Thomas Armstrong, assignee of Absolum Fawler,
a private is granted 640 acres on Stones River joining Col. James Armstrong's
entry of 7200 acres on the south side. Beginning at Lt. Hardy Holm's northwest
comer at a honey locust and two hickories, then west 240 poles to a walnut and
hickory, then south 426 Vi to a stake, then east 240 poles to Holmes west bound-ary,
then north along the same line 426!/2 poles to the beginning. Surveyed by
Robert Hays, D.S., March 12, 1785, in consequence of a Military Warrant No.
86 located March 9, 1784. Grant dated March 7, 1786.
Thomas Armstrong April 28, 1789 page 325
North Carolina Grant No. 48. Thomas Armstrong, a captain, is granted 3840
acres on the main west fork of Stones River on the west side about five miles
from the Commissioner's Line run in 1783 and about a mile from the river, to
include two springs. Beginning at two dogwoods and a hickory, then south 540
poles crossing a small creek, continuing south in all 1050 poles to an ash, and
two mulberries, then west 48414 poles to a stake, then north 1050 poles to a stake,
then east 484'/2 to the beginning. Surveyed by Robert Hays, D.S., on March 9,
1785. Grant dated March 14, 1786.
James Armstrong April 28, 1789 page 326
North Carolina Grant No. 35. Col. James Armstrong is granted 7200 acres on
Stones River on the west side between Smart's and Farmer's Creeks, including a
large spring which empties into Stones River. Beginning at a mulberry and dog-wood
running each 680 poles to a walnut and hickory, then south crossing spring
branch at 40 poles same course 1459 poles crossing Farming Creek, same course
48 poles to the north boundry of an older claim, a mulberry and white oak, then
20 poles cross Farming Creek, same course 100 poles to a dogwood and white
oak, then south 203 poles to a cherry tree, then west 560 poles to a mulberry and
honey locust, then north 1720 poles with the east boundary of older claims to the
beginning. Surveyed March 8, 1785 by Robert Hays, D.S., in consequence of
Military Warrant No. 84, located February 14, 1784. Grant dated March 14, 1786.
Thomas Hickman April 29, 1789 page 329
North Carolina Grant No. 739. Thomas Hickman, assignee of Nathaniel Smith, a
private, is granted 640 acres on the first creek that runs into the east fork of
Stones River on the east side above the mouth of Bradley's Creek. Beginning at
a black walnut and ash south cross a branch at 80 poles, another at 164 poles in
all 320 poles to an ironwood, northwest corner to John Marshall, east with his
line 320 poles to a stake, north 320 poles to a stake, west to the beginning. Sur-veyed
by James Sanders in consequence of a Military Warrant No. 2776, located
August 30, 1787. Grant dated July 11, 1788.
Thomas Hickman April 29, 1789 page 329
North Carolina Grant No. 744. Thomas Hickman, assignee ofprivate James Davis,
13
is granted 640 acres on the first creek that runs into the east fork of Stones River
on the east side above the month ofBradley's Lick Creek. Beginning at a red oak
and ash northwest corner to Joseph Hendrick, south with his line cross the creek
at 30 poles, a branch at 184 poles, all 320 poles to a hickory and ash, west 320
poles to an ash and wliite oak, north cross the creek at 88 poles in all 320 poles to
a stake, east to the beginning. Surveyed by James Sanders in consequence of a
Military Warrant No. 1791. located August 30. 1787. Grant dated July 11. 1788.
Thomas Hickman April 29. 1789 page 329
North Carolina Grant No. 742. Thomas Hickman., assignee of Frederick Cross, a
private, is granted 640 acres on the first creek that runs in on the east side of
Stones River above Bradley's Lick Creek. Beginning at a black walnut and ash,
then south cross a branch at 80 poles and then at 154 poles, in all 320 to an elm
and ironwood, west 320 poles to a stake, north 320 poles to a stake, east to the
beginning. Surveyed by James Sanders. D.S.. in consequence of a Military War-rant
No. 2712. located August 30. 1787. Grant dated July 11, 1788.
William Murry April 30. 1789 page 331
North Carolina Grant No. 16. William Murry, assignee of Col. Martin Armstrong.
surveyor, is granted 100 acres on Hurricane Creek running into Stones River on
the lower side. Beginning at a black walnut. Green Hills southeast comer, then
north with Ins line 80 poles to an elm. then east 89 4/10 poles to a mulberry, then
south 168 8/10 poles to an ash, then west 89 4/10 poles to a stake, then north 98
8/10 poles to the beginning. Surveyed for said Murry April 8, 1786. in conse-quence
of a service right of said Armstrong. Located July 14. 1786. Grant dated
October 8. 1787.
Thomas Hickman June 19. 1789 page 334
North Carolina Grant No. 758. Thomas Hickman, assignee of James Cannon, a
private, is granted 640 acres on the first creek that empties in the east side of the
east fork of Stones River above the mouth of Bradley Lick Creek. Beginning at a
buckeye and ash. southeast corner of Joseph Hendrick. then cross a large branch
18 poles, in all 320 poles to an elm. then north 320 poles to a stake, then west 320
poles to Joseph Hendrick' s line, then south with said line across the creek to the
beginning. Surveyed September 3, 1787. by James Sanders. D.S., in consequence
of a Military Warrant No. 2638. located August 30. 1787. Grant dated July 13,
1788.
Nathaniel Hays June 19. 1789 page 335
North Carolina Grant No. 24. For the sum of ten pounds for even 100 acres
Nathaniel Hays is granted 640 acres including a spring which lies in the entrance
into Jones Bent (Bend) on the south side of Cumberland River. Beginning at a
hickory and hackberry in John Doneldson's line 31 poles south of his northeast
corner running then each along Samuel Hay's line 408 poles to white oak and
mulberry, north 25 1 poles to a white oak comer to Hugh Hay's, then along Hugh
Hay's line west 408 poles to a black walnut, south 251 poles to the beginning.
Sun eyed by Daniel Smith June 17. 1785. agreeable to a Warrant No. 655. Entry
dated January 8, 1785. Grant dated April 17. 1786.
14
Hugh Hays June 19, 1789 page 335
North Carolina Grant No. 89. For the sum of ten pounds for every 100 acres
Hugh Hays is granted 640 acres on the south side of the Cumberland River at the
entrance into Jones Bent (Bend). Beginning at Nathaniel Hay's northeast comer
at white oak running west with his line 408 poles to a black walnut, north 251
poles to a honey locust and elm, east 408 poles to a poplar, south 25 1 poles to the
beginning. Surveyed June 18, 1785, by Daniel Smith agreeable to a Warrant No.
654, located January 8. 1785. Grant dated April 17, 1786.
John Tucker July 28, 1789 page 347
Indenmre made July 10, 1789. For the sum of 200 pounds Moses Shelby has sold
300 acres on Stuart's Creek, a branch of Stones River, and known and distin-guished
by the number 67 in the patent. Begiiming at a mulberry and dogwood
the northwest corner of Edwin Hickman's survey, then east 16 chains and 50
links to Stuart's Creek, then north with the creek the different courses down to
Hickman's line, then with the meanders to a stake on said creek, then west 53
chains to a stake, then to the beginning.
Wit. Joel Rice.
Edwin Hickman July 29, 1789 page 349
Indenmre made July 11. 1789. For the sum of 40 pounds Moses Shelby has sold
Edwin Hickman 300 acres being part ofMoses Shelby's guard right, the Warrant
No. 242. Beginning at three mulberries running east 400 poles crossing Smart's
Creek to two hickories, then north 130 poles to a stake, then west 276 poles to a
stake in the bank of Stuart's Creek, then with the meanders of the creek to a
stake, then 66 poles to a mulberry, dogwood and elm, then south 100 poles to the
beginning.
Jacob Movers August 24, 1789 page 350
North Carolina Grant No. 38. Jacob Moyers is granted 400 acres in consideration
of the services of Col. Martin Armstrong, surveyor, lying on the east side of
Stones River. Begiiming at a sycamore and hickory on the river bank at the mouth
of Searcy's Creek, then up the river with its meanders 200 poles to a white oak
on Cornelius Ruddle's north boundary line, then east 92 poles with said line to
an elm being said Ruddles' corner then north 265 lA poles to a stake, then west
274 poles to an elm, then south 180 poles to the beginning. Surveyed April 1,
1786 by John Bucchanan, D.S., by virture of service right of said Armstrong.
Entered November 19, 1785. Grant dated October 8, 1787.
15
Deeds on Stones River
from Davidson County Deeds Vol. B
Benjamin Jostling October 23. 1789 page 8
Indenture made November 1. 1789. For the sum of 2000 pounds have sold Ben-jamin
Jostling 640 acres on Stones River on a small creek known as Bushneirs
Creek and on Maj. Blount's last boundary line and at Bushneirs southwest cor-ner
of a 1000 acre Survey No. 1660. Beginning at a mulberry, walnut and oak
then south 279 poles crossing Bushnell*s Creek to a walnut and three big red
oaks, then east 367 Vi poles to a stake, then north 279 poles to a walnut, then west
367 1/2 poles to the beginning. This grant to Bushnell and Dobbins by patent dated
September 15, 1787. Wit. Win. A. Pease. Louis Reily
Robert Creswell October 23. 1789 page 9
Indenture made October 3, 1789. For the sum of 65 pounds. Maryland currency,
Eusebius Bushnell and William Dobbins have sold to Robert Creswell 640 acres
on Stuart's Creek, a branch of Stones River. Beginning at Moses Shelby's south-east
comer on the east side of said creek at three hickories, then north 400 poles
with Shelby's line to a mulberry, then east 256 poles to a stake, then south 400
poles to a red oak. west 256 poles to the beginning. Known by the No. 265 grant
to Bushnell &amp; Dobbins, assignees of Jacob Gwin.
Philemon Thomas October 27. 1789 page 10
Indenture made August 1. 1789. For the sum of 300 pounds. Carolina currency,
Eusebius Bushnell and William Dobbins have sold Philemon Thomas ofWoodford
County. Kentucky, 1622 acres. Lying on the main east fork of Stones River.
Beginning at the northwest comer of Col. Isaac Shelby's 5000 acre survey (granted
him for his senices as commissioner appointed to settle the claims of preemp-tion
and lay off the boundary of lands granted officer and soldiers of the Conti-nental
Line) on a red oak and hickory running east with said Shelby's north
boundary line 648'/2 poles crossing Stones River to a walnut on said Shelby's
line, then north 400 poles to a stake, then west 648 !/2 poles to a stake, then south
400 poles crossing Stones River to the beginning. Which land Bushnell and Dob-bins
obtained by patent dated September 15. 1787. as assignees of Capt. Mather
Wood. Wit. Robert Weakley. Griswald Latimer, and Richard Thomas
Philemon Thomas October 27. 1789 page 10a
Indenmre made August 1. 1879. For the sum of 300 pounds. Virginia money.
Eusebius Bushnell and William Dobbins have sold Philemon Thomas ofWoodford
County. Ky., 1000 acres on the east fork of Stones River. Beginning at Col. Isaac
Shelby's northwest comer, a large red oak and hickory running south 320 poles
to a walnut in Shelby's line, then west 500 poles to a stake, then north 320 noles
to a stake, then east 500 poles to the beginning. Bushnell &amp; Dobbins obtained the
land by patent dated September 15. 1787, assignees Henry Cole, a drummer.
Wit. Robert Weakley, Griswold Latimer, and Richard Thomas.
Charles Longmier Janury 18, 1790 page 32
Indenture made November 23. 1789. For the sum of 100 pounds Robert Weakley
16
has sold to Charles Longmier 640 acres on the east fork of Stones River. Begin-ning
at a sugar tree said Longmier* s northwest corner of a 640 acre survey War-rant
No. 3397 on Isadore Skerretts' line, runs north 106 chains, 70 links to an
ash, east 60 chains to a black walnut, then south 106 chains, 70 links to said
Longmier northeast corner, then west 60 chains with his line to the beginning.
Land granted said Robert Weakley by North Carolina by virture of a Military
Warrant No. 2252.
Wit. Valentine Sevier, Ezekiel Smith, Samuel Weakley.
Charles Longmier January 19, 1790 page 33
Indenture made November 23, 1790. For the sum of 100 pounds Robert Weakley
has sold Charles Longmier of Washington County, North Carolina, 640 acres on
both sides of the east fork of Stones River. Beginning at an ash on the south side
of said fork 20 chains south of Isadore Skerrett's southeast corner of a 640 acre
survey, nms north to said Skerrett's corner and with his line crossing said fork in
all 106 chains and seventy links to a sugartree, then east 60 chains to a stake, then
south 106 chains &amp; 70 links crossing said fork to a black walnut, then west 60
chains to the beginning. Land granted to said Weakley by virture of a Military
Warrant No. 3397.
Wit. Valentine Sevier, Ezekiel Smith and Samuel Weakley.
Thomas Williamson January 19, 1790 page 33
Indenture made November 16, 1789. Weakley for the sum of 60 pounds has sold
Thomas Williamson 640 acres on the east fork of Stones River. Lying on both
sides of the east fork beginning at a hackberry on the north side of the river on
Griffith Rutherford's line of Ins 640 acre survey and 5 chains south of his north-east
corner. Runs east 80 chains to a black oak and hackberry on the east side of
a ridge, then south 80 chains to a sugartree, then west 80 chains to a stake, then
north 5 chains to said Rutherford's corner and with his line in all 80 chains to the
beginning. Land granted to Robert Weakley by virture of a Military Warrant No.
2487. Wit. Anthony Crutcher &amp; Thomas Molloy.
Robert Weakley February 3, 1790 page 39
North Carolina Grant No. 1015. Robert Weakley, assignee ofBenejah Yarkins, a
private, is granted 640 acres on the east fork of Stones River about six or seven
miles above the first line mn by the Commissioner's in the year 1783. Beginning
at an ash on the south side of said fork 20 chains south of Isadore Skerrett's
southeast corner runs north to Skerrett's corner with his line in all 106 &amp; 70 links
to a sugartree, then east 60 chains to a stake, then south 106 chains &amp; 70 links to
a black walnut, then west 60 chains to the beginning. Surveyed May 27, 1788, in
consequence of a Military Warrant No. 3397, located March 22, 1788. Grant
dated May 18, 1789.
Robert Weakley February 3, 1790 page 39
North Carolina Grant No. 1010. Robert Weakley, assignee of Jacob Deaderick, a
private, is granted 640 acres on the east fork of Stones River about one mile
above the first line run by the Commissioners in the year 1783. Beginning at an
elm at the south side of said fork Martin Armstrong's southeast comer runs east
17
106 chains &amp; 70 links to a white ash in a dry branch, then south 60 chains to a red
oak on the north side of said fork on a bluff of the same, then west 106 chains &amp;
70 links to a stake, then north 60 chains to the beginning. Sun eyed by said
Weakley on May 17. 1788. in consequence of a Military Warrant No. 2264.
located March 22. 1788. Grant dated May 18, 1789.
Robert Weakley February 3. 1790 page 39
North Carolina Grant No. 1012. Robert Weakley, assignee of the heirs ofAbraham
Green, a private, is granted 640 acres on the east fork of Stones River. Beginning
at a hackberry on the north side of said fork on Griffith Rutherford's line of a
survey of 640 acres. 5 chains south of his northeast comer, runs east 80 chains to
a black oak and hackberry on the east side of a ridge, then south 80 chains to a
sugartree. then west 80 chains to a stake, then north 5 chains to Rutherford's
corner and with his line in all 80 chains. Sun eyed May 17. 1788 by said Weakley
in consequence of a Military Warrant No. 2487, located March 22. 1788. Grant
dated May 18. 1789.
John Bucchanan April 30. 1790 page 52
North Carolina Grant No. 1020. John Bucchanan. assignee of Henry Richards*
heirs, is granted 640 acres on Stones River. Beginning at an ash and elm on the
east boundary of a survey of John Rice's, then south 390 to a black oak said
Rices' comer then east 26214 poles to a sycamore on the west bank opposite to a
high rocky cliff, then north 390 poles to a stake, then west to the beginning.
Surveyed by said Buccchanan May 2. 1786. in consequence of a Military War-rant
No. 1981. located December 31. 1785. Grant dated May 18. 1789.
Lardner Clark May 3. 1790 page 54
North Carolina Grant No. 64. Lardner Clark, assignee of Col. Martin Armstrong,
is granted 150 acres. Beginning at a white oak on the bank of Stones River, being
the beginning comer of Cornelius Ruddle's preemption, then west with Ruddles'
line 134 poles to an elm and white oak. then south 70 poles to an elm on said line,
then west 124 poles to a dogwood, then north 120 poles to the west bank of the
river, then up said river with its meanders to the beginning. Surveyed by John
Bucchanan, D.S., on May 2. 1786. in consequence of a senice right of said
Annstrong. No. 1595, located November 26. 1785. Grant dated May 18. 1789.
John McCutchen May 13. 1790 page 58
North Carolina Grant No. 960. John McCutchen, assignee of Edmorit Haddock,
a private, is granted 228 acres on the north side of the east fork of Stones River
on a branch of the same. Beginning at a hackberry and black oak Robert Weakley's
northeast comer on the east side of a ridge, nins west 45 chains &amp; 60 links with
said Weakley "s line to a sugartree, then north 50 chains to a hickory, then east 45
chains &amp; 60 links to a stake on Gen. Matthew Lock's line, then south with his
line 50 chains to the beginning. Surveyed by Robert Weakley on June 13. 1788.
in consequence of a Military Warrant No. 1235. located March 22. 1788. Grant
dated May 18, 1789.
Stephen Cantrill May 14, 1790 page 61
North Carolina Grant No. 1020. Stephen Cantrill, assignee of Moses
Weaver, a private, is granted 274 acres on the head branches of the
second creek above Bradley's Lick on the east branches of the east fork
of Stones River. Beginning at Stockley Doneldson's corner a buckeye
and ash, then east 148 poles to an ash. then north 296 poles to a stake,
then west 148 poles to an ash and hickory, then south 296 poles to the
beginning. Surveyed November 1, 1787, by John Doneldson. D.S., in
consequence of a Military Warrant No. 1678, located September 21,
1787. Grant dated May 18, 1789.
William Bleakamore May 19, 1790 page 73
Indenture made April 15. 1790. Thomas Hickman for the sum of 100
pounds has sold William Blackamore 640 acres on the first creek that
runs into the east side of the east fork of Stones River above the mouth
of Bradley's Creek. Beginning at a red oak and ash norhwest comer to
Joseph Hendrick, south with his line across the creek at 30 poles, a branch
at 180 poles in all, 320 poles to a hickory and ash, then west 320 poles to
white oak and ash. then north crossing said creek at 88 poles in all 320
poles to a stake, then east to the beginning. Land granted said Hickman
on July 11, 1788. Wit. Ed Hickman and Robert Weakley.
Ebenzer Brooks May 20. 1790 page 75
North Carolina Grant No. 216. For the sum of 10 pounds for every 100
acres Ebenezer Brooks is granted 640 acres on Hurricane Creek, a branch
of Stones River. Beginning at a black walnut and mulberry on the north
side of said creek below an old Buffalo Road then south 226 poles to
two hickories, then west 452 poles to a cedar, then north 226 poles to an
ironwood, then east 452 poles. Surveyed by John Bucchanan, D.S., on
August 17. 1785. in consequence of a Warrant No. 435, located May
12, 1784. Grant dated July 13, 1788.
Wra. Terrell May 20, 1790 page 77
North Carolina Grant No. 190. For the sum often pounds for every 100
acres Wm. Terrell is granted 640 acres on Overall Creek, a branch of
Stones River. Beginning at a red oak and elm on the east boundary of
Col. James Armstrong's 7200 acre survey, then south along his line 260
poles to an elm. mulberry and walnut, then east 394 poles to a stake,
then north 260 to a stake, then west 394 poles to the beginning. Sur-veyed
by B. Wm. Pollock, D.S.. on March 9, 1785, in consequence of a
Warrant No. 199, located Janury 28, 1784. Grant dated July 13, 1788.
Thomas Kennedy May 21, 1790 page 78
North Carolina Grant No. 23 1. For the sum often pounds for every 100
acres Thomas Kennedy is granted 640 acres on the west side of Stones
River. Beginning at a post oak and dogwood running then north 304
poles to a post oak, then east 182 poles to the junction of Overall Creek
with Stones River, then up the river with the meanders 490 poles to a
19
honey locust and a white oak, south 102 poles to two hickories, west 417 poles to
the beginning. Surveyed by James Mulherin. D.S., on January 15, 1784, in con-sequence
of a Warrant No. 363, located March 18. 1784. Grant dated July 13,
1788.
Thomas Gillispie June 4. 1790 page 82
North Carolina Grant No. 241. For the sum often pounds for every 100 acres
Thomas Gillispie is granted 640 acres on Stones River. Beginning at a poplar on
Samuel McMurry's east boundary, being Win. Moore*s southwest corner, then
south 226 poles to a persimmon, then east 452 poles to a white oak, then north
226 poles a red oak being said Moore's southeast comer, then west with his line
to the beginning. Surveyed on April 11, 1785. by John Bucchanan agreeable to a
Warrant No. 628. Entered November 20. 1784. Grant dated July 10, 1788.
Col. Joseph Martin June 4, 1790 page 83
North Carolina Grant No. 261. For the sum often pounds for every 100 acres
Joseph Martin is granted 640 acres on Stones River. Beginning at a white oak,
hickory, and dogwood about 100 yards from Overall Creek on Col. Armstrong's
east boundary, then along his line 226 poles to three cherry trees and an elm. then
east 452 poles to a stake, then north 226 poles to a stake. Then west 452 poles to
the beginning. Surveyed by B. Wm. Pollock on March 10. 1785. agreeable to a
Warrant No. 600. Entered October 9, 1784. Grant dated July 10. 1788.
James Todd June 5, 1790 page 84
North Carolina Grant No. 249. For the sum of ten pounds for every 100 acres
James Todd is granted 640 acres. Beginning at a dogwood and white oak run-ning
then north 120 poles to a black oak and elm on the bank of Stones River
then down said river with its meanders 490 poles to a hornbeam, then west 212
poles to a red oak and walnut, south 432 poles to a hickory east 360 poles to the
beginning. Sun eyed July 10, 1784, by James Mulherin. D.S.. agreeable to a
Warrant No. 72. Entered January 10. 1784. Grant dated July 10, 1788.
Cornelius Ruddell June 7, 1790 page 87
North Carolina Grant No. 228. For the sum often pounds for every 100 acres
Cornelius Ruddell is granted 640 acres on Stones River. Beginning at a white
oak on the east bank of said river about 1/2 mile above the mouth of Searcy's
Creek, then east 192 poles to an elm. then south 452 poles to a white oak. Then
west 226 poles to a white oak and dogwood, then north 452 poles to an elm and
white oak, then east to the beginning. Surveyed November 30, 1785, by John
Bucchanan. D.S.. agreeable to a Warrant No. 738. Entered May 30. 1785. Grant
dated July 10, 1788.
Lewis Robbards June 8. 1790 page 88
North Carolina Grant No. 206. For the sum often pounds for every 100 acres
Lewis Robbards is granted 640 acres on the south side of the Cumberland River.
Beginning at an ash. then south 234 poles to an elm in Hay's line, then along his
line west 443 poles passing his corner 160 poles to an elm. Then north 234 poles
to a sugartree and red oak on the river, then do the same as it meanders to an ash
20
at the mouth of the spring branch and then east 200 poles to the beginning. Sur-veyed
March 13, 1786 by John Donelson, D.S., agreeable to a Warrant No. 399.
Entered April 6, 1784. Grant dated July 10, 1788.
William Moore June 8, 1790 page 89
North Carolina Grant No. 200. For the sum of ten pounds for every 100 acres
Wm. Moore is granted 640 acres on Stones River. Beginning at a poplar on
Samuel McMurray's east boundary line, being Thomas Gillespie's north west
corner, then east with Gillispie's line 452 poles to a red oak, then north 226 poles
to a white oak, then west 452 to a hackberry. being said McMurry's northeast
corner, then south with said line to the beginning. Surveyed December 6, 1784,
by John Bucchanan, D.S., agreeable to a Warrant No. 45. Entered January 1,
1784. Grant dated July 10, 1788.
James Montflorence June 30, 1790 page 91
Indenture made June 16, 1790. William Nash has sold for the sum of2000 poimds
three military tracts of land to James Montflorence.
(1) 640 acres on the north side of the Cumberland River.
(2) on the waters of the first creek above Stoners Lick Creek and on the east side
of the river. Beginning on the east side of the creek at a mulberry George Suggs*
southeast corner No. 2236, and running then east 320 poles to a dogwood, then
south 320 poles to a mulberry, then west 320 poles to a black oak, then north 320
poles to the beginning. Contains 640 acres.
(3) On the water of the first creek above Stoner Lick Creek on the east side of
Stones River. Beginning at the north west cornier of Aquilla Suggs"s and on the
west boundary of said Suggs Warrant No. 1503 at a dogwood, then running west
320 poles to a hickory and poplar, then south 320 poles to a dogwood, then east
320 poles to a stake, then north 320 poles to the beginning. Contains 640 acres.
Wit. B. Searcy, A. Foster, and Wm. Cmtcher.
William Nash July 1, 1790 page 94
North Carolina Grant No. 938. William Nash, assignee of Isaack Simmons, is
granted 640 acres on the first creek above Stoners Lick Creek on the east side of
Stones River. Beginning on the northwest corner of Aquilla Suggs and on the
west boundary of said Suggs" s Warrant No. 1503 on a dogwood, then running
west 320 poles to a hickory and poplar, then south 320 poles to a dogwood, then
east 320 poles to a stake, then north 320 poles to the beginning. Surveyed by said
Nash on Nov. , 1788, in consequence of a Military Warrant No. 2235, located
October 18, 1788. Grant dated May 18, 1789.
William Nash July 1. 1790 page 94
North Carolina Grant No. 936. William Nash, assignee of Richard Cobart, is
granted 640 acres of land on the first creek above Stoner' s Lick Creek on the east
side of Stones River. Beginning on the east side of the creek on a mulberry George
Suggs' s southeast corner No. 2236, running then east 320 poles to a dogwood,
then south 320 poles to a mulberry, then west 320 poles to a black oak, then north
320 poles to the beginning. Surveyed by said Nash on May 19, 1788, in conse-
21
quence of a Military Warrant No. 1499, located November 12, 1788. Grant dated
May 18. 1789.
Wm. Overall &amp; Martin King July 2, 1790 page 100
North Carolina Grant No. 212. For the sum often pounds for every 100 acres
Wm. Overall &amp; Martin King are granted 640 acres on Overall's lower creek near
the mouth. Beginning at a honey locust tree, miming thence south 452 poles to
an elm and black oak. west 226 poles to a buckeye and two ash trees, north 452
poles to a stake, then east 226 poles to the beginning. Sun eyed on January 1,
1784. by James Mulherin. D. S.. in consequence of a Warrant No. 301. Entered
February 16. 1784. Grant dated July 10. 1788.
John Blackamore August 3. 1790 page 114
Indenture made May 8, 1790. For the sum of 126 pounds Thomas Hickman has
sold John Blackamore 640 acres on the east fork of the first creek that empties
into the east fork of Stones River above the mouth of Bradley's Lick Creek on
the east side. Beginning at a buckeye and ash southeast comer ofJoseph Hendricks,
then crossing a large branch at 18 poles in all 320 poles to an elm. then north 320
poles to a stake, then west 320 poles to Joseph Hendrick's Line, then south cross
the creek with said line to the beginning.
Wit. Thomas Johnston. William Cnitcher.
William Blackamore August 6, 1790 page 120
Indenture made April 15. 1790. For the sum of 100 pounds Moses Shelby of
Tennessee county, has sold William Blackamore 600 acres on Stuart's Creek on
Stones River being a part of a tract of 1200 acres granted the said Shelby. Begin-ning
at a hickory and sugartree. run then east 400 poles to a red oak and walnut,
the northeast comer of said survey, then south 350 poles to a stake Edwin
Hickman's northeast corner then with Hickman north boundary line 290 poles to
Stuart's Creek then down the creek with its meanders to John Tucker's northeast
corner on said creek, then west with Tucker's north boundary 218 poles to a
stake, then north 190 poles to the beginning.
Wit. Edwin Hickman &amp; Matthew Talbot.
William Nash August 10. 1790 page 129
North Carolina Grant No. 937. William Nash, assignee ofDaniel Elmore's heirs,
is granted 640 acres on the east fork of the first creek above Stoner's Lick Creek
on the east side of Stones River. Beginning at a cherry tree and dogwood John
Logue's corner, southwest comer of a survey of 1000 acres, then east with Logue's
line 320 poles to a white oak and dogwood, then south 320 poles to a mulberry
and dogwood, then west 320 poles to a mulberry, then north 320 poles to the
beginning. Surveyed by said Nash May 12. 1788. in consequence of a Military
Warrant No. 1512, located April 3, 1788. Grant dated May 18. 1789.
William Nash August 10. 1790 page 129
North Carolina Grant No. 939. William Nash, assignee of Foster Reaves, a pri-vate,
is granted 640 acres on the west fork of the first Creek above Stoner's Lick
22
Creek on the east side of Stones River. Beginning at a hickory and poplar marked
as a comer tree, running north 320 poles to a white oak and hickory, then west
320 poles to a dogwood, then south 320 poles to a stake, then east 320 poles to
the beginning. Surveyed by said Nash May 14. 1788, in consequence of Warrant
No. 2762, located April _, 1788. Grant dated May 18, 1789.
William Nash August 10, 1790 page 129
North Carolina Grant No. 732.William Nash, assignee of Ezekiel Rigley, a pri-vate,
is granted 640 acres on the east side of Stones River. Beginning 20 poles
above the mouth of the second creek above Stuart's Creek at a white oak and
black oak on the east side of the river, running down with its meanders to a cedar
bluff, then miming north, comer on a elm. hickory and ash, then east 464 poles to
a hickory then south 240 poles to a stake, then west 374 poles to the beginning.
Surveyed by said Nash February 10, 1787, in consequence of a Military Warrant
No. 2577. located January 1, 1787. Grant dated July 11, 1788.
John Logue August 11, 1790 page 130
North Carolina Grant No . John Logue. assignee of James Gurley, Corpo-ral,
is granted 1000 acres on the first creek above Stoner's Lick Creek on Stones
River. Beginning at a cherry tree and dogwood, then east 400 poles to a cedar
and dogwood, then east 400 poles to a black oak, then west 400 poles to two
dogwoods, then south 400 poles to the beginning. Surveyed by Wm. Nash, D.S.,
in consequence of a Military Warrant No. 1737. located January 28, 1786. Grant
dated May 18, 1789.
Joseph Mitchel November 9, 1790 page 137
North Carolina Grant No. 197. Joseph Mitchel, a private, is granted 274 acres on
Stones River joining Henry Winburn's (5)89 acre survey. Beginning at a sy-camore
tree 80 poles below the head of a large spring, then east with the north
boundary of Winburn's survey 240 poles to a mulberry, then 174V&#163; poles to a
stake, then west 240 poles to a stake, then south 174V4 poles to the beginning.
Surveyed by Barclay William Pollock on March 13, 1785, in consequence of a
Military Warrant No. 146, located February 7, 1784. Grant dated March 7, 1786.
Thomas Hardiman November 10. 1790 page 139
Indenture made October 11, 1790. For the sum of 1000 pounds William
Blackamore has sold Thomas Hardiman 600 acres on Stuart's Creek &amp; Stones
River, being a part of a tract of 1200 acres. Beginning at a hickory and sugartree,
mns east 400 poles to red oak and walnut the northeast comer of said survey,
then south 350 poles to a stake, Edwin Hickman's northeast corner, then west
with Hickman's north boundary 290 poles to Smart's Creek, then down the creek
with its meanders to John Tucker's northeast comer on said creek, then west 218
poles with John Tucker's north boundary to a stake, then north 190 poles to the
beginning. Land a part of Moses Shelby's grant.
Thomas Hardiman November 10, 1790 page 139
Indenture made October 1 1, 1790. For the sum of 1000 poimds Edwin Hickman
has sold Thomas Hardiman 300 acres on Stuart's Creek. Beginning at three mul-
23
berries running east 400 poles crossing Stuart's Creek to two hickories, then
north 130 poles to a stake, then west 276 poles to a stake on the banks of Stuart's
Creek, then with the meanders of the creek to a stake, then 66 poles to a mul-berry,
dogwood and elm, then south 100 poles to the beginning.
George Ridley November 15. 1790 page 145
Indenture made October 11, 1790. For the sum of 300 pounds John Caffrey has
sold George Ridley 640 acres on both sides of Stoner's Creek, a branch of Stones
River, and about three miles above Stoners Lick. Beginning at a sugartree. white
oak and ash on the north side of said creek, then north 226 poles to a white oak,
then east 542 poles crossing two branches to a white oak, black walnut and ce-dar,
then south 226 to a white oak, ash, and dogwood, crossing said creek, then
west 452 poles to the beginning. Land granted to Caffrey by patent dated April
17, 1786, and No. 142.
George Augustus Sugg November 23, 1790 page 149
North Carolina Grant No. 902. George Augustus Sugg, assignee of Henry
Humpries. is granted 640 acres on the main east fork of Stones River. Beginning
at a large poplar, Reed's corner and running south with Read's line 320 poles to
a white oak and ironwood on the bank of the river, then with the meanders of the
river about west 320 poles to a poplar, then north 320 poles to a stake, then east
320 poles to the beginning. Surveyed by Win. Nash on March 21, 1788. in con-sequence
of a Military Warrant No. 2457, located March 1. 1786. Grant dated
January 17, 1789.
George Augustus Sugg November 23, 1790 page 149
North Carolina Grant No. 921. George Augustus Sugg, assignee of John Peters,
a private, is granted 640 acres on the main east fork of Stones River. Beginning
at a poplar John Read's northwest comer, then north 320 poles to an elm. then
east 320 poles to an ash and dogwood, then south 320 poles to a stake, then west
320 poles to the beginning. Surveyed May 11, 1788. by Win. Nash in conse-quence
of a Military Warrant No. 2213. located April 5. 1788. Grant dated May
18, 1789.
Samuel Wilson January 21, 1791 page 150
Indenture made October 1 3. 1789. For the sum of 160 pounds John Rice &amp; Elisha
Rice have sold 640 acres to Samuel Wilson of Hartford County, Maryland. The
land lying on both sides of Stones River. Beginning on the west bank of said
river at a sycamore at Major John Bucchanan's southeast comer, then west with
his line 262 14 poles to a black oak being said Bucchanan*s southwest corner,
then south 390 poles, then east 262'/2 poles to a stake, then north to the begin-ning.
The land obtained by patent dated June 13. 1787. No. 306.
Wit. Edward Peatt P. H. Lee
John Williams January 21, 1791 page 151
North Carolina Pitt County. For the sum of 200 pounds. North Carolina money,
J. Ambrose Jones of Pitt Co.. N.C., has sold to John Williams of Pitt Co. N.C.,
24
640 acres on the east side of Stones River. The land was taken up by said Jones
as assignee of Daniel Ray by a Warrant No. 2741 and grant dated July 10, 1788.
Beginning 20 poles above the second creek above the mouth of Stuart's Creek
that fall into said river on the east side at a white oak and black oak on the bank
of Stones River and running up with the meanders of the river to the lower end of
a large island to two white ash trees, then east 352 poles to a cedar, then north
3 15 poles to a stake then west 206 poles to the beginning.
Wit. William Corbitt, Roderick Williams &amp; Robert Williams.
John Thompson January 21, 1791 page 151
Indenture made October 21, 1790. For the sum of 50 pounds William Nash has
sold John Thompson 640 acres on the east fork of the first creek above Stoners
Lick Creek on the east side of Stones River. Beginning on a cherry tree and
dogwood John Logue's southwest corner of a 1000 acre survey, running then
east with Logue's line 320 poles to a white oak and dogwood, then south 320
poles to a mulberry and dogwood, west 320 poles to a mulberry and dogwood,
north 320 poles to the beginning. Signed Paty Nash, Wm. Nash
Wit. David Hay, Andrew Ewing, Andrew Casselman.
John Thompson January 21, 1791 page 152
Indenture made October 21, 1790. For the sum of 50 pounds William Nash has
sold John Thompson 640 acres on the west fork of the first creek above Stoners
Lick Creek on the east side of Stones River. Beginning at a hickory and poplar
marked AV corner trees, running north 320 poles to a white oak and hickory,
then west 320 poles to a dogwood, then south 320 poles to a stake, then east 320
poles to the beginning. Signed Wm. Nash &amp; Paty Nash
Wit. David Hay, Andrew Ewing and Andrew Casselman.
Reading Blount February 7, 1791 page 170
North Carolina Grant No. 916. Reading Blount, assignee of Abraham Wolf, a
private, is granted 640 acres on the head branches of the east fork of Stones
River. Beginning at two lynns Major Reading Blount's southwest corner of a
tract No. 2534, runs with his line east 60 chains to a sugartree said Blount's
corner, then south 106 chains &amp; 70 links to a stake, west 60 chains to a sugartree
Elijah Robertson's comer then with his line north 106 chains &amp; 70 links to the
beginning. Surveyed by Robert Weakley on May 26, 1788, in consequence of a
Military Warrant No. 2041, located March 22, 1788. Grant dated May 18, 1789.
Reading Blount February 7. 1791 page 170
North Carolina Grant No. 953. Reading Blount, assignee of Jessee Bagworth, a
private, is granted 640 acres on the first creek the first line nm by the Commis-sioners
in 1783 crosses running west from the east fork of Stones River. Begin-ning
at two white oaks about 20 poles east of the head of a large spring and about
3/4 ofa mile south of said line, runs west 106 chains &amp; 70 links to a hickory, then
north 60 chains to an ash, then east 106 chains &amp; 70 links to a cedar then south 60
chains to the beginning. Surveyed May 26, 1788, by Robert Weakley in conse-quence
of a Military Warrant No. 2559, located March 22, 1788. Grant dated
May 18, 1789.
25
Reading Blount February 7. 1791 page 170
North Carolina Grant No. 956. Reading Blount, assignee ofprivate Edward Thust.
is granted 640 acres on the east fork of Stones River near the head branches of
the said river. Beginning at a wash. Elijah Robertson's northwest comer of a
tract No. 3202. runs north 106 chains &amp; 70 links to a stake, then east 60 chains to
a sugartree. Reading Blount's comer, then with his line south 106 chains &amp; 70
links to two lynns said Blount and Robertson, then with Robertson's line east 60
chains to the beginning. Surveyed by Robert Weakley D.S. on May 26. 1788. in
consequence of a Military Warrant No. 2552, located March 22. 1788. Grant
dated May 18, 1789.
Reading Blount February 10. 1791 page 175
North Carolina Grant No. 914. Reading Blount, assignee of Nathan Murdock. a
private, is granted 640 acres on the north branches of the east fork of Stones
River. Beginning at two lynns Elijah Robertson's northeast comer of a tract No.
3462, nui north 106 chains &amp; 70 links to a sugartree, then east 60 chains to a
stake, then south 106 chains &amp; 70 links to a sugartree. then west 60 chains to the
beginning. Sun eyed May 16, 1788. by Robert Weakley, D.S., in consequence of
a Military Warrant No. 2534, located March 22, 1788. Grant dated May 18,
1789.
For having located a parcel of land Reading Blount signs over to Elijah
Robinson the title to this tract. September 25, 1791.
Wit. Cox Coartland. John Grey Blount.
Robert Thompson February 14, 1791 page 179
North Carolina Grant No. 1088. Robert Thompson, assignee of Stephen Joiners,
a private, is granted 640 acres on Hurricane Creek. Beginning at two ash sap-lings
being Minos Camion's northeast comer, then east 272 poles to a hickory,
then south 376 poles to an elm. then west 272 poles to said Minos Camion's
southeast corner, then north with Ins line to the beginning. Surveyed by John
Bucchanan, D.S.. in consequence of a Military Warrant No. 1917. located De-cember
27. 1788. Grant dated Nov. 14. 1789.
Archibald Marlin February 16. 1791 page 181
North Carolina Grant No. 462. Archibald Marlin. a private, is granted 297 acres
on both sides of Stoner Creek a branch of Stones River. Beginning at John
Caffrey's comer, white oak. ash. and sugartree. then west 297 poles to an ash.
then north 160 poles crossing the creek to a cedar tree, then east 297 poles to a
red oak in said Caffrey's line, then along his line south 160 poles to the begin-ning.
Surveyed by John Donoldson. D.S.. by virtue of a Military Warrant No.
848. located April 18. 1785. Grant dated September 15. 1787.
Isaac Right May 24. 1791 page 194
North Carolina Grant No. 1009. Isaac Right, assignee of David Passnore. a pri-vate,
is granted 365 acres on Stones River. Beginning at a cedar and black walnut
Benjamin Flood's beginning comer, then south with said line 320 poles to a red
oak. then east 1821/2 poles to an elm. then north 320 poles to a dogwood then
west to the beginning. Surveyed March 2. 1786, by John Bucchanan. D.S.. in
26
consequence of a Military Warrant No. 417, located January 18, 1786. Grant
dated May 18, 1789.
Robert Weakley May 24, 1791 page 194
North Carolina Grant No. 1 1 82. Robert Weakley, assignee ofThomas Winstill, a
private, by his heirs, 640 acres on the east fork of Stones River adjoining a sur-vey
of said Weakley on the north side, warrant of which is No. 3397. Beginning
at a sugartree said Weakley's northwest corner on Isadore Skerrett's line, runs
north with his line 106 chains &amp; 70 links to an ash, then east 60 chains to a black
walnut, then south 106 chains &amp; 70 links to said Weakley's northeast corner,
then with his line 60 chains to the beginning. Surveyed by said Weakley on July
28, 1790, in consequence of a Military Warrant No. 2252, located October 1,
1789. Grant dated November 30, 1790.
Jason Thompson May 24, 1791 page 195
North Carolina Grant No. 1201. Jason Thompson, assignee of Isaac Brown, a
private, is granted 640 acres on Mill Creek and Stones River. Beginning at an ash
being Minos Cannon's, Robert Thompson's and Jason Thompson's corner, then
east with Robert Thompson's line 272 poles to a hickory, then south 376'/2 poles
to a dogwood, then west 272 poles to an elm being the northeast corner of said
Jason Thompson's survey, then south with said line to the beginning. Surveyed
by John Bucchanan on January 28, 1791, in consequence of a Military Warrant
No. 3678, located January 11, 1791. Grant dated March 15, 1791
Jason Thompson May 24, 1791 page 196
North Carolina Grant No. 1097. Jason Thompson, assignee of Peter Cotench, a
private, is granted 640 acres on the east of Mill Creek. Beginning at a black oak
being Minos Cannon's northwest corner, then east with said line 272 poles to
two ash sapling, then north 376 poles to an elm, then west 272 poles to a dog-wood,
then south to the beginning. Surveyed by John Bucchanan on January 20,
1789. in consequence of a Military Warrant No. 3454, located January 8, 1789.
Grant dated November 14, 1789.
Minos Cannon May 25, 1791 page 196
North Carolina Grant No. 1087. Minos Cannon, assignee of Vinson Allhead, a
private, is granted 640 acres on Mill Creek near the ridge between said creek and
Stones River waters at the north edge of Big Hurricane. Beginning at a black oak
being Jason Thompson's comer, then east 272 poles to two ash saplings, then
south 376 poles to an elm, then west 272 poles to an ash, then north to the begin-ning.
Suveryed December 4, 1788, by John Bucchanan in consequence of a Mili-tary
Warrant No. 2105, located January 2, 1787. Grant dated November 14, 1789.
* John Bucchanan May 16, 1971 page 198
North Carolina Grant No. 1199. John Bucchanan, assignee of Aron Garner, a
private, is granted 640 acres on Stones River. Beginning at a sugartree and ash
being John Forman's and John Ford's corner, then south with Ford's line 226
poles to a white oak. then east 452 to an ash, then north 226 poles to an elm on
Thomas Cotton's south boundary, then west to the beginning. Surveyed Decem-
27
ber 4. 1788, by said Bucchanan in consequence of a Military Warrant No. 2722,
located December 3, 1787. Grant dated November 30. 1790.
John Bucchanan May 26. 1791 page 199
North Carolina Grant No. 1 183. John Bucchanan, assignee of private John Har-ris,
is granted 640 acres on Mill Creek. Beginning at a white oak Jolm Ford's and
John Bucchanan "s corner, then west 452 with Forde's line to an elm. then south
226 poles to a sugartree. then east 452 poles to an ash, then north to the begin-ning.
Surveyed by said Bucchanan on December 4, 1788, in consequence of a
Military Warrant No. 2730, located December 3. 1787. Grant dated November
30. 1790.
Stephen Brooks June 25, 1791 page 202
North Carolina Grant No. 905. Stephen Brooks, assignee ofprivate John Mosland.
is granted 640 acres on the first creek above Stuart's Creek on the east side of
Stones River. Beginning at a mulberry and white oak running north 227 poles to
a hickory and post oak. then east 452 poles to a stake, then south 227 poles to a
stake, then west 452 poles to the beginning. Surveyed by Win. Nash on October
10, 1786, in consequence of a Military Warrant No. 3515, located October 10,
1786. Grant dated January 17. 1789.
Stephen Brooks June 25. 1791 page 202
North Carolina Grant No. 910. Stephen Brooks, assignee of William Glaughn. is
granted 640 acres on the east side of Stones River on the first creek above Stoner
Lick Creek. Beginning about a mile above the fork of said creek on the main fork
of said creek on a hickory and ash. running north 320 poles to an elm and mul-berry,
then east 320 poles to a white ash tree. Thomas Thompson's corner, then
south along Thompson's line 320 poles to a stake then west 320 poles to the
beginning. Surveyed by Wm. Nash. D.S.. in consequence of a Military Warrant
No. 2917, located October 10. 1786. Grant dated January 17, 1789.
Stephen Brooks June 25, 1791 page 202
North Carolina Grant No. 911, Stephen Brooks, assignee of Private William
Goodman, is granted 640 acres on the first creek above Stoner' s Lick Creek on
the east side of Stones River. Beginning about 1
lA mile above the mouth of said
creek on an ash and hickory running north 227 poles to a cedar, then east 452
poles to a stake, then south 227 poles to a stake, then west 452 poles to the
beginning. Surveyed by Wm. Nash, D.S., in consequence of a military warrant
No. 2920. Located October 10. 1786. Grant dated June 17, 1789.
James Thompson August 2. 1791 page 220
Indenture made July 4. 1781. For the sum of 200 pounds Robert Thompson has
sold to James Thompson 640 acres of land on Hurricane Creek. Beginning at two
ash saplings being Minos Cannon's northeast comer, then east 272 poles to a
hickory, then south 376 poles to an elm, then west 272 poles to said Cannon's
southeast comer, then north with said line to the beginning. The land was granted
to Robert Thompson by patent No. 1088 dated November 14, 1789.
Wit. Andrew Ewing.
28
Aquilla Sugg November 5, 1791 page 233
North Carolina Grant No. 926. Aquilla Sugg, assignee of private Meradeth Berk's
heirs, 640 acres on the east fork of the first creek above Stoner's Lick Creek.
Beginning at the southeast corner of Thomas Thompson's survey on an ash and
dogwood, running then south 320 poles to a mulberry, then west 320 poles to a
hickory, then north 320 poles to a stake, then east 320 poles to the beginning.
Land surveryed May 11, 1788, in consequence of a Military No. 1514, located
April 13, 1788. Grant dated May 18, 1789. Surveyed by William Nash, D.S.
Joseph Ross November 5, 1791 page 234
North Carolina Grant No. 1067. Joseph Ross, assignee of private James Zailett,
is granted 640 acres on the east fork of Stones River above the first line run by
the Commissioners in 1783. Beginning at a beech marked RN Isadore Skerrett's
northeast corner of a Warrant No. 3398, run west 70 chains with his line to a
hackberry and elm Matthew Lock's comer in John Welch's line, then with Lock's
line north 91 chains &amp; 50 links to a sugartree, then east 70 chains to a stake, then
south 9 1 chains &amp; 50 links to the beginning. Surveyed by Robert Weakley Octo-ber
15, 1789, in consequence of a Military Warrant No. 3400, located June 4,
1789. Grant dated November 14, 1789.
John Fowler November 7, 1791 page 237
North Carolina Grant No. 281. John Fowler, heir of James Fowler, deceased, for
the sum often pounds for each 100 acres is granted 640 acres on Second Creek,
an eastern branch of Stones River. Beginning at an ash, southwest corner of the
heirs of Elijah Oliver's land, running then south 320 poles to a black walnut, east
320 poles to an ash and elm on an east hillside by a creek, north 320 poles to a
small buckeye and gum by a branch corner to Oliver's land, then with his line
west 320 poles to the beginning. Surveyed by Daniel Smith on September 1,
1786, by virtue of a Warrant No. 786, located May 1, 1786. Grant dated Novem-ber
26, 1789.
James Stuart November 8, 1791 page 240
Indenture made November 7, 1791 . For the sum of 150 pounds, Virginia money,
Charles Longmier has sold to James Stuart 640 acres on both sides of the east
fork of Stones River. Beginning at an ash on the south side of said fork 20 chains
south of Isadore Skerrett's southwest corner of a survey of 640 acres, nms north
to Skerrett's corner with his line crossing said fork in all 106 chains &amp; 70 links to
a sugartree, then east 60 chains to a stake, then south 106 chains &amp; 70 links
crossing said fork to a black walnut, then west 60 chains to the beginning.
Wit. Daniel James &amp; Wm. MLin.
James Stuart November 8, 1791 page 240
Indenture made November 7, 1791. For the sum of 150 pounds, Virginia cur-rency,
Charles Longmier of Washington County has sold James Smart 640 acres
on the east fork of Stones River. Beginning at a sugartree said Smart's northwest
corner of a 640 acre survey Warrant No. 3397 on Isadore Skerrett's line. Runs
north 106 chains &amp; 70 links to an ash, then east 60 chains to a black walnut, then
29
south 106 chains &amp; 70 links to said James Stuart's northeast comer, then west 60
chains with his line to the beginning. Land granted to Robert Weakley by War-rant
No. 2252 and sold by Weakley to Longmier by deed on Novennber 23,
1789.
John McNairy, Esq. November 9. 1791 page 241
Indenture made August 19. 1791. For the simi of 500 poimds Lardner Clark,
Esq. has sold the Honorable John McNairy 640 acres on Hurricane Creek, a
branch of Stones River. Beginning at a honey locust and elm on Capt. James
Bradley's north boundary, then east with said line 320 poles to a poplar being
said Bradly's corner, then north 320 poles to Henry Harrow's south boundary,
then west with said line 320 poles to a stake, south 320 poles to the beginning.
Wit. Bennett Searcy.
30
Deeds on Stones River from
Davidson County Deeds Vol. C
William Nash January __, 1792 page 4
Indenture made June 29, 1791. For the sum of 2000 pounds James Colo.
Montflorence has sold Wm. Nash the following tract of land:
1 - 640 acres on the north side of the Cumberland.
2 - 640 acres on the waters of first creek above Stoners Lick Creek and on the
east side of Stones River. Beginning at the east side of the creek at a mul-berry
George Sugg's southeast corner No. 2236, and running then east 320
poles to a dogwood then south 320 poles to a mulberry, then west 320
poles to a black oak. then north 320 poles to the beginning.
3 - 640 acres on the waters of the first creek above Stoner Lick Creek on the
east side of Stones River. Beginning on the northwest corner of Aquila
Sugg and on the east boundary of said Suggs warrant No. 1503 at a dog-wood
then running west 320 poles to a hickory and poplar, then south 320
poles to a dogwood, then east 320 poles to a stake, then north 320 poles to
the beginning. These three tracts are the same sold to James C. Montflorence
in June, 1790.
Wit. Bennett Searcy, William Cnitcher.
Samuel Weakley February 7, 1792 page 7
Indenture made October 7. 1792. For the sum of 100 pounds Wm. Cathey of
Rowan Co., N.C.. has sold Samuel Weakley 213 acres on the north branches of
the east fork of Stones River. Beginning at a white ash on the side of a bluff of
said fork Richard Cathey "s northwest comer and nins with his line west 60 chains
to a small dogwood his corner on the north side of said fork then north 35 chains
&amp; 50 links to a stake, then east 60 chains to a stake, then south 35 chains &amp; 50
links to the beginning. Land granted Wm. Cathey by a military warrant granted
under the heirs of Wm. Garrett, deceased, for 640 acres.
John Bucchanan February 9, 1792 page 12
North Carolina Grant No. 377. John Bucchanan, assignee ofprivate Joshua Lewis,
is granted 640 acres on Stones River. Beginning at a red oak on the west bank of
said river on Cornelius Ruddle's east boundary line then south 452 poles passing
the bent of the river to a white oak, then east 226 poles crossing Stones River to
an elm. then north 452 poles to a stake, then west 226 to the beginning. Grant
dated September 15, 1787.
Thomas McRorey February 18, 1792 page 17
North Carolina Grant No. 735. Thomas McRorey, assignee of private Abraham
Ready's heirs, is granted 640 acres on the west side of Stones River. Beginning
at an elm at the mouth of the first creek above the old station, then west 40 poles
to a white oak, then south joining Wm. More's northeast corner at 74 poles con-tinues
to a dogwood at 440 poles on Thomas Gillispie's east boundary line, then
320 poles to a walnut on the banks of Stones River, then down said river with its
meanders to the beginning. Surveyed on April 1, 1786. Grant dated July 10,
1788.
31
Thomas Cotton February 18. 1792 page 18
North Carolina Grant No. 246. Thomas Cotton, assignee of private James Smith
is granted 640 acres on Stones River. Beginning at an ash and elm being north
east corner of a survey in the said Thomas Cotton's name, then east crossing a
branch of Stones River cornered at a white oak at 320 poles then south 320 poles
to a state, then west 320 poles to the corner of his other survey, then north with
said line to the beginning. Sun eyed April 22. 1785, by John Bucchanan D.S. in
consequence of a military warrant No. 723. Located August 5. 1784. Grant dated
March 7. 1786.
Thomas Williamson April 4. 1792 page 19
Contract dated April 3. 1792. For the sum of 1000 dollars Benjamin Jostling has
sold Thomas Williamson 640 acres on Stones River and located on the east fork
of Stones River. Beginning 320 poles north of Col. Isaac Shelby's northwest
comer miming north and west for quantity, located November 11, 1789. and
held by a military warrant No. 2324.. the land to be first and second rate land. If
the land is found by Thomas Williamson not to be the quality it ought to be. then
Benjamin Jostling is to leave the estimation of the land to three men mutally
chosen and if they find the land short in value then he will pay to Williamson
their judgment. Wit. Lardner Clark. Betsey Clarke. Andrew Ewing.
Thomas Williamson April 4. 1792 page 20
Bond made by Benjamin Josling for 4000 silver dollars to Thomas Williamson
to defend any claim against the preceding tract of land named in the contract.
Sterling Clack Robertson April 28. 1792 page 26
Indenture made March 16, 1792. For the sum of 1000 pounds George Augustus
Sugg has sold Sterling Clack Robertson 640 acres on the head waters of the first
creek above Stoner's Lick Creek on the east side of Stones River. Beginning at
the north comer of Aquila Sugg's survey warrant No. 1510 at a Spanish and
white oak, then south 320 poles to a hickory and cedar, then east 320 poles to a
hickory, ash and hackberry, then north 320 poles to an ash. then west 320 poles
to the beginning. The land granted to said Sugg by a grant and by a warrant No.
2766. Wit. Bennett Searcy, Seth Lewis. George Selden.
George A. Sugg June 4. 1792 page 43
North Carolina Grant No. 987. George Augustus Sugg, assignee of private Isaac
Benford heirs, is granted 640 acres on the headwaters of the west fork of the first
creek above Stoners Lick Creek on the east side of Stones River. Beginning at a
white oak and poplar corner trees, then east 320 poles to two dogwoods, then
north 320 poles to a mulberry, then west 320 poles to a dogwood one of Sugg's
corner of another tract, then south 320 poles to the beginning. Sun eyed May 14.
1788. by Wm. Nash. D.S.. in consequence of a military warrant No. 2703. Lo-cated
April 2, 1788. Grant dated May 18. 1789.
George A. Sugg June 4, 1792 page 44
North Carolina Grant No. 989. George Augustus Sugg, assignee of Private
Applewhite Sander's heirs, is granted 640 acres on the headwaters of the first
32
creek above Stoners Lick Creek on the east side of Stones River. Beginning at
the northeast corner of Aqnila Sugg's survey warrant No. 1510, a Spanish and
white oak, then south 320 poles to a hickory and cedar, then east 320 poles to a
hickory, ash and hackberry. Then north 320 poles to an ash, then west 320 poles
to the beginning. Surveyed May 11, 1788, by Win. Nash, D.S., in consequence
of a military warrant No. 2766. Located April 3, 1788. Grant dated May 18,
1789.
John Johnston July 24, 1792 page 55
Indenture made September 5, 1791. For the sum of 60 pounds North Carolina
money Minos Cannon has sold 200 acres to John Johnston. Being on the east
fork of Mill Creek near the bridge and joining the waters of Old Hurricane. Be-ginning
at a black oak 118 poles of the said Minos Cannon's southwest
corner, running then north 117 lA poles with said line to a stake, then east 272
poles to a stake in the east boundary line of said tract. Then south 1171/2 poles to
a lynn on said line, then west to the beginning.
Wit Oliver Williams, William Armstrong, John Johnston.
Aquilla Sugg July 30, 1792 page 66
North Carolina Grant No. 890. Aquilla Sugg, assignee of Sgt. Patrick Martin, is
granted 1000 acres on both sides of the main east fork of Stones River. Begin-ning
at a white oak Reed's southwest corner running then east 400 poles to a
dogwood and ash, then south 400 poles to an ash, then west 400 poles to a wal-nut,
then north 400 poles to an ash, then west 400 poles to a walnut, then north
400 poles to the beginning. Surveyed by Wm. Nash on March 21, 1788, in con-sequence
of a military warrant No. 1824. Located March 1, 1786. Grant dated
January 17, 1789.
Aquilla Sugg July 30, 1792 page 66
North Carolina Grant No. 907. Aquilla Sugg, assignee of private Johnathan
Cherry's heirs, is granted 640 acres on the second creek above Stuarts Creek on
the east side of Stones River. Beginning on the southeast corner of a survey of
George Augustus Sugg's warrant No. 2768 on a black oak and elm on the east
side of said creek and nms north 320 poles to a mulberry George Sugg's north-east
corner, then east 320 poles to a cherry tree, then south 320 poles to the
beginning. Surveyed March 20, 1788, by Wm. Nash in consequence of a mili-tary
warrant No. 2446. Located May 25, 1786. Grant dated January 17, 1789.
(In the above, one course was wanting in the original.)
Aquilla Sugg July 30, 1792 page 67
North Carolina Grant No. 933. Aquilla Sugg, assignee ofprivate Mathew Polland's
heirs, is granted 640 acres on the headwaters of the first creek above Stoners
Lick Creek on the east side of Stones River. Beginning at the southeast corner of
a survey of said Sugg at a Spanish oak and white oak near the bank of a branch
running then south 320 poles to a cedar and hickory, then west 320 poles to a
black oak Hambleton's southeast corner, north with Hambleton's line 320 poles
to a stake, then east 320 poles to the beginning. Surveyed May 10, 1788, by Wm.
33
Nash, D.S.. in consequence of a military warrant No. 15 10. Located April 3, 1788.
Grant dated May 18, 1789.
Aquilla Sugg July 30, 1792 page 67
North Carolina Grant No. 934. Aquilla Sugg, assignee of private Solomon Parker,
is granted 640 acres on the second creek above Stuarts Creek on the east side of
Stones River adjoining George A. Sugg on the lower side. Beginning at a black
oak on the west side of the creek, then east 320 poles to a black oak and elm. then
south 320 poles to a hickory, then west 320 poles to a walnut, north 320 poles to
the begimiing. Sun eyed May 15. 1788. by Win. Nash D.S. in consequence of a
military warrant No. 2214. Located April 5, 1788. Grant dated May 18. 1789.
Aquilla Sugg July 30. 1792 page 67
North Carolina Grant No. 887. Aquilla Sugg, assignee of private Rice Price's
heirs, is granted 640 acres on the first creek above Stoner Lick Creek on the east
side of Stones River. Beginning on a mulberry George Augustus Sugg's south-east
corner of a 640 acres survey warrant no. 2236, runs north 320 poles to a
mulberry and dogwood, then east 320 poles to a white oak. then south 320 poles
to a dogwood, then west 320 poles to the beginning. Surveyed March 20. 1788.
by Wm. Nash in consequence of a military warrant No. 2218. Located May 25.
1786. Grant dated January 17, 1789.
Aquilla Sugg July 30, 1792 page 68
North Carolina Grant No. 920. Aquilla Sugg, assignee of private Joshua Fowler's
heirs, is granted 640 acres on the first creek above Stoner" s Lick on the east fork
of Stones River. Beginning at a dogwood and ironwood Hambleton"s southwest
corner, then north 320 poles to a hickory and poplar, then west 320 poles to a
dogwood, then south 320 poles to a stake, then east 320 poles to the beginning.
Sun eyed by Wm. Nash on in consequence of a military warrant No.
1503. Located April 2, 1788. Grant dated May 18, 1789.
Aquilla Sugg July 30, 1792 page 68
North Carolina Grant No. 927. Aquilla Sugg, assignee of private Jesse Davis's
heirs, is granted 640 acres on the east side of the main fork of Stones River.
Beginning at John Read's northeast comer of a 640 acre survey, running then
north 320 poles to an elm. then west 320 poles to a sugartree. then south 320
poles to a walnut, then east to the beginning. Surveyed May 10. 1788. by Wm.
Nash D.S. in consequence of a military warrant No. 2800. Located April 5. 1788.
Grant dated May 18, 1789.
Aquilla Sugg July 30, 1792 page 68
North Carolina Grant No. 988. Aquilla Sugg, assignee of private Job Sander's
heirs, is granted 640 acres on the first creek above Stoner Lick Creek on the east
of Stones River adjoining George Sugg on the north of his survey warrant No.
2766. Beginning on a white oak and poplar, then miming south 320 poles to a
Spanish oak and white oak, then east 320 poles to an ash. then north 320 poles to
a dogwood, then west 320 poles to the beginning. Sun eyed May 15. 1788. by
34
Win. Nash. D.S., in consequence of a military warrant No. 1511. Located April
3, 1788. Grant dated May 18, 1789.
Aquilla Sugg July 30, 1792 page 69
North Carolina Grant No. 919. Aquilla Sugg, assignee of private Joshua Fowler's
heirs, is granted 640 acres on the east side of Stones River and on the first creek
above Stoners Lick Creek joining another survey of said Sugg. Beginning at the
northeast corner of Wm. Nash's survey with Logue"s line ninning east 80 poles
to said Logue's southeast corner, the north 150 poles to two mulberries and wal-nut,
then east 227 poles to a mulberry, then south 320 poles to a black oak, then
west 305 poles to a walnut, then north 230&gt;/2 poles to the beginning. Surveyed by
Wm. Nash D.S. on March 18, 1788, in consequence of a military warrant No.
2416. Located May 25, 1786. Grant dated May 18, 1789.
Aquilla Sugg July 31. 1792 page 69
North Carolina Grant No. 918. Aquilla Sugg, assignee of private John Blackwell"s
heirs, is granted 640 acres on the first creek above Stuart's Creek. Beginning
three or four miles from Stones River on a black oak and hickory, then east 320
poles to two hickories, then north 320 poles to a hickory and white oak, then
west 320 poles to a mulberry, then south 320 poles to the beginning. Surveyed
January 10, 1766, by Wm. Nash, D.S., in consequence of a military warrant No.
1505. Located April 5, 1788. Grant dated May 18, 1789.
Aquilla Sugg July 31, 1792 page 69
North Carolina Grant No. 891. Aquilla Sugg, assignee of private Peter Lancer's
heirs, 640 acres on the west side of the main fork of Stones River. Beginnng at a
white oak on the lower line of John Read near his southwest corner of a survey of
640 acres warrant No. 1547. runs south 320 poles to a walnut, west 320 poles to
a cherry tree, then north 320 poles to a stake on the bank of the river, then east
320 poles with the river to the beginning. Surveyed by Wm. Nash, D.S., in
consequence of a military warrant No. 2424. Located March 1, 1786. Grant dated
January 13, 1789.
Joseph Montford August 9, 1792 page 76
North Carolina Grant No. 74. Capt. Joseph Montford is granted 3840 acres on
the main east fork of Stones River. Beginning at Col. Shelby's southeast corner
a double walnut and red oak, then north 640 poles crossing Stones River to a
hickory, elm and red oak, then east 960 to a red oak, then south 640 poles to a
stake, then west 960 poles to the beginning. Surveyed July 12, 1785, by Robert
Hays in consequence of a military warrant No. 340. Located June 29, 1784.
Grant dated March 10, 1786.
William Muir August 9, 1792 page 77
Indenture made March 1, 1791. For the sum of 250 pounds, 7 shillings and nine
pence Joseph Montfort of Halifax County, N.C., has sold to William Muir of the
same county, a tract of land 3840 acres on Stones River. The land granted to
Capt. Joseph Montford for his service in the Continental Line dated March 14,
35
1786. (See preceding grant for description)
Wit. James Tatum, Archibald Jett &amp; Alias.
Stockley Donaldson November 23, 1792 page 85
North Carolina Grant No. 959. Stockley Donaldson, assignee of private Haddin
Hndger's heirs, is granted 640 acres near the head of the first creek that nms into
Stones River above Stoner's Creek. Beginning at a mulberry and ash the north-east
corner of John Hawel's survey, then with said Hawels south boundary 320
poles to a dogwood, then east 320 poles to a hickory, then north 320 poles to a
stake, then west 320 poles to the beginning. Surveyed March 22. 1788. by Win.
Nash. D.S.. in consequence of a military warrant No. 1830. Located May 19,
1786. Grant dated May 18. 1789.
Thomas Dickey November 23, 1792 page 86
North Carolina Grant No. 254.Thomas Dickey, assignee ofprivate Joseph Eller's
heir. John Eller, is granted 640 acres on waters of Stones River. Beginning 800
poles a south course from Col. James Armstrong's southwest corner, at a walnut
mulberry and honey locust, then south 280 to an elm and dogwood, then east 366
poles to the beginning. Surveyed by Robert Hays. D.S., in consequence of a
military warrant No. 1221. Located March 9, 1785. Grant dated March 7. 1786.
Phillip Phillips November 30. 1792 page 87
North Carolina Grant No. 1076. Phillip Phillips assignee of private Peter Jolmston.
is granted 640 acres on Stones River and Mill Creek. Beginning at a Spanish oak
being William Gowen's northeast corner, then east 320 poles to a dogwood, then
south 320 poles to a black oak. then west 320 poles to a white oak being said
Gowen's southeast corner, then north with his line to the beginning. Surveyed
December 4. 1786, by John Buchanan, D.S., in consequence of a military war-rant
No. 2192. Located Februry 26. 1786. Grant dated November 26, 1789.
Phillip Phillips &amp; Michael Campbell December 1, 1792 page 87
North Carolina Grant No. 1349. Phillip Phillips and Michael Campbell, assign-ees
of private Henry Bennett's heirs, are granted 640 acres on the east side of
Stones Riverjoining Win. Nash's survey, warrant No. 2762. Beginning at a pop-lar
and dogwood on the west boundary of said survey north 320 poles to a sugartree
and ironwood, west 320 poles to a hickory and dogwood, south 320 poles to a
stake, then east to the beginning. Sun eyed July 30, 1790, by Win. Nash D.S. in
consequence of a military warrant No. 2837. Located July 6. 1790. Grant dated
November 16, 1790.
John Elliott December 3. 1792 page 88
North Carolina Grant No. 1289. John Elliott, assignee of private John McVey's,
heirs, is granted 640 acres on the west fork of Stones River. Beginning at the
mouth of Overall Creek on a black oak near the mouth of the creek on the west
side of the creek, running east 320 poles to a sugartree, then north 320 poles to a
white oak. then west 320 poles to a stake, then south 320 poles to the beginning.
Surveyed March 18. 1786. by Win. Nash D.S. in consequence of a military war-rant
No. 270. Located July 8, 1784. Grant dated November 16. 1790.
36
John Elliott December 3, 1792 page 88
North Carolina Grant No. 1245. John Elliott, assignee of private James Faulks,
is granted 640 acres on the west fork of Stones River and on the east side about
four miles from the fork including a large spring. Beginning at a walnut marked
as a corner tree, running south 320 poles to a hickory, then east 320 poles to a
black oak, then north 320 poles to a stake then west 320 poles to the beginning.
Surveyed March 19, 1786, by Wm. Nash, D.S., in consequence of a military
warrant No. 268. Located July 8, 1784. Grant dated November 16, 1790.
Anthony Gains January 21, 1793 page 92
North Carolina Grant No. 112. Anthony Gains, a private in the Continental
Line is granted 640 acres on the main west fork of Stones River. Beginning at
the east side on a sugartree and ironwood where the Commissioners Line crosses
the river, then east with said line 320 poles to a dogwood and white oak, corner
to Col. Lytle's 7200 acre survey, then north 260 poles crossing a branch, 320
poles to a red oak and dogwood on the east side of a branch, then west 320
poles to a stake, then south 320 poles to the beginning. Grant dated March 7,
1786.
Robert Smith &amp; Wm. Tilton January 29, 1793 page 105
Indenture made January 14, 1792. For the sum of 22 pounds, six shillings &amp;
eight pence and halfpenny, Lardner Clark of Nashville by his attorney Elisha
Clark of Glouster County, New Jersey, has sold 150 acres to Robert Smith and
Wm. Tilton, merchants of Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. Beginning at a white oak
on the bank of Stones River, being the beginning of Cornelius Ruddle's pre-emption,
then west with Ruddle's line 134 poles to a white oak, then south 70
poles to an elm on said line, then 124 poles to a dogwood, then north 170 poles
to the west bank of Stones River, then by said river with its meanders to the
beginning. Lardner Clark received the land by patent, which was surveyed by
John Bucchanan. Wit. A Dubois &amp; Robert Bicknell.
Thomas Williamson February 5, 1793 page 115
Indenture made July 7, 1792. For the sum of 50 pounds, John Donelson has sold
Thomas Williamson 274 acres. Beginning at the mouth of a small drain and a
point of rocks just above the drain and on the north side of a small south fork of
Stoners Creek, the said fork empties in at Stoner Lick at some plaged trees and
from thence runs north 80 poles to a white oak, then east 195 poles to a corner,
then south 226 poles to a corner and then north 146 poles to the beginning.
Wit. George Lee Davidson, John Williamson, George Nutterfield.
George Wayling February 5, 1793 page 115
Indenture made August 14, 1792. For the sum of 150 dollars, John Cummins of
Sumner County has sold to George Wayling 320 acres. Beginning at a red oak
on the west bank of Stones River in Cornelius Ruddle's east boundary, runs
thence south 226 poles to a stake then east 226 poles to a stake in the middle of
an old line, north 226 poles to a stake, west 226 poles to the beginning. Being 1/
2 of a 640 acre tract granted originally to John Bucchanan and conveyed from
37
him to John Cummins by deed dated July 10. 1792.
Wit. Frederick Stump &amp; David Shaffer.
Thomas Williamson February 6, 1793 page 118
North Carolina Grant No. 1492. Thomas Williamson "s assignee of Joseph Walker,
a private, is granted 640 acres on both sides of the east fork of Stones River.
Beginning at an ash &amp; two sugartrees 320 poles north of Col. Isaac Shelby's
northwest then running north 320 poles to an ash and large hickory, then west
320 poles to a white oak and slippery elm. then south 320 poles to a stake cross-ing
Stones River at 100 poles, then east 320 poles to the beginning. Surveyed by
Win. Nash on August 15. 1791. in consequence of a military warrant No. 2324.
Located November 11, 1789. Grant dated January 4. 1792.
John Reed February 6. 1793 page 118
North Carolina Grant No. 943. John Reed, assignee ofprivate Robert Newby, is
granted 640 acres on the east fork of stones River about four miles above the
mouth. Beginning at a poplar and running south 320 poles to a white oak on the
west side of the river, then east 320 poles to a dogwood and ash. then north 320
poles to a stake, then west 320 poles to the beginning. Surveyed on March 23.
1788, by Wm. Nash. D.S.. in consequence of a military warrant No. 1547. Lo-cated
February 25. 1786. Grant dated May 18. 1789
Caffrey and Calloway May 1. 1793 page 137
Indenture made August 13. 1792. For the sum of 1000 hard dollars. David Wil-son,
Daniel Smith. Andrew Jackson, Robert Hays, Thomas B. Craighead. Ephrim
McLane. James Robertson and Lardner Clark, tnistees of the academy estab-lished
by virture of an act of assembly of North Carolina passed at New Bern
sessions 1785 entitled an act for the promotion of learning in the county of
Davidson, have sold for the use of the academy a tract of land containing 640
acres to John Caffrey and Col. John Calloway. On Stones River known as Stoner
Lick tract. Beginning at a Spanish oak and mulberry marked as a comer tree by
Daniel Smith, surveyor, running then south 452 poles to three small white oak
saplings and an ash. then west 226 to two lynn trees marked AJ &amp; AE. then north
452 poles to a mulberry and two hickories, then east to the beginning.
Anthony Foster June 8, 1793 page 147
North Carolina Grant No. 321. For the sum often pounds for every 100 acres.
Anthony Foster is granted 640 acres on the east fork of Stones River, about two
miles below the Soldiers Line. Beginning at an ash about 1/2 mile below a large
spring on the south side of said river, running north 320 poles to a large hickory,
then east 320 poles to a stake, then south 320 poles to a stake, then west 320
poles to the beginning. Sun eyed December 20. 1792. by D. Hays. D.S., in con-sequence
of a warrant No. 846. Entered December 15. 1792. Grant dated .
1793.
Anthony Foster June 8. 1793 page 147
North Carolina Grant No. 1577. Anthony Foster, assignee of private Benjamin
38
Foster's heirs, is granted 640 acres on Stones River. Beginning at a white oak
and elm northwest comer to Phillip Phillips and Michael Campbell's survey winch
includes Black Foxes Camp, running south with their line 320 poles to a walnut,
then west 320 poles to a walnut, then north 320 poles to a stake, then east 320
poles to the beginning. Surveyed by on December 20, 1792, in consequence
of a military warrant No. 3051. Located December 19, 1792. Grant dated Febru-ary
23, 1793.
Thomas Johnston June 21, 1793 page 160
North Carolina Grant No. 1224. Thomas Johnston assignee of Private Charles
Cox. is granted 228 acres on the east fork of Stones River on Cripple Creek.
Beginning at a black oak and elm in William Ray's line, then south with said line
40 chains to a cedar buck, then west 75 chains to a stake, then north 40 chains to
a stake, then east 75 chains to the begimiing. Surveyed by Thomas Johnston July
31, 1788, in consequence of a military warrant No. 3452. Located July 19, 1788.
Grant dated November 16, 1790.
Thomas Johnston June 21, 1793 page 160
North Carolina Grant No. 1628. Thomas Johnston, assignee of Private Alexander
McGlouskin, is granted 640 acres on Stones River. Beginning at William
Bowman's southwest corner at an ash, nins west 320 poles to a hickory, then
north 320 poles to a stake, then east 320 poles to a stake, then south 320 poles to
the beginning. Surveyed by said Johnston on December 1, 1792 in consequence
of a military warrant No. 1720. Located November 29, 1792. Grant dated Febru-ary
23, 1793.
Wm. Maclin June 22, 1793 page 161
North Carolina Grant No. 125. Wm. Maclin, assignee of Martin Armstrong, sur-veyor,
is granted 108 acres on Stones River. Beginning at a walnut on Phillips
and Michael Campbell's north boundary near Black Foxes Camp, running north
170 poles to an oak, then west 169% to a hickory, then south 170 poles to a stake,
then east 169/2 poles to the beginning. Surveyed by said Maclin on December
22, 1792, in consequence of aforesaid service right. Entered December 22, 1792.
Grant dated February 23, 1793.
Phillips &amp; Campbell July 22, 1793 page 163
Indenture made April 23, 1793. For the sum of 200 pounds Elijah Robertson has
sold Phillip Phillips and Michael Campbell of Nelson County, Ky., 640 acres on
Stones River in Sumner County. Beginning at a hickory about one mile south of
a survey of Phillips and Campbell No. 3 155, running west 320 poles to a wlanut,
then south 320 poles to a hickory, then east 320 poles to an oak, then north 320
poles to the beginning. Wit. Ho. Tatum.
John Nichols July 22, 1793 page 164
Indenture made November 13, 1790. For the sum of 100 pounds, John Welch of
Cumberland County, N. C, has sold to John Nichols of Orange County, N. C,
on the east fork of Stones River. Beginning at a hickory on the east side of a ridge
39
on the east boundary of Robert Weakley's survey of 640 acres and 7 chains
south of his northeast corner, runs east 90 chains to a white ash on the south side
of a high ridge, then south 55 chains &amp; 23 1/3 links to a stake, then west 90
chains to a stake, then north 55 chains &amp; 23 1/3 links to the beginning, contain-ing
502 Vi acres. Wit. Joshua Hadley, Wm. Eryland.
Thomas Amis July 24, 1793 page 167
Indenture made July 14. 1792. For the sum of 77 pounds. Stockley Donaldson of
Hawkins County has has sold Thomas Amis of Hawkins County 640 acres lying
near the side of the first creek that nins into Stones River above Stones Creek.
Beginning at a mulberry and ash the north comer of John Herrald's survey then
south with said Herrald's south boundary to a dogwood 320 poles, then east 320
poles to a hickory, then north 320 poles to a stake, then west 320 poles to the
beginning. Wit. Thomas Harlan. William Page and Lewis Ford.
Samuel Donelson July 24, 1793 page 168
Indenture made August 20. 1792. For the sum of 50 pounds, John Donelson has
sold Samuel Donelson a certain tract of land. Beginning at John Donelson"s de-ceased
corner, on the public line, then along the public line to William Donelson*
s
line then along Wm. Donelson's line to the Cumberland, then up Cumberland
River to a comer which shall be made halfway between the two spring branches,
miming then to John Donelson's corner standing at the bottom of the town hill,
then along John Donelsoivs line 452 poles to the beginning.
Micajah Barrow July 25. 1793 page 170
Indenture made April 17, 1793. For the sum of 500 pounds George Augustus
Sugg has sold 640 acres to Micajah Barrow, lying on the main east fork of Stones
River. Beginning at a poplar John Read's northwest comer, then north 320 poles
to an elm. then east 320 poles to an ash and dogwood, then south 320 poles to a
stake, then west 320 poles to the beginning.
Also another tract of 640 acres on the east side of the main east fork. Begin-ning
at a large poplar Read's comer, running south with said line 320 poles to a
white oak and ironwood on the bank of the river, then with the meanders of the
river west 320 poles to a poplar, then north 320 poles to a stake, then east 320
poles to the beginning.
Another tract of 640 acres on Murfrees fork.
And another tract of 640 acres near the above tract.
Sit. Jolm Childers. Seth Lewis and James Dean.
Howel Tatum esq. July 26. 1793 page 171
Indenture made July 8. 1793. Sampson William, sheriff, has sold to Howel Tatum.
high bidder at five pounds, a tract of land containing 320 acres. Land sold be-cause
of an attachment against William Wallace for 1/2 of a 640 acre tract lying
on the first creek above Stoners Lick Creek on the east side of Stones River.
Beginning at a hickory and ash Stephen Brocks comer, runs east 320 poles to a
stake, then south 320 poles to a hickory, then west 320 poles to two mulberry
trees, then north 320 poles to the beginning.
40
John Cummins August 1, 1793 page 175
Indenture made July 10, 1793. For the sum of 50 pounds John Bucchanan has
sold John Cummins 640 acres on both sides of Stones River. Beginning at a red
oak on the west bank of Stones River on Cornelius Ruddle's east boundary line,
then south 452 poles passing the bent of the river to a white oak, then east 226
poles crossing Stones River to an elm, then north 452 poles to a stake, then west
226 poles to the beginning. Wit. John Lowe and Andrew McNairy.
Robert Herrald August 2, 1793 page 176
Indenture made July 8, 1793. For the sum of 100 pounds John Mulherin ofBurbon
County, Kentucky, has sold to Robert Herrald 640 acres on Overall Creek, a
branch of Stones River. Beginning at a black walnut being southeast corner to
Wm. Overall preemption, nins south 360 poles to an oak, then west crossing
Overall Creek at 124 poles continues to an ash at 283 XA poles, then north 360
poles to a post oak, then east joining Overall's southwest corner at 50 poles and
crossing the creek at 243 poles continues to the beginning at 283 Vi poles. Being
a preemption granted to said Mulherin by warrant No. 11. Entry date December
16, 1783.
John Harrison August 3, 1793 page 178
Indenture made December 9, 1792. For the sum of 100 poimds Micajah Barrow-has
sold John Harrison 500 acres on the main east fork of Stones River. Begin-ning
at a poplar John Reed's northwest corner, then north 320 poles to an elm,
then east 250 poles to a stake in said line, then south 320 poles to a stake, then
west 250 poles to the beginning. Being part of a tract of 640 acres.
Wit. William Barrow and Richard Lancaster.
Elijah Robertson August 8, 1793 page 186
Indenture made July 22, 1793. For the sum of 1207 pounds Philip Phillips and
Michael Campbell have sold to Elijah Robertson 1207 acres of land including
the plantation the said Elijah Robertson now lives on. The plantation part was
obtained by a preemption entered December 29. 1783. The other lands adjoining
the preemption were obtained by military warrants on March 7, 1786. One war-rant
was No. 1837, originally granted to Ephraim Scurlock. The No. of the other
warrant was 3155 which was located March 20, 1786. The two tracts adjoin the
lines of William Maclin, Sen., Isaac Roberts, John Cockrill, William Guinrn and
the public line and is all the land of said Phillips &amp; Campbell adjoining the afore-said
lines. Wit. Wm. Tait, John Gordon, and Andrew McCairy.
John Welch August 20. 1793 page 190
North Carolina Grant No. 975. Capt. John Welch is granted 1508 acres for his
service in the Continental Line lying on the east fork of Stones River. Beginning
at a hickory on the east side of a ridge on the east boundary of Robert Weakley's
survey of 640 acres and seven chains south of his north east corner and runs east
90 chains to a white ash on the south side of a high ridge, then south 167 chains
&amp; 60 links to a poplar, then west 90 chains to a stake, then north 94 chains &amp; 60
links to said Weakley's corner and with his line to the beginning. Surveyed by
41
Robert Weakley on May 17. 1788. in consequence of a military warrant No.
1713. Located March 22, 1788. Grant dated May 18. 1789.
John Donelson November 18. 1793 page 205
North Carolina grant No. 1 520. John Donelson. assignee ofprivate Peter McCabe"s
heirs, is granted 640 acres. Beginning at William Donelson' s corner, a red oak
and white oak on Stones River bluff, then along his line south 342 poles to a
small red oak on Stones River, then up the same as it meanders to a white oak in
Jacob Caselman's line, then on the same north 30 poles to his comer, then east
179 poles to an ash, then along the public line north 64 poles to a mulberry and
hickory on John Donelsoirs line then along the same north 452 poles to an ash.
then along John Donelson Jr. lines west 68 poles to a red oak. then north 182
poles to a white oak. then a new line west 134 poles to a red oak in the river, then
down the same as it meanders to the beginning. Sun eyed by said Donelson on
January 10. 1791, by vhture of a military warrant No. 2574. Located January 10.
1786. Grant dated April 10, 1792.
Samuel Barton November 20. 1793 page 209
North Carolina Grant no. 357. For the sum often pounds for every 100 acres
Samuel Barton is granted 640 acres on both sides of Stones River. Beginning at
a double sycamore and water maple opposite the lower end of a small island
being a corner to William Stuart's preemption, running then east passing the said
Stuarts southeast comer a black oak on the river bank at 33 poles. 320 poles to a
stake, then south 320 to a stake, then west 320 poles to a stake, then north 320
poles to the beginning. Sun eyed by Daniel Smith on November 26. 1792. by
\irture of a warrant no. 821. Entered September 14. 1792. Grant dated 26.
1793.
Daniel Chambers November 21. 1793 page 210
North Carolina Grant No. 379. For the sum often pounds for every 100 acres
Daniel Chambers is granted 640 acres on Stuart's Creek. Beginning at a white
oak on the west bank of said creek opposite to a rocky fall in said creek, then
west 5 1 poles to a dogwood, then south joining Robert Russell's northeast comer
at 88 poles continues south with Russell's line to his southeast comer in all 480
poles, then east 301 poles to a dogwood, then north 327 poles, then west 250
poles to a dogwood on Stephen Cantrill's south boundary line, then north 81
poles to the beginning. Sun eyed by John Buchanan. D.S.. on December 16.
1791. by virture of a warrant No. 557. Located January 28, 1784. Grant dated
June 26, 1793.
John Donelson November 22, 1793 page 211
North Carolina Grant No. 1847. John Donelson. assignee of private Nathan
Lamb's heirs, is granted 640 acres on the east of William Stuart's preemption
and on both sides of a sinking branch of Stones River. Beginning at the said
Stuart's comer a poplar, then along his line south 160 poles to a white oak then a
new line east 363 poles to a stake, north 260 poles to a stake, west 443 poles to a
white oak on Stones Lick survey, then along said line south 100 poles to three
small w</dc:description>
<dc:description>Contains short descriptions of deeds to land on the Stones River in Davidson County records during the time period 1784 - 1806. At this time, much of what is now Rutherford County was part of Davidson County.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.); Stones River (Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Deeds; Davidson County (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Periodical</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>184 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-01-26</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication38ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/134</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>