<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Rock Spring Church of Christ</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Gwynne, Sr., Mrs. Robert M.</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 3</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1974</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>19th century; 20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>70
Rock Spring Church of Christ
By Mrs. Robert W, Gwynne, Sr.
The history of the Rock Spring Church of Christ is the history of the oldest
Church of Christ in Rutherford County. The Rock Spring Church, five miles north
of Smyrna in Rutherford County, Tennessee was organized July 21, 1804 as a Bap-tist
Church, and on May 5, 1832 the charter was dissolved by a membership vote_^
39 to 3^ to become a Christian (Church of Christ) Church, with the two faiths
alternating use of the building.
The first meeting place back in 1804 was under a neighboring grove of trees
where a spring of water came up from under some sandstone, hence, the name Rock
Spring.
In the year 1805, Bird Nance represented the Church at the Baptist Con-vention
and his brother Isaac Nance in 1816 deeded a plot of land for the first
church building, a log structure. William Nance, Joseph Morton, and John Fulton
were in charge of constructing the building. This log structure served for a
number of years until the membership outgrew the quarters. A brick building
was raised to replace the log structure, the bricks were made on the site, and
the Church again made another advancement in a growth to two rooms. This building
also served as a schoolhouse.
Rock Spring was on the direct route from Nolensville to Jefferson. The
stage coach would travel by her doors once each week.
In 1832, the Brethren appointed at the August meeting of the Church the
following: D. R. Gooch , (bishop) W. W. Nance, (deacon) George Batey, (deacon)
James Green, and Richard Cook to go to the Tennessee Cooperation Meeting,
which was held in Murfreesboro, for the purpose of reporting to said convention
on the condition of the Rock Spring Church. Their report follows: "Rock Spring
is situated in the west side of Rutherford County about 5 miles from Smyrna.
In the year of 1832 a majority of the Baptist Church resolved to discard all
creeds as bonds of Christian union and take the Bible alone as their rule of
71
faith and practice. This was done under the labors of Peyton Smith. The distri-bution
of the Word of God, to the destitute of our own land as well as to other
lands, is our object greatly to be desired by all Christians and we believe it
to be the duty of all Christians to aid in this work."
The manner of worship at Rock Spring was, expressed in its exact form, as
follows: "The building being shared equally by the Baptist, the first and third
Lord's days in each month, the Christians meet to worship our Lord and Master,
read the New Testament, qive thanks to God through our Lord Jesus Christ for the
many blessings he has conferred on us and ask the continuation of the same. We
then break the Loaf, partake of the cup, in rememberance of his charge to his
followers, then contribute to the Lord, by each member, male and female giving
what he or she may please to the support of the Gospel. This service is performed
by each person advancing to the table in front of the stand, depositing what they
may wish in the drawer of the table. We have adopted the plan, not to sing while
contribution is going on, supposing most in order to one thing at a time, then
last of all we sing a song and go out. This is our best order of the Gospel plan
of Worship. We sincerely ask the Brethren to note the errorous of the mode, if
not according to the Gospel - - for this is what we want to learn."
The minutes of the Church from its beginning in 1804 were kept in the
most detailed manner. A description of the entire service, who preached, the
number of additions, if any, amount of offering, salary of the preachers,
description of the weather, along with other interesting facts such as the "cost
of demijohn for carrying wine, one basket for convenience of carrying loaf
$2.50, 10 yards of bunbiscin for immersion robes $1.25."
The roll of the Church in 1820 showed 42 white males, 48 white females, 10
negro males, and 20 negro females members. The negroes were the slaves of the
whfte members. All of these worshipped together at the same hour, being seated
in rear of the building and served the Lord's Supper after the white members.
72
The Church continued to grow and was the main strength of the community.
In 1887 the church building was destroyed by a cyclone. The members met in
homes until a new building could be built. Columbus La Fayette Brittain deeded
to the Church in 1887 the plot of land where the present frame building now
stands. Alice Battle surveyed this plot of ground. The building was a large
one-room structure, 30 feet by 50 feet; 4 big windows on each side and 2 front
doors. The men would enter from one door and the ladies form the other. The
men would sit on one side and ladies on the other. There were benches near the
pulpit on each side known as the "Amen" corners. The "Amens" could be heard to
ring out loud and clear when a discourse was presented that sounded true to the
Gospel. The building was heated by a pot-bellied stove and a dedicated member
would arrive early to build the fire. Records show the cost of this building,
including a fence surrounding the yard with 2 stiles and 3 horses blocks at a
cost of $747.00. It took only 7 weeks to construct this building. Other items
listed from records show - 43 yards of matting - $18.00; walnut tab'&gt;e - $2.50;
6 perf. chairs - $4.50; 7 lamps - $15.40; 2 silver waiters, 4 cut glass goblets,
one cut glass decantor - $4.50. This was purchased October 11, 1887 from Hicks,
Houston &amp; Co. The first store bought benches, (earlier the members brought their
own chairs) were purchased from William Sutherland &amp; Co. in Nashville for
$117.00. They were made of solid yellow poplar. Records show that Frances Matilda
Brittain ("Miss Duck" as she was so affectionately called by those who knew and
loved her) rode horseback (side saddle, of course) and asked for donations to help
pay for the new pews. The donations ranged from 5 cents up, mostly under one
dollar. Brother E. G. Sewell gave to the Church a beautiful large leather bound
Bible and a Mr. Wharton gave an easel to hold the Bible. The pulpit stand was
made by Edgefield and Nashville Manufacturing Col. and given to Columbus Brittain
as a gift to the Church. It was a beautiful piece of furniture. The stoves cost
$8.50 each, 2 shovels at 10 cents each, 2 pokers at 5 cents each, and 2 scuttles
73
at 25 cents each. These articles have long since passed into yesteryears except
for the pulpit stand which still graces the church and two of the original chairs,
having an honored place on the pulpit stand after 85 years.
This Church has seen many events take place during her 140 years. Many
have knelt to pray in humility to their God, many have confessed Christ as their
Lord and many, far too many, have forsaken their vows. This Church has seen
tears of happiness at weddings and tears of grief at the burial of her dead and
loved ones and great joy at the first glimpse of a new bundle of life. This
Church has lived to see some six generations enter her doors to worship their
Master. Her hospitality is unequaled in fellowship; caring for the sick, helping
a neighbor, whether member or nonmember, encouragement to the weary and most of
all, to spread the Gospel to all who cared to come her way. Visitors are treated
as her honored guests. After the bountiful basket dinners were spread on the
ground, it seemed that there was always more left than was^atenT People came
from near and far, on foot, horse back, spring wagon or walked just to meet and
be met at Rock Spring on her homecoming special days.
Some amusing stories have been handed down through the years. One such
story goes; a certain wellknown evangelist, E. G. Sewell, was preaching at Rock
Spring and, at the appointed time, he called on Columbus Brittain to lead the
congregation in prayer. Brittain, a tall stately man, white hair and long white
beard, with a most distinct voice, stood and said, "Pray yourself, you are being
paid to conduct this service." Needless to say Brittain's children, Maggie , John,
and Frankie were horrified. Another story: There was a big tree stump close to
the meeting house and, at a given time, there could always be found upwards of
ten nice size "tobacco chews" deposited until after the meeting (one wondered
who knew which belonged to whom). Then, there was a promising young lady of the
community who lost her slip while walking so stately down the aisle one Sunday
morning.
74
This church can be most proud to have had some greats to stand in her pulpit
such as: Randall Hall, Joshua Spears, W. G. Roulack, S. E. Jones, Tolbert Fanning,
David Lipscomb, F. B. Srygley, T. B. Lairmore, E. A. Elam, F. W. Smith, E. G.
Sewell, S. P. Pittman, J. A. Harding, C. M. Pullias, N. B. Hardeman, James E. Scobey,
and Rock Spring's own native sons, Leonard Jackson and Sam Harris, and many, many
more.
This church has always been blessed with capable song leaders who lead the
congregation in the old time gospel songs. Among the recorded names were: D. R.
Gooch, Martin Cutchin, George Haynes, Nobel Naron, Andrew Jackson, Grady Haynes
(son of the above George), Robert Gossett, and David Naron, grandson of Nobel Naron.
Rock Spring has experienced many changes since its humble beginning. In
recent years electric lights have replaced the oil lamps, hardwood floors the wide
pine boards, heating system the stoves, air conditioning the trusted palm-leaf
fans, individual communion set the decantor and goblets, silver contribution plates
(given in memory of Frankie Brittain Carter) the hats and wicker baskets, carpets
the straw matting, running water the everrunning "Rock Spring Branch," along with
the bucket and dipper. The year 1945 brought another improvement with the addition
of a much needed porch to the original building and in 1959, another addition, 4
Sunday School rooms. During the year 1966 there was another great step forward
with the purchase of new pews for the original benches which had served for 79
long years and, it might be added, they served extra long and extra hard. The
cost of the new pews was $2,600.00 which was quite a difference from the price of
$117.00 paid some 79 years before. History repeats itself for this time a grand-daughter
of Mrs. Brittain helped with the donations. The year 1968 brought
another addition: the vestibule, concrete porch, walk, steps, and the most
useful wrought iron rails made by Elder Warmuth W. Blair.
Missionary work, financial aid, and the care of orphans always are at the
top of the budget. The amount the Church sends to mission fields (at home and
75
abroad) would make any city congregation take notice.
The roll of the Church today has dropped and dropped but the church will go
forward. The leaders, the pastors, and the members have always been faced with
the problem to regain the disinterested, maintain the attendance, and of competing
with outside interest that pull members away. There may be less jubilation and
fewer "Amens" in the Congregation today but the lamp of faith has been kept polished
and alight in the lives of those gone on before and those who live their Christianity
in good days and bad days.
Those who worship at Rock Spring must remember it took hardships, heartbreaks,
and heartaches of the early settlers to lay the foundation.
BOOKNOTE
The 1840 Census is a premier index to Rutherford County's past.
It was laboriously copied from faded microfilm by Ernest K, Johns,
assisted by Henry G. Wray, and has now been published. The modest
price tag of $5.00 for the Census is in line with the Society's policy
as a non-profit organization to make available historical material at
cost.
Copies of the Census may be obtained from
D. M. Matheny
1434 Diana Street
Murfreesboro, Tennessee 37130
In ordering, please enclose .25 for each copy to assist in
defraying mailing costs.
Bibliographical note: Material for this brief hsitory was taken largely from the
Record Books of the Rock Spring Church (1804-1860; 1940-1968); and from the Diary
of Frances Matilda Batey Brittain.
Membership of the Rock Srping Church
(From an early entry)
Male, Colored
Boss
Andy
Jarete
Harny
Babe
Unazean
Sam
Wash
Joseph
Jessy
George
Guy
Marshall
Aaron
Andy
Female, Colored
Lide Jane
Mariar
Phi lies
Margarett
Esther
Carl in
Ginny
Celia
Mary
Polly
Cilia
Linda
Nancy
Mati 1 do
Myra
Mary
Dolly
Nancy
Charlote
Emily
Judeth
Cilia
OFFICERS OF ROCK SPRING CHURCH OF CHRIST
1832-1972
Peyton Smith (B)
Nathan Williams (C)
James S. Smith (D)
Henry Williams (D)
David R. Gooch, Sr. (B)
William W. Nance (D)
Beverly Nelson (C and D)
John Hill (B and C)
Nathan Garner (D)
John Garner (C)
George Batey (D)
Columbus L. Brittain (C and
George W. S. Haynes (S-T)
David R. Gooch, Jr. (S-T)
(B) Bishop
(C) Clerk
(D) Deacon
(E) Elder
(S-T) Secretary -
Treasurer
S-T)
H. A. Alexander (S-T)
John M. Gooch (S-T)
Joe Potts (S-T)
J. W. Mullins (S-T)
John W. Brittain (S-T)
Nobel Naron (C)
Warmuth Blair (C)
Grady Haynes (C)
Warmuth Blair (E)
Grady Haynes (E)
Tom Irvin (E)
DeWitt Williams (D)
Andrew Naron (D)
W. E. Wood (S-T)
Ministry Record
Rock Spring Church of Christ
Year
1843
1844
1845
1848
1849
1850
1851
1875
1876
1877
1878
1879
1880
1881
Amount Paid
James S. Smith $ ,5.00
Randall Hall 5.00
William G. Roulack 2.56
Tolbert Fanning 7.00
J, C. McQuiddy ~
L. E. Jones &#8212;
Tolbert Fanning ~
L. E. Jones &#8212;
L. E. Jones &#8212;
F. H. Davis 10.00
W. F. Todd &#8212;
F. H. Davis 9.95
John Morton 6.75
Elisha Waldron 4.85
James Harding 8.35
J. W. McGuffey 7.00
J. M. Tanksley 2.90
77
1882 B. C. Young $ 6.00
1883 B. C. Young 8.75
1884 Elisha G. Sewell 4.35
1885 J. C. McQuiddy 5.75
1886 - - Jackson 4.00
1887 - - Bryant 7.00
1888 - - Jackson 9.00
1889 - - - 11.60
1890 David Lipscomb 8.00
1891 John Cayce 5.00
David Lipscomb 50.00
1892 F. W. Smith 60.00
1893 James E. Scobey
David Lipscomb 7.00
1894 J. C. McQuiddy 5.00
1895 S. P. Pittman 4.00
1896 J. A. Harding 7.00
1897 David Lipscomb 3.45
1898 Hiram Hooten 3.95
1899 S. R. Logue 9.00
- - Ridley 40.00
1916 Andy Ritchie 40.00
F. B. Srygley
1917 Leonard Jackson
Charlie Taylor 61.00
1918 F. B. Srygley 63.00
1919 Dr. J. S. Ward
L. B. Jones 80.00
1920 T. Q. Martin 80.00
1921 Price Billings ley
H. W. Wrye 78.04
1922 Clyde Cleaves
L. B. Jones 65.00
1923 L. B. Jones 90.00
1924 L. B. Jones 100,00
1925 J. S. Batey
F. B. Smith 70.00
1926 Ed Cullom
J. S. Batey 60.00
1927 Clyde Gleaves
J. S. Batey 70.00
1928 J. W. Grant 90.00
1929 Leonard Jackson 90.00
1930 Leonard Jackson 125.00
1931 H. M. Phillip 115.00
1932 H. M. Phillips 82.81
Warmuth Peebles
1933 H. M. Phillip 55.00
1934 Gilbert Gibbs 65.00
1935 Gilbert Gibbs 61.00
1936 Gilbert Gibbs 68.00
1937 John Rainey 60.00
1938 J. P. Sanders 90.00
1939 Ellis Walker 85.00
1940 Gilbert Gibbs 65.04
1941 T. W. Brents 100.00
78
1942 J. S. Batey $100.00
1943 Charlie Taylor 117.00
1944 Gilbert Shaffer 110.00
1945 Buford Holt 150.00
1946 Buford holt 165.00
1947 Gilbert Shaffer 150.00
1948 Buford Holt 160.00
1949 Charlie Taylor 150.00
1950 Gilbert Shaffer 150.00
1951 Clyde Gleaves
1952 Gilbert Shaffer 155.00
1953 Leo Snow 225.00
1954 Leo Snow 175.00
1955 Gerald King
1956 Neal Clevanger 150.00
1957 Milton Irvin 200.00
1958 Charlie Taylor 175.00
1959 Gilbert Shaffer 150.00
1960 Larimore Austin 150.00
Lloyd Gaw
1961 Milton Peebles 150.00
1962 Leo Snow 150.00
1963 Gilbert Shaffer 175.00
1964 J. Garvin Smith 150.00
1965 Leo Snow 150.00
Albert Banning
1966 Gilbert Shaffer 150.00
Vincent Doan
1967 Milton Peebles 175.00
1968 Milton Irvin
Bart Laws
1969 Larimore Austin
1970 Mi Xtonv Peebles
Freeman Crowder
1971 Leo Snow
Freeman Crowder
ine Church Roll
1804 - 1832 - 1860
Male charter mem bers of
(lie church in
1804 included
John Fly.
James Hill,
William Nance,
Bird Nance.
Isaac Nance,
Balsam Ncw-som,
A n n a (
Philips. James
Gambel, Rob-ert
Burton, Jo-
&#171; h u a Philips,
William Kjmbro. Jessey Mor-ton,
Guy McFadden. Wiley
Harmon, Ezna Jones, David
Gooch, Nathan Williams. John
Wiihams, Joseph Williams
Frederick Oliver. Enoch Davis
and John Morton.
Charter female members.
1804, were Sallv Flv, Nancy
Nance, Polly Nance, Janie
Nance, Sussanna Hill. Sussan-na
Ganibrill, Ann Davis. Eliza
Harden, Eliza Newsom. Polly
Harper, FranWey Anthony
Hanna Philips, Mary Philips
Nancy Philips, BeUy Burton'
Polly Smith. Peggy Jones.
Eliza Kimbro, Mary Williams
and Rebecca Sect
Antj. the 111!^ '^TsJ?. mn-^
utes include the vote on the
proposal to dissolve its associa-tion
with the Baptist Associa-tion.
Those casting "yea" votes
were E. G. Courts, S. W.
Goodman. M. A. McFarren, M.
D. Goodman. A. E. Courts,
Jane Gooch. Frances Williams.
Sentha Sanders. Mary Hamil-ton.
Mary Smith, E. Sand-ford,
Sarah Rice, Martha
Gooch. Tabitha Harmon, E.
Morton, Sallie Sandford. Ann
Nevens, B. Hamilton, E. J.
Todd, Henley Guthers, Eliza-beth
McFadden, Eliza Mc-
Fadden. Aclnith Blair. Sisley
Williams, James Smith, Wil-
&#8226; liam B. Goodman. Nathan
Williams, William Hamilton.
John Hall. Jeps Morton. J. H,
Courts. J. M. Williams, W. L.
Williams. Wyley Harmon. Wil-liam
Trenary, William W,
Nance Jr., R. A. Yancy, C. D.
Thompson and Crafford Ellis.
Those casting "no" votes were
John Gamble. William Nance
and R. Blair.
The last meeting recorded in
this book was in June, 18.36,
with Nathan Williams as the
church clerk.
ChrisLl The membership reus
for 1836-18K0 will follow here,
using these abbreviations:
rbl-reccived by letter; ilbl-dismissed
by letter;
i-inimersed, and d-deccased
The list includes. Jessey
Motoii, Wm. W. Nance, deacon
(dbl Nov.
)8.")0&gt;. Jessey
Williams.
James S
.Smith (dbl
Nov. 1850 1
.
John Brittnn
Sr. (d 18541.
Wm. P. Book-er,
Jackson
Coving ton.
Samuel Phil-pot
e . Wm.
Ross, Geo. Ba-tey.
John Cooke Sr. (d 1854),
John W. Richardson. John M.
Nolan (d?i, W. A. Harvey.
Joseph Boz, Rufus Bethell
Payton S a n f o r d. James M.
Green. Richard Cook' (dbl.
Oct. 25. 1851), John Briiton
.Jr., Asa Phelpes, John Dickev,
Samuel Newsum, Wm. Waldcn,
C. T. Love (dbl 1848), William
Coleman (d?i, Svel Walden
'rbl Sept. 11, 1856), Wm. Ro-lach,
Henry Williams, David
R. Gooch, bishop (d March 3,
18541.
JOHN HALL, bishop (d?).
Beverly Nelson, deacon (rbl
June. 1855). C. Richard David-son
(rbl 1843), John Garner
mote from Pete Nance: this is
grandfather of John Nance
Garner, former vice president
of the U.S.), Jackson Oliphant
(dbl Dec. 3, 1850), Wm.
Rogers, Robt. Cadwell. David
Garner, Cary Hill (i 1843),
Jashway Phelpes, Nathan Gar-ner,
Wm. W. Britton. Wm.
Whiteman (dbl June 7, 184fii.
Richard Savage. &#8212; Davis,
John Hill, Wm. J. Williams.
John H. Cooke irb! Nov. 1,
1852), Thos. Cooke (rbl Nov. 1,
1852), John H. Read. Wm.
Caldwell. Madison Ross, Jesse
(Dleman, L. (". Waldcn. Henry
Britton, Tabitha Gooch, Lucy
Smith idbl 1850). Hannah M.
Nelson (rhl 1855). Malinda
.N'cvins, Patsy Brilloii, Polly
-Smith 'd?i, Klizabctli Ridlev
I rbl Nov. 3, 18551, Syrtha
?^,Tnriprs (d Dec. 31&#8212; V Ann
\ e r n n, Klizabclh Morton,
.l;ine K Raldride 'dlil Dec. 3.
III.'iflM. I.iu-inil.i llrmlruh ui/i,
Elizabrlli N.ince Ul '.'i.
M.iry Cuokf id Dec 26,
IHtiOi, N.incy (ircpnin&gt;. Mary
Oliphant mI'i, l,u&lt;cy Cncik
M.iry (', M.ilhurs, Lucuid.'i
( lilcinan, Agu.sta Hichanlsun,
Polly Nolin. Cisiley Smith,
Elizabeth Balhell (d Aug.
1858 1. Darindd Sanford, Lucy
Gambill, Elizabeth Green.
Nancy C. Austin, Unity Cook
(dbl Oct. 25, 18.',] I. Sarjh Ann
Phelpes (rbl Oct. 27, 1857',
Francis Newsum. Nancy Wal-den,
Elizabeth Rolach, Conne-
Icy Walden, Marth.n Crocetter
(rbl Nov. 3, 18551, Nancy
Phillpot, Cyrcna i'hcphcard,
Judy Pursele (rbl 1845), &#8212;
Conley. Rebecca Ncusum, Co-line
Hall (d Dec. 1844).
LUCENDA BOZ, Jane Hill (i
1843), Dclcla Mah^in 'rbl J846,
Sarah Oliphant irbl Dec. 3.
1850), Nancy Mitchell 'd?).
Polley Garner. Margarete Da-vidson.
Mrs. Joshway Phclph.
Mary Gin^avy. Harritc B.
Booker, Marthey Ann Britton,
Mary Ann Nance, Mary Jane
Britton. Theodica B. Nance
(dbl 1850), Eliza Smiili (dbl
Dec. 1850). Margaret Freeman
(dbl Jan. 19, 18.50), M. P. lliil,
Lourany Cooke (dbl Dec. 20.
185L), Susan P. Smith (dbl
Nov. 3, 1850), Elizabeth P.
Garner, Ann C. Ross, .Marv A.
Booker. Ester Williams. M'. D.
Cooke (dbl Dec. 20. 1851).
Lucinda Austin, Elizabeth Lov-cl.
Paralee Walden (rbl Sept
11, 1856). Louisa Batey idbl
Oct. 1853;, Adelia Lillard.
Mary H. Hardin. Louisa Conly.
Frances M. Hazelwood. Emi-
Jv Caldwell, Alinira Roberli
.dbl Nov. 3, 18.50', .Mari^recia
Savage, Lucinda Nance irbl
Nov. 3. 1850). Elizabeth Harris.
Elizabeth Bennett. Eliza J.
Harris, Elizabeth Coleman,
Elizabeth Smith idbl Nov. 3,
1850), S. Cooke. E. Cooke irbl
Nov. 1. 1852). L. Ann Havnes,
Fran B. Beaty, &#8212; Hill, Pricilla
Mitchell li Oct. 8. 1851), M&#171;ry
Elder (i Oct. 1851', .Margare!
Hazelwood (i Aug. 2. 1852),
Miss Perry li Aug. 2, 185-.;),
l\Iiss Eskridge (i Aug. 2. 1852),
Leak Mullins. Kliza Ca\itt &#8226;!
Oct. 3. 1852), Elizabeth Leak
(rbl Nov. 18.521, Marv E.
Gooch, Elizabeth Leak Jr. (rbl
May 8. 18,53.'. Marsaret Mul-lins
I rbl May 8 1853). Sarah
Dove (rbl 1853), Louisa Mullins
irbl 1853), Virginia Burl (rbl
18,53), Nancy Walden uhl
18531. Ann McQucddy ubl
18.53).
MARV BRKWKR 1 1 bl 18.3',
M.nriha g. Phillpul irbl Oct ;3,
18.531, Isadora H. Wnlrion,
Domariiis H, W.ilde MV'aldcn ' i.
Ann L. Womiiulf, uhl March.
111541. E Konne.v irbl 1K,&gt;;)|.
Emily Cook ii Aug , ;h.i4i,
Margaret .Spear Mbl !)(&#187;c 24.
18.54'. S&gt;!irab K. Narin rl&gt;' July
IH. 1H.55I, Marth.i A. Culeman
III)! July 18, 18.5,5 . and ^. A.
Spoer (rbl March 26, l&#171;.55i.</dc:description>
<dc:description>A short history of the Rock Spring Church of Christ, including a list of African-American members, officers, and ministers with salaries</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.) -- History</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>churches; Church of Christ</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Smyrna</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>19 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-16</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication03ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/141</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>