<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Jefferson Springs</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hoover, Margaret Denny</dc:creator>
<dc:contributor>Swain, Effie; Bradley, Margaret; Wright, Martha; Moore, Bessie; Johns, Ernie; King, Adeline</dc:contributor>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 21</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>198?</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>19th century; 20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>JEFFERSON SPRINGS
By Margaret Denny Hoover
(With assistance fw&gt;m Mrs. Effie Swain, Margaret Bradley, Martha
Wright, Bessie Moore, Ernie Johns and Adeline King)
For over 50 years, it was known as "Sulphur Springs," As early as
1850, the "Black Sulphur Spring" had been discovered; and people came
there on horseback, in wagons or buggies, on foot, to drink the water
they believed very beneficial, to take it home with them. To them, it
was a sort of "elixir of life" that would cure or ward off most of their
aliments. The spring was even called a "spa" by seme, from knowledge of
or acquaintance with healing springs of Europe. At first and for a long
time, it was just a spring, bubbling vsp from the earth about ten feet from
the river's edge. Later, someone blasted out the spring, laid big stones
around it; even later, a concrete platfoim was poured. In the early days,
access to the spring was by a slippery path sloping down the river bank.
To get to Sulphxir Springs from Smyrna and Nashville, visitors and
devotees of the water proceeded out Jefferson Pike tintil they came to the
shore of the West Prong of the Stones River; at that point, the Pike con-tinued
on to the right across a bridge (originally iron, later a concrete
structTire), into the historic village of Old Jefferson, and on to Mona
and Walter Hill. The Road to the Sulphur Springs turned sharp left just
before the bridge approach and continued until it ran alongside the river
again (this was the main stream of the Stones, after the East and West
Prongs had merged near Old Jefferson town). The people heading for the
north side of the river forded it here at a shallow shoals maybe a quarter
mile or less from the spring itself. The distance from the town of Old
Jefferson and the Springs was approximately two miles by road.
Sometimes in the early l800's, the Rutherford County Census listed
19
Caleb Swain Age U2
Martha Swain 37
Their Children:
Fraildin Swain 17
Lorenzo P. Swain 15
Amanda &#163;. Swain 12
Bluford 3. 10
Benjamin S. 8
Fountain E, P. 6
Juna A. V. 3
Wmiam T. 1
the "Sulphxir Springs District." Mrs. Effie Harrell Swain has related
that her late husband LiUard Swain was the grandson of Caleb Ward Swain
and his wife Martha, who settled in the Fall Creek District between I830
and I81i0. According to the l850 Census, they were listed:
Farmer Bom lii North Carolina
Bom in North Carolina
Bom in Tennessee
Bom in Teimessee
Bom in Tennessee
Bom in Tennessee
Bom in Tennessee
Bom in Tennessee
Bom in Tennessee
Bom in Tennessee
Fountain E. P. Swain was the father of Lillard and James Franklin
Swain. His wife was Elizabeth Barber; they bxiilt their home on a large
tract of land on the north side of Stones River, for a long stretch along
the river above and below the actual Springs. The house sat on a rise
facing west. On the south side of the river was a large farm owned by
Rufe Johns. Bom to Franklin E. P. and Elizabeth Barber Swain In addition
to Lillard and James Franklin (Jim^ was a child called Johnny, who died at
an early age. In later years, Jim Swain lived at the southeast end of the
Swain tract, and Lillard Swain at the northwest.
On December 22, 191U, Lillard Swain was married to Effie Harrell, who
was bom in I896 in Hillsboro, Texas. Her parents were Henry Jones Harrell
and Nancy Bell Harrell. Her grandparents James T. and Roxanna Young Bell
were homesick for the Harrells and the Harrells homesick for Tennessee; and
Mr. Bell purchased the Tom Sanders farm in the northwest bend of the Stones
River and invited the Harrells to come home to Tennessee. When they return-ed
in 1898, Miss Effie was two years old.
The children of Lillard and Effie Harrell Swain:
20
Pearl Swain (Mrs. H. Herbert Batey) Dllton, Tennessee
Eugene Franklin Swain Smyrna, Tennessee
Janes LllLard Swain Nashville, Tennessee
Rachel Swain (Mrs. l&amp;rd Lee Wri^t) Kingston, Tennessee
The children of James Franklin (Jim) and Elizabeth Hester Swain:
Ruth Swain (Mrs. Clarence Terry) Petersburg, Tennessee
James Fountain Swain (died in 1982) Nashville, Tennessee
Note: E. F. (Frank) Swain and his wife Beulah presently have their
home on the New Jefferson Pike, on some of the original Swain property.
Sales of land parcels began in the area of the Springs before 1900.
These excerpts from the Records of Deeds in Murfreesboro show that Fount-ain
P. and Alice Swain purchased a tract of land from the Qeorge Adkerson
estate in 188U. Thereafter, they sold lots, as follows:
In 1891 to Mrs. Virginia Nash
In 1891 to W. H. Sanders
In I89U to J. A. Qua, Jr., and H. L. Fox
In 1895 to Mrs. Sallie Loid (Uoyd ?)
In 1895 "Lot No. 1" to H. H. Hicks, Jr., and T. A. Bridges
(the deed says "on the north bank
of Stones River opposite the Sul-phur
Springs; they can not do
business such as selling goods or
merchandise or produce," Dated 2
February 1895)
In 1900 to John H. King, northwest comer,
west to Zanons (sp7), southeast to
Charlie Ward, and north to Charlie
Ward line.
In 1901 to Louis Huggins
In 1902 to J. C. and Maggie Rushing, land
bordering on north by Swain, east
by James Harrell and J. P. Sanders.
This plot of land in \rtiich to be
"situated a projected hotel b\iild-ing
for viijitors to Sulphur Springs,
for F. P. Swain, Sam and Hattie Reed
Adams, C. A. Ward, and Ton Smith.
In 1906 to M. T. Altmeyer
21
1
P^tK
r- ~f&lt;~^ ^ 7&gt; -^&gt; Ctf^'Trt
C&#171;^'
f;
.t^
..^1
A
c&lt;^.
QO&#187;l
.-(^^
_ a
^/
&gt; t^Ar/&lt; S-^'^^^^"^'"'
22
U.S. Army Engineer's map
for property in Percy Priest
Lake ,
22 a
TRACT REGISTER OF ACQUISITION AFTER I JAN. 1943
LAND OWNER
ACREAGE
FEE EASE. REMARKS
? 'J / f J
I
MRS. MOLLIE MILLFR
MRS. )rv^;aie /wnttR
EARL L. COLEMAN ET AL
EARL L. COLEMAN ET AL .
ELIZABETH SANDERS
DORIAN E. CLARK
MRS. MOZfLLE M. SMITH
GEORGE W. MULLINS JR. ET. AL
E.G. RION
W.O. DENNY
CLARA BELL BAKER
EFFIE SWAIN
EMMETT H. WEBB SR.
E.G. RION
MARGARET A McLURE
OSCAR S. BASKIN
H,G. AND SALLIE YEAR6IN
BESSIE MAI BUCHANAN
JESSE JULIAN WARD
LEON GILBERT -
C;S. AND J.T. D'.:GGER
MARGARET A. McLURE
JAMES F. MORRISON
JOHN S, RIDLEY ET AL
MARGARET A. McL RE
JESSE JULIAN WARD
JESSE JULIAN WARD
MARGARET ROONEY BAREFIELD
MAUDE A. McCANi ESS
JAMES M. BRLNT
MARGARET A. McLURE
JOHN S. RIDLEY ET AL
^i..TX
IU8.50
1^.60
30.70
17.80
0.10
88.00
0.63
0.15
0.58
I .15
0.26
2U.30
0.140
I .88
4.85
o.m
0.16
0.311
0.il5
0.22
O.ll
0.141
0.73
I .HO
0.50
0.35
0.01
2.00
0.08
0.23
0.55
29.24
2/ &#8226;s'.o
n*)Wv*-^
ft '
\1 &gt;Tr&#171; i/&#171;v ui v^*.t%&lt;.&gt;r
'^
U. "S. Arniy Engiijifeer &#8226; s list of I LandoiAOiers'
at Jefferson Springs when land was taken for
Percy Priest Lake. .
j
22 b '
:
'*;::,&#8226;* .'
In 1906 to Charlie Ward&gt; northwest side. He
built a two-story house with ci^la.
This was the first hotel.
In 1907 to W. H. Tiniiion (Tiraraons ?)
In 1908 to Eugene Black, property which was
on the north fronting of public
road&gt; east by Swain to middle
of the river, west by lands of
Stoiith.
In 1913 Eugene Black sold this to Frank Davis, "an xmnarried man,"
Davis sold it to J. J. Anderson
and E. H. Murray, also in 1913.
The new ownership was known as
the "Jefferson fringe Hotel
Company."
In 1913, W. W. Dillon, J. J. Anderson, and E. H. Murray acqiilred
six acres on the south side of the River from W. R. (Rufe) and J.J. Johns.
Ttd.a transfer included the Sulphur Springs and the sand bar.
In I9IU, F. P. and Alice Swain sold land to J. J. Martin, W. H. Martin,
R. S. Waller, Claiborne Waller, northeasterly by Sam Adams and wife, south
by public road, west by F. P. Swain and wife.
In 1916, J. J. Anderson and W. T. Young bought 51 acres from F. P.
and Alice Swain on the north side of the river. It bordered the property
of J. F. Baskin.
In 1916, J. J. Anderson sold a number of lots to M. T. ^yrd, George
W. Haynes, and others. J. J. Martin sold a lot to John H* King, northeast
comer, formerly owned by Charlie Ward, west 150 feet to a lot known as
Zanals (sp?) Lot.
In May 1916, F. P. and Alice Swain sold a lot to W. G. and Margaret
Denny (grandparents of Margaret Denny Hoover), at the southwest comer of
the Sam Adams cottage (the lot had been purchased from WLUie Watrd (grand-father
of Kathryn Qre&amp;a. McClary). The Demy family had been coming to the
Springs each summer since 1912, camping out in tents.
In 1918 and later years F. P. and Alice Swain sold lots to the
23
following:
Mrs. John Valley VJhite
Ifrs. C. W. Webb
C. M. Ward
C. H. Sanborn
F. W. Miles
J. R. Culbertson
Sam Cox
Mrs. M. S. Swain
In 1922 to W. O. Denny
A. S. Overall
The need for a bridge across the river at the Springs was recog-nized
early; and, in 1908, Nashville Bridge Conqpany entered into a
contract (with the County, we presiane) to build an iron structure a-cross
the river a few feet downstream from the spring itself; the north-side
exit was into what was to become the "hub" of the Jefferson Springs
Summer Resort. Mrs. Effie Swain tells us that, although the bridge was
begun in 1908, it was not conq;)leted, due to financial problems, mtil
January 1913* She recalls that she and Idllard Swain were married on
December 23, 19lU, and they had been able to cross the bridge for nearly
a year before their marriage. In the 1960's, the bridge was taken out by
the Corps of Qifleers (as were several others across the Stones River in
the area) for the impoundment of the waters of Percy Priest Lake. Through
the efforts of local people (Everett WalLer, to name one), Adeline King,
then employed at Nashville Bridge Company, obtained the builder's plate
that was attached to an \:;&gt;per truss. This plate was dated 1908; and,
because that was the birth year of one of the builder's sons, she turned
the plate over to the son. lliis bridge was set at right angles to the
road approaching from the south, and its approach rstap curved gradxially
from the road. It was a one-way structure, with a railed off walkway for
pedestrians on one side. Its flooring was of wide, thick planks, reinforced
24
and double-thickness for the wheel tracks. These planks rattled loosely
with the passing traffic, and the noise of them could be heard several
miles away. On crowded, summer Sundays, it was filled with people, walk-ing
back and forth, leaning against the rails, watching the boats and
swiimers in the water below.
As mentioned before in this record, Charlie Ward had in 1906 bought
a small tract on the northwest side; on it, he built a two-story house
with a cvqx)la. Later, Mr. J. J. Anderson purchased this lot and house
from Mr. Ward, added a third story, kept the ciqwla} he added a large,
screened-in area for dining and dancing. On a Saturday night in 1920,
Mr. Anderson's hotel b\imed. Mr. Anderson rebviilt and, on Friday evening
of State Fair Week in 1920, both this hotel and adjacent dance hall were
burned, along with the Adams house (also called the WLUie Ward house).
The fire engine from Smyrna answered the call and saved the Denny house.
A bucket line, providing water from the lAllard Swain house about 100
feet behind the Denny house, dance hall, and store, was also responsible
for saving those structures.
The third hotel was the Bob Smith house on the south side of the
river. Mr. J. J. Anderson bought it from the Smith family about 193u.
His son, J. J. Anderson, Jr., wife, and twin children, Jimmy and Cather-ine,
came vop from Florida each summer for a number of years to run the
hotel enterprise for Mr. Anderson, Sr. In this structure, there was room
for about 30 (maybe more) people. They provided lodging and three meals
a day to their boarders.
The Bob Smith family, comprised of several sons and daughters, were
talented people and very musical. They provided music for square dances,
put en dramatic shows during the summer for visitors at the resort
(conedies and tear jerkers like "Face on The Bar Room Floor ," etc.),
25
Denny? store
W.G. Denny-leaning
against
post
Anderson store
about 1925
Bob Smith house
Used as hotel
Bought by
R.L. (Dick) McLure
about 1926
Oi\
along with regular participation In the well-remembered Toby Shows.
The first store in the resort was operated by Mr. "Cap" Johnson.
He provided not only food, kerosene, incidentals, but also Just about
any item called for by a suraier caitqjer. He even offered costumes or
materials to make them for any special occasion. Tommy Wrather also
had a store in the eastward end of the settlement. After the store
owned by Mr. J. J. Anderson was destroyed by fire in 1925, it was re-built.
Adjacent to it was a bowling alley (5 pins); there was also a
pool room adjacent to the large dance hall. This was just to the ri^t
of the exit from the bridge on the north side of the river.
Directly in front of the north exLt of the bridge, there was a
large plot of ground known as The Playgroxmd. It was surrounded by a
rock fence and was entered through a large center gate. In this area,
were shady picnic grounds, horse show throwing facilities, a baseball
field. There was also a popular feature known as "The Flying Jennyj"
it would hold well over SO people at a time. With circular tiers of
seats, it went up and down, and required six to eight boys to keep it in
motion. Mr. Anderson had it built by John Bell Smith and Charlie Sam
Parker about 1925.
For many years after its discovery, and with increasing popularity,
the spring was just that, a spring bubbling up from the ground. Qushlng
up from the earth from a small mound about ten feet from the steep river
bank, it was reached by making ones way down a narrow, slippery path
diagonally down the river bank. We are told that, to enlarge it, someone
blasted out the spring (could have destroyed itJ in the early 1900 's. In
or before 191ii, concrete steps were built strlght down the river bank
directly in front of the spring, steep, high, narrow, dangerous steps. At
the same time, a concrete platform was laid surrounding the spring "gumj"
27
the gum was about four or five feet tall and had three spigots on Its side
facing west. At one time and for a tiioe, there was a large umbrella in-stalled
above the "gum."
Mr. J^erson also built a large wooden slide-chute and bath house in
the next few years; they were on the south side of the river and were
operated by Gene Smith and wife. The slide, a flume-like structure, was
an exciting Innovation for the young swimmers. It was of wood; its top
was at road level of the river bank, and its bottom at water level. The
starting point was above and not far fW&gt;m the "spring" site, and the chute
curved away slightly in its downward course to mid-river. It had to be
kept watered down so the slide boards would movej and sliders provided
their own pails of water for the process. Climbing the long stairway to
the top carrying board and pall of water was not easy; but the process
went on in steady procession. The youngsters watered down the chute, got
onto their boards, pushed themselves off, picked yip roller coaster speed,
and went screaming to plunge into the river at midstream. Moving pictures
were taken one lith of July of Margaret McLure ^^^ Margaret Denny making
their speedy descent of the Slide . Later, when the reels were rolled in
the Dance Hall; the operator showed the descent, then reversed the reel,
and shot the girls back vp the Slide at terrific speed.
As outlined earlier, people wei&#171; birring lots from the Swain family
before the turn of the century and building s\anmer houses. Two of those
earlier residents were Willie and Charlie Ward, brothers from Stayma
(Willie and Kate Black Ward were the grandparents of Kathryn Green, 'Mrs.
R. W. McClary. The two large campsites of the Wards could accomodate
25 to 30 people. In the years after 1913* the Willie Ward house was
known as "the Adams house." It was next door to the home and store of the
W. G. Denny family, grandparents of Margaret Denny Hoover. The Denny
2g
The wooden slide and the bath house above
with people swiming: in river. About 1920
Cars parked on sandbar on south side of the
river near the Sulphur spring about 1920
Pictures furnished by Wm. H, V/hite.
reverse
A token issued by the Jefferson Springs Co.
furnished by E.K. Johns. "Probably dates about 1920
Pencil tracing of Aluminum token.
2S A
^.:|fy^
i't 1
1
S^Wile i L:-. 1 &#8226;
r^'* ,.
^^^^^^*'^r^Bl1^
Point Veiw
built by Smith family
of Nashville
Baskin's house
Built by Charles Moore
about 1914
Triangle house
Dick McLure house
29
Hilltop
Home of J.J. Anderson
Mrs. Eades in front of
gate to park at Sulour
(Jefferson) Springs
\.-*''11W
Im
Rental house
Building ne:&lt;:t door v;as to
be a T.B. Hospital but vras
not finished.
"//rather house
Built before 1914
30
Pictures of Jefferson Springs- cnbins of Iirs. John
V. V/liite From her .""randson V/m. H. V/}iite
30 A
/
When the hot da(Vs come, and the suffocat-ing
&#8226;ights, everyone asks
:
Where shall -we go for a holiday.
What change will do us the most good?
Modern science gives the answer.
Out among the hills and streams.
Change of climate, change of surroundings.
Complete change is the first condition of
health and recreation.
Enjoy these in
Stiiphur Springs
"5 Minutes from the Dixie Highway"
Smyrna, - - Tennessee
Boating, Bathing, Fishing, Hunting and
Motoring. Cedar-clad mountain valleys ; Pic-
^ turesque and historical Stone River, forcing its
way through precipitous gorge and deep canon,
lending a sort of awe to the wild mountain
passes.
Tennessee's famous blue-white sulphjii*^
spring water absolutely free to visitors.
Hospitality is a striking characteristic of the
select occupants of Mrs. White's Rustic Camp
Cottages. Here everybody is made to feel at
home. One cannot fail to be impressed with the
freedv^.n from restraint and withal th si&#171;y,
home-like atmosphere that pervades the ^.lace.
Two, three, and four room complely fur-nished
rustic cottages for weekly, monthly, or
season rentals. Make your reservations now
for this and next summer.
Rates and full information from,
*^7" MKS. JNO. V. WHITE,
&#8212;SulphSr Springs, Smyrna, Tennessee or
217 East Vine, Murfreesboro, Tennessee
An Advertisement for rental cabins by Firs. John Valley
'iiThite now ovmed by her grandson V/m. H. VThite.
i@BB@ 30 B
Reverse of Advertisement of rental cabin by l-n
John V-alley V/liite
30 C
store was called "The Campers Store." Also, as indicated earlier, the
Dermys purchased their lots from the F. P. Swains in 1916,
After tiiming left after crossing the bridge to the norti-! side of
the river, there was located the J, J. Anderson hoxise on a hill on the
right side of the road. N&#171;xt to it was the Willie Ward (or Adams)
house J then the W. J. Denny store, dance hall, and home. Across from
the score on the river side of the road was the Vlebb cottage. Beyond
the Denny place on the right side of the road was the LiUard Swain
home and farm; there were many beautiful oak trees on thia property.
On the river side here was an open lot through which 'Ar. Swgin's cow^
went down to the river twice a day for water. It was also Uie north-side
end of the former x-ord used by travelers before the bridge was
built. Also on the river side of the road s a teiinis coiirt, the ".J.
0. Baker cottage, and lots owned by C. VJ. Parker and W. 0. Derxr,-/ (these
lots were enclosed by fences). The "Cap" Johnson store was along i:i this
areaJ and then up on a rise i2i the river's bend was tha ;L=rrell home and
farm (the Bumstts lived here at one time). The main road separated the
river side from the farm side of the area; this road continued on past
the Larrsll place to the Su'tnsr Sanders home and f-n'.n. Originally, this
had been a public road, followirig ttiC river to the Jesse ;;=aidoi&#171; pi-ci^ity,
whei-e one could ford the rivei- ovsi- to Shai-j Springs xioad, or you oou2.d
continue along the road back to Lamar Road, vjiiicli came from zhe norLh
in^o Jefferson Spiir.^s.
Back to the bridge and turr.ing right afocr c:d.tdr.g onoo the noi-th
side of the river and moving eastward, there were on one's; rJ.gxri, or
river side of the road, tvrc rental cottages ov:i;ed by D; -&gt; Mc*^ ure (father
of Margaret Mc'V-VJ-e Bradlfty); a rental house o-wned by Mi^s. John Valley
I'Tiitej a vacan-o let; then houses rf Bud Baskin, Buddy Barefield, Mr. Doyle,
31
Louis Todd, Joseph Vaughn, John Dugger, Claude Dugger, two houses ovmed
by the Ward brothers, Mr. Smith, Dr. Woodring; (all these, except Mrs.
White and Mr. BasVdLn, were Nashville people); then a cottage of Mrs.
Wrather. On the other side of the road, coming back from the east end
of the settlement, was the gate leading into the farm of James Franklin
Swain (known as Jim) and his wife Elizabeth. This place was later owned
by J. L. and Daisy Ross. Caning back west along the road, was the Tommy
Wrather hoiisej Mr. Wrather was a man of diminutive stature, but of person-ality
and character to outreach his size. The VJrathers were early resi-dents
of Jefferson Springs community. Next came the Thompson Ward house,
built of rock; then five or six rental houses built by Buddy (E. W.) Bare-field,
the Moore house, owned by the father of the late Herbert Moore,
the Geny house, largest of the summer cottages; next was Mrs. John Valley
White's log house, the John BaskLn house, purchased by R. G. McI, ure, a
rental house, and the "Triangle House" (summer home of the Mc Lures).
Turning right after the McL .ure house, one entered the end of Lamar Road,
with the Playground on thje immediate left. Then came the Tom Byrd house,
the Robert Dudley house, house of AUen Dobson, Uie Gregory Ross House
(they were year-round residents). Gregory was the twin brother of J. L.
Ross. Across the road was the Overall house, which was destroyed by
fire and not rebuilt.
With the continuing popxilarity of the sulphur water from the spring
with the older generation, the convenience of the bridge, the enthusiaan
of young people for summer camping, swimming, and boating, Jefferson
Springs grew rapidly as a summer place. People came from Nashville and
other places; they came in early svmimer after school ended and stayed
until the first of September or school time again. Some built and owned
cottages; other rented. They built their private ladders or steps down
32
the river bank from the cottages to the water below. They brought boats,
bathing siilts, fishing gear, stocked up their cupboards and iceboxea,
filled the oil lanqps, and were ready for the sunmer. Fathers who worked
in Nashville or elsewhere coioauted daily to their jobs, while mothers and
youngsters spent much time in the river, getting their bodies deep-tanned,
their hair bleached i^hite by the sisi. They came year after year on their
annual happy trek. The Denny family can9&gt;ed in tents for several years be-fore
they built a cottage.
Bessie Wright Moore has given us some of the personal recollections
of her late husband Herbert Moore, who as a boy spent much happy s\znner
time at the Springs. She writes:
"The Moores went to the 'Sulphur Springs" after their crops were
'laid by', and they stayed several weeks each summer, leaving some of
their older sons at home to do the milking and other chores. They and
their camping necessities traveled by wagon from their farm seven miles
from Murfreesboro on the Franklin Road. It was about a day's journey;
they came from the Murfreesboro Road into Florence Road, having to ford
streams several times, which gave the horses a chnace to drink and rest.
One of the fordings was at the West Prong of the Stones River which passed
between the Mann and Creech farms, off Florence Road. The Creech place
was later owned by ray relatives Joe and Ollie Waller King. A narrow road
frrm the ford brought one into the village of Old Jefferson and passed
the Waller home (of my maternal grandparents). This was the house where
they kept the buggy sheltered on the porch.
"At Sulphur Springs (the Moores never called it anything else), the
Moores stayed in a tent for some seasons; later Baddy Moore built a cook
house where the meals were prepared. Many cousins and other relatives
came to visit for a few days at a time; they usually came with full hands
t
33
Tent Gamp said to be Smith and Bateys
These camps v;ere built in li39o and 1900
34
of provisions, including fresh vegetables. Daddy Moore and Mrs. John
Valley White both were owners of several cottages for rental.
"Herbert recalled seeing Mrs. White slipping quietly through the
trees on the lot to go swimming, attired in baggy bloomers, long black
stockings, canvas shoes, and a bulky cap.
"As a boy Herbert and his brother earned summer spending money by
rowing campers across the river before the bridge was built. For a
small fee of a nickel or dime, they ferried anyone who came to their
canoe dock."
On the ktti of Ju3y, the big day of the summer holiday season,
people thronged to Jefferson Springs; they came on foot in wagons, trucks,
cars, anyway. The summer residents and the visitors by ten a.m. haul the
playground, parking areas, bridge, stores, sand bar, and roadways congest-ed.
The Saturday night dances drew crowds too; there were some dances
on week nights, but Saturday nights filled the halls. The gatherings
were not always peaceful. After some over-indulgers began or got into
quarrels, petty spats, fist fights, law officers sometimes had to take
over. After one very high night, one couple greatly intoxicated, got
into their car, roared off, and plvmged off the river bank into the water
below. When men waded across the stream to pull the occupants out of the
car, the giggling, pixilated girl confided, "I always did want to be in a
wreck."
Mr. W. G. Denny b\illt a dance hall connected to his store in 1917;
in 1920,on each Satruday night and special summer holidays, orchestras
were playing there, as well as at the hall of J. J. Anderson. Some of
the good orchestras irtio came to play, chiefly out of Nashville, were
those of Bill McDowell, Red McBwen, Beasley Smith, on at least one occa-sion,
Fhil Harris and his band played at a Jefferson Springs dance.
35
'A Land of Pure Delight'
Jefferson Springs
ON PICTURESQUE STONE RIVER,
RUTHERFORD COUNTY, TENNESSEE.
A Restful Place to Spend a Vacation
Swimming in sparkling water under safe conditions.
Boating along the wide reaches of a restful river.
Fishing for those who enjoy that fine sport.
Rest and Recreation, helpful and healthful.
Long walks through the cool woods.
Come to Jefferson Springs
Convenient and conveniences for
those who appreciate the charms
oj the Water, IVoods and Fields.
Bring the Kiddies and Turn Them Loose.
Pamphlet advertising Ilrs. John V.'./hite's rental
cabins . Furnished by ',/m. H. V/hite her grandson.
35 A
JEFFERSON SPRINGS
Everywhere, everyone loves the "good old summer
time," but when the real hot days come, with the suffocat-ing,
trying nights, we all ask ourselves where we can go to
get away from the heat. (Just a holiday with change of
environment always does us good.) Nature always fur-nishes
the answer, "Go ro the hiils, woods, streams, and
get acquainted with Nature, and what she has to offer you.
"
When it comes to where to go, there is only one answer
&#8212;Jefferson Springs, Rutherford County, Tennessee, lo-cated
twenty-three miles from Nashville and eleven miles
from Murfreesboro, over the finest automobile roads one
could wish to travel on. There are jitneys and a motor bus
which run making three trips a day between Nashville and
Murfreesboro and they can take you to Smyrna where you
can make arrangements to be taken over to Jefferson
Springs for a mere trifle.
There are accommodations for those who come to Jeffer-son
Springs. There is a hotel; there are also several board-ing
houses and Mrs. White's famous rustic cottages. The
beauty and actractiveness of Stone River must not be over-looked.
On one side the rocky bluff rises to a height of fifty
feet, while on the other side the slope is very gentle with a
wide, clean, pebbled beach which makes it delightful for
bathing. The water is clear and pure except immediately
following a rain storm. The current is gentle and the river
is not deep, nor is it full of snags, which makes it safe for
swimmers, and for a mile or more the water is shallow on
one side making it safe for the little folks to play in the water
and have fun to their heart's content. There is a well
equipped bath house near the bridge with a chute for those
who enjoy the sport of sliding down into the refreshing
water of the river.
Phamplet of Mrs. V^ite page 2
35 3
1. Riverside Drive. 2. The Log Cabin, one of Mr^. White's Cottages. 3 and 4.
Swimming in Stone River. 5. The Bath House, Chutes and Bridge.
Fhamplet of Ivjr^s. I'/hite- note picture ,/ 5
r-* MRS. WHITE'S COTTAGES
ON THE bluff side of Stone River, more than fifty
feet above the water, facing River Side Drive, Mrs.
J. V. White has built and furnished a number of rus-tic
cottages, for the accomr jdation of those who want to
"~^
SOffiiu "atiiiic at Liira n,aiiul,-.icalt.iful rcsc; &#8226;
.
- -^
These cottages of two, three and four rooms, are not
mere "shacks," but comfortable, convenient homes in which
to spend a vacation. They are completely furnished for
keeping house, and all the necessary supplies may be pur-chased
at the Springs as needed.
There is entire freedom from restraint or formality.
You are at home, to do as you please; to enjoy the abundant
hospitality of your neighbors, mingle in the simple sports,
and rest and recreate as the spirit moves you. It is only a
step from your door down to the river's edge, and nothing
is more delightful or invigorating than a plunge and swim
in the clean, living water of Stone River.
There are boats, which may be rented for those who de-light
in this form of healthful recreation. There is fishing
&#8212;real, honest sport with an abundant reward for those
who have the patience and skill, as well as love for the sport.
When you are tired, or think you are and do not want
to go to the trouble of cooking, the hotel, or restaurant can
furnish_Vou meals at a reasonable price.
Reservations for cottages stiouIQ be rfiaut cuily, as vhcic-is
always a waiting list. You can rent them by the week,
month, or for the entire season.
Rates and further information may be had by address-ing:
Mrs. J .V. White, 217 East Vine St., Murfreesboro,
Tenn. After May i&#167;th Address Jefferson Springs, Smyrna,
Term.
Phamplet of Jirs. John V. VJhite page 4
35 D
Local imislclans also played there; some of them were Red azid Jimmy Gvyn,
Robert Davis, Granville Harris. J. Beasley Smith was a piano player;
with a young man named S, E. Franklin, he formed the "Dixie Novelty
Orchestra;" they filled many engagements in Middle Tennessee, as well
as at Jefferson Springs. Smith was a well-known, outstanding Tennessee
musician.
On a Saturday night in 1920, Mr. Anderson's hotel burned while many
people were dancing at both halls. Bill McDowell was playing at the
Denny hall. People ran, formed a bucket line from the LiHard Swains'
well, and kept the Denny hall from being destroyed. Bill McDowell
climbed to the roof and worked hard to help the bucket line; the heat
was so intense that his pocket watch burned a large spot on his leg.
Margaret Denny was about six years old at the time and watched the fire
and flreflghting from her grandmother's house, about 100 feet behind the
store and dance hall.
In the era of the big dances at Jefferson Springs, Richmond Sanders
and Jimmy Gwyn often served as "bovmcers" at the Denny Dance Hall. Scoie
of the Smyrna regulars who were on hand for all dances were Carlos Dement,
Bernard Mann, J. B. and Ifenry Randolph ,Sut Pulllas, Joe Harris and Bennle
King, Frank Cheathem Ward, Everett and Bob Waller, Sanders Hibbett, Hollis
Sanders, Walter, John, and Buddy Hoover, John "Lap" Jordan, Earl Coleman,
Sam and Knox Ridley, Sarah and Winston Moore, and many more; also Mr. and
Mrs. Bonner of Murfreesboro.
Some of the songs played and sung and danced to in the heyday of
Jefferson Springs were "Yes, We Have No Bananas," "South," "Small Hotel,"
"Stardust," "The Waltz You Saved for Me," "Make Believe," "I'm Looking
Over a Four Leaf Clover," "Nighty Night," "These Foolish Things," "Moon
over Miami," "The Music Goes Round and Round," "So Rare," "That Old Black
36
Magic," "Me and Ify Shadow," "All of Me," "Sweet Leilani," "iOle^eny
Moon," "Peg of Ity Heart," "Good Nl^t, Sweetheart," and many more.
Some additional items of interest related to Jefferson Springs:
The mail boxes for the campers and dwellers were placed at a central
point, at the intersection of the east-^west road and Lamar Road, where
a large wheel was moxinted on a post, with a rotating hub, so the wheel
could be tttmed by the mail carrier or the mail box owners
In 19h3j the adjacent fields and river side were one of the local sites
for some of the maneuvers of General Fatten 's Third Army . . . .Mr. J.
J. Anderson, when selling any property to a prospective camp owner gave
that owner rights to use of the river and the water from the spring. . .
When the Corps of Qigineers projected the area to be covered by the
waters of the Percy Priest Lake, Gil Olerud bought a log house some&gt;rtiere
in the area and moved it to a location behind his house on Sam Davis
Road. In it, he found a handwritten letter in a cornerstone of that
house. The letter, on a letterhead headed "J. J. Anderson, Nashville,
Tenn.," undated and unsigned, reads:
"It is with pleasure that we give this little history of Jefferson
Springs to be placed in the comer stone of Mrs. F. I. Ward's cottage.
"First, we wish to say that Mrs. F. I. Ward iS quite an asset to
Jefferson Springs with her high Igrpe of character and never-ending energy
and for more than average intellect.
"Jefferson Springs was purchased by J. J. Anderson in 1912 for the
purpose of making a summer and health resort becaiise of the wonderful
stomach water for building vap general run down system.
"At this time, there are forty-three cottages, one hotel, one large
dance hall, and large amusement hall which contains a general store.
Sandwich shop, pool room, and bowling alleys. Also another store owned
37
by Mr. W. G. Denny with bowling alley attached. The cottages are of a
better class than most sranmer resorts have. And this one to be btdlt
on this corner stone is equal or better than any camp here at this tine."
Vlhen, in the 1960*s, the Corps of Engineers acqtiired property ad-jacent
to the river and to the projected elevation of 300 feet, Jefferson
Springs was interred by the deepened waters of the Stones River in the
headwaters of the Percy Priest Lake. After World War II, the resort
had never regained its former popularilgr. Cottages were disposed of,
other resorts opened up to attract people; a few year-round residents
remained tintil I960. The new Jefferson Pike was opened, necessarily
created after the bridges at Old Jefferson and Mbna were removed and a
new bridge was erected across the Lake not far f):x&gt;m the former Jefferson
Springs. Bven Lamar Road, turning north from the area, has few recog-nizable
landmarks.
Where for a number of years, many carefree simmer people came to
drink the black sulphur water, fill their jars and jugs to take home,
getting there by the old slippery path or the later steep concrete stepsj
where people came to cajq&gt; in tents or cottages or stay in one of the
hotels; where they spent happy months swiitming, boating, bowling, dancing;
there is now a broad, smooth expanse of water, maybe 50 feet deep at the
site.
The people who were there sunrier after staimer, old and young, can
look back on good years when many fine and lasting friendships were
made, many h&#163;4)py and good memories inspired. To paraphrase the Sinatra
song, "They were very good years."
3S
ti%^^S
Sulphur Spring 139^- seated- I-:if,s Maybelle Gre^'^ory , Joe 21nck
1st rov; - Mable Smith, Nannie Smit]i,Ella Black, Carlos Smith,
Kate Searcy, Billy Smith, r-Iitchie McLaughlin,ym. Kerritt. 2nd
rov7- Sallie 3atey,Jack Batey, F-rs. Thida Merritt,Pete Searcy,
"ie Batey, Lucy Rucker ,i-';iss V/att Bate-y, Charlie Batey.
Sulphur
Springs
139 '
The Sulphur Spring before 1903, Youns boy in front Carlo;
Smith.
The Sulpur Spring in sunrncr of 191f^ or 1919
40
The Sulphur Spring .?,bout 1914 or 1915. L.-cies h^.ts
on top of spring. Ladies "Svelyn Dickinson ?z Annie Doll
Harris
Steos to the Spring nut in in lite 191 'i- picture rn^dc
about 1915
41
Looking north on Sulpur Springs bridge
Notice the first dance hall building built by
Iir. Joe Clack Cc other campers Ladies are Evelyn Diciiinsor
and Annie De].l Harris
The bridge at Jefferson Sorings -ibout 191&gt;
42
Crossing river before I914 bridge at Jefferson Sorings
Group at the spring -note acron at too of the "Giim"
43
V/m. H. V/hite
1945
on bridge
I'lrs. John V.
V/hite cabin
Vjts. John V.
V/hite cabin
Dictur^ of Vto.H.V/hite
43 A
</dc:description>
<dc:description>A history of Jefferson Springs, also known as Sulphur Springs and Black Sulphur Spring</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.); Sulfur springs; Springs -- Tennessee; Health resorts</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Jefferson</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>39 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-08; mt2011-02-10</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication21ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/26</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>