<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Tennessee College alumnae association</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Sloan, Eugene H.</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 13</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1979</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1910-1919; 1920-1929; 1930-1939; 1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>31
TENNESSEE CGLLEGE ALUMNAE ASSOCIATICM
The Alumnae Association of Tennessee College was organized
on Tuesday, May 31, 1910, with 39 charter members. Officers
elected were Grace Dean, president; Katie Lowman, vice-president;
Alice Eaton Burnett, Secretary and Lucy Alexander, treasurer.
The second meeting of the Association was held in the College
Chapel May 30, 1911. The following officers were elected: Mary
Belle Judson, president; Julia Brown, vice-president; Alice Eaton
Burnett, secretary; Lucy Alexander, treasurer.
After much enthusiastic discussion at this second meeting it
was decided that the Association should start an endowment fund to
be known as the Altomnae Scholarship Fund. The fxind was to be used
for educating worthy girls, who may use the funds interest free
while in college.
The purpose of the Association according to one of several
resolutions that were passed was set forth as follows:
"The purpose of this Association is to promote fellowship
among the Alumnae and to advance the interests and welfare
of Tennessee College by all means within it's power; and
to stand for high ideals and standards, remembering that
the College is what the Alumnae are."
Mary Adelia Strain delivered a homecoming address entitled
"The Warm Heart" at the May 4, 1946 meeting of the Alumnae during
the trauma of transferring of the school to Cumberland University,
Miss Strain reported that, based on incomplete research, 67,14
percent of TWC graduates had married. Almost 10 per cent of the
506 degree graduates of the College had earned graduate degrees.
This number has been greatly increased in recent years.
32
A large nvunber of T}&gt;fC graduates became teachers. Among
those who returned to their Alna Mater to be faculy raeinbers
were Rubye Taylor Sanders^ Violet Gross Erwln, Elizabeth Braswell
Stephens, Eva Inlaw, Mabel Cosby, Freda Alexander Woodfln,
Lillian Paul, Ruth Wood, Eva May Atwood and Sarah Frances Kerr.
Social work, dietetics, medical technology, and varied
careers in music attracted many graduates. Several served in
the women's &#8226;uxiliary forces including the Signal Corp, the Red
Cross and the Nxirse Corps in World War II.
Journalism claimed the attention of several graduates.
Lucretia Penny had short stories published by the Saturday Evening
Post. Lucy Mai Robinson became a cartoonist. Ina Smith published
four works on methods of teaching religion for young people. She
also served as Jvinior-intermediate editor of the Southern Sunday
School Board.
Miss Strain stated, "we are proud of the preachers' wives and
full time church workers. She listed TWC Alumnae who were in church
work in Cuba, China, Palestine, Chile, Nigeria and Lebanon in 1946.
Miss Strain concluded her address with these words:
Tennessee College has as her motto, "Where there is
no vision the people perish," and seeks to inpress
on every young woman the ideal life. A college educa-tion
which does not serve to create a wider interest
in mankind and a deeper synpathy for all hxiraanity is
not worthy of the name. We can only say, with Nicholas
Murray Butler, "God spare us the day when sordid
materialism shall leave no room for the inspiration
of things of the Spirit."
The Tennessee College for Women continues to hold annual
meetings the third week in September of each year. Through
diligent efforts this list of former TWC graduates have been
conpiled.
33
Members of the charter class that graduated Jxine 4, 1912
with Bachelor of Arts degrees were Julia Elizabeth Brovm (Mrs.
Grover Russell, Alice Eaton Burnett (Mrs. E. C. St^ens) , Louise
Hunter (Mrs. Roscoe Meadow), and Ophelia Aterbum Selph (Mrs.
Bright Taylor) . Miss Burnett was the first to receive a
graduate degree, the M. A. from Radcliffe.
There were only two degrees conferred at the June 3, 1913
commencement. They were Lillian Selph and Martha Clarice (Mrs.
W. D. Hoover)
&#8226;
In 1914 degrees were awarded Ada Graves (Mrs. Reginald
Doggett) ,Effle Haynes (Mrs. Will Adrendale) , Cora Dean Hibbs
(Mrs. H. G. Grant), Eula Holt (Mrs. J. D. Knodell), Gladys House
(Mrs. Horace N. Hoore) , Rhoda Early Smith (Mrs. Charles Holland)
,
Virginia Clayton W^^re (Mrs. W. B. Abney) , Myrtle Marguerite Ware
(Mrs. W. L. Wharton) and Nera Varelle White (Mrs. A. C. Shacklett)
.
Gradxiating seniors in 1915 were Sarah Ruth Baty (Mrs. Charles
Battin) , Jennie Bridges (Mrs. J. S. McClanahan) , Verna Fumbanks
(Mrs. James Lassiter) , Frank Byrne Hoskins (Mrs. Leroy Guidry)
,
Bessie May Jones (Mrs. Newton H. Culbertson), Elizabeth Eliott
Lytle (Mrs. Hardin Ragland) , Irene Patterson (Mrs. W, M. Haulsee),
Ina M. smith (Mrs. O. N. Magruder) , Lucia Norwood Watson (Mrs.
Norman Mandes), and Corinne Williams.
Graduating seniors in 1916 were Ruth Virginia Alexander (Mrs.
J. 0. Key), Florie Nell Broach (Mrs. Karl Adolf Warapl) , Laura
Violet Gross (Mrs. R. H. Erwin) , Fay Poole (Mrs. Gardner Backett)
,
and Perraelia Ethyl Richardson (Mrs. Frank Dawson).
34
On May 31, 1917 degrees were conferred on Maude Alexander,
Ozzie Kate Cannon (Mrs. T. H, Briggs) , Esta Davis (Mrs. R. B.
Holt), Luclle Frances Inlow (Mrs. peilx Davis), Lois Bell Jaggers
(Mrs. C. T. Bamhill), Mabel Frances Jaggers (Mrs. Sidney Vincent),
Lois Monie Jarrell (Mrs. Fred Jacobs), Iroa Rebecca Lewis, Belle
HcCandless (Mrs. William Houston Fulton), and Mary Agnes Ray
(Mrs. Jameson Calvin Jones)
&#8226;
in 1918, the graduating seniors were Frances Elizabeth Durham
(Mrs. C. R. Byrn) , Alna Barry Early (Mrs. Albert Abington) , Annie
Lee Hall (Mrs. H. D. Hill), Frieda Bethroann Hays (Mrs. Graves Pate),
Ruth Holt (Mrs. William S. Meyer), Sara Allene Johnson (Mrs. A. R.
Lester), Emily Blanche McConnell (Mrs. Roswell Britton) , Lucile
McSween, Edna Estelle Moore (Mrs. E. E. Tartar) , Ruth Parsons,
Ina Pickens, Frances Stockard Sanders (Mrs. Foster Spain, Jr.),
Hattie Margaret Sory (Mrs. L&#171;miel Waggoner) , Vetries Elizabeth
Tucker (Mrs. S. F. Harwood) , and Nelle Williams (Mrs. Frank Q.
Crockett)
.
Gradxiating seniors in 1919 were Lucy Alexander (Mrs. VPlton
Smith), Georgia Bell Gorman (Mrs. W. D. Howser) , ^falry Hamilton
(Mrs, H, P. Kicklighter) , Ruth Hendricks Hunt, Jennie Jackson
(Mrs. Sam Felts), Pauline McPherson (Mrs. Wheeler Woolfold),
Margaret Anne Nolen, Annie Belle Rion, and Mary Louise Whitlock
(Mrs. W. H. Richeson)
.
In 1920, the graduating seniors were Lena Bonner, Annie Byrn
(Mrs. Earl Roberts), Bess Crutcher (Mrs. Herman Clayton), Mildred
Dodson (Mrs. William McMuriry) , Bess Flowers (Mrs. W. P. Rhoads)
,
35
Elwe Griffith, Lavinia Maney (Mrs. Leslie O. Merrell), Margaret
Johnston, Jessie Sutherland (Mrs. W. N. Johnson) , Alice Timber-lake
(Mrs. Vfalter J. Hills, Jr.), Hilda Tubb (Mrs. S. E. Mahon)
,
and Mattie Williams.
Graduating seniors in 1921 vere Oneida Bass, Margaret Brevard,
Ethel Childress (Mrs. John Clark) , Frances Clark (Mrs. W. R.
Roraine), Agnes Ezell (Mrs. J. Wilkes Leitzell), Eva Inlow,
Elizabeth Leigh (*%-s. S. Carroll White), Lena Martin, Loulie
Pugh, Katherine Rambo (Mrs. C. P. Cox), Annie Mae Vandiver fMrs.
J, W. Summers), and Tennessee Woodson,
Graduating seniors in 1922 were Irene Bartlett (Mrs. J. A.
Morley), Otye Brovn (Mrs. R. S. Bly) , Catherine Clark, Pauline
Crunp (Mrs. J. Rivers Wiggins), Gene Gardner (Mrs. J. A. Rhodes),
mry Weber Glass (Mrs. W. D. Brown), Mary Cathem Hagan (Mrs.
Ivan Pedigo) , Marcella Hall (Mrs. James I. Laten) , Nola Hodges,
Era House (Mrs. R. S. Brumraitt) , Marjorie Jennings (Mrs. W. C.
Mcpherson) , Lorena Mai Martin, cna Mullins, Annette Pierce (Mrs.
Robert Hutton) , Blanche Sandl&#177;n, and Tossie Mae Thorpe.
In 1923, the gradxiating seniors were Mabel Adams (Mrs. R. L.
Searcy, Jr.), Lelya Dority (Mrs. Lester Powres) , Frances Dyer
(Mrs. Leslie Fairfield), Lillie Mae Ford (Mrs. K. T. Edens),
Rose Allan Goodman (Mrs. John Parker) , Ruth Gwaltney, Grady
Hargis (Mrs. Herman Thacker) , Nannie Bell Helm, Elizabeth
Jamison (Mrs. Leighton Ewell), Josephine Rebecca Merritt (Mrs.
Neil Hof stetter) , Bess Mofield, Ruth Officer (**rs. C. H. Dowell)
,
Carrie Nicholls Pugh (Mrs. J. W. Ingram), Katherine Rennolds,
36
Ruth C. Rlngo, Ella MbI Scott, and Weaver Jane Smith (Mrs.
B. T. Barrons).
In 1924, the graduating seniors were Virginia Bagwell (Mrs.
Rollo Every), Josephine Byrona (Mrs. Allen Person), Marlon Conoway
(Mrs. J. S. Mc^tahao) , Eugenia Cook, Julia Doyel (Mrs, Galther
C. Webb), Katherlne Haley, Margaret Hanpton (Mrs John Worley)
,
Lera Jaggers (Mrs. Joe Embry) , Elizabeth Lowry (Mrs, BUI Rowan),
Madge Jackson Manson (Mrs. Will Manson)
, Loren &#187;feGehee (Mrs. W.
H, Couch), Avonia Morton (Mrs. J. B, Martin), Jessie Overall
(Mrs, Emery Nelson), and Eva F, Woodfln (Mrs. B, W. Hawks).
There was only one graduating senior In 1924 who received
a Bachelor of Science degree. She was Doris Jones (Mrs. Oliver
Bratton)
.
On June 2, 1925, the seniors receiving Bachelor of Arts
degrees were Louise Alexander (Mrs. Carlisle Butler), Eleanor
Avent (Mrs, J, C, Bradford) , Ellen Burnett (Mrs Sheridan C,
Cavltt) , Rebecca Clark, Ruth Hutchinson (Mrs, Martin Manion)
,
Flora Douglas McMahon, Nelle Pearcy (Mrs, Everette Lannhom)
,
and Mary Hannah Tucker,
Ch June 2, 1925, the seniors receiving Bachelor of Science
degrees were Ruth Dougherty (Mrs. G. Hughes), Minnie Fairfield
(Mrs. Dyer), Mary Lou Gordon (Mrs. J. L. Davidson), Mary Lou
Gossum (Mrs, Stanley Phillips), Lollie Ruth Kimbrell, and
Elizabeth Walton,
In 1926, the graduating seniors receiving Bachelor of Arts
degrees were Camille Atherton (Mrs, C, W. Thomason) , Susan
37
Beesley (Mrs. Richard Lyle) , Ruth Boone (Mrs. Joseph Crxan)
,
Annabel Bratton (Mrs. T. J. Vfelker) , Mary Lou Derryberry,
Mabel Hamilton (Mrs. Wallace Roberts), Sara Elizabeth King,
Mildred Maclln (Mrs. W. D. Edwards), Jessie Officer (Mrs.
J. W. Crowley), Clara Rennolds, Edwina Rowden (Mrs. D. W. Bruce),
Grace Weaver (Mrs. Charles H. Stevens), Martha Williford (Mrs.
R. C. Tlllinghast) , Ruth Wood (Mrs. Fred Boehne)
.
There were only three Bachelor of Science degrees conferred
on June 2, 1926. They were Mary E. House (Mrs. John B. Maxwell),
Jennie Mai Paris (Mrs. Ray Taylor), and Caroline Wingo.
On June 1, 1927, the graduating seniors receiving Bachelor
of Arts degrees were Frances Caldwell, Esther Carlton (Mrs.
William W. Travis), Frances Cook (Mrs. C. M. Murdock) , Sara
Crockett (Mrs. N. D. Ellis, Jr.), Rose Hillsman (Mrs. Graham
Funderburke) , Adeline King, Aline Lowry, Maycon Martin (Mrs.
J. Irwin Bell), Marjorie McMahan, Mary Parker (Mrs. E. C. Orfen Jr.),
Lillian Paul, Mary Pulliam, Astra Belle Stark (Mrs. Walter Lee
Cathcart) , and Ida Love Taylor (Mrs. R. H, Jones, Jr.).
Only three gradxiating seniors received a Bachelor of Science
degree on June 1, 1927. They were Opal Cole (Mrs. Herbert
Scheldt), Zenobia Quails (Mrs. Leslie Grizzard) , and Cecile
Rhodes (Mrs. Gordon Arnold)
.
Graduating seniors in 1928 receiving Bachelor of Arts degrees
%*ere Frances Allen (Mrs. Baxter E, Hobgood) , Ida Lee Byrn (Mrs.
E. J. Evans), Elizabeth Clark (Mrs. Hubert Coleman), Malinda
Cooper, Jane Howard, Louise Jackson (Mrs. John C. Catlett)
,
38
Nellie Jaggers (Mrs. Clifford N. Wade) , Frances King (Mrs.
Frank Johns) , Dorothy Lee (Mrs. Paul Dodd), Anne Raby,
Luzelle SisX (Mrs. Hap Babbs) , Elizabeth A. Stephens (Mrs.
John J. Steitz) , Elizabeth B. Stephens (Mrs. Sam Stephens),
Mary Stephens (Mrs. P. A. Danielson) , and Maurine Todd (Mrs.
Ed, H, Cherry)
.
Graduating seniors in 1928 receiving Bachelor of Science
degrees were Martha Evans (Mrs. Cecil Neville) , Rebecca Hancock
(Mrs. R. N. Corley) , Elizabeth Harwood, Rachel Lewis (Mrs.),
Mary Buford Martin (Mrs. Robert Huddleston) , Lucile McCarley
(Mrs* A. Yakimovich) , Hortense McClellan (Mrs, Paul M. Glenn)
,
Mary Beth Morris, Kathleen Pogue (Mrs. C. G. Tranthan) , Mary
Belle Robinson, Ola ftee Ryan (Mrs. M. F. Gardner), Louella
Travis (Mrs. George Huber) , and Lola Mai Upchurch,
In 1929, the seniors receiving a Bachelor of Arts were Eva
May Atwood, Martha Elizabeth Bernard (Mrs. Samuel M. Hammond)
,
Danna Binder (Mrs. L. P. Vfhorton) , Susie Cardwell, Jean Carlton
(Mrs. Harold C. Baggett) , Nancy Cheely (Mrs. William B. Cole),
Buist Dement (Mrs. J. W. Smythe) , Mary Gutherberg (Mrs. Richard
H. Denham) , Reba McClellan (Mrs. Marvin Whitley), Sadie Mai
McMahan, Elizabeth Moss (Mrs. Bill Palmer), Lucy Mai Robinson,
Ernestine Smith (Mrs. Frank t\. Lewis), and Lane Walker (Mrs.
John Wilson)
.
Graduating seniors receiving a Bachelor of Science degree
in 1929 were Catherine Boyd, Elsa Ann Butcher, Helen Elizabeth
Caii^jbell (Mrs. Howard Kirksey) , Winnie Ruth Currey (Mrs. R. M.
39
Johnson), Virginia Fulghum (Mrs. Howard Holland), Sarah Hardeman,
Sara Hawkins (Mrs Blevins Rittenberry) , Lucile Hines, Ruth Johns
(Mrs. J. P. McCluskey, Jr.), Rosa Jordan (Mrs. Roi Cason)
,
Dorothy King, Cornelia Leatherman, Marg.-^ret .'-tetthews ( Mrs. Raymond
Beatele), Grace Ann Moore, Christine Owen, Clarf&gt;bel Pearcy (Mrs.
Allen C. Barrett), Marjorie :;nith, and Verdry D. Vaaghan.
In 1930, the seniors who received a Bachelor of Arts degree
were Ophelia Anderson (j^s. Joe Wesl Williams), Martha Gannaway,
Ann Gannaway, Louise Hartsf ield (Mrs. Jack Ross) , I.ura Hiygs
(Mrs. J. Vernon Red) , Fleeta Hudson (Mrs. Russell Haskins) ,Sara
Jackson (Mrs. John Cason), Vera Johnson (I-ir^. Ewell I ollard) ,
Ophelia Moore, Mabel Nichols (i-lrs.John S. Harris), Elizabeth
Pyland (Mrs. Jesse Porter), Virginia Rion (Mrs. Lee Covington),
and Dorothy Williams (Mrs. Jamt-s Boykin) .
In 1930, the seniors v&#187;ri'&gt; received n P.achclor of Science degree
were Frances Bunnell (.Mrs. R. J. DusVirk), Frances Cary (firs.
F. W. Kittrell) , Vera Coleman, Clara ''ae Crockett (:4rs. R. M.
Kirkland) , Ruth Cunningham, yrances Ewlon, .^ttye Jackson,
Fausteen Jones (Mrs. Kenneth Whitt ington) , ?j.lzabeth Lannora,
Rachel Raby, Cleo Reed (firs. R. E. &lt;:arpenter) , Julia Smith,
Lanta Weaver ("r^.), and Frances Wooc.
Graduating seniors rereivinc r. f'achelor )f Aits degree in
1931 were Flora liaggett (Mrs, James Cox), Milured Clark (Mrs.
A. C. Gibson), Robbie Coffey, Wendell Corban, 3essie Fetzer
(Mrs. W. L. Williams), Margaret Jennings, .'-iary Virginia Fcvfll
(^"Irs. Mary Virginia Morgan), Kathleen Robinson (Mrs. J. n.
Sullivan), and Virginia Short (iirj. John Gately) .
40
Graduating seniors receiving a Bachelor of Science degree
in 1931 were Lorene Ashvorth, Clara Bragg (Mrs. V. A. Conley)
,
Janet Gonce, Rebecca Jaggers (Mrs. Richard Carrigan) , Neena
Johnson, Allie Manson, Pauline Stark.
In 1932, the seniors receiving a Bachelor of Arts degree
were Virginia Avey, Virginia Byrn (Mrs. Ro^er Sanders), Carol
Cox (Mrs. George Brandon), Nettie Dillard, Helen Dunn (Mrs.
Beckman) , Helen Hancock (Mrs. John D. Sadler, Jr.), Roberta
Harris, Nancy Kirtley (Mrs. Fred Kerr), Theresa McCutcheon (Mrs.),
Elizabeth McNeil (Mrs. W. L. VJhitehurst) , Frances Potter, my
Robertson, Helen Roth (Mrs.), Corinne Stevens (Mrs. J. E. Arm-strong),
Annie Mary Sweet (Mrs. W. R. Rollins), and Mary Alice
Wood.
In 1932, the seniors receiving a Bachelor of Science degree
were Louise Clark, Frances Crocker (Mrs. Mack Savage) , Mora
Fisher (Mrs. James Pernell) , Lizzie Sue Hampton (Mrs. Leo Brown),
Mildred Jeffers, Lucile Morgan (Mrs. Harry Cartwright), Allie
Lee Pearcy, and Helen Roberts.
Graduating seniors receiving a Bachelor of Arts degree in
1933 were Mary Anderson, Ellnar Harris, Temple Rogers Harris,
Martha Johns, Nekoda McMahan, Naomi Rhodes (Mrs, Malcom Smith)
,
Anibel Rogers, and Geneva Springer.
Graduating seniors receiving a Bachelor of Science degree
in 1933 were Kitty Alexander (Mrs. Bingham) , Elizabeth Beasley
(Mrs. R, S. Robinson), Elizabeth Farkes (Mrs. R. A. HcWilliams),
Emily Rawlins (Mrs. Tip Allensworth) , Christine Sanders (Mrs.
Sam Collins), Alta Thomas, and Lorene Tilford.
41
In 1934, the seniors receiving a Bachelor o&#163; Arts degree
were Mary D. Carey, Carolyn Cook (Mrs. Eugene Holloway) , Mabel
Cosby, Frances Davis (Mrs. Fred Castleroan) , Ada Hanlcins, Mary
Frances Johnson (Mrs. Boyd Coleman) , Louise Kerr, Laura Lax,
Mary Nelle Nail (Mrs. Ed Morris), Lillian Nickens, and
Margaret Dean Robinson.
In 1934, the seniors receiving a Bachelor of Science degree
were Edna Ruth Davis (Mrs. Jack Bowman), Mary Kate Ladd, Frances
Roy (Mrs. Robert Mason), Dorothy Schmidt (Mrs. Leon McCauley)
,
Martha Young (Mrs. Albert Wright).
Graduating seniors in 1935 receiving a Bachelor of Arts
degree were Ruth Louise Albanese, Louise Bryan (Mrs. Louis T.
Finney) , Mary Virginia Farrar, and Freda Alexander Woodfin (Mrs.
James Woodf in).
Graduating seniors in 1935 receiving a Bachelor of Science
degree were Wilmoth Dean (Mrs. Fred Clinard) , Evelyn Douglas
Fite (Mrs. Donald Anderson) , and Leonora McKissack (Mrs. Robert
E. Ikard)
.
In 1936, the seniors receiving a Bachelor of Arts degree
were Niva Delores Brewer, Katherine Brooks (Mrs. James Smith)
Florence Cox (Mrs. T, S. McFerrin) , Nancy Lou Roth, Marguerite
Sugg, and Martha Nancy Trevathan.
In 1936, the seniors receiving a Bachelor of Science degree
were Julia Mai Edwards, Margaret Fisher (Mrs, Jarris Kerr),
Rebecca Fisher, Kate Ellen Gruver, Maribeth Keeling, Virene
Maddox, Lurleen Bugg McMlnn (Mrs. Allan McMinn) , Pauline Neal,
Naomi Redding, Grace Savage, and Evelyn Frank Sloan (Mrs.
Lillard Sloan)
.
42
There were only &#163;lve Bachelor of Arts degrees conferred
on June 2, 1937. These included Katherlne Lucille Bass, Ruth
Webb Brandon (Mrs. Ray Brandon) , Mary Elizabeth Duckworth,
Mrs. Georgia Taylor Parks, and Lillian Walker Stickney (Mrs.
R. C. Wilson) .
There were six Bachelor of Science degrees conferred on
June 2, 1937. These included Anna Davant, Mary Elizabeth Davis
(Mrs. W. C. Babbs), Elizabeth Drake, Christine Johnson, Harriet
A. Kelley (Mrs. H. C. Bennett), and Reraa Love (Mrs, Richard Davis),
Graduating seniors in 1938 receiving a Bachelor of Arts
degree were Helen Canibron, Maj^orie Cambron, Mrs. Ruth Dance
Cainbron, Majorie Roix Campbell (Mrs. Sumpter Canpbell) ,
Elizabeth Curtis, Beverlie Marcia Derminer, Lillian Edmondson,
Lenora Edwards, Josephine Hunphrey, Iris Mae Johnson, Georgia
Lee Lowe (Mrs. Glenn Sanderson) , Ruth Irene Merriam, Christine
Mueller, Anna Mary Parker, Elsie Robertson, Beatrice Mary
Schilling, and Grace Emma Williams.
Those receiving the Bachelor of Science degree in 1938 were
Mary Frances Cotham, Ida Lenora Davis, Jessie B. Gann (Mrs.
Rudolph Manassco) , Jane Mayo, Christine Parker, Harriet Allen
Peach (Mrs. Llwellen McCord) , Margaret Putman, Mary Hurt Satter-white
and Earnestine Smith (Mrs. John Williams)
.
In 1939 seniors who received the Bachelor of Arts degree
were Elizabeth Lynn Bingham, Nona Evelyn Boitnott (Mrs. J. C.
Meserve) , Winifred Bumpass, Dorothy Burns, Willine Chadwick,
Kathleen Deakins, Loretta McFadden Duckworth, Ruth Allene Evans,
Mary Douglas Holman, Jean Kirtley, Dorothy Noland, Marion Frances
Smith.
43
There vere only four Bachelor of Science degrees conferred
in 1939. They included Mary Ellen Boyd, Maude Dev Holmes,
Estelle Hooper, and Edvrlna Key (Mrs. Gordon Oldham).
Members of the 1940 class were Kate Dodson, Sarah Louise
Donaldson, Mary Alice Hall, ^fary Elizabeth Hardby, Clara Harper,
Earllne Harris, Carole Hass, Ethel Herron, Betty Cella Jackson,
Maurice Jackson, Nancy Malone, Edith Palmer, Rachel Sisk,
Margaret Frances Wilson, Roseanite Faith Woolson and Louise
Young.
Graduating in 1941 vrere Gladys Bugg, Ellen Avery Carlton,
Frances Davis, Mary Vicie Dillon (Mrs. John Scott) , Myrtle
Fleenor, Margaret Groom, Sue Harrison, Mary Lou O' Bryan, Louise
Bilbrey, Virginia Christian, Minerva Cowan, Eugenia Gaffin,
Duerell Gray. Lorraine Tanner, Harriet Townley, Virginia Groves,
Mary Gene Hobbs, Evelyn Howell, Billie Kuykendall, Judith Peace,
Lorraine Porterm, Ruth Thomas, Lois Walls and Christine Young
were 1942 graduates.
Members of the 1943 class included Christine Hargis Parker,
Sara Frances Kerr, Inez McBroom, Margaret Holly, Virginia Adkins,
Marie Holman, Louise Thomas Kraus, Virginia Thompson, Mary Lee
VanSickle, and Evelyn Floy West.
The members of the 1944 class were Elizabeth Furgason,
Frances Graves, Pauline Rogers, Mary Catherine Manley, May Jones,
Nelle Smith and Rebecca Eddinger.
First graduates in the three year accelerated degree program
were in the class of 1946. The members of the class were Monita
Benson, Lotta Burchfield, Barbara Jane Copeland, Ida Dunaway,
44
Mary Frances Hayes, Helen Helton, Miriam Jardine, Jewell Jones,
Kathryn Kerr, Doris McCall, Mary Lucille Parchment, Frances
Travis, and Evelyn Willard.
Degrees awarded at 1946 final program, reproduced on page
31 of this article included Rita Marie Bentley, Margaret Lanier
Dxmaway, Mary Elizabeth Smith, Elizabeth Wright, Aletha Waline
Baker, Lucy Carmine Boyd, Alta Lee Grimes, Peggy Schneider
Havens, Dorothy Clark Hendrix, Margaret Jackson, Evelyn Purdue
Sinclair, Mary Fay Pierce, Carol Porter, Mar y Bedford Rogers,
Effie Lee Smith Miller, Emma Anderson Towns, and Dorothy Pxirdue.
ACKNOWLEDGMENT
The author is indebted to many individuals and sources for
information and aid in compiling the history of Tennessee College
for Women.
Miss Ethel Herron, for many years, secretary of the Alumnae
Association opened her files and provided yearbooks and pictures,
Mrs. Lawrence Freeman, librarian for the First Baptist
Church of Murfreesboro, contributed important information,
Ida Dunaway Read provided editorial assistance.
Mrs. Thomas L. Craddock typed the manuscript.
Photographs were reproduced from yearbooks by Dr. Bealer
Smotherman.
History of Tennessee College for Women by Tommy Lowe Curtis
was the basis of much source material, Frances Allen Hobgood,
45
Minerva Cowan Shacklett and Catherine Clark vere among those
who made valuable contributions and suggestions.
Pillar and Ground by Dr. Homer Plttard and records of
the Tennessee Baptist Convention and Cumberland University have
been noted in the text.</dc:description>
<dc:description>A history of the Tennessee College for Women alumnae association, presented as an accompaniment to the preceding history of Tennessee College for Women</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Universities and colleges -- Tennessee; Women--Societies and clubs</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>alumnae associations; Tennessee College for Women</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>29 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-01</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication13ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/125</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>