<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>History of Stones River Presbyterian Church 1816 - 1973</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Couch, Ester</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 7</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1976</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>19th century; 20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>72
HISTORY OF STONES RIVER PRESBYTERIAN CHURCH
1816-1973
by Ester Couch
The Stones River Presbyterian Church, U.S., located In
the 17th District, Rutherford County, Tennessee, near the east
branch of Stones River, was organized April 1, I816, by the
Rev. Jesse Eagleston Alexander. It was the out-growth of a
camp meeting previously held about three miles from the present
church on the road to Milton. After meeting for some years
in a small log building on the opposite side of the road from
the present church, Jacob Wright, whose wife, Becky, was a
member of the Stones River Church, gave the land on which Stones
River and Antioch Churches are built; Antioch is a Church of
Christ, of which Mr. Wright was a member. The deed was recorded
in 1848.
A big log building with twelve corners was built just east
of the present church. This building was replaced by a frame
building on the same ground in I878, and the log building was
torn away. An addition of Sunday School rooms was added about
1954 or 1955.
This building is in good state of repair. Worship ser-vices
are held each Sunday, and other activities, as the program
of the church directs.
The following were charter members of the church:
James, Eleanor, William and Isabell McKnight
Joseph and Jane Knox
Charles and Polly Ready
Joseph and Jane Weatherspoon
Charles and Jane Porterfield
Polly Weatherspoon
Peggy, David and Polly Andrews
John and Sarah Henderson
John, Peggy, Moses, and Rixney McKnight
John M., Peggy, and Abigal McKnight
73
Some of the ministers who have served as pastors:
Rev. Jesse Eagleton Alexander, E. T. Brantley and
his son, Erskine
Rev. Thompson
Rev. Mosley
Rev. A. J. Crane, I9OI-I902
Rev. T. A. Patton, I903-I907
Rev. T. R. Riley
Rev. W. W. Patton
Rev. Mr. Johnson
Rev. W. H. Matherson
Rev. William Janes
Rev. Wythe M. Peyton, Jr., (present pastor)
Four men from this church were ordained ministers:
Erskine Brantley, Walter Creson, Charlie Ralston, and Henry
Sneed. They helped to carry the Work of God to other parts
of Tennessee and to other states.
It might be interesting to note that Frank and Silva
Brantley, descendants of Brantley slaves, attended preaching
services regularly until their deaths in early 1900's.
by Esther Couch
197^
</dc:description>
<dc:description>A very short history of Stones River Presbyterian Church, including information about some attendees, ordained ministers, location and organization</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.) -- History; Stones River (Tenn.); Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A.</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Churches;  Stones River Presbyterian Church</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>LaVergne</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>3 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-15; mt2011-05-20</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication07ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/79</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>