<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>The state capitol 1819 - 1826</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Ray, Alice N.</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 11</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1978</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1810-1819; 1820-1829</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>THE STATE CAPITOL
1819-1826
By Alice N. Ray
The history of a town can be preserved in different ways, and Murfrees-boro
can certainly share in the architectirral, religious, and cultural forms
with its historic courthouse, many beautiful hones, and lovely churches.
There is a variety of architecture that contributes greatly to the rj.chness
of the tovm.
A unique place in this commcjiity is the Old City Cemetery, which houses
the foundation of one of the most historic buildings in this area. Not only
was it the First Presbyterian Church, but the State Capitol as well. This
was the kind of building often referred to in the early eighteen hundreds ass
a "Meeting House". During this time, there was usually a structure in each
town that seized for regular Svmday services and for town meetings as well.
In times of trouble or emergency, people would meet there to help each
other. Much can be learned about a town when we study these churches.
Here people would come for every purpose, thus, they were called "Meeting
Houses". "Going to meeting" beca'aas a common phrase for attending church.
The old foundation of East Vine Street is that of the First Presbyter-ian
Church, founded in 1812 as the Murfree Springs Church with eighteen
members. In 1818 the name of the congregation vras changed to First Presby-terian,
and a new building was erected. TMs new building stood until it
was demolished by the Union army in 1864.
The building was constructed of hand-made brick with the exterior
similar to the larger meeting houses of the period. Builders of these ear-ly
ftructv.res to.^k pride in their crnft ?.nd \s'orkEianship. Thev used the best
materials available, and, as a result, many of thcco biiilding hnve ctood
for hundreds of years.
In 1779 Asher Benjamin published a book. The Country Builders Assistant .
In this book there appeared a "Design for a Church". Up until th5.s time, no
one really knew or had any guide lines as to vrhat a church really should
look like. This design was used throughout New England, where the author
v/as bom and the book was published. Many of these buildings still stemd
today and can readily be recognized by the three front doors, two rows of
windows on each side, octagonal bell tov/ors, balconies, raised pulpits,
and many other features described in this book. They became known as the
"Benjamin Design".
The biiilding here on East Vine Street certainly had many of the Benja-min
features. In New England the buildings differed in the exterior
materials, since weather board was used most often instead of brick or
stone as was the custom in the south.
Since the foundation is all that remains for us to see of this historic
structure, we are able to learn about the appearance from the specifications
that Dr. Ernest Hooper was successfu-1 in obtaining from the National Archives
in Washington, D.C. The foundation vrns two feet wide of hammered stone four
feet high with two feet above the ground. The stone was laid with lime and
sand mortar. The lime was slacked in a pit on the site. Stone was usually
quarried in the general vacinity of the building site. To transport stone
from the quarry to the site required a lot of labor and ingenuity. Larger
stones were secured underneath wagons by log chains to avoid much heavy
lifting, while smaller stones v/ere hauled in v/agon beds. Stone was hammer
dressed and cut by skilled stone masons. During this period of time stone
Sinnott, Edmund W., Meeting House and Church in New En^qland . p. 80-89.
masons made and sharpened most of the tools that wore used to face stono.
A greater amount of skill was required to cut and face sillo&gt; oteno, and
lintels, because they had to be cut to exact dinencions.
The walls were seventeen inches thick of hand"=-mado brick and laid
v/ith sand and lime iKjrtar. The exterior walls were of a high grade, hard
brick usually made near the site. Brick masons not only laj.d the brick,
but they made them and built the ld.ln as vrell. To mako brick a pit was
dug and clay was taken directly from clay banks and thrown into the pit
with the proper amoiont of water. A large wheel operated on a shaft and
was drawn by a horse or several laborers through this pit to thoroughly
mix the clay and water. The clay mixtuTe was then pressed into brick molds
and turned out on boards to air dry, VJhen the desired number of bricks
were mad^ the kiln was built and fired at a very high temperature until
the bricks were burned hard. This firing usually required several days
and nights. The bricks nearest the fire vrcro the hardest and were used
on the exterior, while the softer ones were used for Interior walls.
Windows along each side of the building vrero in two rows with five in
each row, making ten windows on each side. These windows were eight feet
high and three feet six inches vide vrith sills and lintols of hammer-dressed
limestone. Blinds or shutters were used on all vrindows, as was the custom
at this time.
The roof was put on of heavy material, with the rafters and beams
being made of eight by ten inch timbers. Sheathing was one inch thick and
was covered with cedar shingles. Ifeking shingles was a craft that required
special tools that most often were made by the craftsman, himself. Some
2
Andels, Masons and Builders Guide. Vol 1, p. 11-13.
3
The Foxfire Book . Vol. 1, p. 33-52.
tools used were steel wedges, go-devils, froes, mallets, gluts, mauls,
poleaxes, and broadaxes. Large trees were used for marring the bolts that
were cut into boards the correct length and then finished into sh5.ngles.
Dressing boards to make the finished shingle required a shaving horse
and a draw knife. A craftsman could rive over one thousand boards a
day, and the average building required about five thousand shingles.
One of the most interesting parts of this structure was the entrsmces
with the large stone platforms reaching six feet long and being two feet
wide and eight inches thick. Steps were over four feet long at each of
the three front doors. The folding doors had a circular sash, and each
opening had an entablature supported by pilasters at each side. This made
a very attractive entrance, similar to the Benjamin design.
Towers were traditional, and cupolas and be].l towers with steeples
were almost alv/ays used. The tower had a cornice, as well as the remain-der
of the building. Tlie bell tower was octagon shaped.
Plaster was used on the inside vjalls with two or three coats usually
being the custom. The final coat is very smooth and white, and it was
often used this way and then painted later.
The vestibule reached across the entrance end with a partition that
had two folding doors that separated it from the main part of the building.
Two large colvuims supporting the back side of the towf?r were near the fold-ing
doors. Also In the vestibule were the two winding stair ways that were
used to reach the galleries along each side and across the front of the
bxiilding. The galleries vxere supported by turned columns ten feet high,
and the fronts were three fset high with panel v;o:&#187;-k, pilasters, and molded
caps. The side galleries were laid out in steps wide enough to have pews
set on each step. The front gallery was arranged for the choir and for an
orpan
.
Pews were fitted to the space in the three sections foi'ined by the
tv/o aisles. They had panels in the back with rounded top rails. The
ends of the pews were also paneled with scroll caps, and each pevr had
a panel door.
Pulpits being focal points were, naturally, made very attractive,
and the one here was no exception. It had a panel front and pedestal
and was elevated about four feeto The pulpit coiild be reached by two
small circular stairs on each side. The altar, stair rails, and newel
post were all cade of walnut.
With a bviilding so stately and near the center of town, it seems
logical that it would be selected to become the State Capitol, when the
need arose. Both houses of the General Assembly could make use of this
peirticular building, since the Senate could use the gallery for their
meetings, and the Lower House could meet on the first floor.
A number of interesting acts that concerned ^-brfreesboro and Ruther-ford
County were acted upon diiring the time Murfree&#171;boro was the capital
of Tennessee.
A special session of the Legislature was begun on July 22 eind ended
on August 24, 1822, An Act was passed to divide the state into districts
for the election of Representatives in Congress. At this time Rutherford
County was placed in the seventh district along with Davidson and Williamson
Counties.
On August 17, 1822 authority was given Rutherford County to levy a
property tax to obtain the amoiuit of $6,000 to build a courthouse. The
levy was to continue for three years and was levied as follows: 37^^ en
each 100 acres of land; 75^ on. each town lot; 25^ on each white pall; 50^
on each black pall; twice the season price on each stallion; ^10 on each
pleasure carriage; $5 on each two-v^heel vehicle; sir.d ^10 on each ordinary
where liquor was sold.
On August 23, 1822 an Act was passed to create a lottcryj alBo on
this same date, Acts ooncerning marriage, divorce, end some on the rights
of vjomen were acted upon. Another Act on August 23, 1822 provided for
payment of expenses for certain trials. The amount of $200 was paid to
James K. Polk, clerk of the court, for his services. Not only did this
clerk marry a Murfreesboro girl, Jiiss Sarah Childress, but he became gov-ernor
of Tennessee, a Representative in Congress, and our nation's eleventh
president.
In a special session of the General Assembly held from September 15
through November 29, 1823, one of the first bills to be acted upon was an
Act to Preserve the Purity of Elections. In this Act a person could be
fined for threatening a voter ^Jith spirituous liquors, wagering cr betting
anything of value, and the fine coiald be $100. The first voting precinct
was authorized in October, 1823. Many other Acts concerning Rutherford
County were acted upon during the years the General Assembly met here. It
was moved to Nashville in early 1826. While here the Acts were recorded
on a Franklin Hand Press borrowed from a Nashville printing office.
This brief account of the activities carried -&gt;i at the vmique little
"Meeting House" on East Vine Street, v;hile it was the Capitol of Tennessee,
has been taken in part from C G. Henderson's The Storj &#163;&#163; Murfreesboro .
published in I929 by the News Banner Publishing Germany in Murfreesboro,
Tennessee. The book had long '&#8226;;8en out of print, but through the efforts
of the R'-therfurd County Historical Society and the generosity of Mr. Jesse
Beesley, a limited number of these books have been reprinted and are avail-able
through the Society, P. 0. Box 906, Murfreesboro, Tennessee 37130.
</dc:description>
<dc:description>Describes the time in Tennessee's history when Murfreesboro was the state's capitol</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.) -- History; Murfreesboro (Tenn.) -- History; Capitols</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Tennessee state capitol</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>11 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-24; mt2011-02-28</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication11ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/59</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>