<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Rutherford County Historical Society publication no. 4</dc:title>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1974</dc:date>
<dc:description>Digitized by the Internet Archive
in 2010 with funding from
Lyrasis IVIembers and Sloan Foundation
http://www.archive.org/details/publication04ruth
7
NOT TO Um LIBRARY
RUTHERFORD COUNTY HISTORICAL SOCIETY
PUBLICATION NO. 4
FALL, 1974
THE COVER: Built in the 1820's, the Dr. James Maney home and its
family have been closely interwoven with the early history of Ruther-ford
County. A focal point for Confederate Colonel Nathan Bedford
Forrest's raid on the town's garrison, July 14, 1862, the home and
outlying resources served both armies, according to which military
force was ensconsed in the town at the time. The "bottomless" spring
in a declivity east of the house was a source of supply for the water
wagons of both armies.
Published by
Rutherford County Historical Society
Murfreesboro, Tennessee
1974
RUTHERFORD COUNTY HISTORICAL SOCIETY
PUBLICATION NO. 4
FOREWORD
Publication No. 4 has three most attractive features. In the
first place, the 1810 Census of Rutherford County is carried in full.
This rare document, tediously extracted and prepared for publication
by Henry Wray, is a bonanza within itself. Then, there's a sampling
of how artists saw the Battle of Stones River and events related to
it. And, in the third place. Miss Mary Hall's saga of Readyville
records for posterity valuable information that is rapidly being
obliterated through the passage of time. I regard our publications
as being one of our strongest reasons for existence as a Society.
Dr. Fred Brigance
President, Rutherford
County Historical Society
-/b-01v)93
RUTHERFORD COUNTY HISTORICAL SOCIETY
PUBLICATION NO. 4
published by the
Rutherford County Historical Society
OFFICERS
President Dr. Fred Brigance
Vice-President Mrs. Sue Ragland
Secretary &amp; Treasurer Mrs. Dotty Matheny
Recording Secretary Mrs. Frances Clayton
Interim Recording Secretary Mrs. Florence V. Davis
PUBLICATION NO. 4 (Limited Edition--300 copies) is distributed
to all members (in good standing) of the Rutherford County Historical
Society along with the monthly newsletter, "Frow Chips." Surplus
copies of PUBLICATION NO. 4 may be obtained at $3.00 per copy.
All correspondence concerning additional copies and information
about membership should be addressed to
D. M. Matheny
1434 Diana Street
Murfreesboro, TN 37130
Those desiring to contribute articles and/or pictures to future
issues should contact
Henry G. Wray
104 McNickle Drive
Smyrna, TN 37167
CONTRIBUTORS
The Rutherford County Historical Society gratefully acknowledges
the efforts of those who provided material for Publication No. 4 .
These include:
Henry G. Wray - County Archivist who spent countless hours in
reading, copying, and arranging for publication the Rutherford
County Census of 1810 .
Miss Mary Hall - For preserving in a historical format the story
of Readyville, Tennessee. One must remember that the progeny of
Charles Ready, later Readyville, was strongly considered as the
site for the county seat in 1810. Incensed that his offer of
his property was rebuffed. Ready refused to sign the petition
and resolution confirming the choice of Captain William Lytle's
land. He resolved to develop Readyville into a strong rival of
the new seat. However, the establishment of Cannon County in
1856 divided his land into two segments and his dream never
quite materialized.
RUTHERFORD COUNTY HISTORICAL SOCIETY
PUBLICATION NO. 4
1974
Contents
History of Readyville Page
By Miss Mary Hall 1
Artists Depict Battle of Stones River
From Walter King Hoover's Collection 35
Census of 1810 and List of Taxpayers not
in Census prepared by Henry G. Wray 41

* Charter Members
y/ Junior Member
NOT TO LEAVE m\m\
DATE DUE
ivl S'?5
'.It 1 _ we i ft
JEOIOO
9*&#187;
OCTl J 2002
PCTv
mii ?'0(j:i
m^"^^
MAP '
IC
^G'5 '. u..
Ifp &#171;9tiiff
NOV 23 209
f\M 5 \ Ml
Ml^^
DEC 4 20( 3
HIGHSMITH # 45220
3 3082 00527 4583
976.857
R931p
v.U
76-01593
Rutherford coimty historical
TITLE
society. Publication no. U
Fall, 197U
LIBRARY
MIDDLE TENNESSEE STATE UNIVERSITY
MURFREESBORO, TENNESSEE</dc:description>
<dc:description>This volume contains several articles, each of which is treated separately in this collection and can be searched individually</dc:description>
<dc:description>History of Readyville -- Artists Depict Battle of Stones River -- Census of 1810 and List of Taxpayers not in Census </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Stones River, Battle of, Murfreesboro, Tenn., 1862-1863; Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Periodical</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>210 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-15</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication04ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/94</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>