<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Petition of William Cocke for Revolutionary War pension</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Cocke, William</dc:creator>
<dc:contributor>King, Mrs. Hughey</dc:contributor>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 16</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1981</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1770-1779; 1780-1789; 1830-1839</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>PETITION
of
WILLIAM COCKE
for
REVOLUTIONARY WAR PENSION
-furnished by Mrs. Hughey King
West Tennessee # 138 38
William Cocke of Rutherford Cotinty in the State of Tennessee who
was a private in company commanded by Captain Talbot of the Regiment
commanded by Col, Nelson in the Va. line for six months
Inscribed on the roll at the rate of 20 dollars per annum to commence
on Uth day of March I83I.
Certificate of Pension issued 26 of June I832 and sent to Alfred
Johns, Murfreesborough.
Declaration in order to obtain the benefit of the act of Congress
passed 7th June I832
State of Tenn.
Rutherford County
County Court August I832
On the 2Uth day of August 1832 personally appeared in open comrt before
Henry Trott, James C. Mitchell and Vamer ?_ Cowin Justice of said court now
setting William Cocke a resident of said county and state, aged seventy two
years who being first duly sworn according to law doth on his oath make the
following declaration in order to obtain the benefits of the act of Congress
passed 7th June I832
.
That he entered the service of the United States on the 10th day of
September 1779 under Capt. Talbot in the county of Bedford and state of
Virginia, and that in a day or two afterwards the conpany of Capt. Talbot
was marched through the city of Richmond to Williams Berg in the state of
70
Virginia where they remained about two weeks \mder the conmand of Col&#187;
Nelson. Col. Nelson inarched
Capt. Talbot's conpany with one other company then stationed at
Williams Berg to York Town ;riiose distance apart is about 12 miles. They
remained at York Town something like seven weeks. When we arrived at York
Town there was but a small force remaining most of them being discharged
before we arrived. During the whole of ottr stay at York three men of war
belcaiging to the British fleet were anchored in the mouth of York River
within sight of York Town.
From York Town Capt. Talbot's con55any was marched back to Williams Berg
lAere they remained 2 or 3 days thence through Richmond back to Bedford
County. No engagements took place during this tour. In this csu&#187;5)aign I
served three months, but do not know exactly what time we were discharged
but know that we received 3 months pay.
Again about 2 years afterward in the month of February 1781 as well as
he recollects he enlisted as a volunteer in county of Bedford, State of
Virginia under Capt. William Jones whose conqiany was attached to Col. Lynch 's
Regiment, and in Col. I^ynch's Regiment which consisted of 500 men, he marched
through Halifax county State of Va. crossed Dan River at Irvin's ford thence
into Caswell County State of North Carolina where he joined Gen'l Green..
We found Col. Washington at the head of the horse under Gen'l Green.
These forces were in that section of the state for sometime and went thence
toward Guilford courthouse. He was at the battle of Guilford which he says
was fought on the 15 th day of March in the year 1781. The circumstances
attending the battle that made the most inqsression upon his mind were these
(to wit) that Col. Green was commander in chief. Col. Washington commanded
the calvary and if he is not mistaken Gen'l Lawson commanded the militia.
(Kevins ? ) was present and as he understood was wounded in the thigh and
his horse was shot under him. The captains belonging to Col. Lynch 's
71
Regiment, Capt. Jones, Moon and Helium were slain at the battle of Guilford.
The British forces remained upon the ground after the engagement and the
American forces evacuated in confusion about 8 or 10 miles north of
Gilford C. H.
He does not recollect the precise time when he was discharged twt thinks
'twas about the last of April; that he received pay for 3 months. He was
discharged at a place called (Duck River ?). about UO or 50 miles south of
Guilford C. H, He does not recollect to have received any other than a
verbal discharge.
Again In August about the 1st he believes 1781, he volimteered into the
United States service in the county of Bedford, state of Va. under Col,
Quails. They remained in the county of Bedford and Pittsylvania engaged in
collecting beefs, putting them in pastures and branding them upon the hams
with the letters U. S. The cattle were to be sent to the army which was
some where in the neighborhood of Richmond. He was in no engagement during
this term of service. He was discharged sometime between the Ist and 15th
of November of the same year. He does not recollect to have received any
but a verbal discharge. He has no documentation evidence and knows of no
person whose testimony be can procure who can testify to service.
He hereby relinquishes every claim whatever to a pension or annutity
except, the present and declares that his name is not on the pension roll of the
agency of any state. Sworn to the day and year aforesaid.
)
) s/ Vfilliam Cocke
s/ J. R. Lau^lin )
We, Martin Clark a clergyman residing in the County of Rutherford,
State of Tennessee and Granville S. Crockett residing in the same do hereby
certiiy that we are well acquainted with William Cocke who has subscribed
and sworn to the above declaration. That we believe him to be 72 years
of age that he and believed in the nei^borhood where he resided
72
to have been a soldier of the Revolution and that we conciir in that opinion.
Sworn to and subscribed the day and year aforesaid.
s/ Martin Clark
s/ 0. S. Crockett
And the sd court propounded the following interrogation to William
Cocke the within named applicant for a pension in open court on the day
and year aforesaid.
1st. Where and in what year were you bom?
&#8212;In the county of Hanover, State of Va. in the year 1759.
2nd, Have you any record of your age and if so where is it?
&#8212;I have a record of ray age in a family Bible at ray house In this
county.
3rd. Where were you living at the time you were called into service?
Where have you lived since the revolution and where do you now
live?
&#8212;When I entered the sevice I lived in Bedford County, State of Va.,
remained there for some years after the revolution and then moved to
Rutherford County, State of Tennessee where I have resided ever
since and **iere I now reside.
lith. How were you called into service; were you drafted, did you
volunteer; or were you a substitute, and if a substitute for?
&#8212;In my Ist canpaign under Capt. Talbot to Yorktown, I was drafted.
But in the campaign to Guilford and in the service under Col. Quails,
I volunteered, was never a substitute.
5th, State the names of some of the regular officers who were with the
troops where you served, such continental and militia regiments
as you can recollect and the general circumstances of your service?
&#8212;Qen'l Green, Col Washington and Col Leigh Gen'l Kevins was with me
at the battle of Guilford. Gen'l Lawson commanded the militia at
Guilford. Troops of the Maryland line served at Guilford, I do
not recollect any inportant circumstances except such as is mentioned
in the above declaration,
6th, Did you ever receive a discharge from the service and if so by
whom was it given and v^at has become of it?
&#8212;I do not recollect to have received any other than a verbal discharge.
7th. State the names of persons to whom you are known in your present
neighborhood and who can testify to your character for veracity and
73
their belief that you served ia the revolution.
&#8226;I am known by MaJ. Dance, ffertln Clark, Solomon Beesley Esq, and
to many others, also to Granville Crockett.
IL
</dc:description>
<dc:description>A reprint of Revolutionary War soldier William Cocke's 1832 petition to Rutherford County courts for a pension from his years of service</dc:description>
<dc:subject>United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1783; Rutherford County (Tenn.); Military pensions</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>9 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-15; mt2011-02-16</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication16ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/43</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>