<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Lascassas Baptist Church 1883 - 1983</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Craddock, Ladelle R.</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 21</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>198?</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1880-1889; 1890-1899; 1900-1909; 1910-1919; 1920-1929; 1930-1939; 1940-1949; 1950-1959; 1960-1969; 1970-1979; 1980-1989</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>LASCASSAS BAPTIST CHURCH
1883 - 1983
by - Ladelle R. Craddock
The Lascassas Baptist Church, located nine miles from Murfreesboro
on Highway 96-ea8t, 22nd Civil District, Rutherford County, Tennessee
In the midst of the unincorporated village of Lascassas, was organized
In 1883 by S. G. Shepherd and G. A. Ogle, Ministers of the Gospel.
The new church was dedicated on the third Sunday In June 1925 &#8226; Dr.
E. L. Atwood preached the dedicatory sermon. The following report was
read at the dedicatory service -
"Your committee appointed to report the Baptist cause here,
to subscribe the following: The records show that surround-ing
Baptists met and after due consideration agreed to erect
a church house, and for that purpose appointed the following
committees to solicit funds for sane - W. A. Jones, chairman;
B. F. Phillips, G. ^f. Burke, J. T. Saimders, C. S. Dlllcm,
i
Qeorge Jarman and R. E. Jarman^ who began the erection of the
old house in the fall of 1882 and after heroic struggle &gt; the
sane was completed, at a coat of about $l2iO0.0O. An organi-zation
was effected on February 25, 1883, bgr the election of
Bro. S. Q. Shepherd, Moderator, and in the absence of Rev. J. J.
Martin, Bro. Q. A. Ogles preached the first sermon. Brethren
from Bradley's Creek and Republican Qrove furnished the larger
part of the membership. Bro. J. M. Robinson, at that time,
editor of the B&#171;^tlst and Reflector, preached the dedicatory
semon.
*']ii the summer and fall of 1922, a conmittee was egppointed to
investigate the question of repairing the old house or the
erection of a new one. After many meetings and asking Ood's
help and direction, the church appointed the following committee-
R. E. Jarnon, Chainnan; C. W. Baird, R. H. Martin, Z. T. Herron,
J. W. Owen, Frank Cason, W. T. Delay, Irvin Martin, and R. H.
Donnell to act according to the wisdom of said committee and with
a full assurance the endorsement of the entire church. On the
2Uth day of May, 192U, we began taking down the old building
and by continuous effort from day to day, and at an approximate
estimate of l5 or l6 thousand dollars, we have the pleasure to
present to you, the present structure, as you see it with no
indebtedness."
s/ R. H. Martin
s/ R. 2. Jarman, Coomittee
Charter members of this church included R. H. Jarman, R. &#163;. Janun,
T. P. Ricn, Miss Fannie Rica, Mrs. M. E. Jarman, B. F. Phillips, Mrs.
Betty Phillips, E. W. Phillips, E. D. Phillips, W. H. Fillips, M. S.
Phillips, H. C. Martin and Miss Maggie Martin fr&#171;n Bradley Creek (Twelve
Comer) Baptist Chtxrch; and W. A. Jones, P. B. Jones, G. H. Jones, Ed
RLon, 0. W. Burk, Mrs. S. C. Burk, J. T. Sanders, Steven Owen, Jtidlth
Owen, C. L. Owen, Miss Lucy Owen, Nathaniel Owen, Mrs. M. &#163;. Owen, T. E.
Owen, lira. Mattle Owen, Llllle Owen, J. W. Owen, G. 3. Janaan, Mrs. Sally
Jaman, Calvin S. Dillon and Mrs. Mary Dillon from Republican Grove (now
called HlUvlew) Baptist Church.
The new church prospered spiritually and physically. Bro. Harry
Jaman, Bro. C. S. Dillon and Bro. J. Wallace Owen were licensed and
ordained to the gospel ministry hy this church.
In 1939, the church building was destroyed by fire, but a new
facility was soon erected and worship continued under the leadership of
Bro. H. A. Russell, pastor.
In 1955, under the leadership of Dr. L. S. Sedberry, an educational
wing was added on the west side of the church.
In i960, the sanctuaiy was cooqpletely remodeled and a new lifting
system added.
In 1962, a complete water system was installed, which Included two
rest rooms.
The addition of the basement-including Sunday School class rooms, a
fellowship hail and kitchen were added in 1965*
In 1979, the east wing educatlcaial addition over the basement was
c&lt;&#187;qpleted at an approximate cost of $80,000.OU, including reworking of
the brick and rest rooms. The dedicatory service was held on 17 June
1979, with Bro. Bobby J. Bradley delivering the message. Bro. Henry H.
Innran was pastor at this time.
Bro. S. G. Shepherd was the first pastor, serving from I883 to I89U.
Regtaar business msettns were held on Saturday before the first Sunday
of each month. These meetings are currently held on Wednesday night
preceding the second Sunday of each month.
The Constitution and Rules of Decorum vere adopted Kay 1883. The
nans given to the church vas "Baptist Church of Christ at Lascassas."
Bro. R. E. Jarman vas elected to serve as the first clerk of the church.
The treasurer's report for the year 1885 shows an amount received
at $L32.iiO, and total expenditures at $132.30, leaving a balance of ten
cents. The current budget is $l4l,6ll.76.
The Concord Baptist Association, organized in September 1810, of
which Lascassas Baptist Church is a cooperating church met at this church
for the first time in August 1888.
Deacons serving this church in the past weret C. W. Baird, 0. W.
Burky F. M. Cason, C. S. Dillcn, Roy Dunaway, E. Byron Dement, D. Mac
Elrod, Kenneth Florida, Z. T. Herron, R. E. Jarman, W. B. Jazman, W. A.
Jones, E. Irving Martin, R. H. Martin, W. Henry Martin, J. W. Owens,
Nathazilel Owens, Darrell Rhodes, Wilson Rhodes, J. T. Sanders, W. D.
Vaught, and Y. B. Yearwood. (Darrell Rhodes was a son of Wilson Rhodes)
Preston Cason is currently inactive.
Those serving the church as deacons at this time are: Aiibry Arnold,
Thomas Lee Craddock, Kelly Dement (sen of E. Byron Dement) Edwin E.Florida
Sr., John R. Hovse Jr., William McBro&lt;Mn (grandson of W. Henry Martin),
Don Odom, Douglas Rhodes (son of Wilson Rhodes) and Don A. Webb. Each
active deacon had a special place on the program for the centennial
celebration - mentioned later. Don 14Bbb is great grandson of Z.T. Herron.
Following is a picture of the active deacons made at the centennial
celebration on Sunday, 27 February 1983:
s
&#8226;^ o "^ (u
H- cr rr to
&#171; Q ^
tfl
Former pastors, and the dats of their tentire are as folloKSS
S. Q. Shepherd 1883 - I89li
Enoch WindyA^indes I89li - 1900
E. S. Bryant 1901 - 1903
S. G. Shepherd 1903 - 190U
J. B. Alexander 1905 - 1906
W. J. Watson 1906 - 1912
W, C. McPherson 1913 - 1919
W. G. Mahaffey 1920 - 1922
E, L. Atwood 1922 - 1923
J. A. Kirtley 1923 - 1929
J. T. Barbee 1929 - 1935
J. D. Barbee-V)
*&gt;
1936 - 1937
1 U
DR. JOHN D. BARBEE, " '
Oct 197?
H. A. Russell 193&#171; - 19liO
W. A. Idverman 19la - 19li2
Fred Wilstai Morgan, Sr. 1913 - 19li6
Allen C. Barrett 19U7 - 1950
James C. Wilson 1951 - 1952
Ernie Meyers 1952 - 1953
L. S. Sedberry 1953 - 1956
Charles LeMay 1956 - 1958
Dellmer Nichols
Fairis Jordan
Bobby J. Bradley
James M. "Jim" McPherson
B. B. Isley
1958 - I960
i960 - 1961 (Interim)
1961 - 1965
1965 - 1967
1967 - 1969
B. B. Isley ^ Sadie - as of 25 Febiniary I983
Vance King ^ I969 - 197li
James; Fred, Gertie
Fred Knox James 197 li - 1975 (Interim)
REV. BOBBY BRADLEY
Pastor Lascassas Baptist
_Chureh
1961 - 1965
Honrj' H. Inmon Archie D. King
Pastor Interim Pastor
1978 - 1980 1980 - 1961
and wife, Mary
David L. Elliott
Evans B. Bowen
Hemy H. Innon
Archie D. King
WiUard Karol Crawley
197$ - 1978
1978 (Interim)
1978 - 1980
1980 - 1981 (Interim)
1981 - Present time
WiUard Karol "WiUie" Crawley, wife-Gail,
Daughter-Brandy and son Willard K. "Will" Jr.
Special services were held at the chvtrch Friday evening, Saturday
evening and Simday morning 25 - 27 February 1983 in observance cf the
100th anniversary of Lascassas Baptist Church. The splendid program
was prepared under the capable leadership of Bro. Van Carroll Jones with
approval of the church. Much time, many long hours and miles were spent
in the research and preparation of the chui^ch history for this appointed
time.
Bro. William A. Cox, Jr., from the Sunday School Board, Nashville,
Tennessee, directed the singing for each service. Following is a picture
of Bro. CoQC, also the choir that participated in the services:
Facing the choir picture, reading
fl:om left to right- Front row;
Elaine Dement-organlst, Mary
McKee, I^ynn Vaught, Kin Florida,
Betty Florida, Qall Crawley,
Mary Arm Odom, lynne McBroom,
Peggy Vaught, Lena Martin, and
Joyce Florida-pianist;
Middle row: Edwin Florida,
Bryan Dement, 3111 McBroom, Peggy
Jordan, Betty Dodd, Malissa
Arnold, Amanda Maxwell, Cathy
Martin, and Betty Kelton
Back row: Walter Nipper,
James H. McKee, Jr., Darce Putnam,
and Jerry Kelton.
Winiam A. Cox, Jr.
CHOIR GROUP
o cj n
7^
Bro. Donald Owen, pastor of Immanuel Baptist Church, Lebanon, Tn.
delivered the Friday evening message; Bro. Tom Madden, ExBcutive-
Secretary-TreasTirer of Tennessee Baptist Convention, Nashville, IVi. on
Saturday evening, and Bro. "Jim" McPherson, a former pastor, now pastor
of Second Baptist Church, Clinton, Tennessee on Sunday morning.
Donald Owens, top picture; Tom Madden, lower pict&#187;Jire
27 February 1983
Ministers in attendance on Stmday, 27 February 1983, for the Centen-nial
Observance of the Lascassas Baptist Church. Reading left to
right, facing the picture are:
David Levd.s Elliott - Pastor 1975 - 1978
J. Wallace Owen - Ordained son of the Church
Willard Karol Crawley- Pastor 1981 - Present time
Allen C. Barrett - Pastor 19U7 - 1950
Evans B. Bowen - Interim Pastor - 1978
James M. "Jim" McPherson - Pastor 1965 - 1967
Bro. J. Wallace Owen, ordained son of this chiirch was present on
Simday morning and former pastors attending one service were B. B.
Isley, Fred Knox James, David Lewis Elliott, Evans B. Bowen and Allen
C. Barrett. Each of these men were given an opportvnity to speak
briefly to the congregation.
Bro. Thomas E. Bryant, Jr., Concord Baptist Associational Missionary
attended each service, and on Stmday morning presented to Pastor '-lllard
K. Crawley a plaque from the Historical Society of the Tennessee Baptist
Convention congratulating Lascassas Baptist Church on its 100 years,
reading thus:
THE HISTORICAL SOCIETY
of the
TEMESS2E BAPTIST CONVENTICN
Salutes the
LAiaC.lSSAS BAV^IST
OtURCH
on its
lOOtl-i Anniversary
1983
A picture of Bro. Crawley holding the foregoing mentioned plaque is
on the following page, also a picture of Bro. Bryant.
13
Bro. Thomas E. Bryant, Jr. Bro. Vftllard K. Crawley
A bountiful oovered-vilsli dinner was served In the fellowship hall
at the conclusion of the Sunday moming service after many pictures were
taken by Dr. Bealer Smotheman of Murfreesboro
.
This was indeed a great experience in the life of each one who
attended
.
Lascassas Baptist Church, cooperating with the Concord Baptist
Association, Tennessee Baptist Convention and Southern Baptist Convention
has a full-time program for each one, and cordially invites everyone to
visit with us and participate.
(D
f
w
S' 1
p^
a.
&#187; &#171;&lt;
1
3
y? o
t
^
&lt;&#187; TO
d (B
1
3
p.
a
ro
&#8226;a
Hj OO
O VaJ
c*
ar
I am unable to identify efexyone in the picture of the congregation
ade on Sunday 27 February 1983, therefore , I am listing those vrtio
registered for one or more of the three seznrioes. The majority of these
people listed were in the picture.
ALLEKt Janes R. and Olivia
ARNOIDt Anbry and Christens
Dwain, Kitty, Malissa and Beth
BARRETT: Allen C.
BENNETT: Jeny, Evelyn and Qlna
KMWi Evans B. and Elizabeth
BREi&#171;rHl: James, Bonnie, Ryan and Lindseyi TamBQr
BRCMN: Kenneth, Dcnna, Robin and Brian
BRYANT: Thomas E. Jr. and Irbyj Carol
COAKER: Mr. and Mrs. George M.
CRADDOCK: Thomas Lee and Ladelle
CRAWUSY: WiUard, Gail, Brandy and Will
DEMENT: Kelly, Glsnner, Dan and Dana}
Paul, Elaine, Bryan, Mark and Joyj
Harris, Joyce, Tom and Marilyn
DeHlIEST: Robert and Mary
DILLON: Pauline
DCDD: Paul S. Sr., Betty and Tim K.)
Paul S. Jr., Pat and Adam
DUNAWAY: Sheldon and Yvonne lynn; Lucy
ELLIOTT: David Lewis and LaVema
FLORIDA: Phillip 0., Bet-fy, Phyllis and Brentj
Edwin E. Jr., Kim and Jessej
Edwin E. St., and Joyce
nUSEMAN: James
GBXFFlTHi Brent and HoUy
GHOE: Russell, Judy, Jason and Cara
HALL: William and liaogene
HOWSI: John R. Jr., Judy, Suzanne, Paula and Rick
ISLEY: B. B. and Sadie
JAMES: Fred Knox and Gertrude *'Mama", also knoun as Gertie
JONES: Van Carroll, Van Michael and PatridLaj Violet
JORDAN: Ernest and Peggy; Charles| Randy and Peggy
i6
KELLTi Hugh and Janat
KELTON: Jerry, Betty, Michael, Jill and Jason}
Janei Klnberlle
KBlGt Mr. and Mrs. Varia B.
KNIGHT t Ronald P., Rosalind, Rhonda and Roljynj Ricky
LEE:
LESTER:
Link and Marie
Lalla
MADDEN: Tom and Edna Earl
MARTIN: San, Evelyn and Cathyj Lena; Benj Angle
Jlminy, iMienia and Edgar
MATHIS: F. Murray and Loretta
MASf^ELL: Amanda
MINGLE: Jinny, SLalne and Brooke
MOORE: Charles, Kay, Gabriel and Daranee
McBRO&#8364;M: 6111, I^nme, Monica and Jennifer
McCULLOUQH: Era
McCDRDI: Mr. and Mrs. Art
McKEE: James H. Jr., Mary Jean, Derek, Lori Jean and Zane
McPherson: James "Jla" R*, Carolyn, John Mark and Sara
McVlcker: Norn and Joan
ODOM: Marvin and Ctsna Lee;
Den, Mary Ann, Leanne and Donna
OWEN: Mr. and Mrs. J. Wallace
OWENS: Donald
PENUEL: J. D. "Jack" and Alice Brown
PHILLIPS: Hazel; Pauline
FOWEL: Petis and Nina Ruth
POWELL: Kellie
PRIEST: Mr. and Mrs. Harry
PUTNAM: Daroe, Margaret and Darrell
RHODES: Douglas, Karen, Greg and Brad; Rachel; Rhonda;
Rosalind; Frances, Dawn and Mike
ROSS: Sidney and Ola
SMARXT: Carl and Ila
STILL: Jennie
TQIPLETDN: Mr. and Mrs. Rick , Rikl Lauren and Mary Beth
VAUGHN:
VAUGHT:
VERBLE:
WEBB:
WELI2:
WINN:
Troy J. and "Ltl" Troy
Melvln, Peggy and Stan; Mike, I^mn and Phillip
Bob, Barbara and Marilyn
Don A., Patoy, Michelle and Jeff;
Marion, Tonmie, Any and Robert
Bobby, Eleanor, Bill and PhilLlp
Mr. and Mrs. Dan A.
Pauline
17
Lascassas Baptist Church faces north, but with the rerouting of
96 Highway, it now goes to the back of the church as seen in the following
photo. The front of the church is featured on the front cover of this
publication, courte^ of Mr. James Ifetheriy.</dc:description>
<dc:description>A history of the first century of Lascassas Baptist Church</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Baptist churches; churches</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Lascassas</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>18 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-08</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication21ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/136</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>