<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Minutes of church session of Hopewell</dc:title>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 7</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1817 - 1821; 1976</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1810-1819; 1820-1829</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>18
Minutes of Church Session of Hopewell
(April 1, 1816 - Sept. 25, 1821)
The congregation of Hopewell was organized April 1, I816.
Members in full communion at that time 45 and received stated
supplies from Jesse Alexander Licentate until April 1, 1817.
During which time there was added by examination 4, by certifi-cate
6, Baptized adults 2, Infants "J &#187; Deaths 3.
April 7, 1817 J. Alexander was ordained pastor of this
congregation Baptized the following infants Alans Trigg , John
Peterson, David Morison , William Bogle , Zachius Alexander .
August 11, 1817 The Church session of Hopewell met agree-able
to appointment. Members present Ezekial Sharp, Zachius
Alexander and William Rea.
Session preceded to make such regulations as would be to the
spiritual advantage of the congregation. It was the order of
session that the moderator in order to prepare the congregation
for examination should deliver a connection sermon imbracing the
doctrines contained in each chater of our confession of faith.
And then precede to the examination of ghe congregation on these
doctrines
Session adjourned to meet on the last Saturday in November
next, concluded with prayer.
August 10 Baptized Abner Alexander.
Sept. 5 Baptized Samuel Maberry, Joseph Sharp.
Sept. 7 Admitted to communion by examination M. Thomas,
Eliza McNight, Ellen Andrews, Rachel McNight. By certificat
James Kilpatrick.
Nov. 19 Session of Hopewell met agreeably to adjournment
19
members present Ezeklal Sharp, Zachies Alexander, and William
Rea constituted with prayer. Session attended to the business
that came before them relative to the spiritual and temporal
advantage of the congregation. Session adjourned to meet on the
first Saturday in April 1818, concluded with prayer.
Nov. 30, Baptized Andrew Morison, Removed from the congre-gation
Jane F. Peoples in Full communion.
Feb. 2, 1818 Joseph Sharp, Ephram Farr and Abner Alexander
were ordained elders in this congregation.
Session met agreeably to the appointment of the moderator.
Members present Ezeklal Sharp, William Rea, Zachel Alexander,
Joseph Sharp and Ephriam Farr. Constituted with prayer.
Ezeklal Alexander who was suspended from the Church of
Stones River Falling into the bounds of this congregation made
application to be restored to the privlliges of the church. The
session being satisfyed with the acknowledgments and pennence of
Mr. Alexander restored him to the communion of the church session,
concluded with prayer.
April 6, 1818 Members of session met agreeably to the
appointment and attended to the things that came before them.
April 7, Baptized Jacob H. Thomas and Ephraim Farr.
July 1818 Members of Session met agreeably to appoint-ment
and attended to some of the temporal conserns of the congre-gation.
Aug. 22 Admitted to communion Polly Farr.
Sept. 13, Baptized Thomas Leach, Ezeklal Sharp.
Died on the 1 day of November Alexander Witherspoon a member
of this congregation.
20
Nov. 27 - Baptized Alanson Trigg, John Boid.
Feb. 1, 1819 Session met agreeably to appointment consti-tuted
with prayer. Inquiry was made whether there was anything
to be laid before the session.
Session was informed that said that ( )
had been guilty of unchristen conduct. Ephram Farr and William
Rea were appointed by session to converse with Mr. ( ) on
the subject.
Session adjourned to meet on Saturday the 13th.
Session met agreeably to adjournment constituted with prayer.
William Wilson applied for church priviliges . Con-cluded
with prayer.
April 5, 1819 - Oswin Alexander and his wife Ann were
received into full communion by certificate. Samuel Mitchell
and his wife Mary were also received by certificate.
June 16 Baptized (Thado Rose?)
Aug. 5 Baptized Alexander Witherspoon
Admitted to communion James (Mclannel?) Ezekiel Alexander.
Jan. 9, 1819 Baptized Oswin Alexander
Feb. 13,1820 Baptized Jospeh Sharp, Horatio, G. Alexander,
Reported to Presbytry.
For this time member in communion 66
June 4 Baptized John Boid
June 18 Bapt. James Mcnen (crossed out)
Sept. 1, 1820 The Sacrement of the Lord supper was adminis-tered.
There were added by certificate James S. Witherspoon. By
examination James Wilson, Ezekiel Sharp, Zachius McCorkal,
Armelia McCorkal, William Garmanay and Eliza Alexander.
21
Oct. 22 Baptized Zachus Alexander, Ezeklal Sharp.
March l821 Baprlzed David Morlson, Baptized Ephramln Farr.
April 21 Baptized Abner Alexander
Admitted to communion Neon Dorn on the 2 of May l821
departed this life Mrs. Catherine Sharp .
June 25 Baptized Jacob H. Thomas
July 24, 1821 Admitted to communion Ellen Wilson, (Lues?)
F. Wilson, McKnlght Alexander, John and Polly Rains, Baptized
(Rev?) Jessee Alexander.
August 13,1821 Baptized Thomas, Powel
Sept. 25, 1821 At this time a report was made, members In
communion 81.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Printed minutes of Hopewell Presbyterian Church between the dates of April 1, 1816 and September 25, 1821</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.) -- History</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>churches; church records; minutes; Presbyterianism</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>7 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-02</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication07ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/152</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>