<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Pillar of fire or angelic agency</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Cooper, Sarah F.E.</dc:creator>
<dc:contributor>Jones, Shirley Farris</dc:contributor>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 34</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1855; 1994</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1850-1859;</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Sarah F. E. Coopec's Essay.
Soule Female College.
Mupf treesbopo, Tennessee.
A.D. June 26th 1855.
In the year of the Ametrican Republic L.XXIX
k9
Pillar of fipe
or angelic agency.
How often are the protecting arms of angels thrown
around us in the pathway of life. As a pillar of cloud by
day and a pillar of fire by night.
They mark our way, choose our steps, keeping us from a
course which might plunge us into inevitable darkness,
sorrow, or the tomb.
Angels are with us wherever we roam on earth. Though
distant from our native home, on lowland, sea, or mountains
vast, they can wave their pinions over our youthful heads
allowing us to heaven.
They hover around us whispering words of love, beguiling
us with delightful thoughts and often reminding us of those
who have gone before us in triumph, and thus inspire us to
follow them to heaven.
"Angels our noonday walks attend,
And all our midnight hours defend."
It was an angel that appeared to the Israelites in a
pillar of cloud by day and a pillar of fire by night,
throwing the mantle of protection around them, shielding them
from the enemy as they journeyed to the land of Promise. At
one time they had been overcome, had not Divine Providence
changed the pillar of fire to Egyptian darkness, enveloped
their foes in cinnerian night, and shed on Israel a luster
brighter than the sun.
Have you not read of the angel that "heralded the birth
of Christ?" when
"Heaven bursted her azure gates and posessed Her spirits
to the midnight hour."
"There was suddenly with the angel, a great assembly of
the heavenly host praising God in the highest, shouting peace
and good will towards all men." The morning stars who sang
together and the sons of God who proclaimed the eternal works
of creation were angels.
Was it not an angel that appeared to the wise men "as a
star going before them" until they arrived at Bethlehem. It
was supposed by some that this was a luninous sector prepared
for the occasion.
We cannot tell whether this is true or not, but as the
problem is solved entirely by the rule of supposition we may
suppose it a glorious angel that descended to Earth from his
heavenly abode, to proclaim the advent of Christ to the lord,
shepherds, as they were watching their flocks by night.
Heavenly angels are spiritual beings, peculiarly holy,
happy, innocent and virtuous; and the first in rank among
created beings, they are also the most intelligent. The word
angel profanely signifies a messenger. Angels are spiritual
beings of great power and of understanding vastly superior to
that of man.
It is supposed that they can assume human forms at any
time they choose. Besides this they are possessed of such
great velocity that they can descend from the third heaven to
minister to mortal woes. Meditations upon the nature of
angelic beings are ever pleasing to the humble of Earth and
often our dreams are peopled by legions of celestial
visitants. Tn my own slumbers I have often seen their
glorious forms.
Their faces were fair, very fair, with flowing curls
clustering thickly around their heads and shoulders. Their
wings were white as snow and the tips of their feathers were
lightly fringed with azure; such a contrast made them appear
of matchless elegance.
They were beautiful, exquisitely beautiful; and as I
gazed T felt a longing to join their company. Glowing and
Utopian as this may seem, angelic grace far surpasses our
dreams and our highest conceptions of their beauty fall far
below the reality.
One evening lately I was thinking of angels at twilight,
just as the glorious sun dipped and disappeared behind the
western hills; leaving a golden hue of his gorgeous robe upon
the closing gates of day.
My spirit became so perfectly transformed in beholding
the luminous bodies of the skies, as one by one they appeared
from beneath a purple veil until the celestial globe was
illuminated with millions of sparkling gems unrivaled by the
diamond and marking the footprints of a God. In the
enthusiasm of my heart I exclaimed I wish I was an angel.
Then my enraptured spirit would take its flight to happier
scenes beyond, where the sun is never concealed by a cloud,
and where the flowers ever remain of a dazzling beauty. It
seemed to me I heard angels whisper, saying arise and come
with us and we will lead you to the sublime regions of
eternity
.
You shall outstrip the wings of death, and the sorrors
of time and change. I seemed to rise, to float upon the thin
air, heaven spread out before me, and I was almost within its
gates, but atlas! just then a mortal finger touched me and
51
broke my slumber, and the dneam dissolved.
I traised my drooping head ftrom its hard pillow and lo!
all was fancy. Yet angels were doubtless watching around me
and weaving the fabric of my vision.
Have you ever wondered what angel intercedes for you?
Often when my brow has been parched with feverish heat and
gentle winds fanned my burning cheek I have thought maybe
that the motion was caused by the flitting of an angels wings
above my pillow. If human feeling can tempt a spirit from
heaven to minister to mortal woes surely a mother's love
would bring her down to the sick bed of her child to fan the
aching head with the wings of holy tenderness.
Friends and associates may angels surround you as a
pillow of cloud by day and a pillow of fire by night in all
your daily walks through life;
"Making earth an eden land
And guiding time's departing hours."
And finally when the angel of death knocks at your door, may
the angel of the covenant who's flaming fire has directed
your wandering footsteps through all the meandering of life
gently bear you over the gloomy stream of death.
Finis.
Transcribed by Shirley F. Jones (1-25-94).
Note: According to the 1850 Census of Rutherford County,
Sarah F.E. Cooper, age 12, William H. Cooper, age 13, and
Wise A. Cooper, age 10, were shown as living in the household
of Joseph and Temperance Lindsey. Joseph is shown as being
a 46 year old male who was born in North Carolina. He listed
his occupation as a Clergyman of the Methodist faith.
Temperance, female, age 70, was also born in North Carolina.
The Cooper children were all listed as having been born in
Tennessee. Based upon this information, Sarah would have been
17 years old when the above was written.</dc:description>
<dc:description>An essay on angels and angelic intercession written by a seventeen year old student at Soule College in Murfreesboro, transcribed by Shirley Farris Jones</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Soule College; angels; Christianity</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>7 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-01-26</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication34ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/170</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>