<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Matthias Hoover of Hoover's Gap</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hoover Sr., Edwin Francis</dc:creator>
<dc:contributor>Hoover, Walter K.</dc:contributor>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 22</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1984</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>18th century; 19th century; 20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>MATTHIAS HOOVER OF
HOOVER'S GAP
Taken from the book Hoover Huber Ancestry and
Family Record by Edwin Francis Hoover Sr., 1954.
Information furnished by Walter K. Hoover.
"The name Huber originated from an old German work "Hube", pronounced "Hubay"
meaning the possessor of a tract of land or small farm. In the German dia-lect
the name is invariably pronounced "Huver" as if spelled with "v" instead
of "b", which accounts for the many variations in the English tongue. From
the original name Huber, Huver, Hoover, and Hoober. The descendants of Hans
Huber, with the exception of one branch, have changed the name to Hoover."
"The first of the Huber clan to leave Lancaster County (Pa.) was Matthias Huber.
He and his younger brother, Jacob Huber, jointly inherited the Huber homestead
in Martic, now Providence, Township, which was willed to them by their father.
Jacob Huber (son of Hans Huber). In 1776 Matthias transferred his interest in
the homestead to his brother, Jacob, the transfer being signed by his wife,
Maria, which proves that he was married at that time" (Note by Edwin Hoover,
Information from the records of my father, Rufus Archibald Hoover, states that
Matthias Hoover's wife was named Barbary Statler, and that they were married
at Appomattox Court House in Virginia. It may be that this information
concerns a second marriage of Matthias Hoover).
The date of this transfer without doubt fixes the year in which Matthias Huber
with his family, left Lancaster County for the southland. In August, 1904,
a (great) great grandson of Matthias Huber, Rufus Arthur Hoover (brother of
Edwin Hoover) of Bell Buckle, Tenn., visited the writer (Harry M. Hoover, in
Philadelphia) and told him that his grandsire stayed a short time in Virginia,
then went to Middle Tennessee where he took up a large tract of land, also
that he brought a German Bible with him from Pennsylvania, being a very
religious man and a member of the Methodist Church.
First Generation
"Hans Huber was born in Switzerland probably between 1670 and 1675, and died
in Earl Township, Lancaster County, Pa., October, 1750. His wife, Margaret
99
Koch (Cook) was born in Switzerland and died in Earl Township. The exact date
of her death is not known. She was living when Hans Huber transferred his land
to his son, Jacob, on Sept. 21, 1745, as her name appears on the transfer. They
were Mennonites and without doubt are buried at Graffdale, as there is no
private burying ground on the Huber homestead.
Issue: Jacob, Catharine, Magdalene, Margaret, Christiana, and Anna."
Second Generation
"Jacob Huber, born in Switzerland or in the Palatinate prior to 1700 and died
in Martic, now Providence, Township, Lancaster County, Pa., July 9, 1759.
(Note: There seems to be an error here, as Jacob Huber 's will bears the date
of July 29, 1759. On September 12, 1792, this will was "duly proven and re-corded").
He was married twice. There is no record of his first wife, she
having died in Earl Township. The second wife's name was Anna, and she was
living when he made his will in 1754 (?). We have no further record.
Mennonite, farmer, residence Martic Township, Lancaster County, buried in a
private graveyard on the homestead, Providence Township, (then a part of
Martic Township). Issue to first wife: Anna, married Yost Kendrick, no record;
Barbara, married Philip Stetzler, who lived in Earl Township, and died before
1754, two miles south of New Holland; Maria, married Jacob Eberly, no record;
John; Martin; Margaret, married John Winter. No record.
Children to second wife: Christian; Magdalene, married Adam Gefeller;
Catharine, married Abraham Ladshaw, no record; Matthias; Jacob. Jacob Huber
son of Hans Huber, came to Pennsylvania with his fathers' family and most
likely was married after he came. His will, written in 1754, shows that
his children to the second wife were then under age".
Third Generation
"Matthias Huber was born in Lancaster County, Pa., and died in Rutherford Co.,
Tenn., married Maria ? in Lancaster County; went to Tennessee (first to
Virginia, E.H.) in 1776; Methodist, farmer, residence (Hoover's Gap) Ruther-ford
County, Tenn.
Issue: Martin, married Sallie Bradford; Christian (Christopher); Jacob;
John; Nancy, married John Glase; Elizabeth, married Joseph Allison; Sallie,
married William Rawlins; Polly, married John B. Pruett.
100
Matthias Huber was the first of the clan to leave Lancaster County or to join
another church (than the Mennonite)."
Here ends the material taken from the Huber-Hoover History, which brings the
record down to that of my father as recorded on pages 3 to 5 of this book.
It will be noted that Matthias Huber and his children appear in both records.
While there seems to be no doubt that the Matthias Huber of the Huber-Hoover
History and the Matthias Hoover described by my father as his great grandfather
are identical, yet a few differences in the two records are noted here:
Huber-Hoover History Record of Rufus Archibald Hoover
Matthias Hoover married Maria ? Matthias Hoover and his wife were
in Lancaster County, Pa., prior to natives of Germany. Her name was
1776, the year in which he left Penn- Barbary Statler. They were married
sylvania. at Appamattox Court House, Va., and
went to East Tennessee, thence to
Childred of Matthias Huber: Middle Tennessee. (Perhaps this was
, ., ^ . -J r 1 1 &#8226; n ^*- ^ a second marriage).
1. Martin, married Sallie Bradford
children of Matthias Hoover:
2. Christian
3. Jacob
1. John H., wife's name unknown
2. Jacob, married Miss Broils
:&#8226; t&#176;^^ &#8226; ^ 1 ^, PI 3. Martin, Married Miss Bradford
5. Nancy married John Glase
^ Christopher, married Miss Lotspeech
6. Elizabeth, married Joseph Allison 5^ H. married John Prewett
7. Sa y, married Wm Rawlins g^ ^^^\ ^^^^.^^ ^^^ R3^1i^3^
8. Polly, married John B. Pruett 7^ ^^^^^^ ^^^^.^^ j^^^ ei^^^^
It. is reasonable to conclude that Christian and Cristopher were the same
person. Elizabeth was evidently omitted from R.A. Hoover's list. Polly and
Mary were the same person as indicated by husband's name, Pruett (Prewett) it
is not known if either list is in the order of their ages.
DEED
From records in Office of Register, at Court House at Murfreesboro, Rutherford
County, Tennessee. Book B. Page 225)
Guilford Dudley to Deed 5000 Acres
Mattias Hoover. No. 264
This instrument made the ninth day of August in the year of our Lord, one thousand
seven hundred and ninety-three, between Guilford Dudley, of the County of Cum-berland
and State of North Carolina, of the one part, and Matthias Hoover, of the
County of Greene and the Territory of the United States South of the Ohio, of
the other part, witnesseth; that the said Guilford Dudley for and in considera-tion
of the sum of five hundred pounds current money of North Carolina, to him
101
in hand paid by the said Matthias Hoover at and before the sealing and signing
of these presents, the receipt and payment of which is hereby acknowledged, and
the said Guilford Dudley for himself and his heirs doth hereby bargain and sell
a lien thereof and confirm unto the said Matthias Hoover, his heirs, executors
and assigns forever a certain piece of land in the County of Davidson, formerly
Greene County, situated, lying, and being as follows: On the waters of the
Duck River, beginning at the said Dudley's southwest corner of the survey of
1456 acres at a hickory, thence south six hundred and forty poles to a sugar
tree, thence west twelve hundred and fifty poles to a walnut, thence north six
hundred and forty poles to a stake, thence east twelve hundred and fifty poles
to the beginning, containing five thousand acres, which said piece or parcel of
land with all ways, woods, waters, and every other appurtenance thereunto be-longing
or appurtaining the said Guilford Dudley for himself, his heirs, execu-tors,
and administrators hath hereby sold, set over, conveyed, released and
confirmed in open market to the said Mattias Hoover, his heirs, executors, ad-ministrators,
and assigns and he, the said Guilford Dudley, for himself and his
heirs, executors, and administrators doth hereby consent and promise to and with
the said Matthias Hoover, his heirs, executors or assigns that he, the said
Guilford Dudley, his heirs, executors, and administrators shall and will warrant
and forever defend the said piece or parcel of land with all and every of its
members and appurtenances free from all lawful claim of any person or persons
whatsoever unto the said Matthias Hoover his heirs, executors, and administrators,
sets his hand and seal this day and year above written.
Guilford Dudley
Signed, sealed, and delivered in the presence of J.M. Lackey and Isaac Burklace.
James M. Lackey, a subscribing witness to the within instrument of writing made
oath before me, David Campbell, one of the judges for the Territory of the
United States south of the River Ohio, that he saw Guilford Dudley, sign, seal,
and acknowledge the within instrument as his act and deed for the purpose within
mentioned.
David Campbell
Feb. 3, 1794
State of Tennessee,
Davidson County Register's Office.
The within deed of conveyance and probate is duly registered in Book D, page 154,
May 9, 1797.
Thomas Mai lory. Register
102
Christopher Hoover inherited the old homestead where he lived to be about seventy
years of age, meeting his death by a fall from a load of hay, (Died about March
22, 1844) breaking his neck. His wife, Elizabeth Lotspeech . was of a wealthy
family, her father owning many slaves all of whom he set free, believing it
wrong to hold them in bondage. The family was very religious, being Methodist.
One son was a preacher, three other sons were exhorters and would lead in
public prayer. My grandmother conducted family worship, leading in the prayers
herself, using many scripture quotations in her prayers. She died March 31, 1838
being fifty-five or sixty years of age. She aied of dropsy of the heart.
Her husband afterward married Martha W. Dillard, (who died March 7, 1861) whom
he left a widow, dying as above stated.
Christopher and Elizabeth Hoover's children were as follows:
1. Matthias, born Oct. 20, 1795, married Nancy Warren. They moved to Texas
where they both lived to be old, and died in a few hours of each other.
They had eleven children.
2. Sally Hoover was born Feb. 16, 1797, married John Rawlins. They lived and
died in Hoover's Gap, she being left a widow with ten children. She died
aged about fifty years of age.
3. Jacob Hoover was born Oct. 10, 1798. He was drowned in the Garrison River
near Fairfield, Tennessee, being about sixteen years of age.
4. Catherine Hoover was born Nov. 24, 1800, married George Uselton. They
lived in Rutherford County at various places. She died at about fifty-five
years of age, leaving ten children.
5. Martin L. Hoover, born March 29, 1802, married Mary Holland of Shelbyville,
Tenn., They lived in Hoover's Gap, where he died at about 45 years of age,
leaving his wife with seven boys (one record says "Died June 20, 1840").
6. John L. Hoover, born Aug. 4, 1804, married Thankful Murfree. They lived in
Hoover's Gap, where he died aged 76 years, leaving his wife and one son.
7. Mary Hoover, born Sept. 29, 1806. Died young.
S.Nancy Hoover, born April 26, 1808, married Allen Blankenship, a methodist
preacher of West Tennessee. She was thirty-eight or forty years of age
when married. They lived in West Tennessee, where she was left a widow
with one son.
This record follows the family of:
9. William Hoover , born March 23, 1810, married 1st wife Sarah A. Lingo of
Beech Grove, Tenn., August 3, 1832. Settled in Bedford County, Tenn.
where his wife died having borne him four daughters and two sons. On
March 21, 1850, he married 2nd wife, Sarah E. Clark, who born him two sons
103
and two daughters, she died - - - " (The manuscript of Rufus Archibald
Hoover ends here. He was evidently preparing it from pencil notes in his
handwriting, which are in my possession, and from which this record is
completed through the fourteen children of Christopher and Elizabeth Hoover)
- - - Dec. 3, 1858. Afterward he married 3rd wife, Ursula Jane Orr, who
born him one son. Died Nov. 4, 1895 - 4:30am. 85 yrs, 7 mo., 11 days.
10. Barbary Hoover, Born Jan. 11, 1812. In her twenty-fifth year married Dr.
Joseph Walker of West Tennessee, where theylived, she being left a widow
with one son.
11. James Hoover, born July 29, 1814, married Susan Moore of Beech Grove, Tenn.
She died leaving him ten children (Another record says nine). He then
married Minerva Winn, of Unionville, Tennessee. He died at about seventy
years of age, leaving his wife with eleven children.
12. Susannah Hoover, born March 7, 1818, married Jamed L. Hawkins of West
Tennessee. She died in West Tennessee, leaving her husband with four children,
three boys and one girl.
13. Matilda Hoover, born Jan. 9, 1820, died young.
14. Benjamin Sewell Hoover, born March 26, 1822, married Sarah Elizabeth
Oil lard. To them were born ten children. They settled at the old Hoover
homestead in Hoover's Gap where they now (1898) live.
Benjamin Sewell Hoover died July 30, 1902. Sarah Elizabeth (Dillard) Hoover
was born Oct. 20, 1823, died May 29, 1905.
104</dc:description>
<dc:description>Includes genealogical information on Matthias Hoover, a founder of Hoover's Gap, and his ancestors and descendants</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Hoover, Matthias; genealogy; family histories</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Hoover</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>6 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-02</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication22ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/167</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>