<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Veterans Administration Medical Center</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Sloan, Gene H.</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 19</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1982</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939; 1940-1949; 1950-1959; 1960-1969; 1970-1979; 1980-1989</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>42
VETERANS ADMINISTRATION MEDICAL CENTER
by - Gene H. Sloan
"I recall being in the circulation office of the Nashville Banner in
Murfreesboro, located in the rear of a restaurant on the comer of Mjple
and College Streets across from the Haynes Hotel (present location of J. C.
Penney), when the factory whistles began to blow," writes Mark Wonack.
Womack is an executive of the N.C. and St. L. Railroad. He was describing
the excitement that occurred when the official announcement cane that a
hospital for veterans would be erected five miles north of Murfreesboro
on the Lebanon Road.
43
Womack remarks on the ironic paradox that tragedy and pathos of World
War I would result in such local jubilation. "But it was a shot in the
arm of our people as they struggled to esca^ the sluggish recovery fJrom
The Great Depression," he concltides.
Carefully guarded negotiations between government agents and the
Batey, Camahan, McCrary, Posey, Smith and Sullivan families in 1936-37
had resulted in the government acquiring U51 fertile acres situated be-tween
the Lebanon Pike and Stones River. Those families had, over the
years, acquired fee In lands that the Janes Rucker family had secured
from General Isaac Shelby, hero of King's Mountain. It was an historical
site. "In I80li, the first session of the Rutherford Counly Court met,
according to the Leglalatlve Act, at the Thomas Rucker home, near where
the Veterans Hospital now stands," states Sims History of Rutherford
County, p. 2li. The James Rucker grave is located on the present Medical
Center grounds. Late in 1862, the Cavalry Command of 26-year old General
Joseph Whe J.er used these acres for a rendezvous prior to the two-day sweep
around the Federal Army with destruction of Union waigon trains at LaVergne.
Construction of the original fifteen buildings of Georgian architec-tural
design began in 1938. The facade of the Administration Building is
an exact reproduction of the Harmitage, home of Andrew Jackson.
The Medical Center opened January 1, I9I4O, with a bed capacity of 600,
which was gradually Increased to a peak of 1$10 in August 1968. The
Veterans Administration Regional Office opened January 1, 19U0, and re-mained
with the Itedical Center until it was moved to Nashville on January
1, 191*6.
Mark Wonack was a youthful employee of the N. C. &amp; St. L. Railway In
19U). His record reveals that the special train bearing the first patients
from a Johnson City facUi-^ arrived by special train. He states," The
44
train came fl?om th&#171; south from Chattanooga where it had arrived over the
Southern Railway. J. W. Tucker, Aaeistant Superintendent of the N. C. &amp;
St. L. Special Number 7 accompanied the train as it arrived from the
South. I remember the locomotive pulling the train was a U-82-2, known to
railroaders as &#187;The Mountain Type.' Some of the patients being transferred
from the passenger cars were litter borne."
Since that January I9I4D opening date, an outpatient clinic was started
In 1968. This clinic currently averages about 26,1^0 visits each year. The
average number of hospital patients admitted yearly from the past few years
has been around 2,100. Many additional buildings and services have been
added over these four decades. The hospital at present has 315 psychiatric,
235 intermediate and ii,8 nursing home care beds.
The staff, of approximately 1020, conqjrises a conqilete team of physi-cians,
dentists, nurses, with a full range of auxiliaries of psychologists,
physical therapists, dietitians, pharmacists, occi^tlonal therapists,
medical laboratory technicians, radiology technicians, ward and administra-tive
personnel. The staff is augnented by trainees, consultants, and some
300 volunteer workers from civic clubs, religious and fraternal societies
of the area. The Murfreesboro Veterans Administration Medical Center has
an annual payroll of above $21,000,000.
The hospital en9&gt;loys the most modem equipment and methods of diagnosis
and treatment of patients. Included in these facilities is electro&#171;iceph-alo
graph, drug therapy and psychotherapy* In addition, the hospital con-ducts
specialized medical programs. Among these are speech pathology,
intensive care, respiratory care, nuclear medicine and alcohol rehabili-tation.
There is also a Pulmonary Function Laboratory, Mental Fftrgeine
Clinic and a 38-bed long tera stroke rehabilitation unit.
45
San Jared&gt; Jr., vas administrator and medical centar director for
the hospital from December 12, 1939 untU August 31, 1962. During this
long tenure additional buildings were constructed and an unusually fine
rapport was established with the comuni'fy. He was succeeded by Dr.
Alexander Harvey who served fzx&gt;m September 30, 1962 until January 6,
1968. Dr. John T. Mason became director on January 7&gt; 1968 and was
retired in October 1978. Robert S. Pepiot has served since October 15,
1978.
A canteen and a credit union are available to employees. Qnplpyee
Association members have access to a swimming pool and golf course when
they are not in use by patients. They also have access to the lake
twice each year.
Joyce M. Barrett finished 30 years as a nurse at the hospital on
December 31, 1981. On September 2, 1982 JuaneUe G. Neely wlU receive
30 years of service recognition. Alvlna P. Prlram and Lotilse M. Moss each
have 25 years of work with the nursing service. Clifton Frazler will
complete his 25th year in October 1982, and Mollle Young and Patricia
Jemlgan have each completed two decades of service.
Dr. Richard L. Harris was the first chief medical officer when the
hospital opened in 19l|D. Only four medical doctors now on the staff have
been there ten years or moz&#171;. They are Dr. James T. Allen, Dr. Booker T.
Crombie, Dr. Horace E. Lucamo and Dr. James W. Tenpenny. Dr. Walter P.
Pegram has been on the dental staff since November 2, 196U.
Many Rutherford County organizations work with the patients in the
annual Halloween carnival, on the bowling lanes, in horse shows, Softball
games, fishing in the lake, and other recreational and social activities.
There are regular religious services in ^ich local groups participate,
aided by the hospital chaplains.
46
Volunteers In 17 departnents are considered the same as einployees.
The only difference is that they do not receive any coB$&gt;en8ation for their
work and cannot replace a paid enqployee. They sinply enhance and BvppLe^
ment patient care. Voltinteer needs are constantly changing and include
many patient contact assigunents as well as office assistance assignments.
Listed as recipients of certificates during 19dl for cooperation in
volunteer activities vere iimerican Legion and Aaxiliaxy&gt; inerican Red Cross j
Elks Clubj Daughters of the American Revolution, Disabled American Veterans
and Auxiliary, General Federation of Women's Clubs, Military Order of the
Cootie and Auxiliaxy, U. S. Catholic Conference, Salvation Amy* Veterans
of Foreign Wars and Anxiliary, Order of Eastern Star, American Federation of
Musicians, Business and Professional Women, Middle Tennessee State I^-
versity. Daughters of the Confederacy, Lions Club, Moose Club and Auxiliary,
Aide Sociely, East Main Street Church of Christ, Rutherford County Hone
Demonstration Clubs, Lock's Memorial TMlted Methodist Church, Klwanis Club,
Murfreesboro Women's Bowling Association, Newcomers Club, New Hope Church
of Christ, North Boulevard Church of Christ, Trinity Itolted Methodist Church,
Sqyma Home Demonstration Club, Oakland High School and the Al Menah Temple
Shrlners.
On January 1, 1982 there were 52 volunteer workers with more than 10
years contribution. Among these vere Annie Fulton with 36 years, Cora King
with 35 years, Dorothy Conditt with 33 years, Catherine Alspach with 31
years, Anita Heflln with 31 years and Benldee White with 30 years. Volunteer
workers with more than 20 years creditable service include EsteUe Beggs,
Annie Black, Jack Gandy, Mrs. Mahlon Garber, Margaret Hayes, May Hendris,
Florence Hunter, IdUlan Johnson, Bertrum Layne, Pat^ Layne, Rattle
McKlnney, Ethel Smith and Virginia WlUeford.
47
The Rutherford County HLstorlcal Society acknowledges vlth deep
appreciation the research of Spencer Dlzon, Chief of Voluntary Service
&#187;
In coBQxLllng much of the Information contained in this article.
</dc:description>
<dc:description>A brief historical piece on the Veterans Administration Medical Center in Murfreesboro</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.); Veterans Administration Medical Center (Murfreesboro, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>6 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-08; mt2011-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication19ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/30</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>