<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Rutherford County courthouse</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Jones, Shirley Farris</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 39</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>199?</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>19th century; 20th century;</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>RUTHERFORD COUNTY COURTHOUSE
The Rutherford County Courthouse is one of only six remaining courthouses built in the state prior to the
Civil War. It is listed on the National Register of Historic Places for its significant architecture, political and military
history This building was completed in 1859, at a cost of $50,000 and -^-as the third courthouse to be built in
Murfireesboro.
Rutherford Countyw^as formed in 1803, withJefferson being selerted as the county seat. In 1811, the county
seatJivas moved fiximJeflFerson to Cannonsburgh, which is present day Murjfreesboro, and the first log courthouse
was built the next year in 1812 in the center of the Public Scjuare. This name was later changed to Mmfreesboro
(borough) in 1817, since the site chosen was land donated by Captain William Lytle, and at his request named in
honor of his firiend, Colonel Hardy Murfite, who had recently passed away By 1818, the first courthouse was
declared inadequate for county fijnctions. To provide funds for the improvement and repair of the courthouse,
the county court levied poll and property taxes in the amount of 12 1/2 cents and 25 cents, and a $ 10 tax for each
billiard table.
Murfi:-eesboro served as the capitol of Tennessee fi-om September 1818 until 1826, with the Tennessee
General Assembly meeting in the Rutherford County Courthouse. The Courthouse burned in 1822, forcing the
state legislature to meet in the First Presbyterian Church, then located on Vine Street, next to the Old City Cem-etery
(This church ^'as destroyed during the Civil \X^kr and its bricks were used in the construction of Fortress
Rosecrans. Its foundation is still visible.) The Courthouse was partially rebuilt in 1822 at the cost ofapproximately
$5,000 and served until the present courthouse was construaed in 1859. Originally its form was square, with
classical columns on the east and west sides capped by a pediment. Between its completion in 1859 and 1861,
certain improvements were made, including the addition ofa privy house, carpeting, and piped water to dstems.
During the Civil War, the courthouse was a very strategic building. The cupola was used as a watch tower to
monitor signals, and was occupied by both armies. It was in Federal hands fix)m late March 1862 until General
Nathan Bedford Forrest's raid on Murfii-eesboro, July 13, 1862, when the courthouse was stormed and Confeder-ate
civilians were fineed. Forrest's men tore down the courthouse doors with axes and started fires in the hallways,
causing some damage but also forcing the Union soldiers to leave their positions. Miufeesboro remained in
Confederate hands until their withdrawal to Shelbyville following the Battle of Stones River, December 31, 1862 -
January 3,1863.
In late spring of 1862, one ofthe neighbor's who lived just across the street on the southeast comer, a young
lady by the name of Miss Mattie Ready was crossing the street of Federally occupied Murireesboro one morning,
when she heard some ''i:^nkee soldiers making less than-flattering comments about General John Hunt Morgan.
She went up to them, stomped her foot, and gave them a pretty good tongue lashing. They asked her name and
she informed them that "It's Mattie Ready now. But by the grace of God, I hope to call m^-self the wife ofJohn
Morgan one day" They allow^ed her to continue on her way nev^er guessing that she and Morgan were already
engaged, The wedding took place just across the street on December 14, 1862 and was considered by many to
have been the social highlight ofthe Confederac&gt;: There w^ much gaiety on the courthouse lawn, with music and
bonfires burning brightly Then on Christmas Eve, a grand Christmas ball was held by the Sixth I&amp;ntucky and the
First Louisiana in the Courthouse. It was decorated to the hilt with greenery candles, and a chandelier fashioned
out of the soldiers' bayonets. Dancing continued all night. This would be the last happy times seen in the Court-house
for quite some time.
During early 1863 with Murfreesboro under Federal occupation again, this same grand structure served as
both barracks and a prison. When the Federals set oflf on the Tullahoma Campaign in Ma&gt;^ of 1863, those left
behind had orders to shell die townn and bum the Courthouse in die event of a Confederate raid. One gun at
Fortress Rosecrans was even trained on the Courthouse as a deterrent. By the end of the war, half of the roofw^as
blown oflf by the wind, windows and doors were broken, and plaster crumbled fi-om the ceiling.
In 1865 the War w^as over Reconstruction begun. People were trving to get their lives back in order and get
onwith the business ofliving. Times were tough. Monev' was short. Repairs were slow^ It was not until 1872-78 that
hitching posts were added around the courthouse to prevent citizens fi-om tving horses to the courthouse fence.
Page 18
Railingwas placed over iron spikes on top ofthe fence to prevent damage to livestock. Finally, in the 1890's, repairs
began in emest to improve the courthouse. It was re-carpeted and wallpapered and damaged plaster repaired.
Water closets were added. The exterior was penciled and gutters added.
In 1899, just before the turn ofthe century, theJ. B. Palmer Bivouac, the Ladies MemorialAssociation, and the
Sons ofVeterans were granted permission to erect a Confederate monument on the lawn ofthe courthouse. It was
to be a bronze monument with Johnny Reb poised menacingly atop a pedestal in battle stance and facing down
East Main Street. This was later moved to the northeast comer of the lawn where the infantryman was feeing the
north symbolically poised to defend home and hearth.
In 1906 and 1907 more extensive renovations were done. When the two story courtroom had a ceiling
added, it created a third floor These additions resulted in changing the configuration of the roof from hipped to
flat. It is probable that the cupola was changed from an octagonal cupola to its present appearance at this same
time. The original cupola of the 1859 courthouse reflerted the design of the Tennessee State Capitol which was
completed in 1854.
In 1913, a tornado hit Murfreesboro causing massive damage along the north and west sides of the public
scpaare. Luckily the Courthouse received only minor damage, and this was caused mainly from flying debris.
In 1921, men's toilets were added - one for white men, and one for colored. Although women didn't get
thefr own bathroom, a couple ofyears later The Daughters ofthe American Revolution and the United Daughters
of the Confederacy sp)ent their money on placjues in memory of both Confederate and World War I veterans.
In 1923 an interesting event occurred when a stranger appeared on the courthouse lawn, claiming to be the
"Human Fly". He wasn't. But as such, he proclaimed his intention to scale the courthouse and the cupola and
money was quickly gathered to compensate him. As the crowd watched, the Human Fly climbed both the court-house
and the clock tower, holding to the weathervane at the top ofthe cupola. Unfortunately it had begun to rain
and he lost his footing on the slippery surface, falling to his death. Men who examined him could find no trace of
identity and he was placed in a glass casket at Sweeney's Funeral Parlor on the square, hoping friends or family
would come forth. No one did, and the Human Fly was buried nameless in the pauper's section of Evergreen
Cemetery with no marker
Mmfeesboro was slowly growing between the years of 1924 and 1942; streets were widened around the
Courthouse, cutting off several feet of the yard. The cupola columns were replaced and the Courthouse beU was
used as an air raid alarm during World War n.
By 1945 World War n had ended, soldiers returned home, and in the next few years once again people got
on with the business of just living. It was not an uncommon sight to see men gathered in the Courthouse yard,
whittling, chewing tobacco, and solving world problems aU the while. Uncle Dave Macon, a local musician and
folklorist, among them. The monument placed in honor of General Griffith Rutherford, an Irishman and Revolu-tionary
War veteran for whom the county was named, was also added during this period.
In 1951, General Douglas MacArthur and his wife, Murfreesboro native Jean Marie Faircloth, visited the
county. There was a parade and thefr motorcade cfrove them around the courthouse square. Schools let out for
this occasion, and there was much excitement as the bands played and all the Uttle boys and gfrls stood on tippy-toe
in the courthouse yard trying to get a good look at the war hero and his bride.
By the mid 1950's, the courthouse had grown too small for the many county officials and a good manyofour
very progressive leaders wanted to tear this building down and build a more modem faciHty Fortunately there
were others who cared and could appreciate the fact that this grand old dame represented Murfreesboro's heri-tage
and fought for its preservation. After many and somewiiat heated discussions a compromise was finally
reached, which included the additions of the two-storywings on the north and south sides ofthe courthouse. This
provided much needed additional office space in 1961. Major internal renovations and repairs were also com-pleted,
including the addition of an elevator and new electrical and plumbing work. A fi-esh coat of paint, new
furnishings, repair to the steps, the renovation of the jury box, and the addition of new seats in the courtroom
were completed by the early 1960's. Then in the 1970"s, restoration on the outside began wiien the cupola and
some of the exterior was repaired. After extensive exterior reno\'ations, the Rutherford County Courthouse was
listed on the National Register of Historic Places. In 1997, interior restorations were once again undertaken and
when completed returned the courthouse to its mid nineteenth century appearance. The Courtroom reopened
Page 19
in its original twostory configuration, complete with period fixtures and wallpaper.
For almost a century and a hali^ the Rutherford County Courthouse has stood a silent wimess to the evolve-ment
ofMurfi^esboro and Rutherford County She has watched our children grow and have femilies, their chil-dren,
and their children's children. She has watched our sons go ofi"to war, some ofthem never to return. She has
kept a watchful eye over us, while w^e searched many times for our footing, and all the while, accepted growth and
change with dignity and grace. Fewwould argue that the Rutherford County Courthouse has been the soul ofour
community!
This article was written by Shirley Farris Jones, a past president of the Rutherford County Historical Society
and a prior contributor to this journal (Publication 34). She is also actively involved in the Friends of Stones River
Batdefield, the Association for the Preservation ofTennessee Antiquities, and the United Daughters of the Confed-eracy
Page 20
</dc:description>
<dc:description>Describes the history of the Rutherford County Courthouse from its beginnings in 1859 to present day</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Murfreesboro (Tenn.); Rutherford County (Tenn.); Courthouses -- Tennessee</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro;</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>3 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-01-25</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication39ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/2</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>