<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>The anniversary of two churches (Stone's River and Hopewell)</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Cranor, Moses</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 7</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1916; 1976</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>19th century; 20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>THE ANNIVERSARY OF TWO CHURCHES
(stone's River and Hopewell)
By
Moses Cianor. 1916
As we gather today to celebrate the Anniversary of Hopewell and Stone's
River Presbyterian Churches, it is iny purpose to malce it a histoiy of Faith
and facts for the churches at these places.
Faith is a reliance on testimony that which is real truth, a desii-e for
something good, with the evidence of trust that will be a proof of out- beliel
The Characters to be represented will furnish an adequate conception of the
Divinely vital and exuberant doctrine of Presbyterianism. Oui- creed is a
Christian faith briefly summed up in the two Catechisms and the Confession
of Faith, not three but one, with the word of God as fjuide.
V/hat is the chief end of man? It is to Glorify God and enjoy him for-ever.
The historic faith of the Presbyterian Church as a body in latter
years has been assailed with the most searching criticism by a merciless
vivid and eloquent abuse, however, she stands today a monument toweling over
the frailties of man. These fathers and mothers, creators of the modern
world, born of heroes, saints and martyrs, crown it the greatest Creed of
Christendom. I will not stop here to defend its origin, history of govern-ment.
One thing I will say, it has "Tlius saith the Lord" for every word it
has incorporated therein.
As the footprints of the red man of the forest were scarcely gone, when
a steady stream of Scotch and Irish with a mixed blood of thirsty liberty
loving souls, could be seen wending their way across the mountain plateaus
of the east, along blood stained beaten trails that the savage
hiinter trod, as he fled before civilization's massive wheels, which has
transformed these fertile valleys and her circling hiUsidos, from natures
garb to ooe of lovely grandure, that seldom fails to attract the passer-t.y,
and bring fi'om their lips praises of delight. As we muse over the all absorb-ing
thought of one hundred years ago, and those devout men and women who
banded themselves together to serve the Lord God of their fathers, in a land
which has already been won for freedom by bravery, niese men we/e of command-ing
personality, of strong faith and courage, of intense energy, who exercised
a wonderful influence upon the moral and spiritual life and ideals, over a
large portion of the surrounding country. In theli- dwellings nestling along
the range of hillsides to the East, running North and South; between two noted
points or peaks that stand as sentinels of trust, they are known as Solomon
George on the north and Pilate Knob on the South. The Bible was their inhei'-
itance. Their SEunctuary was around the hearthstone, a place of more vital
religion in that day than all others combined. A need that has been sorely
neglected. The two points above mentioned, one north, the other twelv^ miles
south, in sight of each other, stand as sentinels to the faith and bfotherly
love that existed between the two ext'^emes.
Why were these two churches, Hopewell and Stone's River organized on the
same day, April 1, 1816? At or near the two points designated, by the ilev.
Jesse Alexander, a licentiate of Shiloh Presbytery. (Their pla.ce of vrorshlp
in the few years that had past was near the center under no name that either
of our recor-ds mention, in brotherly love and feeling no doubt the two
extremes were anxious for a place of worship dividing near the centci-.
Hopewell, one mile east of north from her present position; two ::iiles
south of that noted peak, Solomon George, Wiose head was covered with a lu::-
urient forest looking down upon the rudely constructed log house near the old
bui-ying ground, where many of theii- members lie beneath the sod awaiting the
resurrection morn. Two of their niunber, the records tell us, were taken to
the beyond in the first year of Hopewell's organization, Capt. Thomas Black,
a soldier of Revolutionary fame, and his wife, Polly (Polk) Black. The
blood of these two pioneers flows in the veins of over one fourth the member-ship
of Hopewell today. Out of over two hundred of their descendants we can
trace fully three fou'ths that were and are members of some branch of the
Pi-esbyterian church. A history that few of the chuj ches of this Presbytefy
can parallel.
Hopewell was organized April 1, 1816 as above stated with members then
in communion 38^ six of which were elected and installed elders, namely:
Ezekiel Sharp, William Rea, Zacheus Alexander, Ephram Farr, Joseph Shai-p &amp;
Abner Alexander, Clerk of Session. Hopewell received as stated supply from
Rev. Jesse Alexander, Licentiate, from Apr. 1, I816 to Apr. 7, 1817.
Hopewell's histo;ry I will divide into four periods.
Period 1, was one of 15 yeai'S with no very active demonstration recorded.
Each year had one informal record of additions, deaths and disraissaJs, with
only three session meetings in regular fonn recorded. Members added on cei-tificate
&amp; examination, 62. Baptized adults, 10, Infants 39^ benevolent
causes $5^.00. Deaths lU, Dismissed 15. Suspended for heresy, 2. The
report to Shiloh Pi-esbytery for April I83I was kO members. In concluding
this the 1st period, three new elders had been elected and installed, William
McKhight (Dr. Billy) usually called, was a ruling elder fiom Stone River
Church received into Hopewell in I825. On July 2k, I829, he was chosed Clerk
of Session. Elders John H. Baxter and David Morrison were elected and instal-led
July 30^ 1830. Of the old remaining elders, William Rea was born in
Ireland I^fe.r. 6, 1752. He professed religion at the age of I8 years, remained
an elder in Hopewell ^ years, died at the age of 104 years. The other, Abner
Alexander, serving as Clerk of Session 13 years. (oo far unable to find his
record).
Period 2. In the beginning this Period of 23 years, from the past you
can plainly see that Hopewell, with all her struggles, barely held her own.
I hope that no one will feel that it is my purpose to digress in the least
from the subject, for if their ever was two sister churches organized on the
same day, by the ssune man, out of a united brotherhood, who had been woi'king
together in love and unity, it was Hopewell and Stone River. It may be
safely said that nine tenths of the past one hundred years the same ministers
have filled the pulpits of both churches.
A little ways up Stone's River near its banks stands that noted Peak,
(Pilate Knob) alx'eady mentioned as a Sentinel of peace and unity. Until 50
years ago her- head was uncovered by the ravages of war by Federal authority.
Redoubts were built constructed upon her crest and a light towet' on her sum-mit
that displayed a beacon of calmness and peace, or the red
flashing signal of the approaching enemy.
This was a period of great religious activity. It is likely that in
this decade Hopewell was removed to her present location, though the records
m&#163;Lke no mention of it anywhere. At this time the congregations felt the need
of closer relations, and on Sept. 23, I83I, the two congregations met in Camp
Meeting at the Contor Nursery or McKJnight's Ceimp-ground, near the dividing
line between the two congregations. The Carap-ground, w?j.e situated on a plat
of two or more acres, in the center was a large shed 35 or kO by 60 to "0 ft.
On three sides of this square were rudely constructed tents, some of logs
others of board and plank. Around this large auditorium were large beech
trees that furnished ample shade. The seats were the time honoi-ed puncheon
and a new straw floor for each general occasion. In the rear of the pulpit
the full width of the structure, was a shed for the colored man and his
family, the eacort of his master. The entrance was from the east, there was
a main aicie with two f)f more crocs aides forming sLde entrances. There
were meetings onco or Lwice a year which were looked rorward to wltli I'allli
and supplication for the outpouring of the Holy Gpirit, upon them uud t)ioir
efforts. Hundreds upon hundreds attended these meetings. Order was the pre-vailing
characteristic. It seemed that the power of God and his presence was
felt and recognized by all. As many as fifteen visiting Presbyterian ministers
are recorded as attending during a meeting; two to four and 5 at a time. I
will najne a few of them-Mui-freesboro's greatly beloved. Dr. Wm. Eagleton,
Rev. M. Marshall, Amzi Bradshaw, William Porter, E. T. Brantley and Dr. A. H.
Dashiell, that noted ministorial orator, of persu.aGive language and convinc-ing
power. It was no wonder that men thronged these meetings, coming two and
two and others alone, some walking others in deep meditation, wending their
way to the near by grove, as the sun was inking behind the western hills v/hile
twilight came, later the woild wrapped in nature's night. The burdened cry
from many a soul could be audibly heard as it v^as wafted on the stillness of
the breeze, that some poor perishing souls that night might find Jesus
precious to their souls. The records mention 10, 25, '?0, and 75 being
gathered into the garnor of the Lord; and Hopewell, Stone River, Cripple
Creek and Murfreesboro were edified and built up in the most holy faith. I
find that in the l8 meetings recorded 535 persons made pro. of religion.
On Nov. 10, 1832, Elder David Morrison (after serving 2 yrs.) and family
were dismissed, moving out of Church bounds. May 31^ iQhO., Elder V/llliam
McKnight departed this life. He served as Clerk of Session 11 years. Apr.
12, l34l Bro. Williamson Cosby was chosed Clerk of Session. Oct. 25, l3U2 he
vras dismissed at his own request in good standing, serving 1 year as clerk.
Oct. 25, 1&gt;342 Bro. David McKnight was elected clerk of Session, serving 8 yrs.
Apr. 1, 1849, Bros. Dennis Hog\/ood &amp; William R. Alexander were elected and
ordained elders In Hopewell. Oct. 9th of the same year, lQ^9, Elder William
R. Alexander departed this life. He was a son of the beloved Pastor., who .
WJiB near throe score and ten years. Apr. ih, l''&gt;!)0. Elder Dennis Iloi^yood wj^s
chosen Clerk of Session.
July 20, l85if, $235-35 was collected from Hopewell and LJtone Rivet-
Churches to pay for the Presbyterian church at PJashville, Tenn.
During this period Hopewell had 19O additions, 26 deaths, 95 dismissed,
1^3 Baptisms. Church expenses $905.00, Benevolent causes $6o4.00, totaling
$1509.00.
April 9, 1859 the report to Sliiloh Presbytery was. Rev. Jesse Alexander
pastor, John H. Bastor and Dennis Hogwood elders. 111 members.
Period 3- The period from Apr. 9^ l859 foi' seven years, was one o!" the
greatest declines in all of Hopewell's history. First, at the beginniiip; she
was an independent Church, with no ecclesiastical connection anyi-^here. The'
few years preceding this thei'e \ra,s considerable agitation in the higher
church courts over two or more much debated questions which I can explain
more fully by giving a copy of a Church meeting held in Hopewell I'lay '), l"59-
Congregational meeting
Hopewell's members were called together by order of Session on the 5th
day of May l859 for the pui^pose of choosing their ecclesiastical connection.
The meeting was constituted by calling Rev. Jesse Alexander to the chai-r, and
L. B. Creson, clerk. Rev. Jesse Alexander opened the meeting with prayei-, he
also explained the object of the meeting. A committee of three, to wit, John
H. Baxter, D. Hogwood and George Peoples, was appointed to draft and present
suitable resolutions which were severally considered and adopted.
V/hereas the Presbyterian Church of the United States cf America, divided
in the year I838 on the subject of the Excinding Acts of I837, and fonned two
Assemblies known by New and Old School, and whereas a number of the
Px'esbjrterians belonging to the New School Assembly being aggrieved with the
continued agitation of the subject of slavery in this body, withdrew from
said assembly in l857 convened at Cleveland, Ohio and formed a Synod at
Khoxville, Tenn. in IO58, known by the name of the United Synod of the
Presbyterian Church in the United States of America.
And whereas Shiloh Pi'esbytery to which we belonged was not one of the
number that withdrew, but disolved by a vote of her own body on the Oth day
of April 1859^ ve being thereby destitute of any ecclesiastical connection
whatever, "Therefore resolved, first that it is expedient that we foi-m a con-nection
with some ecclesiastical body.
"
"Resolved secondly, that we approve of the I'esolution of the United
Synod in excluding the agitation of slavery from its Judiciary."
"Resolved thirdly, that we also approve of its explanation and mode of
adopting the confession of faith, as embracing the doctrines contained in the
Bible."
Resolved fourthly, that we in uniting with said Synod, make no sacrifice
of principal or doctrine."
"Resolved fifthly, that we the undersigned members of Hopewell Church,
unite with said Synod through some one of her Presbyteries as soon as possible."
Fifty eight of the One hundred and eleven members of last repoi-t signed
the above preamble and resolutions. To this report two were added and 5 dis-missed.
Oct. 6, i860, Elder D. Hogwood reported to North Alabama Presbytery, two
elders and 5&gt; members uniting with said Presbytery. Following all this came
the War Between the States.
On the 15th day of June I863, Rev. Jesse Alexander, Hopewell's Pastor,
departed this life and was laid to rest in the city of the dead among his
bretheren and friends, awaiting the final summons. His age was 82 years and
5 raonthe. Two elders, John H. Baxter and Dennis Hogwood were left with the
buidens of Hopewell Lo bear. God in hie mercy seeing Hopewnll't-, Tew upon
their- knees sent visiting ministers to their relief. Such men as the Hevs.
A. Bradshaw, M. Marshall, E. T. Brantley, Henry C. Smith and others; Rev.
H. C. Smith serving near 2 years.
Sept. 25, 1865, a call for a congregational meeting, for the purpose of
electing elders. Oct. J, I865, H. A. Baxter was ordained elder by the Rev.
Henry C. Smith.
Wearing the closing scenes of this the third Period, a peace and haimony
were being promulgated throughout our beloved land. Hopewell looking back
upon her records find only three reports to Presbytery, with 21 additions, 7
dismissed, 1 expelled and 15 deaths, with 19 baptisms. For church expenses
$155 '00^ foi' benevolent causes $7'+.00, with 10 regular sessional meetings
recorded in the 7 years period.
A report to Noi-th Alabama Presbytery, April 9, I867, with 3 elders, 5'l-members,
closed the first 50 years of Hopewell's organization.
Period h. In the beginning this the 4th or last period including a space
of fifty years of Hopewell's history, it is my purpose to deal with facts and
figures concerning the active forces of this organization, concluding with a
brief summary of the two Churches, with a few sketches from life.
Sept. 16, 1867, Rev. M. A. McFeaters was called as stated supply for
Hopewell and Stone River. For over three years he served these people. He
was a man of deep consecration and earnest piety, decisive in his denunci:.i-tion
of evil and wrong doing. It was on Oct. h, 1867 that he with Rev. W. L.
Rosser began a seven days meeting in Hopewell, which resulted in ik profes-sions,
and the church members greatly refreshed. Mar. J, I871, Rev, Robert
Caldwell was chosed as supply. He was a man of strong character, showing
distinctive qualities and traits for good. Apr. 22, 1872 the records state
that Xanthius A. Baxter was chosed delegate to Nsishvllle Presbytery, the
first date of said Presbytery mentioned in our record. The Rev. Robert
Caldwell being called elsewhere, served Hopewell only one yeai'.
May 18, I872, Rev. W. L. Rosser was called to this field as supply. He
was one who in other days had stood upon the tented field pouring forth words
of comfort and consolation with warning against sin, and a judgement to come,
to his comrades in arms. For nine years he held the banner of Prince
Emmanuel aloft in Hopewell's rank. In this decade her prosperity was above
normal. Nov. 5^ 18^7 three elders were elected. Bros. J. C. Herndon, H. G.
'
Johns and Jas. M. Weatherly were ordained and three Deacons, the first that
Hopewell ever recorded. Bros. Robert F. Baxter, Jas. N. McKhight and Wm. B.
White were duly elected and installed Deacons.
Apr. 1, 1875^ the first Elders and Decons' meeting was organized in
Hopewell. Dec. 19, l875^ elder Jas. M. Weatherly was relieved from the
active duties of the eldership. Aug. 21, I876, Ruling Elder X. A. Baxter,
departed this life after serving 11 years, calmly trusting in Jesus, with
suitable resolutions recorded in Book 3) page 139* ^t. 25, I880, ruling
elder John H. Baxter, a Father in Israel for more than 57 years, departed
this life. On May 28th, I881 Bro. G. W. Lorance was duly elected and ordained
a ruling elder in Hopewell, which was a period of religious activity both in
numbers and in the spirit of giving, exceeding a3J. past records. Rev. W. L.
Rosser was called to another field of labor.
Dec. 31, 1881, the Rev. Geo. E. Thompson a young man fresh from the
S.W.P. University and Union Theological Seminary, Hampton Sidney, Va., was
called as supply. But the minutes of Sept. 2, 1882 recorded that Hopewell
call the Rev. G. E. Thompson to become her pastor, to serve this church one
ha2i" his time, at a salary of $225.00 per year. On Sept. li^-, l882, Nashville
Presbytery, convened in Hopewell, a meeting long to be remembered by loany.
10
for Rev. G. E. Thompson was ordained pastor of Hopewell. And on the 15th one
of the flowers of Hopewell's young manhood was received under the care of
Presbytery as a candidate for the Gospel ministry. Rev. John R. Herndon, a
man who has proven himself worthy the calling accepted.
June 3, 1883, Elder Dennis Hogwood resigned as Clerk of Session, serving
33 years. Elder H. G. Johns was chosen as Clerk of Session July 5, I885.
Bros. H. B. Hogwood and S. P. Brantley were elected elders and Wm. Hoopei\,
as deacon, being installed by Rev. G. E. Thompson to their several officers.
Aiig. 6, 1885, Deacon Robt. F. Baxter departed this life, serving over ten
years
.
On May 16, I886, Bros. W. W. Rion and W. H. Herndon, were elected and
installed as Deacons. Mar. 3^^. I888 the two above Deacons named tendered
their resignation leaving temporarily the bounds of this church. May h, 1889
the Rev. G. E. Thompson resigned as Pastor of Hopefwell seiving 7^ yr. Sev-eral
months passed before another Pastor was secured. This was a Season of
\inpleasajitne6S for it is with deep regret, and a feeling of reverance to
record the first and only Stigma that rests upon Hopewells fair name, by
referring you to the records of July 7th I889, for in this meeting the Elder-ship
divided upon the question at issue. And in the controversy later on,
one member of the session was called before a commission to answer charges,
who was Exhonerated by them, and two others Apr. 5, 189O 2-esigned from the
active duties of the Eldership. I will only refer you to the record Book No.
k P^ge 121 8C Oct. 6, 1889 Rev. J. W. Mosely, was called as stated supply.
Serving near two year then He was called to another field of labor Apr. h,
1891&#8212;Hopewell remained without a leader and preaching foi- one year, for it
was on Apr. 3, I892 that the Rev. A. J. Crane a Licentiate of Knoxville
Presbytery canvassed the field and on Apr. 10, I892 He Rev. A. J. Crane was
by a Congrational meeting unanimously called Pastor of Hopewell. On Feb. 15,
11
l893 Deacon Vftn B. White departed this life. Serving Nineteen years, March 2h
,
1893. Elder H. G. Johns resigned as clerk of Session, having sei-ved ton yearE.
Elder J. C. Herndon was Elected in his Stead Aug. 31st., 1893 Elder 11. G.
Johns. At his own request was dismissed to unite with the Edgefield
Presbyterian Church Nashville, Tenn., Serving Hopewell Nineteen yrs. Apr. Sth,
1896 Bros. Andrew McKhight and Jesse Alexander were duly Elected and Installed
Deacons Dec. 3rd, I899 Bros. Win. D. Black and Andrew McKnight previously
Elected were Installed and Ordained with S. P. Brantley, who was reinstalled
and Ordained as ruling Elders, in Hopewell. It was on Feb. k, 190O Bros.
Wilson Dement and Wm. D. Brantley were duly Elected and installed as Deacons.
Feb. 10, 1902 Deacon Wm. Hooper was dismissed at his own request to the first
Presbyterian church Murfreesboro, Tenn. Serving Sixteen yrs.
By an order of Session a congregational meeting for July 6, 1902 was
called to accept the resignation of Rev. A.J. Crane one who had served
Hopewell for ten years was accepted with Suitable resolution recorded in Book
k Page 178 July 11th, 1902 Elder S. P. Brantley departed this life. Serving as
Elder Seventeen years. It was on April 6th, I903 Rev. T. A. Patton was called
as stated supply serving Hopewell in that capacity for five yrs. Aug. 30, 1903
Elder J. C. Herndon resigned as clerk of Session, having served ten yr. Moses
Cranor was chosen Clerk of session on the above date-Oct. 5^ 1903 Deacon
Jesse Alexander was dismissed by a letter at his own request, having served
seven years No. 1st, I9O3 Elder J. C. Herndon at his own request was granted
a letter to unite with the 1st Presbyterian church of Murfreesboro, Tenn. hav-ing
sein^ed as Elder twenty nine years On July k-, 1904, Elder Geo. W. Lorance
departed this life serving Hopewell twenty three years. It was on Aug. 3}
1905 that Elder Dennis Hogwood a father of Israel in Hopewell ranks departed
to the beyond in the triumph of Faith having served Hopewell as Elder over .
fifty six years. On May 2nd, 1907 Deacon Jas. N. McKnight departed this life
12
Serving Hopewell as Deacon thirty three years Pi-esbyterlan church Sei-vinp;
Hopewell 8 yr. Nov. I907 Elder A. M. McKnight united with Wartace Dec, 29,
1907 Bros. Wm. D. Brantley and Wilson Dement were ElecLed and ordained. l!;idei-3
and Elden Young was elected and installed Deacon by Kov. T. A. lYitton who
before closing the Service called for a dissolution of his labors with this
church to answer a call to the Monroe Harding Orphanage which was unanimously
granted with reluctance. It was during the latermlssion between Rev. T. A.
Pattons two Services that Bro. A. A. DuBois a Baptist Minister, who had united
with the first Presbyteriaji church Nashville, Tenn. was sent to this field with
the recommendation of his Pastor Dr. Wra. Anderson who acted as supply until
Sept. 1908 when He Entered the S.W.P. University under the care of Nashville
Presbytery as a candidate for the Gospel Ministry Nov. 1st 1908 The Second Call
for the Rev. T. A. Patton was made for him as Pastor-Feb. 7, 1909 Bros. Neil
White and Chrle. E. Furgason were duly Elected and installed as Deacons by the
Rev. T. A. Patton Dec. 26, 1909 Rev. T. A. Patton having Served Hopewell one
year as Pastor called a congregational Meeting for the purpose of dissolving
the Pastoral relation between himself, and Hopewell, asking Nashville
Presbytery to grant the request which was done.
The year I9IO was one that ought to be long remembered by Hopewell mem-bers,
from the fact of having no direct service, only through the Kindness of
the Rev. L. A. Street, Pastor of the U.S.A. Chvirch while Serving his own
people in Hopewell, which had been tendered them to use although the officers
of Hopewell had five Sessional meetings, and all reports made to Presbytery
the delegates failed to attend Said Presbytery that met at Clarksville, Tenn.
Apr. 26, 1911. The above report included kO members in Hopewell.
This was the condition found Existing Mar. 5^ 1911 when a congregational
meeting was called for the purpose of calling the Rev. R. Q. Riley as Pastor,
of Hopewell who accepted the ca3J..
13
It was Oct. 15, 1812 that the two congregations U. S. and the U.S.A.
were united by the action of both their Presbyteries, and confinned by Dr.
W. L. Caldwell chairman of the Home Mission committee of the Nashville
Presbytery Twenty members were added to Hopewell's list Bmb racing three
Elders, Go W. Oakley, R. H. Suramar, and Wm A. Baxter together with two
Deacons, Jas. A. Baxter &amp; Hop Smith Increasing Hopewell official forces to six
Elder, and five deacons On Mar. 2nd 1913 Deacon Neil White at his own request
was granted a letter to unite with the 1st. Presbyterian church Murfreesboro,
Tenn. Serving k yrs. It was on Oct. 3rd, 1915 our dear Bro. Elder 0. W.
Oakley departed this life From 1816 to 1916 5 meetings of Presbytery were held
at Hopewell. Presbytery of Shiloh met April 30, iBSO - April 10, 1858
Nashville Presbytery met Sept. k, 1873, Sept. ik, 1882, Sept. 12, I899.
During these 100 years the Ch. has had a total of 529 members, hei- pre-sent
membership is- . Her contributions to Benevolent causes have been
generous. There have been 3 church buildings.
Brief Summary of the past one hundred years work of the two churches,
Hopewel&#177; and Stone River five meetings of Presbytery have convened in HopewelJ ,
Shiloh on Apr. 13, IO5O Apr. 10, IO58 Nashville Presbyteiy Sept. k, vyj3 Sept.
14, 1882, Sept. 2, 1899, Total 529 Mem. 393 ad. one Ex. 98 ad on Cirt. 1'36
Dissm. 9 Expelled 17O Deaths 350 Baptised.
Financial Report
for church work and maintaining the Gospel at Home in Hopewell $r^',552
to benevolent causes 3,8l6
beside three chiirch Houses and one Manse it being Bui-ned 22,368
the other now Standing was the combined efforts of Hopewell Stone River Crip-ple
Creek and the community at large.
Stones River Church
Organized Apr. 1, I816 as above Stated with 30 members in Communion five
were chosen Elders David Andrews, Jas. Bowl John Henderson, John Dickson, and
Charles Ready Clk. of session Their records were Kept similar to those of
IH
Hopewell. It is through the Kindness of her clerk that I make the following
statement Total membership 509 members ad on Ed. 429 Ad. on Cirt 50 Dismissed
170 Deaths 93 Here is a lesson for us in the two congregations there are over
hOO unaccounted for it is Just as Jesus Said to the one Leper- "Were there not
ten cleansed. Where are the nine" Jno. 17-12. Five Pastors sex-ved Hopewell
85 Stones R. about Seventy years ten others as supply thirty year^ with twenty
five Elders and Eight clerks of Session, three of them chosed from the laity.
The 15 Deacons have served forty two years. In this computation, I have been
as brief as I possibly could.
In Conclusion
I wish to give you a short Sketch of four of Hopewells most Self Sacrificing
ones. 1st. Rev. Jesse Alexander, Pastor k'J yrs. through all his ministerial
labors upon Earth.
2nd. Elder J. H. Beixter for 50 years
3rd. " Dennis Hogwood, Clk of session for thirty three years.
4th. " Geo. Peoples a consistent member ^7 yrs.
A Sketch from life
Rev. Jesse Alexander Born Jan. 15, 17^1 moved to Tennessee Oct. l''^02
Entered the Grammar School May 1st, l3o6 was Licensed to Preach the Gospel
Sept. 2nd, l3l4 was Ordained Pastor of the churches of Stone River ami
Hopewell Apr. 7th I817 &#8226;',ra.s married to Eliza Rea, Aug. 3, l320. To this union
ten children were born. Seven of whom lived to maturity two are living, one a
member of Hopewell, the other of Spring Creek Presbyterian church. Tiie
object of this Sketch was rather tall but slender and Straight as an ar.-ow.
His countenance was solid, genial, and gentle. His bearing was dignified
with a tendency to ir_fluence others for good. Living as he did on the borders
of three counties. He was BxtenDively Known as he went from place to place,
bearing the messages of love and peace. In all his relations with the woild,
he was the accomplished gentlemar. in his pej-sonal life he was above all things;
the hiomble and devoted christian in Home affail's, he was a man of Energy and
15
foi'ce, as he went from his Study to the farm and his work Shop that furnished
him ample support with a bearing of dignity yet genial with affectionate feel-ing
the very Soul of Hospitality. A home of relief, for the friend the weuiy,
and the desolate. In his Pkstorate, he was lovingly tender and graeiou:;, Foj-forty
seven yrs. he went in and out before this people winning theii- love;, and
commanding their respect yea a veneration, of all classes in the community
from the highest to the humblest, in his latter years when he became totally
blind, it did not detain him, from duty to his appointments, or prevent him
from Service to his Lord and blaster, at time without an escort relying upon
Faith in God, and confidence he had in the animal he always rode to carry him
to his appointments in safety.
An Elder in Hopewell foi' 50 years
In this Narative or Sketch of Elder John H. Baxter Boi-n in North Caj'olina
l804 One whose Portrait with others, Should adorn these Sacred walls with a
delimation of their lives, as Memorials to Hopewell, He left the parental
roof a beardless boy coming with friends to Tennessee, about the year l3l5
preceeding his parents. Some months David and Sarah Baxter with one Sister
who were in the original organization permit me Say this Sister Rebecca Baxter
was a consistent Christian member in Hopewell for Seventy one years. In lo23
John H, Baxter united with Hopewell. In I826 he married Betsy Black, to this
union Seven children were Born, that lived to Maturity two of these were
office bearers in Hopewell, as already mentioned. He, like most boys of his
day, received a very limited Education but when he came to manhood, he v/as a
man of almost unlimited powers of ability, an Earnest student of his Bible,
the greatest text book that ever lay upon any ones desk quick Energetic, and
witty Ever ready with an answer upon his tongue an amateur of Music who could
sing like the nightingale, with a voice tuned to mellodious praise both sweet
and Heavenly. Ever a pet of the children in their childish games, always one
16
with We boys and girls taking part in Especially blind mans bliiff we listen-ing
to his i-etorts winning our confidence. Many were the times when the
Minister had made every appeal at his command with no move or Even a tear.
When John H. Baxter arose from his Seat clearing his throat, with a quivering
voice repeating Some verse or Something that had been said, when it seemed that
the vei-y Sound of his voice appealed to every one in his pj-esence with Sorrow-ing
hearts, and weeping Elyes such was the chai-acter of the man that his words
were received as coming from the heart to reach the heart.
A Clerk of Session 33 years
In these written Statements of facts addressed to Hopewell, may they
ever stand as momentoes to the unfaltering love, and devotion, that Elder D.
Hogwood Ever Exhibited in fulfilling two offices of trust to God and his
church. He was born Oct. 19th, l8l3; Departing this life Aug. 3rd, 1905 . He
was a man of heavy frame rather Shoi-t of Stature, his hair and complexion wei-e
dark, a Tanner by trade yet farming was a chief occupation, and a well o.-dered
home was his delight. The stranger was welcomed at his door , if they showed
manhood just the same as a friend the destitute forsaken and homeless, veve
treated treated with respect, and seldom, if ever, left without a rememberance
regardless of color. If you were met by him upon the highway, it i^as with an
open greeting and the same in parting. In his official church relations he
was tender, brotherly, and dignified, both conscientious and courteous, a
favorite with the young people. But his appeal to the wayward and eiring in
the ranks were dreaded and feared, though reveranced. He made his mistakes as
all do, but in the wind up was proven of the head and not of the heart. One
of his marked characteristics was the reconciliation of parties at vaiiance
anywhere and under all circumstances. Elder D. Hogwood served Hopewell longer-than
any of his predecessors, an Elder over fifty six years and clerk of the
Session thirty three years faithfully Earnestly and devotedly and at his death
17
leaving a legacy, if it is judlciovisly handled with a memorial to his name a,s
it goes on down through time, while nothing but the interest can be used and
that for a Pastor's Salary.
One of Hopewells laity 47 years
Concluding with a Short Sketch of one of Hopewells members Bro. Geo.
Peoples. He served as a soldier under Jackson at the Battle of New Orleans
against the British in l8l2. He was a man of brawny make. Strong and robust
in his younger days, and was noted as a brawler of a refractory disposition.
But when he wought mercy &amp; pardon at the foot of the cross there was a changed
man, as his afterlife has proven, uniting witn Hopewell Aug. 14, 1(332 and
Departing this life Apr. 21st., I879. To show more fully the character of the
man, he at one time called upon the wi-iter to grant him a favor which was
accepted on the spur of the moment. But in a second said to him don't
do it, it may bring ruin upon you and our friends. His head dropped upon his
breast with downcast eyes, every muscle being Ebctended was I'elaxed in a minute
he raised his head with a brighter countenance and a Smile upon his lips said
if you say, I won't. He was always a liberal giver for church purposes. The
recoi'ds show that he gave at one time fifty dollars for benevolent causes.
He was often called on for consultation and committee work, ever Eager and
willing to help in any work or cause to advance the church in his blessed
Mission. In his latter days he made a gift to Hopewell of several hundred
dollars worth of property put in the hands of a board of Trustees. Elected
by the church the proceeds of which ten dollars go to a Pastor's Salary, the
remainder to benevolent causes and church Expenses. There could be much more
said of each one of these characters, but feel that this is ample as we cele-brate
this day with appropriate ceremonies may we call to remembrance these
lives with solemnity as we dedicate this memorial of written facts addressed
to Hopewell.
Hopewell Church,
M-ilt.nn. Tenn-
</dc:description>
<dc:description>A written speech prepared for the 1916 anniversary of two Presbyterian churches in Rutherford County, Hopewell and Stone's River</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.) -- History; Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A.</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-02; mt2011-05-05</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication07ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/68</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>