<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>John Price Buchanan: farmer and politician</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hoffman, Carol</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 21</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>198?</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>19th century; 20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>J &lt; Sf r
JOHN PRICE BDCHANiUf
Farmer and Fblltlcian
bgr- Carol Hoffinazm
-6U-
JOHN PRIQE BUOHANAN&#8212; FARMER AND P0LIII3IAN
John Price Buchanan Is the only man from Rutherford
Oounty ever elected governor of Tennessee. He was one of
those basically unremarkable men who, through a strong sense
of duty and community service, attain high office. Lacking
the charisma of many politicians, most notably his predecessor,
Robert L, Taylor, he nevertheless brought a consistency and
thoughtfulness to his term as governor that is deserving of
more recognition. Although his administration Is remembered as
one of strife, if should be remembered that to a large extent
he was a victim of the culmination of long-term problems and
the political factionalism swirling around him,
Buchanan was born in Williamson County, Tennessee, a few
miles northeast of franklin, on October ^4, 18A7, His ances-tors
were among the first settlers of the Cumberland; his
great-grandfather was Major John Buchanan, founder of
Buchanan's Station, an early pioneer fort. His father, Thomas,
was a prosperous farmer and slave owner. The young Buchanan
was educated in the common schools of the area and had to gain
additional education by private study, an experience which pro-bably
led to his later interest in improving the Tennessee
public school system.
Although his father wanted him to go to college, at the
age of 16, Buchanan ran away from home and enlisted as a
private in Reddy's Escort (4th Alabama Cavalry) and was
assigned to Nathan Bedford Forrest's command, serving until
65
his unit surrendered at Pond Spring, Alabama, on May 17,
1865. According to a family story, while retreating from a
Yankee charge, Buchanan rode under a tree and cut his throat
on a hanging branch. For a long time he had people believing
the Yankees did it, but finally told the truth about the cause
2
of his wound, thus missing out on receiving a pension.
After the Civil War, Buchanan moved to Rutherford County
and married Frances (Fannie) McGill, daughter of James and
Amanda (Norman) McGill, on his twentieth birthday, October 24,
1867. In 1873 they moved to a farm on McGill family land
which had been inherited by Mrs. Buchanan, Located on the
Manchester Pike about eight miles southwest of Murfreesboro,
this became known as the Big Creek Stock Farm and encompassed,
in 1877, about l60 acres. The Buchanans had eight children
(plus one who died in infancy): James Thomas, John Price, Jr.,
Rebecca Jane, Robert Norman, Margaret Dosia, Susan Matthews,
Frances Louise, and James McGill,-^
Buchanan's political training and prominence in the
community began early. He first served as a delegate to the
Democratic state convention in 1876 and continued in this
capacity until his gubernatorial nomination In 1890, 4 He
also ran once for County Court Clerk and twice for District
Constable, but was defeated,"^ His start in politics was
described differently by Buchanan himself in an Interview with
a reporter for the Nashville Dally American the day after he
was nominated for governor. According to this story he was
a delegate to a convention to nominate candidates for the
66
legislature and his name was proposed. He declined, but his
name was put before the convention a second time and this
time he was nominated. Having never made a speech before, he
told two of his colleague , Mssrs. Avent and Sparks, that he
had a good horse and buggy and would drive them around if they
would do the talking. At the start of the trip one of the
other men became ill and Buchanan began soeaking for himself.^
Actually, he probably began speaking for himself earlier than
that since in 1881 he chaired a meeting of the Rutherford
County Democrats to resolve that the 100-3 debt settlement
(law to fund state debt at full face value by three percent
interest bonds, with interest coupons acceptable as tax
payment) was "a step toward serfdom."'^
However it began, Buchanan's fairly short success as a
politician cannot be separated from the rise of the farmer
movement in Tennessee and, indeed, in most of the U. S, Many
of the concerns he voiced and the legislation he was involved
with, both as a representative in the General Assembly and as
governor, were influenced by the farmer movement and,
naturally, by his own farm background, and he was to show a
remarkable consistency of thought throughout his six years in
Nashville,
In the years following the Civil War, farmers were
increasingly burdened with declining prices, rising costs,
overproduction and foreign competition. In addition, they
felt alienated from the local elites. As a result, several
farmers' organizations were formed, (The agrarian revolt in
67
Tennessee was not as profound as In the Deep South because of
a more even industrial development and less dependence on
cotton.) The most well known of these was the Grange (Patrons
of Husbandry) of which there were more than 1,000 chapters in
Tennessee by the 1870 's. As the Tennessee Grange declined in
membership in the early 1830 's, two organizations, the National
Agricultural Wheel and the Farmers' (or Southern) Alliance
moved in to fill the vacutim. These two groups were united in
December of 1888 as the Farmers' and Laborers' Union of
America, In Tennessee, the two groups were organized at
Nashville in July, 1889 under the same name (usually called
the "Farmers' Alliance" or simply the "Alliance") as a tax
exempt, chartered business corporation and acted as a farmers'
cooperative. By 1890 the Tennessee Alliance had between
30,000 and 50,000 members.^
Not initially a political organization, the Alliance's
main goal was to lessen farmers' dependence on merchants.
Theoretically, only farmers, farm laborers and country school
teachers, ministers, physicians, and mechanics were allowed
to Join, but in practice some men of property and status
became members as they enhanced the Alliance's social standing.
(Buchanan himself was the fourth largest landholder in the
25th District of Rutherford County.). Specifically excluded
was anyone connected by ownership or employment with a mer-cantile
business, lawyers and any stockholder in a bank.-"-^
A typical Alliance program Included the following
points: l) Just income tax; 2) popular election of officials;
6g
3) regulation of interstate commerce; 4) improvement of
patent laws; 5) pure food laws; 6) regulation of transporta-tion
systems (and ultimate government ownership); 7) free
silver coinage; 8) public school industrial education and
improvement of agricultural colleges; 9) restriction of the
liquor trade.
Naturally, in order to articulate these goals the
Alliance soon became a political force. Starting at the
grass-roots level, by 1888 4l out of 132 Tennessee legisla-
12
tors elected in November of that year were Alliancemen,
The next step was to recognize that execution of any political
program depended on capturing the machinery of the Democratic
party which had fallen into the hands of the conservative
"court house rings" after Reconstruction,
Buchanan Joined the Agricultural Society in 1883. He
became the first president of the Tennessee Alliance in 1587
and president of the combined Wheel and Alliance in July of
1889. The real power in the Alliance, however, was John H,
McDowell, vice president of the Southern branch of the
Alliance and editor of the Weekly Toiler (Nashville), the
movement's principal mouthpiece,
Buchanan first went to Nashville as a state representative
in 1887, As a freshman legislator Buchanan was not especially
active but did display interest in topics that he would
follow consistently during the next six years. They included
Civil War veteran's pensions, the improvement of the public
school system, economical government, the need for a new
69
Tennessee constitution and the betterment of conditions for
farmers and laborers.
In the Forty-Fifth General Assembly (188?) he introduced
House Bill 8, To pension certain soldiers, which passed with
amendments; authored an amendment to a road bill decreasing
the amount allowed for use of a wagon and team (adopted
March 24); and put forward a petition from the County Court
of Rutherford County relative to redistricting the various
counties into new school districts. Notably, it was left to
N.T. Delaney, of Sullivan County, to introduce House Bill 237,
To charter the Farmers' and Laborers' Association. He was a
member of the standing committees on Finance, Ways and Means,
Penitentiary and Tippling and Tippling Houses, -^
In the 1889 session of the General Assembly, Buchanan
became more active. Bills introduced included: House Bill
164 (with H,E, Palmer), To carry into effect Article 4,
Section 1 of the Constitution (referring to qualification of
electors); House Bill 203, To regulate the business of
banking;- House Bill 239, To amend the law apportioning the
State into congressional districts; and House Bill 543, To
prevent the location of hospitals by counties and munici-palities
within the vicinity of charitable institutions
maintained by the state. He was also influential in the
passage of House Bill 233, To exempt agricultural agents from
privilege tax.
Under the heading of "Explanations" Buchanan followed
his party and voted to support an Appropriation Bill (Senate
70
Bill 456), but objected to a raise In salaries for two
officials and to spending $4,000 for stationery; and voted no
on a Joint resolution to adjourn sine die "because there is a
quorum present in both Houses and there is important business
to transact which will require an extra session, and this is
both unnecessary and inexpedient when that business can now
be transacted" (with H.E, Palmer and nine others). Committee
memberships in the Forty-Sixth legislature were Finance, Ways
and Means and Charitable Institutions (chairman).^
The contest for the gubernatorial nomination was not
one of personalities so much as it was a fight among factions
of the Democratic party which had been in disarray since the
Civil War. Three distinct groups had emerged. The Bourbons
&#8212;
the Old South, states rights conservatives&#8212;were the strongest
faction though they lost control of the governor's office in
1886, Their leader was Senator Isham G. Harris, secessionist
leader and Civil War governor. The New South group favored
industrialization and, because of their resources, enlightened
leadership and success in bargaining with the Republicans for
patronage and legislation, they had an influence dispropor-tionate
to their size. Their leader was Colonel Arthur S,
Colyar, industrialist, lawyer, and publisher of the Nashville
Dally American. The third group was the small farm element,
or wool-hat boys, who looked for their leadership to Buchanan
and McDowell (and Andrew Jackson, Andrew Johnson and Robert L,
Taylor). ^5
71
When McDowell first announced he wanted Buchanan as
governor, the urban press did not take It seriously, and also
questioned the possible conflicts of Interest caused by
Buchanan's association with the Farmers' Alliance, a problem
that would continue to plague him until he retired from active
politics In 1892. Democratic papers stressed the importance
of party solidarity. In a short article copied from the Obion
Democrat at the beginning of 1890, the Nashville Daily
American wrote.
If J. P. Buchanan really means to run for governor
he should endeavor to escape forthwith from the hands
of some of his alleged friends. It may be added,
without overstepping the bounds of truth or propriety,
that the idea of J.P, having any symptoms of a states-man
borders somewhat on the ludicrous. ^&#176;
In the campaign leading to the Democratic convention of
1890, Buchanan's relative obscurity proved attractive to
farmers and other voters since It distanced him from the
machine politics they were dissatisfied with. By the middle
of May, 1890, 28 County Alliances and hundreds of sub-
Alliances endorsed Buchanan and proved to be ready-made
campaign organizations which were able to dominate county
conventions. 17 In Rutherford County he carried three out of
six wards in Murfreesboro and. In general, he was strongest
In Middle and Western Tennessee, winning all the delegates
from the Middle Tennessee counties of Marshall, Warren,
Grundy, Van Buren, White, Stewart and Cannon.^&#174;
The Democratic state convention, which was known as the
"Farmers' Convention," began on July 15, I890. Buchanan's
72
opponents were Jere Baxter, the New South candidate; Joslah
Patterson, for the Bourbons; and John Taylor,
The Alliance platform was tailored to avoid frightening
delegates with radical proposals. They pointedly excluded
mention of the Sub-Treasury Plan which they had long advocated
and limited themselves to calling for free coinage of silver,
a recognition that agrarian interests are the mainstay of a
dual system of government, condemning the Republicelns for
legislative discrimination against this class, and to con-demning
the granting of land to corporations instead of home-
/ V IQ steaders (the only true Alliance plank), ^
More far-reaching was the regular Democratic party
platform. It contained the following points: l) opposed to
Importation of pauper labor and for opening public lands for
homesteading; 2) gold and silver coinage and ready conversion
of paper money to metal; 3) extension of free school system;
4) strict economy and minimum government expenses; 5) just
and equal taxation; 6) amendment of lien laws for protection
of farmers and mechanics; 7) establishment and development of
good roads; 8) welcome capital and labor to the state; and
9) modification of the penal system to eliminate competition
20
with free labor*
Buchanan's name was put into nomination by Committee
Chairman J. D, Richardson and it took 26 ballots before he
was declared the Democratic candidate for governor. His
victory can be seen as being more the result of successfully
capitalizing on the enmity between the Bourbon and New South
groups than because of personal popularity.
73
Patterson, Senator Harris and John Taylor threw their support
behind him because of fear of a Republican victory (and Negro
domination) In the fall,
Buchanan's acceptance speech endorsed the principles of
the Democratic party: "... as long as the power of speech
will endure, I will be heard proclaiming to the people the
great principle of Democracy as enunciated by Jackson, Polk
and Johnson," He also declared himself opposed to large
national or state government and for strict adherence to the
21
Constitution.
Right after the convention, in an interview with a Daily
22
American reporter in his room at the Duncan Hotel, Buchanan
expanded on the topic of his loyalty to the Democratic party
and stated that the Interest of farmers lay with the party,
I am making this campaign as a Democrat on a
Democratic platform. I have never urged anybody to
support me because I was an alliance man or a farmer;
in fact, I have never told that I was a farmer in any
speech I have made. It is a grave mistake to suppose,
as some do, that I am seeking to array one class
against another, or that I want to benefit the agri-cultural
at the expense of other interests. I believe
that the farmers cannot be benefited by any course
which would be oppressive or unjust to other Interests.
None more than the agricultural interest is benefited
by the legitimate growth of the mercantile, manufac-turing
and railroad interests. It is to our interest
that the merchants with whom we deal should be
prosperous, that manufactures should be developed, and
that transportation facilities should be Increased and
cheapened. We want nothing that would injure any of
them, but we want to help all and hurt none. I want to
be a Governor for the whole people of the State, and
you know me well enough to know that I will be as I ^^
have always been a souare, clean, upper-case Democrat, -^
He would return to this theme over and over again in an
attempt to avoid strong identification with the Alliance,
74
part of his reasoning being that many of the Alliance demands
were national in scope and had no place in state politics.
There was much excitement in Murfreesboro when the news
of Buchanan's victory at the convention was received. It is
said that the Oourt House bell was rung for nearly an hour,
and the Murfreesboro Home Journal went so far as to put out
24 an extra. When he arrived back in Murfreesboro from
Nashville on July 19&#187; over 2,000 people met him at the depot.
A procession had been organized which included a pleasure
wagon carrying local society ladies and was emblazoned with
the slogans, "Andrew Johnson from the tailor's bench; Buchanan
from the plow," and "It is not wealth, nor pomp, nor state,
but git up and git that makes a man great," The procession
route started at the train station, went east on Main Street
to the Public Square and up to Academy Street, north on
Academy to College Street, west to Lebanon Street and then
back to the Square, -^
The gubernatorial contest began in the newspapers before
any of the candidates (Buchanan; Republican Lewis T, Baxter;
and David Oato Kelley, Prohibitionist) hit the campaign trail.
In the Daily American Buchanan, or "Old Buck" as he was now
being called, was praised as a man with the courage of his
convictions, an able leader of debate in the legislature, and
watchful of his constituents' interests. It was pointed out,
in an effort to reinforce his appeal to the farm element,
that he was a self-made man, did not have much money to spend
on politics and that his farm was not well Improved and lay in
an indifferent part of Rutherford County.
75
The J^ public an-controlled Nashville Banner , on the other
hand, dug up Buchanan's poor political showing on the local
level (see page 2) and once again questioned the influence
of the Alliance on Buchanan and the Democratic party which it
pictured ",,, kneeling down abjectly and taking upon its neck
the yoke of a secret class political organization, whose
pledged policy is in outright antagonism to the time-honored
and fundamental principles of -"democracy," Also pointed out
rfas the fact that the Republicans had had to give lip service
to some national policies, such as the Force Bill, that were
odious to the South, ^"^
Buchanan began his gubernatorial campaign in earnest
early in September, 1390. Speaking to a crowd in Franklin,
Williamson County, his opening speech followed Democratic
policy closely and was a model for future speeches and for
his legislative goals as governor.
He went on record as being for states' rights and against
alien ownership of land. Centralized wealth was blamed on
the ^publican tendency toward centralized government and
could be cured by revising the tariffs, breaking the power of
the monopolists, free coinage of silver and creating a greater
money supply. Economy in government was stressed and was used
as one argument against the Force Bill (which called for
federal supervision on Congressional elections), Buchanan
called for the extension of school system facilities and an
increase in the school term from four to nine months. His
enlightened views on penal reform included separating criminal
76
classes and decreasing competition with honest labor. The
establishment of good public roads and the development of
resources were also discussed. Finally, again, Buchanan
stressed that he was wedded to no special interests.^"
Organized out of Democratic headquarters in Room 7 of
the Maxwell House Hotel in Nashville, Buchanan's campaign
schedule was a busy one, especially considering the trans-portation
facilities of the era. Included in the schedule
were soeeches in:
September 5 South Pittsburgh
September 6 Sequatchie County
September 7 Jasper, Marion County
September 8 Dayton, Rhea County
September 10 Cleveland
September 12 Sweetwater, Monroe County
September 13 Morristown, Hamblen County
September 23 Tullahoma
September 29 Lebanon
September 30 Dover
October 1 Clarksville
October 2 Springfield
October 3 Gallatin
October 4 Centreville
October 6 Charlotte (cancelled because
of illness)
October 7 Pulaski
October 8 Lawrenceburg
October 9 Waynesboro
October 11 Savannah
Hia last campaign speech was delivered at the Masonic Hall in
29 Hashville on the day before the election, November 3.
As in all political contests, rumors and counter- rumors
were soon flying. To refute a report that the entire Murfrees-boro
bar would vote against Buchanan, the Daily American sent
a reporter to canvas the membership. He found that of the 25
members, l6 were for Buchanan, seven were against and two
were doubtful.
77
In reply to the Daily American 's claim that thousands
took part In a procession in Murfreesboro on November 1, the
Nashville Banner reported only 204 people, four carrisiges,
one drag, two bandwagons, four or five buggies and 60 people
on horseback. According to the Banner story this group
marched around for a half hour then went to Mason's Opera
House where transparencies were shown and Buchanan made the
same speech as elsewhere, on which many people walked out,^^
Election day in 1890 was on November 4 and the results
were as follows:
(Dem.)
Buchanan
(Re pub.)
Baxter
(Prohib.)
Kelley
East Tennessee 26,828 39,383 2,221
Middle Tennessee 53,297
(2,381)
22,126
(1,197)
6,790
( 349)
West Tennessee 33.424 14,572 2.071
Total 113,549 76,081 11,082
( ) Rutherford Oounty vote 32
The reasons for his victory were: 1) continuity of
voting habits; 2) organized Alliance support; and 3) the
discriminatory effect of new election laws. As was true at
the state convention, Buchanan's strength was in Middle and
West Tennessee. After his victory, he went to Florida to
3"5
recuperate,
Buchanan was sworn in as Governor of Tennessee on
January 19, 1891, His inaugeral address ran true to form.
Its main points:
lo The system of government has fallen into serious errors;
violated the principles of equality by the undue protection of
a favored class. It has made "dangerous strides toward
plutocracy by submission to the power of aggregated money; it
has centralized power until it threatens the destruction of
popular government and the rights of the States to local self-government.
It has by these errors fostered monopoly until
it has placed itself within the merciless grasp of this
relentless tyrant."
2, Tennessee has, on the whole, a good code of laws, Oare
should be taken to enact only needed laws and not overburden
the statute books, Buchanan believes in the Jeffersonian non-interference
theory of government. The weakness of the state
does not come from inefficient laws, so much as inefficient
execution of laws,
3, Government should encourage the development of the
material resources of the state. Progress should not be in
"booms" but in growth upon a solid base of an increase in
wealth, taxable property, resources and revenues bringing
prosperity to everyone. His administration will welcome all
capital and labor that are for the best interests of the
state in the development and proper use of resources.
Capital should be protected by the "strongest security guar-anteed
by law," The extension and further development of the
educational system depends on increased material prosperity;
crime will decrease as literacy increases,
4, Monopolies and sectionalism denounced.
79
In his first message to the legislature, Buchanan
expanded on the topics covered In the Inaugeral address and
in his previous speeches, the emphasis being on education
and penal reform (see Appendix 1 for summary), -^^
At first Governor Buchanan received praise and support
from both Democratic and Republican newspapers. The Nashville
Banner commended him for presenting a "well-considered and
broad-minded"message to the legislature and, quoting the
Memphis Commercial said, "He has laboriously and intelligently
addressed himself to his executive duties, won respect, and
made friends every day since his inaugu^ration. "^
But trouble wasn't long in coming and Buchanan's admin-istration
proved to be one of the stormiest in many years.
His problems revolved around three issues: 1) the distribu-tion
of patronage; 2) the Goal Miners' Insurrection in East
Tennessee; and 5) his continued affiliation with the Farmers'
Alliance and, especially, John H, McDowell.
As governor, Buchanan tried to follow a pragmatic policy
designed to build an independent base for his party. However,
in doing this, he inevitably alienated some of the party
regulars. Especially galling was the appointment of John H.
McDowell as coal-oil inspector of Nashville, a lucrative Job
($8,000 a year vs. only $4,000 for the governor) that was seen
as payment for his work as Buchanan's campaign manager. It
was predicted that McDowell's radical Alliance views would
reflect badly on the governor, ^"^
ao
The major event of Governor Buchanan's term of office
was the Coal Miners' Insurrection which took place in East
Tennessee, a revolt that had its roots in Tennessee's convict
lease system. After the Civil War there was a general
increase in crime in the South which the impoverished states
were ill-equipped to handle. Like many Southern states,
Tennessee began leasing convicts to companies in order to pay
for the penal system, and even make a profit. During Grovernor
Buchananfe administration the lease was held by the Tennessee
Coal Iron and Railroad Company at #100,000 per year. The
convicts were put to work in TO I mines and sub-leased to
Other mining companies in East Tennessee. The convict lease
system had long been criticized both for the deplorable
conditions under which the convicts were kept and because
cheap convict labor took jobs from honest laborers.
Conditions were also poor for the honest miners. They
were paid in scrip, sometimes at irregular intervals, were
forced to trade at the company stores and could not trust
the weighmen employed by the mine companies.
These grievances came to a head in the summer of 1891
when miners at the Tennessee Coal Company mine in Briceville,
Anderson County, were told to sign a new "iron-clad" contract
which would have left them little better off than slaves.
The miners refused to sign and on July 5 convicts were
brought into Briceville to take their place. Ten days later
the miners took over the convicts* stockade and took the
prisoners, their guards and officers to Coal Creek where they
Bl
were put on a train for Knoxvllle, The same thing happened
on July 20, both at Brlceville and at the Knoxville Coal Oo.
mine at Ooal Creek, To each uprising Governor Buchanan res-ponded
with state militia&#8212;first three companies on July 16,
then 14 companies, under (Jeneral Sam T. Games. Governor
Buchanan's general attitude toward the miners, as he told
them in an address at Thistle Switch, was that he had to
enforce the laws and that they should go to court to redress
their grievances. By agreeing to call a special session of
the legislature to examine the problem, the governor was able
to avoid bloodshed and he personally accompanied the convicts
back to the stockades at Briceville and Ooal Creek on July 25o^^
Public opinion, in general, was sympathetic to the
miners and Governor Buchanan was criticized for being a tool
of the industrialists and for overreaching his powers by
calling out the militia. Also, the problems of the convict
lease system and the miners' grievances were only postponed,
not really solved.
Governor Buchanan called an extraordinary session of the
legislature on August 31, 1B91&#171; Twelve points were enumerated
as purposes of the session:
1, give executive dlspof^al of sufficient forces (civil or
military) to execute the laws;
2, reform penitentiary and convict lease system;
3, prohibit use of scrip and penalties for interference
with state convicts;
4, amend or appeal state election laws;
82
5o dividing state into representational, senatorial and
floterial districts and apportioning legislators;
6, amend division of congressional districts so as to
include Sequatchie County;
7, change Judicial circuits and chancery divisions and time
of holding court;
8, provide for payment of expenses connected with establishing
a law court at Cumberland Gap;
9, consider appropriation for a Tennessee exhibit at the
World's Pair;
10, make laws for the encouragement and benefit of the state
militia;
11, amend existing revenue and assessment laws to pay for
changes brought about by extra session legislation;
12, make necessary appropriations to defray militia expenses
40
at Briceville and Coal Creek, and of the extra session.
In his message to the session the governor talked at
length on the penitentiary question and the problems at the
mines and recommended: 1) repeal of the lease law; 2) imme-diate
restriction of convicts to a few mines through changes
in the lease contract; 3) change in the criminal law so
counties could use minor offenders on public roads; and
4) removal of the penitentiary to a location outside the
Nashville city limits. ^^
The extra session was not a success, at least from the
miners' point of view. Although a law was passed prohibiting
payment in scrip, it had a limited term. Primarily, the
extra session appropriated more money for the militia and gave
the governor limited authority to use them in situations where
local officials could not cope. It did not repeal the lease
law, which shortly afterwards were upheld by the State
Supreme Court (presided over by Chief Justice Peter Turney)
in a test case.
In the fall of 1891, the miners rebelled again, this
time under the influence of a more radical leadership. On
October 31, convicts were released at the Tennessee Coal
Mine and the stockade and buildings burned. This action was
repeated at Coal Creek and, on November 2, at Oliver Springs,
Governor Buchanan was very slow to act and when he did it
was only to reinforce branch prisons and offer rewards for
the leaders of the miners and for the escaped convicts. With
the convicts gone, the Coal Creek Valley miners were once
again employed with the iron-clad contract abolished and
their own check-weighman.
The peace was not to last, however. On December 51
&#187;
1891, the convicts were returned to the Knoxville Iron Mine
along with the militia, a stockade, trenches and a Satling
Gun. In August, 1892, the fourth miners' revolt began, this
time in Middle Tennessee at the Tennessee Coal Iron and
Railroad Company mines at Tracy City and Inman. Governor
Buchanan and the prison board issued a joint statement
declaring the lease contract forfeit, but before it could be
carried out there were new rebellions at Oliver Springs and
Coal Creek, A large militia force suppressed this last
uprising, this time not without bloodshed.
^4
Although over 300 people were Indicted and tried after
this rebellion, most were acquitted or given minor sentences
and the miners were back in the mines by the fall. The
convict lease system was finally abolished in 1896 when the
contract ran out, at which time the convicts went to work
mining coal for state use only at the new facilities at
ho
Brushy Mountain, '^
Buchanan's political career was badly damaged by the
Goal Miners' Insurrection. He was caught between the busi-ness
element who considered the strike a crime and thought
it his duty to enforce the law and labor and reformers
(including the Farmers' Alliance) who considered the system
unjust. Some blamed him for negotiating with strikers,
others for calling out the militia. He was made to appear
the victim rather than the master of circumstances, and
perhaps he was.
The Farmers' Alliance faction of the Democratic party
was able to get into office only because of the disarray of
the regular party; they were never fully accepted by party
leaders and as soon as the old-line Democrats saw an oppor-tunity
they began working against Buchanan. The Goal Miners'
Insurrection, of course, gave them just such an opportunity
and they used this and their dissatisfaction with his
patronage policies to add fuel to their campaign. By late
in 1891 Bourbon successors to Buchanan were being mentioned,
including Ohief Justice Peter Tumey of Franklin Goimty. By
March of 1892, 17 Democratic dailies had declared themselves
S5
43
opposed to the governor's re-election, and the Bourbons
had repudiated the leadership of Buchanan and McDowell,
Buchanan's primary problem, however, was still his rela-tionship
with John H. McDowell, the Farmers' Alliance and,
by the Spring of 1892, the newly-formed Peoples' Party of
Populists.
McDowell was accused of fraternizing with Negroes and
even with dining with a Negro, Jehazy Cole, which stirred up
the always-present fear of Republican-Negro domination.
Buchanan tried to maintain his position by reaffirming
his loyalty to the Democrats and distancing himself from
the Populists. He thought a third party of agrarians would
be detrimental to the South and made a public statement of
his views in late March, 1892:
If you wish a declaration of principles from me,
look at the Democratic platform of 1890, upon which
I was nominated, by which I pledged myself to stand
... am still standing, and expect to stand until the
Democracy . . . shall formulate another . .
.
I am opposed to a third party or peoples' party ...
There is need of an unbroken front in the ranks
of the Democratic party against Republicanism and
third partyism, and I regret to say that the radical
elements in the party are endeavoring to array
faction against faction. The great conservative
masses will, however, I believe, hold in check these
elements in accord with the spirit of the call issued
by the National Democratic Committee,
Memphi s Oommercial ,
.
March 28, 1892 ^^
But the damage had been done. The Democratic party was
again factionalized as in 1890, but this time it did not
work in Buchanan's favor. Rutherford and Tipton Counties
each sent two delegations to represent them at the guberna-torial
convention of 1892 because neither Buchanan nor
Turney men were strong enough to prevail. Many former
Buchanan supporters joined the Peoples' Party, thus dis-rupting
the Alliance faction. Some people said they wanted
to vote for "Buchanan without McDowell," but the governor
would not break with him.^ The Peoples' Party, on its part,
tried to take strength away from both the Democrats and the
Republicans, To make matters worse, McDowell declared him-self
a Populist and by June 1 Bourbon control was almost
complete.
Realizing his situation vis-a-vis the Democratic party
was hopeless, Buchanan withdrew from the governor's race on
July 30, 1892, Calling his opponents "sky-blue bolters" and
" radicals," he made a rather bitter speech in which he announced
he was no longer a candidate for renomination in which he
covered the following subjects:
1, He has tried to keep the party united but it has now
split into hostile factions.
2, He has been true to both the Alliance and the party.
3, An organization like the Alliance should be nonpartisan
but must concern itself with the effects of legislation. The
Democratic party should promote the interests of all and give
attention and consideration to the needs of all classes since
it claims to be a party of the people,
4, His continued connection with the Farmers' Alliance has
bound him by no political pledge.
5. He has obeyed the policies and principles that were
enunciated when elected in 1890, "Had a like obedience been
rendered by all those who accepted its declarations, the
party of Tennessee would have continued united and harmonious."
6, The radical faction affected alarm because of the
presence of Alliancemen and declared "vindictive warfare" on
all who did not agree. They resorted to unfair means to
secure the party machinery and coerce voters at the primaries.
They sacrificed party welfare for factional gain.
7. The August 9 convention will be controlled by the same
elements which are not representative of a majority of voters,
8, He thanked his friends for their generous and faithfvil
support and released them from any restrictions which might
47
be imposed by his continued candidacy.
Shortly after, Governor Buchanan was drafted by a
coalition of Alliancemen, Populists and "Buchanan Democrats"
and announced as an independent on August 15, Ihe Populists
endorsed his candidacy on August 18, The other candidates in
this race were Peter Turney (Democratic), George W, Winstead
(Republican) and Edward H. East (Prohibitionist).
As an Independent candidate, Governor Buchananfe platform
included free coinage of silver, an increase in the currency,
popular election of U, S. Senators, restriction in agriculture
futures dealing, free trade, abolition of national banks and
prohibition of alien ownership of land. The last two planks
of the platform went beyond the ideas of the Tennessee
88
Populists; the whole platform was similar to the Alliance
platform of 1890.^&#174;
In Southern politics In 1892 it was not unusual for the
Republicans and Populists to cooperate against the Demo-crats.
In Tennessee, for instance, the Republicans offered
to withdraw Winstead in return for Populist support of
President Harrison, Here again, Buchanan became the victim
of his loyalty to J. H, McDowell,
On October 23, a sensational account came out (called
the Ivins-Hill letters) concerning a deal engineered by
McDowell between the Republicans and Populists, According to
this deal, the Republican national committee agreed to pay
McDowell $15,000 for bringing Buchanan into the contest and
for aiding the Republicans in electing legislators and con-gressmen,
McDowell was to be further rewarded by election
to the U, S, Senate by the Republican/Populist-controlled
legislature. It was charged that McDowell failed to live up
to his part of the bargain, except for the candidacy of
Buchanan and, in addition, threatened to withdraw him from
the race when the $15,000 was slow in coming,^ This was
the final blow to Buchanan's hopes for a second term;
although he was not implicated he was made to look like a
tool of McDowell,
The Republican/Populist fusion failed and those who
voted for Buchanan in November represented an alienated
element of the Democratic party, both things combining to
seriously weaken Democratic hold of the state for several
years to come. The total vote in the 1892 gubernatorial
election was Tumey, 126,348; Winstead, 100,577; and Buchanan,
29,918,^^ The Populists won only five out of 99 House seats
51
and one Senate seat.^
In spite of the large number of Alliancemen and farmers
in the Forty- Seventh General Assembly, the legislation pro-duced
was rather lackluster. Important acts of Buchanan's
administration included the declaration of the first Monday
in September as a legal holiday, the creation of a Bureau
of Statistics and provision for inspection of mines and
provision of assistance for Peabody Normal College. A Con-federate
Pension Bill was enacted, first appropriating $60,000
(raised to $100,000 in 1899 and $980,000 in 1923). Perhaps
most important was the act to establish and maintain a uni-form
system of public schools&#8212;the "Secondary School Law
(Chapter 132, Acts of 1891). Also during Buchanan's term,
interest on $469,000 worth of bonds was reduced from six to
four percent.^
Buchanan's final act as governor was to send a message
to the legislature on January 9, 1393. In this message he
discussed at length the labor troubles and the status of the
prison question, revision of the criminal laws and convict
labor. He reported on state finances and expenditures and
spent considerable time on the public school system, including
statistical evidence of its growth and development over the
preceding two years. Also reported on were charitable insti-tutions
and the Farmers' Institutes, Finally, he called for
90
a new Constitutional Convention, amendment of the election
laws and inspection of state banks, 53
Buchanan probably realized from the beginning that his
governorship might only last one term, depending as it did
on a critical balance of Alliancemen and lack of unity among
old-line Democrats, He followed consistent and fairly pro-gressive
policies throughout his political career and that
his term as governor was less than a success was not entirely
his fault. Like so many high-ranking politicians before and
since he became a victim of situations not of his own making
and of the excesses of a subordinate, in this case, McDowell,
His personal character and integrity were never seriously
questioned,
Buchanan had never moved his family to the Governor's
Mansion preferring Instead to commute to the city. After
completing his term in office he returned to farming and
stock raising. With the exception of supporting his old
enemy, E. W, Oarmack, editor of the Nashville Daily American.
in the Prohibitionist campaign of 1908, Buchanan was never
again active in politics. He did, however, retain an interest
in politics and was eventually accepted again by the Demo-cratic
party.
As before he went into state politics, Buchanan retained
an active position in community and agricultural affairs. He
was a member of the board of the Farmers ' Voice , a ruling
elder of the Mt, Tabor Cumberland Presbyterian Church and a
member of the Free and Accepted Masons,
^
91
In 1925 or 1926 the Buchanans moved into a house at
216 Fourth Street in Murfreesboro. Fannie Buchanan died on
November 30, 1927. The governor was in ill health for the
last six years of his life and practically an invalid for the
last two-and-a-half years, Buchanan died on May 14, 1930 and
was buried, beside his wife, at Evergreen Cemetery, At the
time of his death he still owned the farm, but it was
divided into three sections and the house was torn down in
1953.5'^
The Buchanan family has remained prominent in Murfrees-boro,
Buchanan's daught, Rebecca, taught at Middle Tennessee
State University; the "Buchanan Dramatic Club" is named after
her, Rebecca died in 1965. Elizabeth Buchanan Whorley,
following in her grandfather's footsteps, is active in the
Rutherford County Democratic party, ^&#176; But what the governor
would have liked best perhaps is the new John Price Buchanan
School located not very far from the farm on which he spent
so much of his life.
92
Appendix 1
Summary of Governor John Price Buchanan's first message to the
Forty-Seventh General Assembly of the State of Tennessee,
February 11, 1891. (See Footnote 35)
1, Federal Relations
There is widespread discontent among agriculturalists, in
common with almost every other state, ,,, result of unjust
Federal sectional and class legislation for tVie last 30 years.
The state legislature is powerless to remove them and also
powerless to do anything about the short money supply,
2, Finances
Congratulated past legislature on the success of the
assessment law and recommended appointment of a State Board of
Equalizers for the purpose of more evenly adjusting taxes
among the various counties.
3o Educational Interests
a. Public Schools - The duty of the state to educate
children is no longer a debatable question. In towns
the municipal tax has enabled public school terms
lengthened to nine months and a course of study to meet
lower classes of a college or university, but in the
country the term is limited to four months on the average
and to elementary grades. Recommends extension of the
public school system, establishment of schools in which
higher branches can be taught, uniform textbooks and a
book on civil government,
b. Remuneration for the State Superintendent of Public
Instruction should be placed on a permanent basis.
c. $2,000 appropriation for teachers' institutes,
d. Praise for the University of Tennessee,
e. Agricultural College - Must assent to additional
appropriations by Congress to land-grant colleges under
the Morrill Act of 1890,. Request for further appropria-tion
for Teachers' Department and scholarships.
f. Peabody Normal College - Looking for money from
Peabody Board of Trustees.
4, Charitable Institutions
Need a reformatory for youthful criminals, an industrial
school for girls and other charities.
93
a. Confederate Soldiers Home is most imperative,
b. Private Charities - Thanks and gratitude of the State.
5&#187; Agricultural Department
There have been attempts to abolish the Department from
the belief that it has no practical benefits; this is due to
insufficient funds,
a. The Commissioner of Agriculture should hold institutes
for the purpose of "awakening activity of thought .o.
bringing about an interchange of opinions and experience
upon practical problems, and creating a professional spirit
and pride among farmers,"
b. Increase the appropriation from $8,000 to #10,000,
6, Geological Reports
a. Interest in investment in mineral resources in
Tennessee warrants publishing geological reports (last
appeared in 1869),
b, -Especially important if State builds an exhibition at
the World's Pair in 1892.
7, World's Pair
Recommended an aporopriation for an exhibition commen-surate
with the necessities involved and the ability of the
State,
8, Dairy Interests
Should receive encouragement and such protection by law
as will prevent adulteration of products,
9, State Board of Health
a. Board of Health has asked for legislation to help it
register births and deaths,
b. Recommended legislation concerning health of livestock.
c. Recommended sanitary organization by counties to
prevent spread of contagious diseases among animals.
10, County Roads
Can't see how a uniform law can be reached; left it in the
hands of the Road Congress to help the legislature formulate a
good law.
94
11, Penitentiary-
Repeated arguments for new penitentiary.
12, Convict Labor
a. Convict labor is the best solution to the problem of
expenses,
b. It is injurious to criminals and unjust to taxpayers
to keep convicts in idleness,
c. No practical plan as yet,
13. Corporations and Trusts
a. Talked about the growth of trusts,
b. Recommended "such restrictions, as amendments to
corporation law, as to prevent the issuing of charters
to any other than public, quasi-public, and such indus-trial
purposes as lie beyond the field of individual
endeavor.
c. Recommended further restrictions to prevent forming
of trusts,
14, Inspection of State Banks
15. Election Laws
The present election laws are a success, -t^emedying any
defects will not leave any excuse for Federal intervention.
16. Military Affairs
The efficiency of the State Guard should be increased and
the duties of the Adjutant-General be restructured so he can
devote proper time to the military.
17, Improvement of the Capitol
Provision should be made for maintenance and repair,
18. Appropriations
Should be adequate to preserve credit, sustain what has
already been undertaken and answer other needs.
Conclusion - It is not the number of laws enacted but their
character and quality that will determine their usefulness.
95
Appendix 2
Buchanan, James. Interview taped by Jeff Whorley (grandson)
and Dr. James Buchanan (son), 1970 (transcribed December 14,
1981).
Jeff This is Jeff Whorley, With me are my uncle,
Dr. James Buchanan of Virginia Tech and my
grandfather, James Buchanan, of Rutherford County. We shall
talk about my great-grandfather, John P. Buchanan who was
governor of Tennessee from 1891 to 1393 and the only governor
from Rutherford Oounty,
Dr. Buchanan Thank you, Jeff. That's fine. I think we
can have a nice conversation. Actually, I
don't recall too much about my grandfather. I was about 13
years old when he died. It was about 1933 as I remember, I
remember mostly an old man with white whiskers who used to
bump me up and down on his lap and sing something about
"chicken foot neck and a gizzard" and a few things like that;
a man, however, whom everybody respected a great deal even in
his old age, I also remember as a boy about your size I used
to wander around upstairs in the old big house which unfor-tunately
is no longer here and find all of this literature
about his political campaigns, all about the Farmers' Alliance
and the Wall Street robber barons and so forth during the
Populist period which he was the representative of in the State
of Tennessee. I think they actually elected something like
six governors in 1890 which was a rather strange phenomenon.
The Farmers' Alliance party rather than the regular Democrats,
Jeff, what I suggest is that you ask Papa what he remembers
about the governor.
Jeff Papa, what do you remember when your father
was governor? Tell us about it.
James Buchanan Well, I was most too small to know much
about when he was governor, but something
happened that made an impression on me about that time. You
know the state hadn't been working prisoners in the mine up
there up till about the time he was governor and they sent
some state prisoners up there and the miners resented it and
they undertook to run them off. They had to call the state
militia and there was some bloodshed along about that time at
Brushy Mountain, Inman. H.H, Bradley, my uncle by marriage, was
superintendent of the mines then and had to
and along after that when he was defeated by Pete Turney, they
brought that all up, you know, about calling the state militia
out to fight the people who lived there, who made a living by
mining. That's about all I remember now,
Jeff What about after he was governor? What about
you taking him to the train at Rucker?
96
James Buchanan I went about every other day to Rucker for
so many years, while he stayed in politics.
And I was just a little shaver and I'd ride behind him to
Rucker and get him on the train and I'd put on a show coming
back. He'd tell me be sure not to ride them horses fast and
I'd stand up in the saddle and put a regular show on. People
would come out and say yonder come that little ole Buchanan
boy. He's going to get killed. Lord have mercy, he's going
to get killed.
Dr. Buchanan Then you went back and got him at night,
James Buchanan And I'd go and get him in the evening, you
know, and I had to ride about five miles in
the dark. Scared, oh, and I had to go by a church and a
graveyard and you talk about going, I was moving on, I passed
that graveyard and I heard somebody holler. Away I went and
he hollered at me again a little louder and a little louder.
Finally, he caught up with me. He'd got a train that stopped
about halfway between Rucker and Christiana, He made them
back up and put him off and he got a man and a buggy and
horse and caught me over there. Like to scared me to death.
But I made it home and I'm here now.
Jeff Was the governor in the Civil War?
James Buchanan Yes, he was in there the last year, run away
from home and Joined the last year of the
war. They went to Alabama, They fought one year in the war.
He was only 16 years old at the time.
Dr. Buchanan Wasn't there something about running under
a bush and cutting his throat?
James Buchanan Yes. The Yankees was charging and they
were running. They had them cut off from
the main beginning and he run under a tree with a great bamboo
stringing down and caught him under the chin and cut his
throat from one side to the other, and he went in first and
told them he got cut by Yankees and had them believing it for
a long time. If he hadn't finally told up he could have been
drawing a pension,
Jeff What about the Farmers' Alliance party?
Was it an offset of the Democrat party?
James Buchanan That Farmers' Alliance, now let me see.
There wasn't nothing on earth but sort of a
farmers' union and they never could get organized again. That
was the beginning of the farmers' union.
Dr. Buchanan After his term the Democratic party sort of
took him back in again, didn't they?
97
James Buchanan
Jeff
Dr. Buchanan
James Buchanan
Jeff
James Buchanan
After he got beat? Yes.
Vfhat sort of politics did the governor stay
in after his term in office?
Did he ever run for anything else? He
liked to hang around Nashville,
He was always a politician. Stayed in
politics as long as he lived.
Was the governor a good farmer?
Yes, he must have been pretty good to raise
eight children on the farm. Must have been
a pretty fair farm.
9B
FOOTNOTES
Tennessee Historical Oonunission, Historical Marker
3D30, "John Price Buchanan;" Tennessee: The Volunteer State,
Vol. Ill (Nashville: The S. J. Olarke Publishing Co., 1923),
p, ; Biosraphical Directory. Tennessee General Assembly &#171;
1796-1967 , Rutherford County (Nashville: Tennessee State
Library and Archives) , p, &#8226;
^Ibid, , po ; James Buchanan, Interview taped by Jeff
Whorley and Dr. James Buchanan, 1970 (transcribed December 14,
1931), p. 2.
-^Biographical Directory , p, ; Rutherford County, Tennesee,
County Clerk's Office, Minute Book EE, 1^66, p. 95, and Book
DD, 1865, p. 668; Rutherford County, Tennessee, County Court
Clerk's Office, Minute Book GG, p. 12; Mary B. Hughes,
Hearthstones (Murfreesboro, TN: Mid-South Publishing Co., Inc.,
1942), p. 67; Rutherford County, Tennessee, Tax Records, 1877,
p. 186.
4Biographical Directory , p .
^Nashville Banner . 31 July, 1890, p. 2,
^Nashville Daily American . 20 July, 1890, p. 1,
7'Roger L, Hart, Redeemers. Bourbons and Populists :
Tennessee 1870-1B96 (Baton Rouge: State University Press,
1975), p. 53.
Q
&#176;Robert E. Corlew, Tennessee; A Short History . 2nd ed.
(Knoxville: University of Tennessee Press, 1981), p. 6,
^J, A. Sharp, "The Entrance of the Farmers' Alliance
Into Tennessee Politics," ETHSP 9 (1937): 79.
'^Roger L. Hart, Redeemers. Bourbons and Populists:
Tennessee 1870-1896 (Baton Rouge: State University Press,
1975), p. 113 and 127.
&#8226;''&#8226;^Daniel Merritt Robison, Bob Taylor and the Agrarian
Revolt in Tennessee (Chapel Hill, NO: University of North
Carolina Press, 1935), p. 137-8.
^^Roger L, Hart, Redeemers. Bourbons and Populists :
Tennessee 1870-1896 (Baton Rouge: State University Press,
1975), p. 129.
&#8226;^Journal of the House of Representatives of the Forty-
Fifth Assembly of the State of Tennessee (Nashville:
Marshall &amp; Bruce, 1887), pp. 204, 950, 191, 135-6,
99
^y,
^ Journal of the House of Representatives of the Forty-
Six General Assembly of the State of Tennessee (Nashville;
Marshall &amp; Bruce, 1889), pp. 76, 101, 113, 310, 717, 721, 8l6,
827, 92-3.
^^Robert E. Oorlew, Tennessee; A Short History (Knoxville;
University of Tennessee Press, 1931), p, 372; J. A. Sharp,
"The Entrance of the Farmers' Alliance Into Tennessee Politics,"
The East Tennessee Historical Society's Publications 9 (1937)
:
^_
^"Nashville Daily American . 20 January 1890, p, 4,
^'Roger L, Hart, Redeemers. Bourbons and Populists ;
Tennessee 1870-1896 (Baton Rouge: Louisiana State University
Press, 1975), p. 138.
^Sj, A. Sharp, "The Entrance of the Farmers' Alliance
Into Tennessee Politics," The East Tennessee Historical
Society's Publications 9 (1937); ^2^
IQ^Roger L. Hart, Redeemers. Bourbons and Populists :
Tennessee 1870-1896 (Baton Rouge; Louisiana State University
Press, 1975), pp. 142-3. The Sub-Treasury Plan was a scheme
to assist farmers in which the federal government would
receive non-perishable crops as security for farm loans,
saving farmers from having to sell in glutted markets and
making the money supply more flexible.
on
^Daniel Merritt Robison, Bob Taylor and the Agrarian
Revolt in Tennessee (Chapel Hill; University of North
Carolina Press, 1935), pp. 144-5.
^^Nashville Daily American . 19 July 1890, p. 1,
^^Nashville Daily American . 15 July 1890, p. 1.
23"Mr. Buchanan Talks," Nashville Daily American . 19
July 1890, p. 4.
^^Nashville Daily American . 19 July 1890, p. 1.
^^Nashville Daily American . 20 July 1890, p. 1.
^^Nashville Daily American . 19 July 1890, p. 2.
^'^Nashville Banner . 31 July 1890, p. 2.
^%ashville Daily American . 3 September 1890, p. 1.
^^Nashville Daily American . 2, 7, 12, 13, 28 September
1890; Nashville Banner . 3 November 1890, p. 5,
100
^^Nashvllle Daily American . 25 October 1890, p. 1.
^^"Buck at Murfreesboro," Nashville Banner . 3 November
1890, p. 1.
^^Oharles A. Miller (prep). The Official and Political
Manual of the State of Tennessee ^Nf&amp;shville: Tennessee State
Library and Archives, 1890; reprint ed. , Spartanburg, SO:
The Reprint Company, Publishers, 1974), pp. 278-80.
^&#8226;^Murfreesboro Free Press . 21 November 1890, p. 1.
^ John Price Buchanan, "Inaugeral Address" (January 19,
1891), Appendix to the House Journal of the Forty- Seventh
General Assembly of the State of Tennessee (Nashville; Albert
B. Travel, Printers to the State, 1891), pp. 5-10.
&#8226;^^John Price Buchanan, "First Message," (February 11,
1 891 ) f Appendix to the House Journal of the Forty-Seventh
General Assembly of the State of Tennessee (Nashville:
Albert B. Travel, Printer to the State, 1"91) , pp. 13-30.
5""The Governor's Message," Nashville Banner . 12 February
1891, p. ^; 31 March 1891, p. 4.
^"^Nashville Banner . 7 April 1891, p. 4.
58oartter Patten, A Tennessee Chronicle (Chattanooga:
By the Author, 1953) i p. 251.
^^k. 0. Hutson. Jr., "The Overthrow of the Convict Lease
System in And. Co.," The East Tennessee Historical Society's
Publications 7 (1935) J 121.
^^House Journal of the Extraordinary Session of the
Forty-Seventh General Assembly . August 31. 1891 (Nashville:
Marshall &amp; Bruce, Printers to the State, 1B91), pp. 4-5.
^^Ibid., pp. 9-25.
^2a, C. Hutson, Jr., "The Overthrow of the Convict Lease
System in Tennessee,", The East Tennessee Historical Society's
Publications 8 (1936): 83-98.
^^Roger L. Hart, Redeemers. Bourbons and Populists ;
Tennessee 1870-1896 (Baton Rouge: Louisiana State University
Press, 1975), p. IBl.
^^Ibid., p. 184.
^^ashville Banner . 4 April 1892, p. 1.
101
SELEOTED BIBLIOGRAPHY
Primary Sources
Buchanan, James. Interview taped by Jeff Whorley and Dr. James
Buchanan, 1970 (transcribed December 14, 1981).
Buchanan, John Price, "Inaugeral Address" (January 19, 1891).
Appendix to the House Journal of the Forty-Seventh
General Assembly of the State of Tennessee . First Session,
1891. Nashville: Albert B. Travel, Printer to the State,
1891.
. "First Message " (February 11, 1891) &#8226; Appendix to
the House Journal of the Forty-Seventh General Assembly
of the State of Tennessee . First Session. l891o Nasbvillej
Albert B. Travel, Printer to the State, 1891.
"Governor's Message" (January 9, 1895). Appendix
to the House Journal of the Fprty-Eishth General Assembly
of the State of Tennessee . 1893. Nashville; Albert B.
Travel, Printer to the State, 1893.
"Buck at Murfreesboro," Nashville Banner . 3 November 1390,
p. 1.
The Daily American (Nashville), 20 July 1890, p. 1,
The Daily American (Nashville), 3 September 1890, p. lo
"He's Out-Buchanan Withdraws from the Race for Governor."
The Knoxville Tribune . 31 July 1892, p. 1.
House Journal of the Extraordinary Session of the Forty-Seventh
General Assembly . Au-^ust 31. 1891. Nashville: Marshall &amp;
Bruce, Printers to the State, 1891,
Journal of the House of Representatives of the Forty-Fifth
General Assembly of the State of Tennessee . Nashville:
Marshall &amp; Bruce, 1887,
Journal of the House of Representatives of the Forty-Sixth
General Assembly of the State of Tennessee , Nashville:
Marshall &amp; Bruce, 1889.
"Mr. Buchanan Talks." The Daily American (Nashville), 19
July 1890, p. 4.
Nashville Banner . 4 April 1892, p. 1,
Rutherford Oovmty, Tennessee. County Court Clerk's Office.
Minute Book EE, 1866, p. 95,
102
Rutherford County, Tennessee. County Court Cleric's Office.
Minute Boole GG, 1872, p. 12*
Rutherford County, Tennessee, Tax Records, 1877, p, 186,
Whorley, Jeff, Telephone Interview, 25 November 1981,
Secondary Sources
Biographical Directory. Tennessee General Assembly 1796-1967
(Rutherford County). Nashville: Tennessee State Library
and Archives,
Corlew, Robert E. Tennessee; A Short History. 2nd ed,
Knoxville: University of Tennessee Press, 1981.
The Daily American (Nashville), 20 January 1890, p, A.
The Daily American (Nashville), 15 July 1890, p. 1,
The Daily American (Nashville), 19 July 1890, p. 1,
The Daily American (Nashville), 2, 7, 12, 13 September 1890,
The Daily American (Nashville), 28 September 1890, p. 10,
The Dally American (Nashville), 25 October 1890, p. 1.
Hart, Roger L. Redeemers. Bourbons and Populists; Tennessee
1870-1896. Baton Rouge; Louisiana State University
Press, 1975.
The Home Journal (Murfreesboro) , 16 May 1930, p. 1,
Hughes, Mary B, Hearthstones . Murfreesboro, TN: Mid-South
Publishing Co., Inc., 19A2.
Hutson, A. C, Jr. "The Coal Miners 'Insurrection of 1891 in
Anderson County. Tennessee . " i'he i^ast i'enne s see His-torical
Society's Publication 7 (1935): 103-121.
Hutson, A. C. , Jr. "The Overthrow of the Convict Lease System
in Tennessee," The East Tennessee Historical Society's
Publication 8 (1936), pp, S2-103,
Miller, Charles A, (ed.). The Official and Political Manual
of the State of T ennessee . Spartanburg, SO: The Reprint
Company, Publishers, 1974.
Moore, John Trotwood, and Foster, Austin P, Tennessee. The
Volunteer State, 1796-1923. Vol. 1, Chicago: Thi
^. J. Clarke Publishing Company, 1923,
Murfrees boro Free Press . 21 November 1890, p. 1,
103
Nashville Banner . 31 July 1890, p. 2.
Nashville Banner . 12 February 1891, p. 4; 31 March 1891, p. 4.
Nashville Banner. 7 April 1891, p. 4,
The Nashville Tennessean . May 15, 1930, p. 1,
News Journal (Murfreesboro) , 11 November 1981, p. 17,
Patten, Oartter. A Tennessee Chronicle . Chattanooga, TN: By
the Author, 1953.
Roblson, Daniel Merrltt. Bob Taylor and the Agrarian Revolt
In Tennessee . Chapel Hill: University of North Carolina
Press, 1935.
Sharp, J, A, "The Entrance of the farmers' Alliance Into
Tennessee Politics." The East Tennessee Historical
Society's Publications 9 (1937); 77-92.
Sharp, J, Ao "The ''armers' Alliance and the Peoples' Party
In Tennessee," The East Tennessee Historical Society's
Publications 10 (1938): 90-113.
Tennessee Historical Commission. Historical Marker No, 3^30,
Williamson County, Tennessee,
Tennessee: The Volunteer State. 1769-1923. Vol. III.
Nashville: The S. J. Clarke Publishing Company, 1923.
rtalker, Nancy Wooten. Out of a Clear Blue Sky. Cleveland,
TN; By the Author, 1971.
104</dc:description>
<dc:description>Details the life of John Price Buchanan, the only man from Rutherford County to be elected Governor of Tennessee</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Democratic Party (Tenn.); Rutherford County (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Buchanan, John Price; governors; politicians</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>41 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-08</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication21ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/158</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>