<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Historical notes on Fellowship Church and community</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Farrar, Christine Sanders</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 6</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1972; 1976</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>19th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>75
HISTORICAL NOTES ON FELLOWSHIP
CHURCH AND COMMUNITY
BY
CHRISTINE SANDERS FARRAR
In the early 1800' s Bethesda Baptist Church was organized and
built on land given by Isaac Sanders for Church grounds and cemetery,
about 500 yards west of his home, on land bought from John Donelson
in 1805. This Sanders Cemetery, six miles north of Smyrna on the
Fate Sanders road is still being used 1972.
"On Saturday before the third Lords Day in December 1827,"
thirty three members of Bethesda Church withdrew from its membership
met in the home of Cornelius (Brother of Isaac) and Mary Sanders and
constituted an independent body which they called Fellowship. The
Charter members were: Elder Joshua Wollen, Deacons Darlin Jones and
Benjamin Flowers, Clerk Hezekiah Gibson. Other members: George
Underwood, Matthew Jones, James Merritt, Gideon Carter, John Hintchy,
Micajah Peacock, Mary Sanders, Mary McMennaway, Margaret Jones Sarah
Jones, Lucy Hedgepath, Lucretia Stephens, Margaret Freeman, Harriet
Freeman, Nancy Lannom, Margaret Barnett, Elizabeth McPeak, Nancy Flowers,
Katherine Ward, Nancy Wollen, Polly Robertson, Charity Wright, Polly
Merritt, Mary Edwards, Susanna Sanders, Rachel Sanders, Theresa Hintchy,
Patsy Barefoot and Mary King.
Even though the church was organized in the home of Cornelius
Sanders neither he nor his brother were among the charter members
but evidently all were well-wishers of the new church since members
continued meeting in the home of Cornelius several months for worship
and business. However, a committee was appointed consisting of Thomas
76
Sanders, Robert Freeman, Jesse Bloodworth, Benjamin Flowers and Micajah
Peacock to supervise the erection of a meeting house. Records do not
show when such a building was completed but it is practically certain
that it was occupied with in a year, after the church was organized.
It was a cedar log structure and was situated east of Bethesda Church
on ground given by William Freeman. In June 1852 a building comm-ittee
was appointed for the second house consisting of John Wiley,
William Meredith, Asa Houston Sanders (all sons of Isaac) Cornelius
Sanders, Jr., John B. Goodwin, N. C. McCullough, Moses R. Buchanan
and 0. G. Tucker. In March 1854 this committee reported a balance
$631.22*5 due the builder Edward Bodily, stone mason. In July 1856
a sub-committee was appointed consisting of John B. Goodwin and John
Sanders to supervise the finishing of the church with plaster and
paint. It appears the present rock structure was completed on that
date on land given by Thomas Kirkpatrick, thus the first district
of Rutherford County known as Fellowship Community for 147 years.
Written from minutes of Fellowship Baptist Church.
Bethesda Baptist Church was admitted into Concord Association
in 1814. Their annual reunion was held at Bethesda in 1835. Bethesda
has long since passed away.
Phillippi Church of Christ organized in 1830 on the site of
present building which was at that time part of the first district
of Rutherford County but now in Davidson County.
Corinth Church of Christ organized in 1867, built on land given
by Yank Til ford on the border of Rutherford and Wilson Counties,
/
77
known as the Burnett Community. First Pastor was Aesap Alsup.
Freedmans Grove Baptist Church was built by Asa Houston Sanders
after the Civil War, for negroes. The building was used 50 to 75
years and its first pastor was Mark Buchanan, colored, who had belonged
to Moses R. Buchanan. Mark was ordained to the Ministry by Fellowship
Church in 1877.
Bryants Grove was another Baptist Church for negroes built near
the Davidson County line in the latter part of 1800's.
Rockdale School 1st District. It is not definitely known what
year this school was opened but since it was in a log building on the
William Freeman land it is thought to have begun in the building Fel-lowship
Church had formerly used before 1854. In 1888 one acre was
given by Henry and Sarah Wood and J. B. and M. A. Bodily for public
school which was slightly west of the old building. This building
was a one room frame with long porch across front. Some of the teachers
were Alvis McCollough, T. Pinkney Edmondson, Miss Jinny Marlin, Miss
Amanda Miller, Miss Mable Callahan, Miss Mary Halliburton, Mr. Neal
El rod. Berry 0. Carter, Miss Inez Carter. In about 1953 a four room
brick building was erected on land given by Geo. A. Patton across
from Fellowship Church, this building was used 10 to 15 years before
all children were carried to Smyrna school by bus.
Burnetts School, 1st District was built on land of Lewis Burnett
in 1851. It was a one room log building. Some of the teachers were Ralph J,
Neal, Dr. James R. Major, Miss Vera Burnett, Miss Mamie Clemmons,
J. Norman Barnett, Miss Lillian Duggin, Mr. Alsup and Miss Zona Burnett.
78
It was abandoned about 1900 when the children came to Rockdale.
Scrough-Out was another early school built at the head of Spring
Creek in the first district near 1900. A Mr. Loyd and Miss Dora Sanders
were two of the teachers. It was abandoned when the children came to
Rockdale.
Bryants Grove was the one negro school in the community. Miss
Dora Hoi den was the teacher for many years.
One of the oldest homes in the community is owned by Mrs. J.
Mabry Goodwin. In 1851 her grandfather, Lewis Garrett Burnett, bought
this two story log house and a farm on Stones River. His son. Turner
Perry Burnett, inherited a portion of this land and bought the other
heirs interest. Turner's daughter, Ottie Burnett, inherited a portion
at her fathers death and she, with her husband, J. Mabry Goodwin,
bought the interest of other heirs. In 1966 when the Federal Gover-nment
acquired this land for the Percy Priest Lake, they moved the
house to Couchville Pike where it now stands in its remodeled condition.
Turner Perry Burnett, Jr. moved to Wilson County where he has served
different terms as Sheriff. Another brother, Herman Tyler Burnett
went to Pittsburg, Penn. as a young man to work with the Reliance Life
Insurance Co. He became Vice-President and was with the company until
retirement. He died in 1970 at the age of 86 years.
Other businesses in this community were operated as side lines
to farming. Wm. Thos Barnett, Guill S. Maddux, Wm.(Pat) Hunter,
John Lewis Wright and Thadeus Kimbro operated general merchandise
stores. E. K. Bond and Joseph Wright were master in every kind of
79
work in their shops from building wagons to shoeing horses. Milliard
D. Spain had a small chair factory. I doubt there was a family in the
first district who could not boast of having one of Mr. Spain's chairs,
Wm. Wright made coffins and did other cabinet work. Every chimney,
cellar and building of stone can be credited to Edward D. Bodily,
a superb stone mason.
Magistrates of the court were Isaac Sanders Freeman, Hickman
Weakley Chandler, Milliard D. Spain and Roy S. Lannom to mention
a few.
John Norman Barnett, son of Wm. Thomas and Mollie Hunter Barnett,
was connected with the First National Bank of Smyrna, Tenn. for 58
years until his retirement in 1971.
Miss Arline Wright, daughter of May and William Wright, was
dedicated to mission work and was the one missionary from Fellowship
Church.
Lafayette M. Sanders had the first automobile in the district
in 1909.
Copied from records of Christine Sanders Poole Farrar. March
28, 1972.
</dc:description>
<dc:description>A collection of notes from the author's research on the Fellowship Church and community just outside of Smyrna.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Churches</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Fellowship; Smyrna</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>9 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-15</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication06ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/70</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>