<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Rutherford County, Tennessee will abstracts</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Daniel, Susan G.</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 19</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1982</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1810-1819</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>67
RUTHERFORD COUNTY. TENNESSEE WILL ABSTRACTS
BY
SUSAN G. DANIEL
38. Record Book 3, Page 29 - Will of James McEwen of Rutherford County,
TN - Date of Will: 26 June 1814 - Recorded: 4 May I8I5 Wife: Sarah
McEwen sons: John Martin McE&gt;fen, Alexander McEwen, James McEwen,
William McEwen, Josiah McEwen daughters: Margery Stewart, Sarah
Henderson, Mary Miller McEwen grandson: David McEwen, son of William
Executors: friends, Alexander McEwen, James McEwen Witnesses: John
Alexander, John M. McKnight
39. Record Book 3, Page 31 - Will of Tarrance Burns - Date of Will: 18
April 1814 - Recorded: 4/ll May I8I5 Wife: Ruth 3 eldest sons:
As(b)urry, Charles C. , James son: Jessee (when comes of age)
legatees: As(b)urryB Burns, Charles C. Burns, James Burns, Jessee Burns,
Sarah Burns, Lois Burns, Mary R. Burns, John M. Burns, Bethemia/
Bethunia Burns, Ruth D. Burns Executor: Wife Witness: Horatio Burns
40. Record Book 3&#187; Page 3^ - Will of George Goodman of Rutherford County,
TN - Date of Will: 5 November 1814 - Recorded: 4 May I8I5 Wife: Jane
Goodman Only son: James Goodman 4 daughters: Elizabeth Goodman
(possibly married - sgd) , Nancy C. Goodman, Caty G. Goodman, Jane
Goodman Slave: boy. Jack (owned by Ant. Kinnard) Executors: wife
and Alexander McKeen( McEwen?) Witnesses: Townzin Fuget, John Bullard
41. Record Book 3, Page 4? - Will of David Barton of Rutherford County, TN
Date of Will: 12 July I8I5 - Recorded: July term I8I5 Wife: Hannah
Barton "money due me from the estate of Daniel Bird Smith"
daughters: Violet, Sarah sons: Swinfield, Robert, Joshua
Slaves: woman. Luce with her son Ben and woman, Nancy to wife then
divided between sons at wife's death; child Charlott (daughter of
Jenny) to Violet; woman, Bett to Sarah; girl, Mary and Simon her son
Executors: Joshua and Swinfield, sons Witnesses: Jonathan Price,
Isaac Hill, John Dickson
42. Record Book 3, Page 9? - Will of William Dickinson of Raleigh, Wake
County, N.C. - Date of Will: 14 August I8I3 - Recorded: ?
Wife: Nancy Executor: Mark Cooke
43. Record Book 3, Page 99 - Will of Walter Keeble, Senior - See Item #
recorded Record Book 3i Page 200
44. Record Book 3, Page 101 - Will of Thomas Crossthwait of Rutherford
County, TN - Date of Will: 22 November I8I5 - Recorded: ?
Wife: Elizabeth Brother: Shelton Crossthwait son: William
(not 21 - Brother is guardian of son) "my children" Executors:
Wife and brother, Shelton Witnesses: W. Keeble, Jr., George
Simpson, N. Cassidy, Samuel Watkins
45 Record Book 3, Page IO3 - Will of Joseph Thompson of Cripple of
Rutherford County, TN - Date of Will: I6 October 1815 Wife: Elizabeth
grandson, James Harvey Thompson &amp; granddaughter, Sally Thompson (child-ren
of my son James Thompson, deceased) daughter: Critty Thompson
Executors: Robert Kirk, Nathan Lyon Witnesses: Joshua Haskill, James
Carmack, Alexander Scott, Thomas Berry, James McFerrin
68
46. Record Book 3, Page 10? - Will of James Berry of Rutherford County, TN
Date of Will: 13 November 18l4 Wife: Elizabeth Berry "my children
as they arrive at age" sons: John Campbell Berry, James Laughlin
Berry "wife now pregnant" Executors: Wife &amp; Thomas Berry
Witnesses: James McFerrin, Burton L. McFerrin, Young Laughlin
4?. Record Book 3, Page 108 - Will of Miles Freeman - Date of Will: 2 Feb-ruary
1815 - Recorded: July term 1815 Wife: Margaret "my children"
Witnesses: Jacob Payne, Charles B. Collier, Willie Hutson
48. Record Book 3, Page 109 - Will of Gwin Howell of Rutherford County, TN
Date of Will: 24 July 1812 - Recorded: July term (1815?) Wife: Cath-arine
W. Howell Brother: William Howell Sisters: Nancy Nelson,
Margaret Whitside (Whitsett?) Executors: Catharine W. Howell, Gwin
Edwards, James Whitside (Whitsett?) Witnesses: Mary Williamson, Hardy
Pope, L. Davis
49. Record Book 3, Page 110 - Will of Bird Nance/Nancy of Rutherford County,
TN - Date of Will: 18 November 1814 Wife: not named sons: John
Nance, Williajn Nance daughters: Elizabeth Nance, Sally Nance
Slaves: woman. Luce and all her increase be equally divided between
Lucy Gajubill, John Nance, Elizabeth Nance, William Nance and Sally
Nance; man, Peter to wife but later to James H. Nance and Polly I.
Nance and Thomas Nance and Milly B. Nance Executors: friend, Allin
Nance, James Stanford Witnesses: Ryliegh D. Murry, John Smith
50. Record Book 3, Page 111 - Will of Robert Bedford of Rutherford County,
TN - Date of Will: 5 July I8I3 Wife: Mary Coleman Bedford
5 sons: Stephen Bedford, Robert Bedford, Clement Read Bedford, Edwin
Walton Bedford, Thomas Jefferson Bedford daughters: Mary Anne Eliza
Bedford, Mary Nash Johns, Lucy Legrand Rucker, Fanny Anne Bedford
4 youngest children (all not of age): Fanny Anne, Edwin Walton, Thomas
Jefferson, Mary Anne Eliza Slaves to Lucy: Milly, Presly, Letty (dead),
girl, Aggy Slaves to wife: Frank, Rose, Nancy, Amy, Glarisa, Juber,
Nancy (daughter of Nancy) Slaves: boy, Jerry to Stephen; boy, Milus
to Robert; boy, John to Clement; boy, Anthony to Edwin; woman, Nisey
(and increase after this) to Thomas; girl, Cinda to Fanny; girl.
Christian to Fanny; girl, Fanny to Fanny; girl. Jinny to Fanny; girl,
Tabby to Mary A. Eliza; girl, Maria to Mary A. Eliza; girl, Nanny to
Mary A. Eliza; girl, Sally to Mary A. Eliza; men, George and Littleton
to be sold Executors: John Spence, John Hoover, Col. William W.
Searcy Witnesses: Williajn Thweatt, George Akin, Elizabeth Daughity,
James Daughity, Elizabeth Akin
51. Record Book 3, Page 118 - Will of Beaty McCoy of Rutherford County, TN
Date of Will: 16 February 1814 - Recorded: 7 May I8I6 Wife: Peggy
McCoy sons: Henry McCoy, Ezekiel Beaty McCoy, Amox Alexander McCoy,
Francis Bradley McCoy, James McCoy, John McCoy daughter: Easther
Boggs son-in-law: David Parks "that was married to Abigail McCoy,
now dead" Slaves: man, Adam to Henry; man, Isaac to Ezekiel; girl,
Hannah to Amos; yellow boy, Jacob to Francis; woman, Darkis to be sold
Executors: Ezekiel and Henry Witnesses: James D. Wooten, Henry
Norman, Andrew Hall
69
52. Record Book 3, Page 121 - Will of Samuel Moody of Rutherford Co., TN
Date of Will: 9 September 1815 - Recorded: 7 May 1816 give to: Samuel
W. Henderson, Eliza E. Henderson Slave: boy, Joe Administrators:
Walter Keeble, Henry Trott Witnesses: Henry W. McBroom, John
Stockird, Richard Henderson
53. Record Book 3, Page 122 - Will of James Davidson of Rutherford Co., TN
Date of Will: 2 March I8l6 - Recorded: 7 May I8l6 Executor and son:
John Davidson daughters: Rebecca Young, Martha Davidson, Sarah Lusk,
Mary Johnson, Ruthy McGee, Sinthy Hubbard named: Martha Benson and
her sister, Jane granddaughters: Polly Kirke, Sarah Davidson
Witnesses: Samuell Killough, William Wilson
5^. Record Book 3, Page 125 - Verbal Will of William Hill of Rutherford
Co., TN - Date of Will: 26 February I8l6 - Recorded: 7 May I8l6
Wife and children: not names Before: Solomon Beesley, J. P., 28 Feb.
Witnesses: James Taylor, John Hill I8l6
^^. Record Book 3, Page 132 - Will of Squire Knox of Rutherford Co., TN
Date of Will: 24 February I8l6 - Recorded: 8 May I8l6 Wife:
Susannah (now pregnant) son: Washington daughters: not named
Executors: Charles Ready; brother, Joseph Knox Witnesses: Elijah
Smith, Thomas Knox, Angles McCloud
56. Record Book 3i Page 142 - Verbal Will of William Manning of Rutherford
Co., TN - He died: 15 February I8I6 Will subscribed: 25 February I8I6
Names: half brothers and sisters Witnesses: Thomas Washington, Jajaes
G. Washington
57. Record Book 3, Page 144 - Verbal Will of William Ranson - Date of Will:
2 February I8I6 - Recorded: 9 May I8I6 2 sisters Witnesses: Ben-jamin
Ransom, Charles C. Holt, Hezia Ransom
58. Record Book 3, Page 147 - Will of William Johnson - Date of Will:
19 January I8I6 - Recorded: 10 May I8I6 Wife: Rebecca (this is her
first marriage) Slaves: woman, Said/Sade; child, Leah
"wife's share divided on her death or marriage to: John Johnson,
Nancy Kuykendall, Edward Johnson, Mildred Miller, James Johnson,
William Johnson, Polly Taylor named: Matthew Johnson wife's
son: Larkin Johnson Executors: Green Norman, James Higgins
Witnesses: John Dean, Jonas Sikes **Widow is dissatisfied with
will
59. Record Book 3, Page 173 - Will of John Keys of Rutherford Co., TN
Date of Will: 25 April I8I6 - Recorded: 25 July I8I6 Wife: Margaret
"her faimily till youngest comes of age" son: James D. daughters:
not named Executors: John Weatherspoon, Moses McKnight Witnesses:
David McKnight, Charles Porterfield, Benjamin Knox
60. Record Book 3, Page 200 - Will of Walter Keeble, Sr. of Rutherford
Co., TN late of Cumberland Co., VA - Date of Will: 8 July 1811 -
Recorded: 1 August I8I6 (*See Item #43) "body interred by rights
of Episcopal church" son: Walter Keeble (known as Walter Keeble ^Black-head)
Slaves: mulatto man, Bauldy and his wife, Sukey and their 3
children, Henry, William and a male infant now at the breast - emanci-pates
all including increase of Sukey; boy, John Witnesses: John
Winn, John Hoover, Peter Winn
70
61. Record Book 3, Page 203 - Will of Thomas Black of Rutherford Co., TN
Date of Will: 23 April I8l6 - Recorded: 1 August I8l6 daughters:
Rebecca and her husband, Moses Cramer; Polly Black; Jane Finny Black,
Peggy and her husband, John Doak sons: Samuel P. Black, James Black
Executors: friends, William Ray, Ephraim Farr and son, Samuel P. Black
Apprentice: Jonathan Thomas (till 21 and more than 3 years remain)
Witnesses: John Garter, Jacob H. Thorn
62. Record Book 3, Page 226 - Will of John Warren - Date of Will: 18 June
I8l6 - Recorded: 20 November 18l6 Wife: Marget "3 children":
daughter, Luiza; son, Peterson; son, Benjamin Brother: William
Warren Slaves to wife: Vine, Abram, Silvey Slaves hired out
till youngest children of age: Jerry, Arter, Dick and Jim, Cornelia,
Venice, Mary, Marina Executors: Wife and brother, William Warren
Witnesses: David Williams, John Thompson
63. Record Book 3, Page 228 - Will of Isaac Wright of Rutherford Co., TN
Date of Will: 7 February 1812 - Codecil: I6 September 1814 - Recorded:
20 November I8I6 Wife: Rebekah Wright Eldest daughter: Mary Dill
daughters: Hannah Statler, Elizabeth Brashear, Rebekah Goodloe
sons: Abram Wright, Jacob Wright, Thompson Wright grandsons: Nathan
Brashear, Isaac Wright Brashear Owes estate: Thomas Searcy
landowners named: George Parks, Squire Phelps, McCorkle, Bell
Slaves: Elam, boy; Jude, girl; Creed; Anna; boy Allen to Jacob Wright;
man, Elam to Thompson Wright after death of wife; man, Sam may have his
freedom for $150.00; woman, Grace to wife Executors: Jacob Wright,
son; Jessee Brashear, son-in-law Witnesses: David Philips, Isaac
Jetton, Jajnes Neilly
CODECIL: names Thompson Wright, son, in right of Jesse Brashear as
Executor
64. Record Book 4, Page 2 - Will of Joseph Wallace of Rutherford Co., TN
Date of Will: 13 October I8I6 - Recorded: 1 December I8I6 Wife:
Elizabeth son: William Witnesses: John R. Bedford, Thomas Evans
65. Record Book 4, Page 72 - Will of Lemuel Lanier of Rutherford Co., TN
Date of Will: 28 February I8I7 - Filed: April term 1817 - Recorded:
29 August 1817 Wife: Lucy Lanier daughters: Patsey Fagan, Betsy
Floyd Grandsons: Robert Fagan (receives any issue of slave, Grace),
Samuel L. Kelly and Abner Kelly, Richard Floyd Slaves: woman, Dafney
and man, Daniel to wife; woman, Grace to Patsey; woman, Beck to Betsy;
boy, Joseph and boy, Alex to Betsy; boys William and Anthony and also
Dafney after wife's death to Samuel and Abner Kelly; man, Daniel after
wife's death to Richard Executor: Jesse Brashear, Drury Floyd
Witnesses: David Price, Rhoda Price
66. Record Book 4, Page 76 - Will of Patrick Sullivan of Rutherford Co., TN
Date of Will: 10 April 1817 - Recorded: 3O August 1817 Wife: Ann
Sullivan sons: John E. Sullivan, Daniel Sullivan, James Sullivan,
Robert Sullivan daughters: Polly McKeen, Nancy Young, Ann Davis,
Peggy Sullivan, Milly Sullivan Witnesses: John Alexander, James McKee
71
6?. Record Book 4, Page 8? - Will of James Wilson of Rutherford Co., TN
Date of Will: 2 September 181? - Recorded: 1 December 1817 Wife:
Sarah Wilson sons: Samuel Wilson, John Wilson, Givins Wilson,
Daniel Wilson daughter: Nancy Wilson Slaves: Old Pompy, August,
Young Pompey, Jude and her female child named Sindey to wife; male
Prince to Samuel; female, Lydia and boy, Weston to Nancy; male,
Monday to John; male, Peet to Givens; boy, Dick to Daniel
Executors: wife, son Samuel, brother-in-law Samuel Givins of Shelby-ville,
nephew James Whitsett of Shelbyville Witnesses: Henry Holmes,
John Davidson, James Neelly
68. Record Book 4, Page 114 - Will of Benjamin Waller of Rutherford Co.,
TN - Date of Will: 22 November 181? - Filed: March term 1818
Wife: Martha Children: Nancy Pinkard, William Waller, Benjamin P.
Waller, Patsey Waller (names daughters Polly Pinkard and Nancy
Pinkard - Polly and Nancy possibly the same person - sgd) "money
due me in Virginia" grandson: Edward (who lives with me)
Slaves: man, Mat; woman, Tamur; woman. Nan (to wife in lifetime then
sold) - girl, Vilet to Nancy; girl, Charlotte to William; girl,
Lavina to Benjamin; girls. Charity and Susan (choice to Patsey)
Executor: William Waller, Benjamin P. Waller and Baily Pinkard
Witnesses: Jonathan Welborn, Ellas Pinkard, William Johnson
69. Record Book 4, Page 118 - Will of William McCorkle of Rutherford Co.,
TN - Date of Will: 25 December I8I6 - Filed: March term 1818
Wife: Jane sons: John, Samuel M. , Richard B. , Miles daughters:
Amelia, Blanch Locke son-in-law: William Anderson sister-in-law:
Glarisa Graham "my father's land" Slaves: boy, George"to wife
till he is 28 years then set free if prudent and safe"; man, Hose to
Samuel; boy, Micah to Richard till 28 then set free; boy. Bob to
William till 28 then set free; boy, Anderson to Miles then set free
at 28; boy, Bradford to Clarisa then set free at 28; woman, Dine( freed)
Executors: James A. Wilson, Daniel Travers and wife Witnesses:
William Travers, Joshua Nichols
70. Record Book 4, Page 121 - Will of David Keas (Keys?) - Date of Will:
22 March 1817 - Filed: March term 1818 Wife: Kitty 2 youngest
children: Erasmas S. Keas, Margaret F. Keas Children: Harriott M.
Keas, Eliza C. Keas, Thizza Keas, Mary F. Keas, Erasmas S. Keas,
Margaret F. Keas Slaves: all to be sold Executors: Joseph Sharpe
and John L. Jetton Witnesses: Adam Simmons, William Thomas, Eliza
Keas
71. Record Book 4, Page 127 - Will of Jonathan Poe of Rutherford Co., TN
Date of Will: 26 February I8I6 - Filed: June term I8I8 Wife: Tabitha
Poe sons: Rhodin Poe, John Poe, George Poe daughter: Fanny Hansen
Slave: mulatto boy, James about 18 years - freed Executors: Joseph
Lannum of Wilson Co., Nathan Lannum of Rutherford Co. Witnesses:
William Nash, John Arnold
72. Record Book 4, Page 128 - Will of John Hampton of Rutherford Co., TN
Date of Will: 1 May 1817 - Filed: March term I8I8 Wife: not named
3 youngest children: daughter, Rebecca; daughter, Martha; son, Isaiah
Elder children: sons: John, James, Thomas, William, Richard and daughter:
Mary son-in-law: George Stinnett Slave: negro give to John
Executors: Edward Moreland, Solomon Beesley Witnesses: Christopher
Batey, Nathaniel Underwood
72
73- Record Book 4, Page I5I - Will of Henry Wigger of Rutherford Co., TN
Date of Will: 2 June I8I8 - Recorded: June term 1818 Wife: Rebecca
Daughter: Susy (not yet 18) Executor: Jonathan Shearwood
Witnesses: Robert Miller, John Miller
74. Record Book 4, Page 164 - Will of Lazarus Crawford - Date of Will:
29 March 1818 - Recorded: Sept. term I8I8 Wife: Rebecca son:
Raiford grandson: Olin Lancer (not yet ^ years old) daughters:
Dellia Joslin, Temperance Thompson "eldest of 2 youngest children
by my last wife": Baldwin Augustus (not yet I5) Slaves: girl, Dicy
to wife then at wife's decease to"my 2 youngest children by my first
wife"; Allen (first son of Dicy) to Olin; man, Ellis to Raiford; man,
Fountaine to Raiford; woma^i, Hannah to Raiford; boy, Richmond and girl,
Famar to Dellia; girl, Tenah and girl, Gassa to Temperance; boy, Peter
to be hired Executors: son, Raiford and Solomon Beesley Witnesses:
B. Gannaway, H. Robinson
75. Record Book 4, Page 16? - Will of Thomas Washington of Rutherford Go.
,
TN - Date of Will: 20 March 1818 - Recorded: Sept. term 1818 Land^
owners named: Hardy Pope, John James, Hesekiah Frederick "my 3
children": James G. Washington, Mary E. Washington, William L. Washing-ton
Wife: Jennett Washington grandsons: WilHia.&#165;-.^M6.3t&#169;r3on,
. Theaaa-CL.- Masierson father-in-law: Allen Love, deceased - Granville
Co., N.C. Wife's brother: John Love, deceased of Petersburg, VA
Guardians: (2 oldest sons) Gilbert G. Washington, Thomas Washington
(they are guardians of Mary E. and Williajn L. as well as 2 grandsons
William W. and Thomas G. Masterson) Mother: Sarah Washington
Slaves: Solomon, Randal, July, Manuel, Simon - to wife; Tom, Peter,
Daniel - to James; Maclin, Jude, Moses - to Mary; Jim, Allen, Abraham
- to William; "number in Brunswick Co., VA Executors: 3 oldest sons:
Gilbert G. , Thomas, Jr., James G. Washington Witnesses: L. Anderson,
Jonathan Currin, Charles Douglas
Codecil : 3 executors are to execute will of Thomas Masterson, deceased
Witnesses: Memucan Wade, Corey James
76. Record Book 4, Page 171 - Will of Asa A. Paul of Rutherford Co., TN
Date of Will: None - Recorded: Sept. term 1818 Wife: Pembroke Paul
my children: James A. Paul, Betsey C. Paul, Polly C. Paul, Zacheriah
M. Paul Executor: Wife Witnesses: Samuel Bowman, Adeline Bowman
77. Record Book 4, Page 181 - Will of Joseph Bowman of Rutherford Co., TN
Date of Will: I6 April I8I8 - Recorded: June term I8I8 2 sons not
21: Hamilton Bowman, William Bowman sisters-in-law: Polly and Dorry
Hamilton "children's mother is dead" sister: Polly McNeely
"William Lewis living on my land" Slaves: London and Jack hired out
till sons come of age; woman, Lucy to Polly McNeely Executors: Samuel
Bowman, Alexander McNeely, David Robinson Witnesses: John Wade,
William Bowman
78. Record Book 4, Page I85 - Will of John Beesley of Rutherford Co., TN
Date of Will: 27 November I8I6 - Filed: Dec. term 1818 Wife: not
naimed daughter: Polly son: Solomon Named: William Moseley
Executors: wife, son and Hugh Robinson Witnesses: H. Robinson,
Andrew Hands, Eliza Robinson
73
79. Record Book k, Page 192 - Will of Joel Childress of Rutherford Co., TN
Date of Will: 10 August 1819 - Filed: Sept. term 1819 Wife: Elizabeth
4 children: Anderson Childress, Susan Childress, Sally or Sarah Childress,
John W. Childress (all under 21) Named: ^Kingsley Slaves:
John and his wife, Kiziah; Isaac and Lydia (all to wife) Executors:
Samuel P. Black and son, Anderson Childress Witnesses: Joseph McMinn,
Blackman Coleman, Edmund Jones
80. Record Book 4, Page 199 - Will of James Rucker of Rutherford Co., TN
Date of Will: 14 July 1819 - Filed: Sept. term 1819 Wife: Nancy Rucker
daughters: Betsy Donelson, Lucinda Miller,, Joanna Price, Joice Rucker
sons: Jonathan Rucker, Henry F. Rucker, James Rucker, Benjamin Rucker,
William R. Rucker, Samuel R. Rucker, Weston Rucker, Jack W. -nucker,
Joseph B. Rucker, Robert Rucker Landowners : Burrus, Samuel
R. Rucker, Dr. Yanday's, Thomas Rucker Slaves: Jim, Sal, Hareda (?),
Mumy, John, Will, Kate, Joe, Easter, Jack, Amy, Hillis, Michael, Juda,
Iquim - to wife; Nelson and Jame - to Betsy ! Abram and Suca - to Lucinda;
Ned (which he has sold off), Hannah - to Jonathan; Hill and Phena - to
Henry; Charlotte and Sanda (Charles being a gift from his grandfather
Read) - to James; Bartlett, Nina and her child Jim - to Benjamin; Brient,
Ceily - to William; David and Betty - to Samuel; Sarah, Critty, Stephen
and Milly - to Johanna; Beverly and Bridget - to Weston; Lydia, Hanna,
Lewis and Dick - to Lydia; Darcus, Frank, Rachael - to Jack; Darius,
Mourin and Doll - to Joseph; Jim, Adaline and Jude's youngest child -
to Robert Executors: James, Benjamin, William R. and Samuel
R. Rucker Witnesses: Thos. Rucker, Jr., Thomas L. Rucker, Jr.,
Thomas Rucker, Sen.
81. Record Book 4, Page 205 - Will of James Taylor of Rutherford Co., TN
Date of Will: 12 December 181? - Filed: Sept. term 1819 Wife: Sary
Taylor daughter: Dorcas Arnold grandson: King Patterson (his
parents are Alex Patterson and Sary, his wife) Named: Jesse Taylor
Executor: son, James Taylor Witnesses: Benjamin Ransom, James Snell,
Joseph Smith
82. Record Book 4, Page 209 - Will of Thomas Evans of Rutherford Co., TN
Date of Will: 20 August 1819 - Filed: Sept. 1819 Wife: Temperance
"our ten children": Julian, Angeline, James, Luan, William, Susanna,
Harrison, Jerusha, Winnifield, Manda Executors: wife and James
McMillion Witnesses: Theos. A. Canon, John Sharp, Lemuel Wright
83. Record Book 4, Page 22? - Will of John Miller of Rutherford Co., TN
Date of Will: 1? October 1819 - Filed: Dec. term 1819 sons: Isaac J.
Miller (not yet 15), William W. Miller (not of age) daughters:
Rebecca Miller (not of age or married), Margaret, Mary Miller, Nancy
Miller, Jenny, Ellender Wife: Mildred Landowners: "bought from
Robert Miller" Executors: wife- and son, Isaac Witnesses: Isaac
Miller, William Johnson
84. Record Book 4, Page 232 - Will of William Nickson of Rutherford Co.,
TN - Date of Will: 15 April 1819 - Filed: Dec. term 1819 Wife:
Hannah "3 youngest children" Witnesses: Joseph Morton, Thomas
Edwards, William Walker
74
85. Record Book 4, Page 233 - Will of William Morris of Rutherford Co., TN
Date of Will: 20 November 181? - Filed: Dec. term 1819 "woman I now
live with": Letty Little my children: Daniel Morris, James Morris,
Mary Morris, Nancy Morris Executor: Esaac Morris Witnesses:
William Johnson, Edward Johnson, Edward Taylor
86. Record Book 4, Page 237 - Will of James Macklin of Rutherford Co., TN
Date of Will: 21 November 1818 - Filed: Dec. term 1819 sons: John
A. Macklin, David W. Macklin, Robert Macklin, William A. Macklin, James
S. Macklin daughters: Peggy H. Bumpass, Catharine S. Bone(Bowen?)
,
Unice Macklin, Jame Overall Executors: W. A. Macklin (son) and
William '^umpass Witnesses: George Rowland, Abner Wasson</dc:description>
<dc:description>Offers abstracts of wills and court proceedings listed in Record Books 3 &amp; 4 housed at the Rutherford County Archives</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.); Rutherford County (Tenn.) -- Archival resources; Court records; Public records; Wills</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>8 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-08</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication19ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/154</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>