<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Occupation mayor: the honorable J.M. Tompkins</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Pittard, Homer</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 2</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1973</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>OCCUPATION MAYOR:
THE HONORABLE J. M. TOMPKINS
In the Union Volunteer , May 20, 1862, a newspaper published
by occupation authorities, this notice v/as carried: "Some weeks
since notice was (part of sentence illegible) of the city of
Murfreesboro, elected during the session
of the 'reign of terror,' that they must
^B- * '^
'^^J take the oath of allegiance as required
by the State Constitution or be removed
from office. The Mayor J. E. Dromgole
(sic) , the Recorder, D. D. Wendel, and
Aldermen Robertson and Saunders declined
to comply with the request. They were
accordingly removed and others chosen by
the remaining Aldermen to fill the vacancies. The following
gentlemen now comprise the city government: Mayor J. M. Tompkins;
Recorder R. D. Reed; Aldermen Alfred Miller, John Todd, E. S.
Jordan, C. B. Huggins , and William McKnight; Magistrates John Jones
and V. C. Carter; and Constable Gannaway." (from microfilm in
Smyrna, Tennessee Library.)
The length of Tompkins' tenure as the Murfreesboro mayor is
not clear. At the time the town was garrisoned by a Union brigade
composed of the Ninth Michigan, the Third Minnesota, and some
scattered detachments from other regiments. Forrest's raid on
July 13 covered a period of some twelve hours, and the prisoners
that were carried away with Forrest's withdrawal were replaced by
31
units under General William Nelson. Sometime later, the garrison
was abandoned, and early in October, the Army of Tennessee, under
General Braxton Bragg, moved into the town and its environs.
Following the battle of Stones River, the Confederate army retired
to Tullahoma and Shelbyville. Rosecrans' Army of the Cumberland
became the reoccupation troops. For the remainder of the war,
Murfreesboro was in Union hands.
Tompkins states in his "Memoirs" (that are carried in full
on the pages that follow) that he acted as mayor "until all civil
and municipal law ceased by the action of the war."
There is no record that even a token form of municipal
government was allowed from January 3, 1863 until the close of
the war. Tompkins' days as a mayor may have covered a few months,
possibly a year. Whatever time his office may have existed must
have been identifiable by controversy. This inference can be
drawn from reading his "Memoirs." It can be noted that biographies
of two of his sons, Robert and Albert, that appear in Goodspeed's
History of Tennessee (1886), make no reference to their father's
mayorship. One may conjecture that their mayor father did not
achieve widespread popularity. Both sons were Confederates.
Robert served with the Forty-fifty Tennessee and Albert with the
Eighteenth Tennessee.
Shortly after the war. Mayor Tompkins may have been rewarded
for his loyalty. He was appointed clerk and master of the chancery
court. He died in 1870.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Recounts the story of J.M. Tompkins, who stood up as Murfreesboro's mayor during occupation by Union forces</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Murfreesboro (Tenn.) -- History; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>mayors; public officials; Tompkins, James M.</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>3 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-15</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication02ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/140</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>