<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Daniel C. Miller: A yankee in Rutherford County</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Pittard, Mabel</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 26</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1986</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Daniel C. Miller
A YANKEE IN RUTHERFORD COUNTY
by Mabel Pittard
Foreword
Several years ago my husband. Homer Pittard, dis-covered
the above carving on a large boulder along Stones
River near the present-day Stones River Country Club.
Through official records he was able to locate descendants
of Daniel C. Miller. These relatives gave him information
concerning this young Union soldier who had left his name
carved with a scroll-like effect on an over-hanging cliff
along Rutherford County's main stream. These relatives
made available to Dr. Pittard some thirty letters written
in German which Miller had sent to his family in Ohio
during the one and one-half years that he was assigned
to guard duty at Fortress Rosecrans. Ortrun Gilbert of
Middle Tennessee State University translated 'these letters
into English for Dr. Pittard. It is hoped that members
of the Rutherford County Historical Society and others
will find these letters to be of interest.
A YANKEE IN RUTHERFORD COUNTY
On the cold night of January 3, 1863, General Braxton
Bragg and his Army of Tennessee headed south from
Murf reesboro, Tennessee to take up winter quarters at
Tullahoma, Winchester, Shelbyville, and other towns in
that vicinity. This retreat on the part of Bragg and his
army was interpreted by the opposing Union general, William
Starke Rosecrans, as a victory for the Federal forces in
the two-day Battle of Stones River which ended on
January 2, 1863.
Rosecrans and his army were to remain in and near
Murfreesboro for almost six months during which time he
reorganized his army and allowed their wounds to heal.
Like other generals before him, Rosecrans was faced with
the problem of keeping his men occupied and in good
physical condition during this period of inactivity and
rest. This problem, in part, accounted for Rosecrans'
decision to erect a hugh fortress just to the southwest
of Murfreesboro that would serve as a supply depot for
the coming operations that lay ahead for the Federal
troops as they penetrated deeper and deeper into southern
territory.
The Army of the Cumberland was 215 miles away from its
main supply base in Louisville, Kentucky and was dependent
upon the Louisville and Nashville railroad line for
military rations and supplies. Enemy raiders and flash
floods could easily disrupt this line of supplies, and
Rosecrans, who was planning a forward movement toward
Chattanooga in late spring of 1863, realized the value
of fortifying Murfreesboro and establishing a depot in
that Middle Tennessee town. Also, Murfreesboro, if well-fortified
and stockpiled with supplies, would serve as a
good point to fall back on in the event the Army of the
Cumberland was forced to retreat.
The design and location for the fortress, later to
become known as Fortress Rosecrans, was assigned to the
chief engineer of Rosecrans' army. Captain James St. Clair
Morton. The site chosen by Morton surrounded the
Nashville and Chattanooga railroad bridge over Stones
River and enclosed an area of approximately 200 acres.
The Pioneer Brigade, a brigade of engineers who
specialized in the construction of fortifications and
railroads, performed the duties of supervising the crews
assigned to building block-houses, magazines, railroad
spurs, saw mills, grist mills, and commissionary buildings.
By mid-April of 1863 the fortress was almost
completed and had been stockpiled with huge stores of food
substances and forage. Also, by this time Rosecrans and his
staff were making plans to march on the Army of Tennessee which by June
would be in retreat toward Chattanooga.
By the time Rosecrans and his army had left
Murf reesboro. Fortress Rosecrans had received a garrison of
some 2,500 men. These soldiers were for the most part
convalescents, thus freeing able-bodied men to be sent to
the front. However, m.any of these soldiers were unfit for
duty and soon it becamie evident that other troops
were needed to help garrison the fortress. Among such
troops sent to Murfreesboro to help man the depot was the
115th Ohio Voluntary Infantry, a unit that after its
organization had seen no combat but had been used solely
for guard duty at prison camps and supply depots. One of
the members of this 115th Ohio Voluntary Infantry, Company B,
was Daniel C. Miller a 23 year-old German immigrant who had
come to the United States at the age of 19.
Daniel C. Miller was born in Germany in 1838 and
came to the United States in 1857. His parents settled
in Cleveland, Ohio and their German name of Meuller was
changed to the American version. Miller. At the outbreak
of the Civil War Daniel was employed as a marble cutter
with a monument company in Cleveland. Official records
indicate that Miller was mustered into the Union Army
on August 11, 1862. His regiment was organized at Camp
Massillon, Ohio. On the fourth of October, 1862 the
regiment reported to Ma jor-General Wright at Cincinnati.
On the ninth of October, 1862, Company B of the 115th
Ohio Voluntary Infantry was sent to Camp Chase to perform
guard duties. It remained at this prison camp until
November of 1862 at which time it was ordered to Maysville,
Kentucky and placed under the command of Colonel Lucy. In
December of 1862 the batallion was ordered to Covington,
Kentucky where it performed provost duty until October of
1863 at which time it was ordered to Murf reesboro,
Tennessee and stationed in blockhouses along the Nashville
and Chattanooga railroad with orders to prevent guerillas
from destroying the rail line. Miller remained in Ruther-ford
County for the remainder of the Civil War and with
the defeat of the Confederacy and the conclusion of the war,
he was mustered out of service at Murf reesboro on June 22,
1865.
During the one and one-half years while Miller was on
guard duty at Fortress Rosecrans, he frequently wrote
letters to his family in Ohio. Dr. Homer Pittard was
successful in contacting descendants of Daniel C. Miller
who made these letters available. They give interesting
insights into the life of a Yankee soldier assigned to
guard duty at Fortress Rosecrans from October 1863 until
C
(oouc9?i^ad, (lJ.,.
Maroh 13, 1961
rjincm J/e ^/lat /ne "i^ece^fd^ ol tni^ c/lcce ^/tom f/tat
Daniel 0, Miller*
115th.
enrolled as a Corporal (it Oom/i aoi/f/ "^"
1862
^.e^cme^it, &#8364;/Uo j^/irifantry ^^^ //,. ^^^^*
c/rry, r/^ August,
-, cii 'h
and mcti '&gt;7iu^le'y&#8364;d iotto Oie UTidecl t/iatei ie'^'uice ai iiic/i /oot //le /icycccl c/
3 years
-, on. //u 13th, September, 1362
Camp Maaaillon, Ohio
-da71^ o/&#8212;
^^, Captain Alexander E, DraTte
~at
My.
%. S^.S^. ^(uUe'&#187;ti'na &amp;^ice't&lt;:. and //tal /if was twenty three years of ape at
the time of h issiknanmen t in the&#8212;Civ ii Unr; Augiiat 7 7, 7^^-?. He served
with the_l 1 5tb&#187;-^eg iimn t,-Jl.J/',j:^^_Infan t rv^. in Company "B". His enlist-ment
was for a period of three years. He was appointed January 1, 1365;
He mustered out with the Company June 22, 1 365, at Murfreeshoro, Tennessee,
*Si/(^'u/a/i/ 'Sc/uj^a/ ^&gt;/'^/iffi
June of 1865. The first such communication was written
the day before Christmas 1863 and relates how he and
other members of Company B were assigned to make railroad
ties. He also tells how he and some of his friends
obtained turkeys and chickens from a rebel farmer. The
letter follows:
24 December 1863
Murf reesboro, Tenn.
Dear parents, brothers, and sisters,
I do not know much news. 36 men from our
company B went twelve miles toward Nashville to
make railroad ties 8 ft. long from cedar trees.
It will probably take us 3 to 4 months because
they want us to make 16,000 ties like those, but
they are not pushing us and we are taking our time
and we have enough to eat. Tomorrow is Xmas day
and we don't do anything. We have already finished
1300 of those ties. Monday a week age while we
went through the woods to our work we saw four
bushwhackers on horses in front of us but they
were too far away to shoot at, but since then 3 of
them have been caught by our Cavalry and will
probably hang.
The Christmas day went by quietly and peacefully.
We didn't have any candy like we did for the last
two yrs . It rained last night so we v/on ' t get
much done again today. But tomorrow we will go
deeper into the forest. Last night we went to a
rich Rebel farmer who had many chickens and
turkeys. We asked him for some. He gave us 1
turkey and 16 chickens. If he hadn't done so
freely we would have taken them by force. They
tasted real good. This farmer still has 150
slaves but every day some flee to enlist. In
Murfreesboro we have a whole regiment of about
1300 of such slaves who have escaped from their
masters
.
with this I will close and wish you a healthy
and happy New Year 1864, hoping to be with you
again. Here they have cotton seeds which are
planted like corn and when it reaches one foot it
is hoed.
On January 10, 1864, Miller explained how members of
his company tried to warm their tents during the bitter
cold weather. He also relates that he had obtained
cotton seed from an old barn and mailed some of these
seeds home to his parents. In the letter he makes an
effort to explain to his parents how the cotton plants
grow.
Murf reesboro, Tenn.
January 10, 1864
Dear Parents, brothers, and sisters.
Received your letter and heard that all of you
are well, so am I. This time I don't know any
news except that we have enough to eat, as much
as we need. Since Christmas we have hardly been
able to do anything because of rain and snow.
4 days ago we had 4 inches of snow, which still has
not disappeared yet. It was rather cold recently
so that the snow froze again over night and we
could not do anything because the trees were too
slick
.
We read this evening in a Canton newspaper,
that the State of Ohio has written to Washington
and gotten permission that we receive 25 dollars
per month which the State of Ohio will give
voluntarily to its soldiers who are in the war.
That would be fine and the State of Indiana will
give its soldiers 20 dollars per month. I think
Congress will permit it. I believe that the war
will soon be over because one sees that the people
at home are more peaceful, they see that as long
as they rebel at home there cannot be peace. I
for my part would like to march 15-20 miles per
day with knap sack and rifle if I could know
that there will be peace in 4-5 months. Some
at home can sit a long time in their warm rooms
and make calendars and we are here like the wild
Indians in the v\70ods, who don't see anyone for
weeks except our comrades. We have made our
tents quite warm, we have ovens under our tents
covered with big flagstones, so that they get
almost glowing hot. VJe can sleep warm the whole
night and get up in the morning without to rub
an eye
.
With this I want to close, stay well, hope
to see you soon and speak to you.
Just one more thing, is it true that they have
made a fort in the town under Bank Street and
that there are canons in it?
The cottonseed I took from an old barn in
which I found more than 50 bushel, it will rot
if it does not get to a dry place. There are
still large fields of it, which have not been
picked. The plant gets 2-3-4 feet high, when it
gets ripe it becomes brown like a chestnut.
There are 10-20-30 seeds on one plant as large
as an egg. They open when they get ripe, like a
chestnut.
In this letter dated January 28, 1864, Miller
reveals his remedy for a cold. Near the end of the same
letter, in very poetic language, he expresses his desire
for peace.
Murfreesboro, Tenn.
January 28, 1864
Dear brother-in-law and sister,
I received your letter tonight, well and
with joy, and learned that you all are healthy and
well which I like to hear only that Fritz is sick
for so long is bad and I wish he will get better
soon. As far as I can tell, I am still o.k. and
have been that way as long as I have been in the
U. S. Army. I only had a cold for three days.
I couldn't speak for 2 days and had to drive
everything away v/ith red pepper and vinegar, since
then I have been fine. I wish the same to you
all. There is no news except that we will have
to wait 6 to 7 weeks until we get our 16,000 ties.
And we still have enough to eat. We get good
spring water, the General has told us that we
should take our tim.e for that which we certainly
do. One only has to make 10 ties per day. I
can easily do them in 2-3 hours, then I am free
for the rest of the day. As we have heard
definitely we are under a French general with
the name of Rousseau and belong to the 2nd
Bridage, 4th Arm.y Corp and the 3rd Division, 4
Reserve. We also got tonight new in-Field Rifles
and one old musket which we got in Cincinnati
we have stored with pleasure in a box.
We have had over 8-9 days very warm and
beautiful weather. You can imagine when the wild
doves are flying and the ants are crawling in
big masses and the birds are singing their praise
songs in the morning&#8212;that there should be peace
soon in this country so that the Bluecoats
cannot destroy all this. VJe have also shot more
than 50 hares since we are here and when a young
pig comes to our lines, it will be seized and
treated like a rebel. With this I would like
to close hoping that you will receive these few
lines in as good health as they have left me.
Write me soon, I have not had a letter for more
than 3 weeks. You must believe that I am astonished
at not having heard from home for such a long
time. Keep well. Many thousand greetings and
wishes from your loving brother and brother-in-law.
P.S. Verenell you can send this letter to
Cleveland if you want to.
On February 15, 1864 Miller stated that he and one
of his comrades, Bauhof, had been working on a monument.
This monument to which he refers is undoubtedly the Hazen
10
Brigade Monument which is located on the Stones River
Battlefield at Murf reesboro, Tennessee. In the same
letter Miller refers to Hazen when he says, "I can't
tell yet whether we shall get extra payment for this,
but the supervisor surgeon told us that General Hazen
will treat us well."
The Hazen Brigade Monument, the oldest Civil War
Monument anywhere in the United States, was erected in
1863 by members of Colonel William B. Hazen 's Union
Brigade as a memorial to 55 of their comrades who fell
during the terrific on-slaught of the Confederates on
Union troops as they sought refuge in a clump of cedars
referred to as "Round Forest."
Since Miller came to Fortress Rosecrans in the late
fall of 1863, it is very likely that he began carving the
inscription on the monument in the latter part of that
year. Miller's experience as a stonecutter in Ohio before
his enlistment in the Union Army made him a likely choice
to perform this task. The inscription on the monument
reads as follows:
"Hazen 's Brigade to the memory of its soldiers
who fell at Stones River, December 31, 1862.
Their faces toward heaven, their feet to the foe
The blood of one-third of its soldiers
Twice spilled in Tennessee
Crimson the battle flag of the Brigade
And inspires to greater deeds."
il
Murfreesboro, Tenn,
February 15, 1864
Dear parents, sisters and brothers,
I received your last letter today at noon
all right and with much joy, and I read that you
are still well. I also am well and all right
and wish the same for you with all my heart.
There is not much news, only that I and Bauhof are
working already for 2k days at the monument of
which I have talked in my previous letters. We
like this work very much and can work when we
want to. We start in the morning round 8:00 or
8:30 and finish at 4 PM or so, I can't tell yet
12
whether we shall get extra payment for that,
but the supervisor surgeon told us that General
Hazen will treat us well. I could get a vacation
for 30 days to come home, but I need the $15.20,
yet if you want me very much to come home, I will
gladly do it. I would like to come home, for it
is long ago since I saw you last. I got a letter
last week fromFuchs. At that time he was still in
a Camp Division 15 miles from Cincinnati, and
are already waiting for them to get the order to
leave. His address is:
Mr. Sergt. Joseph C. Fox
Co. H. 2nd Bat. 9th O.V.C.
Camp Division Ohio
In a letter dated March 3, 1864 Miller once again
mentioned that he and C. B. (Bauhof) were working on the
monument and had become the best of friends. He made
his first reference to ringmaking, "Mother will be very
happy because I made her a pretty ring." Miller made
these rings out of silver coins (usually dimes) by
hammering out the center and smoothing and flattening out
the rim. Often he etched orange blossoms on the outer
rim and sold these rings to soldiers for their brides. At
times his family mailed him the silver coins when it
became difficult for him to procure them. In this letter
he made mention of the increased activity of the Union
Army as it moved more and more men to the front.
Murf reesboro, Tenn.
3 March 1864
Dear Parents and brothers and sisters,
I received your last letter at noon today and
was overjoyed to hear that you are all v;ell. I
can say the same about me. I have no news as of
now but I think something is up. Because every
13
railroad train which comes by here is loaded with
soldiers and freight to be transported to the Army
at the front line.
I do not know when I will be able to come
home, because I have to wait til some others com.e
back who started leave on Friday (30 days) . At
the beginning of next month you may expect me.
Mother will be very happy because I made her a
pretty ring, and for you Verne 11 I have a crest
pin and for you father I have a Rebel shell or a
big cannon ball that I found on the battlefield,
and for you sister something too.
Last Saturday we got paid for two months.
I was thinking about sending you some of it which
I don't need until I am with you. But maybe we
will get paid again before I leave here.
I and C. B. are working together on a monument
and we are the best of friends together. I have
worked already five days and Christie four days.
Now I will close these few lines with the hope
that this letter v;ill arrive there and find you in
as good health as it left me. Many greetings and
wishes from your loving son and brother.
In the following letter dated March 22, 1864
Miller described a trip that he had made to Nashville with
supply wagons. He described the city and the heavy
fortifications that surrounded the state Capitol.
Murf reesboro, Tenn.
March 22, 1864
Dear parents, brothers, and sisters.
Our captain said that none will be able to
go home until the sick and wounded are gone home
from the hospitals. These orders are supposed
to come from the General, but it should not be
long until we can come home and I will be one of
the first. So be patient, for a short time, it
14
will all be good in the end. I send you here 10
dollars. Perhaps we get paid next week. Other-wise
no news. I heard from Caspar Fuchs , they
were in Nashville, 30 miles north from here.
He thought that they would come by here, but
has not been here yet. Last week I was in
Nashville, hoping to find him there, but there
are too many troops. I could not find him. I
think they have gone another direction. I went
to Nashville with 100 wagons, each wagon had 6
donkeys in front, it didn't cost me a cent.
(Nashville is quite a big town and the streets
are narrow and beside the town runs the big
Cumberland River and across this river about
60-70 feet high goes a bridge, like the one in
Cleveland, but tv;ice as long and the railroad
goes over it. The town hall stands on a big
hill. In the m.iddle of the town, around this big
building they have built brick walls with 5 big
cannons inside. Around this whole town they dug
a deep ditch. With this I must close, hope all
are fine. When I come home I will tell m.ore.
Love from your son and brother
In this letter dated April 7, 1864 Miller stated
that thousands of reinforcements were daily passing
through Murfreesboro on their way south. He said,
"Today again 6 thousand new soldiers from Indian a came,
they too are going farther to the south, will only be
here 1-2 days." He mentioned again his work on the
m.onument and said, "But we cannot do much work because
of the spring rains."
Murfreesboro, Tenn.
April 7, 1864
Dear parents, brothers and sisters.
Each day there passes by 1-4-5 thousand
soldiers going to the front. Today again 6 thousand
15
new soldiers from Indiana came. They too are
going farther to the south, will only stay here
1-2 days. I and Bauhof still v/ork on the monument.
But we cannot do much because of the Spring rain.
We have about 3-4 days rain each week, but the
wet season will soon be over and the dry and
warm days v/ill begin. We heard that we will
probably stay here all summer long, perhaps also
the coming winter. We hope that we will soon
have opportunity to list as veterans, then we
will be able to come home for 30 days. Write me
what you think about that the war cannot last a
whole year, as the rebels say themselves.
You say that you would like to buy us a
lot more. I think so too and want to do my best
for you. According to the newspaper we get from
you we will get 15 dollars per month, which would
be fine, yet I cannot see it, but hope it.
I wonder where Fuchs is now, I have not
gotten any letter from him since they were in
Nashville. Has he written to you where he is
now? I can read your writing well. I want to
send you a ring as payment. We still have enough
to eat and drink. Since Feb. 19th I have worked
14^ days on the monument. Otherwise we have
nothing to do. We have very good times. Last
week I weighed 166 pounds. Hope all are fine,
greetings and best wishes.
Your son and brother
In the following letter dated April 19, 1864 Miller
noted that the big Army of the Cumberland was moving out
of Murfreesboro and moving south and said, "We expect
to hear about a great battle." He told his parents that
he did not plan to re-enlist, "for I have no more than
16 months to serve and these are long enough." He also
stated that they were still working on the monument.
16
Murf reesboro, Tenn.
April 19, 1864
Dear parents, brothers, and sisters.
Last Sunday night at 9 o'clock 30 rebels
came close to our outposts, but they disappeared
soon. From our regiment, from Company PC, 3 5
got on their horses but they didn't find them
because the rebels were also on horses.
We also expect to hear about a great battle,
because the large Cumberland Army is moving
further into the South. Also two long railroad
trains came by last Friday filled with planks,
moving toward the army. This answers that some-thing
is going to happen. I decided not to
re-enlist, for I have no more than 16 months to
serve and these are long enough. If they pass as
fast as the 18 past ones, I will be glad. We
still work on the monument. The silken cord
pleases me very much, it is long enough. I have
exchanged my old watch which I bought from Rudolf
for $11.00 for another watch, for which I could
get 20 dollars. But below $25 I will not give
it away. I payed $14.00 for it. I hope that we
get paid next week again, then I will try to send
home $20. I have not gotten father's letter yet,
I would like to get a letter from Father. I have
not gotten a letter from Fuchs, since he was in
Nashville. I won't write him until I get a
letter from him. I got a letter from Rudolf,
they are all well. There are still passing by so
many soldiers, going South to the front. Also a
reQiment of Negroes came by last week. They are
so proud to carry a rifle, most of them have
been slaves.
Greetings
In a letter written on May 21, 1864, Miller told
how he and Bauhof did not feel like working on the
monument and took a walk through the woods "in a part of
the woods where a part of one of the hottest battles was
fought (Stones River)."
17
Dear Parents,
Your last and first letter I received in
good health and was glad to know that you were
well too. I do not know much news this time,
only that we will probably stay here all summer
because there are a lot of bushwhackers in this
area. Last week nineteen of our Company R went
12 miles through the wilderness after those
bushwhackers. They met up with them in a little
village called Shelbyville. We killed two Rebels
and took 2 donkeys and 1 horse. We lost one of
our good men who was shot through the heart, he
died after 15 hours. We shipped him home to
his home eight miles from Canton. He was the first
one we lost because of the Rebels. Three weeks
ago Bauhof and I were at the monument which is 1^
miles away from our outpost but we didn't feel
much like working on it that morning. So we walked
five miles through the woods until we reached a
road then back again to our camp. We didn't
carry any rifles or pistols with us, only our
lunch. The bushwhackers sure could have caught
us, but we didn't see any. And we were in a
part of the woods where a part of one of the
hottest battles was fought. But we are getting
used to all this shooting.
Please write again soon. I can read your
letters well but do not forget to sign them.
Here are ten dollars. Farewell til we see each
other again. When we do we will drink several
glasses of beer again.
In a short letter dated June 4, 1864, Miller told
his parents that "60 men of each company will go to the
railroad between here (Murf reesboro) and Nashville to
guard it.
"
June 4, 1864
Dear parents.
There are many news, but I have not time to
tell them all, for this Sunday morning 60 of each
company will go to the railroad between here and
Nashville to guard it. I don't know where our
company is supposed to go. But I think we will
get to the place where we made railroad ties
last summer. I believe that it will soon be over
and the time will come when we can go home. The
33rd Indiana Regiment is at this fortress and
depot from Murfreesboro to Nashville. I also
think that it is time it is almost over.
With this I will close ....
Miller's June 28, 1864 letter revealed that he and
30 of the men in his company were sent to Stockade #6
at Stewart' Creek to guard the railroad bridge. He
mentioned that his company was eating well, having had
strawberries, blackberries, apple pie, biscuits, and
fish. "Our Lieutenant," he said, "borrowed a net from a
farmer for as long as we want. We catch enough fish for
all 30 men almost every day." He stated further, "We
live like Lords here--are getting fat."
Murfreesboro, Tenn.
June 28, 1864
Dear parents, brothers and sister.
Received your last letter and was so happy to
receive it and was glad to hear that you are all
well and I am happy to say that I am well. Every-thing
seems to be going well at the front. Today
it is 2k weeks since I left Murfreesboro where
we were to watch a railroad and a railroad bridge
at Stewart's Creek. We are in a block house or
stockade. It is a place where the cannon balls
can't do any harm. We are in the shade. I only
have guard duty every three or four days. You
will be surprised to know that the strawberry
19
season is already three weeks past--also the
blackberries are all gone and some apples are
ripe. We make apple sauce, pie and biscuits
and we always have something green. Also we have
fish. Our lieutenant borrov/ed a net from a
farmer for as long as we want. We catch enough
fish for all 30 men almost every day. The weather
is very beautiful here. The farmers are already
harvesting. In another letter I will send you a
drawing of our house. I want you to save the
drawings. I haven't received a letter yet from
my brother Jacob. I would love to hear from him.
William has already written two or three letters
to Bauhof--he says they are having a bad time in
Camp Chase, that they have to be on guard duty
every other night and have to drill so often.
We live like Lords here--are getting fat. Casper
Puchs owes me a let.ter and I will not write until
he writes me first. With this I wish to close.
Your loving sOn, D. C. Miller
Co. B. 115th 0. V. I. Regt.
Stockade #6 near Murf reesboro,
Tenn.
July 12, 1864 found Miller and his comrades still at
Stockade #6 at Stewart's Creek. He related how he and
his fellow soldiers celebrated July 4, "Our Lieutenant
bought us a barrel of beer which cost him. 28 dollars. He
is a real nice young man." He made reference to another
pastime of his&#8212;that of making canes out of cedar. "I
am making a cane now, but instead of putting a snake
design on top I am putting a grapevine on it." He
mentioned making rings and selling them for 50 cents each,
On these rings he carved two hearts and a star. He said.
20
"I have only ten cents in silver. Whenever you get a
3 or 5 cent coin send it to me to use."
12 July 1864
N Stockade #6
Dear parents, brother and sister.
Same greetings as before. Health, happiness,
etc. I would have written you 3 days ago but we
were waiting for the Paymaster every hour. He
just came and we got paid. This time I will
send you ten dollars, and ten dollars in my' next
letter. Week before last I received a letter
from my brother Jacob which I answered right away,
but I didn't know if he got the letter. Not much
news here. I am making a cane now, but instead
of putting a snake design on top I am putting a
grapevine on it with leaves and grapes. It will
be the prettiest one ever made in our Regiment.
I have worked on it almost a week now. I will
send it to Canton. There are 5 or 6 men working
on cane like this. We will make a little box
for mailing all of them which wouldn't cost us
much. I had a good time the 4th of July with
all the others. Our Lieutenant bought us a
barrel of good beer which cost him 28 dollars.
He is a real nice young man. We can tell him
what we want and do what we want to. He goes
swimming in the creek with all of us. We have
very good well water about 300 feet away. I
will close with these few lines. Greetings and
wishes from your loving son.
I have to make four or more rings for 50
cents each and I have only ten cents in silver.
I will put on two hearts and a star. Whenever
you get a 3 or 5 cent coin send it to me to use.
On July 20, 1864 Miller wrote to his brother Jacob
who was stationed as a guard at Camp Chase near Cincinnati,
"Dear brother, I wish that you could be with me, we are
having it good. We 40 men have hired two black women to
21
cook for us for 7-8 dollars a month." He further stated,
"I am busy making rings--! already made seven for three
dollars and a half and have four on hand to make for a
half a dollar each." He remarked that the cedar cane
with the grapevine design was almost ready.
Murf reesboro, Tenn.
July 20, 1864
Dear Brother,
Peceived your letter last evening and see
that you are well, for which I am glad and I too
can say that with God's help I am well. I don't
know anything new to write this time, only that
last night we caught a lot of fish with our net.
Our Lieutenant bought it for us for $2.00. We
were saddened last week when we heard that our
Col., 2 Captains and 4 Lieutenants of our regiment
were let out because they didn't pass the exams
as well as some others. It hit our second Lt.
who is in command here. He is going home happy
and says that he will go to the 3rd Battery
where he had formerly been 9 months. Dear brother,
I wish that you could be with me, we are having
it good. We 40 men have hired two black women
to cook for us for 7-8 dollars a month. We are
divided in two messes. I am very busy making
rings--! already made seven for three dollars
and a half and have four on hand to make for
half dollar each. I am also making a cane again
out of Cedar wood--instead of a snake design !
am making a grapevine--it is almost ready. !
wouldn't sell it for $8,00. The days are going
by like an hour--! have one year yet from the
18th of Sept. to serve. I think this year will
pass as quickly as the others. With these few
lines ! will come to an end and hope this finds
you well and that we will meet again at home
soon, if God wills it. Your loving brother,
D. C. Miller
22
In this letter dated July 24, 1864 Miller stated that
they were building another stockade closer to the railroad
bridge. The first one was 300 yards away from the bridge
and the new one would be 60 yards away. He related that
20 men were sent there to build the new stockade. He
said, "We sleep the whole night and stand no guard, and I
am glad of that." His concern for a younger brother
who was contemplating enlistment was evident when he said,
"I think it hurts parents to lose three sons at once."
Murf reesboro, Tenn.
24 July 1864
Dear parents, brothers, and sisters,
I got your letter this evening and am happy
to hear that you are all in good health. We had
to leave our Log House because it was about
300 yards away from the railroad bridge. Now
we are going to build another one about 60 yards
from the bridge which is octagonal in shape.
We have about 2 men here who will build the new
house and we have a much better time here. We
work from 5 to 7 and then eat our breakfast, then
from 7:30 til 9:00 we have a rest period and work
again slowly in the evening. It should keep us
busy about 5 or 6 months. We sleep the whole
night and stand no guard, and I am glad of that.
I think it hurts the parents to lose three
sons at once. That is about all the news for
now except that the pears are ripe now. 1000
greetings from your loving son and brother.
Here are still $10.50 for your daughter
Vernell. Thanks many times for the silver. I
have enough of it now. If you see Fred Smith
sometime tell him to send me a letter again about
his health and all the news. Greetings to him
also.
23
In a July 25, 1864 letter to his brother Jacob,
Miller expressed his pleasure that Jacob had left Camp
Chase and was now at Covington either guarding forts or
the city. He again said to his brother, "I wish that you
were here. You would have a better time with us."
Daniel Miller described the stockade in v/hich he and 29
other Union men were living and guarding the railroad.
He concluded by saying, "We live like gentlemen from
Cincinnati." He mentioned the apples, plums, cherries,
potatoes, and strawberries that he and his comrades had
been enjoying.
Stockade near Murfreesboro
July 25, 1864
Dear brother.
Glad to have received your letter and am
glad to know that we are both well. Also happy
to hear that you are in Covinton where life is
much easier than at Camp Chase. We too had to do
a lot of training when I was there, but now we
live like gentlemen from Cincinnati. Almost
three weeks now have passed since we left Murfrees-boro
to guard the railroad and bridges between
Nashville and Murfreesboro. We are staying in a
big log house or stockade as they call it here.
This building is made out of big tree trunks
which are about 20 to 25 inches thick and 15
feet high with an 8 ft. deep cistern in the
center of the building. There are many holes in
the walls through which to shoot and room enough
for about 200 men. In my next letter to our
parents, I will send them a drawing of this
stockade. I don't believe that you have ever
seen anything like this. I only have to stand
guard every 3 or 4 days, but it is not so bad
24
because I can sit rather than stand. There are
30 of us and we have a good 2/Lt. in command.
I was wondering whether you guard the forts on
the hill or the city of Covington. If you have
the time why don't you go to Newport and ask
where the Cligsendern Pike is. That is where
we were. There was a drawing in one of the
magazines here about it. It is about 2 miles
from the bridge which crosses the Licking River
between Covington and Newport. You say that it
is warmer in Kentucky but I believe that it is
warmer here. Because the apples, plums, cherries,
potatoes, are all ripe, but the strawberries
have been gone for 4 or 5 weeks . We have a net
here and catch fish every other morning for a
breakfast for 30 men. I v/ish you v/ere here. You
would have a better time with us. Closing now
with the hope that these few lines reach you in
good health, and hoping also that I can talk to
you in person pretty soon. Nothing new this
time. May God bring us home safely together again.
1000 wishes and greetings from your loving brother.
Daniel C. Miller in a letter to his younger brother
dated August 10, 1864 said to him, "To come back to your
enlistment, I would rather let you and our parents decide
that." However, Daniel remarked that if the younger
brother decided to enlist that perhaps he might be able
to join the Company B Regiment to which Daniel belonged.
Daniel mentioned the scarcity of newspapers since
Generals Grant and Sherman had forbidden that any news
or newspapers should get out beyond the lines of
Kentucky. He again mentioned the good life with
peaches and watermelons and a rebel pig to alter the
25
Murf reesboro, Tenn,
August 10, 1864
Dearly beloved brother.
Again I was glad to hear that you are well.
I too can say with God's help that I am well.
News is very rare here at the moment, because
v/e have not received a newspaper for over a week
because the Generals Grant and Sherman have
forbidden that any news or newspapers should get
out beyond the lines of Kentucky. So that when
our troops make another move the Rebels will
not know it as fast as our old Abraham Lincoln.
Today we received the first newspaper again but
without much news in it. We still have a good
life and even better now because peaches and
watermelons are ripe besides that we caught a
Rebel pig that helped to alter our menu. To
come back to your enlistment I had rather let you
and our parents decide that. I believe our
company is filled up now, but I will check again
with our Lieutenant or orderly and will let you
know in my next letter. I believe that you will
be able to get into our Regiment, but I would not
advise you to get into another.
There is one other thing I want to ask you,
William Akerman told some days ago to Christie in
his letter that he was busy for two days carrying
dead soldiers off of the battlefield, but I cannot
believe it because you know he is a liar and a
put-on. Let me know about it in your next
letter. Please be so kind and give this address
to Mortimer Manfeld and tell him that James Kanady
is in Company D, 115th Regiment and that he is
well, but had been sick for several weeks.
I am closing with 1000 wishes and greetings,
your loving brother.
P.S. Farewell, hope we see each other soon.
Write soon again.
Daniel C. Miller's love and concern for his family
was evidenced by the frequency of the letters which they
26
received from him--sometimes three or four a month. In
this letter dated August 17, 1864 he mentioned his sadness
in learning that his mother was sick again. He pointed
out the extreme August heat in the South and said, "I
walk almost always barefoot, not that I don't have socks
or shoes, no I have a good pair of shoes and 2 pairs of
socks." His reference to Sherman in Atlanta indicates
the successes of the Federal forces in penetrating the
Southland. Miller said, "We heard that Sherman's army
is lying still because of the great heat. Near Atlanta
the temperatures are around 100 degrees." In this same
letter, Daniel Miller described the intricate work which
he had put into a picture frame. His sense of humor
comes forth when Daniel said, "It is a very beautiful
frame and especially will be when I will be behind it."
Also, in this letter Miller made a reference to a rumor
he had heard concerning the loyalty of Mary Todd Lincoln,
the President's wife.
Murf reesboro, Tenn.
August 17, 1864
Dear parents and sister.
I received your letter this morning before
I got up, but I was so sad while reading it. I
am so sorry that Mother is sick again, but what
can be done? The Lord knows best, and I hope
that this letter will meet you feeling as well
27
as I am when it left me. Dear parents, there is
not much news this time. We heard that Sherman's
army is lying still because of the great heat.
Near Atlanta the temperatures are around 100
degrees, here it is also very warm, but I got
used to it quite well and run around in this
heat. I walk almost always barefoot, not that I
don't have socks or shoes, no I have a good pair
of shoes and 2 pair of socks. I have also made
6 dollars from rings, since you have sent me the
silver coins, and this week I have to make 5
more rings, and one person wants that I shall make
10 rings for him, so that he can use them as
Christmas gifts at home. You also and Mother
shall each get one; for Father I made a traveling
suit, there is more work on it than on the first.
I could have gotten $5 for it before it was ready,
but $10 could not have bought it. I will soon
have ready the picture frame. It is made thus:
On top the coat of arms, underneath two cannons, on
both sides is a rose with 6 leaves. It is a very
beautiful frame and especially so when I will be
behind it.
Dear parents don't believe everything the
people tell that the 100-days volunteers cannot
come home when their time is over. The government
has the power to do this. After their 100 days
the government has to work 1-2 months before they
can come home. I also cannot believe that Lincoln
is such a blockhead that he lets his wife go across
the border and betray himself. For more than one
night he is occupied to study how he could make
an end to this war. Seven days ago I had been
for 2 years in the army. I think this year will
be over soon. Otherwise I don't know anymore to
write. Greetings to Mama and Louise Refer and
all who ask about me, also Jacob Hirt. Many
thousand greetings and wishes for better health
for Mother. I hope that I can see you all as
well as I have left you. Amen.
D. C. Miller
Co. B. 115 Regt. O. V. I
Murf reesboro, Tenn.
28
In this letter of September 9, 1864, Miller gave a
dramatic account of the Confederate attack on the Stewart's
Creek blockhouse carried out by General Joseph Wheeler and
his troops. At the time of the attack, the Union
soldiers were still in the process of tearing down the
old stockade which was 300 yards away from the railroad
and constructing a newer one 60 yards away from the rail
line. The Union soldiers had just torn down about ^
of their old headquarters when the attack occurred.
Miller along with 30 other Federals was captured and
taken to Nashville v/here they were held in a "very big
house that belonged to the Rebel General Zollicof fer .
"
Nashville, Tenn.
Sept. 9th, 1864
Dear parents, brothers and sisters,
I was sorry not to get a letter from you for
so long. You perhaps heard that the Rebel
General Wheeler destroyed and burned 30 miles of
railroad track.
This Rebel General with 6 or 8,000 men encountered
us just as we had torn down k of our headquarters,
because we wanted to use the wood or material
for our new blockhouse. He came at night and at
seven in the morning we already shot at his cavalry
which destroyed and burned the railroad. I fired
the second shot and I am sure I didn't miss. We
fought til one o'clock when the Rebel General fired
twelve pound cannon six times at us, but he only
hit the blockhouse twice. Since we had lost all
ground we had to give ourselves up. He burned
down the blockhouse containing everything that he
didn't want. He took us with him and let us go
29
after forty miles. We did not get anything to eat
except twice fat bacon or bread. I had two ears
of corn and an apple besides which were very good
and I wouldn't have sold them for ten dollars.
The corn I had stolen from a donkey at night.
Now there are 31 of us in Nashville in a very big
house which belonged to the Rebel General
Zollicaf f er
.
Here now we get enough to eat. Perhaps
today or tomorrow we go back to our old place.
The Rebels took us with them 2h days til our
artillery and infantry were on their heels, then
they let us go. But the Rebels got beaten up
pretty much. Black soldiers took from
them 3 cannon and some 100 soldiers and horses.
On our way back we met the ninth Ohio Cavalry and
I met Casper Fox again. They were after Wheeler.
Will close now and write you a longer letter
next time.
In this letter dated September 11, 1864, two days
after his capture by the Confederates, Miller and his
comrades were back in Murf reesboro. Again, Miller
recounted very dramatically the attack on Stockade #6
and explained that after being held prisoner for two days
the Yankees let them go. When it became imminent that
the Union "guards must surrender the blockhouse. Miller
said that they burned or twisted their rifles so as make
them useless to the Yankees. In a regretful tone Miller
related, "We had to leave everything behind--my
pretty cane and the picture frame I broke in two--I cut
some of the design off of the cane so that they couldn't
use it." He concluded by saying, "If the Rebels come
back later we will show them how Yankees can fight."
30
Murf reesboro, Tenn.
Sept. 11, 1864
Dear parents,
Arrived safe and sound in Murfreesboro t'oday.
We were all in the blockhouse on Aug. 31 when at
7:00 o'clock we saw about 50 men on horseback
about k mile behind our house marching to the
railroad. Then a fellow named Martin Stimmel and
I went to see what they were doing and saw them
start to tear up the railroad ties&#8212;we each fired
5 or 6 shots and they left after four or five
ties were torn up. As we turned to go back to our
blockhouse their pistol shots rang out and we had
to jump back. When we got back we saw 6,000
around our house about 1000 yards, so that we
couldn't do very much with them. 8 or 10 of us
went to the railroad bridge which they were trying
to set afire and we made them jump. Several fell
and we could see them as they raised their hands
before they fell. I am sure that I hit one of
them because as soon as I shot at him, he fell.
This was about noon--then five men came with a
white flag and they wanted us to give up the
blockhouse or they would put a cannon on it--
which later did happen. We said we wouldn't give
it up and they left. In five minutes we saw
that they had a 12 lb. cannon brought out of the
woods and they put it behind a little rise where
we couldn't do anything to them and it was too
far for our rifles. Then came shell after shell
over our blockhouse&#8212;two of them hit a bean and
shattered it. They shot at us six times and only
hit twice&#8212;then our Sargeant put up a white flag
and they quit. You should have seen the Rebels
coming out of the woods from every angle, but
didn't fire anymore. They plundered our house and
we had to stand in ranks. We burned our rifles
(or twisted) so that they couldn&lt;''t use them.
They made us go with them for two days and two
nights about 40-50 miles. Then they let us go
&#8212;
we had to leave everything behind&#8212;my pretty cane,
and the picture frame I broke in two&#8212;I cut some
of the design off of the cane so they couldn't
31
use it. When we were 1 1/3 miles away from the
blockhouse we could see the smoke as they burned
it down and they had hacked down the railroad
bridge If they would have arrived
one day later, they could have taken us with one
cannon shot. The log house v/here the other 3
men were was shot into twice, and from these 30
men there were 3 dead and 8 or 10 wounded. If
we would have had an officer there instead of a
sergeant there would have been more dead. The
battle really went hot there. We are all very
happy that v/e are back here again. If the
Rebels come back later we will show them how
Yankees can fight. They held back their Cavalry
until the big dog which is a big cannon was used
on us. We were very hungry on our trip but I
made it well. I had to laugh when the others
showed long faces and talked bad. They kept us
in a house in Nashville and we walked back to our
regiment in Murfreesboro some 30 miles away.
The trauma which Miller experienced during his
capture is still evident in this letter dated September 18,
1864. He said, "I am thankful to God who has kept me
well and kept the fiery bullets of the enemy away from me."
He described the joyful reception which awaited him upon
his return to Murfreesboro and his regiment. He further
said, "That Rebel VJheeler got licked good after he let
us go." Here he was referring to Wheeler's raid into
Kentucky following the attack on blockhouse #6.
Hurrah for Old Abe and Old Andy
Murfreesboro, Tenn.
Sept. 18, 1864
Dear Parents and sister,
Your letter was received ten minutes ago
and was joyfully received. I see you are all well
32
and I am thankful to God who has kept me well
and kept the fiery bullets of the enemy away
from me. On the 11th we again arrived safely
with our regiment in Murf reesboro. They were
glad to see us because they didn't know that the
Rebel Gen. Wheeler had let us go and that we had
arrived in Nashville, when our Captain saw us he
began to laugh and said, "Hello, what does all
this honor to my boys mean?" He was so happy
he could hardly talk for laughing. He is a good
man. We had to leave everything when the Rebs
came, except what we had on. I still have my
watch&#8212;I could have sold it for $22.00 but I
will not do so under 25.00 or $28.00. We don't
have to pay for the clothes we lost and have
already received new ones. I don't have the
cane and frame anymore either&#8212;when the Reb
came it was broken, but I have another made just
about like the other was. I haven't forgotten
the rings I promised you. I don't know if we
will be paid this time since we were taken prisoner--
since the pay papers are sent in ahead and we were
not here to sign. The next time we will get
that much more. But if you need money, I can
borrow some and pay it back. Write me. I am
glad that Jacob is working in Canton--he is
better off than in the Army. He doesn't have to
kill himself and is free as the birds which we
aren't. The Rebel Wheeler got licked good after
he had let us go&#8212;I don't think he can bring
many out of Tenn. with him. With this I will
close and hope that these few lines will reach
you in good health. With a thousand greetings.
Your loving son, D. C. Miller. Co. B. 115th Regt.
0. V. I., Murf reesboro, Tenn.
The fall of 1864 brought increased activities to
Tennessee from the standpoint of both Union and Confederate
armies. General W. T. Sherman ordered 30,000 men to
General Thomas at Nashville on the chance that General
John B. Hood, Confederate commander, would attempt to
invade Tennessee. The Confederate general, Nathan Bedford
Forrest, stepped up his raids in Tennessee destroying
33
railroad tracks, blockhouses, bridges, and telegraph lines.
In the next three or four letters Miller makes reference
to many of the incidents that took place in Tennessee
during the last few months of the Civil War. In his
letter of September 28, 1864 he is at Stockade #10 on
the Nashville and Chattanooga Railroad. In this letter he
made an appeal to his father. "If you love freedom, vote
again for our old Abraham Lincoln. He is the man for our
land. Hurrah for Old Abe."
Stockade #10 Tenn. on N. &amp; C. RR
Sept. 28, 1864
Dear parents.
Received your last letter and am glad to
hear that you are all well. I too am well.
Nothing new except that the Rebel General Forrest
was around here and where he is now we can't say
&#8212;
for ten days the railroad has not been running.
Our fifty men went on the first train to Tullahoma.
The night before when we were already in Murfrees-boro
by the depot, we received notification that
the railroad had been torn up and the telegraph
had been cut 27 mi. from Murf reesboro. The next
morning at half past five we went on the train as
guards and the Rebels had gotten to the place an
hour before and had torn it up. The Negroes were
busy at it and trying to fix it up so we could
pass. Now 15 of our company are 23 miles from
M'boro at Stockade #10. How long we will be here
I can't tell you. We have it real good here.
Tuesday we butchered a one year old calf which
came too near us&#8212;it was nice and fat. Today we
ate the last of it. Dear sister, I want to make
you some rings when I get the time and send them
home with the cane. Our Lieutenant says we
probably will be mustered out in Cleveland and
that will be a little over ten months. Dear
34
father, if you love freedom, vote again for our
old Abraham Lincoln. He is the man for our land.
Hurrah for Old Abe. With that I will close. Lots
of greetings until we see each other soon. Your
loving son, D. C. Miller.
P. S. We haven't been paid yet--but it shouldn't
be long.
In Miller's letter of November 18, 1864 he had been
sent to a blockhouse in Christiana, Tenn. The election
was over and he remarked, "The voting went off well here.
We thought that the Rebs would bother us, but they
didn't." Miller rejoiced at the election of Old Abe and
had this to say, "Our old Abe was voted in again for the
next four years&#8212;now the War will soon be over--the Rebs
themselves say they can't stand it."
Murf reesboro, Tenn.
Nov. 18, 1864
Dear mother, sister Kamerad and worthy friend.
Received your letter and was glad to hear
all are well. VJith God's blessing and help I too,
am well. As soon as I saw the letter I realized
it was Caspar Fuch ' s handwriting and I wondered if
he was in Cleveland, Tenn. or Ohio. If only I
could be with you we would both have a nice time.
Dear Friend, I don't know if I will be here
because our Co. those that were left, day before
yesterday&#8212;half went to Christiana, nine miles
from here&#8212;the others to Fosterville where I am
going in five or six days&#8212;it is also on this
railroad to Chattanooga. If you come to Christiana,
ask after me. I was glad to hear that my father
went to Canton, I believe he went once before.
I think this week I will send two canes and a
picture frame home. The voting went off well here.
35
We thought the Rebs v;ould bother us, but they
didn't. It was about 100 miles from here, three
of our boys were several miles in the country to
find some U. S. horses, when they were attacked
by this band--one of them got away on his horse,
but the bullets flew and buzzed like bees in a
basket. He made it safely to camp and reported
it at once. Then 80 men from Co. K. went after
the Rebs and took a Captain, a Lieutenant and
four men, besides our two boys. These Rebels
belonged to Rebel Gen. Wheeler's Command&#8212;they
were at home on furlough before they were taken
prisoner--one of them I knew. I believe if this
one had not received word, all three v;ould have
been hung or taken to Dixie. Our Old Abe was
voted in again for the next 4 years&#8212;now the War
will soon be over--the Rebs themselves say they
can't stand it. With a thousand greetings and
wishes, Daniel C. Miller
Miller's letter of January 3, 1865 stated "for over
four weeks we didn't receive any letters or newspapers
because the Rebels were between our blockhouse and
Murf reesboro . We have only a little news but it is good
news, because the Rebels were badly beaten at Nashville,
Franklin, and Murf reesboro. " He mentioned that 195 of
his regiment who were in a blockhouse between Murfreesboro
and Nashville were captured. He further said, "The Rebels
desert by the hundreds every day and they say that the
South would be better off to give up because they do not
have a chance .
"
Christiana, Tenn,
January 3, 1865
Dear parents and sister.
Your two letters I received last night. For
over four weeks we didn't receive any letters or
36
newspapers because the Rebels were between our
blockhouse and Murf reesboro. I am still well and
hope you are too. We have only a little news but
it is good news, because the Rebels were badly
beaten at Nashville, Murf reesboro, and Franklin
and are now on their retreat to the Tennessee
River where they got beaten again. The Rebels
desert by the hundreds every day and they say that
the South would be better off to give up because
they do not have a chance. When the battle of
Franklin began which is about 27 miles from
Nashville and 15 miles from Murfreesboro we
received an order that our forty men were to go
to the blockhouse #16 which is 41 miles from
Murfreesboro to wait out the year there. On the
first of January we returned to Christiana which is
11 miles from Murfreesboro. We have it nice
here. Every five days I am on guard for four
hours. We do not know how long we have to stay
here. We were not involved in any battles, but
our Captain and part of our Regiment was captured
by the Rebels. 195 of our Regiment who were in
the blockhouse between Kurf reesboro and Nashville
including some dead and some wounded ones were
also captured by the Rebels. Our Captain with
70 men who were in a little fort near Lavergne
had to give up after a five hour battle.
Our Captain had been ill for four months
and it is going to be hard on him. Casper Fuch
was with me when the battle began at Franklin.
He told me all about you. Yarn is short here
too. Sometimes you have to walk ten or twenty
miles before you see a sheep. The pound (v70ol)
costs over two dollars and it is hard to get.
I am thinking about sending my coats home in the
spring with my overcoat. If my Captain hadn't
been captured, I would have received a furlough.
With these few lines I will close hoping that
they find you well as they have left me. I
wish all of you a happy new year and good health.
Write again soon and farewell.
On January 18, 1865, Daniel C. Miller was still at
Christiana, Tennessee. Of the plight of the South he
37
said, "Our Rebel Hood is far into the State of Georgia.
Our cavalry is always on his back." He mentioned that he
was now making ax handles which he sold for 50 cents each.'
He also said, "We have enough to eat as long as we have
the chance to visit the Rebels on their large farms. They
don't have negroes anymore&#8212;they are all working for
Uncle Sam in the woods, cutting wood for the railroad."
Christiana, Tenn.
January 18th, 1865
Dear parents.
Received your letter and was pleased to note
that you are all well. I also received a letter
yesterday from Elizabeth and Jacob. There are a
lot of news but I cannot write everything. Our
Rebel General Hood is far into the State of Georgia.
Our Cavalry is always on his back, he can't be still
for a day's rest. It will not be long before the
States of Georgia and Alabama are back in the Union
because they are tired of fighting and are
hungry. Today we heard that a large important
Fort was taken by us&#8212;this is something big because
this fort and the city of Wilmington which also
will be taken in a few days, is the key to Richmond.
I think I have written you that we are in a new
place again&#8212;10^ miles south of Murf reesboro. A
real nice place. Every five days I get 4-hour
watch. For that I need only a little wood to cook
with. Yesterday someone named Sexauer and I made
ax handles&#8212;we get 40 to 50&lt;; a piece&#8212;we have
already made 8. We could make 8-12 a day. We
still have enough to eat. Yesterday we butchered
an ox&#8212;he had strayed from a herd--he belonged to
Uncle Sam. Yesterday we had two barrels of corn
ground. Today five of our men were out and got
four sacks of corn from a good rebel lady. We will
have enough to eat as long as we have the chance
to visit the Rebels on their large farms. They
don't have negroes anyiT\ore--they are all working
for Uncle Sam in the woods, cutting wood for the
railroad. With this I will close and hope the
letter reaches you in good health. Your loving
son, D. C. Miller, c/o Lt. J. Deuble
In his letter of March 11, 1865, Miller was
anticipating his going hone to Ohio since the war would
soon be over. He said, "I would like to be with you
dear parents, so that I could help with the butchering and
you know how I like sausages!" He went on to say, "I
think that when I come home I can hardly find your house."
Christiana, Tenn.
March 11, 1865
Dear parents,
Today I received your last letter and see
that you are well, for which I am happy. Especially
also to receive one from Mother&#8212;I could read it
better than the one from sister, although I can
read everything she wrote. I am still so grateful
to God for the health which I daily enjoy. I
hope that these few lines will reach you in as
good health as I was when I wrote this. There
isn't much in the way of news now&#8212;only a lot of
troops going by on the railroad every day. We
understand that 25,000 men are going to the Front.
That should be a big army when they all get
together. Most of them are cavalry. Yes, I would
like to be with you dear parents, so that I could
help with the butchering and you know how I like
sausages!! I am sorry that the paymaster has not
come yet since I mentioned it in two previous
letters. But it will come. The war will not last
much longer or my time will be over. I think
when I come home, I can hardly find your house.
I am wondering who is in my house, if they are
still there or not and if you see one of them, ask
if they know where Rudolph or Rudi is&#8212;they should
give you their address. I would also like to hear
from them.
39
On March 24, 1865 Daniel C. Miller was still in the
blockhouse at Christiana, Tennessee. He said, "Our
troops are still victorious. It probably won't be more
than 14 days before we occupy the Rebel camp at Richmond.
In a few days Generals Sherman and Grant will really give
it to the Rebels and when they do I pity those Rebels. The
South has just about had it, and instead of staying in the
army, they desert." He stated that he was looking
forward to going to work in Canton, Ohio when the war
was over.
Christiana, Tenn.
March 24, 1865
Dear parents and sister,
Received your letter and am well. Dear sister
I received the gold paper in good order and thank
you very much for it. Everything is still the same
in that every day our troops are still victorious.
It probably won't be but 14 more days until we
occupy the Rebel camp at Richmond. In a few
days Generals Sherman and Grant v/ill really give
it to the Rebels and when they do I pity those
Rebels. A lot of soldiers pass by here every
day. The South has just about had it. And instead
of staying in the Army, they desert.
Bravo . As I read in the Messenger last night,
V7ithin the last 30 days 2,000 Rebels deserted
among them 40 officers. Dear parents as soon as
I get paid, I will send most of my clothes home
so that I won't have much to carry or lose as I
come home. I was glad to get the address from
R. Meyers. I was also glad to hear that my brother
Jacob is well in Canton. I am already looking
forward to going to work there myself.
Greetings to all who ask about me.
40
On May 4, 1865, Miller wrote from Christiana,
Tennessee "The war is not entirely over and Jeff Davis will
not get very far through South Carolina before he will be
caught with his money. Our Cavalry General Stoneman with
15,000 men on horses has almost caught up with him. Davis
with six wagons full of gold and silver and 2,000 cavalry
is only one days ride ahead of him. I would like to be
there when they catch him. " He also stated that he no
longer had to watch the railroad since as of the 15th
of May the Federal government was turning the railroad back
to the State of Tennessee.
Christiana, Tenn.
May 4, 1865
Dear parents.
Have received your letter and am glad to hear
that everyone is well. I am well also. Nothing
new except we read in the paper that 400,000 men
are to be discharged and all men that are in
hospitals, who can help themselves, will be
released. Sherman's troops are to be on the way
home. I can't say yet how it will be with us
because the railroad doesn't have to be watched
anymore and from the 15th of this month, the
government is turning the railroad back over to the
State of Tennessee. Also all quartermasters have
been ordered to draw more rations to last until
the first of June. We think we can come home in
a few weeks. I would be delighted to get home
before my time is over, if not 3k months isn't so
long. It has been a long time since I received a
letter from E. Fox. I have received three letters
from Chas. and Rudolph thinks they are still in
Chattanooga in 20th C. 0. Rudi compalins that he
41
doesn't get enough to eat. The 4th Army Corps came
by here last week on the way to Nashville, and
where they go from there is not known, but we
think the most of them are going home. The war is
not entirely over and Jeff Davis will not get very
far through S. Carolina before he will be caught
with his money. Our Cavalry General Stoneman v/ith
15,000 men on horses has almost caught up with him.
Davis with six wagons full of Gold and Silver and
2,000 Cavalry is only one days ride ahead of him.
I would like to be there vihen they catch him.
Until we see each other soon, I am. your loving
son, D. C. Miller
From Christiana, Tennessee on April 17, Miller wrote
a letter to his parents that has a very tragic note to
it. He wrote, "I am very concerned about what I read in
the newspaper and am still wondering whether to believe
it or not because you can't trust the newspaper. We read
that our President Lincoln was shot in a theatre in
Washington last Friday and died at 7:20 Saturday morning.
If all this is true, it will be very hard on us." He
also said, "that the Rebel General Lee has surrendered,
including the Generals Hood and the bloodhound Forrest."
Miller went on to say, "Yesterday was Easter Sunday, but
we didn't have any eggs like we do at home. They cost
30 cents a dozen here and are very rare."
Christiana, Tenn.
April 17, 1865
Dear parents and sister,
I would have answered your letters earlier but
there was no way to get the letters out of here.
Last Wednesday and Thursday it rained here as much
42
water as could come down from the sky. It knocked
dov/n or flooded some railroad bridges and the
trains can't run. Last week I read in the Canton
newspaper that my brother Jacob Miller broke his
arm or perhaps got it torn off by a horse. That
would be very hard for him and us. I am very
concerned about what I read in the papers and am
still wondering whether to believe it or not
because you can't trust the newspaper. We read
that our President Lincoln was shot in a theatre
in Washington last Friday night and died at 7:20
Saturday morning. At the same time Secretary Seward,
his son, and another man v;ere supposedly stabbed in
bed too, but neither of the 3 is dead yet. If all
this is true, it will be very hard on us. We are
not quite sure of all this, but you perhaps heard
all the news. And also that the Rebel General Lee
with his Army has surrendered, including the
Generals Hood and the bloodhound Forrest. I now
believe that the War is over or very close to it.
We have beautiful weather now. The peach trees
have already bloomed and the trees are green in
their splendor. Yesterday was Easter Sunday but
we didn't have any eggs like vie do at home. They
cost 30 cents a dozen here and are very rare. I
wish I could be with you and see everything I
haven't seen for 3 years.
Hoping this letter finds you as safe as when
it left me.
From Christiana, Tennessee on May 20, 1865, Daniel C.
Miller said, "Thank God for his guidance so far. I hope
He will take care of me and keep me as well as when I
left you to fight for our Fatherland. Amen." He related,
"Nothing much is new except that we see a lot of Rebels
on their way home. You should see them, they are as
filthy as pigs and full of lice."
43
Christiana, Tenn.
May 20, 1865
Dear parents and sister.
I received your last letter this evening, and
was very happy that you are all well. May our
Lord keep you til I come home to you, thank
God for his guidance so far, I hope he will take
care of me and keep me as well as I was when I
left you to fight for our Fatherland. Amen.
Nothing much is new except that v;e see a lot
of Rebels on their way home. You should see them,
they are as filthy as pigs and full of lice.
There is talk that we may not remain in Tenn. any
longer than 15 days. I believe it too. I do not
know the exact time but I wish it was tomorrow.
Dear father I wanted to make you a tobacco box
but it is too hot, but I will try it anyway.
Some of our men captured a Rebel who was
fishing at the River here and we sent some of our
men to look for another one, perhaps his brother,
and if they capture him they will get 100 dollars.
If they do, I will let you know in my next letter.
With these few lines I will close hoping it will
arrive there finding you in good health as it
left me. Farewell, hoping soon to be v;ith you
in person to talk to you. 1000 greetings and
wishes
.
Daniel C. Miller's last communication to his
parents was written from Christiana, Tennessee on June 8,
1865. Miller had this to say, "I will write to you
again and it may be the last time from here since at the
end of this week or the beginning of next, v/e'll be on
our way home. I thank God for my health and the same for
you." He mentioned that he had mailed by express a little
box to Cleveland, Ohio that weighed only 3-4 pounds.
^\? iii^^ V^ W'"^-w^-' ^:^'^ ''^^'^^?'^^-^^M--^^r^^ - '^' &lt;^y*^&#8226;^V.^^^ . &#8226;^:&#8226;.:.
44
?=&#171;
-^.
&gt; -^MIX n, M^ f^^&gt;J..!^ii^^ "'
^'V-^X 44pmii / &#171;F&lt;^ ^^- .U:-i*^^-^^-^^--
: ^^.^. /(fi V-l-^^ii^-&#8226;%&#8212;^ ^...iUJ^:..4J^- --^ ^ p-in
J
;:^..::.^.SL -^'afs
.cL&#8222;._.
^
p- &#8226;&#8226;tbto tonuwoc Will li&#171; &#8226;^^ &#8212;rr^"-* ri^.luiiS
r&#171;iwMr&#171;a&#171; Uim wvM /&lt;&gt;"&#187;' &lt;&#8226;'"&#171;'
45
However, a tobacco box that he had been making wasn't quite
ready and he wanted to bring it himself.
Christiana, Tenn.
June 8, 1865
Dear parents,
I will write to you again and it may be the
last time from here since the end of this week or
beginning of next, we'll be on our way home. I
thank God for my health and wish you the same.
Yesterday I received a letter from Rudolph and he
said my mother was sick and that Verona had written
to Jacob and Elizabeth to come home. I am so
sorry to hear this and hope that she soon v/ill be
well. I wouldn't have written yet but yesterday I
sent a little box to Cleveland on the Express. If
Jacob is still with you, he can get it. I
addressed to H. Miller, Cleveland, Ohio. Lymen
St. #92. It weights 3-4 lbs., only a little box.
The tobacco box however, isn't in it because I
want to bring it myself and it isn't quite
finished. I paid $3.80 to sent the box home&#8212;it
will not cost you anything. Today we learned what
regiment is to replace us. It is the 188th Ohio,
one year regiment. There are about 55 men here
who belong to new regiments. They have always
thought to get home before us but now they have
cooled off and don't say so much. Now I will
close and hope these few words will find all of
you in good health and hope we can talk to each
other soon. Your loving son, Daniel C. Miller.
Thus faded from the picture a young Yankee
soldier who spent one and one-half years on guard duty
in Middle Tennessee, for the most part in Rutherford
County. He fished in the streams, walked in the woods
where the Battle of Stones River was fought, and was
impressed with the beauty that surrounded him. He tried
46
to help pass the long hours by making walking canes from
the cedar that grew so plentifully in the county, by
making rings from silver coins, by making picture frames
and tobacco boxes. Indeed, he was a skilled artisan, and
the engraving on the boulder along Stones River where he
has left a bit of himself amongst us is as clear today
as if he had carved his name there only yesterday.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Recounts the experiences of Daniel C. Miller, a U.S.A. troop quartered in Rutherford County, using letters written by him to his family at home</dc:description>
<dc:subject>United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865; Rutherford County (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Civil War Stories; Miller, Daniel C.</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>50 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-01</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication26ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/143</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>