<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>The Coleman scouts</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Pittard, Mabel</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 13</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1979</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>U6
THE COLEMAN SCOUTS
BY MABEL PITTARD
In a study of the Coleman Scouts, it is well to give some attention to the
activities of the army to which this group of men was attached. This military
component was designated as the Army of Tennessee of thp Confederate States
of America. It was first commanded by General Albert Sidney Johnston.
Johnston's first concern was the fortification of Nashville, Tennessee, the
largest and most important city south of the Ohio River. Because of itr location
on the Cumberland River and being a railroad center, it served the southern
arny as an arsenal and depot of supplies. Ii order to secure the Confederate's
hold on this vital city, two forts were constructed near Nashville&#8212;Fort Donel-son
and Fort Henry. Both of these forts fell to the enemy in February of 1P62.
A series of events brought General Braxton Bragg to the command of this
array. General Johnston was killed at the Battle of Shiloh, and after a bri^f
temporary command by General Beaiiregard, the army was placed under the command
of General Bragg. This new general, a friend of Jefferson Davis, has been
characterized by some as uncompromising, cruel, and even Incompetent. However,
the troops he trained were celebrated for their efficiency.
Following his assumption of command. Bragg; moved his - troops to Tupelo,
ydssissippi and from there to Chattanooga, Tennessee. From Chattanooga, he
crossed the state of Tennessee and marched into Kentucky. H-^re he exper^. "^nced
a satisfactory campaign; yet despite hln successes, he withdrew to Tennessee
and settled at I'urf reesboro. This was in late s^^^ner and fall of 18o2.
Following the general practice of organizing scouting operations to k&lt;---'P
commanders informed of enemy operations, a group of yo'i;ig mm und^.r Capiain
Henry B. Shaw was brought together. These scouts, known interchangeaoly as
47
Shaw's Scouts or Colenan's Scouts, were to play an luportant part In the
operation of Bragg 's ainQr
&#8212;
an amy that had and was to fight some of the blood-iest
battles of the war&#8212;Shlloh, Stone's River, and Chickaaauga. This army
was to caapaign over more terrltoiy than any other army on either side. Its
men were to display courage unequaled by that of any other amy. It was to
suffer the most conqjlete defeat of any Confederate army, but its men were
stubbornly to refuse to admit defeat until only a few were left to fight. Its
scouts were to suffer hardship and constant danger. Some were to be imprisoned
and others to be tortured as they met their death.
The tactics and strategy of warfare depend on information as well as on
soldiers and guns. Spies and scouts were sent into enemy territory to gather
news concerning movement of troops, to secure newspapers, and any other vital
Information about enenQr resources. Both the Northern and Southern armies
during the rfar Between the States availed themselves of this medivun of securing
information. It was for this purpose that the Coleman Scouts was organized.
This group of scouts was actively engaged In their duties by the time Bragg
moved from Kentucky into Tennessee. Shaw, the captain ot the group, assumed
the name Coleman to hide his real Identity. He was a spy. Dressed in civilian
clothing, he operated within enemy lines under the guise of an itinerant herb
doctor. Information secured by Shaw was passed from him to the scouts and then
relayed to Confederate headquarters. The scouts under Shaw's command were not
spies; they wore the uniform of the Confederate array and carried upon their
persons credentials which were to Insure their treatment as prisoners of war in
event of their capt\ire. Following is a copy of the pass carried by one of the
men, Sam Davis, and Issued to him by the commanding officer of the Army of
Tennessee:
Headquarters General Bragg 's Scouts
Middle Tennessee, September 25, I863
h6
Samuel Davis has permission to pass on scouting duty anywhere in Middle
Tennessee or north of the Tennessee River he may think proper.
By order of General Bragg,
&#163;. Coleman, Commanding Scout
These passes served a two-fold pxirpose. Not only were they supposed to
assure the scout of better treatment in the event of capture, but the creden-tials
made it easier for the men to seciire food, lodging, and aid from
Southerners who might otherwise suspect them of being Northern spies.
Since the scouts operated mainly in Middle Tennessee, many of those detailed
for this particular duty were from Middle Tennessee counties. The membership
of this group was a fluctuating one&#8212;some were members for a short time until
their capture or death and others for a longer period. So far as could be
determined, there is no con^jlete published list of the roll that made up the
membership of the Coleman Scouts&#8212;however, it is thought that about one hundred
men seirved at one time or another as a member of this group. Following is a
list of about forty-five members found in a roll published in the Confederate
Veteran following the war.
"We the surviving fellow scouts have met and from memory given to the
Veteran a list of all who belonged to Shaw's Scouts:
Captain - Henry B. Shaw
John Davis
Alf Douglas (Nashville)
Tom Joplin
Bill Robinson
Everard Patterson
Bill Roberts
Billy Moore (Columbia)
Joshua Brown (Clarksville)
Munford Street
Gup Kibble
Tom Brown (Nashville)
Dick Taylor
Alex Gregg (Nashville)
Sam Roberts
Tom Hughes (Nashville)
Pillow Humphrays
"Kage" Everette
Dich Dlllard
James Patterson
Newt Vaughn (Columbia)
E. Grant
Hans Carter
Jim Carter
Hich Kelley
Josh Luck
W. H. Portch (Nashville)
R. F. Cotton (Franklin)
George Hughes
John Schute
E. M. Patterson
49
Dee Jobe L. K. Owen
Dan Sneed Richard Anderson
Sam Davis Li Hard
Tom Gvd.nn WHl Hughes
Charley Lippingwell Ben Douglas
Jack Coffee John Mclvey
Bob Owens (Columbia) John Drane
In the recruiting of young men as members of this group there were certain
characteristics taken into consideration, aamelj: (1) preferably they were to
be young (in their twenties) and unmarried so that family responsibilities
would not be a deterrent in carrying out dangerous assignments; (2) they were
to be familiar with the terrain of Middle Tennessee; (3) they were to be
expert horse-back riders, and (4.) were to exhibit traits of intelligence,
bravery, and unquestionable loyalty.
Henry B. Shaw, the captain, was older than most of the scouts. Before
the War Between the States he had been a steamboat captain. Also, before the
war he had separated from his wife who retained the custody of their only
child who was a cripple. Shaw had been educated at the old "Nashville Military
Institute" now Montgomery Bell Academy. In 1856 he had taught school at
Sn^yma, Tennessee. One of his pupils then was Samuel Davis who was later to
be one of his scouts.
Only brief sketches of incidents surroionding the lives and careers of
most of the scouts were available. Rather full information was found about
perhaps ten or twelve of these scouts. Among the scouts that came to be known
for their exploits were John Davis, Samuel Davis, Dee Jobe, Joshua Brown, Billy
Moore, Tom Brown, Thomas Joplin, William Roberts, R. M. Dillard, and William
Munford Street. The very nature of the Coleman organization lent itself to
secrecy. This secrecy, coupled with the fact that few formal reports were made,
accounts for the fact that very little is known about many of the scouts and
their activities. However, it is known that theirs was a perilous assignment,
50
acconpanled by hardship and danger, and many of then were wounded, captured,
and some met their death in their line of duty.
Some, who were taken prisoner and confined to one of the several prison
o&amp;mpa operated by the Federals, spurned the amnesty oath at the end of the war
and chose rather to linger and die in a dreary prison atmosphere&#8212; far from home
and friends.
Headquarters for the Coleman Scouts was near Pulaski, Tennessee in a little
village called Can^jbellsville. A Mr. Schuler, a farmer in this snail community,
had offered his home as a meeting place for Shaw and his scouts.
Much of the information carried by the scouts was written with no attempt
at concealment by codification, while other information was sent in code so that
even the scouts were unable to decipher it. Messages sent in code used the
"Court Cipher" which entailed the use of a secret word or group of words that
changed often and relayed only by word of mouth&#8212;never put into writing&#8212;and
known by both the sender and the receiver.
"Manchester Bluffs" was a secret word used with the court cipher in messages
relayed by Coleman Scouts. The cipher worked this way: The entire alphabet was
written twenty-six times upon a page in such a way as to appear alike when read
either vertically or horizontally. The first letter of the key word is found in
the first horizontal col\amn and the first letter of the message in the first
vertical column. At the point of intersection of the two colimms is found the
letter used in the cipher message.
Exaii9)le: EHNY JEHMnFO Secret message: MANC HESTORBL
EHNY JEHMTEFO
Write Manchester Bluffs above secret message. Then go down column M until you
come to intersection E&#8212;go across to first column and find letter S:
SHAW CAPTURED
EHNY JEHMnFO
51
Next go down column A to H and write H. Next go down coTuinn N to N and write
A. Go down C to Y and across to W and we have the word Shaw.
The secret word was changed often and it has been said that iinless one
knew the key-word that it would be inpossible to decode a secret message. The
division between words in the original message were not followed. The letters
ran continuously so as not to reveal the ntunber of letters in particular words.
COURT CIPHER
A B C D E F G H I J K L M N P Q R s T u V W X Y z
B C D E F G H I J K L M N P Q R S T U V w X Y Z A
C D E F G H I J K L M N P Q R S T U V w X Y Z A B
D E F G H I J K L M N P Q R S T U V W X Y Z A B C
E F G H I J K L M N P Q R S T U V W X Y Z A B C D
F G H I J K L M N P Q R S T U V W X Y Z A B C D E
G H I J K L M N P Q R S T U V W X Y Z A B C D E F
H I J K L M N P Q R S T U V W X Y Z A B C D E F G
I J K L M N P Q R S T U V w X Y Z A B C D E F G H
J K L M N P Q R S T U V w X Y Z A B C D E F G H I
K L M N P Q R S" T U V W X Y Z A B C D E F G H I J
L M N P Q R S T U V W X Y Z A B C D E F G H I J K
M N P Q R S T U V W X Y Z A B C D E F G H I J K L
N P Q R S T U V W X Y Z A B C D E F G H I J K L M
P Q R S T U V W X Y Z A B C D E F G H I J K L M N
P Q R S T U V W X Y Z A B C D E F G H I J K L M N
Q R S T U V W X Y Z A B C D E F G H I J K L M N P
R S T U V W X Y Z A B C D E F G H I J K L M N P Q
S T U V W X Y Z A B C D E F G H I J K L M N P Q R
T U V W X Y Z A B C D E F G H I J K L M N P Q R S
U V W X Y Z A B C D E F G H I J K L M N P Q R S T
V W X Y Z A B C D E F G H I J K L M N P Q R S T U
W X Y Z A B C D E F G H I J K L M N P Q R S T U V
X Y Z A B C D E F G H I J K L M N P Q R S T U V w
Y Z A B C D E F G H I J K L M N P Q R S T U V w X
2 A B C D E F G H I J K L M N P Q R S T U V W X Y
The scouts became so efficient in secioring vital information concerning
Federal reinforcements and troop movements that in the fall of 1863 General Dodge
of the Union army auid stationed at Pulaski, Tennessee, offered a reward for
information concerning E. Coleman and the location of the scout headquarters.
It is not known who in the community revealed this information to Dodge
52
but in November, 1863, a group of Union calvalry men captured Shaw at the Schuler
home. Since no papers of inqportance were found on Shaw he was not charged with
being a spy. However, he was placed in jail in the courthouse at Pulaski.
On the eve before Shaw's arrest, Samuel Davis of Sinyma, Tennessee, Billy-
Moore, and perhaps others of the scouts had net their leader at the Schuler home.
Vital papers describine Federal fortifications aad the inovenent of Federal troops
in Tennessee had been given to Davis to be relayed to General Bragg at Chattanooga.
Carrying this vital information in his saddle bags and some of it hidden in the
sole of his boots, Davis set out to follow the scout line to Decatur, Alabama and
thence on to Chattanooga. Only a few miles from Pulaski, Davis was captured by
the Seventh Kansas Cavalry, called the "Jay Hawkers". Davis was placed in .jail in
Pulaski in the same room with his captain, Henry B. Shaw. Another scout, Billy
Moore, who was making his way to the Can^jbellsville headquarters, became chilled
and hungry and approached a farm house with the intent to ask for food. It so
happened that a group of Union soldiers were in the house, interrogating the
family about Coleman and his scouts. Billy Moore, realizing his iminent capture,
chewed up his pass so as .to avoid being identified with the Coleman Scouts. He,
too, was taken to Pulaski and placed in the same cell with Davis and Shaw. Under
cover of darkness, Moore managed to jump from an upper story window and ran off
into the night, making his way to Columbia, Tennessee, his home place. After
this escape, Davis and Shaw separated. Davis was repeatedly offered his freedom
if he would divulge the source of the information which was found on him. However,
Davis refused life itself at the price of betraying his leader and he was sentenced
to be hanged on November 27, 1863. Even with the noose around his neck, Davis
was again offered a full pardon, a horse and side arms, and conveyance to Confederate
lines if he would tell from whom he received the information. Rather than. betray
his leader, Davis accepted the sentence.
53
General Dodge ordered that Henry B. Shaw be sent to Johnson's Island in
Lake Erie where there was located a federal prison. This prison was enclosed in
a stockade surrounded by water. Sentinels were stationed on a walkway that was
near the top and on the outside of the stockade. A gun boat lay at anchor in the
lake. Escape was virtually in^iossible. Here Shaw was kept prisoner until near
the end of the war.
Another Rutherford County scout whose death was even more tragic than that
of Sam Davis was Dee Jobe. Dee's father Elibu C. Jobe was a cabinet maker in a
little niral coramunity known as Mechanicsville. On August 30, 186^, Jobe was
scouting in the vicin'ty of his home and lay down =n a thicket of trees and undrr
brush to rest and await darkness before going to visit his parents. A party of
Yankees siirrounded him and in an effort to make Jobe di'/uTgr information about
his activities, the Yankee troops put out his eyes, cut out his tongue and finally
dragged him to his death. Neighbors found his body and took word to his parents.
An old negro servant went for the body and Jobe was buried in the family burial
grounds near the old home place.
Following Shaw's arrest and subsequent imprisonment. Alex Grrgg became leader
of the Scouts. The group continued their operations but witi decreasing activltlps
as the end of the war neared.
Following the close of the war in April 186;,, Shaw came back to Tennessee and
went to the home of a fellow scout, John Davis of Smyrna&#8212;a half-brother of Sam
Davis. In the fall of 1866 the two men, Shaw and John Davis, purchased a steamboat
called the "David ';Vhite." It was a fine, large steamer valued at 3S0,000. On
February 17, 1867, on the Mississippi River below Helena, Arkansas, the boat was
blown up when the boiler exploded. John Davis and :''haw both ""ost their l^vep in
the accident.
Sometimes between the close of the war in 186^ and Shaw's death in 1867, there
was a called meeting of the Coleman Scouts to be held in Nashville, Tennessee
.
54
The pttrpose of the meeting was to pay a tribute of respect to those member scouts
who had accepted death rather than be disloyal to the Southern cause. Henry B.
Shaw was elected to preside over the meeting. Tom Brown and Sam Roberts served
as secretaries. They drew up a circular which they had printed, entitled, "A
Tribute of Respect to the Dead." In this circular the scouts paid tribute to
Sam Davis, Dee Jobe, and to R. M. Dillard&#8212; the latter chose to remain in prison
until he died rather than take the amnesty oath. Of Davis they said, "A truer
soldier, a piirer patriot, a braver man never lived." Of D. S. Jobe they said,
"We can but recollect with pride how nobly he died&#8212;strangled, beaten, abused; yet
he defied his persecutor and died rather than betray his comrades&#8212;he died rather
than betray them, never to be forgotten by the foe, for the leader has become a
raving maniac from contemplating his bloody deed." Of R. M Dillard they wrote,
"A brave and true scout, where is he? The dreary prison of Gamp Morton whispers,
he died here, within my gloomy walls&#8212;spurning the amnesty oath which was offered
him. He lingered and died and thus passed away one of the truest spirits that
ever blessed the earth."
This circular was signed by Shaw and fifteen other scouts who had assembled
to pay their respects to the dead. Uttle did Shaw and John Davis realize that
in only a few months they too would meet a tragic death, not from a military
standpoint&#8212;but in the explosion of the steamboat "David 'White".
</dc:description>
<dc:description>A history of the Coleman Scouts, a group of soldiers within the Army of Tennessee of the Confederate States of America</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Confederate States of America. Army of Tennessee; Bragg, Braxton, 1817-1876; Stones River, Battle of, Murfreesboro, Tenn., 1862-1863</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>17 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-01; mt2011-09-06</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication13ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/112</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>