<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Henderson King Yoakum</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Sloan, Eugene</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 10</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1978</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>19th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>4.6
Henderson King Youkum
.
&#8226; . by Eugene Sloan
There are tvo marble shafts of comparable cizo and close proximity
ia Oalcv/ood Cemetery in Huntsville, Texas, Each marks the resting place
of a prominent Tennessee soldier, .politician, and lawyer. There is no
evidence that the one from Lebanon and the other from Kurfreesboro ever
net in the "Volunteer State". Each^ beset by xmfortunate circumstances
in Tennessee^ vras to rise to undying fame following the "lone Star" of
Texas.
' ~ "' ..- _ &#8212;
Henderson King Yoakum (1810-I856), a West Point graduate, polltican,
and historian, was a lav/yer and six-year mayor of Murfreesboro. In 18-^5
he left Tennessee, by his ovm admission impoverished by political
activity.
: In a single decade he was to gain fame as a soldier, real estate
entrepreneur, lawyer, and Kasonic leader deep in the heart of Texas.
Samuel Houston (1793-1863) practiced law in Lebanon before being
elected to Congress in 1823 and later Governor of Tennessee. Disillusioned
and dishonored, he went to live with his old friends among the Indians.
Called to become the military leader who defeated the Mexicans, he was
elevated to the presidency of the Republic of Texas and ]iiter to the
Texas governorship. When he lay dying Sam Houston requested that ho be
"buried beside rqy good friend, Colonel Henderson Yoakum". Houston is
known to have practiced law in Rutherford County courts while maintaining
his office in Lebanon, but this appearance was while Henderson Yoakum was
a cadet at West Point.
Dr. Homer Pittard, Rutherford County historian^ spent months in travel
and correspondence to coinpile a remarkable eto^y of a man who is remembered
47
in Texas by having a county naiaed in hi 3 honor, but who ha a fev; roots
left in Tennessee.
An* abridgment of a biographical sketch of Henderson King Yoakum
appearing in numerous publications has been put into local perspective
in a presentation by Dr. Pittard, made at a Rutherford County Historical
Society meeting in 1975.
Texas school children learn of Colonel Henderson King Yoakum in
cuch a factual sketch as this;
Henderson King Yoakum, the Texas historian, oldest son
of George Yoakum, and his vri.fe Mary Ann Kaddy, was born at
"Yoakvm Fort" in the famous PougII'c Valley section of
Tennessee, September 6, 1810. At the age of 17 he was appointed
to West Point llilitary Academy, vhore he graduated in 1832.
He married Kiss Eveline Cannon, daushter of Robert Cannon,
near the little tovm of Philadelpliia, Roane County, Tennessee
in 1883.
Soon after his marriage, Henderson Yoakum moved to Mur-freesboro,
Tennessee, and entered tho office of Jud&#163;,e l-litchell
as a law student, soon was admitted to the bar and began
the practice of his profession in that town. He entered the
military service again in 1836 and cerved against the Indians
on the v/estern frontier, as a captain of a company under General
Edmund P. Gaines.
In 1838 he commanded another company in the Cherokee War.
Then on October 7, 1839, he ^/as elected as a member of the
Senate of the State of Tennessee, He made a splendid record in
the legislature, supporting both Jackson and Polk, and stood
strongly In favor of the annexation of Texas.
/8
On October 6, l8/i5, he and hia family and relatives
arrived In Huntcville, Texas. The followin,'^ year he volunteered
as a private, but soon ciade first lieutenant, in the company of
Captain James Gillespie and took an active part in the war \d.th
Kexicoj, distinguishing hirsself in the Battle of Monterey. After
the close of the war, he returned to Huntsville and resumed the
practice of law.
He formed a close friendship v;ith Peter W, Gray, a proni-nent
Texan, who encouraged hiia in writing a comprehensive
history of Texas. In 1853 Ycalnom established a home seven
miles out from Huntsville, called "Shepherd's Valley", and it
1,'as here that most of his work on the famous history was done,,
(Southern History Research Marazine, 1936)
6.
The Shepherd Valley house was constructed on lines of southern
architecture, with a wide hall through the center, large rooms with high
ceilings, and open fireplaces.
A Yoakum is said to have been in the Henry Hudson ex-pedition in the
New York area in 1611. Certainly, Valentine Yoakum appears in Peach
Creek, New York before moving to Greenbrier County in the present state
of West Virginia. There he established Yoakum Station in 1771, v;here he
and his family (with the exception of George) were massacred by Shawnee
Indians.
George killed three Indians with an iron skillet and. being "swift
of foot and great strength", escaped. At the age of 25 he married hiargaret,
the daughter of Isaac Vanbebber. Among their children was George II, who
moved to Powell's Valley in Claiborne County. Tennessee about 1790.
-49
Twenty-nine Yoakum families now live in Claiborne County, but none in
Roane County or in Monroe County, where Henderson King Yoakum's father
i.'aa a Justice-of-the-peace between 1815-1825.
Yoakum attended the "comnon schoolc of his conraunity" before being
recommended for West Point appointment by an Athens, Tennessee Congress-man,
James Coffleld Mitchell. The young Philadelphia, Tennesseean,
Henderson K. Yoakum was duly admitted April, 1828 to the United States
Milita::y Academy at Vest Point on a cadet warrant.
In 1833 he was graduated 21st in a class of 4.5 from the Academy, He
was the 682nd cadet to graduate from West Pointy
Soon after his commissioning, he married Miss Eveline Cannon, daughter
of Robert Cannon in Philadelphia, Roane County, Tennessee and moved to
Murfreesboro, In 1833 he resigned his commission in the array.
Congressman l'2.tchell reappeared in Yoakum's life when he became
his legal mentor after Yoakum resigned from the army and brought his
young bride to Murfreesboro, Mtchell liad become circvdt judge in the
eleventh district, including Rutherford County, where he served from
1830 to 1836. There is no record of how the 23 year-olc', ex-army officer
financed his studies or provided livlihood for his family while studying
law under guidance of Judge Mitchell.
Two interesting hints were discovered in a letter Eveline Yoakum
wrote to her mother. One of these leads to the conjecture that the Cannon
family was aiding their daughter. The letter has the cryptic statement
that, "Henderson started a French school, which will occupy but little of
his time and bo of some profit to us".
On July /&#187;, 1834-, Yoakum delivered an hour and a half address to the
"young men of Murfreesboro". Fortunately, this discourse has been preserved
50
by Q conteinporo.ry nev/spaper,. The speech was preceded by reading the
Declcn.ratlon of Independenceo In tho flowing rhetoric of thiR period,
this panegyric 13 illustrated from this excerpt;
"Our Revolutionary Fathern arc nearly all in a peaceful
grave. Those illustrious men, \/ho bequeathed to us the noble
inheritance that we now en joy 5 have nearly all gone to try
the realities of another worldj to reap the glorious fruits
of a well spent life allotted to the noble and worthy ....
others froa their age it is plain, that a few revolving suns
will carry them to another and better v/orld&#8212;and when it shall
please the GREAT SPIRIT so to do may they be able to report
in Keaven that all is well... They see before them no halycon
yearSp no sweet moments of repose. The bird of Jove v/as
about to grapple v/ith the Lord of the Ocean, the invincible
lion of Britian,"
Unfortuxiately, the Rutherford County court records of the 1835-4.5
era were destroyed, but there is evidence in the Register's records of
ample practice by Yoakum. These indirect references reveal speculation
in real estate, the administration of estates, and mortgage work.
In the I84.O census records, Henderson and his wife are listed as
thirty years of age, having five daughters under 15 years of age and one
female slave. The slave was apparently obtained from one William Bryant,
who had pledged "Killy" as collateral on a $300 note Henderson and an
associate held that was unpaid.
The Toakum residence, according to Dr. Pittard's finding, was located on
about the 1977 site of the Tennessee Employment Security Office on the cor-ner
of Vino and South Spriat^ streota in Mur.frefc&amp;boro.
51
In 1837 Yoalcura was elected the loayor of ^furf^eosbo^o and sexn^ed for
oix years e A Democrat, Yoakum's political activity uas not confined to
local interest. He xras tho friend and loyal supporter of Andrew Jackson,
Martin Van Buren, James K. Polk and Sam Houston. James K. Polk announced
he would run for Governor at a party given in hie honor in Kurfreesboro in
1838. President Martin Van Euren was a visitor in ^iu^freecbo^o in 184.1.
During the bitter 1839 struggle between the Whigs and Democrats, Yoakum
vas elected to the Tennessee Senate. Among the bills he introduced was
one to abolish the office of superintendent of public instruction. He
wag successful in his opposition to the State Aid Act for i.nternal im-provements.
As co-sponsor with James C. (Lean Jiismy) Jones from the
House of Representatives, he recommended the use of convict labor for the
"lunatic asylum". This predates by more than 135 years a "pre-release
for labor" plan for use of convict labor in Tennessee today.
He cajivassed the state on behalf of candidates for national office
and debated John Bsll as a champion of Fartin Van Buren. He accused the
Vlhig candidate, General V/illiam Henry Harrison, of "selling white men into
slavery"
.
In 184.2, when the General Assembly was in special session for the
purpose of redistricting the state, Yoakum appealed to James K. Polk,
requesting that, "Rutherford Co\inty not be sacrificed to political ex-pediency".
Polk took the steps necessary to insure the success of Yoakum's
plea.
Yoakum was a staunch foe of alcohol, recording in his diai-y shortly
after moving to Texas that "liquor and profanity are at present the dis-tinguishing
faults of the great men of Texas." How he reconciled this
philosphy as a member of the Sons of Temperance with the hard drinking of
his close friend, Sam Houston, is one of the perplexities of this military
man, politician and religionist. ,
52
There are a few scattered references to Yoakum in nicrofiltn copies of
Rutherford County newspapers.
He frequently purchased land at sheriff's sales, and he is listed as
a surety on a 3^100 note for Allan Jarnegan.
In 1840 he was an attorney for the reclamation of a slave. In the
same year he was named as an elector from the eighth district (Rutherford
County) for the l^rtin Van Buren-Richard Johnson presidential ticket.
He was given the power of attoi-ney by W. Mo Earthman for the V/illiam
V/ebber estate to provide for Earthman 's mother He handled a deed of
truc^ relating to slaves for Francis S. Manning and a similar duty for
Thomas Yardly,
A conveyance of six acres of land purchased from John Fletcher for
$35.30 is recorded.
One evidence of closing his affairs in Murfreesboro in October,
184.5 is the sale of lot number 69 in Murfreesboro (possibly his residence)
at Church and Vine Street to James B. Blockington for $1,500.
Henry King Yoakum never lost his feel for the military. The "Alamo
fever" struck Murfreesboro in 1835 with reports of Davy Crockett's
death. When volunteers were called to support the war for Texas inde-pendence,
sixty-four men were enrolled in the Murfreesboro Sentinels, a
cavalry unit, with Yoakiun serving as captain. After less than a month,
when it appeared Texas v/ould be successful, the Sentinels were mustered
out. However, on June 29, 1836, Yoakum enlisted for six months service
under Gen. Edmund P. Gaines and served on the Sabine frontier. Returning
to Murfreesboro, ho was elected mayor, a kind of hero's award.
In 1838 the Cherokees were removed from East Tennessee and Georgia.
When the Cherokees refused to move west from the Hiwassee Purchase, a call
53
for 2,500 volxintcors wag made. On Miy 13, 1838 Yoakun enllotcd in the
First Regiment, Tennessee Infantry. Thirteen days later he was named
resinental colonel. In that capacity, he led the rej-jinent into the heart
of the Cherokee coimtry and ever after bore the title, "Colonel Yoakum".
He inia mustered out July 12, 1838,
IJhat in Murfrcesboro ^.-as contemporary vriLth Henderson Yoakum, less
than a decade after it had been the capital of Tennessee?
It trcis a ccTntnimity of about 1,000 population with established
Baptist, Presbyterian and Methodist churches. Yoakum was a trustee in
the Methodist Chvirch, established in 1836. Bradley Academy was well
established and Union University was founded in 184.1 . William Ledbetter
v;as clerk and caster, l/illiam Lillard, sheriff and Charles Ready, post-caster.
The Murfreesboro Female Academy v/as just opening. A slave
market vras on the north side of the courthouse yard. There were et
least three hotels&#8212;Washington on the east side of the square, Lytles on
the south,, and Allcan's en the west.
.Edwin Keeble was editor and publisher of the Central Monitor, a
weekly newspaper. That editor Keeblo Eatutalncd the legend of Fovurth
Estate conviviality is suggested by a bulletin in one edition of the
Monitor that read:
"The gentleman who unceremoniously took E. G. Keeble' s um-brella
from Colonel Smith's tavern on the 5th inst., is par-ticularly
requested to call and pet his cloak also".
Yoakum cade a hurried trip to Texas in Juno, 18/+5 and wrote his friend,
Martin Van Buren, "To ask how I like Texas is to ask how I liko the United
States&#8212;for variety of soil, climate, etc., it is equally as prcat".
54
Having decided, on Huntsvllle, Texas as his future home, Yoakum spent
the period from June to October 1845 in closing out his business interests,
selling his residence for 0l,5OO, and einbarkinp on the journey that was to
bring him fame and fortune in the Lone Star State. Accompanying him were
his wife, Eveline Cannon Yoakum, daughters Eliza, Kartha, I-lary, Anne, and
Emily. In Texas four other children were born to the Yoakxim's&#8212;Houston,
vho married Fannie Dailey; Robert who never married; George, who died
while in service with the 5th Texas regiment C.S.A. in Virginia; and
Henderson, who died at the age of ten. Mrs. Yoakum lived until 1867.
In his diary Yoakum records the stage coach trip to N^w Orleans and
then the steamboat journey to Huntsville. On his arrival he wrote:
"Yesterday ve went house hunting&#8212;the house is old, open,
leaky and smoky. In addition to all this, there has been a
severe, "northern" winter. Yet we have some sweet potatoes
and coffee, upon which we must nake otirselves as comfortable
as we can."
Eight years later he recalled the circumstances of the early winter
arrival in Texas with the statement, "When I arrived here eight years
ago, I had but a single dollar, and neither house nor land where-with-all
to feed and clothe my family; and besides a constitution broken down in
political warfare". In the letter to a friend, Thomas J. Rusl&lt;i he said,
"I threw down the glove against 'Vhite Whiggery. I followed politics as
a profession and practiced it with the zeal of a lover . . . until I had
spent all I had made and my children cried for bread when I had it not to
give them".
On December 2, 1845 he obtained a license to pratice law in Texas and
qxilckly established himself as a successful lawyer. He became the personal
ccmr^alor for Cm nciir^tcrio lie ectinnollccl \rlth Ilounton on c.ll tjrpon of
;;'crcona.l ani poUtical prcblci-a . Jl?. dcfcrrlc;! Itrao Houcton on en arsault
end battery trial end c^-lncd a nictrialo
Hg appoarcd cnce attain in uniform, carving fro:a May l6 xrntil October 2,
1?&lt;,6 as a lioutcnant in the 1st Recincnt, Tc3:as Movmted Rifles, partici-pating
vd.th distinotion in tho tattle of Monterey. He v/as mustered out a
colonel in the Texas ydlitia, a rank he retained xmtil his death.
An inventory of his estate in 1556-57, a decade after he cane im-poverished
to Huntsville, -evcaled the cuccess of his lai; practice and
land speculation. In addition to his residence in Huntsville, he ovmed
3,720 acres of land in Walker Coxmty, 1,065 acres in Polk County, 1,085
acres in Houston and Cherokee Coxmtics, 17 slaves, and other personal
property valued at 02,901,23.
Certainly tb^s \ra3 a remarkable achievement for the former nayor of
Murfreesboro vho had left Tennessee, "broken in health and fortvtne, the
victim of VJhite '.-fhiggery".
He aided in establishing the Andrew Fenale' Academy in Huntsville and
idth Sam Houston served as a member of the official board until the time
of his death. He served on tho Board of Aldermen in Huntsville, and in
1849 was appointed Attorney General by the Governor of Texas. He also
served as an active trustee of Austin College and became the High Priest
of the Texas Masonic Lodge.
Perhaps his most lasting fame came in the writing of a two-volume
History of Texas , From the First Settlement in l6S5 to its Annexation to
the United States in I84.6 . Dr. Pittard states that "it is a mystery how
Yoalcu^i found tir.e to compile this work, which the historian, Hubert H.
Dancroft, described as 'cno of the best, if not tho best history of Texnc'."
56
In November, 1856 Colonel Yoakum accepted an invitation to deliver
a Masonic address in Houston. While there he was stricken with a "tuber-cular
attack" in the home of Judge and lira. P. \1. Gray. On November 29,
at the age of 4.6, he died. The body was carried to Huntsville and in-terred
in Oakwood Cemetery. The moniiment in Oakwood Cemetery reads: "In
memory of the high appreciation of his character as a man, his usefulness
as a citizen, his ability as a lavorer, his fellow citizens have erected
this m-.-nument to Col. Henderson King Yoakum.
loakum County, Texas, of which Plain is the county seat, located
against the New Mexico border was named in honor of Henderson King Yoakum.
When San Houston was dying at his "Steamboat House" in Houston,
Texas, July 1863, he requested that he be buried beside his friend,
Col. Henderson King Yoakum.
Col. Henderson King Yoakum, transplanted Tennessean who became a
close friend and legal advisor for Sam rlouston.
Graveside marker for Col. Henderson King Yoakmri in Oakwood Cemetery,
Kiontsville, Texas. 3an Houston is buried nearby.
58
BIBLIOGRAPPfr
Rhea and McMlnn Coiinty Covirthousc records
U.S. Military Acndeniy records of rGCorninendation and George Yoakuin'vS
letter of assent for his son to sign the articles of obligation
for cervice, April 22, 1823
Letter from Eveline Yoakua to her nother, Murfreesboro, Tennessee,
April 3, 1333, now in the University of Texas, Austin
Sims, Hi story of Ruthe .-ford Coimty , pp.- SS-89
Austin (T3xas) College catalog, 1855-56, pp. 71-73
HandbooV of Texas . Vol. II, p. 945
The Texas banner , (Huntsville, Texas) October 6, 184-9
The Texas Bar Journal, September 22, 1970, an article by Bov;en C. Tatura Jr.,
' "A Texas Patriot", pp. 219-22^
Oakv/ood Cemetery Records, Huntsville, Texas
Houston Daily Post , October 26, 1908, q letter written by his son
Dallas Morning News, August 21, 1932, a featiire story v;ritten by
Evelyn M. Carrington, "Yoakum, Fiery Historian of Shepherd 'rj
Valley", p. 3 et, seq.
Book C, Probate Minutes of Walker County, Texas, p. 24.7, covering will
eind Inventory of Henderson King Yoakum's property.
Letter from Robert J. Suddar^h, Circuit Court Clerk of Rutherford CciLnty,
Tennessee January 15, 1969, concerning legal practice in Tennessee,
records were destroyed by Union operations against the Conf edez-acy,
1861-65</dc:description>
<dc:description>Describes the political and military contributions of Henderson King Yoakum, 1810 - 1856, in his careers in both Murfreesboro and in Texas</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Houston, Sam, 1793-1863; Rutherford County (Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>The Indian Wars; Mexican-American War; Tennessee -- politics; Texas; veterans; Yoakum, Henderson King</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>27 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-16</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication10ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/145</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>