<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Memoirs of Milton</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Craddock, Ladelle</dc:creator>
<dc:contributor>Knox, Elsie</dc:contributor>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 23</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1978</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>19th century; 20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>MEMOIRS of MILTON
1978
Miss Elsie Knox, born 10 January 1893 in the home of
Joe Ivy and Lee James Knox in Wilson County, Tennessee, was
a very gracious personality on the 25th of April, 1978 in
her home in Murfreesboro, Rutherford County, Tennessee.
Four other children were born into this home, namely;
Freece in 1884; Birdie in 1886 (Mrs. Tom A. McKee) ; Charlie
in 1888 and Dana in 1900 (Mrs. T. J. Bumpas^
Miss Elsie was born xn a small community in Wilson
County, Tennessee called Ewingsville. Mr. Knox had built
a house in front of the Ewingsville school, where Miss Elsie
attended her first school. It was this same school in which
Miss Elsie taught other boys and girls in later years. The
only nine months of school ever taught by one teacher in this
school were taught by Miss Elsie. Prior to this, one teacher
taught until Christmas, and then another teacher finished the
term. Miss Elsie left this school and went to Milton for three
years. "I saw I was going to starve" she related, and decided
to go to Draughon's Business College in Nashville to prepare
for a new career. Her brother insisted that she make application
at DuPont, Old Hickory for work. In the meantime, the school
director came to her and asked that she come back to Milton-the
children had run the teacher off. She said "You won't pay
&#8226;me enough to go back." He said, "just name it." Her reply was
$85.00 , (she had never gotten that much) . He said "report to
school Monday morningl She taught there for another four or
five years. Miss Elsie taught several years in Wilson County
at Commerce and Cainsville.
In February 1927 Miss Elsie started a business schdol in
McMinnville in cooperation with Mr. Merchant Pitts and Mr.
Hailey F. Craddock. Classes were open for day and night sessions.
Mr. Pitts left the organization about one year later.
This school was in operation until about 1932-DEPRESSICN
TIME. An opportunity to sell presented itself and Miss Elsie
sold and returned to Murfreesboro, and began collecting for Mr.
Craddock.
In 1940 Miss Elsie returned to McMinnville and opened
another business school which she operated for four and cne-half
years. In 1946 Miss Elsie returned to Murfreesboro and bought
out Lawson's Business College, and operated the Knox Business
School until 30 June 1967. Three years prior to closing, the
school had been sold to Mr. Tom Batey of Batey* s Camera and
Typewriter Company, Murfreesboro, Tennessee, however, it
continued operation under the name of Knox Business School.
During her teaching career in public schools, she
sponsored and presented in the home community and often
carried to Neighboring communities a good play. These were
enjoyed by those who presented them as well as those playing .
Not only that, she also carried bo^s and their girls to ball
games.
Mr. K. T. McCrary, principal at Milton, also a beginner
49
in teaching, asked Miss Elsie "why don't you take that class
and teach Kellogg Grammar? " This she did, and various students
have commented to her of the benefit received.
The Milton school building still stands at the same
location as when it was earlier called "Milton Male and Female
Academy." In bygone days it has been both elementary and high
school. The building has been converted into a dwelling house
and is occupied by the Greene family.
Miss Elsie is a staunch member of the Hopewell Presbyterian
Church U. S., organized in 1816, on the Burns place, now owned
by Mr. Albert Porterfield in a grove of trees in a field. A
cemetery was formed in the area near the church building. In
later years the church building was erected on Milton Scrigre .
It is believed that Joseph Knox, great-great grandfather of Miss
Elsie Knox is buried in this Hopewell Presbyterian Church
Cemetery, related Miss Knox, although no marker is evident.
Benjamin Franklin and Margaret McKnight Knox, great grand-parents
of Miss Elsie are buried at the "Cook"- "McKnight"
cemetery referred to in the Furgason memoirs.
Joseph Knox settled in Wilson County, Tennessee on a cedar
glade, between Ceinsville and Norene off the main road (now)
near the Florida Creek. Cne of our early governors, James K. Polk
a young boy, was one of the group, when his father also settled
here. Mr. Polk did not like the cedar glade territory and
moved to Pulaski then Columbia.
50
According to tradition Joseph Knox had a grant of land
one mile wide which started at Pemberlton House and four miles
long which extended to Knox lane at Ewingsville. This included
all of Milton at this time.
Dr. Riley Vanhook, at one time a practicing physician in
the community of Milton out of Auburn was a first grade student
of Miss Elsie Knox. Dr. Bilbro lived at Milton while practicing
medicine for a while.
During the Civil War, soldiers were buried in the "Beech
Hill" cemetery- the burial ground across the road from the now
Milton cemetery. After the organization of the new cemetery,
the Warrens and Smiths moved their loved ones from the old to
the new burying area.
Miss Elsie assumed the responsibility of caring for the
Milton Cemetery 1 July 1933. To clear the several loads of
briar bushes, debris etc. from the cemetery help was secured
for 50C per day for their labor. The cemetery has been maintained
and Miss Elsie has been instrumental in instigating the Trust
Fund for perpetual care of this cemetery.
Miss Elsie Knox has served these near 45 years without
monetary pay, but the satisfaction derived from this service is
rewarding. A "MILTCN CEMETERY" sign of iron seated in concrete
has already been erected in her memory, by her.
We hereby conclude the memoirs of Miss Elsie Knox
as related to Mrs. Ladelle Craddock.
51
</dc:description>
<dc:description>Ladelle Craddock recounts memoirs told to her by Elsie Knox regarding her lifetime in Milton, Tennessee</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.); Biography</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Family stories</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Milton</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>4 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-01; mt2011-02-08</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication23ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/24</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>