<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>The Civil War letters of Henry Clay Reynolds concerning battles in Middle Tennessee, January - July, 1863</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Reynolds, Henry Clay</dc:creator>
<dc:contributor>Griffith, Lucille</dc:contributor>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 39</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>199?</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869;</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>THE CIVIL WAR LETTERS OF HENRY CLAY REYNOLDS CONCERNING BATTLES
IN MIDDLE TENNESSEE, JANUARY -JULY 1863
H. Clay Reynolds was bom in McMinnville, in 1838, but grew up in Greenville and Selma, Alabama. The
letters printed here were written to his wife, the former Mary Jane Boyd of Selma. After the war he moved his
young family to MontCT'allo, Alabama, where he became a merchant. When his oldest son, William Boyd, gradu-ated
torn Howard College (now Samford University) the firm of H.C. and WB. Reynolds Companywas formed. It
was located on the comer of Main and Shelby Streets in Montevallo.
The Reynolds &amp;milybecame prominent in their city Theyserved their customers as bankers, since MonteN-allo
had no organized bank until 1902. They dealt in real estate, developed a lime business and later owned the
newspaper, the MONTEVALLO NEWS.
It is, however, for his connection with what is now the University of Montevallo, that "Captain" Reynolds is
most vividly remembered. (The title "Captain" is honorary and complimentary since he came out of the Confed-erate
Army as only a lieutenant.) The Alabama Girls Industrial InstittJte was scheduled to open in Oaober 1896,
but shortly before that date. Miss Julia Tutwiler resigned as president. The Board of Tmstees was faced with a
dilemma: their choices were to further delay the opening, which they believed would be disastrous, or choose
another president. After several abortive attempts to employ an educator, the Board tumed in desperation to
Captain Reynolds, who had been the vigorous leader of the campaign to have the school located in Montevallo.
Mr. Reynolds made no pretenses at being an educator but in addition to being a public-minded citizen, he
was a fiiend ofGovemor Wdliam C. Gates, a war comrade. The governor appointed him president on August 24
and a few weeks later, on September 18, the Board oflBdally elected him. Let ft be said to his eternal credit, he
moved with such speed that by October 12, 1896 (which is now observed each year as Founder's Day) he had
hired a fciculty recruited a student body of one hundred forty-five girls (which nearly doubled before the school
year was out), had the old "College" building reftirbished for use as a school, and had arranged for local residents
to board students until a dormitory could be built. It was a herculean task and he deserved the praise given him
when the dignitaries of county and state assembled to see the new institution launched.
Mr. Reynolds was head of the school until 1899- During these years, the institution had received wide and
favorable publicitywith enrollment growing each year. He was able to get the first Federal grant and had built parts
of main Dormitory Efibrts to have the school moved elsewhere generally had died down so that Montevallo was
accepted as its permanent home.
Mr. Reynolds continued to live in Montevallo imtil 1912 when he moved to Fort Myers, Florida, and later to
Tampa, where he died on Oaober 20, 1920.
In later years the first building on campus once called the "college building" was named Reynolds Hall. It is
a stately white columned structure that stands as a landmark among the other buildings ofred brick. It is a fining
tribute to the man who got the place started.
The letters are printed here as they were written&#8212;^with some misspellings and fi:^quently without dates.
Reynolds would firequently write a while, sign ofi^ then pick up and start again.
Lucille Griflith provided these letters and the infomiation about Reynolds to our society several years ago.
More details in the life ofClay Reynolds maybe found in the hook,ALABAMA COLLEGE (1896-1969), published by
Lucille Griffith ui 1969-
My Dear Wife,
Bmce Thomas came up with the Regiment last Wednesday and, to my great surprise and pleasure, brought
me the only letter I have received since leaving you. I see fixjm this you have written before, but I have been so
unfortunate as to not to receive either ofthe 3 you mention. I am very much pleased to hear that you are at Selma
and that you intend going to Woodville and stay some time. I hope you will get a girl firom Uniontown to nurse
Page 21
Willie as I know you cannot have much pleasures with him to nurse. I was very much surprised to hear ofJim's
coming home. How long has He been at home? And is He discharged or furloughed? And how will He stay at
home? I hope He is in good health. You ought to have written me a longer letter than you did; it ^'as so very short.
Jim Lapsly will come on by the cars shortly Can't you write to me by Him ifHe has not left yet? I -wish ifyou have an
opportunityyou would send be my overcoat by some safe person coming on to the Regiment as I will need it very
much. However, I will write to Pa to dispose of it for me so I wiU get it. We are emcamped five or six miles from
Murfreesboro and in twent&gt;^-fi\'e miles of Nash\'ille, Tennessee, vdiih place is cooupied by the \&amp;nkees. They are
surrounded by Southern forces and will probably be starved out. Our citizens also are in a starving condition as the
Feds will not let them out. The Yankees have treated the people in the country very rough. In some cases tripped
ofeverything and burned their houses cursed the women and used insulting language of every kind to them. But
I hope they will not have an opportunity of doing so any more. We go to assist in the capture of Nash\Tlle, and I
ejqjea will soon have a brush with the enemy WalterJeffries is (I understand) killed. I am sorry to hear of it. I hope
William is recovering from His wound and that it \\'as only a slight one. Give Him by best regards and tell Him I
hope He will not have to fight again at Manassas as He is unfortunate at that place. I wish He could be in our
company CapL Robins speaks very highly of Him and Jim.
Gi\^e your Ma Fannie Uncle D and Aunt Adeline my best respects.
Dear Mary I think ofyou very day and wish to see you and hope soon to do so. We see a great many pretty
girls and have had them to stand by the roadside and sing Dbde and other Southern songs for us as we would pass.
I stopped to talk to a pretty blackeyed lass the other day while I halted in Shelby\ille and she stopped me when the
Regiment was ready to move, ran in the house, and brought me one of the prettiest little flags I ever saw, and with
Her own hands put it in my Horse's bridle in the head stall and bed me God speed with tears in Her eyes. I was
tempted to get down and kiss Her by too many were looking on. I made a lettle speech to Her and galloped off to
my company. WHte soon my dear Mary
Clay
'Shortly after this we men General Wheeler, and I saw him for the first time. He had lately come out of
Kentucky, and I was very much atonished to see what a boyish looking general he was. I soon discovered that his
men had gttat confidence in him, and I learned also that he was a graduate of West Point and well fitted for his
position.
We went then into regular service and soon formed a part of a line of pickets covering our fiDnt for many
miles. In forming this line of pickets, the company to which I belonged, then under the command of Captian
Robbins was sent offon our right to occupy an isolated position, not being in touch with our line at any point, but
to guard a road that led out over what was known as the Chicken Pike or Molaus-ville; and w^e had orders to keep
our horses saddled and to keep a dose watch&#8212;no man to leave camp under any circumstances until we were
relieved. We were told that we were in an extremely dangerous position and that would not do to trust for a
moment the people byw+iom we are surrounded as it was a 'Union nest. ' We remained there four day^ and nights,
and in the meantime w^e had eaten up all the supplies we had; and we lived for a day or two on hickorvnuts and
roast pumpkins, without salt or greese. We soon determined we could stand this no longer; and after holding a
'council,' w^e sent two of our number to inquire ifwe still must remain and if so to get provisions. It seemed that
we had been overlooked, and that it was never intended for us to remain so long. As we returned from this
position, we struck a Yankee Scout; and in the skirmish which followed; we lost several of our best horses, which
left us with numerous dismounted men. Captain Robbins, about this time, w^ sent to the rear, sick. To Laveme,
where w^e had a picket line cropped, the turnpike lead from Nashville, to Murfreesboro. Old Fostenille was a
deserted village; and my company had possession of a good ferm house with quite a number ofstables and bams,
where we were comfortably quartered. In the meantime, our regiment was under the command of Lieutenant
Webb. He, being a very strict disciplinarian, gave orders that no man should leave the camp under any cfrcum-stances,
which fit^quently worked hardship, as we had to forage largel)^ on the country to feed ourselves and
horses. These dismounted men ha\ing lost their horses and the Government not paying for them, were obliged to
go back to the Wagon Train. One ofthem was one of the Company's best soldiers, a very poor man, and he fek his
Page 22
loss and the disgrace ofbeing in the Wagon Train so keenly that he mad every effort possible to secure a mount. At
that time I had been made a Third Lieutenant, and I was in command of the Company An order reached me one
morning which required that I should examine and see ifany ofmy Company had in their possession a very large,
fine black horse with a white star in the forehead, which was the support of the wife and children of a confederate
soldier nowin the VirginiaArmy. I read the orders which were sent to the different Company Commanders, as I sat
before the fire with several ofmy men, and made myendorsement on the order 'No such horse in my camp. ' After
the Orderly had gone out, I noticed that the boys who had heard me read this order had gone out into the hall of
the house and were holding a little consultation which attraaed my attention. I asked what M-as the matter.
Sergeant James Du Bose walked back into the room where I sat and said, 'Lieutenant, that horse is in our Com-pany'
I was astonished, and asked horn who had it. He told me a man by the name ofJones, being one of the four
that had lost their horses, had arrived from the Wagon Camp the night before, and had the horse described. He
pointed out to me where I would see the horse, and I went down and sure enough there vs^ no mistaking the
animal, it being one of the finest horses I had seen in many a day This man was one of the best all-around soldiers
I ever saw, and I was very sorrywhen I realized all that the order had said must be done; but in compoance v.'ith it.
I had Jones to arrest himself together with his horse and all of his baggage to the Colonel's quarters.
I followed and saw young McCraw, ofmy Company who was Acting Adjutant for the Colonel; and I told liim
that I could not afford to lose my man. He and I went together to Colonel Webb to see ifhe could assist us in saving
Jones, as I knew that he was to be sent to Virginia as a punishment. The Colonel stated that he could do nothing
but send Jones to General Martin's quarters, as direaed. I saw that I wanted to save my man. He said, ^es, your
man is out in the quarters under guard and will be sent to Infantry' He advised that when General Martin came in
he would introduce men and that I make my appeal to him, which I did. After a long argument and appeal, Jones
was brought in the meantime. I told the General that ifhe would let me have Jones I would mount him; he asked
me if I had a extra horse. I told him No, that I was riding a borrowed one myself 'How then will you mount liim?'
I said, I said, 'I will tell you in confidence.' I then told him that I was going into the enemys camp for horses, as I had
not only Jones but other men, good soldiers, unable to mount themselves. He smiled and said, 'Under whose
orders are you going into the enemy's camp?' I told him that I didn't think he ought to ask me such a question, but
that if pressed I was going to say that I went under his orders. He laughed and said "Well don't let them catch up
with you then.' So I felt I had a friend, if needed. He turned my man over to me, who was overjoyed and cried like
a child. I was most favorable tovrard General Martin, and I never saw a more gallant soldier than he was. I took liis
baggage on my horse, and together we went back to camp, some six or seven miles distant. The next day I went
out on a picket line and found that the enemy's pickets were about three miles fix)m ours&#8212;the ground between
the two lines being what he called 'debatable ground,; where the scouts of each picket roamed. I went very close
to the enemy's one to see a man named Norcross, that I had met several times while outside of the lines when in
command of the picket on our front. I consulted Norcross about how I might get into the enemy's camp, and I
asked him ifhe would assist me. After thinking awhile, he said, "^fes,' that he could show me a vi-ay by which I could
enter through their lines and so get into their camp. I then told him that then next evening after dark I would be
at his house with a select squad of men, and in the meantime I wanted him to go up and spot the different points
where the pickets stood on the left of the road that passed his house. He informed me that he sold supplies,
vegetables, and clothes to them daily He promised to attend to it, and the more we talked the more eager he
seemed that I should make the attempt and finally insisted that he was going with me and guide us. If it was
necessary he would kill a Yankee or two himseff. I thought nothing of it at the time, supposing it was merely
enthusiam on his part.
The next evening at the appointed time I was at his house with six ofmy best men. Jones was amoung them.
We called him out, and I asked him if he had amy arms. He said no.. I told him that I had brought along a gun for
him, a handy short, double-barrel shotgun with plenty of ammunition for my men and I were armed with two
pistols each. He faltered when I insisted on his taking the gun and said he did not dare take it, that he might be
caught. I said, 'Well, you are going with us?' He then backed down completely; he said he would go a Httle ways
with us, which he did. As soon as he turned back and was out of sight, I called my men up close to me and told
them that somehow I had grown suspicious of Norcross and that I deteaed in his speech and manner something
that made me fear him.
Page 23
I asked who would volunteer to go back and guard our horses and keep a watch on Norcross. Sei^eant
Blankenship volunteered. I told him to go back to the cedar brake in which our horses were hid in a lime sink and
take this double-barrelled gun with him and not to let Norcross see him. He was to go immediately where our
horses were and sit down where he could watch them closely, as I feared that Norcross might make an attempt to
steal them. Then, in place ofgoing to the point that Norcross had sent us in his description ofthe enemy's line, we
side stepped about a half mile to our left. There we found another road which led right in to the enemy's lines,
running parallel with the one Norcross lived on, also another femily living very dose to the enemy's lines. Having
called the man ofthe house out, I explained to him our situation, as he seemed to be an honest Southern man. He
told me that I must be careftil, as the enemyw^as often wandering aroimd his place and might see us, and that he
was aftaid ofmy fiiend Norcross, as he believed he was too intimate with the enemy He was afi:aid that he would
attempt to carry our horses to them and bring out a force on us. This made me very uneasy as this ftiUy confirmed
my suspicions; but I deteimined to go on. This was about ten o'clock at night. I calculated I would return about
twelve.
After getting all the information possible as to the enemy's picket line and their reserve picket, we deter-mined
to follow a string of fence that this man said would carry us right up to their line and see where best to
attempt passing it. Aswewere about to leave the old gentelman, he remarked that he would sit up till we returned,
for he could not sleep; so I su^ested that he should take one of my pistols and go with us. He said Well, he
believed he would; but we must not let any ofhis femily know it. He then told his wife to go to bed as he was going
to walk up to the old place, which was in sight with us. After leaving there, we took a fence rowwhich was fiinged
with a dense thicket of shrubery and crawled along as he direaed, one after another, I in front. When we had
gotten up near the enemy's picket, he tapped me with a little stick he had in his hand; and I discovered that the
relief picket was on its round and right at us. We all lay down as dose to the fence as we could get, and they rode
right by us with only the fence between us. They foiled to see us, however; and while they were relieving the next
picket post, we climbed the fence and ran into the bushes inside their lines. Then we went still deeper into the
bushes wherewe stopped to rest. The old man had grown greatly exdted and insisted that he must go back, saying
that he would be usless in case ofdanger I went back to the line with him, and he crossed it safely; then I returned
to mymen. We soon struck an artillery camp which was so well guarded that we could do nothing with it. We then
turned and went up the line to picket reserve near where we had expeaed to crop at first. To our surprise we
found every horse saddle, seeming to be about 30 in all, the men with arms in their hands and apparently waiting
to start on some expedition. We vratched them av^Me; then we continued into the enemy's camp. After going
about a mile, we came to a ca\'alry command&#8212;seemingly a brigade or more. After watching them awhile and
waiting for it to grow later, I decided to take two men and go inside vWth them while the others remained out to
keep a watch for the enemy. We buttoned up our overcoats, hid our pistols, and walked directly into the camp,
passing along between the fires just as though we were at home. We found the men cooking, eating, playing
games of cards, and a little suspecting who we were as quietly walked through camp.
Out near the edge I found a camp where all were asleep; I picked out the best horse they had and quietly
unfastened him and walked oft"with him. I had gone by a short distance v^+ien I v^'aJked upon one horse tied by
himselfwith a good bridle and saddled hanging by him. I immediately saddled and got on him. I then quietly rode
back, leading the other horse, to where my men were. After waiting awhile, my companions came out with their
horses; so then it was the turn ofthe other two men to go in. We explained the situation to them, and they walked
in a diflerent place to the one we had gone in. They had been gone sometime, and the other men and I were
beginning to grow very uneasy When all at once I discovered there was quite a commotion in the camp. I said to
my man, 'Clark's raising a row' Clark was notorious for being one of the most fearless desperate men I ever saw,
always wanting to fight, and never seemingly knowing v^+iat fear w^as. Sure enough I saw Clark coming with three
or four Men after him hollowing, 'Halt,halt!' We mounted our horses and waited for him. He ran up to us, and I
reached down and took him up behind me and we got aw^y still lea^'ing one man in the camp. After going some
distance and seeing that we were not pursed any further, we got down and waited awhile, hoping our other man
might come to us. About an hour later after that we heard a horse come walking through the woods; I stepped out
in the direction of the noise and w+io should it be but my other man with a fine horse. As soon as he got up to us
he commenced to laugh at Clark. He said "VXTiat did you want to interfere with those damned Yankees for?' Clark
Page 24
had secured a fine horse, took him out, and tied him in a convenient place as he thought, and then went back and
attempted to rob the Captain. He soon got into hot water, knocking the Captain down with his pistol; and the rest
tried to catch him, thinking all the time it was one oftheir own men. So he had to lose his horse and get out as best
he could. We then started out, thinking to go out at the same point that we had come in, keeping in the woods all
along; but when we reached that point, we saw that it was utterly impossible to escape on horseback, owing to the
fact that a network ofstone fences lay in the ^'aIleybelowus. We then determined to move up to the road and make
a dash on the picket post, capture it, and tried to make our escape. When we got in sight ofthe post, we drew our
pistols; and going fi-om a trot to a gallop and them to a run, we came sweeping down on the two pickets who,
hearing such a noise and seeing such a force coming fi-om inside their own lines, lost their heads, and broke down
the road in front ofus. As soon as we were in shooting distance, we began firing on them. One man dropped and
the other soon halted and surrendered. Sending a horse back, we found that the first man was not hurt; so we
brought to two with us and came on down to the old man's house. He was delighted to see us but very much
alarmed for fear he might be found out and the enemy destroy him and his family He told us that a short time
before a Captain with 20 or 30 men had come to his house immediately back to Norcross'; and told me that he
feared Norcross had betrayed us and our horses. He began begging me not to go back to the place. I told him that
I must to, that I left one ofmybest men there in charge ofour horses; and I must go back and see what had become
ofhim and get our horses, ifpossible. So hiding mytwo prisoners with two men in the woods away from the road,
the othermen and I slipped down to the cedar brake and found our horses and man there all right. But when I got
up to him, I saw that he had a prisoner with his gun levelled on him. I said, "What does this mean?' He said, 'That
is Norcross, and he is a damned traitor!' In response to my inquiries he told me that he had passed close to
Norcross' house as he came back and that Norcross had betrayed us, but he felt that he could do nothing but
follow out the orders I had given; so he went immediately to where the horses were. After an hour or so, Norcross
slipped up to them. He waited till he came up to the one that was next to him, when he halted him and brought
him up to where he was, with his gun levelled on him as he was Norcross was armed, grabbing his gun, when he
had denied to us that he had any arms. He then told Norcross he inteneded to execute him on the spot, but gave
him five minutes in which to say his prayers and make his peace. But in a moment afterwards he heard the tramp
of horses and saw quite a number ofYankees ride up to Norcross' house and call for him. After they stayed there
for sometime, they passed along the road not far from where he was, and that he had gotten up, walked up to
Norcross and put his gun right in his breast, and told him that if he made the slightest noice he would kill him as
he saw Norcross was on the point of screaming. Then they were gone for about an hour and then came back and
finally had left. So he was then afraid to shoot Norcross for fear they might be in the neighborhood and hunt him
up. One ofmymen had a strong line on his saddle, and with that we tied Norcross' hands, put him on a horse, and
leading our other horseswe went back to where our menwere hiding; and while we were ready Norcross jumped
the fence and ran down the lines. I emptied my pistol at him, and he was hit; he made his escape by cutting the
lines. We started to our lines.
Then I sent two ofmymen with one ofthe prisoners to another place, having left our extra horses with a man
near the picket line until we could get out and get them, as we didn't want to let it be known that we had been in
the enemy's camp. Just before daylight we rode in, put up our horses, and quietly retired, having first turned the
two Yankee prisoners over to the provost guard, ridding ourselves of them entfrely My men were very much
surprised when they saw our dismounted men had horses, and it was the wonder of the day where the horses
could have come from. But they were cautioned to keep quiet about it. And so ended the first scout that I made
into the enemy's lines.
Two days afterwards I returned to Norcross' house, sending a force around, hoping to capture him. Whenwe
made a dash to the house, we found it empty everyone gone. I went to my old friend's house that had helped us,
and he explained that the next morning the Yankees had sent out wagons and moved Norcross and all he had
inside thefr lines. He then told me Norcross had been playing spy inside our lines, giving all sorts of information to
the Yankees; and he ^'as himself in great distress of mind, fearing lest Norcross would bring the Yankees out on
him, should he ever suspect him of the effort he had made to assist us.'
Shelbyville, Term.
January 31st. 1863
Page 25
My dear Mary,
I suppose you have comE to the conclusion by this time that I am either a prisoner or no longer living or that
I have entirely forgotten that I had a dear sweet wife and Babe at home. But when I tell you all, you will, I know
excuse me in you kind indulgent heart. In the first place I started fighting the advancing army ofthe \knkees on the
26 ofDecember (our Regiment being placed in Major General Wheeler's Brigade before that time) and since that
time I have gone through more than I had any idea I ever could.
February 1st. I had just ceased writing yesterday and walked out on the portico when I heard yelling and
firing and looking across the fields saw Yankees pursuing our Cavalry who were running like a parcel of cowards
(I have since learned that we lost about 100 of our Csvahry but leaving the Douglas and Wade Regiments in our
Brigade). I ran into the House and waked Newt up in great haste, and we made railroad trip getting away fixim
there and I am now with the wagons where I found a letter ofyours written on the 21st of December, I was very
glad to hear fixam you again although was so long written. I have never opened the package sent byAllen but will
probably I would indeed be proud to wear something spun by my darling sweet wife. I fear that you do not have
everything that you ought and that is what distresses me most. If I only knew that you was fijmished as you ought
to be, I would be better satisfied. Tell Pa to write to me, and tell me how much com he has on hand. And how
much land He intends to cultivate in com. Tell him I w^unt him to come up as I want to send another Mare home
by him and probably two of them. Tell him to ride any old scmb he can pick up and come and inquire for
Wheeler's Brigade. Tell Pa I will look for a letter from him telling me all about our aSairs and I am anxious to know
how our af&amp;irs are at this time. What has become of our cove's? Tell Pa to try and winter them.
So now farewell mywife. Take the best care ofmy Mary and Baby, buy you some dresses if possible. All you
want at any price as they are going to be scarce after a while. Kiss WiUie and tell him I am going to make a soldier
of Him. I am glad ofHim being such a sw^eet child.
Clay
On the 26th we fought and feU back all day and continued on the 27th. About twelve o'clock on the 27th we
got cut oflFfiDm the Regiment and was left entirely surrounded by the enemy six miles torn our lines. We fought
a while and then retreated. I carried out two \knkees I had captured. They fired-upnan us for a fourth of a mile as
we ran through a long lane trying to make a creek Bridge before the enemygot there. But upon nearing the Bridge
we saw the enemy posted in the lane in fi-ont ofus and Lieutenant Seawell, Charlie Lavender, and ten others ofour
best menwhowere in the lead. They having the best horses seeing what v^^as in fix&gt;nt, turned into a field in the left,
and there another body ofInfantry fired upon them, and I saw several of their horses mn oflFwithout riders. We in
the rear seeing what had befallen those in fi-ont, turned into another field-they firing upon us all the time-and ran
to the creek (which was very difficult to cross on account ofhigh steep banks and high v^'aters there being no ford)
all the time under heavy fire of shot and shells and jumping our horses off the banks into the creek swwn over by
a hard stmggle puffed our exhausted horses up the bluffand so about 15 or 16 ofus made our escape after a race
of about 5 &#176; miles, even though the enemy being fired upon at e\'ery turn in the road and at one place for nearly a
mffe under heavy fire. We lost two horses-kiUed-belonging to two young men in the companywho escaped. They
wer^ brothers; and one ofthem had his horse kffled on the Jefferson Pike, and the other took him upon his horse
and as we ran to the creek in the field the horse carrying them both was shot through and they ran to the creek on
foot and I helped them over We then rode away at our being very cold and wet and exhausted. I dismounted my
prisoner (one having done on v^ith the first who crossed) and mounted the boys on his horse and turned him over
to some of our infentry and so I made his horse bridle, saddle, blankets, pistol, and etc. The horse I sv^apped for
the mare I sent you which is one ofthe best animals I ever owned. I stiff have his fine saddle and etc. - in aff worth
$150 to me.
After that daywe fought them every day until the Battle ofMurfreesboro. We were then sent to the rear ofthe
enemy and burned their wagon trains. It was a rare sight to see three or five hundred wagons burning and aU the
mules which had been hitched to them tumed loose with the hamess upon them running in every direction
braying and kicking the Yanks who were scared to death and our men blondering and burning. It was a glorious
time. Three different times we went to the rear of the enemy and bumed eight or nine hundred wagons in aU. I
Page 26
captured the mule I sent home there from one of those wagons.
I have, also, made money enough to buy the mare I am now riding, which is very much like the one I left
home with. After the Battle of Murfreesboro, I was on duty continually until finally we left for the Cumberland
River, where we burned Osun Boats and transported without the loss of a man in the Brigade from \&amp;nkees. But
the swimming ofthe creek and lying out in snow six inches deep and clothes freezing on liS was terrible. I thought
I was able to stand anything, but that rather got me. We finally came to Franklin where we stayed six days tn gocxj
houses, rested and fed our poor horses, and saw the nicest, kindest, and prettiest ladies in Tennessee.
After leaving Franklin, we started in die direction of Shelbyville; and after four days on the trip, we came to
the front of the enemy once more on the Shelbyville and Murifcesboro Turnpike and are at present engaged
picketing. After getting here, I was taken sickwith the billious attack and have been sick at the house ofa very clever
family by the name ofCooper but now I am all OK once more and would return to the Company immediately but
that S.N. McCrawwho came out with me sick with chills is lying on a pallet by myside with a fever and I can't leave
him until he can go.
"We remained in fi-ont ofNashville for some time. We were doing picket duty When the enemy advanced on
Nashville to fight us at Stone River, our company was under the command of lieutenant Sewell. He was ordered
to take the company and go on a scouting expedition across Stone River, reporting what the enemywas doing. We
started early in the morning; and by noon we had crossed the Stewart's Creek and was dose to what was called the
"Chicken Pike;" wiiich intersects the Mmfeesboro and Nashville P^e. Hearing a great roaring noise, we stopped
to listen and concluded to send out pickets on all sides and try to discover the enemy At the request of the
lieutenant, I made the detail. Among them I detailed one man, Dr Hewell, to go by himself out on Chicken Pike.
The men that we sent toward the Nashville turnpike soon returned, informing us that the noise we heard was the
roar of the Federal Army as they marched fix)m Nashville toward Murfi^esboro; and it looked like there was going
to be a battle. The balance ofour pickets soon came in-all bringing the same report that the enemywas in motion
in every direction. That is, all came except Dr. Hewell, who had not returned. I persuaded the Ueutenant to hold
the company until I could call in Dr Hewell. I rode rapidly down the Chicken Pike, hoping to overtake Hewell,
when all at once a sudden turn ofthe road brought me right up fronting Hewell with a Federal soldier on each side
of him. I immediately drew both pistols that I had in my holsters, whereupon they surrendered. I made Hewell
take their guns. I found that Hewell had ridden into their lines very unexpectedly and was captured and was being
sent to the person in charge ofthese men. I sawwe were almost hemmed in and tried to persuade the lieutenant
to try a difierent route to the one we had come in on, but he could not change the dfrection.
We started to return in a walk, which was increased to a trot, and then to a gallop and in thirty minutes time
we had reached the neighborhood ofStewart's Creek. I was in the rear ofthe company trying to keep the men up
with these two prisoners-one on each side of me-having told them that either of them should separate from me,
I should certainly kill them. I was carrying my lai^e pistol threateningly in my hand. When we had gotten within a
few hundred yards ofthe creek, wewere running through a lane having been fired upon fixDm both sides by a great
many Federal soldiers.
They believed us to be the advance guard of a large force, so we attacked them in the rear. All at once a line
of soldiers, who were lying down, rose and fiured upon us. I could distinctly hear the order to fire by thefr com-manding
officer. This volley killed, crippled, and dismounted nineteen ofour men before we could get out ofthefr
reach, as the lane was narrow and the men and horses were strung out in it. When we reached the creek, we found
that we were on a bluif at least ten feet above the water; but there was nothing we could do except to plunge into
the water, every man and his horse going entfrely out ofsight under the water I made myprisoners jump ofl^ swim
to the other side, and pull out some of the men who were in danger of being drowned. Some of the men, not
knowing how to swim, would involuntarily pull the heads of thefr horses under the vrater After we had crossed
the creek, there was nothing more to hinder us fix)m going on to our command."
Front Picket Lines
12 miles from Murifeesboro
and 10 miles from Shelbyville
Page 27
April 16, 1863
My Darling Wife,
It is only a few days since I wrote you, but nevertheless I concluded to write you once again before waiting for
an answer, though to tell the truth I am almost discouraged from writing any more. Only one letter ofyours has
reached me since I saw Pa, which now seems like a longwhile. In it you mentioned Pa's safe arrival home. I am glad
to hear ofit, as I feared he would have a spell ofhis old sickness before he got home. We are still at our same camps
where we arrived on the 28th ofJanuary It seems almost like home we have been here so long. But when I look
around and think ofmy sweet wife and Babe at home, it seems like anything else. I have been cjuite homesick for
the past two or three weeks. We have so little to do, and it is so very tiresome here in camps that I get out of all
patience doing nothing. But from all accounts, we won't have an opportunity oflying still much longer as the news
now is that the Army Rosencrans is preparing to make a move. And I hope it is true, as he must move. And if his
army does move against ours, I fear there will be a most desperate battle as they are very strong and our army is in
a most excellent position. So dearest, pray for the safety of your unworthy husband, as I have not the slightest
doubts, but that I will be in the engagement in some way and hope to bear a worthy part in the struggle for our
liberty
I am in command ofthe Company now and have been for several days, as the Captan has erysipelas and has
gone to Camp. I can scarcely write for four of the boys who are sitting in the other comer playing a game ofeucre
and singing, "When I can wipe myweeping eyes" in a loud tone. I have just been notified that I am Officer of the
Picket tomorrow I am not sorry to go, as it changes my duties somewhat. I like almost any change now.
I would give $50 to start to Kentucky tomorrow morning, .... I have now come to the conclusion that there
is no end to the war, and I do fearwe have a most desolate prospect before us. I sometimes feel as though I would
give halfofmy life for the war to stop immediately. I so much want to see you all. I sometimes sit and think how my
darling sweet wife and baby look and at such times I go to thinking to m^'selfhow can I get off and go to see my
darlings. Many are the plans I devise but all fail upon second thought. Quite a number of the officers have got off
for 30 or 60 days on different pleas and are now returning to the Regiment. One of the (Lieutenant Castleberry)
returned yesterday having been home on account of his wife's illness. She has been quite sick. You recollect I
wrote about our boys (13 in number) being taken prisoners on the 27th ofDecember last. Three ofthem got back
a few days ^o and give a sad account of the balance. One ofthem was shot on the spot. Three died from exposure
and bad treatment. One managed to get out ofprison and that is the last ever heard of him. The balance of them
were left behind (Charley Lavender among the number) sick. Charley was at Chicago and was expeaed to follow
on the next day. I received and answered a letter from SaUie a few days ago. I wrote her a long letter, as she wanted
me to give her a history ofmy adventures as it seems you had been telling her some big tales about me.
Dearly beloved, write often, I don't think you neglea writing, but the other Boys get letters. Berry Harrison
(my bed mate) gets from two to three every week &amp;x3m his wife at Summerfield. Somehow I have got the blues
today my dear, so must excuse my uninteresting letter A letter from you would give my great relief You have no
idea how much it would help me. And now farewell, my dear wife.
Your Husband,
H. Clay Reynolds
Direct your letters to me, Martin's Brigade, Shelbyville, Tennessee, as I wrote you before. Write often darling.
Newt will take his place as 3rd Lieutenant in a few daN'S, I think. Our Regiment v^'as pronounced first in the Brigade
on inspection a few days ago. Our new Brigade General was much pleased with it. Our Company horses were
pronounced the finest in it and our men the best clothed and equipped.
H.C.R.
"From the time of the battle at Murfreesboro, our movements were so rapid that I did very little scouting. We
were on the retreat with every effort being made to get across the Tennessee River with our supplies. Wheeler's
cavalry, being continually engaged in skirmishes wth the enemy, often lost heavily at the same time, causing great
lost to the enemy
Page 28
An amusing incident occurred while we were encamped at Luveme. The regiment had decided that we
ought to have a chaplain and Rev. D.C.B. Connerly was elected. He, in connection with our quartermaster and
assistant and one or two other ofiBcials including Jas. W Lapsley, and selected a nice place on the pike in the
direction ofMurfireesboro, a mile or so in the rear ofour headquarters. There they had put up two nice wall tents
and enclosed a yard with a light fence making a very homelike, attractive looking place. There they rested at night
with a feeling ofsecurity, knowing that they had the command between them and the enemy But one morning as
day was breaking, they were aroused from their slumbers by the rasping voice of a big Federal soldier who wth
some oaths commanded them to 'come out ofthem tents. ' The whole ofour regiment had the highest respea for
our gifted chaplain, fully belie^^ng that if occasion offered, he would acquit himself finely in the presence of the
ENEMY These gentlemen who were in the tents were not aware of the fact that the enemy had broken through
our lines and captured part of the regiment below us on the picket line, and that they had scattered in various
directions capturing all the small bodies of our troops that they could find, until they heard this raucous voice
ordering them out. The parson hearing so much profanity and never dreaming that it could come from any except
our own men, picked up awash pan in the tent, intending to get some water at the same time rebuke the drunken
wretch who was guilty of such profanity He marched boldly up to where this oflScer and his men sat on their
horses and delivered a forcible reprimand telling them what great punishment he would have visited upon them
for the insulting language they had used in his presence. About that time the parson concluded to take a survey of
their countenances; and holding up his wash pan to shield his eyes from the sun, making I suppose a suspicious
movement to the enemy when the man of raucous voice brought up his gun and a shot a hole through the pan.
This brought to the front the balance of the officers kom the tent who rushed out to the side of the chaplain
causing the enemy to level thefr guns on the whole crowd. It dawned upon their minds then the simation they
were in. fri the meantime whey had informed the chaplain that these were Yankees and that he had better make
the best terms with them that he could. So the chaplain apologized to them for his rudeness and begged that they
be allowed to go into their tents and dress, being in their night clothes, which was granted them. About this time
the nose ofthe gun the man had fired reached our camp. So quite a number of us who had heard of the disaster
of the breaking of our lines mounted our horses, running them at full speed down the pike to this camp. Then
they pursued the now fleeing enemy, capturing everyone of them. The description of this afiair, given by our
chaplain and the dialogue that occurred when we had brought the cursing man back, was a source of amusement
for many long months there after And when they parted, the man ofprofenity begged the parson to pray for him,
which he agreed to do provided he'd quit cursing. The next Sunday our chaplain preached a sermon on profenity
that brought many a snrule and wink as the whole regiment had heard of the fun. The chaplain was not long in
removing his tent down nearer to headquarters."
Old Fosterville
12 miles from Murfreesboro, Term.
May 10th, 1863
My own sweet Mary
I am indeed happy to state that both of your letters of the 30th and May 1st came safely to hand one day
before yesterday and the other today I see that they were mailed at Wilsonville and via Selma. So once more I can
have the exquisite pleasure ofcorresponding to one who is dearest to me than all the world contains. Oh! darling
wife, you cannot imagine the joy I experience when the Post Master hands me a letter and especiallywhen I catch
a glimpse of a certain small handwriting that I have long ago learned that I am delighted to know so well! Yes,
indeed, well do I remember the 30th two years ago-everything is indeliblywritten on mymind. I even recoUea the
least particulars, how much my darling ^'as excited before as well as after the ceremony was performed, which
made me the proteaor of one of Heavens noblest best gifts to man. Oh! Happy indeed have been the hours we
have spent together since that night. I never before knew what happiness was. Since the day I could clasp your
lovely form in my arms, the greatest clouds that have appeared on the horizon of my love is our happiness to
separate from each other for so long. It is indeed a hard fate, but hope that never ftiiling star becomes me on to the
future and I look forward to another day with oh, so much eagerness.
Page 29
But mylove I am heart sick today. There has occurred an incident today that makes me feel so badly It is this:
On Dress Parade day before yesterday eve, I was named as one of the officers of the picket for the next day or 24
hours, commencing on Saturday morning at eight and ending this morning at eight. Immediately after parade two
young men, one named D. Hill, son of Colonel Hill of Cahawba, and the other named Joe King from near
Hamburg, came running up to me and asked me to put them on the scouting party daily sent out from the picket
reserve in the direction of the Yankees. I readily consented as they were both noble soldiers and accordingly
yesterday I called them out to go on the scout. On the day before the scouts went up to the Yankee pickets on the
Yankee line and shook hands with them, they gave our men coffee and newspapers. So the scouts I sent out
concluded they must also have a chat with the Yankees as they had professed such a sincere desire the day before
for a cessation of picket shooting. So the boys went up the pike (they met with no difficulty yesterday and did not
see the Yanks) and just about sunrise (this morning) they reached the hill looking over at the picket on another hill
about a half of a mile distant. Presently, an officer of the Yanks appeared in thefr rear with a number of men, and
immediately a large number ofYanks sprang up on all sides from behind rocks, trees, fences, and etc. completely
hemming them in. The officer in thefr rear called out for them to halt. They were in the act of surrendering when
the officer called to his men, "Don't fire;" but they fired three guns and shot King through the body Hill and the
man who had accompanied them (Dunlap) were taken uninjured. King was carried into the house at hand and
permission given for notice to be sent to our lines so we might bring a surgeon. The note came by a negro; and I
immediately sent for Frands M. C, our regiment surgeon after waiting with great impatience for two hours he
came. He and two of our men went forward with a flag of truce. But we had waited so long that the Yankee
ambulance had come out and taken him away I went up to the Yankee pickets and questioned them about King
and Hill. They did not think King's wound was a mortal one, but the people at whose house he was did. So just as
I was recruiting the Company, I lost two ofmy noblest men; and it disheanens me.
Tell Ma she had better be shy of Mr. Bums if she goes to BumsNiUe, as I have refrised to make John B. a
Lieutenant in Company I. Although he brought me a paper v&gt;ixh the name of every member of the Company
(present) signed to it. The men now think I did right, though at first they did not. I happened to know the man too
well to want him as an associate. The Colonel and McGraw, Lapsley and all wtio know him, say I did just right.
When I refiosed to sign it, some of the men did not think I was showing proper respect for my men; so I drew up
a paper and told them they could get my resignation by signing it, but not one would do it. So bums had to leave
without getting the position. 1 forgot to mention that five or six days previous to that time he (Bums) had been
detailed in the Commissary department at Tullahoma. Now, the men all say I acted right and are rejoiced that all
occurred as it did so far as my refiising to approve his appointment. Captain Robbins came up on yesterday from
Camp and will probably remain until his papers are heard irom. I do like C. H. Lavender, and he pretends to think
a great deal ofme. He will come on soon, and I uill be glad to receive anything you may have to send to me by him.
I am needing some clothing now. I thought I would not send home for anything but find that I now need things
I cannot get. However, I will write Pa about buying for me. And you know I will be proud ofanything you may have
to send me. More especially ifmade by your dear hands. You spoke ofsome shirts you v^'ere making for me. Make
them as neat in the bosoms as you can, as you rememberwe have not vests to wear; and it would be best probably
to put (ifyou can get them conveniently) some fance buttons and any other fancywork on them that you can. I am
about writing to Pa concerning a uniform. I want a nice but not gaudy one, and a nice pafr of boots. I expect all 1
want will cost near $200, but have something neat I must. I did have the misfortune to lose the mare I had when
Pa was up here. She cost me $300. But such things will sometimes happen. I did not mention it because I hoped
you would not hear ofit, and I would try to work along and not have you grieved in any v^^ as I knewyou would
be. I have one now that cost me $350 and I have been offered $450. And as soon as I can get off will go to
Shelbyville and get $500. As I will not have so much invested in a horse. Tell Pa I made $75 on the large sorrel
horse. I had and used him over a month after my mare died. I want to get two neck ties when my clothes are sent,
and I also want to have a small trunk or large valise to keep them in as if I do not have something with a lock to it
I can keep nothing. I also want the initials ofmy name worked on all my underclothes, towels, handkerchiefe, and
etc., as they steal and mix up clothing so badh^
May 1 1th. Since writing the above I have come to the conclusion not to go to too much expense for a
uniform, as I find I can alway'S get tolerably kus clothing from the Qr Master I bought a nice pafr of pants on
Page 30
yesterday (that is common goods). I am expecting Lieutenant Sewell back soon, as I learn they are exchanging
officers. Newt McCraw is Acting Adjutant of the Regiment and will probably be appointed Adjutant. James Lapsley
has been appointed 1st Lieutenant in Company E. Don't the Selma Boys go in for oflScers. We have just heard that
General Stonewall Jackson is dead. What a blow to us. I hope you have heard from WiUiam since the Battle and
that he is safe. I never received the letter you sent mewritten byWilliam. I am sorry I did not. I have written him two
or three letters but received no answer When you write, tell him I wrote him in regards to his being transferred to
our Company But it is a very difficult thing to get a transfer. Now that you have an office that you can send letters
to and know that they will come s;ifely I hope you will write often my darling, for nothing gives me more pleasure
than to get a letter from you. I will have some money in a day or two and am going to send you some. How does
your mare do? Have you ever ridden or driven her, and do you think she is "enceinte." I hope to raise a fine colt
from her. And nowdearest I must come to a dose, as I have had no pay today and it is nownearly 9 o'clock. I rode
out to get supper last night and had to pay $ 1 for some combread and milk and butter Provisions are growing very
scarce and a dollar is customary price for a meal, so I cannot afford to eat many And nowferewell mydarling Mary
Write soon and may Heavens blessings rest on your dear sweet head, is the prayer ofyour husband.
H.C.R.
Captain Robbins afready begins to regret his resignation-not that his health is improving so much. He ^ill be
glad wtien you get some new flour in, and I hope then you will all have plenty to eat. How much wheat does Pa
think he will make? Is Pa making moneyby buying cotton? Give my love to your ma. I do hope she m^y marry Lyles
.
He is a nice man. TeU her I say take him by all means if she can get him. Tell Bethie I often think of her and would
speak of her often in my letters, but suppose you would read her any news I may write. Tell her to write to me.
What is Mack doing? How much salt has Pa on hand, and how is Mrs. Hargrove? Nowdarling, I have written a long
and tiresome letter for you to read. Please write me long and often and try and answer some of the foolish
questions I have asked you.
Yours,
Clay
I would give so much to see Willie. I tell all the men and women, especiallywhen I go to a home any number
of times and get acquainted, about my sweet wife and baby I am proud of them.
H.C.R.
'After the battle of Shelbyville, wiiere we lost heavily we fell back to Elk River. There we had a severe ca\^alry
fight and our Lieutenant Colonel Webb was killed. We were on horseback, and I was within ten feet of him and
heard the ball strike him and saw him reel in his saddle. I quickly dismounted and with others rushed to him. We
carried him into a nearby church building where we had to leave him as a prisoner and mortally wounded."
Trenton, Georgia
July 10th, 1863
My Dear Sweet Mary,
We reached this place two and halfday's ago and are nowresting after our long hard march and fighting from
Shelbyville to Tennessee River Our Regiment \^'as engaged at Shelbyville with the rest of the Brigade and met a
most disastrous defeat for want of diy ammunition and guns, we having been on a march for six days marching
night and day in the rain. The Generals knew the condition of arms; still, they put us out to meet the enemywho
were fast advancing and soon charged and drove us back. Our Regiment stood its ground till every other left it and
consequently lost heavily Over a hundred, out of 300 carried in, were left killed, wounded, or captured. Newt
Page 31
McCraw, I am sorry to say -was severely wounded in the thigh-it being shattered near the body He will, in all
probability die. (Our) Major Dye was among the missing, also. Newt is in the hands of the enemy Poor fellow, I am
so sorry about him. Our next fight was at Elk River near a white church. We had a hot fight but did not lose so
heavily as we had good ammunition and repulsed them. But we lost our Colonel there. He had only been
promoted a few days by Colonel Morgan's being appointed a Brigadier General. Colonel Webb was shot within
ten yards ofwhere I sat on mymare-the balls flying thick all around. I saw he was mortallywounded, or I thought
so. He was shot in the bowels and was left in the hands ofthe enemy. So w^e are without a Field Officer We lost two
Captains and a number of Lieutenants. Upon reaching the Tennessee River, we found the railroad bridge planked
over; and we crossed it about 12 o'clock at night on 4thJuly I thought ofyou while I sat there on that little narrow
bridge, 50 yards high fi-om water (as we were fully an hour crossing some planks being displaced on this end). I
thought ofyou lying asleep, and I hoped dreaming ofme and ^vould have given the world to have been by your
side. But alas! I see no chance for me to be with you soon. We have just heard of the loss ofVicksburg and Lee's
glorious victory in Pennsylvania. Upon reaching this place we received our mail fi-om Chattanooga (direaed to
Shelbyville), and I had the exquisite pleasure of getting two ofyour sweet letters. I can assure you I was delighted
to receive them and hope to get another this evening, as I hope you have not ceased to write because I have not
had the opportunity ofwriting. I have read and re-read your letters and still keep them. I generally bum them after
reading them over and over, for fear I might be taken prisoner or killed and someone else get them. You speak of
receiving a letter containing $40. 1 sent one also containing $20. Did you get it. I had hard work to get the sheet of
paper to write on and don't knoww+iere an envelope is to come fi-om. Dear Mar)-; I have had an idea ofwriting Pa
to bring you up to see me, now I am so near, but it is doubtful about our staying here any length of time. I can't
make up my mind to do so. I feel more sadness in relation to the fiall ofVicksbui^ than I have felt in many a long
day It seems to me that the prospects of the war, being indefinitely prolonged, are increased a hundred fold. I try
to cheer the Boys; but they seem dispirited, although they say they will fight now harder than ever As for m^'sel^
1 have concluded I am my country's and mywife's. I dread to fell on your account but were I a single man I expea
I would have been turning to mother earth long ago. And should I be so unfortunate as to fall what is to become
ofmy dear wife and Babe is the all important question to my mind presented. So for your dear sweet sake, I will
be more prudent in future; and I hope with my former good fortune. Many are the bullets I have heard whistle of
bullets and shells and as yet am untouched. Thanks to my own beloved darling's prayers; and now it is dark so
farewell my own sweet one.
H. C. Reynolds
Page 32
</dc:description>
<dc:description>Presents the letters of Henry Clay Reynolds to his wife, detailing local events and battles during the Civil War, with a short biographical introduction by the Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:description>
<dc:subject>United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865; Tennessee, Middle; University of Montevallo</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>12 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-01-25; mt2011-01-26</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication39ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/8</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>