<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>The Ku Klux Klan</dc:title>
<dc:creator>McFarlin, Ben Hall</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 2</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1973</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>19th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>39
THE KU KLUX KLAN
By Ben Hall McFarlin
The story of the Ku Klux Klan is one of the most colorful,
as well as the most tragic, pages of American history. Its
origin as a social club, its name, and its mysterious actions
are interesting events to read and investigate, but the violent
whippings and murders by the transformed Klan are tragedies.
Many Middle Tennesseans were deprived of voting privileges;
therefore, they resented the Negro's right to vote. After the
Klan began its ghostly activities that frightened the Negroes,
its members realized that the Klan could be made into an organi-zation
which might aid in keeping the Negroes from the polls;
and thereby, defeat the Radicals in the state government.-^
On an evening in December 1865, six young men were sitting
around the fireplace in the law office of Judge T. J. Jones in
Pulaski, Tennessee, just off the Square on West Madison Street.
These men. Captain John C. Lester, Captain John B. Kennedy,
Captain James R. Crowe, Frank O. McCord , Richard R. Reed, and
J. Calvin Jones were citizens of the highest standing in the
community and most of them were college graduates and none of them
at any time were ever accused of any offense against the law.
They had all served with the Confederate Army, and after they had
returned to their homes, and while they were adjusting themselves
to the new conditions of life, time hung heavy on their hands.
40
So that on this December evening when one of them suggested that
they form a club or society of some sort, the idea met with
p general approval.
The name chosen for the club was KuKlox or KuKlos, a Greek
word meaning "circle" or "cycle". The organizers of this club
were out for fun, but it was fun of an innocent and harmless
variety they had in mind at the beginning. ^ As the Klan grew
in membership there was a change in their "fun". Most members
regarded themselves as the protectors of white supremacy. Although
the Klan frightened many Negroes, the white men regarded it with
amusement and were eager to join.l
The members and their initiation was secret, and their
meetings mysterious. They rode their horses through town and
the countryside covered with sheets, in the beginning. It pleased
the members that through their superstitions, they were able to
frighten the Negroes. As time evolved their uniform changed.
The uniforms were made in complete secrecy. Much care was taken
while the robes were being made to keep the facts from being
2 learned by the public.
The Klan began its activities in the political sphere when
the Negroes were granted suffrage and when the loyal militia was
called into effect. The legislature passed the bill granting
Negro suffrage on February 25, 1867; it permitted the Negroes to
vote but still excluded the ex-Confederates. These actions
interferred with the rights of the southerners, and the Ku Klux
Klan was the one organization which struggled to uphold these
rights and privileges of which the southerners believed they were
being unjustly deprived.
41
Early in 1867 the Klan changed from a social club with an
absurd ritual and ridiculous regalia into a "great federation
of regulators". It relinquished its frivolous fun-making for
the serious purpose of controlling the Negro and the carpet-baggers.
The men of Middle Tennessee transformed the Klan into
a regulatory organization. It sought to regain freedom for the
white southerners by combating the aims of the Negroes and a
counter organization called the Union League. Its members
consisted mostly of former slaves and carpetbaggers . -*-
The Klan became involved in politics and state government.
Knowing the attitude and policies of Governor Brownlow-'- (Governor
Brownlow, before the war, was an anti-sessionist. He worked
during the war in the North promoting the cause of the Union.
After the war he returned to Knoxville and re-established his
newspaper and took up his fight against ex-Confederates and
carried his fight on to the governorship) , the Klansmen believed
that his re-election would be disastrous to the Klan. By the
beginning of the election year, the political situation was
already distressing to the Conservatives and the ex-Confederates.
Registration certificates had been granted to a low white class
and to many ex-Confederates who had become Unionists, not because
of conviction, but in order to vote. The granting of voting
privileges to these people, instead of property-owners and tax-payers
was an outrage to most respectable whites both Conservative
and Unionists. Many sincere Unionists were not permitted to vote
because they did not agree with Brownlow' s policies. The Klan
42
did not trust Brownlow. His sympathy lay with the Union and
the southerners thought that his continued rule would push the
South into further ruin.
The Ku Klux Klan had a strong establishment in Murfreesboro.
Membership was so large and bold that it drilled regularly in one
of the open lots near town. The Klansmen practiced their marching
and counter-marching in the fashion of a regular military company.
The Klan also made public appearances in Murfreesboro through
parades and similar group activities. A Nashville newspaper
reported that one parade in Murfreesboro consisted of five to
seven thousand. All marchers were dressed in the robes and tall
pointed hats. "Some were so high that they took the slates off
the roof of the new church building," the reported stated. On
May 12, 1868, a report concerning a Murfreesboro parade declared,
"They were all dressed in uniforms and their horses caparisoned
in usual style." They commenced parading about nine o'clock and
kept it up until after midnight. The Klan increased in number
and extended throughout Rutherford County. On a Saturday night,
February 22, 1868, about twenty Klansmen paraded through the
streets of Murfreesboro. Dressed in white robes, masks, and tall
hats with lights in the top of them, the Klansmen frightened the
Negroes and ignorant whites. The Klansmen rode slowly through
the streets, lingering in front of the houses occupied by teachers
of freedmen. On the doorstep of the office of the Freedmen'
s
Watchman, a Radical owned newspaper, the following message was
left: "Prepare thyself. Your doom is sealed. We swear by our
slumbering dust you shall no longer oppress your downtrodden
Brothers. "^
43
The Klan's methods became violent. There were burnings,
hangings, and whippings. These outrages did not take place in
just one county, but were committed in all parts of Middle
Tennessee and West Tennessee especially in Maury, Lincoln, Giles,
Marshall, Obion, Hardeman, Fayette, Rutherford, and Gibson County. *-
Many of the individuals who were outraged by the Klan and
many witnesses to the violence perpetrated by the Klan testified
to the government. Since the Ku Klux Klan was so intensive and
well-organized, many people did not believe any moral influence
could dissolve the Klan. George E. Judd , an agent of the
Freedmen's Bureau, expressed the opinion that "Powder and Ball
is the only thing that will put them down." Many people shared
this view. The power of the government seemed to be the only
solution for the protection of the Radicals, Unionists, and
freedmen .
-'-
There is no way of knowing just when and under what circum-stances
the Ku Klux Klan was dissolved. The truth of the matter
could be explained by saying that it just melted away and the
process proceeded more rapidly in some sections than in others.
One of the factors which led to the final disbandment of the
original Ku Klux Klan and the end of its influence, was the
appearance throughout the South of groups of counterfeit Ku Klux,
who used the familiar and convenient disguise as a cloak for
robbery, assault, and other crimes. 2 Since the purpose of the
Klan to reinstate disenfranchised southerners by restoring their
right to vote had been accomplished, the story generally accepted
44
by the historians is that Nathan Bedford Forrest, the Grand
Wizard of the Klan, issued a formal disbandment order and that
the Klan obeyed this order and destroyed its regalia, burned its
2 rituals and thus ceased to exist.
'Brenda Mack McFarlin. The Ku Klux Klan in Middle Tennessee ,
(1866-1869), Pages - (Preface ii) , 33, 36, 41, 56, 63, 69, 70, 79.
2Nelle Roller Cohen. Pulaski History , Pages 19, 21, 22.
</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Ku Klux Klan (19th cent.); Violent crimes</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Reconstruction; Freedmen's Bureau</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>11 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-16</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication02ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/98</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>