<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Goochland</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Watson, Virginia Gooch</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 12</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1979</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>19th century; 20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>35
GOOCHLAND
By
Mrs. Virginia Gooch Watson
(Mrs. George F. Watson)
For almost a century, the stately home "Goochland" was a
landmark in old "District 3" of Rutherford County, Tennessee. It was
situated one mile north of the Smyrna depot and one mile east of the
Nashville and Chattanooga railway as the crow flies. Goochland was on a
knoll about 200 feet to the north of Jefferson Pike with the Nelson home
just across the road about 200 feet south and slightly east. Even after
100 years, the old home was a landmark but in a different way. The old
era gave way to the new when in 1942 Sewart Air Force Base, with their
huge, noisy airplanes, took possession of the entire holdings of Goochland
and used the once peaceful grain fields for concrete runways.
The site on which Goochland once stood is now on the air base
northeast of the fuel tanks on the left of the main road going into the
Smyrna complex on the back nine of the Smyrna Municipal Golf Course
and north of the 8th and 14th tees. The old Jefferson Pike passed in
between Goochland and the Nelson home - more precisely, the Nelson
home was slightly north of what is now the 8th and 14th tees while Gooch-land
was closer to the landing strips. The terrain of the land at this point
was altered extensively to permit the construction of the runways, etc. , so
today it in no way resembles the terrain of Goochland as it was once.
Here, Goochland inhabitants from 1842-1942 enjoyed a lovely view in all
directions of green pastures and farmland that surrounded the home.
36
Today, evidence of the existence of the Nelson home can be
found around the tree roots of the big trees close by the 7th green on the
golf course where slave-made bricks are lodged. Since Sewart Air Force
Base closed in 1969, the airport and golf course are owned by the city of
Smyrna.
Dr. John C. Goochf the builder of Goochland, was born in
Caswell County, North Carolina, 4 September 1800. He camie to Tennes-see
about 1814 with his parents, Nathaniel and Martha (Patsey) Tait Gooch,
one brother, Allen Tait Gooch, and two sisters, Sarah W. and Lucinda Tait
Gooch. They first settled in Williamson County with Dr. John's uncle,
David Gooch. In 1818, Dr. John's father, Nathaniel Gooch, purchased
679 3/4 acres on Hurricane Creek in District 1 of Rutherford County with
William G. Kimbro and Major John Buchanan as next door neighbors. Dr.
John's father, Nathaniel, died in 1841 at which time his will directs that
his land be sold and the proceeds equally divided among his four children.
His 21 slaves and their issue were given directly to his children.
The route to Tennessee was rather long and involved before
Goochland could be brought to reality. It began with Dr. Gooch' s grand-father,
William Gooch of Hanover County, Virginia, and later of Caswell
County, North Carolina, who was a Revolutionary War veteran. William
Gooch enlisted 11 November 1777 for 3 years serving as a Private, Taylor's
Company, 1st North Carolina Battalion and Corp. Hogg's Company. His
place of residence during the Revolutionary War was the HiUsboro district.
North Carolina. William died the 22d December 1802 in Caswell County
leaving twelve children, seven of whom came to middle Tennessee in the
late 1700's and early 1800's. Dr. John's father, Nathaniel, stayed in
North Carolina settling William's estate before heading west to the greener
^^Dr. John Claiborne Gooch.
37
38
pastures in middle Tennessee arriving about 1814. He was probably the
last of the seven children to come to Tennessee. Dr. Gooch had 3 uncles
1
and 3 aunts waiting for him in middle Tennessee.
It is unknown exactly where Dr. Gooch received his M. D.
degree, but he was enrolled at Transylvania University, Lexington,
Kentucky, for the sessions of 1823/24 and 1824/25 which completed his
classwork required for an M. D. degree at that time. However, his name
does not appear on the graduation lists of that school, nor of the Univer-sity
of Pennsylvania, the Medical College of South Carolina at Charleston,
Columbia University, or other medical schools of the period. He could
not have graduated from the University of Nashville Medical Department
as it was not established until 11 October 1850. It is possible that after
Dr. Gooch completed his course work, he followed the Europeaji custom
whereby a man "read" medicine under an older physician. In any event,
he did practice medicine and his practice included the areas of Jefferson,
Smyrna, and LaVergne and possibly a wider territory but it would seem
likely that it was confined to this general area of the county.
Goochland became a little closer to becoming a reality when
Dr. John and Eliza Ann Saunders were married by his first cousin, David
Rice Gooch, Justice of the Peace, on the 8th December 1831, in Rutherford
County. Eliza Ann Saunders's father's given name is unknown but her
1. David, Thomas, and James Gooch who came to Williamson County in
18 04 and settled in the Nolensville area, near the Rutherford -Williamson
County line. David and Thomas purchased a total of 741 acres on Mill
Creek in Williamson County in 1804-1805. James Gooch migrated on into
Kentucky; Mrs. Elizabeth (Gooch) Kimbrough and her husband, William
Kimbrough, who settled in the LaVergne area of Rutherford County; Mrs.
Ann (Nancy) Gooch Benton, widow of Jesse Benton and mother of Thomas
Hart Benton, famous U.S. Senator from Missouri; and Mrs. Polly (Gooch)
Williams and her husband, Henry Williams, the latter two girls settling in
Williamson County.
39
mother was Mrs. Cynthia Saunders (maiden name unknown). Eliza was
born 28 July 1814, probably in Rutherford County, Tennessee, and died
28 April 18 77 in Rutherford County, Tennessee.
John and Eliza Gooch had 10 children, 7 of whom lived to
adulthood: Robert Saunders, John Claiborne, Martha Tait, William,
Nathaniel, John (Col. Jack) Saunders, Allen Tait, Eliza, James Pinkney,
and Claiborne Alexander Gooch.
After Dr. Gooch became established in his medical practice, he
began purchasing property in Rutherford County in 1836 in different tracts,
some of which bordered each other. A total of 2, 154 acres 899 poles was
acquired in Rutherford County and 2 99 acres in Davidson County near the
Rutherford- David son County line. About 1, 600 acres of this total was
considered to be the Goochland plantation.
In 1842, Dr. Gooch began building Goochland. It was the tradi-tional
two- story Greek Revival type of architecture of the time, built of
red brick in an ell shape. Traditional in every sense as far as outward
appearances were concerned, the Dr. deviated slightly from the traditional
construction when he made the outside walls 18 inches thick and the inside
load-bearing walls 14 inches thick. The bricks for the structure were made
on the property by his own slaves, and it took three years to complete,
1842 - 1845. Dr. Gooch and his family lived in a log cabin nearby while
Goochland was being built, and it was in this log cabin on the 15th of
November 1833 that one of Murfreesboro's future doctors was born - Dr.
William Lunsford Wilson. In Dr. Wilson's diary, he reflects "l was born
November 15, 1833, the night of the great meteric shower or as it is
commonly said 'the night the stars fell' on a farm near Smyrna and Old
Jefferson, Rutherford County, Tennessee, now owned by the Gooches. "
40
Dr. John Claiborne Gooch
4 Sept. 1800 - 3 Nov. 1853
Mrs. Eliza Ann (Saunders) Gooch
28 July 1814 - 26 April 18 77
Portraits owned by Lt. Col. CM. Gooch, Jr., Clarksville, Tenn.
Tombstone in Cannon Cemetery,
Smyrna, Tenn. , of
Dr. and Mrs. John Claiborne Gooch
41
Allen Tait Gooch
11 Sept. 1806 - 28 Feb. 1883
Portrait owned by Mrs. Catharine
(Richey) Hinton (Mrs. J. Karr
Hinton), Collierville, Tenn.
Mrs. Elizabeth Venable (Morton) Gooch
6 Nov. 18 09-3 Aug. 1865
Portrait owned by Mrs. Elizabeth
(Richey) Stansel (Mrs. Eugene A.
Stansel), Ruleville, Miss.
Mrs. Lucinda Tait (Gooch) Kimbro
24 March 1803 - 14 Aug. 1867
Portrait owned by Mrs. Marion (Pearson) Kinnard (Mrs. George A.
Nashville, Tenn.
Kinnard),
Floorplan after 18 95 Remodeling
(First Floor only)
,/&#8226;"
&#8212;J &lt;/'&lt;
I
^^'"1
/?^^^
[]
[I
^ ,. ^d:!
\ i
Sto^"-
I
"""
:l
&#8226;0
\J/
a
IV/
11
^/z . ''^/^ ^-'j.f
-EE}-
"P^/.-/^'
^:^:f-
[]
/-. c r ^ /^ a7 yj A /Pi' /-&lt;:: /f
\^o^//a^c-^j^
"S=^EE^
The front porch of the home had large fluted columns that
extended to the roof line and supported a triangular, ornately decorated,
pediment. Entrance to a large center passage or hall (reputedly nearly
30' wide) was through heavy oak doors surrounded by glass on both sides
and the top. A circular staircase hugging the right back wall was the
access to the second floor. Of particular interest in the staircase was
the extremely wide treads and the newel post. Three doors led off the
entrance hall - the right door exited to the parlor, the left door exited to
what was originally the "family room, " and the door directly under the
staircase and opposite the front door exited to a small porch. The rooms
were approximately 30 x 30 feet with 12-foot ceilings. Behind the family
room was the large back passage or hall that ran perpendicular to the
entrance hall. Here the back stairs were located. Behind this back hall
was a large dining room thus giving an ell shape to the original floor plan.
The second floor had the same floorplan - a center hall with a
large room on the right and two rooms on the left, separated by the back
hall. These rooms were the same size as those on the first floor, 30x30
feet with 12 -foot ceilings. Chimneys were located at each end of the home
and a third chimney was at the rear of the dining room thus providing fire-places
in every room. The original kitchen was a separate building at the
rear of the home.
In 18 95, the home was extensively remodeled to include porches
across the entire front on both levels. To the center portico was added 4
small columns and "gingerbread" laticework decorated the railings and
portico. It is believed that this was when the brick was painted gray or
off-white as it was when Mrs. Mary Law (Gooch) Johns (Mrs. Hubert Johns)
was living there in 1928. After this time, the gray paint began peeling off
44
exposing the original red brick. The original kitchen was attached to the
dining room on the left side and had a flue added for the stove. After 1928,
Mr. &amp; Mrs. Hubert Johns tore down the old kitchen and built a smaller one
attached to the end of the porch beside the dining room. Between the
dining room and the original kitchen that was attached after 1895, there was
another hallway, with another set of very steep back stairs. The boys used
this "back, back stairway" to have easier access to their room upstairs
which was over the dining room. To the right of the dining room and
directly behind the entrance hall was a spacious screened-in-porch that
was 30 feet wide and 60 feet long which was probably added in the
remodeling in 1895. Here, many family and community gatherings were
enjoyed. With the double doors of the entrance hall open to this porch, a
delightful breeze was enjoyed during the hottest of weather.
The home faced Jefferson Turnpike and had a circular carriage
road that terminated on the Turnpike. From the carriage road, a brick
walkway led to the house flanked on either side by large magnolia trees,
shrubs, and flowers. In the early 1900's, there were two buggy houses,
one at each extreme corner of the yard; however, it would seem more
logical that the original buggy houses were probably to the back of the
home on each side, or closer to the various barns which were to the right
and in back of the home.
Two very large rectangular stones were used for steps to the
front porch. The date of Goochland's completion was carved into one of
these stones - "1845. " When the house was razed in 1942, these two steps
were removed by Mr. &amp; Mrs. Hubert Johns and are now used as front door
steps in Mrs. John's present home in Smyrna, the old Knox Ridley home.
The carved date has been turned inward and is not visible on the steps.
k5
Original Floorplan of Goochland
%
^)
'i'
First Floor
3(c|jTi^
\^ojl
^ ?u....^ Pc.-cA
c -loo.' C
I
'^ -^E==* - ^ --t:^:^ -I1Z3
&#8212;
'41 X r;::
^&lt;^- fa^ri'/'t/
m KCCfn
I]
r\
'V/
.^
\
..,^/&#171;;-
&#163;3: IZZI ' C
F/..-//
r.'no+ I'oc'.
Ttirlor
A-H3
Tfr-cl-.
II ^U.',/'i/i'&lt;-^'
l^^(/'L^^cm
\-
L.,,,/..^
/7.,,,/
^'
,^' l^/fc
Second Floor
sr^
./7&lt;:'- //
1 -. I
/
i
TiE3-
^////.r/'^-i
-;.6
Mr. &amp; Mrs. Johns removed, piece by piece, and reconstructed one of the
original log structures from Goochland when they moved. It is now being
used as a storage area. The steps and the log building are the only known
items that remain of the home itself except for pieces of furniture.
Many of the furnishings for Goochland were purchased in
Philadelphia, Baltimore, and New York, and possibly other eastern cities
by Dr. Gooch's brother, Allen Tait Gooch. Allen traveled a great deal
purchasing stock for his merchantile store in Murfreesboro, and appar-ently
purchased pier mirrors, parlor and dining room furniture, carpets,
etc. , for his brother's new home as is evidenced in letters Allen wrote
home.
A bill rendered to Dr. Gooch from G. W. Rather reflects some
of the expenses encountered in building Goochland. To paint the house
cost $60. 00, which probably was for the inside woodwork and outside trim,
hanging 193 bolts of wallpaper was $48.25, and the "cutting and gazing 64
side and transome lites" was $2. 56, totaling $110. 81. Quite a contrast
with today's expenses. The number of bolts of wallpaper hung in each area
is also given as follows:
Parlor 22
Over parlor 22
Dining 24
Over dining 25
Family 18
Over family 2
Front passage 31
Back passage 31
193 bolts
Dr. Gooch evidently took an active part in community affairs and
education as reflected by various manuscripts that have survived. He was
President of the Jefferson Turnpike Company in August 1843 and on the
Board of Directors of this company in November of 1845.
47
A knife, 17 1/8 inches long and 2 3/8 inches wide, is in the
Tennessee State Museuna, Nashville, Tennessee, which belonged to Dr.
Gooch. His name, the date 1844, Commander, and Stone's River are
affixed to the label. The knife has a plain, straight and apparently hand-forged
blade with a straight and plain handle. Dr. Gooch was commissioned
Captain of the 22d Regiment, Rutherford County Militia, 2 7 February 1826,
and was commissioned Colonel and Commander of the 22d Regiment the 3d
March 1831. He must have continued to be the Commander of the 22d Regi-ment
as evidenced by the knife and an August 15th, 1844, Flag Presentation
invitation. The invitation and note indicate Gooch' s company was known as
the "Slashers, " and another letter reflects Gooch was Commander of the
regiment at that time. Although Dr. Gooch and his brother seemed to have
been very close, they did not serve in the same militia regiment. Allen
Tait Gooch was commissioned 1st Lieutenant in the 104th Rutherford County
Militia 22 March 1832.
Being interested in education and the importance of the three
"R's" is reflected in a catalogue of Poplar Grove Academy for December
1852 which indicates Dr. Gooch took an active part in the Academy. He was
listed, along with J. W. Lindly, the principal, for "further particulars"
regarding the school. In a letter introducing Dr. Gooch in Cincinnati dated
11 February 1850 from Robert Morrison of Jefferson, Morrison states Dr.
Gooch "is the chief patron of our school and of course a friend of education.
"
The school he is referring to evidently was Poplar Grove Academy. The
Academy was located "on the turnpike road leading from Nashville to Jeffer-son,
three miles west of the latter place, on Stewart's Creek, Rutherford
County, Tennessee." It possibly could have been on the edge of Dr. Gooch's
property itself, or within about 1/2 mile of Goochland. The course of study
48
at Poplar Grove qualified "the student for Mercantile, Agricultural or
Mechanical pursuits; or fitting him to enter the Junior or Senior classes
of the best colleges in the United States. " No doubt this is where Dr.
Gooch sent his children to be educated along with other neighborhood
children. The known age range of students that did attend was from
8 to 16.
In 1844, the address of Dr. Gooch and Goochland was "Poplar
Grove, Tenn. " as letters addressed to him during that time reflect. In
1846, he received mail addressed to him at "Stuartsboro, " which address
was naore frequently used and continued longer than "Poplar Grove. "
There may have been a grove of poplar trees near, hence the mailing
address and the name of the academy. No doubt, many of these trees
were probably used in building Goochland, particularly the floors.
From Goochland, 4 sons of Dr. Gooch left for the Civil War -
Robert Saunders, Nathaniel, John (Jack) Saunders, and Allen Tait Gooch.
Robert Saunders Gooch served as Private in Co. B, 2 0th Tenn. Infantry.
Captain Nathaniel Gooch enlisted in April 1861 in Co. C, 18th Tenn. Infan-try
serving as 2d Lieut. He was captured at Fort Donelson in February
1862 and exchanged in November 1862 in Vicksburg, Miss., after which he
became Captain on the staff of General James B. Palmer. Allen Tait
Gooch left home on the 2d September 1864 and joined the rebels at age 19.
Colonel Jack Saunders Gooch became well known for his organization of
Co, E, 20th Tenn. Regiments, in Smyrna in the spring of 1861. W. J.
McMurray's "History of the Twentieth Tennessee Regiment Volunteer
Infantry C.S.A. " has an interesting note showing Goochland property was
used for drill training by son. Col. Jack - "After the organization we
drilled nearly every day, sometimes at Smyrna and sometimes at LaVergne,
but generally in Mrs. Dr. Gooch's lot on the Jefferson Pike near Smyrna,
until June 1861, when we took the cars for Camp Trousdale. There were
either 48 or 49 of us that got on at Smyrna and LaVergne; others following
on later.
"
All four of these men returned from the war and had or have
living descendants in the area still:
Robert lived in Nashville, later in Davidson County near the
Williams on -Rutherford county lines. From 4 daughters, only one grew
to womanhood, married, and lived in Franklin, Tenn. - Mrs. Martha
Tait (Patti) Gooch Rhodes (Mrs. James Elbert Rhodes);
Nathaniel studied medicine and became a medical doctor
practicing in Rutherford County, later in 1886 moving to Nashville and
continuing his practice there. Nathaniel has many descendants, widely
scattered, but two of his grandchildren still live in the area - Lt. Col.
Christopher McEwen Gooch, Jr. , of Clarksville, and Mrs. Jane Gooch
Ambrose (Mrs. Henry Ambrose) of Brentwood;
Allen returned home to Smyrna to live but a short while before
he died in 1869 leaving one daughter, Eliza A. Gooch, who married and
lived in Chattanooga. His descendants are widely scattered over the U. S. ;
Col. Jack came home to Smyrna and remained there, living at
Goochland.
Dr. Gooch died 30 November 1853. His widow, Eliza A. ,
continued to live at the homeplace, Goochland, while his estate was being
settled, she having received the homeplace and 623 3/160 acres as her
dower. His vast holdings and the real estate were finally divided among
his widow and children 5 November 1867. The land distributed totaled
2, 453 acres 899 poles, 299 acres of which was in Davidson County. The
50
value of this real estate, after the Civil War, amounted to $115, 882. 90.
Each child received $20, 033 with the exception of Robert S. Goochwho
received the 299 acres in Davidson County, his share amounting to
$15, 717. 25.
In the division in 1867, the two minor children, James P. and
Claiborne A. Gooch, received the homeplace and land with their mother as
their guardian. Eliza received a life interest in the homeplace and 63 7 1/2
acres. Later, in 1871 and 18 72, both boys died intestate before they
reached their majority leaving no issue having never been married. In
April of 18 77, Eliza died. These deaths meant that the land the two boys,
James and Claiborne, inherited from their father (with their mother having
a life interest only) had to be divided among the next of kin. The division
was made among the living brothers, John S. and Nathaniel Gooch; Martha T.
(Patti) and Susan R. Gooch, minor children of Robert S. Gooch, with B.
Gray as their regular guardian; and Eliza A. Gooch, minor child of Allen T.
Gooch, whose regular guardian was her uncle, John S. Gooch. Each
received 1/4 share. Nathaniel Gooch elected to sell his 1/4 share to his
brother, John S. Gooch, so that meant John S. would receive 2/4's or 1/2
of the division.
On 4 September 1877, the land was divided equally. The 2/4's
or 1/2 share that John S. Gooch received included the home, Goochland
and 182 77/160 acres.
It seems quite likely that John S. Gooch lived his entire life at
Goochland, excluding time spent in the Confederate Army during the Civil
War. He married in 1864 and there is no evidence he lived elsewhere.
His brothers married and left home - Nathaniel to live in Huntsville, Ala. ,
for awhile, Allen T. having his own place, and Robert living in Davidson
County, thus leaving only John S. to care for his mother and run the farm.
51
His mother, Eliza, died in 18 77 and both Robert and Allen died before this.
When the land division was made in 1877, John S, and family continued to
live at Goochland, being a farmer and breeder of thoroughbred harness
and trotting horses, Cotswold sheep and Berkshire hogs. John S. and his
wife, Evaline (Evie) had one child, Mary (Mamie) Eliza, born in 1865, and
when he became guardian of his niece, Eliza, in 1869, he evidently brought
Eliza over to Goochland to live there with the family. John S. was Post-master
of the 1st District in 1886, served in the 1889 Tennessee House of
Representatives, served as Magistrate, and as Elder in the Smyrna
Presbyterian Church for 28 years.
A race-track for the horses was maintained there on the place.
The site of the race-track today is on the corner of the main entrance road
into Smyrna Air Port and the old Jefferson Pike as one would turn right to
go across Stewart's Creek to the Golf Clubhouse. At the death of Col. Jack
Gooch, 23 December 1915, the home passed to his only daughter, Mrs.
Mary (Mamie) Eliza Gooch Neely, widow of William Daniel Neely. Mamie
and Will Neely raised their 5 children at Goochland: John (Jack) Gooch
Neely, Will Daniel Neely, II, George Lee Neely, Evie Hume Neely, and
Jesse Claiborne Neely.
Some of the Neely children remained in Smyrna for awhile as
John Gooch Neely was assistant cashier in 1909 at Peoples Bank in Smyrna
where his grandfather. Col. Jack S. Gooch,was president from 1909-1915.
John and Lee Neely operated the Livery Stable in Smyrna. Both of these
boys left Smyrna as well as their youngest brother, Jesse Claiborne Neely.
Jess Neely became the well-known coach and Athletic Director at Rice
University for 27 years. After Jess's retirement in 1969 from Rice Univer-sity,
he became Athletic Director of Vanderbilt University, Nashville, and
is now Athletic Director Emeritus. Jess has many happy memories of his
52
boyhood at Goochland, The only member of the Neely family that
remained in SmjTna was William D, Neely, II, vrtio married Ella Engles,
On 5 September 1927, Goochlaid passed from Gooch ownership
when I'Irs. I-Iaraie (Gooch) Neely and her son, VJilliam D, Neely, II, sold
it to Ben F, Johns (Sr.), After previous sales of property by the Gooches
and Neelys, Goochland contained oaly lU5,U8 acres xfaen Mr. Jolms p^orchased
it. At this time, the property v/as bounded on the north by Sanders and
Ridley, on the east by Ridley and Stewart's Creek, on the south by Jefferson
Turnpike, and on the west by Jones Mill Road,
I"Ir, Johns died son after he purchased Goochland never having
lived there. His wife, Mrs. Helen Johns, and his five children (A. Frank,
Hubert H,, Ruth Johns McCluskey, Rufus S. Johns, and J. Glendon Johns)
inherited the property. Once more a Gooch inhabited the home, as on
2 February 1928 Mary Law Gooch married Hubert H, Johns, the son of Ben F, Johns.
They moved into Goochland and began housekeeping, Vbc3, Mary Law (Gooch) Johns
is the great, great niece of the original owner. Dr. John G. Gooch, It
wasn't until 16 August 1937 that Mrs. Helen Johns and her children divided
the estate, and Goochland and the ll;5&#187;U8 acres was allotted to Hubert H. Johns
and his wife, Ifery Law Gooch, and Hubert's sister, Mrs. Ruth (Johns) McCluskey
as their share of the estate.
Hubert and Ifery Law Johns lived in the home from 1928 imtil
the State of Tennessee purdiased the home and property 30 January 19U2
for a part of Sewart Air Force Base, The hone was razed at this time.
Instead of ;fche usual bulldozing to wreck a house, Goochland had to bo
dynamited in order to tear doim the 32 inch thick walls of the stnacture.
All of the Gooches in the Dr.'s family belonged to the Smyrna
Presbyterian Cliurch and many of them are buried in Cannon Cemeter:^- not
far from the home. Col. Jack S. "ooch and his family were buried in
Cannon but vjere reinterred in Mapleview Cemetery in Sn^rrna about 1918.
53
Dr. John C. Gooch, his wife, and some of their children still remain in
Cannon Cemetery today. Their tombstones are still standing but have been
badly damaged by vandals.
As was the custom. Dr. Gooch owned slaves who lived on the
Goochland plantation. In 1836 he paid taxes on 11 slaves. That number
increased to 31 by 1840, and by 1850 he owned 81 slaves. In AprU 1854,
when an inventory of the Dr. 's estate was made, it reflects a total of
109 slaves. In the 1860 Slave Census of Rutherford County, his widow,
Eliza Gooch, is shown with 103 slaves and 13 slave houses. Today, not
far from where Goochland stood, about a quarter of a mile (now on the
right of the main entrance road into the Smyrna Airport), a slave cemetery
containing 80 graves remains. This is where the Gooches buried their
Negro slaves. The only remaining marker reads as follows: "Edmund
Weakley, true and faithf\il unti]e(sic) death, aged 80 years. " In 1969, Air
Force Sgt. Weymand D. Garmany marked each of these graves with white
military crosses which remained there until 1970. At this time the crosses
were removed for reasons unknown.
Goochland was in a picturesque setting overlooking rich farmland,
pastures, and all of the natural factors that blend to make a hospitible and
inviting home to those who pass by. Five generations grew to adulthood in
this lovely home, sharing both joy and sorrow. Those who remember
cherish happy memories of time spent in this impressive and spacious home.
The writer, Mrs. Virginia Gooch Watson, is the great, great,
great granddaughter of Nathaniel Gooch, the great, great granddaughter of
Allen Tait Gooch (brother to Dr. Gooch), and the great, great, great niece
of Dr. John C. Gooch.
5..
BIBLIOGRAPHY
Account Book belonging to Allen Tait Gooch of the GOOCH &amp; McKNIGHT
MERCHANTILE BUSINESS, Murfreesboro, Tenn. , 1837-1850;
original in Gooch Collection of Mrs. George F. Watson,
Franklin, Tenn.
Bibles: the Nathaniel Gooch Bible and the Dr. Nathaniel Gooch Bible;
xerox copies in Gooch Collection of Mrs. George F. Watson.
"Biographical Directory, Tennessee General Assembly, 1796-1967,
(Preliminary No. 6) Rutherford County, " pub. by the Tennessee
State Library &amp; Archives, 1968. pp. 22-23.
Caswell County, North Carolina, Will Book D, pp. 13 0-132, WiU of
William Gooch,
"Confederate Patriot Index, 1894-1924, vol. 1, " published by the Tennessee
Division, United Daughters of the Confederacy, 1976, p. 161.
"Confederate Veteran Magazine, " 1919, p. 428, obituary of Nathaniel Gooch.
Diary of Dr. William Lunsford Wilson; original in possession of Mrs. B. K.
Hibbett, Jr., Nashville, Tenn., copy in Manuscript Section,
Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives.
"1840 Census of Rutherford County, Tennessee, " reproduced by the
Rutherford County Historical Society, 1974, p. 5.
"1878 Map of Rutherford County, Tennessee, " by D. G. Beers,
Philadelphia, Pa.
Gooch family papers in possession of Lt. Col. Christopher McEwen Gooch, Jr. ,
Clarksville, Tenn. , xerox copies in Gooch Collection of
Mrs. George F. Watson:
Agreement, 8 Nov. 1845 between Archibald &amp; James Fosset &amp;
the Directors of the Jefferson Turnpike Co. creating toll
gate on Jefferson Pike near Thos. Neal. Dr. John C. Gooch
was Director of Jefferson Turnpike Co.
Bill for services rendered in building Goochland from G. W. Rather
to Dr. Gooch, about 1845. .
Interlocutory Decree, 1841, between heirs of John McGregor &amp;
sureties, Ben Ward, Wm. Alford, Berryman Ferguson,
John C. Gooch &amp; Moses R. Buchanan, vs. Ransford McGregor,
as heard in Supreme Court of Tennessee.
Invitation to Captain J. C. Gooch, commander of company in
55
Rutherford County Militia from J. E. Wendel dated 9 Aug.
1844. Invitation for company flag ceremony in
Murfreesboro.
Letter from J. E. Wendel to Commander Gooch - invitation to
flag presentation by Whig Ladies in Murfreesboro for
Gooch' s company.
Letter of introduction of Dr. John C. Gooch to Will Moore, Esq.
,
in Cincinnati, Ohio, dated 11 Feb. 1850, from Robert
Morrison of Jefferson, Rutherford County, Tenn.
Receipt dated 4 Aug. 1843 from Dr. J. C. Gooch, President of
the Jefferson Turnpike Company.
Granville Coimty, North Carolina, Deed Book G, p. 3 13, and Deed Book M,
p. 127.
Hoover, Walter K. "A History of the Town of Smyrna, Tenn. ,
" McQuiddy'
Printing Co. , Nashville, Tenn., 1968.
Land Grant No. 22033 in Rutherford County, dated 10 January 1851, Grantee
John C. Gooch, on Stewart's Creek, 48 acres &amp; 37 poles; in
Manuscript Section, Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives.
Letter dated 26 August 1931, from U.S. War Dept. , Adjutant General's
Office, stating Nathaniel Gooch' s CSA record, and obituary of
Nathaniel Gooch stating his CSA record; copies in Gooch Collec-tion
of Mrs. George F. Watson.
Letterhead of Peoples Bank of Smyrna, 5 March 1909, filed with Confederate
Pension Application of James Tait Gooch, No. 10827, in Archives
Section, Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives.
McMurray, W. J. "History of the Twentieth Tennessee Regiment Volunteer
Infantry. C.S.A.,"pub. NashviUe, Tenn., 1904, pp. 111,113,
115-116,399.
"Membership Roster &amp; Soldiers, The Tennessee Society of the Daughters of
the American Revolution, 1960-1970, " pub. by the Tennessee
Society, Daughters of the American Revolution, 1970, pp. 383-384.
Medical college records supplied by Dr. S. R. Bruesch, Memphis, Tenn.
Militia Records of Rutherford County, Tenn. , v. 4, in Archives Section,
Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives.
Militia Records of Rutherford County, Tenn. , Records of Commissions,
V. 5, 3 October 1827 - 23 January 1832, in Archives Section,
Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives.
North Carolina Dept. of Archives &amp; History, "Treasurer's Papers, Revolu-tionary
Vouchers, William Gooch, " No. 12 and No. 549.
56
North Caroline State and Colonial Records, v. 15, p. 725; v. 16, pp. 1062,
1065; V. 17, pp. 213, 381.
Personal interviews with:
AUen W. Gooch
Christopher McEwen (Kit) Gooch
John B. Gooch
Mrs. Mary O. Gooch (Mrs. John B. Gooch)
Mrs. Mary Law (Gooch) Johns (Mrs. Hubert Johns)
Jess C. Neely
Mrs. Elizabeth Morton (Farrar) Richey (Mrs. Robert C. Richey)
Poplar Grove Academy catalog, December 1852; original in files of
Mrs. George F. Watson.
"Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 3, " p. 61 -
"Rutherford County Militia Commissions, 1821-1830. "
"Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 10, " p. 24 -
"1864 Diary of F. E. Henderson"
Rutherford County, Tennessee, County Records:
151
Deed Book 89, p. 58
EnroUment Cases, Book 1, 1867, pp. 288-304.
Enrollment Cases, Book 3, 1878-1881, pp. 140-149.
Marriage Book 1804-1881; 5 December 1831 license issued,
8 December 1831 marriage sol. , by D. R. Gooch, J. P.
Record Book 12, pp. 53, 55, 125, 460, 490
Record Book 16, pp. 713, 787
Record Book 17, pp. 52-62, 606, 669-671
Record Book 18, pp.40, 359, 375
Record Book 19, p. 32
Record Book 20, pp. 96, 514, 600
Record Book 21, p. 569
Record Book 22, p. 628
Deed Book N, p. 156,296
Deed Book V, p. 580
Deed Book Y, p. 71, 101
Deed Book Z, p. 72
Deed Book 4, p. 52, 88,
Deed Book 5, p. 341
Deed Book 71 , p. 416
Deed Book 83 , p. 417
57
Rutherford County, Tennessee, County Records continued:
Record Book 23, p. 107
Record Book 24, p. 143
Record Book 25, pp. 208, 257-258
Record Book 26, pp. 347-348, 383-385
Record Book 27, p. 634
Tax List for 1836, p. 333, District 2
Tax List for 1849
1850 and 1860 Slave Census
Tombstone pictures taken in Cannon Cemetery, Smyrna; &#165;iapleview
Cemetery, Smyrna; Gooch Cemetery, Nolensville; Battle
Cemetery, Davidson County, Tenn. ; and Spring Hill
Cemetery, Nashville, Tenn. , in files of Mrs. George F.
Watson.
</dc:description>
<dc:description>Describes the history of a historic Smyrna home, Goochland, owned by the Gooch family</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Family history; Historic buildings; Rutherford County (Tenn.) -- History</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Gooch family</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Smyrna</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>45 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-01</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication12ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/67</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>