<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>History of Fortress Rosecrans</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Wright, David Russell</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 22</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1984</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869; 19th century; 20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>HISTORY OF FORTRESS ROSECRANS
Chapter V
from a thesis for MTSU
titled
"CIVIL WAR PORTIFICATICN"
by- David Russell Wrl^t
The roads to Tiillahonia, Tennessee, were overflowing with Con-federate
soldiers, filled with the emotions of another retreat, as
they headed south with their wagons and guns on the cold night of
January 3, 1863. Their counterparts in blue, unsure of the Confeder-ate
plans and whereabouts, proceeded with caution as they slowly
entered Murfreesboro with two advanced brigades, later, on the 5th,
followed by the amy. Rosecrans followed the retreating Southerners
with patrols and deployed pickets before placing his array at rest.
Both amies had brought on a severe battle along the banks of
Stones River, ana each needed time to lick its wounds and reorganize
before atteo^tlng another stren\xous campaign. Though placed in a
large camp surrounding Murfreesboro for the winter, Rosecrans did not
allow his amy to lose face with discipline and become exposed to the
evils of idleness, a major problem encountered when an amy retired
for a rest. He put his encamped army into motion by ordering the men
to resume drilling and to transport supplies to the front from Nash-ville.
He ordered sufficient nvunbers of hatchets, axes, and shovels
1
to stgjply the troops for future use.
General Order No. 3, January 9, I863, photocopy of the original
order from the National Archives, Washington, D. C. Riotocopy in
possession of Stones River National Battlefield, Murfreesboro, Tennessee.
- 2 -
The Army of the Cumberland was 215 ndles from its main base of
STjpplies at Lovdsville, Kentucky, and over thirty miles from its main
2
depot at Nashville. The anny was dependent upon military rations and
supplies that trickled southward over a single railroad line which was
easily broken by the enemy raiders and by flash floods . Rosecrans saw
that the thin line of supplies could not feed and clothe his army for a
long period of time, and he remembered the e3q)ectations and failures of
the same line in an atteoftt to si?)ply Buell six months earlier. Rose-crans
was planning a forward movement toward Chattanooga which would
require large stockpiles of supplies to be distributed in secondary
depots along the railroad. Copying Buell 's idea of detached depots,
Rosecrans decided on using only one or two depots, instead of a depot
in every railroad town, and fortifying them more thoroughly.
Murfreesboro would fulfill the needs of a secondary depot. Its
proximi-tgr to Nashville added to its secTirity, and the amy was
already encamped in the vicinity of the town, which provided a ready
work force. Rosecrans had to reorganize the army after the battle, wait
for reinforcements, and construct a sufficient cavalry force to be
congjatible with that of tne enemy. In the meantime, he would occupy
the troops with building the depot to erase the idleness of the army
and also to provide the new troops with a taste of field service.
Finally, Murfreesboro, if fortified and stockpiled with supplies,
would be a good point to fall back on and regroip if the army were
forced to retreat. The town was centrally located in the state and
provided flanking capabilities with the Tennessee River on the right
3
and the Knoxville mountain passes on the left.
The site location and fortification design for the depot was
2 Merrill, 3:390, 392.
3 Nejf York Times, 12 Jantiary I863.
- 3 -
assipied to the Chief aigineer of Rosecrans' staff, Capt. Janes St.
Clair Morton. The criteria governing the selection of the depot site
required it to be adjacent to the Nashville and Chattanooga Railroad,
U
to be large enough to protect an army of about fifty thousand troops,
and to maintain a stockpile of supplies that would feed the army for
sixty to ninety days. The site chosen by Morton (fig. 79, appendix A)
encorqjassed a range of rolling hills and ridges that s\irrounded the
Nashville and Chattanooga Railroad bridge over Stones River and the
junction of the Wilkinson and Nashville turnpikes. The location was
chosen for its defensive qualities, as it ccxnmanded the surrounding
country and the town of Murfreesboro, one-half of a mixe away.
As time was important and the size of the depot called for a large
area to be fortified, Morton quickly got down to business and surveyed
the site that he had chosen and began desigaing the depot fortifications,
He decided upon using an enclosed work that would surround the depot
and would be capable of protecting an army during a siege. His fort
or, as it was called, fortress, measured roughly 1,2$U yards north
and south by 1,070 yards east and west, enclosing about 20u acres of
land.^ On January 23, I863, the fort, officially named Fortress Rose-crans
in honor of the commanding general, &gt;fej. Gen. William Starke
Rosecrans, was established, and construction began immediately after-ward.
General Rosecrans began his Tullahoma march from Fortress
Rosecrans in June I863, his army nvimbering 50,617 and the Confederates
under Bragg U6,665j Gilbert C. Kniffin, "Maneuvering Bragg Out of
Tennessee," in Johnson and B\iel, 3:635-3G.
c
Rosecrans to Haileck, February 13, I863, in OR, vol. 23, pt.2,
p. 59j Tower to Thomas, April 28, 1865, in OR, vol71i9, pt. 2, p. 502.
"Militaiy Posts," Section R, p. 371.
-u -
To carry out his architectural plans of the fort, Morton relied
7
on his coninand, the Pioneer Bsrigade, a brigade of engineer troops
which specialized in fortification and railroad construction and
also perfonned the duties of coiranon soldiers. The role of the Pioneer
Brigade was to supervise the construction crews made up of soldiers.
Inportant features such as magazines, blockhouses, and buildings were
built \jy the Pioneers and other soldiers ^o were capable of perform-ing
the special skills needed for those assignments.
Construction of Fortress Rosecrans was given top priority from
January until raid-April when work slackened and finally became piece-meal
by Jime. During January and the early part of February, many of
the Pioneers were on detached service rebuilding railroads and construct-ing
blockhouses. Morton put his available Pioneers to work on the fort
The Pioneer Brigade was formed in December 1862 and commanded by
Capt. James St. Clair Morton, Corps of Ehgineers and Chief Engineer of
the Array of the Cumberland. The brigade was composed of three battal-ions,
whose members were specially chosen from the regiments that formed
the three corps, and one battery of artillery. The First Battalion
was formed from the Right Vftjig (McCook), the Second Battalion from the
Center (ThcmasJ, and the Third Battalion from the Left Wing (Crittenden).
The Chicago Board of Trade Illinois Battery comprised the artillery
battery until March I863, when it was transferred to the Second Brigade,
Second Division of the Army of the Cvnnberland and replaced by Bridge's
Illinois Battery, which had previously been the newly organized Ca75)any
G, 19th Illinois Infantry Regiment. Bridge's Battery remained with the
Pioneer Brigade until October I863, when it was assigned to the Third
Division of the Fourth Corps. In June I863, the Fourth Battalion was
formed from Gordon Granger's Reserve Corps. Not counting the Fourth
Battalion, the Pioneer Brigade numbered about two thousand troops, and
in the spring of I863 the 1st Michigan Engineers and Mechanics under
Col. William P. Lines were attached to the brigade, bringing the total
of troops to about three thousand. In January I86U, General Morton
was transferred to Washington, D. C, and Col. George P. Buell, command-er
of the 58th Indiana Infantry Regiment, was named commander of the
Pioneer Brigade. In June I86U, the Pioneer Brigade was disbanded, and
its members became the 1st U. S. Veteran Volunteer Ehgineers. The
engineer regiment was mustered out of service on September 26, l86$.
Frederick H. Dyer, A Compendim of the War of tiie Rebellion , 3 vols.
(New York: Thomas Yoseloff, 1959), 1:U65, 2h$i OR, vol 22, pt. 2,
page 285j pt. 1, p. l82j vol. 23, pt. 2, pp. 298, 580.
- 5-
and recalled the remainder of the brigade to Murfreesboro after vork
8
was conq)leted at the various points. Construction began with clear-ing
pathways for the raniparts throu^ forests on the east and north-
9
west sides of the fort and two or three houses. The soldiers and
engineer troops weire required to work day and night in eight-hour
shifts for seven days a week until Aprils averaging four thousand
laborers each day. All work on Sundays was aboli^ed beginning on
the Uth of April, followed by the termination of labor on Saturdays
for all troops except those constructing magazines. By the 20th, the
necessity for night work had ceased, and construction of the fort was
trimmed down to include only the daylight hours. The work hours were
reduced In )^rll as the fort neared completion, and In J\me efforts
were caice again stepped up to complete the project before the can^jaign
10
began at the end of the month.
The type of work initiated on the fort between February and May
varied. Outside the routine ditch excavation, special squads of 100
o
"Morton to Davis, January 30, I863, "Records of the Office of the
Chief of Engineers," Record Groi^) 77, National Archives, Washington,
D. C, vol. 173, p. 11 (hereafter cited as "Engineer Records";; Morton .
to Huntington, Febnjary 3, I863, and Morton to Donnahugh, February 12,
1863, "Engineer Records," vol. 173, pp. l5, 16.
9^ Atlas, plate XXXII, map 1; plate CXXI, map 3.
&#8226;'^Rosecrans to Halleck, March 20, I863, in GR, vol. 23, pt. 2,
p. l5Uj Order from Morton, April k, I863, "Engineer Records," 171*: 17;
Morton to Dodge, April 17, I863, and April 2o, I863, "Engineer Records,"
173s37, 39j Morton to Clark, June 19, 1863, "Engineer Records,"
vol. 17U, n. pag.
- 6 -
to 250 men constructed fascines for the revetments during the period
of at least three months. This shows that the parapets were prob-ably
not begun until late February and neared coTi5)letion by May or
June. Hi^ly skilled and specialized work such as the construct-ion
of magazines, blockhouses, and railroad spurs were conpleted by
the First Michigan aigineer and Mechanics Regiment and the more
skilled members of the Pioneers and other troops. Other priorities
within the scope of the fort-st^jply depot included the construction
of railroad switches and spurs, large warehouses for coiranlssary and
13
quartermaster goods, and a field hospital.
During the construction of Fortress Rosecrans, not all of the
men of the Pioneer Brigade were eIt^)loyed yspon the work. Platoon and
company-size sections were used in the construction of railroad block-houses
and bridges while other sections delivered pontoons, a floating
bridge
/svapport, to the front. Other Pioneers found themselves employed In
common brigade drills, skirmish drill, and sapper and miner duty,
practice of constructing earthworks under enemy fire. Morton placed
"Norton to Laniberson, March 8, I863, "Qigineer Records," 17li:8l;
Morton to Stokes, May 6, I863, "Engineer Records," vol. 17ii, n. pagj
Morton to Stokes, March 29, I863, I7li:10.
^^Morton to Dodge, April 17, 1863, "Engineer Records," 17307.
^Amandus Sllsby to father, March 23, I863, l^rpescript copy in
possession of Dr. James Huhta, Historic Preservation Program, Middle
Tennessee State University, Murfreesboro, Tennessee, transcription by
Ms. Inez Bums, Maryville, Tennessee; Moi^ion to Laniberson, March 8,
1863, "Engineer Records," 17U:8l.
^^rton to Moore, March 1, I863, "Engineer Records," I73:l8j
Morton to Lamberson, March 8, i863, 17U:81; Morton to Jiikes, February
22, 1863, 173:17; Circular from Morton, April 7, I863, i7U:22; Morton
to Cianents, April 27, 1863, vol. 17U, n. pag.; Morton to Clements,
April 6, 1863, 17U:18; and Morton to Stewart, April 19, I863, vol.
17U, n. pag.
- 7 -
the training sessions vcpaa a revolving drill and practice 87sten for
the coiopanles and battalions of the Pioneer Brigade to attend. When
a company conpleted several days of drilling in the skirmish formation^
it was then sent to stiidy sapping and mining, pontoon bridge building,
or to resme its former occupation of earthwork or blockhouse construct-ion.
These drills and field practices helped train and maintain a hig^
level of efficiency in the various duties of the Pioneer troops. Later,
when the three battalions were divided between the three army corps,
the Pioneers, after receiving the training sessions, were able to pro-vide
their respective corps engineering services with speed and pre-cision
during the sunmer campaign of maneuvering Bragg out of southern
Tennessee
.
As Fortress Rosecrans neared con5&gt;letlon in April, the summer
campaign was in the making. Stockpiles of supplies were transported
to the Nashville warehouses from Louisville, Kentucky, and the second-ary
depots at Franklin and Murfreesboro, the latter containing enough
food substances to last aliaost six months and forage for three
months.^^ By mid-June the fort had received its garrison, 2,391*
16
convalescent troops. Convalescent soldiers were used as a garrison
to free able-bodied soldiers to be sent to the front where they were
needed. Once the convalescents had reciqjerated from their woTinds or
sicknesses, they were returned to active duty at the front. However,
''Frederick D. Williams, ed.. The Wild Life of the Army; Civil
War Letters of James A. Garfield (East Lansing, Mich.: Michigan
State Ihaiversity Press, 1961i;, Garfield to Secretary, April 12,
1863, p. 256.
16
Garfield to Rosecrans, June 12, I863, in OR, vol. 23, pt. 2,
p. U23.
- 8 -
the average number of convalescents for garrison duty was insuffi-cient,
at one point nvunbering only 926 men, nine-tenths of whom were
17
unfit for duty.
The duties of the convalescent garrison ranged from the monot-otis
functions of military life to the labors of the carpenter and
farm hand. The duties Included preparing logs and the operation of
the four saw mills, altering embrasures and building carpenter and
blacksmith shops, commissary buildings, and housing for the troops.
as late as ;^ril 3, l865, buildings were erected for the chaplain
and livestock. In the winter, the artillery pieces were winterized
by placing tarpaulins or wooden sheds over the cannons and limbers.
On the other hand, routine duties of the troops were drilling,
cleaning cait?&gt;, and guard duty for the blockhouses and construction
crews on the railroads. Maintenance was also required for the
"^Houghtaling to Goddard, November 2, 1863, in "Fort Rosecrans,
Tennessee, Post Records, l863-i86$," "Records of U. S. Army Continent-al
Commands, 1821-1920," Record Groi?) 393, National Archives, Washing-ton,
D. C, p. 8 (hereafter cited as "Arrry Records";. The convales-cent
garrison was supplemented periodically with active duty troops
during the r-emaining two years of war. In January l861i, the 1st Ken-tucky
Battery helped garrison the fort, and in March i86U, one company
from the 31st Wisconsin Volunteers and the ll5th Ohio Volunteers were
sent to the fort. By March 1865, the fort contained only three
artillery coii5)anies, and the infantry force guarded the town and depot.
The sipply depot was not contained within the fort but remained near
the town. Mendenhall to Brannan, January lU, 186U, in OR, vol 32,
pt. 2, p. 93; Special Orders No. 72, March 12, lb6U, "Arny Records,"
p. 332; Tower to Thomas, April 28, i865, in OR, vol U9, pt. 2, p. 503.
For a review of the Confederate cavalry raids on the railroad defenses
around Murfreesboro, Tennessee, and how the garrison of Fortress
Rosecrans coxmtered these movements, see Edwin C. Bearss, The History
of Fortress Rosecrans (M\irfreesboro, Tenn.: Stones River National
Military Park, i960;.
- 9 -
fortress such as euttdng the grass on the parapetsj dunging reftise,
storing ammunition9 and maintenance on the cannons and linibers (for
a review of the guidelines for defense and maintenance of Fortress
18
RosecranSj see appendix B).
Before the war terminated, a period of less than twenlqr-foTir
months from the time the fort was conpleted. Fortress Rosecrans had
suffered severe deterioration. Di seven months' time after the main
amy advanced from Mxirfreesboro in June I863, evidence of deterior-ation
began to appear in areas that were exposed to the elements of
weather. Some of the magazines were damp after long periods of rain,
and parts of the traverses were eroding, althou^ the garrison had
already rebuilt &lt;Mie traverse. The scarps of the redoubts had fallen,
19
and the galleiy, a covered passageway loopholed for defense, around
the main magazine had begun to fall in. The scarps of the redoubts
were giving way because thsy had been left in an unfinished condition
awaiting the garrison to construct galleries. However, plans for the
inclusion of the galleries had been deemed unnecessary and were phased
out. Even the blocldiouses were not immune to the destructive elements
20
of the weather, as they all leaked badly.
Special Orders No. U, October lU, I863, in "Army Records," p.
318; and other references in "Amy Records": Houghtaling to Russell,
August 3* 1863, p. 5; Special Orders No. kt January h, 1865, p. 206j
Special Orders No. U9, April 3, l865, p. 227 j Special Orders No. 10,
January 13, l86$, p. 209j Lawrence to Daxi^ty, September 2, l861i, p.
l83j Special Orders No. 65, August 2li, l861i, p. 179; Lawrence to
Stiles, August 17, 1861^, p. i5j Houghtaling to Jeffers, Atigust 5, I863,
p. 5} Circular, April 2, I863, p. 29U.
19
Mahan, pp. lOU-05; Scott, p. 320.
^endenhall to Brannan, January Iht 1861^, in OR, vol. 32, pt. 2,
pp. 93-91.
- 10 -
By the end of the war, the large fort was deteriorating at an
accelerating rate despite the efforts of the garrison. The scarps
and exterior slopes of the parapets of the redoubts had lost much of
their original slope, settling to a forty-five-degree slope. The para-pets
of the main line had begvm to fall, assisted tty the freeze-thaw
cycle of winter. Lxmette Thomas had about thirty feet of fascine
21
revetment lying on the ground. The fort, considered surplvis, was
finally put to rest In i^ril 1866, when it was abandoned by the United
States Army.
Fortress Rosecrans (fig. 80, appendix A), over two hundred acres
In size, was an irregular, semipermanent work composed of lunettes
connected by curtains and abatis forming a series of bastion fronts.
The outer line or body of the place contained eleven lunettes that
performed as independent forts providing both direct and flank fires.
Between the lunettes were curtains and numerous sally ports with
their fronts protected by abatis. Beyond the ditches of the fort were
three detached works, two demi-lunettes and one redan, located on
prominent hills that commanded the Interior of the fort. Within the
interior of the fort were four redoubts and one lunette which functioned
as keeps to the defense. The outer line was designed to provide cross
fires from the lunettes to the flanking Ixmettes, and the indented
lines were capable of delivering cross fires to the flanks of the
adjacent limettes and direct fires to the front. The gorges of the
lunettes and rear of the curtains were left open for the interior
works to fire into if overrun by the enemy.
2lTower to Thomas, April 28, l865, in ^ vol. k9t pt. 2,
pp. 502-03.
^^"Military Posts," Section R, p. 371.
- u -
Lunettes Thcnas and MoCook and Redoubts Johnson, T.J. Wood,
Schofleld, and Brannan contained cross-shaped blockhouses that pro-vided
a final stron^old in the event the works were overrun.
Rectangular blockhouses were placed in the interior work Lunette
Sheridan and outer works Lunette Negley, Lunette Stanley, which
contained two blockhouses, and Battery Mitchell. However, sane maps
show Lunette Palmer and Lunette Reynolds each containing a rectangular-shaped
blockhouse and Ltmette Stanley without any blockhouses (figs.
bO and tJl, appendix A). Every limette and redoiibt contained one anall
magazine except for Lunette Granger and Lunette Crittenden, neither of
which had a magazine, and Redoubt Brannan, which had a large
magazine.
The interior arrangements of the fort (figs. BO and Bl, appendix
A) contained warehouses full of military sipplies and food for the
T'he lunettes, demi-lunettes, batteries, and redoubts of Fortress
Rosecrans were named after brigade, division, and corps commanders of
the Army of the Cumberland: Redoubt Brannan, Brig. Gen. John M.
Brannan; Lunette Crittenden, Maj. Gen. Thomas J. Crittenden; Battery
Cruft, Brig. Gen. Charles Cruft; Demi-Lunette Davis, Brig. Gen. Jeffer-son
C. Davis; Demi-Lunette Garfield, Brig. Gen. James A. Garfield;
Lixnette Gordon Granger, Maj. Gen. Gordon Granger; Redoubt Johnson,
Brig. Gen. Richard W. Johnson; Lunette McCook, Maj.Gen. Alexander
McDaniel McCook; Battery Mitchell, Brig. Gen. Robert B. Mitchell;
Lunette Negley, Brig. Gen. James S. Negley; Lunette Palmer, Brig.
Gen. John M. Palmer; Lunette Reynolds, Brig. Gen. Joseph J. Reynolds;
Lunette Rousseau, Maj. Gen. Lovell H. Rousseau; Redoubt Schofield,
Brig. Gen. John M. Schofield; Lunette Sheridan, Brig. Gen. Philip H.
Sheridan; Lunette Stanley, Brig. Gen. David S. Stanley; Lunette Thcnas,
Maj. Gen. George H. Thomas; Redan Van Cleve, Brig. Gan Horatio P.
Van Cleve; Redo\ibt Wood, Brig. Gen. Thomas J. Wood; Battery Turchin
near the depot. Brig. Gen. John B. Turchin; Fortress Rosecrans, Maj.
Gen. William S. Rosecrans.
^^lendenhall to Brannan, January lli, I863, in OR, vol. 32, pt. 2,
p. 93; Tower to Thomas, i^ril 28, l865, in OR, vol.l^, pt. 2, p. 502.
- 12 -
embattled amy at the front. The depot-fort was funaiahed with
three coimnlssary depots , a qtiarter-naster depots two ordnance
depots, an engineer warehouse and depot, and a large ell-shaped
magazine. Timber for railroads, buildings, and blockhouses was
prepared at the fort by fo\ir steam-powered sawmills. War materials
and st^Ues were brou^t into the fort and shipped out by the rail-road
with loading accessories connected to a railroad spur and two
side tracks.
The site of Fortress Rosecrans has changed drastically since
the Iftiited States government abandoned the fort following the close
of the war. The pop\ilation and economic growth of Murfreesboro,
Tennessee, has fostered widespread growth of both industry and
stiburbia over the old fortified grounds of the two-hundred-acre
svpply depot (fig. 82, appendix A). The once-enclosed earthen fort-ress
has become a victim to the urban sprawl which has taken grip
throughout the nation since World War II. Of the approximately four-teen
thousand linear feet of parapets which formed the perimeter of
Fortress Rosecrans, only about three thousand feet of parapet and one
redoubt have survived the phenomenon of progress. The remaining para-pets
are confined to three areas; the city-owned Old Fort Park (fig.
83, appendix A) containing Lunette Palmer, Curtain No. 2, and portions
of Lunette Thomas j Redoiibt Brannan owned by the Naticmal Park Service;
and sections of Limette Negley along Manson Pike vhLch are privately
owned. One other section of earthworks is still extant but not included
in the above figures because it was never completed and was soon
abandoned after initial construction by the army. Approximately 1,025
feet of parapet were partially constructed from the salient of
Ltmette Thomas and in front of its right face. This line, except for
- 13 -
alx&gt;ut 225 feet ^^ilch were destroyed "by a park road. Is located
in the city park.
14
APPENDIX A
^, m
,;&#8226;.&#171; V-.. . ,, .'0,t* -
.';
. :,
. ..
.
...&#8226;;,'... /!' . r^ ^^
-&#8226;!
&#8226;H
i'^,3^:
&gt; t&#163;
&lt; c
.- 7i
c -o
c: &#8226; z ^
w E
tl 7.
:3 c
c c
APPENDIX A
16
'k-.l^i^
mi.
in
CD
00 bn
a
E
\ \ I r ; &#187; ' ''V r = =^- ^ ;/ x**&gt; '\*^
pm.
mc:
^SSSftj^ \\^'i'^
&lt;
&#8226;J)
w
l-&gt; &gt;
00 c!
r=3- '-^ -P
*i^Ji^
-^;ri;:?%^;^;//;a\::;&lt;^^5
0)
o
3 in
o r- w
+j
a'
0)
K
APPENDIX A 17
18
APPENDIX A
E &#8226;
o c c
C'-. -rJ
C-rJ O
&#187;- /. a; =
o
a
^ iiir
w
w
0)
u
&#8226;p
o
o
p
c
o
r-l
fl4
19
APPENDIX A
- 20 -
APPaJDIX B
DEFENSE WiAN OF FORTRESS ROSECRANS
MEMOIR
E^qplaining the Situation and Defense
of
FORTRESS ROSECRANS
Illustrated By
PLAN OF WORKS AND MAP OF VICINITY
Prepared for the use of the Commandant. According to Art.
8U2, Rev. Reg., by Order of MaJ. Gen. W. S. Rosecrans,
U. S. Army, Ccxnd'g Army of the Cumberland
By J. St. Clair Morton Brig. Gen., and Chief Engineer,
Army of the Cumberland
Fortress Rosecrans
Printed at the Pioneer Press
1&#171;63
- ZL -
APFQIDIX B
MEMOIR
1st. At no time of day or night, is any one of the Blockhouses
to be occ\5)ied by less than hO effective men, the doors being habit-ually
kept closed and barredj not less than half a regiment should be
constantly witMn each Lunette of the outer line, day or night.
2nd. The regiment or compaxxy designated for the garrison of any
particular Lunette or Redoubt should continue to garrison that partic-ular
work throughout. Exception may however be made of the garrisons
of the exterior detached wolies (see table) idiich being furnished
from regiments permanently posted close at hand, may be occasionally
changed in ordinary times, and even during a siege or blockade every
night. The artillery troops will habitually canip within the works
to which their pieces respectively belong.
This article and the preceding one are of more importance to be
observed than all the rest.
3d. The pickets, scouts, videttes and mounted patrols are to be
furnished out of the reserves; the pickets should be stationed not less
than a thousand yards from the works.
iith. The sortie passages of the main line of fortifications are
designed to admit, or give exit to, large masses of our own troops,
in case of a general engagement taking place i^jon or near the position;
and, in case of more than two divisions forming the garrison, to
enable the defence to assume an active character; therefore, the
garrison being of but one division, all the sortie passages should be
carefully closed with abattis, or otherwise obstructed: at the points
where the railroad and pike enter and leave the works, barricades of
some description, such 3.3 wagons loaded with stone or earth, should be
kept handy to close the gaps.
5th. Each Lunette and Redoubt should be considered a fort in
itself, and its commander be held responsible that it offers a vigorous
resistance to the enerty; which means that the garrison hold their
ground, \mder all circximstances, except being overpowered in hand to
hand conflict with the bayonet.
6th. It is presumed that any one of the main Lunettes will not
be surrendered, or evacuated, until its artillery fire and that of the
collateral Ltmettes has been completely over-powered and silenced by
that of the enemy, and their parapets so rained by the enemy's bom-bardment
as to cease to afford shelter except for sharpshooters. Even
then new parapets, traverses and merlons should be constructed by the
garrison, which ought to labor at night, assiduously, to that end.
When, notwithstanding the utmost efforts of the garrison to keep one
or more pieces of artillery in the Lunette of attack and the collateral
Lunettes (so as to be enabled to fire grape and cannister at the
enemy's columns of attack), th^ are reduced to a musketry defence, it
must be understood that an obstinate resistance can yet be made, and
much loss inflicted upon the enemy before he can enter the Lunettes of
- 22 -
APPffllDIX B
attack. A vigilant watch is to be kept vipon his movements when affairs
have come to this pass. When his colionn of assault ^&gt;pears his
cannonade must shortly cease the disposable reserves of the fortress
are si^jposed to be massed under shelter, as near as circumstances will
permit to the Lunette of attacks&#8212;the moment the cannonade ceases on
the part of the enemy, they are to be marched out with the utmost
dispatch, so as to arrive at the contested point in time to reinforce
its garrison. The troops thus accumulated are e:q)ectad to resist the
enemy with the bayonet, and, even if driven out, should return to the
charge once or oftener, and attenqjt to regain possession.
7th. By disposable reserves, in the preceding article, is meant
all the troops designated as reserve of the garrison of the fortress;
the commandant may, if he sees fit, increase these reserves by such
troops as can safely be spared, for the time being, from such of the
works as are not likely to be assaulted simultaneously with the
Lunette of attack.
8th. It may happen that the commandant can dispose of a larger
force as reserves than can advantageously be assembled at the contested
point to meet the enemy's assaultj in that case, the troops in ex-cess
will be held in readiness, in some sheltered place close at hand,
to charge the enemy with the bayonet on his flank, at an opportune
moment during the assault, sallying without the works for that purpose;
or otherwise to charge him within the contested work, should he
succeed in driving out its defenders.
9th. It is probable that at this period of the siege the
artillery of the Lunette of attack will be in a raised condition, and
the ammunition mostly e;q&gt;ended; of course, should any pieces remain
serviceable, they should not be permitted to fall into the enemy's
hands, but must be spiked if they cannot be removed; and such powder
as remains should be removed or blown up. It may happen thei^ is
enou^ powder to spare to form a mine in the salient of the work, or
&#8226;under the breach; in which case the Chief Engineer should see that one
is prepared, and a Commissioned Officer detailed to explode it when it
may do most damage to the enemy.
10th. If, notwithstanding every exertion on tte part of the
defenders, the enemy gain and retain possession of the Lunette of
attack, its defaiders, and in some cases, the reserves, according to
the judgment of the Comriiandant, should retreat to the collateral
lunettes. The rear of the Lunette of attack having thus been \anmasked
by our troops, the Redovibts and Limettes of the inner line will, with-out
loss of time, open fire upon it from an the guns they can bring
to bear, and endeavor to dislodge the enemy before he can construct
his lodgement, and shelter himself from their view. (It is probable
that the enemy would have directed his artillery against the said
Redoubts and retired Lunettes for some days before making the assault,
but it is supposed that the Commandant of each has kept one piece in
reserve, having removed it from its platform to the most sheltered
part of the parade, and that at the moment of assault he has caused it
to be run into position.) Sijpposing that a Lunette is taken by regular
- 23 -
APPENDIX B
approaches, some five weeks must have elapsed since the commandant
ascertained it would be selected as the point of attack; this inter-val
should be employed by hhn^^bly in the construction of intrench-ments
within it, but also in coistructing batteries and rifle-pits
in its rear, or in strengthening the collateral Lixnettes and the
inner line of works, so as to oblige the enemy to take two Lunettes
at least l^y siege, and coiTq&gt;el him to silence the artillery fire of
at least two more before he can attack the inner line, and reduce
hira to the necessilgr of planting his batteries in the captured
Lunettes and approaching the inner line by the double sap.
nth. The enemy cannot well make an open assault, much less an
attack by regular approaches, without first making himself master of
the exterior detached works. These will therefore be regarded as
obstacles In his path, and should be held, with more or less obsti-nacy,
according to the jTidgment of the commandant; who will not main-tain
them at too great a loss of life, or send out too many troops
to resist the enemy's attack on them: he should however require
their garrisons to sustain the assault once at least, seeing that
they have a strong profile, and are flanked from the Lunettes of the
outer line by artillery; for which reasons the enemy will sustain a
considerable loss in the assault, and the garrisons will be enabled
to retreat without being pxirsued . As the interior of these works is
exposed to the view of tiie said Lunettes, the enemy will find it very
difficult to hold them; it may therefore happen that the garrison
may reoccvpy them once or oftener, and the enemy be obliged to make
repeated sacrifices before they fall permanently in his hands.
12th. The Commandant sho\ild carefully instruct all the commission-ed
and non-commissioned officers in the elementary principles re-lating
to the defence of the works from assault, as follows; that
whichever Lunette is attacked by the enemy, should be immediately
reinforced from the reserve; the collateral Lunettes, namely those on
the right and left of it, together with such others as have a view
of the ground over which the enemy must approach must likewise be
reinforced; the curtains connecting Lunettes Thomas and McCook,
Lunettes Thomas and Palmer, Stanley and Negley, will be manned also
from the reserve, with a line of skirmishers, or with one or more ranks
of infantry, according to the judgment of the commandant, and according
to their bearings on the point threatened to be attacked.
13th. The Lunette attacked repiases the enemy by its direct
fire of musketry and artillery; the collateral Lunettes and curtains
cross their fire in front of it. In case the eneny attack one of the
curtains, such curtain is to be strongly reinforced, as well as the
collateral Lunettes, and the enemy is met by the direct fire of the
cxirtaln, and cross fire from the said Lunettes; should a Lunette or
c\irtain be taken by surprise, or by night attack (owing to want of
vigilance or proper precautions^, the troops belonging to it should
retreat to the right and left, unmasking the captured work, so as to
permit the works of the inner line to open fire into it and to clear
the way for the reserve. Both the gunners and the infantry troops
should be carefully instructed to fire low, and to reserve their fire.
- 21; -
APPaiDIX B
in resisting an assatilt, till the eneny arrives in force within 600
yards of the point of attack. To this emd, marks will be establish-ed
in frcxit of each Lunette on a circumference 600 yards distance
from it; and the enemy should not be fired i^n except by sharp-shooters,
isitll the chief part of the assaulting column has approach-ed
within these marks.
The Block-^iouses cannot be taken by surprise, and will prevent
the surprise of the Redoubts and Lisiettes in which they are seated;
they will also be a security for the heavy artillery, which is not
posted habitually in any work not provided with a Block-house.
li^th. The Comnandant must chiefly apprehend, and guard against,
surprises and night attacks, by a proper system of pickets, scouts
and patrols. He must give the garrison confidence that the works
cannot be carried by assault, even by an amy, if the attack is
properly anticipated, and if it should ever happen that the Fortress
is cut off from its communications and invested by a powerful amy,
he should cause it to be understood that the place can hold out a
month or so, and that reinforcements can reasonably be expected with-in
that time.
15th. It is estimated that the Fortress, garrisoned and provided
with an armament as above specified, is capable of holding out eight
weeks at least, against a force of thirty thousand men, equipped with
a heavy siege train; and double that period against an army of sixly
thousand men, unprovided with a siege train. These estimate will
serve as a basis upon which to calculate, approximately, the resist-ance
that should be ejq&gt;ected of garrisons exceeding one division.
l6th. The squadron of cavalry supposed in the estimate to be-long
to the garrison, of one division, is desigied to furnish patrols
and videttes. By its means the Commandant can keep himself informed
of the positions and movements of the enemy. When the Commandant can
do so with perfect security, he may send out small foraging expedi-tions,
guarded by the squadron only, and with not more than two
con5)anies of infantry (with their arms J to load the wagons.
17th. The horses and mules belonging to the garrison, if of one
division, will consist of the cavalry horses, horses of officers en-titled
to be mounted, and sitfficlent animals for fifty teams, viz.,
three to each regiment. These will suffice for the ordinary require-ments
of the garrison. The Post Quarter Master's teams are, of course,
in addition to the garrison teams. The Post Quarter-^^aster will be
expected to reduce them to the minimum capable of doing the work. The
Post Quarter-Master teams, and such teams as may have arrived from
the rear or front, for the purpose of bringing up or carrying forward
siQ)plies, will be parked between the pike bridge and Murfrees' house,
near the river: the regimental teams, viz., three teams to each
regiment, and a proportionate allowance to the artillery, will park
according to regulation.
- 25 -
AP^aUDlX B
18 th. It may happen that the Coranandlng General, upon marching
forward with the an&#187;cr, will station a Ught division at the Fortress,
with Instructions to prevent cavalry raids upon the communications of
the amy with Nashville, and the Fortress itself. It is recommended
that such a division habitually encamp on the west side of Stone s
River, and nearly it, on the high grounds between the Wilkinson and
Franklin roads.
loth. The Cowraandant should cause his officers to study the
Revised Regulations of the Am^jr, Articles 793 to 850, relating to
sieges and the defence of fortified placesj also the following;
Extracts from "Regulations for the Care of Field
Works and the Government of their G.irrisois."
1st. It will be the duty of the Commanding Officer of each work
to provide for the care of the armament, and the safety and service-able
condition of the raagazdnes, ammunition. Implements, and equip-ments;
and, by frequent personal Inspections, to secure the observance
of the rules prescribed for this purpose.
2d. The Conmanding Officer will make himself acquainted with
the ^jproaches to his work, the distance to each ground between them
and his post, and the most probable points of attack \qx&gt;n it.
TABLES OF RANGES or DISTANCES for each point, and the correspond-ing
elevations In each case, according to the nature of the projectile,
with the proper length of time of the fuse when shell or case shot
are used, wiU be made out for EACH GUN, and furnished to the officer
and non-commissioned officer serving it. As these tables differ for
different kinds of guns, the same men should be permanently assigied
to the same piece.
3d. The projectiles should be used in their proper order. At a
distance SOLID SHOT; then shells or case-shot, especially if firing
at troops IN LINE. CANISTER OR GRAi-E IS ONLY FOR USE AT SHORT RANGES.
When columns are approaching, so that they can be taken in direction
of their LENGTH, or VERY obliquely, SOLID SHOT is generally the best
projectile, because of its greater accuracy and penetrating power. If
the COLUMN consists of cavalry, some shells or case-shot will be useful,
from the disorder their bursting produces among the horses. As to the
ABSOLUTE distances at which the projectiles must be used, they vary
with the description and calibre of the gun, and can only be ascertain-ed
by consulting the TABLE OF RANGES. The prcminent parts on the
approaches to the works should be designated, their distances noted,
and directions drawn up for the different kinds of ammunition to be
used at each gun when the enemy reaches them. D\inng the drills the
attention of the chiefs of pieces and gunners should frequently be
drawn to this subject.
Uth. Commanding Officers will pay special attrition (sic) to
the police and preservation of the works. AH filth will be pronptly
- 26 -
APt&#171;&#169;IX B
removed, and the drainage be pariicularly attended to. No one sho\ild
be allowed to walk on the pargets, nor move or ait upon the gabioxis,
barrels or sand bags that may be placed iqxjn them. When injuries
occur to the earth works, they shovild be repaired as quickly as
possible by the garrison of the work. If of a serious nature, they
should at once be reported to the Qngineer Officer in charge of the
work. ALL INJURIES TO THE MAGAZINES OR i-LATFORMS OF THE GUNS WILL
BE i'ROIieTLY REK)RTED AS SOON AS OBSERVED.
5th. No persons not connected with the garrison of tl-ie field
works will be allowed to enter them except such as visit them on
duty, or who have passes signed by conqiet^nt authority; nor will any
person, except commissioned officers, or those whose duty requires
them to do so, be allowed to enter the magazine, or touch the guns,
liieir inqjlements or equipments.
6th. The garrison can greatiy improve the work by sodding the
si^jerior (upper; slope of the parapet, and also the exterior or
OUTER slope, or by sowing grass seed on the si^jerior slope, first
covering it with surface soil. The grass covered or sodded portions
of the parapets, traverses, magazines, &lt;Scc., should be occasionally
watered in dry weatherj and the grass kept closely cut.
7th. The armament of a fort, having been once established will
not be changed except by the authority of the Commander of the District,
geographical department or anny corps.
APPQIDIX B
- 27 -
9&gt;
2 'Q &#187;&lt;
&#8226;p ^ g
II
^3
+&gt; -P
H CM
irpqoonj, Xiaq.^Ba ;5
spiBa s-^q-aimi-piBa
PTBTJoqos
uosuqof
Poo/1 T '1
iiemiBjg
UBpfjaqg
spxou^H
a9BIXBJ
neossnoH
t&#187;piB^^-fJO
JlooooH
9^q.9Un'I "^
n CO to P &#174; Coh
4)
TJ O
, g 0)
ftJO CO ^
a
0) ^
a) -P
bO-P 0) -H bC O 0)
to T3 01
(D H &#169; 0) a&gt;
t-i m E-i O Eh
O -c &#174; 2 Vi
</dc:description>
<dc:description>A chapter from an MTSU thesis titled "Civil War Fortification," this essay describes the history of Fortress Rosecrans during and after the Civil War, up to development in present day</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.); United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865; Rosecrans, William S. (William Starke), 1819-1898; Stones River National Battlefield (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Fortress Rosecrans; Military fortifications</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>27 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-02; mt2011-02-08</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication22ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/22</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>