<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>History Cripple Creek Presbyterian Church</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Youree, Pearl</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 7</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1940; 1976</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>19th century; 20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>74
HISTORY
CRIPPLE CREEK PRESBYTERIAN CHURCH
19^0
by Miss Pearl Youree
The records of the Cripple Creek Presbyterian Church were
destroyed by fire in the year 1927j a regrettable and irrepa-rable
losSj but from deeds and records of our sister churches.
Stones River and Hopewell, we have secured a partial outline
of the history of our beloved church.
The Church was organized either in l820 or l821 with the
following charter members who were dismissed from the Stone
River Church:
James Bowie Thomas Berry
Margaret Bowie Sarah Berry
Mary Bowie Francis Youree
Nancy Bowie Elizabeth Youree
Nancy Neely
Of these James Bowie and Thomas Berry were ruling elders.
It is not known positively where these first worshipped,
but it is known that a site of worship, very probably a log
school house, about one-half mile from the present building, was
used very soon after organization.
A church building was erected some time before 1830 a few
hundred yards across the creek from and directly in front of
the present building. The land upon which this first building
had already been erected was given by Richard Standridge, the
deed being written September l4, 183O, but not recorded until
1839. The elders who received the deed were Francis Youree
and John Neely.
The name of the church changed about this time to
75
Standrldge Church (generally mispronounced as Standard's)
whether from gradual usage of the donor's name or from deliberate
choice is not known, but supposedly the former. The name was
changed back to Cripple Creek about the first of this century
during the pastorate of the Rev. T. A. Patton.
We have no record of the disposition of either building
or land, but we do have in our possession a deed for two and
one-half acres, dated Feb. 24, I869, granted by William Patrick,
Benjamin Becton and wife, and Mary Becton to the elders of the
Cripple Creek Presbyterian Church, on the west bank of Cripple
Creek for the consideration of fifteen dollars ($15.00). In
that year, 1869, or very soon after, the present structure, a
one room wooden building 60 feet long, 4o feet wide, and 25
feet high was erected. Several improvements including a belfry,
pews, concrete steps, and other small items have been added
from time to time.
This church having branched from the Stones River Church
I it has kept rather closely associated with this church through-out
the years. We find various accoiints of some famous camp
meetings being held on McKnights Camp Ground, a plot of two or
more acres, well shaded with hugh beech trees. There these
meetings were held once or twice a year with a record of 535
conversions in I8 meetings, these uniting with the Hopewell,
Stones River, and Cripple Creek Churches, thus greatly strength-ening
these churches in numbers and faith. That was a time of
much manifest interest, sometimes as many as fifteen visiting
ministers attending during one meeting.
I
The first pastor of our church was Jesse Alexander, who
served the Murfreesboro Church; "Mr. Alexander was born January
76
15, 1781, in North Carolina, immigrating to Tennessee in October,
1802 and settling near Milton, in Rutherford County. He was
licensed to preach September 2, l8l4 by Shiloh Presbytery and
was ordained pastor of Stones River and Hopewell Churches April
7, 1817. He also served the Cripple Creek Church. Mr.
Alexander's labors continued over a period of the churches men-tioned.
He lost his eyesight and for many years the blind
preacher was a familiar sight with his saddle-bags and Bible
as he rode on Sundays to fill his appointments, and his faith-ful
horse v/as his only guide. The horse knew where to carry
his master and never failed to keep the right appointment. He
also know where the most cordial welcome awaited them and would
draw up and stop at the gates of the members who loved to
entertain the preacher."
In the unpublished record of the Hopewell Church we find
that this godly man departed this life June 15, I863 still in
the service of these Churches.
We also find from the above mentioned records that four
years prior to Mr. Alexander's death the Stones River and Hope-well
Churches had belonged to Shiloh Presbytery which did not
withdraw from the General Assembly of the United States of
America in common with most other Southern Presbyteries, but
dissolved by a vote of its own body in April, I859. These
churches then attached themselves to North Alabama Presbytery
sometime before I872, that being the first date this presbytery
is mentioned in the record.
When our church was left without a pastor because of Mr.
Alexander's death, several visiting ministers came to her
felief over a period of four years, one of which, the Rev.
77
H. C. Smith served almost two years. The others mentioned at
this time were the Reverends Matt Marshall, A. Hradshaw, and
E. T. Brantley. We were unable to secure any date on the lives
of these men.
In the fall of 1867 the Rev. M. A. McFeaters, a man of
consecration and piety and very quick in his denunciation of
any evil, was called as stated supply, serving more than three
years
.
The Rev. Robert Caldwell, a man of mighty qualities for good,
was chosed as the next shepherd of this small flock. However,
duties called him elsewhere and he remained with our church
but one year, beginning March ^ , I87I.
Rev. &#165;. L. Rosser, whose worth was already known and
attested by results in previous series of meetings on the camp
ground and in the church group, began a nine year ministry in
this group in May, I872. This period was characterized by much
religious activity and in an increase in the prosperity of the
church.
He was the father of Miss Ray Rosser who for several years
has been the beloved teacher of Bible at Monroe Harding Home.
In December, 1881 Rev. George E. Thompson was called as
stated supply but was ordained in September, 1882. This young
man came to us shortly after graduation from Southwestern
Presbyterian University at Clarksville and Union Theological
Seminary at Hampden-Sidney, Virginia.
The records of Hopewell state that this young man was
employed to give that church one-half his time at a salary of
$225. We suppose that he divided the other half between Cripple
Creek and Stones River. He labored in this field for a period
78
of seven and one-half years.
After being without a pastor from May, I889 until October,
1889, the Rev. J. W. Mosely served almost two years as stated
supply.
The group was then without a pastor for almost a year.
In April, I892 Rev. A. J. Crane, a licenciate of Knoxville
Presbytery canvassed the field and was called for a pastorate
of ten years.
The Rev. T. A. Patton came to this field as stated supply,
remaining five years. The following is taken from an obituary
published in the Christian Observer and written by Rev. A. S.
Allen: "Rev. T. A. Patton was born September, 23, I867, and
died September 10, 1924. At the age of sixteen he joined the
Mt. Vernon Presbyterian Church in Wilson County, Tennessee.
Here he grew to young manhood, and at the age of twenty- six
married Miss Sallie Louisa Turney. To this union were born
twelve children, ten sons and two daughters. One of the girls
died in infancy.
After he was married and several children had come into
the family he felt a strong call from God to preach the gospel
of Christ. And at a great sacrifice and inconvenience to
himself and family, he with his family moved to Clarksville,
Tennessee, to prepare for his life work. Here he took both
literary and theological courses in Southwestern Presbyterian
University.
He began his ministry in Asheville Presbytery, N.C, In
Sept. of 1901. His field of labor was Bryson City and Dillsboro,
In March, 1903j he was called to the Milton group in the Presby-tery
of Nashville. This group was composed of Milton, Stones
79
River, and Cripple Creek. He served the Milton group until I908;
when he was called to take charge of the Monroe Harding Chil-dren's
Home, Nashville, Tenn. After one year's service at this
institution he was called back to the Milton group
In October, 1923, he was called to take charge of the
Watertown group of churches in the Presbytery of Nashville.
This group is composed of Buffalo Valley, Mt. Olivet, Mt.
Vernon, and Spring Creek. He was now back in the field of his
childhood and a young manhood, a happy man. His health soon
gave way to a ravaging disease and he rapidly declined to the
day of his death, September 10, 1924."
It was during his pastorate that our belfry was built and
the bell for the belfry was bought and installed. The money
for these improvements was secured through the efforts of Mr.
Patton who bought pigs and gave them out to the boys and girls
of the church who fed and sold them and gave the proceeds to
the church.
There has never been a more highly esteemed or better
beloved pastor on this field than this Godly man.
During the year of Mr. Patton' s service at Monroe Harding
Home, our group was served a few months by Rev, A. A. Dubois,
a Baptist minister, who had united with the First Presbyterian
Church of Nashville, and came to this field on the recommenda-tion
of his pastor. Dr. William Anderson. In September, I908,
he left us to enter Southwestern University under the care of
Presbytery as a candidate for the ministry.
The Rev. R. Q. Riley became our pastor in March, 1911?
remaining until I919. This good man was very faithful in carry-ing
out his pastoral duties. His old horse, John, and the buggy
80
with the back curtain rolled up in summer, or with a storm apron
tightly fastened on in winter, became a familiar and beloved
sight moving about the countryside. He was the power behind
the throne when our pews were remodeled, a carpet bought, and
the church painted on the outside.
Mr. Riley was born January 24, I865 in Kosciusko,
Mississippi. He received his education in French Camp Academy
and Southwestern, graduating from the latter in June, l894,
leaving there to begin his first pastorate the first Sunday in
July. He served his church in five states over a period of
forty- five years. He is now retired and living in Memphis.
In 1920 Rev. J. G. Johnson began an eighteen month pastor-ate
of this group, which now included Woodbury. He made his
home there as all the succeeding pastors have done. Mr. Johnson,
the eldest of seven children, was born in Choctaw County,
Alabama, September 8, 1868, but moved with his parents in infancy
to West Station, Mississippi, where he spent his early years
attending the free schools and helping with the expenses of the
large family. At the age of twenty-six he left home to begin
three years preparatory work in French Camp, Mississippi. He
was then in Southwestern four years. He has been preaching
since I902 when he began his work in Dickson ans Waverly. He
is now pastor of the Madison Church. On December 20, 1905 he
married Miss Isabelle Hopkins Boyd of Covington. To this union
two sons were born.
We were without a pastor for some months after Mr. Johnson
left. He was succeeded by the Rev. W. W. Patton who was here
four years 1923-1927. As have been so many of our pastors, he
was a graduate of Southwestern, It was during his ministry
ai
that concrete steps were erected at the front entrance. Mr.
Fattens wife was Miss Laura Neil, who with thi-ee cliildren survive
him, sinc^e his death in 1936 at Watertown, his ;:hildhood home.
After Mr. Patton left us to go to Alabana, he was followed
by Claude C. Williams, a young man who had come into the U.S.
L Church, from the U.S.A. Church. He served as stated supply
for some months during I928-I929, never being received into the
Nashville Presbytery.
Our present pastor, the Rev. W. H. Matheson began his work
in our midst in October of I929. He is a man of integrity,
very kind and gentle. In his sermons he presents God's word
in its truth and simplicity. He is held in the highest esteem
I
by every denomination.
Mr. Matheson is a native of North Carolina. His education
I was received at Davidson College and at Union Theological Semi-nary
in Richmond, Virginia.
He was licensed to preach May 20, 1927 by Concord Presby-tery
and ordained June 19, 1927 in Mecklenburg Presbytery. His
first pastorate of two years was Thomasboro, North Carolina.
In 1927 he was married to Miss Laura Barclay, the daughter
of a Presbyterian minister. Mrs. Matheson has been very active
in church work, being Presbyterial Secretary of Young Peoples
Work in I928 in Mecklenburg Presbytery. She taught vacation
church schools in the synod for two years after moving here.
Mr. and Mrs. Matheson have one child, Alice Barclay, born
in November, 1937.
Our grouping has been changed this year, 1939? because of
distances. Our group now consists of Stones River, Cripple
Creek, Woodbury, Rock Island, and a new church. Amity, which
82
was organized through the efforts of Mr. Matheson and Mrs. M. B.
McCrary, a member of the Woodbury Church.
The Departments of Our Church
The Sunday School
The Church School should ever be a very Important depart-ment
of any church and has been so in our church. Cripple
Creek has always supported an evergreen Sunday School even
though its membership has ranged from twenty-five to now more
than sixty. J. D. Youree served as superintendent for many
years. How well I remember, although a small child, his oft
repeated prayer, "Hasten the time when the knowledge of the
Lord shall cover the earth as the waters cover the sea."
The Godly man was succeeded by W. M. Vaught a Baptist
in our midst who was kind enough to help out when leadership
was needed and none seemed to be forthcoming from the Presby-terians
.
J. L. Burks, Bryan Lyon, a young man who died in service,
Searcy Coffy, Tennyson Youree, and Craig Youree have served
as superintendents during the years since 1920.
The Auxiliary
The women organized some time before 1912 as the Ladies'
Aid. Miss Pearl Youree was president when the name Ladies'
Aid was changed to the Auxiliary. They later disbanded but
have been reorganized twice since, the last time in 1936.
The officers at this time were: President, Mrs. W. H.
Matheson; Secretary, Miss Mae Caffy; and Treasurer, Mrs. Tom
B. Youree.
The present executive board consists of the following:
President, Miss Pearl Youree; Vice-president, Miss Mae Caffy;
83
Secretary, Miss Maggie Sue Youree; Treasurer, Miss Maggie Sue
Youree; Circle Chairman, Mrs. Tom B. Youree; Secretaries of
Causes are; Spiritual Life, Miss Mae Caffy; Foreign Missions,
Miss Kate Walkup; Assembly's Home Missions, Mrs. F. C. Youree;
S. and P. Home Missions, Mrs. Tom B. Youree; Religious Educa-tion,
Miss Pearl Youree; Christian Education and Ministerial
Relief, Miss Mae Caffy; Pastor's Aid, Mrs. Ray Walkup; Christian
Social Service, Mrs. Tom. B. Youree; Historian, Mrs. Tom B.
Youree.
There being fourteen places to fill and only eight active
members, there had to be some doubling and tripling in order
to carry out the work of the auxiliary.
&#165;e meet twice a month, the first Thursday in the month
as a circle and the third Thursday as an auxiliary. Though
few in number we try to witness for Christ remembering that
he said, "It is not by might nor by power, but by my spirit
saith the Lord."
The Young People
There once was a Christian Endeavor in the Church. We
don't have any records to show the years.
There being so few juniors and young people and more inter-mediates
we grouped them into one organization in April 1939,
using the pioneer literature with the following officers:
President, Virginia Trott; Vice-president, Dorothy Fox; Secre-tary
and Treasurer, Edna Falkner; Adult Advisor, Miss Pearl
Youree.
The present officers are: President, Edna Falkner; Vice-president,
Irene Smith; Secretary-Treasurer, Fred Walkup;
Adult Advisor, Miss Pearl Youree.
84
Daughters of the Church who have married Ministers
Miss Sue Belle Youree, the daughter of William Hall and
Jimmie llerrick Youree, was married to Rev. E. C. Brainard.
At that time Mr. Brainard was pastor of the Watertown
group of churches remaining there two years. They then moved
to Norwood, Louisiana and from there to Humbolt, Tennessee
where Mrs. Brainard died following an operation in I919.
After three years he was married to Miss Maud C. Youree, a
half sister of the first Mrs. Brainard. They are now serving
the church of Welsh, Louisiana. They have one daughter, Sara
Evelyn.
In July, 1910, Miss Lizzie Youree, daur.hter- of James I'^rancis
and Sallie Nelson Youree was married to the Rev. C. N. Ralston.
He was engaged in Sunday School work in Columbia Presbytery
at the time. He was superintendent of Purdy Missions School
in Memphis Presbytery for several years, moving from there to
Ripley, Miss, where he and Mrs. Ralston are ministering to five
mission churches.
Miss Annie Youree, daughter of William Hall and Sallie
Craig Youree married Rev. J. B. Butler in 1916. He was pastor
of Bethel Springs group of churches in McNairy County. They
later moved to Fausdale, Alabama, and are now living at Hobbs
Island, Alabama. Mr. Butler has recently resigned because of
loss of health.
Miss Pearl Youree
Historian
By Mrs. J.O.J.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Presents a partial history of the Cripple Creek Presbyterian Church from records of sister churches Hopewell and Stones River Presbyterian</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.) -- History</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>churches; Cripple Creek Presbyterian Church; Presbyterianism</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Kittrell</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>21 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-15</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication07ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/130</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>