<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>The Jenkins home in Rutherford County</dc:title>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 19</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1982</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>18th century; 19th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>59
THE JENKINS HOMES in RUTHERFORD COUNTT
by- Rosalind Manson James
A WILL probated in Greene Coun-ty, Ohio, 11 November 1807 (quote)
"Item 5, I give to n^ sons Hiram Jenkins and Nij&amp;rod Jenkins nineteen
htmdred and twenty acres of land in the State of Tennessee to be
divided in the same manner that I directed it lAen I was there, ex-clTisive
of what they have had, to them and to their heirs and assigns
forever. October U, l807" signed/Aaron Jenkins
This WILL of 1920 acres really started the fun! Where did Aaron
who was only a private in John Guthray's Class Roll (c) First Battalion
Washington County, Pa MLlltia during the Revolution, get this Tennessee
property? Well, since I960 there have been "cousins" from Los Angeles,
California; Fbrtsmouth, Ohio; Mocha Bend, Mlsso\iri; Harrisburg, Pa. and
me here in Rutherford County searching for verification of that bequest.
The court house has been beseiged and volumes of records copied and all
has been enjoyed.
I have found that we "Jenkinses" are numerous and inquisitive. We
have docTznentation of ptirchase liy the inmigrants of property in Pa. and
Virginia since 1752 so the "cousins" came to document the Tennessee
property.
We took them to see "Marymont" and from that beautiful antebellum
home which is still in the family and from this they "advertized" to all
interested "cousins" arotmd the country.
What they didn't know until they toured the county and copied wills
and coiirt records of the ntinerous law suits at the Cotrt House Just how
the beautiful "Marymont" evolved.
60
The stoxy Is slnple- For Revolutionary service Aaron II (Aaron I
was from Frederick County, Virginia) received 610 acres for service and
probably bought adjoining grants.
"In 1799 Aaron and his wife Rebecca Baldwin Jenkins and five of their
children moved from Pettis County, Missouri settling on Stones River near
Murfreesboro in Rutherford County. Rebecca died enroute 17 May 1799 and
was buried at Crab Orchard, Kentucky. Aaron returned to Pennsylvania
and married Charity Harlan Garwood, a Quakeress. During his absence,
his sons killed and assisted in killing fifty-two bears. In vhLch the
country greatly abounded."
"In 180U, Aaron and Charity with their famlly-wlth the exception of
sons, Hiram and Nimrod, returned to Ohio to land purchased in 1799 from
Albert Gallatin."
It was Nimrod and Ifi.ram who built the first Jenkins house on the
northeast part of the "Marymont" property. It is still staisdlng (just
off the lane leading to the old Klngwood property).
The two large rooms were well built of brick with good features of
deep window slUs, large twelve paned windows, a chimney at each end,
and a porch across the front with small round pillars.
A story is told in the family of how one night a rec\irrent dream
disturbed Nimrod so he got ip and went back to where there was a very
deep spring and there burled their hoard of gold. When he returned to
the house he found that thieves had ransacked the place.
This house was the beginning of a series of fine Jenkins homes in
otir community.
Nimrod never married but his brother Hiram I married Deborah
Allison, ( Davidson County Marriage Book), May 31&gt; I803. Since Ruther-ford
County was created from Davidson County in I803 they probably
61
Married here. He built his hams an the Hanson Pike (then not named
perhaps) and there reared a large family. That house burned and the
old graveyard was destroyed but I rescued two tall marble markers
from Mr. Martindale's bam (later owned b7 Frank Wanack) and had these
placed in the Jenkins lot in Evergreen Cemetery. They marked the graves
of Hiram Jenkins, Jr. who was bom in Fayette County, Peimsylvania,
February 21 , 1780 and moved to Tennessee in the year 1797 and died 10
October 1857.
"Blessed are the pure in Hart for they shall
see God"
(and the other)
In memory of Nimrod Jenkins
Bom in Pettis Co, MLssourl
Septr. 22
1822
Died in Rtitherford Co.
Tenn Dec 13
1855
Nimrod Jenkins was united in marriage with
Jane W. Moore
of Rutherford Co., Jan 18, l85U
and closed his earthly career
Dec 13, 1855
"Blessed are the dead which
die in the Lord from henceforth
Yes saith the spirit they
may rest from their labor and
their works do follow them.
Nimrod I never married. He left a WILL which caused many lawsuits
(see Rutherford County court records) . But ny ancestor Nimrod II (named
for his uncle) married January l8, l85ii-Jane Woodson Moox&#171; and they had
two daughters. Mazy Jane (Jenny) and Nimmie (named for her father iriio had
died shortly before her birth). He had built a house, however, on the
Jenkins property which he had inherited across the lane (later named
Gresham Lane) from his father's place on Ihe Manson Pike. After his
death '*Mlttie," as she was called married Captain Amossa Gresham and
62
Original Jenkins home built about iSO? on "Marymount
"
property om Rucker lane.
James Jenkins home on IVIanson Pike built by Hiram Jenkins
Sr. and owned by Robert Martindale in I969.
63
there they reared their large family. This home was used duxdng the
Battle of Stone's River as a hospital and was known as the "Greshan
Place.'* This hone remained in the family until in the early 1930*s&#187;
^en it was sold to Mr. Allen Ragland. Ownership changed se-veral times,
it burned, and now among the large oaks and maple trees is a modem brick
home owned by Mr. Thomas Lane.
Another Jenkins home was almost directly across from the Gresham
place and also the Frank Womack place (fozner Hiram Jenkins hone,
identical in architecture to the Nimrod Jenkins place) was Jennie
Jenkins Manson's place. It was a typical Victorian home with tall
windows across the front and a vestibule style entry. Ceilings were
high, rooms were large and the "parlor" had a black marble mantel and
black iron fireplace. Around the high walls were enlarged family
photographs. This home also is gone, the interstate intersects the
property and another land mark is gone.
A smaller, but sturdy brick house down the road toward the city of
Murfreesboro still stands, a pretty Jenkins home. Hiram Jenkins II gave
his dau^ter Alice Jenkins this home when she married Mr. H. H. Kerr,
but when she died in 1870 he sold it. It reminds us however, that homes
built sturdily, thou^ stonas and disasters came, they remain - as the
first Jenkins two-room house on "Marymont" property, the Hiram or James
Jenkins house on Manson Fike, and "MarTmont" itself.
"Marymont" was built by Hiram Jenkins II (brother of Nimrod H) and
his wife Nancy Puckett while he was guaztlian for the infant dau^ters of
Nimrod, Jennie and Nimnde. This is on the other end of the Jenkins
property and was the property inherited by Niimie Jenkins who married Dr.
James J. Rucker, and was named for their only surviving child, Mary. It
was greatly embellished about the time of Mary's marriage to R. E. Donnell
64
ly the addition of the Corinthian columns. All of the children of the
fasUy Uked to visit there and ride Dr. Rucker's horses and see and
lay around the deer park kept by Dr. Ruoker for Mary. It still stands
and Is a reminder to us to protect and preserve.
May we always keep alive our Interest In our Jenkins &#171;cou8lns" and
always cqspreclate what our forbears did to enrich our lives and the lives
of our progeny.
65
Dr. James E. I^lanson son James E. I/lansons home on Manson Pike.
House now gone and site occupied by Bascom Williamson house.
Jennie Jenkins Manson , Virginia Bagwell &amp; Findley Hudgens are
in the picture.
The Jenkins home on the Manson pike &amp; Gresham lane.
In the field v/as the former home of Hiram 1 .It burned.
66
Jenkins - Gresham house on T/Ianson Pike. Built about 1^50 &amp; usee
as a hospital in Battle of Stones River.
Maryraount- Home of Mary Rucker Donnell. Built about
lS6l by Hiram Jenkins on Rucker Lane</dc:description>
<dc:description>A history of the Jenkins home, "Marymont"</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>historic homes; family histories</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>8 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-08</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication19ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/129</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>