<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Rutherford County, Tennessee, will abstracts</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Daniel, Susan G.</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 17</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1981</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1800-1809; 1810-1819</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>47
RUTHERFORD COUNTY. TENNESSEE WILL ABSTRACTS
by
SUSAN G. DANIEL
1. Record Book 1, Page 72 - Will of John Ford of Burke County -
Date of Will: 2? October 1804 Recorded: 12 January 1809
Wife: Judith Ford "Leave to": Children "Leave also to":
John Payne, Charles Duncan Executors: Jacob Ford, James
Ford (friends) Witnesses: Sally Payne, Lucinda Payne, John
Godfrey.
2. Record Book 2, Page 6 - Will of Jeremiah Thacker of Davidson
County, TN - Date of Will: 7 October 1803 Recorded: 12 April
1804 Wife: Mary Ann Thacker daughter: Gashandy son: Siar
Thacker son: Larkin Thacker "my ^ children": Charles,
Ursellus, Larkin, Cashandy Thacker Executors: wife and son,
Larkin Thacker Witnesses: John L. Jetton, Jonathan Rucker,
Henry Rucker William Payne owed money to estate and the land
of Cummins was mentioned.
3. Record Book 2, Page 7 - Will of Isaac Barr of Rutherford County,
TN - Date of Will: 10 March 1804 (No filing or recording date)
Executor and wife: Elizabeth "my 4 children": Enoch, Robert
Steel, Isaac Ross, and Mariah slaves: Simon, Pat ( to be sold)
Witnesses: Robert Smith, William Smith.
4. Record Book 2, Page 12 - Will of Samuel Williams of Rutherford
County, TN - Date of Will: 2 December I8O5 Filed: 15 April
I8O6 Wife: Elizabeth "lawful children, until they shall
become of age" "a child I had by Betsy Tinker" "a child I
had by Nelly Buckridge" Executors: wife and Robert Williams
Witnesses: William Mitchell, Nancy Mitchell (when proved:
Executrix sworn, Executor dead)
.
5. Record Book 2, Page I6 - Contested will of John Price of
Rutherford County, TN - Date of Will: 17 January I8O6
Recorded: 29 September I8O6 Wife: Nancy Price daughter:
Polley Carr (not yet 18) Executors: wife and friend, Joseph
Dickson Witnesses: John Dickson, Henry Davis.
6. Record Book 2, Page 18 - Will of John Cason of Prince Edward
County, VA - Date of Will: 20 June I806 Recorded: 5 November
I8O6 brother: Seth Cason sister: "money in hands of Elisha
Bennett upon Thomas Huddleston to" Susanna Adcock and her chil-dren
sister: "paid out money in hands of Thomas Armstrong to"
Mary Arnold sister: Lucy Bennett, her children slave: Charles
to Lucy Bennett sister: Milly Armstrong and children slaves:
Rose and child, Wiatt to Milly Armstrong slave: Hannah to Seth
Cason "my sisters and sisters' children in Virginia" Named:
Edmond Harris Executor: friend, Edmond Harris Witnesses:
Ishajn Harris, William Hunter, Wilson Hunter.
43
7. Record Book 2, Page 21 - Will of Bradley Gambill of Rutherford
County, TN - Date of Will: 19 June 1806 Filed: 1806
son: Benjamin Gaunbill son: Metton (?) son: James son: Jordan
(unmarried) Wife: not named 2 youngest sons: Bradley and
Hourain or Hovram (?) daughgers: not named Executors: son,
Benjamin Gambill, Joseph Morton Witnesses: Bird Nance, William
Nance.
8. Record Book 2, Page 30 - Will of William Baker of Bedford County,
TN - Date of Will: 6 November 1806 Recorded: 20 August 180?
Wife: Martha Baker slave: Eve to wife daughter: Gemperance
"children": James, Mary, John and child my wife is carrying
Executors: wife, John Nail, John Baker Witnesses: Richard
Baily, Robert Baker, Jonathan Bailey.
9. Record Book 2, Page 32 - Will of John Tilly - Date of Will: 20
May 180? Recorded: ^ November 180? Wife: Jane slave: Rhodey
(female) to be free at wife's death Named: John Billingsly to
have J of land at wife's death Referred to in will: Robert
Bean, Thomas Blair, Doctor Jonathan Edwards Witnesses: Robert
Bell, Thomas Dougan Copy given to: William Wright.
10. Record Book 2, Page 35 - Will of Francis Wright of Rutherford
County, TN - Date of Will: 3 December 180? Recorded: 7 February
1808 Wife: Nancy "dear children": not named Executors:
wife and Jacob Wright Ramsey Witnesses: James D. Partrick,
Francis Youree.
11. Record Book 2, Page 36 - Will of William Robertson of Davidson
County, TN - Date of Will: 19 October 1802 Recorded: 7 Febrioary
1808 Wife: Nancy Robertson son: Matthew Robertson son:
Benjamin Robertson son: Samuel Robertson son-in-law: Thomas
Thornton daughter: Elizabeth (wife of Thomas Thornton) son-in-
law: John Kinkade daughter: Isbel Kinkade son: Joseph
Robertson son-in-law: William Plumber daughter: Margaret
Pliimber son-in-law: Moses Robertson daughter: Mary Robertson
son-in-law: George Buchanan daughter: Dinah Buchanan
Executor: son, .-Matthew Robertson Witnesses: John Buchanan,
William Philips.
12. Record Book 2, Page ^^ - Will of John Howell, Sr. of Rutherford
Goimty, TN - Date of Will: 16 December 1807 Filed: 20 April
1808 Wife: Sarah slave: girl, Shaw to wife On wife's death
equal shares to: William Howell, Gwin Howell, Nancy Nelson,
Peggy Whitsett son: Gwin Howell slave: man. Purse to Gwin
Howell slave: boy, Jerry to Gwin Howell son: William Howell
Named: James Whitsett, Thomas Nelson granddaughter: Patsy
McBride (not yet 16) slave: woman. Seel to Patsy McBride
Executors: James Whitsett, Thomas Nelson, William Howell
Witnesses: John Stockird, Sr. , Hugh Shearwood, Alexander Martin
Codecil : 4 January 1808/Filed: 20 April 1808 Wife: Sarah
son: Gwinn named: Nancy Nelson, Peggy Whitsett Witnesses:
John Stockird, Sr. , Hugh Shearwood, Alexander Martin.
49
13. Record Book 2, Page 60 - Will of Harrison Gilliam of Rutherford
Coimty, TN - Date of Will: 10 Jiane 1808 Recorded: 1? July 1808
slave: man, Anthony made free brother: Thomas Gilliam's children
Executors: William Gilliam, William Thweatt Witnesses: Rhoda
Benge, Polly Thweatt, Elizabeth Thweatt, Mary Tarpley.
14. Record Book 2, Page 62 - Will of Matthew Patton of Rutherford
County, TN - Date of Will: 16 September 1808 Filed: 14 October
1808 wife: Katen or Katea Patton daughter: Margarett
daughter: Rhodah "my children" (other than Margarett and Rhodah)
brother: James Patton Executors; wife and James Patton
Witnesses: John Ferguson, William Hajina, James Cochran.
15. Record Book 2, Page 64 - Will of James Morton of Rutherford
County, TN - Date of will: 28 January 180? Recorded: 21 November
1808 wife: not named son: Joseph slave: boy, Dennis to
Joseph named: "Joseph' s mother" son: James slave: boy.
Jack to James daughter: Judith slave: girl, Edy to Judith
daughter: Sally slave: Fanny, Gury Clary to Sally daughter:
Lucinda slaves: girls, Lucy, Sabry to Lucinda daughter:
Tabitha slaves: Isaac, Corbis, Winna to Tabitha slaves:
Daniele, Abraham, Ag, Rose to wife Executors: sons, Joseph
Morton and James Morton Witnesses: Thomas Shute, William Still
landowner mentioned: Allen Nance.
17. Record Book 2, Page 66 - Will of John Norman of Rutherford
County, TN - Date of Will: 12 November I8O8 Recorded: 12
January 1809 wife: Marget "the children when come to age
of maturity": not named Executors: wife and Theophiles Cannon
Witnesses: John Stockird, Jr., John Irwin.
18. Record Book 2, Page 82 - Will of Thomas Welch - Date of Will:
14 May I809 Filed: 11 July 1809 verbal will to James Norman
and witnessed on 18 May I809 Witnesses: James Caldwell,
Aaron Oliphant, Joseph Norman wife: Rachel 4 daughters:
Rachel Welch, Lydia Welch, Rebekah Welch, Catharine Norman
names: John Norman, husband of Catharine.
19. Record Book 2, Page 83 - Will of Francis McBride, Senior of
Rutherford County, TN - Date of Will 19 December 180? Filed:
20 October I809 oldest son: Isaiah McBride daughter: Martha
Simmons grandson: Francis McBride granddaughter: Martha L.
McBride (not yet I5) son: Samuel McBride Executors: James
Sharpe, Theophilus Cannon, Samuel McBride Witnesses: John
Stockard, David Magness
20. Record Book 2, Page 85 - Will of Elizabeth Davis of Rutherford
County, TN - Date of Will: 11 September 1809 Recorded: 30 October
1809 daughter: Elizageth Davis slave: girl, Silla to Elizabeth
son: Henry Bishop slave: boy, Sampson to Henry Bishop son-in
law: Robert Elliot son: William H. Davis slave: woman,
Dolle to William son-in-law: John Irwin Executors: John
Irwin, Robert Eliott Witnesses: Jajnes Sharp, Marcus Sharp,
Isabella Martin.
50
21. Record Book 2, Page 113 - Will of Major William Buckner, Jiuiior
of Sumner County, TN - Date of Will: 9 September 180? Filed:
3 June 1811 wife: Polly Buckner slaves: Winney, Nelly,
Austin, and Grace to be sold "my children": not named
Executors: friends, Edward Sanders, James Scinders Witnesses:
Wiley Lassiter, Austin McWade
22. Record Book 2, Page 11^ - Will of James Sharpe of Rutherford
County, TN - Date of Will: 30 September 1809 Filed: 3 June 1811
wife: Rachel Sharpe slaves: man, Moody; woman, Phillis to wife
"our children": not named son: Theophilus A. Sharpe (not yet
21) slaves: Candis, Amos, , George, Milton, Dorcas, Daniel, Marg,
Levi to Theophilus Sharpe eldest son: Marquis Sharpe slaves:
boy, Milton to Marquis Sharpe son: Alfred Sharpe slave: boy,
George to Alfred Sharpe son: John Sharpe slave: boy, Daniel
to John Sharpe slave: boy, Amos to Theophilus son: James
Morriss Sharpe slave: boy, Levi to James Sharpe daughter: Emma
Sharpe slave: girl, Candis to Emma Sharpe daughter: Peggy
Carlile (?) Sharpe slave: girl, Dorcas to Peggy Sharpe
davighter: Jemima Alexander Sharpe slave: girl, Nancy to Jemima
Sharpe slaves: Cordance, Amos, George, Milton, Dorcas, Daniel,
Nancy, Levi, first to wife then to children mentions "when
the boys are 20 years of age and the girls are 18 years of age"
Executors: friends, John Sharpe, Theophilus A. Gannon, Marquis
Sharpe Witnesses: Henry Bishop, William H. Davis, Theophilus
A . Cannon
Codecil : 1 December 1810/Filed: 3 June 1811 "prospect of
another legatee to be added to the family by my wife Rachel Sharpe"
Witnesses: Jeunes Martin, Nancy Wilson, John Sharpe, Theophilus
A. Gajinon landowners named: James Aspey, James Roseberry.
23. Record Book 2, Page I58 - Will of Edmund Johns of Rutherford
County, TN - Date of Will: 20 March 1811 Proven in part:
October session 1811 Recorded: 2^- February 1812 wife: Sarah
Johns brother: John slaves: man, Will; man, Joe; girl, Jane
(pregnant) to wife son: Jack Haden Johns son: Madison Johns
slave: girl. Clary to Madison son: Frederick Johns (gets Jane's
child when bom) daughter: Martha Johns slaves: girl, Abby;
boy, Sam to Martha Executors: wife and my brother, Abner Johns
Witnesses: Gross Scruggs, John Johns.
24. Record Book 2, Page I60 - Will of William Roberts of Rutherford
County, TN - Date of will: 21 October 1811 Recorded: 14 March
1812 wife: Nancy Roberts slaves: man, Harry to wife
daughter: Lucy daughter: Nancy son: Jessee slave: man,
Harry to Jessee (this slave might be the same as one to wife - sgd)
daughter: Betsy "other children not named in this will"
Witnesses: Toliver Simpson, William Simpson Executor: not named.
25. Record Book 2, Page I65 - Will of Hugh Prior Brawly of
Rutherford County, TN - Date of Will: 12 November 1811 Filed: not
shown wife: Ruth Brawly sons: Hugh, Levi, John, Prior
Executors: wife and son, John Brawly Witnesses: Joshua Barton,
John Bankhead, Dainiel Webb
Codecil: 12 November 1811 daughter: Polly Crownover daughter:
Ruth Brawly daughter: Gintha Brawly
51
26. Record Book 2, Page 184 - Will of William Loftin of Rutherford
Coimty, TN - Date of Will: 1? June 1811 Recorded: October term
1811 wife: Levina Loftin slaves: Matt and his wife, Sail;
woman, Darkis to wife then to son, Thomas son: Thomas Loftin
daughter: Polly Brothers slave: woman, Nelly to Polly Brothers
daughter: Elizabeth Cole slaves: woman, Tener; girl, Annebar
to Elizabeth Cole son: Eldridge son: William daughter:
Nancy Featherston slave: girl, Kirlinda to Nancy; boy, Jack
to Eldridge; girl, Mary to Levina; boy. Matt to Levina
daughter: Levina Loftin daughter: Lucy Loftin slave: woman,
Darkis to Lucy son: Henry slave: boy, Sam to wife
landowners named: Jajnes Johnston, Samuel Hcuids, James Higgins
Executors: wife and sons, William and Thomas Witnesses: Jessee
Featherston, James Barfield, A. Pearce.
2?. Record Book 2, Page 204 - Will of John Gasaway of Rutherford
County, TN - Date of Will: 5 December 1812 Filed: ?
wife: Peggy Gasaway my children: Elenor Gasaway, Thomas,
Nicholas, William, John, Patsy, Hannah Gasaway, Nancy Gasaway
Executor: George Furr Witnesses: William Bowman, Henry Ward,
Mordecai LiHard.
28. Record Book 2, Page 205 - Will of Jacob Stroup of Rutherford
County, TN - Date of Will: 15 August 1812 Filed: ? wife:
Elizabeth Stroup son: John Stroup (not yet 18) "my children
when they come of age" Executors: wife and friend, Abraham
Scriber Witnesses: George Wallace, Fielder Bevins.
29. Record Book 2, Page 214 - Will of John Smith of Rutherford
County, TN - Date of Will: 2? July 1812 Filed: 20 April 1813
Wife: Polly daughters: Betsy, Patsy, Anna, Polly (last three
not of age) son: James slaves: Bob, Dave, Silvey, Milly to
wife - Mary, Lydia to Betsy - Charles and Easter to Patsy -
Delph and Reuben to Anna - Jinny and George to James - Bill and
Silecy to Polly Executors: John Fulton, Joseph Morton, James
Morton Witnesses: Sajnuel Watkins, John Fulton.
30. Record Book 2, Page 226 - Will of Edward Eppes of Rutherford
County, TN - Date of Will: 24 August 1813 - Recorded: 8 November
1813 Wife: Rebecka Eppes "my children not of age": not named
Executor: wife and Daniel Eppes Witness: John B. Prewit
31. Record Book 2, Page 228 - Will of James Brookshire of Rutherford
County, TN - Date of Will: 16 April 1813 Recorded: 8 November
1813 Wife: Martha Brookshire "my children": not named
2 youngest children: William and Joseph Executors: friends,
Thomas Brown, George Uselton, Thomas Ashley Witnesses: Daniel
Green, Stephen Chalton, Frederick Brady
32. Record Book 2, Page 235 - Will of James Espie or Espey - Date
of Will: 2? December 1811 Recorded: 10 October 1813 son:
William and his wife, Cynthia, "only daughter-in-law" slave:
girl, Nice about 10 years to William granddaughter: not named,
(William's oldest daughter - no sons as of Will) son: George
52
32. (Cont'd) son: Robert daughter: Polly Overall daughter;
Rachel Goodloe daughter :Caity Espy daughter: Marget Youry
son-in-law: Francis Youry grandson: James Car Bradshaw
wife: Catey Espy "My four youngest children": George, Robert,
Gaity, Sally Executors: friends, Nathaniel Overall, Henry Belah,
William Espey Witnesses: J. Posey, Isaac H. Overall slaves:
wife is to have choice, rest divided among children.
33. Record Book 2, Page 239 - Will of David Rogers of Rutherford
County, TN - Date of Will: 6 January I8I3 Recorded: April term
I8I3 Wife: Peggy oldest son: Robert "wife is to raise
children until boys wants to do for themselves" second son:
William 4th son: James Bamet daughter: Nancy (not married)
3rd son: John Executors: wife and brother-in-law, William Ramsey
Slave: woman, Lydia (not to be sold out of family) Witnesses:
James Ramsey, Robert Raunsey.
34. Record Book 2, Page 248 - Will of Humphrey Nelson of Rutherford
County, TN - Date of Will: 24 July 1813 Filed: 19 March 1814
son: Beverly Nelson slave: girl, Betty/Cetty (?) to Beverly
Nelson daughter: Matilda Nelson son: Ambrose Nelson "rest
of the children" "younger children" Wife: Sally Nelson
Executors: Daniel Nelson, Beverly Nelson Witnesses: William
Vaughan, William H. Wade, William Edwards.
35. Record Book 2, Page 249 - Will of Elijah Fan of Rutherford County,
TN - Date of Will: 6 December I8I3 Recorded: 19 March 1814
Wife: Jane my 2 daughters: Jamima, Tabitha Executors: Henson
Coulter, Anderson Coulter, James Sutfin Witnesses: Anderson
Coulter, James Sutfin
36. Record Book 2, Page 288 - Will of Mary Whitnell of Rutherford
County, TN - Date of Will: 8 January 1814 Recorded: 2 April 1814
"being old and sick" daughter: Mary Wadley son: Daniel
Wadley son: John Wadley son: Thomas Wadley son: Samuel
Wadley son: William Wadley daughter: Lenaresa Wadley daughter:
Elander Wadley Executor: Thomas Nash Witnesses: Thomas A.
Sikes, Jessee Sikes.
37. Record Book 2, Page 298 - Will of John Winn of Rutherford County,
TN - Date of Will: 8 December I8I3 Recorded: 2 November 1814
2 daughters: Harriot and Margaret (apparently not of age - sgd)
slaves: girl, Febe (Phoebe) to Harriot; girl, Jane to Margaret
Wife: Pennelope Winn daughter: Ann McKinney son: Miner Winn
son: John Winn son: Richard Francis Winn son: William Wright
Winn daughter: Mary Kirkland son: Joseph T. Winn other 8
sons: Peter Winn, Daniel Winn, David Winn, Jefferson Winn, Robert
Winn, Obed Winn, Zacko Winn, Edward G. Winn Executors: 2 sons,
Joseph and Peter and wife Witnesses: Charles Kavanaugh, James
Dorothy ( ?Daugherty) , Peter Metheny.
</dc:description>
<dc:description>Abstracts of wills taken from Rutherford County record books 1 and 2 housed at the Rutherford County Archives</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.); Rutherford County (Tenn.) -- Archival resources; Wills</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>11 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-15; mt2011-02-17</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication17ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/46</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>