<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>The new monument in Old City Cemetery</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Miller, Julia Clarice</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 13</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1979</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>55
The New Monument in Old City Cemetery
by Julia Clarice Miller
You turn the key in the rusty lock and the iron
gates swing open. It is early spring and the young,
green grass smells sweet as it becomes the background
for the ancient monuments and markers of the graves in
Murfreesboro, Tennessee's Old City Cemetery on Vine
Street, You walk among the stones; some broken and
cracked. The inscriptions are dim from long years of
wind, hail, and snow. The dates go back into the 1700
and 1800' s. Some are flat on the ground, some are tall
columns and some are short and squat. Many vacant
spots have no stones at all. Who could be resting
there?
Suddenly you come to a massive, new monument.
Its gleaming, grey granite is in sharp contrast to
the ancient stones around it. You stand reading the
inscription. A mocking bird's song fills the silence.
You read:
56
WILLIAM HENRY LAWRENCE
&#8226;Husband of
Henrietta Stanfield
Died During Civil War
No dates available
HENRIETTA STANFIELD LAWRENCE
Mother of
Nina H. and Bertha
Dates no available
DAUGHTER
NINA H. LAWRENCE
Wife of
Alfred Crockett Vaughan
October 11, 1866
March 24, 1903
Infant Vaughan 1903
JOHN A. STANFIELD
Brother of
Henrietta S. Lawrence
Died March 10, 1880
BERTHA S. LAWRENCE
Sister of
Nina H. Vaughan
Death not available
&#8226;r.jii.-;::* i ri i-^n ^ \ :i '".erne t ',-i'\
The Letter Edged in Black
5S
59
Who could have placed this beautiful memorial here so
recently that the granite looks newly polished?
The monument was made and inscribed by the
hand of John Lawrence Vaughan, son of Nina H. Lawrence
Vaughan, to honor her memory. She died in 1903, when
Lawrence was eight years old, in the birth of her
second child. The infant was buried in the same
grave with her.
The monument was made and inscribed in the
Pulaski Monument Company, Inc. (since 1938), Pulaski,
Virginia, owned by John Lawrence and Julia Vaughan,
who made monuments and markers in granite and bronze.
This monument is grade AAA Longblue Georgia
granite, and weighs approximately two tons (Julia
Vaughan ' s approximation )
.
There are many familiar names among the pall
bearers at Nina's funeral, notice the Letter Edged in
Black. It is believed that R. C. Cawthon was Louise
Cawthon ' s great uncle. Louise is the secretary for
the Rutherford County Historical Society.
Lawrence and Julia Vaughan came to Murfreesboro
from Pulaski, Virginia, in 1967 looking for his mother's
grave in the Lawrence lot. At that time the Old City
Cemetery was in a shambles, the result of neglect,
vandalism and overgrown with weeds. He was broken
hearted and discouraged that he could find no evidence
60
of her grave or record of the lot. After several
visits here, Mayor W. H. Westbrooks told him that he
could certainly place a stone in the old cemetery in
his mother's memory. The Rutherford Co. Historical
Society and others had been working on the cemetery,
and Lawrence was pleased with the improvement.
In some of his research here, a kind person
sent him to an "old lady living in a hotel," according
to Julia. This woman was Miss Ida Richardson who knew
his mother, Nina Lawrence, when she was young. He
enjoyed his visit with Miss Ida. Julia continues,
"He went to the old cemetery and I can see him yet,
walking to the spot where he thought the Lawrence
square was located. But there was no marker. He was
determined to see that a monument was placed there."
In September of 19 76, Lawrence was working on
the monument when he became ill and was taken to the
hospital. He died September 9, 1976. His wife, Julia,
shipped the nearly completed monument to the Georgia
granite company where he obtained granite for his
monuments, and they completed it and sent it to an
agent near Murfreesboro , who had a Mr. Burnett of
Smyrna set the heavy stone in concrete in Old City
Cemetery. Mayor Westbrooks accompanied him and showed
him where to place it at a spot that Lawrence previously
told him he remembered as the location of his mother's
grave.
61
Nina Stanfleld Lawrence was the daughter of
William H. (Henry) and Henrietta Stanfield Lawrence,
and the granddaughter of John the elder and Henrietta
Stanfield, who were the first known Catholics to come
to Rutherford County.
A history of the Catholic faith in Rutherford
County is found in a booklet which was used at the
dedication of St. Rose of Lima Church in 1954. It
reads :
Seventy-five years or more ago, there
moved into the Bethlehem community, a few
miles southeast of Murfreesboro, Tennessee,
a family by the name of Stanfield. They
Ceune from Murfreesboro, Hertford County,
North Carolina, the place from which the
Tennessee town took its name. The family
consisted of the mother and father, who
was a jeweler, and three children. Mrs.
Stanfield was a Catholic, the first Catholic
so far as is known, to come to Rutherford
County. She arranged with the Bishop in
Nashville that a priest should come out once
or twice a year. He would be met at the
Murfreesboro station and driven out to the
Stanfield home where he said Mass. When the
children grew up, the son married and moved
away from Murfreesboro while one daughter
married a Mr. Lawrence and continued to live
on in the old home. She was soon left a
widow with two little girls. A sister of
Mr. Stanfield taught in the public schools
in Memphis and after a few years she took the
little girls and sent them to the Clara
Conway school in that city. The property of
that school was afterwards bought by the
Dominican Sisters of St. Cecilia Academy.
Several years later a Mademoiselle
Wuille, a Catholic, came to teach French at
old Soule College. A Mr. Frazier, a resident
of Murfreesboro, was converted, and this
little group used to meet in the Odd Fellows'
62
Hall where Mass was said whenever a priest
came. When Mrs. Stanfleld died, she was
burled in Nashville, as Bishop Rademacher
had always promised she would be. After
her death and that of Mr. Frazler, meetings
in the Odd Fellows' Hall were given up and
Mass was again celebrated at the Lawrence
home at Bethlehon.
This was the meeting place for the
Catholics when Mrs. S. B. Christy, who,
before her marriage, was Miss Addle Collins
of Nashville, moved to Mvurfreesboro about
fifty years ago. The mission was later
served by the priests fr&#171;n Winchester and
Father Kuel was in charge. Since he came
only occasionally, Mrs. Christy and Essie
Hancock used to meet every Sunday morning
at Mrs. Christy's home to say the Rosary
and read the Gospel, and after the death
of Mrs. Lawrence, Mass was celebrated at
Mrs. Christy's.
Following is copied from A HISTORY OF RUTHERFORD
COUNTY by Carlton C. Sims, 1947, p. 193:
&#8212;
CATHOLICS&#8212;Before the Civil War there
were several Catholic feunilies in Rutherford
County. Mass was occasionally said at the
home of John Stanfleld. Gen. Rosecrans is
reported to have attended Mass at Murfrees-boro
during the war. Father Jacquet appears
to have been the first missionary here.
Later, Sunday devotions were conducted
in the home of Mrs. S. B. Christy. By 1918
a sufficient number of families were in town
to justify the renting of a room in the
Masonic Building, and a Sunday School was
organized. On Sept. 15, 1929, the congrega-tion
moved into a beautiful little building
on Lytle Street, constructed through the
generosity of Mr. and Mrs. Hoffman of New
York. Miss Essie Hancock has long been one
of the faithful members. The Federal census
of 1926 reported 36 members, while in 1936
the number had risen to 45.
63
Following is copied from PACTS, Aug. 4, 1894
(a Catholic Weekly published In Chattamooga )
.
MURFREESBORO , TENN.&#8212;Established by
Pr. Jaquette early in the *40s. In 1856
Rev. Pr. Orengo visited the mission and
said Mass at the home of John Stanfield,
whose children still hold the faith at
their original home, Murfreesboro.
During the late war Rev. Prs. Cooney
and Walsh officiated here. Gen. Rosecrams
made this place his headquarters. He
edified the army by attending the holy
saccifice of the Mass.
At present the mission is doing nicely.
Mass being celebrated once during each
month. The following clergymen visited
the mission: Fr. Jaquette, Fr. Orengo,
Fr. Host, Fr. Wta. Walsh, Fr. McNally,
Fr. Gavin, Fr. Murray, Fr. Tiepel, Fr.
Braun and Fr. Graham.
Note:&#8212;The Fr, Cooney referred to above
as officiating during the war was probably
Pr. Peter T. Cooney, C.S.C., who enrolled
as Chaplain in the 35th Indiana Infantry
Dec. 11, 1861, and saw action at Stone's
River and Chickamauga.
It is believed the "Seventy-five years or more
ago, there moved into the Bethlehem community a few
miles southeast of Murfreesboro, Tennessee, a family
by the name of Stanfield ..." was written at the
dedication of the small white mission chapel on the
comer of College and Lytle Streets in 1929. The
quotation from the Catholic Weekly above shows that
the Stanflelds were here as eeurly as 1856, "when Mass
%ras said at the home of John Stanfield." Also the
64
Rutherford County Census for 1860 lists John Stanfield
as being a watchmaker from North Carolina and age
twenty-one.
From the Catholic Weekly quote above we also
find that General Rosecrans, a Catholic, attended Mass
during the Civil War at the John Stanfield home. The
current Rosecrans Recreation Center was named for him
and is located on part of the battlefield ground.
In the Deed Records at Murfreesboro Court House
is recorded the transfer of a lot in a parcel of land
in the (then) 13th District of Rutherford County from
John J. Lawing to Mrs. Henrietta Stanfield (Nina's
grandmother) on August 12th, 1865.
Deed Book #13 . p. 194:
I, John J. Lawing, have this day
bargained and sold and do hereby transfer
and convey to Henrietta Stanfield a lot on
parcel of ground for the consideration of
two hundred dollars in hand paid to me a
certain tract or parcel of ground in Civil
District No. 13 County of Rutherford, State
of Tennessee and bounded as follows:
Beginning at a stake N.E. corner of Lot
No. 2 running South 24 poles and 6 links to
a stake, thence South 51 1/4&#176; East 5 poles
and 8 1/2 links to a stake, thence North
27 poles 9 links to a stake, then West 4
poles and links to the beginning con-taining
106 3/4 poles. Said parcel of land
being the same that I purchased of J. F.
Fletcher, Sr. which is duly recorded in the
Register's Office of Rutherford County. To
have and to hold the same to Mrs. Henrietta
Stanfield, her heirs and assigns forever.
I do covenant with the said Henrietta
Stanfield that I am lawfully secured of
65
said land; have a good right to convey
it and that the same is unencumbered. I
do further covenant and bind myself, my
heirs and representatives to warrant and
defend the title to the said land to the
said Henrietta Stanfield against the
lawful claim of all persons whatever.
Given under my hand and seal this 12th
day of August, 1865. J. J. Lawing
Witness: William P. Henderson
Frank Winship
The John J. Lawing land is shown on the 18 78
map of Rutherford County obtained from the Rutherford Co.
Historical Society. It is located in the 13th District
of that date, on Salem Pike where Stones River crosses
it, which is southwest of the town; not southeast as
cited in the St. Rose history. It is the current home
of the Farmers, Sterling and Tom.
Neither the Bethlehem community nor the
Stanfield or Lawrence names are on the map which shows
land owners of that time. John J. Lawing and son are
listed as undertakers. C. C. Henderson's Story of
Rutherford County lists a Mr. S. N. Lawing. Maybe he
was the son.
Henrietta Stanfield purchased the Lawing plat
in August, 1865, and marriage records in the Murfrees-boro
Court House show that William H. Lawrence and H.
(Henrietta) R. Stanfield (her daughter) applied for a
marriage license on January 1st, 1866, the following
year (p. 184, Marriage Records 1863-70).
66
Nina Henrietta Lawrence, their first child,
was born October 11, 1866 (see the monument and death
notice). She and her younger sister, Bertha, attended
the Catholic school in Memphis (see St. Rose History).
Later the girls attended Old Soule Female
College in Murfreesboro , and Nina graduated with "The
Degree of Mistress of English Literature, the third day
of June in the year of our Lord 1886." John R.
Thompson, President, signed her diploma. This informa-tion
was supplied by Lawrence Vaughan's wife, Julia.
She has the notebook of Nina's sister, Bertha, who also
attended Old Soule that year.
Nina was born in 1866 and graduated in 1886,
making her about twenty years old at that time.
Julia also said that Nina took art at Old
Soule and taught her son, John Lawrence Vaughan, much
that she had learned. From this early training, he
became a designer and maker of monuments in his own
monument company. He also painted oil pictures.
Julia tells of an auction she attended in
Pulaski in 1970 of an old couple who had come there
from Tennessee many years ago. Julia and Lawrence
collected picture frames for his paintings. She bid
on a rather small gold frame. When J. L. (as she
called him) saw it, he nearly fainted for it was an
oil painting of some pansies and had been painted in
67
Old Soule College by Lorena Ransom. The Ransoms were
friends of the Lawrence family. He remembered them
very well. What a small world, was her comment. He
wouldn't have replaced that oil painting with one of
his own for anything. He treasured it deeply.
While Nina was growing up, there came to
Murfreesboro, Tennessee, in 1887 a family from Grayson
County, Virginia. Mr. John Floyd Poff, his wife,
Julia Ann Vaughan Poff, and two children, Kelley and
Myrtle (later Mrs. Albert Bridges Miller). Mrs. Poff's
brother, Alfred Crockett Vaughan, came later to join
them. He soon met the young girl who completely won
his heart, the lovely Nina Lawrence.
Julia again tells how J. L.'s father, Alfred
Vaughan, in his last days would sit in his rocker,
close his eyes and tell her in great detail how he
had won the hand of his beloved Nina back in Tennessee.
Her first love gave her a gold plated bracelet set with
garnets and said, "You must have this." Julia has the
garnet bracelet in her collection today. She wore it
one time to the University of Georgia in Athens.
Several people commented on it.
The marriage records in Murfreesboro, Tennessee,
show that A. (Alfred) C. (Crockett) Vaughan and Miss
Nina Lawrence (daughter of Mrs. Henrietta Stanfield
Lawrence) were issued a marriage certificate on
6a
October 15, 1894. They were married the next day,
October 16, 1894. An article found on MTSU microfilm
tells about the Lawrence-Vaughan marriage and was
found in the Nashville American newspaper dated October 17,
1894. Note the misspelled names Laurence-Vaughn, and
Rev. W. J. Kent instead of the W. J. Keal in the
marriage records. The article reads:
Nashville American . October 17, 1894
Vaughn-Laurence
MURFREESBORO, Oct. 16&#8212;(Special)&#8212;Mr.
Alfred Vaughn and Miss Nina Laurence of
this place, were married this morning at
8 o'clock at the residence of the bride's
mother, Mrs. Henrietta Laurence. Mr.
Vaughn is a highly respected citizen of
Murfreesboro, and Miss Laurence is a very
popular young lady. The ceremony was
performed by Rev. W. J. Kent, of
Winchester, according to the ritual of
the Catholic Church. The young couple
left immediately on a short wedding tour.
Alfred Vaughan's sister, Julia Ann, was the
wife of Mr. John Floyd Poff , a well-known woodworker
and cabinet maker, in Murfreesboro with the old Perkins
Lvimber Company, later to become the Young and Ogilvy
Company, on South Church Street. Currently the Police
Department, WGNS , Cohens and Hargroves are in that
location. Mr. and Mrs. J. F. Poff were the grand-parents
of your author of this article.
After Nina and Alfred were married, she soon
realized she would have her first child. John Lawrence
69
Vaughan was born August 2, 1895. He remembered well
the many services held in his grandmother's home as a
child. He was Baptized a Roman Catholic in the
Stanf ield-Lawrence home. Julia says that J. L. spoke
of his mother, Nina, as the most devout person he had
ever known. He remembered how she corrected him just
by speaking to him in the voice of a teacher&#8212;with
respect.
He recalled quite well when his mother died,
March 24, 1903, in the birth of her second child. He
was eight years old at the time, and remembered the
approximate location of the Lawrence lot in Old City
Cemetery.
After his mother's death, young Lawrence
Vaughan became devoted to his Aunt Julia Ann Poff.
She seemed to fill the vacancy when his mother died,
according to Mrs. Poff's daughter, Gladys Poff Ellison
of Smyrna.
Later Lawrence accompanied his father, Alfred
Vaughan, when he returned to the home place in Spring
Valley, Grayson County, Virginia. Here he grew to
young manhood.
J. L. volunteered for service in World War I.
He was inducted into the army at Pulaski, Virginia,
May 23, 1918. In six weeks with no training, he was
shipped to Europe and moved directly to the front. He
70
was actively engaged in the last battle that was fought
the morning of November 11, 1918, the "Battle of the
Argonne Forest." He often told his wife, Julia, how
the tops of trees were falling all around him that
morning and how lucky she was that her future sweet-heart
was spared.
He was an honor member of the American Legion;
and after his death, Julia received a beautiful
memorial card from President Ford. He came back by
boat to the U. S. on June 21, 1918 and received his
honorable discharge on July 1, 1919. His discharge
papers listed him as being born in Murfreesboro,
Tennessee, on August 2, 1895. He died in Pulaski,
Virginia, September 9, 1976.
When J. Lawrence Vaughan was at the wholesale
granite place located in Tate, Georgia, he traveled
in twenty-nine states and three foreign countries.
Once when he came to Mur freesboro , Tennessee, to visit,
he was greatly surprised to have three nuns meet him
at the train station. He never did find out how they
knew he was coming, but they added much pleasure to
his visit.
Julia D. Underwood finished school at age
nineteen and went immediately to the Vaughan Pulaski
Monument Company in Pulaski, Virginia, as secretary.
She and J. Lawrence Vaughan were married in Dublin,
71
Virginia, February 28, 193 3. They had one son and two
grandchildren, the first of whom was born on Julia and
Lawrence's wedding anniversary.
When their son, John Lawrence Vaughan, II,
married, his father-in-law was named John Lawrence
Harter. His ancestors, too, came from Wales to North
Carolina, as did the Stanfields. Julia wonders if
they are related to the Lawrences of Rutherford County.
The newspapers called to find if there was a mistake,
there was John Lawrence Vaughan, the father, John
Lawrence Harter, the groom's father, and John Lawrence
Vaughan, II, the groom.
Julia recalls many fond memories in their
lives in Pulaski, and the heavy sorrow in his death;
but without the sorrow she would never have known forty
years of happiness.
It took a long time and a great deal of work to
complete John Lawrence Vaughan ' s dream to place a
beautiful monument made by his own hands in Murfreesboro,
Tennessee's Old City Cemetery to honor his mother's
memory, but his wife, Julia, completed the necessary
work and the stone was set in concrete in December,
1977.
</dc:description>
<dc:description>Describes the new Lawrence monument placed in Old City Cemetery while telling the story of the Lawrence family</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Cemeteries; Family history; Rutherford County (Tenn.) -- History</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>monuments &amp; memorials</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>33  p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-01</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication13ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/105</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>