<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Militia orders from Library of Congress</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Henderson, James, Lt. Colonel</dc:creator>
<dc:contributor>Brigance, Fred</dc:contributor>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 7</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1811; 1976</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1810-1819</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>85
Militia Orders from Library of Congress
Furnished by Fred Brlgance
Major General Andrew Jackson
Sir seeing your Division orders from the of
Dec? 1811, I have requested the officers under my command to
call their companies together (agreeably to the requisitions of
your said orders) and know thereby what number of volunteers
could be raised In my Regiment.
In consequence of which request I have received the following
returns, three Captains In the First Battalion having made no
returns they being absent, but I have the fullest confidence that
I shall receive handsome returns from each of these companies
immediately on their Capt, return home.
First Battalion Men
Capt. McFerren 43
" Gordon 21
" Ramsey 7
Second Battalion
Capt. Reynolds 7
" Crawford 33
" Nash 13
" Jetton 12
" Hartgrove 8
" Kindle 31
one light Infantry company Capt. Yardley 46
one Rifle Company Capt. Brandon 40.
The above quota of men with myself and the second major
tender our services through you to the President of the United
States to be in readiness at any time when called on to serve
our Country.
I have not a doubt but the volunteers so named will march
at any time to any place on the continent in defense of their
Coiintry.
86
I have established a military school in the bounds of my
regiment to which all the volunteer officers above have sub-scribed
and I hope they will improve much thereby as the teacher
(Mr. Thomas Hubbard) is an old revolutionary character and who
has the good of his country at heart and whose spirit is
with flame of seventy six.
I am Sir with deep regards
yours
James Henderson Lt. Col.
Second Regt. Rutherford Co,</dc:description>
<dc:description>Transcription of correspondence related to militia orders between Lieutenant Colonel James Henderson and General Andrew Jackson</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Militias; Tennessee. Militia</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Henderson, James; Jackson, Andrew; United States--History--War of 1812, 1812 - 1815</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>3 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-15</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication07ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/147</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>