<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>A fifty-year history of Murfreesboro schools</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Jones, John Hodge</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 34</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1990</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>11
TO: Murfreesboro City Board of Education
FROM: John HdpgeJones
DATE: March 5, 1990
RE: A Review of School and School System Organization&#8212;A Personal Statement
Reflecting Upon the Past, Present, and Future
INTRODUCTION
Changes are rapidly taking place in Rutherford County and Murfreesboro's education institutions.
The history of where we are is relatively young and the opportunity window for change
has again been opened- Because that window is now open, it is my responsibility to give
you my perception of yesterday, today, and tomorrow. Because of my own limited time
to do research, many of the dates which I will use will not be documented; it will be based
upon my memory. Conclusions which I will draw will be my own, and I will attempt to
refrain from making recommendations until the subjects are more fully researched and
discussed.
CHAPTER I
A FIFTY-YEAR HISTORY
Recently a young local businessman visited my office to discuss school system unification.
He is a member of the Leadership Rutherford class which is addressing this subject. After
talking to him for approximately one hour, I realized that I had given him a lesson in local
school/school system history dating back approximately fifty years. When reflecting upon
this, it occurred to me that many of our local officials now in decision-making roles are
either younger than I or may not be natives of this community. I have often thought that
Mr. Hobgood should write down his thoughts and his knowledge of education history dating
back to the early 1900s. This would indeed be valuable, but I also realized that I possess
knowledge and experience which provide information on where and why we are at this
junction in today's local school organization and control.
My father served on the Rutherford County Court from 1936 until 1972. I started to school
at Rockvale in 1943. Dad always felt a need and expressed an interest in consolidating
78
the small schools throughout Rutherford County. I never heard hinn discuss school system
unification. Because of this, I developed an early interest in the organization and control
of local schools.
When I started to school in 1943, Rutherford County had more than 50 schools scattered
throughout the county. Many of these schools were one or two-teacher schools. Grades
1-12 schools were located at Eagleville, Rockvale, Christiana, Kittrell, Lascassas, Walter
Hill, and Smyrna.
There was a dual system for the races with small schools for black children being scattered
throughout the various portions of the county. Most all of these schools were one- or
two-teacher schools. Holloway was the one central high school for black high school age
children. Not only was there a dual school system, but there was also a dual pupil transportation
program. An extensive separate pupil transportation program served the entire county
with overlapping routes for black and white children.
In those days elementary children went to school for eight months and high school children
attended nine months. Schools were closed for approximately one month in the fall in
order for children to stay home and pick cotton. Many children from rural share-cropping
families dropped out of school early because of excessive absenteeism caused by staying
at home to assist their families with picking cotton and other farm work.
In Murfreesboro there were four elementary schools attended by Murfreesboro's elementary
children. Several children from the county also attended these schools. It has been reported
to me that children from upper income or so called "elite families" attended the Homer
Pittard Campus School, at that time called the Training School. Children from middle
income families enrolled at Crichlow Elementary, and children from low income families
attended McFadden Elementary. The old Bradley Academy, which now houses our maintenance
shop, was the elementary school for black children.
Central High School, according to Mr. Hobgood, became a county high school sometime
soon after World War I. Interestingly, Mr. Hobgood stated that the school originally started
because many citizens across the county wanted to develop a football power house. Prior
to that time, many Murfreesboro children had received their high school education primarily
in private schools. At some point during the twenties and thirties, the principal of Central
High School also served as the superintendent of the Murfreesboro City Schools. This
is probably one of the reasons why Murfreesboro never developed a high school program-
Murfreesboro's elementary schools encompassed grades 1-8.
79
Until the early 1950s, there was little change in the structure of the public school program
as discussed above. Murfreesboro began to grow in the fifties in the Mitchell-Neilson,
Reeves-Rogers, and Hobgood areas. Under Mr. Hobgood's superintendency, Mitchell-Neilson,
Hobgood, Bradley, and Reeves-Rogers were all built during the 1950s; I believe in this
order. Bellwood and Mitchell-Neilson Primary were not built until approximately 1964
and 1965. During the period of the fifties there was little change taking place in Rutherford
County in terms of school construction- Additions, of course, were being built to all schools.
Portables on campuses became popular. The Smyrna area had grown and the 1-12 grade
school in that area had split up into more than one school. The Smyrna High School was
built sometime during the mid fifties. Basketball was the center of activity for all of
the rural high schools. Central High School, under the coaching of Mr. Lee Pate, became
a power house both in basketball and Football. They nearly always competed in state
competition.
DESEGREGATION
In 1954, in Brown vs Topeka, Kansas, the dual system of public education which had historically
separated the races was declared unconstitutional. Integration, however, developed slowly.
School systems across the nation first met the requirements of the Brown Decision by
establishing freedom of choice for all children. Obviously, there were few black children
to enter all-white schools, and in this area, no white children entered all-black schools.
By 1966 there were a few black children who had enrolled at Crichlow and only a handful
at the other city schools. Not many black children attended Central High School and
no white children enrolled at HoUoway High or Bradley Elementary. Practically no integration
had taken place at the schools scattered throughout Rutherford County.
Other suits to force desegregation began going through the court system of our country
and forced desegregation became a way of life. Many school systems came under court
order. Many boards and superintendents lost much of their control and school systems
were placed under the control of the judicial system. During the latter part of the 1960s,
both the black and white leadership of Rutherford County and Murfreesboro did an excellent
job developing desegregation plans and rapidly integrated our school systems. Holloway
High School was closed and became an annex to Central with most of the vocational courses
being housed at old Holloway. In 1968 Bradley was closed as an all-black school and Crichlow
was closed as a 1-8 grade school. Central, of course, became a fully integrated high school,
and Crichlow and Bradley became seventh and eighth grade schools for the City of Murfreesboro.
For the first time, Murfreesboro entered the pupil transportation business by establishing
80
simple shuttle routes from the Bradley and Crichlow schools to the perimeter schools
and brought seventh and eighth graders from the perimeter schools back to Crichlow and
Bradley. Crichlow and Bradley remained seventh and eighth grade schools until the fall
of 1972 when Oakland and Riverdale were opened as high schools leaving Central available
for a large seventh and eighth grade school.
REAPPORTIONMENT
Another important event was taking place in the nation up to and during the late 1960s
which had an impact upon the history of our school systems. These circumstances had
to do with the one-man, one-vote court decisions that were being made in the nation.
In an earlier decade, courts had ruled that congressional districts must be reapportioned
on a one-man, one-vote basis. They later ruled that state legislative districts must reapportion.
Not until 1968 was there a ruling on local governing bodies related to the principle of
one-man, one-vote. This ruling came from the United States Supreme Court and was
applicable to the local governing body in Midland, Texas.
A similar suit had been filed in Rutherford County against the Rutherford County Quarterly
Court and against the Rutherford County School Board. Since the Midland, Texas suit
was already pending before the United States Supreme Court, the local suits were held
in local courts waiting for the Supreme Court ruling. The Rutherford County Quarterly
Court, now called the Rutherford County Commission, was composed of fifty-four members;
only four being from Murfreesboro, which at that time had approximately forty-five percent
of the county's population.
Likewise, the Rutherford County School Board was extremely malapportioned. There
were eleven members of the Rutherford County School Board; only one representing the
City of Murfreesboro. Obviously, this kind of representation contributed to very high
provincialism for every community throughout the county making school consolidation
almost impossible. Every magistrate and every school board member were elected by people
who wanted to maintain the status quo, maintain their one- and two-teacher schools, and
particularly maintain the six rural high schools which were the focal point for high spirited
basketball games and other community activities. Practically no candidate had a Chinaman's
chance for winning an election who became associated in anyway with the subject of school
consolidation. Mr. Hollis Westbrooks defeated Mr. Wilkes Coffee in a bitterly fought
campaign for the Tennessee Legislature in the early 1960s. The issue was reapportionment
81
and to everyone, reapportionment meant school consolidation. Mr. Westbrooks obviously
represented the status quo on that issue. In 1966, I came much closer to winning a county-wide
election. 1 was identified as a consolidation candidate for county school superintendent,
but failed to win that election by 400 votes.
RUTHERFORD COUNTY SCHOOL CONSOLIDATION
As soon as the Midland, Texas decision was made regarding one-man, one vote at the local
level, the Rutherford County Quarterly Court and Rutherford County School Board immediately
set up a reapportionment plan. In fact, our local governing bodies reapportioned prior to
Midland, Texas, making them the first local reapportioned county government entities
in the nation. Some very progressive local citizens had been behind the local suit. Some
of these citizens were elected to the newly formed Rutherford County Commission and
Rutherford County School Board. The Commission was lowered to forty-two members,
and the new School Board was composed of seven members.
Many of the forty-two members on the new County Commission and seven board members
did not represent areas of the County composed of the six rural high schools. Therefore,
the stage was set for consolidation of many of Rutherford County Schools. The highly
credentialed, qualified, and progressive county board that was elected around 1970 invited
Mr, Hobgood, me, and other City officials to sit in with the county superintendent and
board in the development of a consolidation plan for Rutherford County. Mr. Hobgood
and I were quite actively involved in the proposal to build two new high schools at their
current sites. The county commission agreed to the Board's proposal and the city agreed
to waive certain rights to tax collections. A half cent sales tax was approved; a wheel
tax was imposed; and some increase occurred in local property taxes. The county built
Oakland and Riverdale High Schools which opened in the fall of 1972.
SYSTEMS UNIFICATION DISCUSSIONS
With a very progressive and highly credentialed county school board and recognizing a
new county commission that was able to support school consolidatation for the first time,
local city officials began to discuss with county officials the possibility of school system
unification. Mr. Hobgood and Joe Sloan, Chairman of the Rutherford County School Board,
using the Clarksville-Montgomery consolidation instrument as a guide, developed a school
system consolidation proposal for Rutherford County-Murfreesboro. It had already been
agreed that the available space at Central would become available for seventh and eighth
82
graders in the City of Murfreesboro. It was felt that the systems would unify and the
logical use of the old Central High School building would be for seventh and eighth graders.
It was perceived that the Crichlow facility needed to be closed for school use; therefore,
the city school board agreed to turn over the seventh and eighth grades to the County
school system.
The unification proposal called for a superintendent appointed by the county school Board.
This, along with rural suspicions, caused the 1972 vote on school system unification to
fail. Once prior to this time, I believe it was in 1969, a referendum failed on the subject
of changing the method of selecting the county superintendent to an appointed position.
Another referendum was attempted on this subject in the late 1970s and it was also soundly
defeated.
In summary, because of the highly credentialed progressive school board, the newly created
progressive county commission, the effort to consolidate the school systems, and the available
space at Central, Murfreesboro lost its seventh and eighth grade program to Rutherford
County,
Most of us are aware of the changes and developments taking place in local school systems
for the last two decades. Since 1970, there has been a change in the Rutherford County
School superintendency every four years. Mr. Hobgood retired in 1975s, Dr. Swick left
our school system in 1981, Roger Landers was superintendent for only seven months in
1982, and I became your school superintendent in August, 1982. Since the opening of Bellwood
and Mitchell-Neilson Primary School, there was no new school building opened in Murfreesboro
City until 1987 with the opening of Northfield. During that period of time, several additions
were made to Murfreesboro city school buildings. Classroom additions were added because
of increases in federal and state requirements for special education and our own efforts
to improve these programs. Additions were also made because of the new requirements
for library space in elementary buildings and with the advent of the kindergarten programs
in the early 1970s. Our schools were retrofitted for energy conservation in the late 1970s.
There were few changes in schools during the seventies and early eighties because our
pupil population stabilized during these years. In fact our pupil population had decreased
by approximately 500 students during this period while the city's population was increasing
by approximately 10,000. North Rutherford County experienced growth, and some school
construction took place in the Smyrna and LaVergne areas. The county's $40 million plus
building program got under way in about 1984.
33
SUMMARY
From the foregoing history, I call your attention to the following:
1. One prime reason for the existence of the city school system was the gross malapportionment
of representation on the county court and county school board.
2. The city never developed a high school program, among other reasons, because in the
early years, the city school superintendent and the principal of Central High School
were one position-
3. The city lost its seventh and eighth program because of the anticipated approval of
a unification plan and the available space at Central when the two new high schools
were built.
4. Desegregation played a major role in the forming of our school systems as we see them
today.
There is one other important reason for the justification of the city school system and
that relates to the city's willingness to spend more for a quality education program. I
will refer to this later in this presentation.
CHAPTER n
EVENTS SHAPING TODAY'S HISTORY
There are several items under consideration at the state and local level which may have
an impact on the Murfreesboro City School System.
STATE OF TENNESSEE
Several related discussions are taking place at the state level. First, is the suit which
has been filed by 66 small rural counties against the State of Tennessee which relate to
equity funding- Second, is the discussion regarding the Tennessee Foundation Program
(TEP) which proposes to distribute state funds to local school districts by a basic education
program (BEP); and, third, is the subject of state tax reform which is needed in order
to adequately fund the state's public school program. Unification and capital outlay notes
are also on the state agenda.
84
Rural Counties Vs. State
The subjects interrelate, but let's look first at the suit filed by 66 small rural counties.
Whether these counties win this suit does not seem to be of great importance at this
time. Nearly all public officials, school administrators, and the public as a whole,
acknowledge that a more equitable distribution of state funds should be implemented.
Similar suits have occurred throughout the nation. The plaintiffs in Texas won their
suit and the courts have called for reform in the Texas Foundation Program. Also,
the most drastic example is in the State of Kentucky where the plaintiffs have won
and the courts have called for a complete restructuring of the Kentucky Foundation
Program for distributing its state funds. Our State constitution is written somewhat
different from that of Kentucky causing many to speculate that Tennessee's rural
counties will not win their suit but as indicated, this seems to be a moot issue. It appears
that the Tennessee Legislature is sympathetic with the suit and are moving toward
a system of redistributing state monies.
The Foundation Program
Our current foundation program dates back to 1956. The distribution formula was
revised in 1978. Prior to 1978, state funds were distributed to local school districts
on the basis of required positions needed to operate a school program and a few other
categories which included maiirtenance and operation, pupil transportation, and provision
of free textbooks. In 1978, the formula was changed to support school systems across
the state on the basis of weighted average daily attendance with various weights being
given to pupils according to their assigned grade level.
I am on the state committee working on the new foundation program and we refer
to it as the basic education program or the BEP. While I am not in total agreement
with my colleagues on this subject, it appears they will go back to position funding
if and when such a proposal is ever approved. The assumption is that every school
and school system should have a certain number of positions in order to have an adequate
education program. The number of teaching positions and most support positions will
depend on teacher/pupil ratio requirements. For example, one guidance counselor
for each 500 elementary children, one librarian for each 500; one assistant principal
after you reach a certain point, a resource teacher, a supervisor, and a principals,
etc., according to pupil enrollment. The proposed BEP calls for the state to furnish
70 percent of the cost to meet the requirements for a basic education program, and
85
the local school districts across the state will supply 30 percent of the cost. The 70
and 30 percents are averages, and the degree to which a school system varies from
the average will depend upon the established relative wealth in that school district
as compared with the rest of the state. The basic difference between the BEP and
the current foundation program is that the current program is totally inadequate to
meet the needs of education across the state. Since the state is doing such a poor
job in meeting the education requirements, those school districts across the state who
do not have the local wealth to provide an adequate program are not doing so. Those
school districts across the state like Murfreesboro, Oak Ridge, Kingsport, and even
counties of relative wealth which includes Rutherford are generally considered to
be providing an adequate education program. Thus, when an adequate program depends
heavily on local ability, a wide disparity develops from school district to school district
across the state,
Tax Reform
The third subject is tax reform. In order to implement the proposed BEP, it is estimated
that $400 million new state dollars will be needed. Most lawmakers believe that the
sales tax is fully utilized. Our own Representative John Bragg presents an excellent
case for this point- The elimination of all sales tax exemptions would bring in a significant
amount of new funds to the state, but from my observation, lawmakers are not close
to eliminating these exemptions.
A state income tax is most frequently mentioned in reference to tax reform. Many
believe Governor McWherter will most likely serve in the State House for another
four years and that he is ready to advance such tax reform. But lawmakers are now
saying that an income tax in Tennessee, if it is ever approved, will be approved under
the provisions of a constitutional amendment. Assuming that all of the proper steps
are taken and that in each step there is a green light given, lawmakers indicate this
process would take at least six years. Therefore, many of us who had hopes of achieving
tax reform because of earlier impressions are beginning to become pessimistic regarding
its chance.
State Discussions on Systems Unification
Because of the foregoing discussions at the state level, other subjects are being generated
which have a direct bearing upon the Murfreesboro City Schools. The average citizen,
86
and I'm afraid, the average lawmaker in the State of Tennessee, feel that 141 school
districts in the 95 counties in the state is a factor contributing to inefficiency, waste,
and the lack of equity in expenditures per pupil and thus a lack of equal education
opportunity. Such positions are being promoted by William Snodgrass, Comptroller
of the Treasury for the state.
I admit that the above positions are debatable. But those of us who are students of
school finance are aware that those assumptions are not really all that obvious. The
Tennessee Municipal League has taken a stance in opposition to those points and does
a good job in defending the role, nature, and need for city school districts. But in
addition to Comptroller Snodgrass' role, it appears that city school districts do not
have a great deal of support from the current commissioner of education as well as
the state board of education. City school superintendents have been very sensitive
to the statements made from the commissioner and from the state board regarding
this subject. While the attack is generally levied at counties such as Gibson and Carrol
where there are numerous small school districts, nevertheless, I suspect that in the
long run, an effort will be made at the state level to consolidate districts into 95 county
units. Unfortunately, the basis for this movement is a financial one and does not consider
all of the other reasons why school districts should be allowed to operate as independent
units separate and apart from county governments. Quality education is seldom mentioned
nor is the right for certain geographical areas to tax themselves at a higher rate in
order to produce a superior school system.
In addition to the above, the governor has just employed Dr. Don Thomas, a well-known
consultant from the State of Utah, to spend a year in Tennessee and take a look at
Tennessee's education program and the means by which it is financed. Early indications
from Dr. Thomas indicate that he will encourage school system consolidation. He
already is speaking in terms of state incentives for promoting consolidation of school
districts. Prior to this time, the discussion has been centered around disincentives
for multiple systems. Basically they seem to be one and the same with just a different
emphasis on the positive! I recently heard Dr. Thomas speak and he stated that he
would be studying the issues of "adequacy, equity, accountability, and school governance"
in the state.
Capital Outlay Notes
As a sequel to the above, the courts and Attorney General opinions are also playing
a role in the current affairs of city and special school districts across the state. School
87
law requires that counties share bond proceeds with special and/or city school districts.
Rutherford County has traditionally shared such bonds with us when those bonds were
issued for elementary purposes. In the past, the city has received funds on the basis
of our elementary children to the county/city total pupil population. Bonds for high
school purposes, of course, have been waived. It is easy to see there is a mathematical
discrimination against an elementary school system in regard to such distribution.
In other words, we waive high school bonds but are paid a percent on elementary bonds
equal to our elementary pupil count as a percent of the total K-12 enrollment. But
counties have been able to go one step further. High schools have been built and former
high schools have been converted to elementary use without sharing in bond proceeds.
In recent years, the capital outlay note, or as some label it, the bond anticipation note,
has become another instrument used by counties to circumvent city payments . The
attorney general ruled last fall that it was not necessary for counties to share the
proceeds of capital outlay notes, and capital outlay notes may be issued up to a fifteen-year
period of time. Thus, if a county wishes to build an elementary school, it now has
either the option to issue bonds or capital outlay notes. If it issues the latter for a
fifteen-year period of time, it is in essence the same as a bond, except according to
the current interpretation of law, the county no longer has to raise an amount to distribute
to the city school system.
The Tennessee Municipal League has recently introduced legislation which would place
the same requirement on capital outlay notes as upon bonds. In my opinion this legislation
has no chance of making it through the legislature. In fact, I am told that Representative
John Bragg does not support this move and I personally talked to Senator Womack
and he has indicated that he does not support this legislation. His statement was "that
if cities are going to have school districts, they should be willing to support their districts"
even at the cost of double taxation for this specific purpose. Needless to say, I was
disappointed in Senator Womack's position.
Local Events
As you are aware, Rutherford County is discussing an extensive elementary school
program. They are proposing schools for Lascassas, Rockvale, Kittrell, and Smyrna.
These schools will be built with core facilities for 1600 pupils. It is proposed that
the schools be completed in three stages: The first stage taking care of 800 pupils,
op
the second 1200, and the third stage 1600. The schools would incorporate grades K-8.
The county has already ftpproved a million dollar capital outlay note for the purpose
of purchasing four new school sites and taking care of maintenance needs. From what
I can understand by reading the Daily News Journal , apparently the delay of purchasing
school sites hinges on the location of the site at Rockvale. In a recent conversation
with Superintendent Jerry Gaither, he indicated that he believes the county school
board and county commission are almost reaoy to move on their plans for these elementary
schools. He points out that crowding in the elementary schools is becoming a major
problem with numerous portables being used throughout the county to alleviate overcrowing.
Superintendent Gaither also went on to indicate the next high school for Rutherford
County will most likely be somewhere in the area between Murfreesboro and Smyrna.
CHAPTER III
FUTURE IMPLICATIONS FOR THE CITY SCHOOL BOARD
What implications does the foregoing have for the Murfreesboro City School Board
and the Murfreesboro City Council. Obviously most of what I referred to in Chapter
II is outside of the control of the school board or the council. It appears to me, however,
that the window is now open for some major decision making which will have long-range
impact upon the Murfreesboro City Schools and education in our area. I believe
there are three basic areas that we must study at this point: (1) the subject of
unification of school systems and/or metropolitan government or some other organizational
alternative for operating public schools in the area, (2) the scope of our present school
program and consider broadening that scope to at least incorporate grades K-8 and
maybe eventually locking toward a K-12 program for the city, (3) stay charted on
our present course and develop additional K-6 schools when needed, (4) and study
our financial resources. A more lengthy and intensive study of each of these four
areas may be in order, but for the present time, I will provide you the benefit of my
thinking on these subjects.
UNIFICATION OF SCHOOLS AND/OR METROPOLITAn GOVERNMENT
As you have read above, unification of school systems is a popular subject at the state
level, and I find it is being discussed more and more locally. As indicated, the Leadership
Rutherford group is currently studying the issue. Almost every-day someone brings
this subject to my attention for comments.
Up front 1 neither support consolidation of school systems nor do I oppose consolidation
of school systems. I want it made clear that my vested interest should never be a
factor in determining what is best for children's education in this area for decades
to come. There are two major problems in having separate school systems in the same
general locality. One is the ability to do long-range planning and the second problem
is the misunderstanding which local citizens have regarding the nature of two separate
school systems. Animosity and adversarial attitudes develop among the citizens of
the county and city which generally should be seen as one community.
When thoroughly investiaged the argument that separate school systems such as ours
produce waste and inefficiency and that inequity in education opportunity are inherent
does not hold water. It is my opinion that if school system unification takes place
locally, there will be an immediate need created for additional tax payers' funds.
The funds will be turned over to the present county organizational structure where
it would be obliged to continue doing everything in a traditional and status quo manner.
This would result in having to generate millions of new dollars for school purposes
which may very well be wasted and not produce a better product.
A large bureaucracy unwilling to meet the challenges of change, efficiency, and good
management will not save money and most likely will not provide a better education
program. Unification would require that top dollar cost in any given area between
the two school systems would need to be achieved in all of those areas in the unified
school system. For example, Murfreesboro operates a most efficient and very low-cost
transportation program. Murfreesboro does not claim to give the same services that
the county gives to most children in the county who use transportation services. Immediately
tax payers inside Murfreesboro would have the right to claim the same quality service.
The county does not operate a Classroom on Wheels program; rural citizens would
have the right to demand one. Salaries for personnel would have to equal those paid
by the higher paying school system- In the case of teachers, four county teachers
for every one in the city system would need to be raised to the salary schedule level
of the city school system. While this may be a very desirable objective, there is no
guarantee that it would produce a better educated child.
Given the fact that there is difficulty in long-range planning and that a perennial misunderstanding
exists regarding the nature of two school systems, what are some of the alternatives
90
to unification of school systems? Traditional unification from what I have observed
involved cities going out of business . In spite of the documents that might be drafted
and agreements promulgated, in the long run, my observations indicate what happens
is that the city quits and the county takes over.
This is not an acceptable alternative to me. I do not support our school program being
turned over to the county school board and to the county commission with only the
hope that the total school program for county and city will be raised to the quality
and quantity level we now possess. I do not see the current political organization and
local governing structure capable of producing the high expectations, standards, and
reputation claimed by Murfreesboro City Schools. I do not see the unified school system
bringing to Murfreesboro the marketing value that we have brought to our citv.
We should not shut the door completely to discussions on this topic. It appears that
the state is not going to allow us to shut the doer, and we must be open minded citizens
recognizing there are problems associated with two separate school districts.
ALTERNATE NUMBER ONE&#8212;METROPOLITAN GOVERNMENTS
A county and/or unified school system is the largest cost to local government. When
administered only by the county government, it is excluded from certain taxing powers
which are possessed exclusively by Tennessee municipal governments. Metropolitan
government would prevent this. Also I am convinced that little would be accomplished
in addressing long-range planning and especially the misunderstanding that occurs
among local citizens if other branches of local governments were allowed to be separate.
The Nashville media has not helped promote metro-government. It makes us keenly
aware of all of the problems associated with Metro-Nashville. Recently Cecil Branstetter,
the man who drafted that charter, acknowledged that a lot of revision is needed in
the Metro-Nashville Charter. If we take the route of a metro-government, I would
insist that we identify and circumvent those problems in the Metro-Nashville Charter.
Also, we should be assured that the control of the school system would be placed into
the hands of a board of education that was not provincial in its vested interest. The
head of the school system should be an appointed chief education offficerwhc is accountable
to the board of education. Also I would like to make sure that the charter contdned
provisions related to the organization and administration of the school system so that
91
elementary education would not become a step child to secondary programs, athletic
activities, discipline problems, and secondary administration in general.
OTHER ALTERNATIVES
Another alternative could be a fiscally independent school district for the total county.
This alternative would be similar to the one called for under the Metro-Nashville Charter.
The guarantees listed above would need to be incorporated into such a school district.
This alternative would make a board of education and the school district a complete
governing entity capable of raising its own taxes, fully governing and implementing
its own program. The school district would strictly be a creation of the state legislature
and would be completely separate from any other local government entities.
Another alternate could be similar to the above in which more than one school district
would be created. There would be two districts, both county wide including the cities.
One would be an elementary district and the other a secondary. Because of the large
size of Ruterford County, it is conceivable that such an alternative would be good
for the future of our community. Each of the districts would operate very similar
to that as described above. The advantage of this alternative would be the guarantee
that high emphasis would be placed on elementary education.
EXPANDING THE SCHOOL GRADES IN THE MURFREESBORO CITY SCHOOLS
The most urgent consideration is the possibility of incorporating grades seven and
eight in the Murfreesboro City Schools. The window is open on this subject because
we are adding classroom space for 1000 children beginning in August of this year.
Being crowded is everybody's definition. But from a management standpoint, especially
if we see the need to reorganize our school system and expand its scope, we would
have space for the next two years to add the seventh grade.
Another building or two would need to be started by next February and completed
by August, 1992. The eighth grade would be added on this date; I believe there is much
support for this proposal. The reason for the support lies in the fact that the county
is proposing the construction of modern K-8 facilities throughout the countryside.
These schools will handle up to 1600 pupils which will be financed in large part by
monies paid by taxpayers who live inside the City of Murfreesboro. After our city
children finish the sixth grade, they must attend school in an old facility in the middle
of downtown which has not been well maintained. Also the large middle school is
92
a less desirable organizational structure for educating the adolescent and young teenao-er
than the K-8 organizational structure which will be available for rural children.
We have no guarantee that the county will issue school bonds for their elementary
building program. 1 have received word through city sources that the county does
intend to issue bonds instead of capital outlay notes. This certainly is the fair approach
since Murfreesboro citizens will be major contributors to paying bonded indebtness.
Immediate study and attention should be brought to this issue.
While undocumented, because of the social changes that have occurred in recent years,
adolescent peer pressures, desire to immediately gain their license for teenage behavior
and to exercise independence; the middle school as it exists in Murfreesboro is not
the optimum environment for our thirteen through fifteen year old children. I believe
if we keep the adolescent in elementary school in a nurturing environment for two
additional years and continue to provide an elementary program rather than a pre-high
school program or a pre-teen environment for them, we would see a significant improvement
in the quality of their education.
Is such a move possible? Dr. Klaus, other staff members, and 1 have not yet been
able to intensively research this proposal. 1 believe that we can add the seventh grade,
approximately 500 students, for the next two years at a reasonable cost to city government.
In 1992-93 when we open one or two new schools for grades 7 and 8, the cost would
increase significantly. It does not necessarily mean that the cost will increase significantly
to the city taxpayers If we can operate our schools at a more efficient rate than
the county, then it is conceivable that the cost to the city tax-payers would increase
very little. They would be paying more taxes through the city government and less
through the county government.
We currently are receiving approximately 19 percent of each education dollar collected
by the county. Obviously if we increase our enrollment, this percentage will increase
and the state contributions will increase proportionally. After the state adopts and
implements the new basic education program, the City of Murfreesboro may be able
to lower its financial support; thus, the city may gain greater control over the destiny
of its students at little to no cost.
There may be major problems associated with such a move. Would this move produce
more or less efficiency in the county program? The first big question for the county
would be the dispostion of the large school facility at Central, its staff, and program.
93
They might continue to operate it as a middle school for certain children whom they
would bus into the city. They might close McFadden. Wishful thinking and the most
immediate ideal option would be for MTSU to lease or purchase the building for its
additional classroom space. Frankly, 1 have no idea how we could use it. For years
we have labored over how to keep students in Bradley and Hobgood. Even if the building
was restored to optimum conditions 1 think we would have problems in converting it
into an elementary school that would be adeqrstely utilized. We might, of course,
take the position that it would be the county's problem and none of our business. I
doubt if we would want to do this because, after all, we are all tax-payers in our local
community and it would have an impact upon each of us.
At this point 1 have not given thought to the subject of expanding our school program
on through the high school years. Jerry Gaither mentioned to me the possibility of
the city taking over Oakland and allowing the county to build another high school between
Murfreesboro and Smyrna. I do not believe that addressing this subject is necessary
in order for us to look at the other subject of expanding our school system to incorporate
grades seven and eight.
In addition to the nurturing atmosphere of a K-8 grade school and the continuance
of a more elementary approach to this child's curriculum, there are some advantages
which 1 will mention. These include providing almost every child an opportunity to
experience the various arts, music, languages, athletic programs, etc. These often
become electives to the child who is enrolled in a large middle school. Conceptually,
I can see Murfreesboro Recreation Department playing a big role in coordinating the
various youth league programs so that every seventh and eighth grade boy and girl
who wanted to take part, especially in basketball, baseball, and soccer, would have
an opportunity to do so. Even in football, there could be a touch league. Through
the Extended School Program, 1 could see many more children having the opportunity
to be involved in instrumental music which would include not only band but piano,
have exposure to several different foreign languages, and the visual arts. The opportunity
for expanded school day will be enhanced. Flexible scheduling to provide services
for more and more children will make for a more efficient program. Best of all, by
keeping the children in a K-8 environment they would not be exposed so quickly to
those societal elements which are creating problems for our youth. 1 think there would
be a decline in drug abuse and in teenage pregnancy. I believe an increase in parental
involvement would occur, particularly if extended school is offered.
94
III. STAY CHARTED ON SAME COURSE
We can, of course, remain a K-6 school system. Should we decide to take this course,
we will be placing ourselves in a position of accepting our lot as measured out by state
and county governments. My foregoing discussion regarding seventh and eighth grade
expansion indicates that severe dissatisfaction might occur because our children would
be moved from our K-6 program to a middle school program perceived less desirable than
the school organization provided for most children in Rutherford County.
Growth trends in Murfreesboro indicate that we will be building another elementary school
every three to five years. The rate of our growth will depend somewhat upon where the
county places its new large elementary schools and the degree to which the county provides
pupil transportation to these schools. Our own policy toward accepting county students
and whether the county implements an ESP program will also be factors which will impact
upon our future enrollment.
Should we add to our scope of grades, we must be very protective of the quality and quantity
of instruction that we are currently providing in K-6. We would not want the added responsibility
detracting or detering our efforts to provide the K-6 child with the best education foundation
possible. It would be unfortunate if we eroded our good reputation by assuming a larger
responsibility.
IV. FINANCIAL RESOURCES
Resources to expand the scope of our school program may be within our reach. Continuing
rate increases or instituting new tax sources obviously are not desired by anyone, but
we all have a tendency to be willing to pay for what we want. Many rural citizens are
going to be very excited over having a brand new school building in or close to their communities.
I believe most city school parents would welcome an expansion of our schools through
the eighth grade-
It appears that sometime within the next few years the state legislature will address and
bring about significant tax reform in Tennessee. Should this tax reform include anything
that relates to an income tax, we can expect the state to take over some of the services
currently being rendered by local governments. I would expect the state to take over
a much larger cost for public education than it is currently assuming-
Therefore, in the interim, Rutherford County and Murfreesboro have available a one-half
cent sales tax option which could be assessed if approved in a public referendum. There
have been no open discussions as to how the county intends to pay for its new buildino-program.
My guess is they will look at the half-cent sales tax as a source. Should the
county initiate a referendum on this option, any chances of approval will probably depend
upon the vote coming out of the City of Murfreesboro. If we, at the same time, were
proposing the construction of two more elementary schools and converting our program
to a K-8 program, the sales tax option might be approved. Hopefully, this tax as well
as other sales taxes would be rolled back when state tax reform is implemented. At the
present time, 1 do not have the revenue figures such a tax would yield, but 1 am convinced
that it would go a long way in financing both the county and city school building programs.
CONCLUSION
I have provided you with the foregoing in order for you to understand from my perspective
why schools are organized in Rutherford County and Murfreesboro the way they are.
I have also attempted to inform you of certain events taking place at the state and local
level which indicate that changes are coming which have an impact upon us and; finally,!
have attempted to show that we do not necessarily need to sit and wait and react in regard
to those changes. We now have the opportunity to be pro-active, not reactive. I trust
that you will study this document at length.
I am sure that you have concluded that time is urgent on this subject. If we are going
to make any move or consider making any move, the foregoing topics need to be opened
up very soon. I am pondering my responsibility to open those topics before the public.
Your suggestions or advice will be sincerely appreciated. Thank you very much.
95
</dc:description>
<dc:description>Article reflects on Murfreesboro City Schools between 1940 and 1950 and makes recommendations for the future. Encompasses the story of school segregation and integration.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Murfreesboro (Tenn.); Public schools</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Murfreesboro City Schools</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>19 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-01-26; mt2011-02-02</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication34ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/17</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>