<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>The Childress family of Tennessee</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Childress, John Williams</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 16</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1981</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>18th century; 19th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>THE CHILDRESS FAMILY OF TENNESSEE
Compiled by
John Williams Childress
37Ca Oliver St., H. W.
Washington, D. C.
I960
Our great grandfather, Joel Childress, was bom on March 22, 1777 &#8226;
He married Elizabeth Whitsitt, 1781 - 1863, cane to Tennessee from Virginia,
and settled January 17, 1799, in Svunner Counter, vhere his children were
bom. About 1812 he moved to Rutherford, a newly formed counly, and
bought a farm about three miles south of Nurfreesboro, situated where
Stones River is crossed by the Shelbyvllle Pike. There was a large
frame house in which he lived until his death, August 19, 1819. He was
buried in a fence -enclosed family plot near the house. Among his activities
he was the Postmaster of Murfreesboro.
I well remember his grave in the apple orchard, irtiich was marked by
a ten-foot stone resting iq&gt;on six coluims to a base. The top stone con-tained
the inscription: "Joel Childress, son of John, son of Joel&#187; irfio
emigrated from Wales, in his owi ship with cargo, in the year 17U5." The
last two digits of the date were very dim but my brother and I agreed
upon "145." His migration in his own ship was of frequent occurrence where
the migrant had sufficient means to outfit such transportatlcxi, since it
was well known that a ship and its contents coiild readily be sold at a
profit, thus giving the emigrant ready capital. He landed probably in
Virginia, or possibly North Carolina, since the name is found in both states,
but Joel and his wife were both bom in Virginia. Her mother was PoUy
Sevier.
Upon a visit with ray family to Tennessee in 1923, I was distressed
20
to find no trace of the gr&amp;^e, but foimd that the two large stones had
been used by the then oi&#171;ier of the nearby cottage. Just built as fire-place
bases. At least the inscription above had been left t^idemea'^ and
1
did not show at the floor level.
After Joel's death, his widow moved into town and lived there until
her death In I863. Elizabeth VJhitsitt's oil portrait is in the home of
my niece and her great, great niece, Harriet Childress Tune, Nashville, Tenn.
There were six children of Joel and Elizabeth, but two died in
infancy. The others were Anderson, 1799-1837; Susan, I8OI-I878; Sarah,
1803-1891; and John Whitsitt, I8O7-I88J4. All were given the best educational
advantages available. Andersen went to Chapel HiU College (now the
University of North Carolina); Susan and Sarah were sent to the famous (and
first) girls' school In the country, the Moravian Church Acadengr, Salem,
N..C. John entered the 1822 class at Chapel Hill. Andersen graduated In
1818, but John spent only one year, his schooling cut to one year, pre-sumably,
by his father's death in I819. The girls and their brother ibiderson
rode horseback from Middle Tennessee to Salem (some 500 miles), he going
on farther about 100 miles to Chapel Hill, and picking them up in the spring
for return home. They were acconpanled only by a faithful slave to look
after the horses and baggage.
In Anderson's class were several close friends, among than James
Knox Polk, later President of the United States, also Jamas Otey and
Green, who were to become the first Episcopal Bishops of Tennesse and
Alabama, respectively. By coincidence, my son-in-law, James Otey (Bill)
Urquhart, is the great-grandson of Bishop Otey, for irfiom he is named. It
^ This tombstone was found when the Butler Manufacturing Company was
built and was placed at Cannonsburg.
21
was also qidta natiiral that Sarah Childress should meet and marry Jlmngr
PoUc when he came to Murfreesboro&#8212;then the State Capital&#8212;^in his first
political Job as Secretary of the State Legislature.
For the story of Sarah and James Polk, see any history book, but
particularly the two, "Young KLckory" and "Memorials to Sarah Childress
Folk.** The only other known copy of the latter book is in the Congressional
Library in Washington.
As is well known, Sarah Childress lived for U2 years after her
husband's death in I8U9, continuing to the end to occupy the fine estate
the President had bought shortly before his term expired. She lived
singly but, making no visits except to Murfreesboro and Columbia, kept
practically open hoiise to old friends. She died in I89I. As a boy I was
taken to see her at regular intervals. I remember her with affection. }ty
father was the favorite of all her relatives. At death. Aunt Sarah was
buried beside her husband, until both were transferred to a Joint tomb on
the Capitol grounds.
Susan Childress married Dr. Rucker and had two dau^ters. These
girls visited their Aimt in the White House.
The farm and house on Stones River were inherited by my grandfather,
John Whitsitt, and were successfully operated by him until his death,
although late in life he moved to town to a house at College and Academy
Streets, which was owned by his second wife. This house s.tiU stands and
a picture of It can be found in the book called "History of Rutherford
County." The caption of this picture reads; John W. Childress frequently
entertained in this house his brother-in-law. President Polk." This is, of
course, an error as Polk died in I81i9.
In 18$3 John W. Childress built, on the site of his father's house,
22
a very modem and inposing two-atory brick, ^rfiich I visited oftai as a boy
of 12 to 1$, \A\en it was owned by lay cousinj .Frank Avent. At Frank's
marriage this hovise and farm were given to him hy his father as a wedding
present. I often stayed with them jiist to be in the country and to live
in the old place. At 10 I had learned to swin in the nearly Stones River,
and Frank, a great dog fancier and huntsman, would let me hunt with him.
I remember toy grandfather only at his funeral in I88I1, but the country
place forever stands out in my memory.
That 1853 house was built of brick made on the place, and of stone
from the River. The portico was stcne, with 3-foot in diameter stone
columns extending above the second floor. Inside was a large entrance
hall, with curving, "flying, "-no visible support- stairway, with strong
bannisters. All rooms were I6 to 20 feet in height, each with about two
foot frieze, the whole being of such hard plaster (no paper) that I have
often wondered about the lost skill of such constiruction.
I don't remember the size of the farm, but it extended East about
one-half mile to the railifoad track and the same distance to the River in
the other direction. The house was set about one-fifth of a mile from the
gate at Pike lAere it crossed Stones River and was reached by a curved
driveway, marked by red cedar trees. When I last saw the property (1923)
the last one of these trees had just been cut down for firewood, but ny
girls gathered some of the sweet smelling cedar chips as souvenirs. The
house had two rooms, both sides of hall, both storeys, and an Ell, with
full porch in the front.
The most outstanding memory of the house was that the portico, the
colums and the room walls were conpletely covered with pencil and charcoal
names and regiments of Federal soldiers stationed at or near the house, who
had spent their time &#8226;Taeautifying it with their 'art'," Actually, many
names had been chiseled with nail and haniner almost to the roof, and many
23
of them were well done from the operators point of view. The plaster of
that day was so hard that little harm had been done to the room walls.
When the Federal troops took over Murfreesboro in the summer of
l862j lay grandfather was forced to refugee with his daughters and small
children to North Georgia, where he remained until the end of the war.
His house and farm were i.iBnediately taken over and occi^ied by three
'&#8226;cau9&gt;follower" families, who worked the farm and slaves during the period,
taking, of course, all benefits from them as their profit as "conquerors."
VHiile the land was overworked and the servants mistreated, it is quite
possible that this occupancy by Northerners may have preserved the place
from complete destructicxi, as happened to many other Southern owners vAio
were less fortunate.
In this connection occurred an unusxial and interesting incident.
During the war ray father happened to be in the vicinity of the place and
so made bold to ride up to the house to look things over. This he could
do because he wore a long, blue Union overcoat ^ich he had taken from a
captured Negro soldier. His inquiries of one of the squatters as to who
owned this place, etc. were being insolently answered as became the sqooatter's
right when dealing with a private, even a Unionist. Just then there
appeared, however, a small Negro boy who had come out to gather chips from
the woodpile. He glanced t^ and in astonishment said: "Fore God, if it
ain't Little Marse JohnJ" Whereupon father showed his Confederate uniform,
forced the man to go with him across tshe river&#8212;by wading&#8212;and turned him
over to the military authoritites. When the family returned from Georgia,
no one was found of the three former "owners," but they left their marks
on the property.
I dcai't know how and when this place got out of the Childress family,
for I remember it only after its purchase by father's brother-in-law, James
M, Avent, for Frank. In I896, while at school at Bell Buckle, Tenn., the
principal, Sawney Webb, called me aside to tell me Uiat, as he was passing on
2U
the train the night before, he happened to look out of the window and
saw the house being destroyed by fire. I never knew how it happened,
but I never forgot ray grief at the loss of the old house I loved.
Grandfather also owned and operated another and larger farm about
ten miles East of Murfreesboro, Most of his 150 slaves were stationed
here, but only the overseer staff lived there.
While ccntinviing to operate his two farms. Grandfather had other
interests in town, being organizer and president of two banks, and was,
from its beginning in 18$3&#187; a Director of the Nashville and Chattanooga
Railroad. His rather distinguished career is told in considerable detail
in a clipping from a Nashville paper which will be found in my mother's
scrapbook, in the suitcase. While this obituary is signed only "A.S.C,"
it was written by Col, Arthur S. Colyax, owner of the "Nashville American,"
to my father's law partner in the firm of Colyax, Marks and Childress. The
other partner, Marks, was a former Governor of Tennessee, and Colyax was
a famous orator and former member of the Confederate Senate. I have always
believed that, while the firm had probably the largest law practice in the
State, the partners let father do all the work, resulting in his breakdown
of health and his retirement&#8212;l86Ii to 1888&#8212;to Florida. However, he re-covered
and led an active and useful life for many years.
By his first wife, Mary Williams of Nashville (for whom I am named),
my grandfather had four sons who lived to full maturity and two daughters.
Two of these sons were my father, John Whitsitt, Jr., and Joseph. The latter
had two daughters, Mary Kee and Sarah Polk, but Joe died when they were child-ren.
John's older daughters were Mary, who married James Monroe Avent, and
Bettie, who married Major General John Calvin Brown, of Pulaski. Avent took
my father in as law partner \intil he moved to Nashville in 1882. We were always
very close to the Avent family, my younger brother bearing that name. The only
remaining member (i960) is Sara, who still lives in the old house and has
25
one son, Jesse C. Beesley, New York. The other dau^ter, Bettle,
married James B. Murfree, Jr. His widow STunrived hire until 1959. She
was 92 at the time of her death* The third brother was James M&#171;, Jr.
Bettle Childress married Brown while refugeeing in Georgia, and
''between battles" of the war. They returned to Pulaski, from which he
was elected Tennessee's Oovernor in 1870. Later they moved to Nashville,
where he died in 1869. At which time he was President of the Texas k
Pacific Railroad. There were two daughters, Marie and Daisy, and a son,
John. No males of the name survive.
It was while living with the Browns in Pulaski that my father
studied law, and in 1870 was made Manager (at 25) of Brown's cainpaign
for Governor. That was his first experience in politics, and probably
led to his 25 years as head (Ghairman)of the Democratic Party in the State.
While he retired as Chairman when he became a judge in 1895, he was until
his death (1908) always consulted and followed in political matters.
It was also at Pulaski that my father became one of the organizers
of the original Ku KLux Klan. (For the conplete and torue story of the
Klan, see its history in the Ridley book. This gives the only true history
of its beginnings, its operations, and its end, and could have been written
only ty one who knew the story perscxially. ) I could never get father to
admit his membership, for the Federal laws against it were never repealed;
but there can be no doubt that he was one of the boys i*o started the KKK
in 1867, when he was living in Pulaski. All KLansmen were yo\mg Confederate
officers and the original groi^ got together as a club or fraternity for
fun only. The later KKK activities were brought about for protection against
outrages of the scalawags and carpetbaggers who were exciting the Negroes
to crimes.
Incidentally, this Ridley book is now considered a "collector's item"
because the writer's story of his return home af^ar the surrender of the
26
Canfdderate Army Is the only )aio\ia account of that phase of a soldier's
llfe&#187; Several histories of that period quote Ridle7*8 dlazy for the
only picture of a Confederate's thoughts aiid acts after his parole.
}ty father also surrendered at the same time In North Carolina, but all
I could get out of hire was that he burst into tears many tines a day
during the long trip to Tennessee. Incidentally, Ridley wsis also from
Rutherford Cotmty be he and father never met during the war. He married
my mother's youngest siifc^er^Ideyette, while she was visiting mother in
Hurfreesboro. "Uncle Brom" was one of the finest and most lovable persons
I ever knew, and his book&#8212;of which he was very proud&#8212;is most interesting.
He was, during his whole service, on the staff of Gen. A. P. Stewart&#8212;CSA.
After the death of his wife, mj grandfather married Mary Phillips,
a cousin of his former wife, and by her had the following sons and daughters;
William Sumner, \^o married Inez Wade;
The second son of William was Levi Wade, who lived nearly all his
life in St. LoTiis, Mo. He died abcut three years ago, leaving one dau^ter
and two sons: Wade, Jr. and Fielding, and his widow, all of \ihom 1 believe
to be alive.
Another son of John Wiitsitt Childress, Eugene, was never married
and died while relatively a young man. The last one, Horace, had no sons,
nor did Annie, nor Ella, and the baby of the family&#8212;Selene&#8212;had no children,
though married twice&#8212;first to Jonathan W. Jackson, and then to Frederick
Wighthall.
With the death of his father in I88I4, my father John Whitsitt Jr.
(AprU 20, 18U5 - March 28, 1908) became the beloved head of the family
and was so recognized by all. He had little education since he ran away
frOTi Military school to Join the Confederate Army and never returned. He
did, however, acquire an excellent knowledge of law while studying in
Gen. Brown's office in Pulaski, and proved his capacity when he served in
27
Nashville as Circuit Court Jtidge for the last 13 years of his life, as
well as in his only active practice after moving to Nashvlll@c But he
served capably and successfully in many other capacities, incltiding
Qeneral Manager of the "American" Newspaper, Assistant U. S. Attorney,
President of the South Pittsburg City Co&#187; operating the utilities and
building \sp of that town and organizing and presidi^ as President of a
National Bank which is still&#8212;after 75 years&#8212;the strongest institution
in that section of the State. In every capacity and situation he was sought
after for advice and assistance. His best-known seirvice was as advisor
of the Democratic Party in politics. This began as Caiopaign Manager
for his brother-in-law, John C. Brown, in his successful race as first
Democratic Governor after the war, in 1870, at the age of 25, From then
until his judgeship in 1895 &#187; he was Chairman of the Democratic Committee,
at vrtiich time he gave up the title for ethical reasons, \Mt continued in
his advisory capacity until the end. Amazing to say, with all his political
activities, and the usual unpleasant feelings thus engendered, I don't
believe he ever had a personal or political enemy. Partly, no doubt, his
popularity was due to his wanting no office for himself, his only interest -^
being to find the right man for the place in his Party. Thus, every Governor
and U. S. Senator depended ^xpaa him. In fact he declined appointment to
the U. S. Senate by Governor Taylor, and later declined an election to that
body by the State Legislature, which was trying to break a long deadlock
between two candidates--Taylor and McMiUin. He did not want the job any-way,
but spumed the appointment because both men were his close friends and
he would be put in a position of profiting by their defeat. The Legislature
acted, apparently, to get itself out of a long deadlock which seemed endless.
It did end, however, when a third man, Luke Lea, became a candidate through
the proper pressure (money?) to break the tie. Taylor, after three terms
as Governor, later became a United States Senator. McMillin, after being
28
Governor, and after 20 years in the House of Representatives, died Just
after his appointment&#8212;1933&#8212;as Ambassador to Mexico, His second wife,
Lucile, was made a TOmber of the Civil Service Commission in Washington.
McMillin first married lay cousin, Marie Brown (General Brown's daughter).
Both Taylor and McMillin were devoted friends of father's and I also kept
up my friendship with them until their deaths.
In the late days of father &#187;3 life he was often \mable to hold Court
and the docket was so full that someone had to carry on. Volunteers were
welcome and the man most helpful in these emergencies was Cordell Htill, a
young Judge with 13 counties in his Circuit, who could still come to
Nashville to help out. I realized later that he did so at his own expense.
Hull was, however, one of father's political proteges, as well as friend,
and he probably profited by the experience and association. Another sudi
protege was Joseph W. 5yms, later Speaker of the House. When Hull was
Secretary of State he took occasion at several public gatherings in Washing-ton
to introduce me as the "son of the man who taught me all the politics
I know, if any." I recall two occasiois at the Jackson Day Dinners, and at
other tiiiBS when he was a guest In my home. I knew most of the Tennessee
Delegation and Byms and Hull were most helpful in my one entry into poUtica&#8212;
the appointment by President Coolidge as Chairman of the D. C. Public Utilities
Commission in 1926.
Vty father was in 1861 at military school in Nashville, but his parents
were endeavoring to keep him out of the war because of his health and
weighing only 90 pounds, and believed by them to have "consuTiqjtion." They
thought military life would be fatal. However, he ran away from school and
Joined the array at Bowling Green, Ky., in October, 1861. He was sent to
Fort Donelscn just in tiro to 8\irrender. From there he was sent by flat-boat
to Columbus. Ohio, and then on to prison camp at Johnson's Island, near
Sandusky, Ohio.
29
At the end of nine months he was exchanged, at Vicksbvirg, Miss.,
and iranediately returned to the army. At the beginning he became drill-master
and Adjutant of the 50th Tennessee Regiment, and remained with that
organization. He was four times wounded, once shot entirely through the
thigh, and in the head at Franklin. In the futile charge over Federal
breastworks he crossed the Harpeth River, climbed up and was on the point
of Jun^jlng down into the trench when a bullet tore away his right eyebrow
and he was left for dead. About midni^t he cane to life to find himself
in the burial ditch, but, most fortunately, near the top and so able to
climb out and crawl back to the lines. VJhile his life was saved in this
miraculous manner, he escaped the amy's collapse at Nashville two weeks
later. Despite the annihilation of the Western Am^r, three divisions were
gotten together (in part, of course) and reached Johnson's Army in North
Carolina, only to be surrendered. This formality occurred for him on his
20th birthday, April 20.
Father was always known and spoken of as "Captain Childres" until he
became a Judge, but he never used either title when speaking of himself
over phones or otherwise. From the time he entered the army, he was an
officer. Adjutant, but drill -master also because he was probably the only
man in his reginent who had any knowledge at all of military matters. The
framed Commission on my wall shows him still a Lieutenant and Adjutant in
September, 186U, and it is pres\imed he was promoted to Captain after Franklin
on November 30th. I know that he was breveted Major before the surrender,
but he never used the higher rank.
After serving ^ years in arny and prison he returned to Murfrees-boro,
but soon Joined his brother-in-law, General Brown, for the study of
law. Upon conqjletion of these studies he Joined another brother-in-law, James
M. Avent, in practice in his home town. In March 1867 he and a friend,
Jim Moore, decided to travel and see the world, which ended four months
30
later after they had seen moat of it. , His diary was an extremely well
written and unusual document for a boy of 21, whose education had been
interrupted by the War, and since he had run away frdm school three months
before he was 17, and never agaiji attended school. The interesting way
he tells the story of this trip indicates the early use of a mind which
enabled him to become the useful and successfxil man for which he was
destined. To me the story tells of places, people, methods of travel,
etc. of which I had no knowledge. While Father told us all these stories
of the trip when we were small boys, this diary's existence was unknown,
to any of us, and was not found until the death of my mother, vrtio survived
him by 20 years. When found then by Lyon, he fortunately, made copies of
it, but I have never been able to come upon the original. It was written
in a small notebook of the time. Also, I have wondered all my adult life
where Father got the money to make the trip and learned only recently that on
his majority he received an inheritance from his grandmother. I certainly
never heard him express regret at the way this was used. I know only that
at the time of his marriage in 1870, and immediate years thereafter, he
and his wife were forced to live very simply. Upon his law partnership
in Nashville, things promptly took a turn for the better. Even with the
three years of idleness while he was recovering his health in Florida, he
was never again so strapped financially and was able to give the three sons
proper education. Not until I had finished iry sophomore year at Princeton
did I realize the strain that cost and his illnesses were causing him. Wiere-upon
I got a job and quit college, Lyon was doing well in business and so
Avent could freely continue and graduate.
While always a loyal Confederate, he never became a "professional,"
as 80 many others were inclined to do. However, he served the Cause out-standingly
in one instance. Probably in his capacity as manager of the
largest newspaper in the State, he attended the funeral of Jefferson Davis
31
In I889. It was there determined that something should be done to
perpetuate the ideals of the Sough and collect and disseminate lihe
facts. Father was Chairman of a Coranittee to effect these p\irposes and
they decided to act through a magazine, "The Confederate Veteran."
Father chose as editor an editorial writer on the American, Scanner A,
Cunningham, Through the efforts and intelligence of this man, the
magazine became the "Bible" of the veteran every%rtiere, and at the same
time became a most interesting and financially successful literary venture.
Its publication continued until its editor's death, and until the vast
majority of the old boys were gone. I was very fond of Mr. Cunnin^am and
he almost worshipped rny father.
My mother was Mary Adair Lyon (August 6, IBU? - September 29, 1928),
oldest daughter of James Adair and Adelaide Deaderick lyoft of Columbus,
Miss. It was while she was visiting some Deaderick kin in Murfreesboro&#8212;
the Wendell3~that she met ray father and they were married in Columbus on
December 13,
David Deaderick (originally Dletrick) had come as a "Pennsylvania
Dutchman" from Germany, 1720, settled first in that state, moved to Vln-chester,
Va., anglicized his name to Deaderick. Again migrated to Tennessee,
founded its oldest town&#8212;Jonesboro&#8212;and his son, David Anderson, was father
of ray grandmother, Adelaide, 1817 - 1907.
Icon's family was almost equally distinguished in East Tennessee,
but he put himself through four years at Princeton Theological Seminary
(New Jersey), 1832 - 1836, after which he had churches in Tennessee and
Columbus, Miss, St. Louis and again in Columbus, with the last ten years
of his life as Professor of Religion and Philosophy at the University of
Mississippi. His Journals and pertinent data are in the State Archives at
Jackson, and at the Mississippi State College at State College, Miss.
lyon was almost a fanatic on education. He personally educated his
32
two older sons to enter the junior class at Princeton (then the College
of New Jersey), to graduate in the Class of 1859, the younger one being
first in his class. The third son graduated in 1872, but he got through
mostly on earned scholarships. He sent my mother to a fashionable and
expensive finishing school in Philadelphia. Just how all this was done on
his salary as a Presbyterian Minister will always remain a inystery, althou^
he didn't seem to think it so. He also, almost alone, founded in Clarks-ville,
Tenn., a Presbyterian College, built on the lines at the Princeton
seminary, although he was assisted some\*at by a Dr. William Stewart and
by Dr. Joseph R. Wilson (Woodrow's father). Lyon was elected (in 1870)
ttie first president. He pron?)tly accepted but later reneged because his
church just refused to let him go. His son, Adair, later became a pro-fessor
there and I spent one year &#8212;1898-99&#8212;as a student before trans-ferring
to Princeton. The whole story of the College and I^yon's part in it
ts told in Cooper's history&#8212;"Southwestern at Menphis"&#8212; . This book gives
sole credit to Lyon as the real founder. In 1925 the City of Men^jhis took
over the records, etc. and brou^t them to that city, with a change in the
name of "Southwestern at Menphis" from its old and well-known "Southwestern
Presbyterian Itaiversity." While still under Presbyterian auspices, it is
a thriving co-educational institution, which has put new life in the old
Clarksville school of which I and hundreds of alumni are still fond, but of
which thei'e are so few left. To illustrate, there was published in the
Southwestern News, in 1958, a picture of the I898 football team&#8212;of which
I was captain. There was found no one left of the 17 members except ityself.
I have the original photograph.
Yfy mother was remarkable woman in many ways. First, she was a great
beauty and always admired, but never seemed to be conscious of that. At
about UO her hair was anow white and set off her ruddy con9)lexion and black
eyes. She was vivacious, a great talker but never a gossip, and made friends
33
readily and permanently. She was not, however, a "society woman," but
preferred churoh work, and to the end remained a "ftoidamMital Christian."
She was at horns in any gathering, society or church, and was greatly
beloved, being a foil for n^r quiet father. She was one of the last of the
old -timers who hated Uquor and worldy things," even begging me, for
axauple, not to dance or play cards even after I went away to college.
While we all wandered away from our strict upbringing, we always respected
her wishes and principles.
The sons of John Whitsltt and Mary lyon Childress were Adair lyon
(always called lyon), John Williama, and Avent. They were born, respect-ively,
August 31, 1873, February 16, 1879, and November 30, 1880. lyon
died in October 19U8. A dau^ter was bom dead in 1872. All seven
children of these three sons are girls and, therefore, the Childress name
of the earlier branch of the family is now ended.
31&#187;
</dc:description>
<dc:description> </dc:description>
<dc:description>A history of the Childress family in Tennessee, of which Sarah Childress Polk, wife of President James Polk, was a part</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Polk, Sarah Childress, 1803-1891; Polk, James K. (James Knox), 1795-1849; Rutherford County (Tenn.); Family history; Genealogy</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>29 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-15;mt2011-02-16</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication16ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/41</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>