<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>From Jefferson to Elkhorn tavern: The Story of Ben McCulloch</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Pittard, Homer</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 11</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1978</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>18th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>7 &#8212;
-
FROM JEFFERSON TO ELKHORN TAVERN?
The Story of Ben McCulloch
By Homer Pittard
Ben McCulloch, a Rutherford Countian, has almost a muted enshrinement
in the pantheon of heroes. He gained fame during the Texas Revolution, the
Mexican War, as a Texas Ranger, and finally as a Confederate general officer
during the Civil War. let, Texas history has made only a token curtsey in
his direction. One rather petulant McCulloch admirer measured his hero
alongside Davy Crockett, a Texas immortal:
"Crockett, \rfio was in Texas but a few; weeks and fought but
twelve days, is known as one of the state's great heroic characters;
McCulloch served Texas a quarter of a century, rendering
a thousand times more service than did Crockett. The former
fought one battle, the latter fought in three wars, to say nothing
of Indian engagements by the score. Both died a sacrifice
to the cause which the state espoused. let Crockett is known as.
one of Texas' greatest men, while McCulloch is all but unknown."
Also, reference should be made to the fact that the Confederacy appointed
McCulloch to the rank of brigadier general on May 14-, 1861, the identical day
that the venerable Robert E. Leo was elevated to the same officer rank.
These two led the vanguard of appointments above the colonelcy level followed
some thirty days later by storied gray heroes James Longstreet, Albert Sidney
Johnston, Joseph E. Johnston, Thomas "Stonewall" Jackson, and Jeb Stuart.
Ten months later a minie ball ended McCulloch' s military career at Pea Ridge,
or Elkhorn Tavern. Despite his considerable friction at times with fellow
officers and superiors, his star was on the rise. It is conjecture, of
course, as to what his status in Confederate history, as well as Texas lore,
would have been had he survived the four-year struggle.
Ben McCulloch was born near Jefferson in Rutherford County on November 1
1
,
^Webb, "Exploits of the Texas Rangers", p. 24.
""Warntjr, Generals in Gray . (Random references)
8
1811. His parents were Major Alexander McCulloch of North Carolina and
Frances LeNoir of Virginia, Alexander was an aide-de-camp to General James
Coffee in the Creek War and the War of 1812. The Major, inheriting with
his brother, a large plantation, several slaves, money, and considerable
unimproved land in Tennessee, came with his brother to middle Tennessee
3
near the turn of the century and settled along Stone's River. He v/as a
graduate of Yale and was described by his son, Henry Eustace, as "one of
the stern men of his day with great decision of character."'* Despite his
impressive educational background and generous inheritance, his penchant
for the life of a wastrel and his habit of lavishing his friends with gifts
and money, left scarce support for the education of his burgeoning family:
six sons and six daughters. In addition to Ben, there were Henry Eustace,
who was to win a modicum of fame as a Texas Ranger and Confederate brigadier;
Alexander, a Mexican V/ar participant and a colonel of militia in
Dyer County; John S., a Confederate captain in the quarter-master's department;
Samuel, a merchant in Florence, Alabama; and James C, the youngest
brother, a rheumatic invalid who died in 1862. The j^ix sisters were Sarah
Stokes, who married Albert Keehle of Rutherford County; Mary Annie, who
married William L. Mitchell of Rutherford County and died in Gonzales,
Texas; Francis Olivia, who married Charles Parish of Weakley County, Tennessee;
Harriet Maria, who married Nat Benton, a nephew of Thomas H. Benton,
captain of a company of Texas Rangers, and an officer in the Confederate
amy; Elizabeth Julia, who married Robert H. Tarrant, a Methodist preacher
of Dyer County; and Adelaide Delia, v/ho married Albert C. Pierce, also of
5
Dyer County.
^Rose, Ben McCulloch , p. 14&#171;
^bid, p. 15.
5
Speer, Encyclopedia of the New West, p. 281
.
General Ben McCulloch. It is
possible that this is an example
of trick photography with the
head mounted on a "standard"
body.
McCulloch marker near Brady,
Texas city limits. Brady is
the county seat of McCulloch
County,
~^fts^
*:, ^'^i#^-v-vU
&#8222;&#171;i.&#187;tMp.^ &#8226;'.^ f
Elkhorn Tavern,
Arkansas&#8212;McCulloch
was killed near here.
Note the antlers on
the roof.
10
Alexander worked at the surveyor's trade, and it is conjectured that
he plotted the county seat of Jefferson for speculators Thomas Bedford and
Robert Weakley when Rutherford County v/as established in 1803. He is
listed as one of the petitioners for the forming of the new county on
August 10, 1803 and as the first trustee of the new political entity.
Deed abstracts and other records of the period show; a diversification of
real estate activities on the part of the elder McCulloch. He served as
witness for several real estate transfers and bought and sold land himself.
In the fall of 1820, for some unexplainable reason, Alexander loaded
his family and household furniture on the plantation wagons and ox carts
and moved to Alabama &#187; There at Muscle Shoals along the Tennessee River,
he continued his surveying activities and efforts at farming.
Ben, almost ten years of age at the moment of his removal to Alabama,
augmented his one year of schooling at Jefferson vrith a fev/ months at the
neighborhood school some three miles from his home. Beyond this, his
lessons were learned from the practicalities of the frontier life and a
voracious appetite for reading. Near the McCulloch home was the favorite
winter camping grounds of the Choctaw Indians. From them he learned the
intricate basics of building canoes, tracking animals and humans, and, in
particular, the habits and lore of Indians.^ This knowledge was to serve
him well v/hen he later found himself a Redman adversary on the Texas plains.
In 1830, the McCullochs loosened their roots again and moved back to
Tennessee, three miles from Dyersburg in West Tennessee, Ben, then nine-teen
years of age, was sent ahead vrith ox-carts containing most of the
"Publication No. 2&gt; Rutherford County Historical Society, p. 55.
7
Wray, Rutherford County Deed Abstracts . (Random references)
g
Dictionary of American Biography, p. 5-
'^Gunn, Ben McCulloch . p. 20.
11
household furniture, the Negroes, and livestock. Major McCulloch had
calculated to arrive first, but when he arrived, Ben was waiting and had
selected the site for the cabin, farm, and spring. In addition, several
house logs had been cut.
Once ensconced in his new home some twenty miles from the Mississippi,
his restless and active spirits came into full flower. He built a large
pirogue and began trapping in earnest, along with operating a low-key trans-port
business. His constant hunting companion, despite the disparity of
ages, was Davy Crockett who lived in the neighboring county. In the spring
of 1832, Ben left for Independence, Missouri, where he had hoped to join a
trapping party. When he found there was no room for him, he switched to
Galena where he found employment in the lead mines for some twelve months.
Following a restless summer in Wisconsin, Ben returned to Tennessee and
joined with brother Henry Eustace in cutting eind marketing cypress logs-
These were rafted down the Obion River to the Mississippi and then to Natchez
1? where the logs were sold.
Confinement to a precise occupation for any extended length of time
appeared to accentuate Ben's restlessness. It was natural that he should
turn his attention to Texas. On rafting trips to Natchez, he frequently
visited New Orleans where he had searched for the grave of one of his kins-
13
men, St. John Petersen LeNoir, an uncle. In the Crescent City, he heard
tales about the struggles of Americans in the new land above the Rio Grande
and, in particular, the report of atrocities by Mexican soldiers. Too, many
Rose, Ben McCulloch . p. 3A.
^^Ibid, p. 40.
12
Gunn, Ben McCulloch . p. 4-0.
Reid, The Scouting Expeditions of McCulloch ' s Texas Rangers , p. 24.,
12
Tennesseans had already left for Texas. Neighbor Davy-- Crockett was poised
for the trek west. Supposedly, he had confided in Ben that if he were un-successful
in his re-election campaign for Congress, he would follow the
Tennessee exodus to Texas and would invite his young neighbor and some
other West Tennesseans to accompany him. To complete the story, Crockett
lost his 1835 re-election bid and shortly thereafter, the first of October,
he left for Texas. Fortunately or unfortunately, according to one's degree
of preference for immortality, Ben could not leave his farm chores at
the time. Possibly a month later, with his home obligations completed, he,
accompanied by his young brother, struck out for the Crockett trail. They
crossed the Mississippi at Memphis, then to Little Rock, crossed Red River
at Compton, and then took the Gaine's Ferry at the Sabine to Mexico. At
this point Henry Eustace was persuaded to return to the family farm in Dyer
15
County, remain for two years, and then join his brother. Early in January
of 1836, Ben set out alone on foot for San Antonio. At the Brazos
River a kind fate intervened, and he was delayed several weeks by measles.
On February 23, the Alamo siege began with 169 valiants, including Crockett,
facing Santa Anna's 5,000 Mexicans. Thirteen days later, the mission fort
fell with all of the remaining defenders being summarily placed before the
firing squad. '6
In the midst of the angry outcry that follovied the butchery at San
Antonio, Ben MoCulloch entered the portals of his destiny. He immediately
joined Sam Houston's rag-tag army and thus geared himself for his role in
the Revolution. He was twenty-four* years of age upon his entry into Texas
"&#8226;"^Ibid, p. 35.
1
5
Rose, Ben McCulloch . p. 60.
G'lnn, Ben McCulloch . p. 36.
13
and was described as "five feet, ten inches in height, slightly thin, but
muscular arms and shoulders gave him the appearance of an athlete. Sharp
blue eyes illuminated his keen features." Ben must be categorized as
one of the free spirits of his time- Never affiliating himself with a
religious faith, he also studiously avoided marriage, thus remaining a
dedicated bachelor during his fifty-one years. Sam Houston who later became
a close friend of the Rutherford Countian, concluded one of his letters to
McCulloch with this warning: "Never get married. "^^ This was obviously an
iraploration in jest, but the warning was possibly of no serious consequence
to McCulloch, since he had already set his course. Some disposition toward
shyness may have motivated Ben to choose the life of single solitude. Once
when stationed in Washington, D.C., he visited White Sulphur Springs, Virginia
in an effort to escape the searing heat in the nations 's capital.
This excerpt from a letter to his mother may imply his acceptance of the
loner's role and his slightly cloaked reticence and discomfort in the company
of the opposite sex: "People were there (the resort) for three reasons.
These were to drink, gamble, and make love. I'm not handsome enough to marry
to advantage or sufficiently dishonest to be a successful gambler. The only
advantages offered me were health and knowledge." However, there is some
evidence that he was not completely oblivious to the allurements of the at-attractive
female. Ben's patrol duties later as a Texas Ranger carried him
through many of the Mexican villages. The brownskin native woman, naked to
the waist by custom, were observed strolling through the streets or staiiding
agape at the passing horsemen. A companion rider reported that "Hen McCuiioch
^'^Ibid, p. 4.3.
'^Ibid,, p. 91.
^^Ibid, p. '8.
14
20
spoke enthusiastically of the unveiled charms of the Coir?.rgo". Probably
the best explanation for his choice of life style v.'as his restlescnccs and
hxs passion for mobility. Apparently never satisfied vrith a task or activity
for any length of time, he was forever in search of aev; vistas end
physical challenges. One observation of McCulloch, if near the truth,
pi'obably places him in the proper perspective, thus explaining his intense
individuality and the rationale for remaining single and unencumbered: "He
was flamboyant, headstrong, intelligent, coarse, sometimes bnatnl, usually
profane".'^^
McCulloch' s first combat action came at San Jacinto on April 2, 1836,
a battle that proved to be the deciding engagement of the Revolution. It
was not difficult for an aggressive, outspoken, and combative young man of
twenty-four to attract the attention of Houston in his tiny force of no more
than 80C. Ben was pulled from the line and placed in command of one of the
"Two Sisters", two pieces of artillery which represented the total heavy
22
ordnance complement of the Texans. The battle was over in fifteen minutes
with an almost complete destruction of the 1500 Mexican army with General
Santa Anna among the captured. Ben's courage and ability demonstrated in
directing the maneuver and fire of the "Twin Sister" resulted in his pro-
23
motion next day to first lieutencjit. ^ An unknown versifier gave some
small iaanortalization to McCulloch' s performance in the fray in a poem en-titled,
"Ben McCulloch at San Jacinto". Here is a sample from the nine-verse
effort: "Hurrah for stout Ben I and hurrah for the band/ That gave freedom
21
Ibid, p. 107.
22
Rose, Ben McCulloch . p. 101.
The "Twin Sisters" were contributed by a ladies organization in Cincinnati
23
Barker, "San Jacinto Campaign", p. 237.
15
to Texas that day/ And hurrah for the gun which so bravely was manned/
When the hero was passing that way." ^
Ben's military life ended for the moment after San Jacinto. Bored
with the inactivity of garrison and occasional patrol duty, ho requested
and received a furlough which led him into an exploring foray to Lavaca
and Guadalupe. This was followed by a trip to Tennessee to recruit a
company of troops. After retxirning to Texas and finding himself no
longer obligated to the militai-y, he labored for a few months as a whip-sawyer
in a Houston Ivunberyard. Ben was soon teick in Toanesoee for the
purpose of learning svirveying from his father. After a brief "schooling"
from Major McCulloch, he returned to Texas with residence in Gonzales,
where he anno\mced himself as a surveyor.^ Brother Henry Eustace followed
his brother to Gonzales in July, 1838, and they bunked together in a cabin
two miles from the town. This continued until Henry Eustace was married
in 1840.2^
Surprisingly, Ben McCulloch devoted much of hi 3 time to surveying
during the next few years. In 1839 when Austin was tapped for the Capital
of the state, Ben surveyed and plotted the road from Gonzales to Austin.
However, he always kept a weather eye out for action; tho previous year he
had organized a vigilante unit which later became a contingent of the Texas
Rangers, a famed frontier security force which was formed in San Antonio in
1840. Elected from Gonzales to the first Texas Republic Congress in 1839,
and, in the process, fighting a duel with one Colonel Alonzo Sweitzer, his
opponent (in which he emerged second best with an ugly shoulder wound), he
2/
Rose, Ben McCulloch . p. 45.
^^Ibid, p. 50.
26
fiunn. Pen McCulloch , p. oO,
16
27
served only one term, the political lethar^ at Austin not to his liking.
Interspersed with his sojourn at Austin was his somewhat eager role with
other volunteers in subduing a band of marauding Indians near Gonzales in
March, 1839. This incident, known as the Battle of Peach Creek, served as
a preliminary to a larger drama: the Great Comanche Raid. The Indians,
angered by the incursions by the white man, swept across the southern
plains the following year in a frenzy of stealing, raping, and murdering.
McCulloch, commanding a detachment of Rangers, met the band of over 1,000
28
warriors at PItud Creek on August 12, 184.0 and virtually destroyed them.
The action at Plum Creek catapulted McCulloch into the Republic's lime-light,
and thereafter he retained a high visibility in the military affairs
of Texas. During the early months of 18^2, there were rumors of a possible
Mexican invasion of the Republic, and McCulloch was dispatched to San Antonio
to aid in repelling the invaders. The Mexican troops soon retired,
but the incident provided, in essence, a kind of dress rehearsal for the
29
major conflict that was to erupt four years later. In 18^5, Ben was
elected to the first legislature of the new state of Texas, possibly as a
reward for his military prowess and emerging hero status.:. On April 24, I846,
the Mexican War "officially" began when sixty-three American dragoons were
30
killed on the Rio Grande.
Responding to General Zachary Taylor's clarion call, McCulloch left
his desk at the Capitol and raised a company of Rangers, a highly mobile
unit that traveled lightly and, most Important, required no encumbering
27
Smither, Journal of the Fourth Congress of Texas , p. 13.
28
Rose, Ben McCulloch . p. 55.
^Gunn, Ben McCulloch . p. 80.
^30Ibid, p. 81.
I
17
supply wagons. At this time, Ben was thirty-five years of age and was
remembered as being "rather lean, sinewy, and a fine horseman."-^ David
Wilkins Kendall, a jotirnalist who was attached to the Rangoro, v/as on ar-dent
admirer of the Captain, and his dispatches added much to the McCxilloch
n^rstique, however minimal. He described his hero as "a man of rather delicate
frame, about six feet in height, with light hair and coE^lejdon. His
features are regular and pleasing, though, from long exposure on the frontier,
they have a rather weather-beaten cast. His quick smd bright blue
eyes, with a mouth of thin compressed lips, indicate the cool, calculating,
32
as well as the brave and daring energy of this man." Webb added this
salute: "His face was a mask and his features under such control as to
give no clue of his feelings or emotions, or intentions. It was as natural
for Ben to remain calm in danger as it was to breathe ... His courage
33 may best be described as a complete absence of fear."
McCulloch commanded Ranger units in most of the principal battles of
the war which included Palo Alto, Resaca De La Paliaa, Monterrey, Buena
Vista, Cerro Gordo, Churibusco, and perhaps others. The Ranger companies
under his command "were perhaps the best mounted, armed, emd equipped, and
appointed units that were out in the ranging service. . . . (They) enjoyed
more of the trust and confidence of the commanding general than any other
volunteer company of the invading army."-^^ There is evidence that the Rangers
performed little line duty but occupied their time principally in
scouting, reconnoitering, and spying. However, at Monterrey on September 21
,
31
Rose, Ben McCulloch . p. 75.
32
Kendall, Picayune, June 24, 1SA6.
33
Webb, Texas Rangers , p. 95.
-^'Tleid, McCulloch ' s Rangers , p. 38.
18
the Rangers in scouting the west sector of the fortress city, foxmd a fatal
flaw in the defense. Tvjo limestone heights guarding the city had a ninimmn
of armament on the steep west faces, and this become the vulnerable point
that led to the storming of the works and the eventual capitulation of
Monterrey on September 23. In this pivotal battle, the Rangers led the
onslaught.-'^ Buena Vista also saw the Rangers rise to the attack. At
this time McCulloch held the rank of major-general in the Texas militia.
V/ith the fall of Mexico City in 1848, the war wound down and Bon re-turned
to Texas as a national hero. His response to the wide acclaim was
reported in this manner; "He bore his honors with modesty and shrank instinctively
from any parade of himself; being at all times the plain,
unpretentious citizen; yet in spite of himself, he was also the famous
xinique Ben McCulloch.""^'' At thirty-seven Ben was, indeed, unique. Al-ready
he had begun to embrace some of the eccentricities that were to set
him apart during his remaining fourteen years of life.
In 18^6, during Ben's single-minded involvement in the Mexican War,
Major McCulloch had died in Tennessee. After the war's cessation, McCul-loch
returned to Dyer County to assist his mother in settling the estate.
Retracing his steps to Texas by the way of Huntsville to visit friend Sam
Houston, he ended his military career, for tho time being, after assisting
General David Emanuel Twiggs in xocating the United States posts or forts
along the border of Texas.
Until 1849 he followed the surveying trade again vrith a few years of
unprecedented muting of his wanderlust. During this period, his mother
^Hardeman, Wilderness Calling , p. H7.
^^Gunn, Ben McCulloch . p. 67.
^'^Rose, Ben McCulloch . p. 116.
19
came from Dyersburg to Texas to establish residence near Ben and Henry
Eustace. Early in 184.9 liis thoughts turned to the military again, and he
decided to travel to Washington, D.C. in an effort to exploit his fame or
prestige, if euxy, gained in the late war. Also, there were rumors that
an Indian agency was to be formed. The Indian agency failed to develop,
and his aspiration for a commission in a United States cavalry unit proved
38
fruitless. His ambition, however, died a slow and agonizing death, for
he remained in the Capital City most of the summer and fall and almost
daily appeared before various military tomes of all description to augment
his credentials.-^" Ben's failures may have been attributable to his crude
habits and his personality now bordering on the eccentric. It is possible
that his persistent and gnawing appearances at the office in the War Department
could have easily been interpreted in the spirit of harassment.
Disgusted, he left Washington and was in Austin by September. Gold
had been discovered in California, and all roads led to the Golden State.
Always drawn to the source of action, Ben made his travel preparations and
arrived in San Francisco on December 1, 1849. Apparently, for some unexplainable
reason, he made no particular effort to try his hand at mining
gold. Records show that he left for Los Angeles in January, 1850 on a
mule-buying trip.^ The disposition of the purchase, if any, is not known.
By September, McCulloch was in Sacramento, possibly to be closer to
the mining operations. Nearby, Sutter's Mill, the focal point of the gold
madness, had long passed the boom stage. It was a "city" of some 300 canvass
houses with lots in the market place ranging from $4-00 to $20,000.
38
Gunn, Ben McCulloch . p. 76,
^^Ibid, p. 78.
^ Sacramento Union . September S, 1850, p. 2,
20
The Magnetic Telegraph Company
NORTH, SOUTH, EAST ANQ WEST,
OoiilKtial vUh ti\ tb&lt; fe'itbora Wciuin. Eutin xn/. Xorlhgrn L,^r&gt; &lt;f T&#187;|io|,l
DIRECT SOUrHEftN LINE. NEW YORK TO NEW ORLEfNS
M'\HRINOTUN OmUE NsliODt] HoUI. Peiin&gt;Tlv&gt;ni&gt; Avcixi.- ,iv[ h.iHi Ml t. NEW YORK OTKICI-No il W&#171;U m&#8482;.t
PHILADBI.HHIA OJTICB-lOU onii 107 B.j.ilh Thir.l H,..
Tvnaa aat eoalitionl oa wUeb Mojugoj arc r TCd by ihi* Comp iny (or Trin&#187;nu
Gov, Sa:;. Houston requesting assistance from
McCulloch in the plan for an invasion of
Mexico
.
21
Sacramento, a terminus of the short-lived Pony Express, was the supply
center for prospectors in the northern mines of the I-lother Lode and became
the Capital in 1854.* It mushroomed almost overnight as a reunbunctious,
teeming city of saloons, fandango houses, and gambling dens, all designed
to separate the gold from the miners. Lawlessness stalked the muddy or,
conversely, dusty streets, and, undoubtedly, only a lawmaji in the cast of
a Wyatt Earp could meet the awesome challenges of this frontier town. The
Sacramento sheriff was Joseph McKinney, whose most onerous problem centered
in squatters who converged on the mining crossroads like a plague of locusts.
The sqxiatter regarded all vacant property as public land and at night would
seize unoccupied lots, enclose the areas with "ribbon fences", and construct
shanties. One night after a sqviatter had summarily been evicted from a lot,
forty armed squatters moved to regain it. Facing them were Sheriff McKinney,
the mayor, and several vigilantes rounded up for the occasion. In the street
battle that followed, Sheriff IfcKinney and several squatters were killed.^
A special election was then held to fill the xmexpired term of the
lawnjEUi who had expired, a common occupational hazard of a frontier sheriff.
McKinney 's term had some two years remaining.
Apparently, with scarce regard for the marginal survival record for
law enforcers, ten hopefuls offered themselves to the Sacramento voters.
Ben McCulloch was one of these. Prior to this entry into local politics, he
had foTond a minor government job which required the collection of a twenty-dollar
tax from all foreigners entering the tovm for the first time. Evidently
the Sacramento citizens, those who could vote, were more favorably
inclined toward Ben than the 'Washington officialdom, for he led the ticket
with 678 votes, only one more than his nearest opponent. He was sworn in
&#8226;^^Rolle, California; A History, p. 107.
^Ibld, p. 118.
22
on September 9, 1850. ^ The office was q\iite lucrative. It was reported
that revenue from a variety of sources inflated the Sheriff's annual income
to over $4.0,000, more than the salary of the President of the United States
and three times that of the California Governor send the judges of the
Supreme Court.
^
Although moderately successful, Ben evidenced little interest in his
new elective position. Bookkeeping and other office chores were not to
his liking. He appeared to be principally drawn to the operation of four-teen
quartz mines in which he had made some investment. Also, he found the
time to visit Tennessee during the attenviated term and then to Washington
where he tried unsuccessfully to generate funds to build a mill at one of
the California quartz mines.
His term of office ended in 1852, and Ben returned to Texas. One year
later, March 29, 1853, the long drought of government rejection ended, for
McCulloch was appointed United States Marshal by President Franklin Pierce.
His territory was the Eastern District of Texas vdth headquarters at Galveston.
His appointment being well received by the people, he remained in
the position for nearly eight years. On several occasions his duties
carried him to Washington, where he continued his study of military subjects
including, among others, gunnery, fortifications, cavalry, and infantry.
Hearing that two regiments of riflemen were to be formed, he again sought
to fulfill his long-time ambition by applying for a colonel's rank. For
some reason, he failed once more, although he was offered a commission as
major, whi.ch he declined. Reacting characteristically, he sat down and
^^Sacramento Union . September 9, 1850, p. 2.
^bid, March 15, 1863, p. 2.
Rose, Ben McCulloch . p. 75.
23
wrote an open letter to the National Intelligencer in which he chided the
President for bypassing him in the appointment. VJhethor Pierce ever had
th&#171;- ''letter to the editor" brought to hin attention is not knovm, but some
of the sharp edge of disappointment may have been dulled when McCulloch
was reappointed Marshal for the Eastern District.'*'
In 1858 President James Buchanan appointed McCulloch and L- VJ. Pov/ell,
former governor of Kentucky, as the two commissioners to Utah. There were
grave problems in the Mormon territory, for Brigham Young had literally
forced Federal troops and their officers out of the territory by the simple
expediency of refusing to sell supplies to the military. Acts of violence
were being committed against troops emd Federal property, and two military
installations. Fort Bridges and Fort Supply, were burned by the Mormons.
Toung, as a result, remained in virtvial control of the territory'. The jour-ney
to Utah by the two commissioners v/as not a diplomatic mission but one of
conveying a proclamation ordering the Mormon leader to desist and to use
his influence to reestablish law and order. McCulloch, in light of past
performances, was not equipped persoxmlly for the nicetiv-s of diplomacy,
but, for the purpose of the Utah javint, he appeared to be a logical choice.
On May 27, 1858, the message was forthrightly delivered at Camp Scott and,
after two days of conferences, the matter was settled.^
During the interim preliminary to the impending sectior^al conflict, Ben
returned to V/Washington where he was recorded as purchasing an interest in
what he described as "an apparatus to bore wells." What practical use he
Gunn, Ben McCulloch . p. 91.
'^'^Ibid, p. 80-81.
^Otis, The Utah Expedition , p. 266.
Gunn, Ben McCulloch . p. 86.
2A
subsequently made of this new acquisition is not knovm. Also, dxiring this
period, he resigned his marshalship and was successful in securing an appointment
for brother Henry Eustace to complete his unexpired term. There
were strong efforts made to persuade Ben to become a candidate to replace
United States Senator Sam Houston who was to become Governor of Texas.
McCulloch vehemently declined. late in 1858, Houston devised a visionary
plan to invade Mexico, establish a protectorate over the country, and there-by,
hopefully, reduce slavery to a secondary issue, at least temporarily.
In order to pursue this bizarre plan, he called in several of his friends,
including McCulloch, for assistance. Ultimately, Ben and two other Houston
representatives in search of funds, met with London bondholders in New
York City. The idea was soon set aside, for war clouds were now hanging
menacingly over the country. At the time of Abraham Lincoln's inauguration,
McCulloch was in Washington, and a north persisted that "he was making arrangements,
at the head of a body of secessionists, to take possession of
the city; but, owing to the precautions of General Scott, the idea was
abandoned."''
With the coming of the Civil War, Texas cast her lot with the Confederacy,
much to the dismay of Governor Houston. Although secession had not
been officially declared, the State's Committee on Public Safety was deeply
concerned about a Itaion pocket of resistance at San Antonio. Ben was ad-vanced
to the rank of colonel and instructed to capture the garrison at San
Antonio, With only 4.00 men, he moved and occupied the city in February,
1861; emd, the hero of Monterrey, General David Emanuel Twiggs, seventy-one
years of age at the time, siirrendered without firing a shot, not only the
Rose, Ben McCvaioch. p. 90.
^^ Davis, An Illustrated History of Sacramento County, p. 34..
25
garrison but all of the personnel stationed at the various posts in Texas,
over 2700 troops in all.^ It must be conjectured that the first signifi-cant
engagement of the Civil War might have been triggered at Sa.n Antonio
predating the firing on Federal troops at Fort Sumter, seventy-five days
later. The atmosphere was highly charged in the garrison tovm, and Mc-
Culloch's little band was thirsting for combat, A defense was at first
ordered, but General Twiggs, the "Bengal Tiger" of many stirring engage-ments
in the Southwest, was now old and tired, and the order was counter-manded.
McCulloch's fame in Texas and Confederate history nay have been
greatly enhanced if this "early Sumter" had occurred. Following the events
at San Antonio, Ben was employed by Texas to purchase 1,000 Colt Revolvers
and 1,000 Morse Rifles. He was successful in locating only the revolvers
and, returning from his assignment, he was appointed brigadier general by
President Davis on May 11, 1861, after McCulloch had declined a colonel's
53
rank. His command, with headquarters at Fort Smith, Arkansas, embraced
the military district including the Indian Territory went of Arkansas.
The assignment was specific: "To guard the Territory against invasions
from Kansas and elsewhere. "^^ This initiated the nevi brigadier's brief
service of less than a year as a Confederate general officer.
McCulloch, subsequently stationed near Wilson Creek, Missouri, was
soon to experience his first full-scale engagement. Union Brigadier-General
Nathaniel I^on began a movement from his position in southeast Missouri to
attack the forces at Wilson's Creek. Sterling Price's army combined with
McCulloch's to face I^yon, On August 10, the battle opened with the Confederate
52
Gunn, Ben McCulloch, p. 96.
53
Warner, Generals in Gray , p. 200.
^^ose, Ben McCulloch . p. 175,
26
line being driven several miles from its original position. Only the
tenacious stand and cotinterattack by McCvilloch saved the day, and Vfilson's
Creek became a Confederate victory. ^^ As was his custom, Ben's abrasive
personality usually ran afoul of his fellow officers, this time the target
became the imperious Price, an individxialist in his own right. Price had
the audacity to sharply censure McCulloch for not pursuing the Federals
toward Volia and refusing to cooperate with Price in an advance movement
into central Missouri.
Ben, never one to buckle tinder any criticism, angrily tvimed over his
troops to Price and left for Richmond to plead his case with President
Davis. The description of him as he appeared on the streets of the Confederacy
is in full accord with his habits as a loner and practicing eccentric,
"His face was nearly concealed by a brown beard and mustache. Keen,
gray eyes looked with a piercing glance from beneath shaggy eyebrows; a
brown felt hat placed firmly on iiis headj black and vrtiite checked overcoat,
pants of blue army cloth, the inside half of the legs being lined v/ith buck-skin,
and hands encased in soiled buckskin gauntlets, with not a mark or
ornament to betoken his rank, or attract attention. An observer would have
en
little supposed him to be the famed and dreaded Ben McCulloch."-'
There is no way of knowing just how much or to what degree Davis was
impressed with his picturesque petitioner, but an organizational change was
made in the Missouri and Arkansan troops. General Earl Van Dom was assigned
to the department with both Price and McCxilloch serving tinder his command.
It was March, 1862 before there was further sustained action. General
Sam Curtiss, commander of the Union Army of the Southwest, In February
succeeded in driving both Price and McCulloch from Missouri into northwest
^ Gxmn, Ben McCulloch . p. 110.
^'^Rose, B^ McCulloch . p. 190.
27
Arkansas. Van Dorn marshalled both armies into a unit for an attack against
Curtiss at Pea Ridge near Elkhorn Tavern. The battle opened on March 7 and
throttled down near the close of the next day vd.th disastrous results for
the Confederates. Ben McCulloch was killed in the first day's engagement
near Elkhorn Tavern shortly after eleven o'clock in the morning. Riding
in advance of his troops, he vras shot by a sharpshooter who was later identified
as Peter Pelican, a private in Company B. thirty-sixth Illinois.
Pelican removed a gold watch from the body and later, in carro, displayed
the watch and substantiated the report that he had mortally wounded the
brigadier. To the end in character, Ben, when carried from the battlefield,
was clothed in a suit of black velvet, patent leather high top boots, and
was wearing a light colored broad-brimmed Texas hat. toother description
had him attired in a dove-colored coat, sky-blue panta, and VIellington
boots. ^^ Whatever sartorial habiliments were present during Ben's last
moments, it can be assured that they bore little resemblance *o what would
be regarded as typical officer attire. McCulloch did not die on the battle-field
as several sources have reported but in a field hospital. This description
of the last moments possibly depicts the typical McCiilloch:
He died of his wounds about 11 o'clock the same night, though
he insisted that he wo\ild recover, repeatedly srying with great
oaths that he was not bom to be killed by a Tanl:ee. A few minutes
before he e:q&gt;ired, his physician assvired him that he ha.d but a very
brief time to live. At this, Ben looked up incredulously and say-ing,
"Oh, Hell I" tvimed away his head and never spoke after. I
presume, if Ben be really dead (he is dead, as the order of his
funeral has been published), the Southern papers will put some
very fine sentiment into his mouth in his closing moments; but the
last words I have mentioned are declared to be correct by a prisoner.
They are not very elegant or dramatic, but quite expressive,
and in McCulloch 's case decidedly appropriate.-'^
Texas and the Confederacy needed heroes, and McCiaioch was the first and
most noted to fall, therefore, he became the initial candidate for the state
^^Sacramento Union . April 19, 1862, p. 1.
5%bid, April 2^, 1862, p. 3.
28
and national pantheon. So, after a battle that saw three regiments of
"Confederate" Indians, plied with pro-battle whiskey, murder and scalp both
friend and foe; a mimerically larger Gray arncr outfought and defeated; and
a legendary Westerner, "Wild Bill" Hickock, serve as a scout for the op-posing
Union Array, it was fitting, in the wake of such a bizarre, if not
epochal occasion, that the body of one of its principals should be carried
over 400 miles for proper eulogy and enshrinement. Major John Henry Brown
left Fort Smith, Arkansas on March 10, in an army ambulance with the embalmed
body of McCulloch. On April 9, he arrived in Austin. Along the
way, authorities in several of the coxrnty seats and large towns requested
that the remains lie in state for brief periods and that time be allowed
for ceremonies and eulogies.
The final rites for Tennessean-Texan Ben MoCulloch at Austin is des-cribed
as follows:
The remains of General Ben McCulloch, the hero of Wilson's
Creek, the pride and boast of the amy of the West, were on
Thursday, with all the usual poiop and ceremony attending such
occasions, laid by the side of Burleson, Henphill, and McLeod,
The body laid in state in Representative Hall from four p.m. on
Wednesday, until fo\ir p.m. on Thursday last. About eleven
o'clock, after prayer from Rev. Mr. Phillips and Bishop Gregg,
Captain John Henry Brown, who acted as aid to General McCulloch
in the action in which he lost his life, entertained the large
concourse of citizens that crowded the Representative Hall, with
an address, narrating the thrilling incidents of the battlefield,
and portraying the military acconplishments, patriotism, heroism,
and noble single-heartedness of our Ranger General.
General Henry MoCuD.loch being present, remarked, in a voice
tremulous with emotion, whose accents reached the hearts and
filled the eyes of all present, that his brother had, in his will,
commended his soul to God, and bequeathed his body to hia State.
The procession at MoCullooh's funeral was a mile long.&#176;0
As it has already been indicated, Texas may have given only a quiet
salute to the memory of one of its transplanted heroes. In 1856, while Ben
60Ibid, June 7, 1862, p. 3.
29
was a United States Marshal, McCvilloch County was formed. Located in the
central plains, the political entity was not conpletely organized until
1876. The county, until the early 1890's, was a central staging point for
marauding Comanche Indians. Also range problems and mob violence took a
heavy toll of its citizenry during this period. Today, McCulloch County
regards itself as progressive with ranching, farming, msjiufacturing, and
mining serving as the principal economic bases. An historic marker out-side
Brady, the county seat, relates the essentials of McCulloch' s career.
In the Texas Ranger Museum in V/aco, there is scattered reference to Ben.
In one exhibit case is a razor purportedly lifted from the brigadier's
body shortly after he died at Elkhorn Tavern. In a conjunctional exhibit,
housed in another building, a few pictures of JfcCuiloch are on display,
and a mechanical sound-visual presentation focusing on Texas Rangers has
a few commendatory references to his contributions.
Rutherford County does not know Ben McCulloch and for good reason.
When he was bom near the forks of Stone's River in 1811, Jefferson was
still the county seat, but Jefferson no longer exists in the sense that it
existed in 1811. Also, the Alexander McCulloch fsunlly left the county for
Alabama in 1820 when Ben was only nine years of age. Alexander's brother,
Henry, may have remained at Jefferson for an Alexander McCulloch, possibly
62
Henry's son, is listed as local militiaman, first lieutenant, in 1829.
Too, Beer's 1878 Rutherford County Map shows a McCulloch farm in the
Jefferson area.
61
Spiller (Correspondence), October 27, 1977.
^2
Publication No. 2f Rutherford County Historical Society, p, 64..
30
BIBLIOGRAPHT
Barker, Eugene C, "The San Jacinto Campaign", Southwestern Historical
Quarterly. Vol. IV, April, 1901.
Davis, Winfield, Jr., An Illustrated History of Sacramento County.
(Chicago, 1890).
Dictionary of American Biography. Edited by Allen Johnson, Dumas Malone,
and Harris B. Starr. Charles Scribner's Sons, 1928-^,
Gunn, Jack Winston, Life of Ben McCulloch (Masters Thesis at University of
Texas, Dept. of History"n~1947.
Hardeman, Nicholas P., Wilderness Calling . Knoxville, Tennessee, U.T.
Press, 1977 (Selected by Dr. Fred Brigance)
.
Hartje, Robert G., Van Porn . Nashville: Vanderbilt IMiversity Press, 1967.
Otis, Grant Hammond (ed.). The Utah Expedition . Concord, N. H. (New
Hanpshire Historical Society) , 1928.
Picayune (Microfilm Newspaper) , New Orleans, Louisiana, 1846-1847.
Publication No. 3 . Rutherford County Historical Society, Murfreesboro,
Tennessee, Summer 1974.,
Reid, Samuel C, Jr., The Scouting Expeditions o&#163; McCulloch ' s Rangers .
Philadelphia (B. G. Zieter and Company), 1847.
Rolle, Andrew F., California . A History. New York, Thomas V. Crowell Co., 1969.
Rose, Victor M., _Life and Services of General Ben McCulloch . Philadelphia
(Pictorial Bureau of the PressTT 1888.
Sacramento Union (Microfilm Newspaper) , Sacramento, California, 1850-1873.
Smither, Harriet (ed.). Journal of the Fourth Congress cf the Republic of
Texas . 1839-1840, II. The House Journal .
Speer, J. A., The Encyclopedia of the New West (Part I), Houston, 1900.
Spiller, Wayne (McCulloch Coimty Historian), Correspondence, Oct. 27, 1977.
Warner, Ezra, Generals in Gray. New Orleans (Louisiana State University
Press), 1959.
Webb, W. P., The Texas Rangers . Boston and New York (Houghton Mifflin Co.), 1935.
Webb, W. P., "Exploits of the Texas Rangers", Reprint from The News (Dallas),
April 19, 1921
.
^ ~~
Wray, Henry, Deed Abstracts (Rutherford County, Tennessee), Vol. I, 1804-1810.
Yesterday's California . Miami, Florida, E. A. Seemann Pub. Co Inc., 1910.
</dc:description>
<dc:description>Tells the story of Ben McCulloch, a prominent native of Rutherford County who gained fame as a texas ranger and through his service in the Texas Revolution, Mexican-American War, and Civil War</dc:description>
<dc:subject>McCullock, Ben, 1811-1862; Biography; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>veterans; Mexican-American War; Texas Revolution; Texas rangers</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Jefferson</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>47 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-24; mt2011-02-28</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication11ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/61</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>