<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Rutherford County Historical Society publication no. 20: a history of the roads of Rutherford County</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Annable, Jr., Edward C.</dc:creator>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1982; 1983</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>18th century; 19th century; 20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>RUTHERFORD COUNTY
HISTORICAL SOCIETY
Publication No. 20
Digitized by the Internet Archive
in 2010 with funding from
Lyrasis IVIembers and Sloan Foundation
http://www.archive.org/details/publication20ruth
A HISTORY OF THE ROADS OF RUTHERFORD COUNTY,
TENNESSEE, 1804-1878: HISTORIC ROAD
RESEARCH, AND ITS APPLICATIONS FOR
HISTORIC RESOURCE SURVEYS AND
LOCAL HISTORY
Edward C. Annable, Jr
A thesis presented to the
Graduate Faculty of Middle Tennessee State University
in partial fulfillment of the requirements
for the degree Master of Arts
December, 1982
LIBRARY
WI91&gt;LE TEWNESSSF ITAT! BNIVIRSITT
V, 2
TABLE of CONTENTS
Introduction * Page 1
Rutherford County Public Roads from Indian
Trails to the Civil War Page 3
The Turnpike Era in Rutherford County I830-I86O. Page ijl
Roads in Rutherford County during the Civil War
and Reconstruction Page 119
Appendix A Road References in Rutherford County
Quarterly Court minutes l30U-l877 . . Page lUl
Appendix B Rutherford County Road Overseers
I80U-I826 Page 192
Appendix C Verification of Selected Road Termini
in Appendix A Page 219
^pendix D Maps of Road Development in Rutiier-ford
County l80ii-l878 Page 260
Selected Bibliography Page 26U
* Most of Chapter 1 and all of Chapter 5 were not published.
These chapters discuss Benefits and Problems of Historic Road
Research and could not be included due to space. Anyone wish-ing
to read these chapters may find them in Middle Tennessee
State University Library.
83-07087
FGR 3ALB
THE POLLOWINQ PUBUCATIOMS ARE FOR SAI2 BTj
Th&#171; Rutherford County Historical Society
Box 906
Murfreesboro, Tennessee 37130
Publications # 1, 2, 3, U, 5, 6, 8 and 9 OUT of PRINT
Publication # 7: Hopewell Church, Petition by Cornelius Sanders
for Rev. War Pension&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;$ 3.50 $ 1.00 postage
Publication # 10: 186U Diary&#171; Peter Jennings, Henderson Yoakum,
Early Methodist Church, and Overall
family ~&#8212;&#8212;
&#8212;
&#8212;&#8212;&#8212;&#8212; $ 3.50 + $ 1.00 postage
Publication # U: State CapLtol, Ben McCuUoch, Petition of
Michael Lorance, A Country Store, and
Soule College &#8212;&#8212;~&#8212;~&#8212; $ 3.50 + $ 1.00 postage
Publication # 12: HLstoxy of Sewart AFB, Goochland and
Will Index $ 3.50 $ 1.00 postage
Publication # 13: Tennessee College, Coleman Scouts, New
Monument in old City Cemetery and Rev.
War Pension of James Boles &#8212;&#8212; $ 3.50 + $ 1.00 postage
Publication # lU: Murfreesboro Presbyterian Chttrch, Kirks and
Montgonerys, Russel Home, John lytle, and John
M. Leak Revolutionary Pension-- $ 3*50 + $ 1.00 postage
Publication # l5t WWLgs in Rutherford County, 1835 - 181*5
$ 3.50 + $ 1.00 postage
Publication # I6: Harts' Spring, Childress family. Gov.
John Miles, Fosterville, Cherry Shade,
Revolutionary Record of Vftn. Cocke
$ 3.50 + $ 1.00 postage
PublicaUon # 17: Jefferson I803 - 1813, Will Abstracts,
Murfreesboro &#8226; 8 Old City Cemetery
$ 3.50 + $ 1.00 postage
FOR SALE
Publication # 19: Smyrna I869 - I88I, Veterans Hospital, Manson Family,
Jenkins Homes, Rutherford Wills, Historical Society-
Early Newspapers abstracts, Macon Co lU from Ruther-ford
County $ 3.50 + $ 1.00 postage
Publication # 20: Road and Turnpikes in Rutherford Counly I8OU-I878
$ 5.00 + $ 1.00 postage
HISTORY of RUTHERFORD CODNTY by C. C. Sims
A reprint of the 19h7 edition of our county history, contains 230
pages with index and hard covers $ 12.00 + $2.00 postage
and handling
INDEX of Publications 1 throu^ 5 $ 5-00 + $1.00 postage
I8U0 Rutherford County Census with Index $ 5-00 + $1.00 postage
Deed Abstract of Rutherford County I803 - I8IO . . $ 10.00 + $1.00 postage
GRIFFITH; Hiustrated bi-centennial publication. . $ 2.00 + $1.00 postage
COMMEMORATIVE PLATES:
Plate # 2: Tennessee College In Murfreesboro . $ $.00 + $1.00 postage
laate # 3s Rutherford County Courthouse, 1900 $ 5.00 + $1.00 postage
AVAILABLE FROM: Mr. William Walkt?)
202 Ridley Street
Smyrna, Tn 37167
Rutherford County Map 1878, shows land owners - $3.50 + $1.00 postage
CEMETERY RECORDS of Rutherford County:
Vol. 1: Northwestern third of cotmty and part of Wilson and Davidson
counties, 256 cemeteries with index and maps.
$ 10.00 + $1.00 postage
Vol. 2: Eastern third of Rutherford and the western part of Cannon
county, 2lil cemeteries with index and maps- $10.00 + $1.00 postage
Vol. 3: Southwestern third of Rutherford county, 193 cemeteries with
index and maps $ 10.00 + $1.00 postage
ALSO AVAILABLE FROM: Mrs . Fred Brigance
1202 Scottland Drive
Murfreesboro, Tn 37130
Marriage Records of Rutherford Coxxnty l85l - l872
$ 10.00 + $1.00 postage
RUTHERFORD COUNTY HISTORICAL SOCIETY
PUBLICATION NO. 20
Published b7 the
RUTHERFORD COUNTY HISTORICAL SOCIETY
OFFICERS
President Mr. Ernest K. Johns
Vice-President Mr. W. H. Westbrooks
Recording Secretary Miss Louise Cawthon
Corresponding Secretary Mrs. Susan Daniel
Publication Secretary Mr. Walter K. Hoover
Treasurer Mrs. Kelly Ray
DIRECTORS: Mr. James Matheny
Mrs. William Walkup
Mrs. Tall a Lester
Publication No. 20 (Limited Edition-U25 copies) is distributed
to members of the Society. The annual membership dues is $10.00
(Family $11.00) which Includes the regular publleatlons and the monthly
NEWSLETTER to all members. Additional copies of Publication No. 20
may be obtained at $5.00 per copy.
All correspondence concemlng additional copies, contributions to
future issues, and membership should be addressed to:
Rutherford County Historical Society
Box 906
Murfreesboro, Tennessee 37130
ACKNOWLEDGEMENTS
Like the laborers who worked on the roads in
Rutherford County, I, in working on this thesis, could not
have completed it on my own. I would like to thank my
parents, Mr. and Mrs. Edward C. Annable, Sr . , and my
grandfather, Mr. Edward R. Annable, for their continuous
support on this project.
Many Rutherford County residents assisted me in the
research phase of this thesis. Dr. Sam Woods provided
insight on the location of roads in relation to animal
husbandry. Miss Martha Wright, a staff member of the
Rutherford County Register's Office, has done tremendous
work in indexing the county's deed books. Without her new
system of indexing the old deeds, there is no doubt that
I would have had little success in locating road termini.
Mr. William Patterson provided me with an immense amount of
information on Rutherford County's early history and histor-ical
sites. It is a fact that I would not have located as
many of the road termini as I did without his help. Mr.
Ernest K. Johns, with his vast knowledge of Rutherford
County' s history, has added immensely to the scope of this
thesis. Many key road termini would not have been located
without his assistance.
I would also like to thank Mr. Keith Smith for
helping me construct a map board which was utilized in
determining road locations in the county. I also appre-ciate
the advice that Dr. James K. Huhta provided me in
the completion of this thesis. With all the helpful
assistance provided me by these individuals, I alone take
responsibility for any mistakes and omissions.
CHAPTER I
INTRODUCTION TO HISTORIC RESOURCE SURVEYS
AND HISTORIC ROAD RESEARCH
The road system is an important factor in the
political, economic, and social vitality of an area.
Routes of transportation from the roughly cut trail to the
superhighway have always performed an important role in
the development of a community or region. This thesis is
oriented towards emphasizing the importance of utilizing
the historical development of the road system in the local
historic resource survey of historical, architectural, and
cultural resources.
The research for supporting the proposition that
the road system's development is important in planning for
surveys and using the survey data is primarily from Ruther-ford
County, Tennessee. The county is located in the
central portion of the state, southeast of Nashville, the
state capital. The years 1804 to 1878 were determined as
the parameters for the study because 18 04 signifies the
establishment of the county and 1878 was the year in which
the most detailed county map was published up to that time.
In addition to a general history of the roads in Rutherford
County, benefits for historic preservation and local history
1
are addressed in this thesis. In an effort to encourage
further research into the roads as a resource for surveys,
the methodology used as well as problems encountered during
the research are expressed.
This thesis also includes four appendices primarily
to serve as a data base and to aid individuals interested
in the history of Rutherford County. The first appendix
lists all references in the Rutherford County Quarterly
Court Minutes that can possibly aid in determining the
location of roads in the county. It does not include all
references to the roads in the county; items such as some
road overseer appointments and appropriations for tools
were excluded. A table of road overseers during the early
period of road construction is shown in another appendix.
It is chronologically organized and attempts to trace the
changes in road overseers. The concluding data for this
appendix was arbitrarily determined primarily due to a lack
of further data. The third appendix documents many of the
road locations by tracing the land ownership of some road
termini to the 1878 map. The final appendix consists of
several maps showing the development of roads in the county
to 1878.
CHAPTER II
RUTHERFORD COUNTY'S PUBLIC ROADS FROM
INDIAN TRAILS TO THE CIVIL WAR
This chapter will examine several major aspects of
Rutherford County's roads, including the historical back-ground
of the roads prior to the formation of the county in
1804. Public roads built prior to 1861 will be extensively
studied in this chapter. Major historical themes as well as
relationships between the roads and historical events will
be presented. This examination of the public roads will be
oriented towards the construction process and the overall
development of the roads rather than the specific locations
which are presented in appendices A and D.
There were two historical precedents to the early
Rutherford County road system; one precursor was the Indian
influence in establishing trails in the area, and the other
factor was the English background in the road construction
system and technology. At the time of the arrival of
settlers to the area known later as Rutherford County, there
were no permanent Indian camps, but there were trails. In
^Travis E. Smotherman, "Archaeological and Anthro-pological
Aspects of the Prehistory of Rutherford County,"
Rutherford County Historical Society Publication , no . 3
(1974) , p. 21.
the eighteenth century the area was disputed as a hunting
ground by several Indian tribes, including the Cherokees,
Chickasaws, Shawnees, Creek, and possibly the Iroquois.
Indians throughout North America were adept at
blazing trails. Many trails were a result of Indians track-ing
herds of buffalo or deer and were later adapted to other
uses such as commerce between tribes. They were influenced
in their travel patterns by the natural topography of the
land. In level areas, they sought trails allowing both ease
of movement and directness. In areas of rough terrain, they
preferred to make detours around hills. Their routes were
determined by watercourses, hills, and valleys. As Indians
predominantly settled along streams or rivers, the trails
paralleled them.^
In Rutherford County, physical evidence of Indian
trails has probably declined over time, but several impor-tant
Indian trails traversed the area. The "Great South
Trail," which ran southward from the Great Salt Lick in the
vicinity of Nashville and through Williamson County, entered
Rutherford County west of Eagleville. It proceeded in an
eastern and southeastern direction to the head of Wartrace
^Ibid., pp. 22-25.
^Caroline E. MacGill, History of Transportation in
the United States Before 1860 (Forge Village, Mass.: Murray
Printing Co., 1948), p. 6.
Wheaton J. Lane, From Indian Trail to Iron Horse;
Travel and Transportation in New Jersey 1670-1860 (Prince-ton,
N.J.: Princeton University Press, 1939), pp. 15-16.
Creek. From there it ran to the present city of Tullahoma
and south to the Indian settlements in Alabama and
. 5 Mississippi. It was a:
. . . broad beaten path made by the buffalo which came
from the South to the French Lick (Salt Lick at Nash-ville's
Sulphur Springs Bottom). ... It was worn
into the earth one or two feet or more in many places.
In some places it was three or four feet wide.^
Another trail passing through Rutherford County was
the "Cisca" or "St. Augustine Trail." It was called the
"Nickajack Trail" by the settlers of Middle Tennessee. The
portion of the trail in Rutherford County was part of a
longer trail network that ran from Nashville by the Stone
Fort, possibly Cisca, in Coffee County, Tennessee, to St.
Augustine, Florida. From the old Stone Fort the trail
crossed the Garrison Fork near Fort Nash, not far from the
present town of Beech Grove and into the county. The trail
passed by Black Fox Spring and through the Murfreesboro area
7 to Nashville.
The "Black Fox Trail," last of the Indian trails
known to have passed through the county, was part of a
longer trail known as the "Saline River Trail." The Saline
River Trail began at the Cherokee settlements on the
^William E. Myer, Indian Trails of the Southeast
(Washington, D.C.: Bureau of American Ethnology, 1924;
reprint ed., Nashville, Tenn.: Blue and Grey Press, 1971),
pp. 116-117.
^The Civil and Political History of the State of
Tennessee , 2d ed. , cited by Myer, p. 11/.
^Myer, pp. 112-117.
Hiwassee River in East Tennessee. It crossed the Ohio River
at Golconda, Illinois, and the Mississippi River at Cape
Girardeau, Missouri, and extended into Missouri and Oklahoma,
The Rutherford County portion of the route, or Black Fox
Trail, ran from Woodbury in Cannon County west across the
county line near Readyville and intersected the Nickajack
Trail at Black Fox Spring. From there it split into two
trails, one following the Nickajack Trail and the other
branch entering Nashville along the Murfreesboro and
Nashville Turnpike.^
The importance of the Indian trails lies in the fact
that they were present in the Rutherford County area when
the settlers arrived. Most secondary sources consulted by
this writer support the idea that Indian trails were adapted
by the early settlers into traces, later county roads, turn-pikes,
and finally modern state and interchange highways.^
This idea seems to be plausible as the Blackjack Trace was
mentioned in the Rutherford County road orders. -^^ These
Indian trails were possibly expanded into crude roads prior
to the formation of Rutherford County, thus resulting in the
absence of numerous references to them in the county's
^Ibid., pp. 103-105.
^Carlton C. Sims, ed . , A History of Rutherford
County (Murfreesboro, Tenn.: By the Author, 1947), p. 55;
MacGill, pp. 6, 120; Lane, p. 33.
"Rutherford County, Tennessee, County Court Clerk's
Office, Quarterly Court Minute Book C, p. 167.
quarterly court minute books. It is evident that modern
highways parallel the old trails if they do not use parts
of them. Part of the Black Fox Trail identifies with U.S.
Highway 7 0S, while the Nickajack Trail correlates with the
Manchester Pike and the Old Nashville Highway. This rela-tionship
leads to the unanswerable questions of how much and
where do the Indian trails impact on our modern transporta-tion
system?
The system of road construction and maintenance in
nineteenth century Rutherford County had its origin in
sixteenth century England. With the breakdown of feudalism,
the government relied on the common law liability of the
inhabitants of the parish to maintain the roads in good con-dition.-^^
This was reinforced by a statute of 1555 which
required every parish to muster its men once a year for six
unpaid days of labor on the highways. -^2 j^ surveyor of high-ways,
or waywarden, was chosen in each parish on an annual
basis. He had the authority to call out all the available
labor of the parish to work on the roads. -^-^
The English system of road construction and mainten-ance
was adapted to the different conditions of North
'^Neil Cossons, The BP Book of Industrial Archaeol-ogy
(Oxford, England: Alden Press, 1975), p. 316.
^^Brian Bracegirdle, ed . , The Archaeology of the
Industrial Revolution (Ganbury, N.J.: Associated University
Presses, 1974), p. 59.
13Cossons, p. 316
America. This thesis will examine the road system of
Colonial North Carolina because of Tennessee's close ties
to North Carolina prior to 1789. Before 1715, surveyors
were appointed for districts with the counties. When
specific roads were petitioned for, the surveyors for the
district in which the road was to be located were called to
clear the road. The precinct court granted the petition and
the district's surveyors marked the road's location. But
over time, a committee or jury of from two to three men
replaced the surveyors and delineated the route of the pro-posed
road. After the road was marked out, the surveyor and
the men of the district&#8212;called a road company&#8212;opened the
road by removing the obstacles to traf f ic. &#8226;''*
After 1715, roads were laid off by a twelve-member
jury. Surveyors were appointed by the precinct courts, and
by law they were required to serve for one year. It was
their responsibility to call out all male tithables or
taxables , consisting of all free males sixteen years and
older, and all slaves twelve years and older. By 1700 the
term "overseer" and "surveyor" were used interchangeably,
and by 177 5 the term "overseer" was being used almost
solely. ^^ For a period of time between 17 34 and 17 64 the
^'^Alan D. Watson, "Regulation and Administration of
Roads and Bridges in Colonial Eastern North Carolina,"
North Carolina Historical Review 45 (Autumn 1968) :401.
^^Ibid., pp. 401-402.
northern and southern counties in the colony split into two
types of road administration. The northern counties con-tinued
to use the old system while the southern counties
adopted a commissioner system. Supervision of the roads
was conveyed from the overseer and the road company to com-missioners.
This group of three to five men was independent
of the precinct courts, and they were empowered to act as &#8226;
the courts and overseers had previously done in the con-struction
of roads and bridges. The commissioner system
was a failure in maintaining roads. The problem resulted
from the death or removal of commissioners, or the neglect
by these individuals of their duties. They could not be
disciplined by the precinct or county courts for their
laxness in fulfilling their duties. &#8226;^^
A law enacted in 1764 closed the break between the
road systems of the northern and southern counties. All
roads were to be twenty feet wide and laid out by a jury of
twelve freeholders. The overseer was required to place a
post with the direction to the nearest town or public ferry
and the number of miles to the location wherever the road
forked. They were also ordered to set mile markers on the
roads. '
The roads in Colonial North Carolina were important
in trade, travel, and local convenience. The people of the
16 Ibid., pp. 402, 412, 413. ^"^Ibid., p. 403.
10
colony, in their petitions for roads, desired access to
political, economic, social, and religious centers such as
courthouses, river landings, churches, schoolhouses, ware-houses,
gristmills, and ferries. The road construction
procedure usually began with a petition to the precinct or
county court. If the court approved the road, directions
for the road's route were given to a jury of twelve men.
These freeholders had the duty of marking out the road and
assessing damages caused by the construction. An overseer
and road company were appointed to construct the road. The
road jury was sworn before a magistrate and told to mark
the road's route by the next court session and to provide a
report of its activities. Many court orders for roads had
to be reiterated because the juries were remiss in carrying
1 p out their duties. ^&#176;
The overseers and road companies were responsible
for constructing and maintaining the roads. All of the
taxables within a road district constituted the road company.
The courts would divide the district if the number of roads
became too immense for one overseer to handle. Exemptions
from duty in road companies were given to individuals who
were over sixty years old and those physically unable to
work. The road overseers and members of the road companies
ISibid., pp. 403, 406, 407
11
were liable to fines for not appearing to work on the roads
19
or for keeping the roads in a state of disrepair.
Road legislation of the state of North Carolina is
important in understanding road development in Tennessee.
The county courts had the power to order the laying out,
altering, and discontinuing of public roads, and designating
the location of bridges. All the roads were laid out by a
jury of freeholders to the best advantage of the inhabitants.
Roads were required to be twenty feet wide. All stumps and
runners were required to be cut and cleared for a width of
sixteen feet from the center of the road. If the overseer
and members of the road company could not construct a bridge,
it was contracted out to private individuals. To construct
and maintain roads, all the male taxables from sixteen to
fifty years of age were required to meet at designated loca-tions
to work on the roads. Those individuals who had been
excused from working had to send three slaves or three other
hands to work in their place. Anyone who refused or neg-lected
to work on the roads when called was fined five
shillings per day. This money went to the overseer to hire
other laborers. No individual was required to serve more
than one year in three as road overseer. The overseers had
to notify each male taxable and slave owner of what tools
they were to bring to work on the roads. The laborers had
l^Ibid., pp. 408, 411.
12
to be notified three days prior to the designated workday or
they could not be fined. It was legal for the road overseer
to assign equal apportionments to the workers if requested
by a majority of them. The overseer was still required to
set up direction posts and mile markers or face a fine of
five pounds. No individual was allowed to turn or alter
20
any public road without permission from the county court.
According to Alan D. Watson, an authority on roads
in Colonial North Carolina, the colony "possessed one of the
poorest transportation systems in the colonies." He attrib-utes
this observation to several factors: the disdain for
authority that the citizens had, physical obstacles, a
scattered and insufficient population, and more roads
authorized than could be sufficiently administered. Court
orders for marking off roads were not obeyed. Overseers and
laborers failed to complete their duties or even appear for
work. The area of North Carolina studied by Watson abounded
in sounds, rivers, and swamps, which hindered the physical
completion of the roads. There were not enough men to main-tain
the existing roads, and as more roads were authorized
2&#176;North Carolina, An Act to Empower the County
Courts of Pleas and Quarter Sessions of the Several Counties
. to Order the Laying Out of Public Roads . . . (11&#187;^) ,
Laws . . . (1791) , quoted in Clifford K. Shipton, ed.. Early
Amer ican Imprints 1639-1800 (Worchester, Mass.: American
Antiquarian Society, 1969), Readex Microprint, Evans No.
23641 (5th cont.), p. 532.
13
by the county courts, productivity declined, and the roads
21 fell into disrepair. -^
The importance of examining the road system of North
Carolina prior to the statehood of Tennessee is to show the
many similarities between the two systems. They will be
brought out in examining Tennessee's and Rutherford County's
road system. Several facets of North Carolina's road system
should be considered. These include the role of the county
court, road jury, road overseer, and those who worked on the
roads.
The first effort at constructing roads in Tennessee
began in 177 8 when commissioners were appointed to mark out
a road from Jonesboro in Washington County to Burke County,
North Carolina. It was a very roughly cut road and at times
was not passable for wagons. In 17 83 a road from Mansker's
Station to Nashville was ordered to be cleared of growth
22 that had been permitted to grow in the road. James
Robertson petitioned North Carolina's House of Commons in
1784 to authorize the recruiting of troops to construct a
wagon road from the lower extremity of Clinch Mountain to
the Cumberland settlements. This endeavor did not begin
until 1787 when an eighty-man battalion command by Ma j
Thomas Evans began cutting the road from Clinch Mountain.
Peter Avery, a hunter, was appointed to mark out the route.
^^Watson, p. 417. ^^j^acGill, pp. 27-28,
14
The soldiers cut the trees to a width of ten feet and
occasionally leveled the road. This road, known as the
"North Carolina Road," "Avery's Trace," or the "Old North
Carolina Trace" was not completed until September 1788.
After all the labor invested in the road, it still could
not support wagon travel. Anything that could not be
carried on horseback was shipped down the Tennessee River
23
and up the Ohio and Cumberland Rivers to Nashville.
It was not until after Tennessee was admitted as a
state that any attempt was made to construct a viable wagon
road from East Tennessee to Nashville. In 1799 the state's
General Assembly appointed three individuals (William Walton,
William Martin, and Robert Kyle) as commissioners to open a
road. The legislature also appropriated one thousand
dollars for its construction. Construction began in 1799
but was not completed until 1802. The commissioners marked
out the route of the road. The road laborers had to cut
down trees to a minimum width of twelve feet in the moun-tains
and fifteen feet for the remainder of the route. The
road had to be leveled by shovel and measured for mile posts.
Bridges and causeways had to be constructed where necessary.
The road became known as the "Walton Road" because Captain
Walton had been the leading commissioner in surveying the road
and overseeing the actual construction. In 1801 the General
23 John Dawson Boniol, Jr., "The Walton Road,"
Tennessee Historical Quarterly 30 (Winter 1971) :403.
15
Assembly incorporated it under the name of the Cumberland
Turnpike Company, and toll was collected to help defray the
cost of construction. The significance of these early
roads for the history of Rutherford County's roads lies in
the fact that the first intrastate road that can be con-sidered
a true wagon road was completed only two years prior
to the formation of Rutherford County. From this it can be
surmised that there were few wagon roads in Rutherford County
prior to its formation. This writer believes that the
technology used in constructing the Walton Road was not much
different from that used in the construction of early
Rutherford County roads.
The first public road legislation in Tennessee was
enacted in 17 96 by the General Assembly. The legislature
deemed a public road to be any road that was viewed and laid
out or altered, if the road was viewed by five to twelve
freeholders. Any damages that resulted from the construc-tion
of the road was paid by the county. A jury had to be
summoned to assess the damages. In order that no individual
be compelled to work on more than one road, the county
quarterly court had the power to designate which road each
individual would work on.^^ This writer believes that
^^Ibid. , pp. 406-407.
25Tennessee, An Act for Amendment of the Laws
Respecting Public Roads and Ferries, Tennessee Session Laws,
Acts Passed at the First General Assembly (1796), pp. 48-49.
Hereafter cited as Public Acts.
16
Tennessee was at this time still utilizing the road laws of
North Carolina because this is the first legislative refer-ence
to road laws and it is referred to as an amendment.
There were roads located in Rutherford County prior
to its formation by an act of the General Assembly in 18 03.
There are several references in the Rutherford County deed
books to Taylor's Trace. The exact location of this trace
is unknown, but it was in existence prior to 1794. Gen.
James Robertson mentioned the trace in orders to Major Ore.
His force was to march from Brown's Blockhouse and proceed
along Taylor's Trace in the direction of the Tennessee River.
The unit departed the blockhouse on September 7, 17 94, and
encamped at Black Fox's Camp. Major Ore's force then pro-ceeded
to the Barren Fork of the Duck River near the Stone
Fort and attacked the Cherokee and Creek Indians of the
Lower Towns on the Tennessee River. ^^ Brown's Blockhouse
was located west of the present Hillsboro Road near the
headwaters of Richland Creek. 27 with the locations of Black
Fox's Spring and the Stone Fort, the route of Taylor's Trace
was very similar to the Nickajack Trail. Major Ore's
26a. W. Putnam, History of Middle Tennessee or Life
and Times of Gen. James Robertson (Nashville, Tenn. : n.p.
1859; reprint ed . , Knoxville, Tenn.: University of Tennessee
Press, 1971) , p. 479.
27 James A. Crutchfield, Early Times in the Cumberland
Valley from its Beginnings to 18 00 (Nashville, Tenn.: First
American National Bank, 1976), p. 128.
17
advance into Indian territory was also known as the Nicka-
2R jack Campaign.
There were several roads in the county that probably
were viewed and marked out while it was a part of Davidson
and Wilson counties. These include roads from Robert Smith
to Cummin's Mill, the forks of Stones River to the Davidson
County line, Howell's Mill to Bird Nance's, John Sullin's
Creek to Thomas Rucker, William Kimbro's to a ford on
Hurricane Creek, Billingsley ' s to Stewarts Creek, the
Garrison Road, and others. ^^ The Rutherford county Quar-terly
Court appointed road overseers to these roads in the
early period of county government, but the court never
appointed a jury of view to open the road. The Quarterly
Courts of Davidson and Wilson counties probably had
appointed the jury of view to open the road, and Rutherford
County's Quarterly Court assumed the responsibility of
appointing overseers to supervise the maintenance of the
roads. Also, references to the Chickamauga Trace and
Taylor's Trace in land descriptions in Rutherford County's
deed books were found.
The road legislation, which was to regulate the
construction of public roads in the state throughout the
time frame of this thesis, was enacted in 1804. Minor
^^Putnam, p. 479. ^^See appendix A.
^Rutherford County, Tennessee, County Register's
Office, Deed Books M, p. 518, and 3, p. 694.
IB
amendments were enacted periodically by the General Assembly.
This legislation is of extreme importance in understanding
the process of road construction in nineteenth century
Tennessee.
All roads which had been previously laid out were
declared public roads by the General Assembly. The county
quarterly courts were given full power and authority to
order the "laying out of public roads where necessary."
The courts were also given the power to discontinue roads
that were found useless and to alter roads to make them
more useful to the local inhabitants. The authority to
approve river ferries and locate bridges was also given to
the quarterly courts. The county courts were responsible
for calling overseers to account for money obtained from
fines that were paid for defaulting on road labor. The
money was to be used in maintaining the public roads and
bridges . ^^
The public roads, according to the legislation, were
to be laid out by a jury of freeholders numbering from five
to not more than twelve individuals. Their oath upon
appointment was:
I, , do solemnly swear or affirm
that I will lay out the road now directed to be laid
out by the court of pleas and quarter session to the
greatest ease and advantage of the inhabitants; and
with as little prejudice to inclosures as may be.
^&#8226;4&gt;ublic Acts (1804), p. 3.
19
without favor, affection, malice, or prejudice, and
to the best of my skill and knowledge. ^2
The "jury of view,"^^ as it was called in Rutherford
County, was supposed to lay off the roads at least twenty
feet wide, if it was practicable from the terrain standpoint.
The overseers were directed to "completely cut and clear all
stumps, rocks, brush and obstructions so far as practicable
for the width of sixteen feet in the center of the road under
their care." They were to build the necessary bridges
through swamps and across small runs and creeks. These
bridges were to be sixteen feet in width. If the road over-seer
and the members of his road crew were not capable of
constructing the bridge, the county court was empowered to
have the construction and maintenance contracted. The cost
of construction would come from county tax receipts. If
the bridge crossed county lines, the construction costs
would be defrayed by both counties in proportion to the
number of taxables in both counties. '* A toll bridge or
causeway was authorized for rivers and large creeks, where
the depth, current, or width of the water obstacle would
cause the bridge's construction and maintenance to be a
burden on the taxpayers.^
32ibid., p. 4.
^^Rutherford County, Tennessee, County Court Clerk's
Office, Quarterly Court Minute Book B, p. 155.
^"^Public Acts (1804), p. 4. ^Sjbid., p. 5.
20
Overseers of roads were to be appointed annually by
the county quarterly court. According to the legislation,
no person was compelled to serve as overseer for more than
one year in five.^^ Annual appointments of overseers did
not always hold true in Rutherford County, and many over-seers
served more than one full year. ' The road overseer
was to summon all white males from eighteen to fifty years
of age and notify all slave owners to send their male slaves
of the same age to work on a road at a certain time and
place. The county court determined who would work on each
road by determining the boundaries for each particular road.
No individual was compelled to work on more than one road.
Several exemptions from working on public roads existed:
judges of a superior court, ministers, keepers of public
ferries, justices of the peace, the governor, secretary of
state, attorney general, and any free white persons sending
three slaves or other able persons to work on the road.
Nothing from this act was interpreted to exempt the slaves
from working on public roads within their district. -'&#176; This
might seem to be a physical impossibility since all males
between eighteen and fifty years of age had to work on the
road. So how could a slave owner provide three slaves to
work on the road instead of himself? This writer believes
^^Ibid., pp. 5-6. ^"^See appendix E.
^^Public Acts (1804), pp. 5-6, 9.
21
that the slave owner might have had several tracts of land
in the county; and, to work on a road near one tract of
land, he would use slaves living in another district.
There were several fines associated with public
roads that were assessed against those eligible for work on
public roads, overseers, and travelers. Upon notice from
the road overseer, anyone who refused or neglected to work
on the road was liable to fine of seventy-five cents per
day that the individual did not work. The process involved
the road overseer's going before any justice of the peace to
initiate a warrant against the recalcitrant worker. The
local constable would collect the fine and pay it to the
overseer, who would expend the money to hire other individ-uals
to work on the road. The road overseer had to notify
those individuals who worked on the road of what tools to
bring and the time and place of the work at least three days
prior to the appointed day. If he did not, the individual
was not held liable for the fine.^^
The road overseer was liable to an indictment by a
grant jury if he refused or neglected to perform his duties,
excused any person who failed to attend the work, or
accepted any bribe. If any person refused to serve as a
road overseer, he was fined fifty dollars. This money was
recovered by the county solicitor if the individual did not
^^Ibid., pp. 6-7
22
give sufficient cause for refusing. The overseer could be
fined five dollars for failing to set up and maintain posts
pointing the direction and displaying the mileage to public
places. Anyone caught knocking down or defacing the posts
was fined fifty dollars. -^ The overseer was also required
to measure his road, set up mile markers in a legible and
durable manner, and maintain them in good condition. Neg-lecting
to mark the miles or repair the markers resulted in
a five-dollar fine. In 1819 the General Assembly required
that the markers be of durable wood. The overseer, who
failed to keep his road and bridges in good repair for a
period of fifteen days, was liable for a fine of five
dollars unless he was delayed by extremely bad weather. 42
No individual could turn or alter any public road
unless approval was obtained by the quarterly court. A jury
of view had to report the potential consequences of the
alteration to the court. Once the road was turned or
altered, the overseer had to certify that the new road was
in good condition before the old portion of the road could
be closed. Anyone turning a road from its old route without
permission was liable for a fine of five dollars. If any
individual believed that he had been injured by the con-struction
of the road, he could petition the quarterly court
40ibid., p. 6. '^llbid., p. 7.
^^ibid., p. 8; Public Acts (1819), p. 50.
Z3
for a jury of view to consider the project and assess the
damages. Either the road could be turned to solve the
problem, or the county could pay the individual for the
damages. The jury had to weigh the public good against the
individual's injury. ^^
Evidence of the administration of early public roads
in Rutherford County is limited to road orders and jury of
view reports in the county quarterly court minute books.
The process was basically the same as that stated in the
legislation of 18 04. The quarterly court would appoint from
five to twelve freeholders as a jury of view to mark out a
road, usually from two designated points. Sometimes a more
44 involved description was given by the court. There are
few references as to who originally petitioned to have the
road built. This writer believes that the county court, the
jury of view, and the road overseer were familiar with the
road legislation of 1804, as the consistent order given to
the jury of view was to mark the road the "nighest and best
way." This would allow a broad interpretation of the
court order if those involved were not aware of the state
law.
"^&#8226;^Public Acts (1804), pp. 8-9.
44 See appendix A.
^^Rutherford County, Tennessee, County Court Clerk's
Office, Quarterly Court Minute Book A, p. 12,
24
The jury of view was ordered to report back to the
County Court at the subsequent session with the results of
their work.^^ From researching the court minutes, this
writer believes that in a majority of the cases the jury
never reported back to the court. It is also possible that
the clerk never recorded the jury's report in the court
minutes. Another explanation is that the jury of view never
accomplished the task. The road orders in appendix A of
this thesis show that the Quarterly Court often repeated an
earlier order to view and mark out a particular road. A
final interpretation is that the jury of view was late in
accomplishing the marking out of the road
It can be ascertained if the road was constructed by
determining when the road overseer was appointed by the
county court to open and keep the road in repair. This
appointment signified approximately when work began on con-structing
the road. If the road was lengthy in distance,
several overseers were appointed to supervise its opening
and maintenance.^^ During the early period of the county's
government, sometimes the overseer's workers were identified
by name.^^ Later the county court designated the overseer's
workers by delineating geographic boundaries. The court
^^Ibid., Book A, p. 7. ^^See appendix A.
^^See appendices A and B.
^^Rutherford County, Tennessee, County Court Clerk's
Office, Quarterly Court Minute Book A, p. 129.
25
also ordered those eligible to work on roads, who lived
within one to three miles on each side of the road, to work
under the supervision of an overseer. ^^
There were occasions when an individual petitioned
the county court to turn a road more favorably with their
own interests. ^1 The Rutherford County Court was amenable
to discontinuing roads if they served no useful purpose. 52
There were also instances when the county court appointed a
jury of view to assess the damages that had resulted or
would result from the construction of a particular road.
One well-documented case was that of Capt . William Lytle's
attempt to get the court to alleviate the damages of a road.
The road began at the west end of Main Street in Murfrees-boro
and ran in a straight direction through Lytle's land
to the place where the Franklin Road crossed the west fork
of Stones River. The initial court order for a jury of view
to mark out the road began in 1819 and was not settled until
1821.53
In 1805 the General Assembly appointed Jesse Bean,
John Drake, and John Gowen commissioners to view, mark, and
survey a road from the headwaters of Stones River to inter-sect
the Georgia Road. This was to be accomplished in
pp. 6-9, 194.
^&#176;Ibid., Book A, pp. 4, 135.
^&#8226;&#65533;&#65533;Ibid., Book A, p. 136. ^^Ibid. , Book A, p. 186.
53ibid., Book 0, pp. 86, 179, 180, 231, 324; Book P,
26
accordance with the treaty signed at Tellico with the
Cherokee Indians in 1798. These coiranissioners were to
select the most direct route under the circumstances and
note principal water courses, mountains, and other remark-able
places. The road had to be sixteen feet wide and
cleared so as to allow loaded wagons to travel on it.
It is possible that all three of these individuals owned
land in Rutherford County. ^^ It is unknown what resulted
from the legislative appointment, but the road was mentioned
in a Senate report dated October 23, 18 09. George Doherty,
Archibald Rhea, and John Dew were commissioners who had
examined the road cut out by John and George Lowry from the
headwaters of Stones River "through the Cherokee Nation to
where the great road led&#8212;to the State of Georgia." The
commissioners reported it was passable by all types of
"land carriages." The examination of the road took the
commissioners twenty-eight days to complete, and they used
"chain carriers" to survey the road.^^ The importance of
this road is that it was probably the first wagon road from
Rutherford County to southeastern Tennessee.
^^ Public Acts (1806), pp. 158-159.
Henry G. Wray, Rutherford County, Tennessee, Deed
Abstracts Vol. 1 1804-1810 (Smyrna, Tenn. : By the Author,
n.d.) , pp. 124 130, 132.
^^John Dew, "Report in [the] Senate," 23 October
18 09, Folder 12, Box 9, Record Group 60, Archives Section,
Tennessee State Library and Archives, Nashville, Tennessee.
27
The General Assembly noticed in 1807 that there was
a general shortage of the necessary tools to open public
roads and remove rocks and other obstacles. It authorized
the county courts to reimburse road overseers for purchasing
a stone hammer and crowbar. These tools had to be kept by
the overseer and not used for any purpose other than road
work. The overseer was liable for a five-dollar fine for
lending out the tools. The stone hammer and crowbar were
utilized throughout the period prior to the Civil War.
Requests for financial reimbursement for purchasing these
tools are evident in the quarterly court minutes. The
stone hammer is often referred to as a sledge hammer in the
Rutherford County court minutes. ^^ Those individuals who
worked on the roads were referred to as "hands" in their
allotment to the road overseers of the county. ^^
In 1811 the General Assembly passed legislation
requiring the county courts to appoint a suitable number of
overseers for stage roads. The stage roads, when opened,
had to be at least thirty feet wide, and causeways on the
stage road had to be at least twenty feet wide. The stage
roads were to be kept in repair according to the road
57public_Acts (1808), p. 101.
58 Rutherford County, Tennessee, County Court Clerk's
Office, Quarterly Court Minute Book Z, pp. 94, 114.
^^ Public Acts (1811), p. Ill; Rutherford County,
Tennessee, county court Clerk's Office, Quarterly Court
Minute Book A, p. 7.
28
legislation of 1804. The first reference to a stage road
in Rutherford County was in 1817. An 1834 gazetteer listed
two stage routes that ran through Rutherford County: one
from Nashville through Mount View, Murfreesboro, Shelbyville,
Lynchburg, Fayetteville, Hazle Green, and Meridianville to
Huntsville, Alabama, a total distance of 117 miles; and the
other from Knoxville to Nashville, via Sparta, Murfreesboro,
and Jefferson. A stage coach advertisement of an unknown
date announced that a stage coach owned by Todd and Company:
. . . will leave the St. Cloud, Commercial, and Sewanee
Hotels in Nashville for Murfreesboro on Tuesdays, Thurs-days,
and Saturdays at 8 o'clock A.M. and will leave the
Keystone House in Murfreesboro on Mondays, Wednesdays,
and Fridays for Nashville at 8 o'clock A.M.&#176;2
Enclosing land of one property owner by another must
have been a serious problem in the early nineteenth century,
as the General Assembly passed legislation in 1811 concern-ing
the problem. This legislation allowed property owners
to build private roads through lands enclosed by other
property owners who refused passage. The county court had
to Simmon a jury of view upon a petition of the surrounded
60Public Acts (1811), pp. 136-137.
^&#8226;Rutherford County, Tennessee, County Court Clerk's
Office, Quarterly Court Minute Book L, p. 80; Eastin Morris,
Tennessee Gazetteer (Nashville, Tenn. : W. Hasell Hunt and
Co., 1834; reprint ed., edited by Robert M. McBride and Owen
Meredith, Nashville, Tenn.: Gazetteer Press, 1971),
pp. 302-303; see Appendix A.
^^"Notice," no date. Accession Number 919, Map
Cabinet Number 1, Manuscript Section, Tennessee State
Library and Archives, Nashville, Tennessee.
29
individual. It was to lay off and mark out a road so as to
do the least possible damage to all involved individuals.
The road was not to exceed fifteen feet in width, and the
petitioner was to keep the road in good repair. Anyone
obstructing the road could be fined. ^-^ The same legislation
was reenacted in 18 69, so the problem must have been a
recurrent one."^
In 1821 the General Assembly passed legislation
designating that the public roads in Tennessee would be of
three different classes. First class roads were stage roads
or other roads deemed by the county quarterly court to be of
equal importance. No width was given for this road. Since
the road legislation of 1804 authorized roads to be twenty
feet wide, it is presumed they were from twenty to thirty
feet wide, the width authorized in 1811 for stage roads.
These roads had to be maintained, indexed, marked for mile-age;
and bridges and causeways had to be erected on them.
Second class roads were known as wagon roads. They had to
be twelve feet in width and cleared of all obstacles. They
had to be causewayed and bridged where necessary to afford
safe passage for loaded wagons. They also had to be indexed
and mile marked. The third class roads were to be con-structed
with sufficient width to allow the passage of horse
^^ Public Acts (1811), p. 65.
^^Tennessee, Statutes of Tennessee 1858-1871 (Nash-ville:
[title page missing], 1871), p. 226.
30
and rider, and milling on the backs of individual horses.
The roads had to be bridged and causewayed where necessary
to allow safe passage. The term "index," referring to first
and second class roads, was the building of directional
posts at forks in the road that showed the direction to the
nearest public place. Trees along the route were notched
according to the class&#8212;three notches for first class roads,
two notches for second class roads, and one notch for third
class roads. The county quarterly court had to assign a
competent number of hands to keep the first and second class
roads in good repair. The third class roads were worked
only when necessary, presumably after the other classes of
roads were in good condition. The quarterly courts decided
the class of the roads that were constructed. The court
did not need a jury of view to decide on third class
roads. ^^ For roads that the county court refused or failed
to class would be kept in the same condition as required by
the road laws in force. ^^ In 1823 the General Assembly made
a reference to the first class roads as those on which the
mail stages traveled. &#176;'
The General Assembly on several occasions amended
the road legislation of 1804 regarding overseers and those
who worked on the public roads. In 1823 the legislature
^^Public Acts (1821), pp. 10-11.
^^Ibid., (1822), p. 19. ^"^Ibid., (1823), p. 19.
31
prohibited the appointment of a road overseer who did not
live within the bounds of the road hands. &#176; This signifies
that the overseer lived in the general vicinity of the road
as did the hands who worked on the road. It also may be
interpreted to mean that the inhabitants of an area, who
were liable to work on roads, did not want outside super-vision.
In 18 25 paper makers were no longer exempt from
working on roads. ^^ This indicates that those who had the
skills of making paper were highly regarded in the communi-ties
of Tennessee during the early nineteenth century.
Searchers and members of patrols were exempted from working
on public roads in 1831. Those who served a term of three
months on patrols were exempted for twelve months of road
work. In 1860 one miller at operating grist mills and
common school commissioners were exempted from working on
public roads. That same year, slave owners were no longer
exempted from working on roads. Previous road legislation
never mentioned that female slaves were required to work on
roads, but they were exempted in 18 60.
In 1833 the General Assembly outlawed horse racing
on public roads. Those who gambled on or operated horse
racing on public roads and those who aided or abetted the
activity were liable for indictment under the state's gaming
^^Ibid., p. 15. 69ibid., (1826), p. 13.
70ibid., (1831), p. 124; (1859-1860), pp. 30-31;
(1860) , p. 13.
32
laws. This legislation did not affect turf racing or horse
racing run on a track. ^ No reason was given for this
action, but it could possibly relate to public safety or an
attempt by the legislature to put some type of constraints
on horse racing. There also might have been a morality
issue involved in the legislation.
Evidently the public roads of Tennessee had a road
sign problem in the 183 0s, as many individuals believe the
highways presently have the same problem. In 1835 it became
illegal for a road overseer or anyone else to set up any
false signs misrepresenting a road's condition, either as
to its excellence or distance. False representations con-cerning
a road, calculated to influence strangers to travel
on a road, were prohibited. The individual who became lost,
stuck, or delayed and who brought suit against the respon-sible
person, was entitled to one-half of a twenty-five
dollar fine. Any overseer who did not remove false signs
from the road within ten days of observing them was liable
for a twenty-five dollar fine.'^
The road overseer was responsible not only for the
maintenance of the roadbed but also for the place where the
road crossed a river or stream. An act passed in 1842
required the road overseer to have his workers construct
^llbid., (1833), p. 6.
''^ibid., (1835-1836), pp. 114-115,
33
foot bridges where the width of the stream and the condition
of the banks allowed it. A foot log was to be built on the
side of the ford for the passage of travelers on foot. It
was to be constructed of well hewn durable timber, one foot
in width and flat on the top. The foot log was to be
"abutted on either side of said stream or run upon good
sound abutments of stone or timber above high water mark."'-^
There are references made to "pole bridges" in the Ruther-ford
County Quarterly Court minutes, and it is assumed that
bridges of this type were constructed in the county.''*
A law enacted in 1860 promoted the clearing out of
fords where public roads crossed rivers or streams. At the
April term of the county quarterly court, with a majority
of the magistrates approving, the magistrates of each civil
district could report which fords in the district needed
to be cleared of obstructions. The court was to act on each
ford separately. The approved list of fords was given to
the sheriff, who advertised for bids for the fords' clear-ing.
Contracts for the fords' clearing were given to
bidders at the July term of the court. The contractor
cleared the ford of all loose rock; all fastened rock had
to be battered down with heavy, blunt, or square-end crow-bars
or sledge hammers. All rubbish and other obstacles
were cleared if the action did not deepen the ford. The
73ibid., (1842), p. 161. "^^see appendix A.
34
cleared width of the ford depended on its use, although no
ford was cleared over sixty feet in width. The contractor
returned to the court's August term with a certificate
signed by two freeholders who witnessed the completion of
the clearing of the ford. It is believed that much activity
in clearing out of the river fords was postponed until after
the Civil War when there were perhaps more obstacles in the
river and stream fords. ^^
Legislation enacted by the General Assembly in 1850
ordered that third class roads were to be opened seven feet
in width and that a fourth class road be authorized. Fourth
class roads, called bridle ways, were probably those roads
constructed in the state that were not wider than seven
feet.?6 The extreme variance in road widths is evident in
comparing this to earlier legislation. Prior to the Civil
War, public roads existed in the county and state where
widths measured from under seven feet to thirty feet.
Research of the Rutherford County Quarterly Court
minutes for road orders and appointments of juries of view
did not reveal any after 1826. Only bridge building and
repair and overseer appropriations were included in the
minutes after 1826. A positive answer for not showing the
information formerly given was located in the minute book
'^Tennessee, Statutes of Tennessee 1858-1871 ,
pp. 58-59.
"^^ Public Acts (1850), p. 294.
35
for 1839. Robert S. Morris, the Clerk of the Rutherford
County Quarterly Court, was allowed:
. . . $1.50 for one blank book to record marriage
licenses, $2.50 for one blank book to record school
commissioners and their reports, $1.00 for seventeen
juries of view and thirty-nine road orders. ^^
This indicates that between 18 27 and 18 3 8 Rutherford County
altered its documentation procedure by adopting separate
road order books, but no road books were located in the
research for this thesis. Table 1, which shows the amount
of road orders and requests for juries of view, is helpful
in determining the amount of public road construction in
the county after 1827.
That there was a large amount of public road construc-tion
in the 1840s and 1850s is shown in Table 1. This
in itself might indicate why the county court adopted the
separate road books. Recording of road construction in the
county became too cumbersome to be included in the regular
court minutes. Another possible explanation for this change
was that on May 22, 1828, the county court was of the
opinion that:
. . . some of the public roads and highways in this
county, and particularly the stage road, are in bad
condition, and it being the opinion of the court that
it is of the highest importance to the public, that
said roads should be at all times kept in good repair. '&#176;
^^Rutherford County, Tennessee, County Court Clerk's
Office, Quarterly Court Minute Book Z, p. 103.
^^Ibid., Book V, p. 203.
36
TABLE 1
RUTHERFORD COUNTY JURIES OF VIEW
AND ROAD ORDERS
Year Number of Juries
of View
Number of Road
Orders
1839 17 39
1840 22 42
1841 &#8212; &#8212;
1842 &#8212; &#8212;
1843 &#8212; &#8212;
1844 &#8212; &#8212;
1845 &#8212; &#8212;
1846 10 62
1847 15 58
1848 24 57
1849 23 73
1850 27 83
1851 48 93
1852 43 92
1853 55 75
1854 27 106
1855 18 102
1856 17 70
SOURCE: Rutherford County, Tennessee, County
Court Clerk's Office, Quarter Court Minute Book Z,
pp. 103, 163, 565, 63; Book AA, pp. 56, 135, 221, 333,
459; Book BB, pp. 155, 326, 497; Book CC, p. 45.
37
As a result, the court ordered that Samuel H. Laughlin be
appointed to assist the state's attorney general in any
prosecutions that had been or would be initiated against
any road overseers.'-7^9 This might have resulted in the
county court's altering its procedure of recording road
information. Instead of looking through several volumes of
court minutes to locate directors for a road, concerned
individuals could refer to volumes that pertained only to
public roads.
This chapter has examined the early public roads in
Rutherford County and, to some extent, in Tennessee.
George Rogers Taylor, in The Transportation Revolution
1815-1860 , refers to this type of road as the "rural road."
These rural roads led from farms in neighboring towns,
8 mills, cotton gins, and country stores. Taylor states,
. . . the fact that the years from about 1800 to 1830
have been called the "turnpike era" has diverted
attention from country roads, roads which were really
much more important . . . than were the turnpikes,
which were chiefly designed for travel between large
towns or . . . westward across the mountains.
He provides several reasons as to why the rural or public
roads were permitted to continue in poor condition. Rural
communities during this period had neither the capital nor
"^^ibid.. Book V, p. 203.
o r\
George Rogers Taylor, The Transportation Revolu-tion
1815-1860 , The Economic History or tne United states,
no. 4 (New York: Rinehart and Co., Inc., 1951), p. 15.
S^Ibid., p. 16.
3^
the manpower to expend on improving the system of country
roads. The interest of the farmer was in clearing land and
building homes, schools, and courthouses. The second
factor involved road building as a community responsibility,
and for citizens to work off their highway taxes. The road
workers assembled often in a carnival mood and at a time of
year when farm work was slack. This was frequently not the
best time to construct roads. The road overseers and
workers were skilled at cutting trees and pulling stumps,
not highway engineering. Finally, according to Taylor,
farmers did not deem it worthwhile to expend large amounts
of labor and expense on constructing good roads. Road
maintenance was low priority work. Bad roads were an
inconvenience to the farmer. &#176;^
Research for information about Rutherford County
roads seems to uphold the explanations given by George
Taylor for poor roads. The county court authorized many
roads to be constructed from 1804 to the Civil War, but
there was never a sufficient labor force to keep all of
the public roads properly maintained. This is emphasized
when male residents had to contribute only five days of
labor each year to road work. There were also individuals
exempted from the potential labor pool used by the over-seers
for work on the roads. It might be possible to test
82Ibid.
39
this by using the census records for a district in Ruther-ford
County and comparing the road mileage. &#176;-^
Due to the simple technology used in road construc-tion
prior to the Civil War, there was little need for a
large amount of capital. With sledge hammers costing the
county about $3.50 each in the 1830s and 1840s and that
being the major expense to the county, a large amount of
capital was not necessary. Most of the other tools were
brought from the farm.^^ As to the lack of knowledge in
constructing roads, the road workers had developed skills
over time which had been tested by the environment and
experience. Farmers became adept at building roads because
they did not have professionals to construct roads. They
followed common rules such as selecting the shortest and
most direct routes commensurate with easy grades or con-structing
the road along the southern or western slope of
ridges so that it would be least exposed to storms and
8 R would dry out more quickly. No comment on the outlook
of those who worked on the public roads can be given as
S^ public Acts (1873), p. 161. The amount of manda-tory
days worked on the roads by male residents prior to
1873 was not found in earlier road legislation. It is
assumed that the days required of the male residents were
approximately the same
S^Rutherford County, Tennessee, County Court Clerk's
Office, Quarterly Court Minute Book Z, pp. 180, 326, 401, 566.
Logan Waller Page, Roads, Paths and Bridges , The
Farmer's Practical Library (New York: Sturgis and Walton
Co., 1913), p. 64.
40
no eyewitness accounts of road work were located. That the
roads of Rutherford County were not of low priority can be
seen by observing the number of turnpikes located in the
county that were chartered from 1830 to 1860. This road
building mania does not identify with a society that sees
poor roads and transportation as an inconvenience.
41
CHAPTER III
THE TURNPIKE ERA IN RUTHERFORD COUNTY,
1830-1860
If transportation in Rutherford County during the
nineteenth century is examined, it is most likely that two
major developments will be noticed. One development was
the introduction into the county in 1851 of the Nashville
and Chattanooga Railroad. The other more pervasive trans-portation
improvement was the construction of an extensive
network of turnpikes from 183 to 1860. These turnpikes
were the predecessors of many of the county's present roads.
It is interesting to note that turnpikes, like early
road technology and the administrative system for building
roads, were initiated and developed in England. The
renowned turnpike builders like "Blind Jack" Metcalf,
Thomas Telford, and John Loudon McAdam built roads that
were, in many respects, copied in the United States. It is
important for later comparison between the English turnpikes
and those constructed in Rutherford County to describe the
methods used by Telford and McAdam. Telford's method began
by laying a solid course of big stones seven inches in depth.
Sims, p. 223.
42
On this course a four-inch layer was built up, and a two-inch
binding layer of gravel was added. Attention was given
to the road slope to insure that it slanted from the crown
or high point to the sides of the road. McAdam's method
left out the costly footing of large stones. Two four-inch
layers of broken stone were placed on the camber or sloped
roadbed.^ None of the stones utilized were to exceed six
ounces in weight. To establish the size of the rocks, the
road surveyors carried either a pair of scales with six-ounce
weights or a two-inch-diameter metal ring. On top
of the two layers of broken stone, a two-inch layer of one-inch-
diameter stone was consolidated to the others by
ramming and later by traffic. The success of these types
5
of roads was in their ability to drain and repel water.
It is possible that the technology involved in con-structing
the turnpikes came from Pennsylvania rather than
from England. John McAdam moved to England from America in
1789 and possibly carried with him ideas on constructing
roads that did not deteriorate rapidly from water. The
introduction of the turnpike as a toll road in the United
States began with the Lancaster Turnpike built around 1792.
^Bracegirdle, p. 72; Cossons, p. 321.
^Bracegirdle, p. 72. ^Cossons, p. 321
5 6.
'Bracegirdle, p. 72. '^MacGill, p. 52.
43
It was referred to as being macadamized; but, since the
process was not invented until after 1816, that is open to
question. The major impetus for the construction of turn-pikes
in portions of the United States was the War of 1812.
This impetus resulted from the need for troop movements and
the general improvement of commerce following the war. The
controversy over Federal support for internal improvements
and sectional jealousy influenced the delaying of turnpikes
and other internal improvements in the South.
&#176;
The first turnpike company incorporated by the
General Assembly in Tennessee was the Cumberland Turnpike
Company in 1801. It was the company formed to finance
Walton's Road. The act of incorporation gave certain indi-viduals
authority to collect tolls on the road. The toll
receipts were allocated to pay the toll keepers and for the
road and its maintenance.^ Besides the legislature's char-tering
of turnpike companies, it also appointed commissioners
to have a particular road cleared, opened, and maintained,
much like the Georgia Road.-^^ According to Stanley Folmsbee,
a noted Tennessee historian, the expansion of settlement,
trade, and commerce led to the development of an increased
'Lane, p. 143; Bracegirdle, p. 72.
^Taylor, pp. 18-23. ^Boniol, p. 407.
Stanley John Folmsbee, Sectionalism and Internal
Improvements in Tennessee 1796-1845 (Knoxville, Tenn.
East Tennessee Historical Society, 1939), p. 24.
44
interest in the construction of turnpikes in Tennessee.
This interest increased after the process of macadamizing
became familiar.
In Middle Tennessee, the merchants of Nashville
encouraged the construction of turnpikes that radiated from
the city into the outlying area. Travel on Middle
Tennessee's roads in 1834 was described in a newspaper
account
With a heavy load of cotton a strong team can not
travel more than ten or fifteen miles a day. The mud
is from 6 to 18 inches deep, the ruts are frequent and
dangerous quagmires, which occur "ever and anon," are
bridged over with logs that are often broken or
decayed .^^
Gov. William Carroll in 1824 advocated the incorporation of
turnpike companies to improve commerce in the state. In
1827 Gov. Sam Houston argued for improving the terms of
incorporation to promote private investment. He stated
that promotion of private capital was necessary
. . . because the "deep richness of the soil" in cer-tain
parts of the state made difficult "the construc-tion
of public roads upon the ordinary plan," and
because "the population residing in the neighborhood
of great and leading market roads, can not with the
labor and time justly devoted to that duty continue
such repairs as our present laws contemplate for all
public highways. "13
lllbid., p. 72.
Nashville Republican and State Gazette , 27 Novem-ber
1834, cited by Folmsbee, p. 17.
'^Folmsbee, p. 72.
45
On January 4, 183 0, the first turnpike company was incor-porated
to operate in Rutherford County as the Nashville
and Murfreesboro Turnpike Company .
''^
From 1830 to the beginning of the Civil War, forty-seven
turnpike companies were chartered by the General
Assembly for operation in Rutherford County. All of the
companies did not build roads in the county, but all of them
will be examined in this thesis. Specific information on
the turnpikes, such as turnpike routes and those individuals
involved in the formation of the companies which might be of
interest to the reader, will be provided. Comparisons of
the turnpikes will be by decades rather than as one group,
and they will then be tied into the turnpike movement of
Tennessee as a whole. Some turnpikes such as the Nashville,
Murfreesboro, and Shelbyville Turnpike; Murfreesboro,
Manchester, and Winchester Turnpike; Jefferson Turnpike;
and the Cumberland and Stones River Turnpike will be con-centrated
on because of the availability of documentary
evidence in the state archives.
During the 1830s ten turnpike companies were char-tered
by the state for operation in Rutherford County. This
county, relative to other areas of the country, was a late
-'&#8226;'^ Piablic Acts (1829), p. 228; Folmsbee, p. 72,
states that the legislature chartered a turnpike company
from Nashville to Murfreesboro in 1824, but this writer
could not verify this.
46
arrival to having internal improvements within its bounda-ries.
In 1827 State Senator Rucker of Rutherford County
stated that:
. . . he would be in favor of appropriating the whole
or a part of land revenue to "the great work of inter-nal
improvement," if he believed there was "any
practicable plan of laying out money to advantage and
without wasting it. Nothing can be done, because
everything is required to be done."!^
Fortunately for the county there were "merchant capital-ists"&#8212;
those individuals active in banking, commerce, and
local industry who were willing to take a risk in organizing
and financing turnpike companies in Middle Tennessee without
state financial assistance. &#8226;^^
On January 4, 1830, the Nashville and Murfreesboro
Turnpike Company was chartered by the General Assembly. The
company's initial stockholders possibly included Charles I.
Love, James H. Foster, William H. McLaughlin, David Wendell,
James Morton, Robert Jetton, David W. Dickinson, Zachariah
Posey, William Bowman, George Thompson, John McGrigor,
Martin Clark, Henry Ridley, Moses Norvell, George Shall,
Robert Weakley, and Beverly Nelson. Any six of these indi-viduals
were considered by the state to be able to form the
company. They were authorized to open and establish a turn-pike
from Nashville to Murfreesboro.
&#8226;^-'National Banner and Nashville Whig , 13 October
1827, cited by Folmsbee , p. 77.
^^Taylor, p. 25. ^"^Public Acts (1829), p. 228.
47
In order to build the road, the Nashville and Mur-freesboro
Turnpike Company was allowed to take all the
necessary timber, gravel, stone, and dirt from the lands of
adjoining property owners. If the landowner and the company
could not agree on an equitable value of resources, the
property owner could petition any justice of the peace to
appoint three disinterested freeholders to value the mate-rials.
The jury would assess a fair and reasonable value
of the materials, and the landowner would be compensated
for that amount by the turnpike company. This concept of
the valuation of materials utilized by the turnpike company
existed throughout the period focused on by this thesis.
It was unlawful to establish any other road so close to
this turnpike as to injure the financial interests of the
1 Q
company.
Something happened to the Nashville and Murfreesboro
Turnpike Company, because it either became insolvent or
merged with the Nashville, Murfreesboro, and Shelbyville
Turnpike Company. On December 17, 18 31, a nine-member Board
of Commissioners of Internal Improvements was constituted by
the state legislature. Henry D. Jamison, Samuel Anderson,
and Vernon D. Cowens were its Rutherford County members, and
Davidson and Bedford counties also had representatives. It
was the duty of these commissioners to open books of
18 Ibid. , pp. 229, 231.
43
subscription for stock in a turnpike that was to run from
Nashville through Murfreesboro to Shelbyville. The sub-scribers
were to constitute the Nashville, Murfreesboro,
and Shelbyville Turnpike Company. ^
An extensive system of state financial aid for
transportation was passed by the General Assembly in 18 30.
Robert E. Corlew, in Tennessee; A Short History , states:
"On January 2, 1830, lawmakers appropriated $150,000;
$60,000 each was earmarked for work in East and Middle
Tennessee, and the remaining $30,000 was designated for the
western district. "^^ The Nashville, Murfreesboro, and
Shelbyville Turnpike Company took advantage of this state
aid. As soon as $20,000 was subscribed by individuals, the
turnpike's commissioners were allowed to subscribe the
amount allotted to Davidson, Rutherford, and Bedford coun-ties.
When the governor was notified that $50,000 had been
subscribed by individuals, he was to subscribe the amount
of the common school fund of the three counties. The turn-pike
commissioners were to pay six percent per annum to the
board of commissioners for common schools. Work on the
turnpike was scheduled to begin on April 1, 18 32. 21
^^Ibid., (1831), pp. 69-70.
^^Robert E. Corlew, Tennessee; A Short History ,
2nd ed. (Knoxville; University of Tennessee Press, 198l)
p. 200.
^^Public Acts (1831), pp. 69-71,
49
Turnpike construction in Middle Tennessee was still
conducted at a slow pace. By 1834 only one turnpike had
been completed. In November 1834, Washington Barrow became
the editor of the Nashville Republican and State Gazette .
He was a strong advocate of a system of turnpikes radiating
from Nashville to combat the loss of commerce from railroads
and the Tennessee River. ^^ More state aid was needed to
stimulate turnpike construction. The General Assembly of
1835-1836 authorized state subscriptions of one-third the
total stock subscribed in railroad and turnpike companies. ^-^
By August 1836, the Nashville, Murfreesboro, and Shelbyville
Turnpike Company's president reported that he had received
from Gov. Newton Cannon $66,666 in state bonds, one-third
of the company's total capital stock.
By the end of 1837, completion of the Nashville,
Murfreesboro, and Shelbyville Turnpike was reported in sight
by the company's president, R. C. Foster, He stated in
correspondence to the state government that:
The commissioners, aware that the propriety of any
system of internal improvement depends greatly on the
permanency and success of the first works undertaken ,
devoted all the energies and means in their power to
^^Folmsbee, pp. 100-101. ^^Ibid., p. 112.
^^R. C. Foster, receipt to State Board of Internal
Improvements, 6 August 1836, Folder 22, Box 4, Record
Group 5, Archives Section, Tennessee State Library and
Archives, Nashville, Tennessee.
50
the successful accomplishment of the work under their
management. . . .25
He said that the company had entered into contracts on the
total fifty-five-mile length of the turnpike. At the time
the State became a stockholder, the company had borrowed a
large sum of money and invested it in the turnpike's con-struction.
At this time ten tollgates had been built, and
toll was collected at them. The final tollgate was to be
put in operation by December 1, 1837. The President hoped
that toll receipts would pay six percent per annum on the
two hundred thousand dollars of capital stock. The company
had also purchased small tracts of land at each tollgate on
which to construct the necessary buildings. ^^ The turnpike
was completed in 184 2.^7 Even with the state's substantial
financial aid, the turnpike company had difficulty in meet-ing
its obligations in completing the turnpike. In 1850
the company was paying a 4^ percent dividend on the capital
stock, which was not much of a return on investment. ^&#176;
The Nashville, Murfreesboro, and Shelbyville Turn-pike
had a problem with persons living near the road and
R. C. Foster to Luke Lea, 11 November 1837,
Folder 22, Box 4, Record Group 5, Archives Section,
Tennessee State Library and Archives, Nashville, Tennessee.
26ibid. 27sinis, p. 220.
^^Willis Snell to Col. W. B. A. Ramsey, 13 January
18 50, Folder 22, Box 4, Record Group 5, Archives Section,
Tennessee State Library and Archives, Nashville, Tennessee.
51
using the turnpike for up to three miles without paying any
toll. Beyond this impropriety, the same individuals charged
an excessive amount of money for rock taken from their land.
The Board of Directors hoped to get a law enacted that com-pelled
every person who utilized the turnpike to pay in pro-portion
to the distance used without passing a tollgate.''^
The company did get relief in 1858 in not having to maintain
the turnpike within the city limits of Nashville, Murfrees-boro,
and Shelbyville . -^^
The Hoover's Gap Turnpike Company was incorporated
on January 4, 183 0, the same day as the incorporation of the
Nashville and Murfreesboro Turnpike Company. Individuals
who were the first stockholders of the company included
Christopher Shaw, Jacob Hoover, Joel Smith, Joseph Carney,
Moses Hart, John Hilton, James Arnold, T. L. D. W. Shaw,
and William S. Watterson. They were to open a turnpike from
Murfreesboro through Hoover's Gap to Thomas Powers in
Bedford County. They had the opportunity to extend the
turnpike to Winchester or as far as they thought necessary.
The company was required to begin construction of the turn-pike
by January 1831; however, the turnpike company either
29ibid.
^ "^Tennessee, Private Acts of the State of Tennessee,
Passed at the Thirty-Second General Assembly of the State oT
Tennessee (1857-1858), p. 114. Hereafter cited as Private
Acts .
^^Public Acts (1829), pp. 231-232.
52
became insolvent, or it merged with the Murfreesboro, Man-chester,
and Winchester Turnpike Company.
The McMinnville Turnpike Company was chartered by
the General Assembly on October 13, 1832. Individuals
appointed by the state legislature to open books for stock
subscription in the company included Charles Ready, Jr.,
John H. Wood, Jr., Henry Trott, Jr., Alexander Shields,
George R. Smartt, William M. Robertson, Thomas S. Rucker,
Isaac Hill, Henry D. McBroom, John Black, Archibald Hicks,
Edmund Taylor, Leighton Terr ill, Lusk Colville, Jesse Locke,
James Berkley, Joseph Youree, Daniel M. Stewart, David
McKnight, William M. Beard, George Brandon, Christopher
Baty, Hiram Tenison, John W. Connelly, Joshua Barton, and
Absolom Weatherly.-^^ The route of the turnpike was from
"Murfreesboro to the top of the Stones River Ridge in Warren
County in the direction of McMinnville, passing by Danville
in Warren County. "-^^ The board of directors was authorized
to subscribe to the Warren County common school funds by
executing a bond of $10,000 and paying six percent per annum
interest to the commissioners of the common schools, but not
until $40,000 was subscribed. ^^
In 18 37 the General Assembly granted the McMinnville
Turnpike Company the "authority to enter upon all lands and
32private_Acts (1832), p. 21.
33ibid., p. 22. 34jj^i^^^ pp^ 22, 24
53
tenements through which they (president, directors, and
agents) may judge it necessary to make said road." If the
company and landowners could not agree on the value of the
land, either party could petition the circuit court to
appoint five disinterested freeholders to value the land.
This jury had to take into consideration the damage that the
landowners would sustain from the road relative to the bene-fits
of the road accruing to the landowner .
^^^ The last
reference that this writer could find regarding the McMinn-ville
Turnpike Company was an amendment to its charter,
passed on January 18, 1838, when the company was still con-structing
the road. The General Assembly required that the
directors proceed in locating and marking out the road and
contracting for the construction of the road.-^^ Evidently
the company was having financial problems, as no later
reference was located on its progress. The company probably
became insolvent, or merged with the McMinnville, Woodbury,
and Murfreesboro Turnpike Company.
Stanley Folmsbee said of the 1836 legislation which
permitted state subscription of one-third of the capital
stock that it put into operation a system of internal
improvements that far exceeded the needs of the time.^^
Some state officials observed that the 1836 legislation was
^^Public Acts (1837-1838), p. 70.
3^Ibid., p. 292. ^'^Folmsbee, p. 112
5/f
not advancing internal improvements at a level that they had
intended. According to Folmsbee, there was not enough fluid
capital in the state for any large-scale internal improve-ment
companies to obtain the individual subscriptions neces-sary
to qualify for state aid.^^ Middle Tennessee was the
only area to benefit from the legislation. This was due to
its having a larger population base, a higher level of
wealth, and fewer natural obstacles than the other two areas
of the state. Also, Middle Tennessee concentrated its
attention on constructing turnpikes rather than pursuing the
illusive railroad. 39 In 1838, an act was passed in the
General Assembly that attempted to increase state aid for
internal improvements. The governor was allowed to sub-scribe
for stock in "sanded," "graded," and macadamized
turnpikes in the amounts of $750, $1,000, and $3,000 per
mile, respectively.^
The major drawback of this legislation was the
opportunity of the turnpike companies to defraud the state.
The law required that all individuals pay a certain portion
of their subscription to the company before the state would
invest in the turnpike company. The law did not specify the
method in which these individual payments should be made.
One of the illegal schemes perpetrated on the state was to
2^Ibid., p. 131. ^^Ibid., p. 137,
^&#176;Ibid., pp. 167-168.
55
incorporate a company of about ten stockholders who borrowed
the full amount to finance the road, say $7 0,000. This
would entitle them to receive an equal amount in state bonds.
The stockholders would then get the construction contract
for the whole turnpike at an estimated cost of $140,000.
They would borrow the whole fund from the board of directors
and buy three hundred slaves. The slaves would build the
road in one year, and once the road was completed the stock-holders
would sell the slaves at an increase of $100 each.
Since all the expenditures probably did not exceed $4 0,000,
they were able to pay back the borrowed $7 0,000 and clear a
profit of $60,000.^-'- This writer did not discover any
similar scheme in Rutherford County.
Governor Cannon attempted to stop the fraudulent
activities of some of the turnpike companies by requiring
specific information from the companies prior to granting
any state aid. The information included the length of the
road, its description, the number of miles constructed and
in progress, and the nature of the contract for the turn-pike's
construction. There was a noticeable decrease in the
speed in which state bonds were issued after the governor's
circulars went into effect.
On July 4, 1836, Russell Dance, William Ledbetter,
and Logan Henderson of Rutherford County were appointed by
^^Ibid., p. 179. 42ibid., p. 183
56
the General Assembly to open books for stock subscriptions
in the Murfreesboro, Manchester, and Winchester Turnpike
Company. ^-^ The first reference made about the turnpike
company in the General Assembly on February 20, 1836, con-cerned
its capital stock, so it is difficult to determine
the date when it was actually chartered.'*^ In January 1838,
Henry Norman and David McGill replaced Ledbetter and Dance
as commissioners of the turnpike .^^ The role of the com-missioner
in the company was to observe the company's opera-tions
in the interest of the state. William Watterson,
the president of the company, had been one of the original
stockholders in the Hoover's Gap Turnpike Company. ^&#176;
The Murfreesboro, Manchester, and Winchester Turnpike
Company was having financial problems in 1843. The problems
partially dealt with state aid. The company's board of
directors made a proposition to the state in which the com-pany
would discontinue the twenty-two miles from Manchester
to Winchester and concentrate on the thirty miles from
Murfreesboro to Manchester. The board resolved to macadam-ize
twenty miles and grade ten miles. ^' Further concessions
^^Private Acts (1835-1836), p. 189.
^^Ibid., p. 67. ^^Public Acts (1837-1838), p. 291.
"^^illiam Watterson to Newton Cannon, 19 July 1838,
Folder 35, Box 3, Record Group 5, Archives Section, Tennessee
State Library and Archives, Nashville, Tennessee.
^^A. Maxwell to F. K. Zollicoffer, 15 March 1844,
Folder 30, Box 4, Record Group 5, Archives Section, Tennessee
State Library and Archives, Nashville, Tennessee.
57
to the state included that the road be contracted out in
one-mile sections, that the date and place of bidding for
the contracts be advertised in newspapers, and that the
company guarantee the average cost of the macadamized por-tion
not exceed $4,000 per mile and $2,000 for the graded
portion.
The Murfreesboro, Manchester, and Winchester Turn-pike
Company's Board of Directors compromised with the
4 9 Board of Internal Improvement on June 22, 1844. The
company's name was changed to the Murfreesboro and Manches-ter
Turnpike Company. The company informed the Board of
Internal Improvement of those who had the lowest bid for
50 each mile from Murfreesboro to Manchester. By September
1845, six miles of the road had been completed, eleven
miles were halfway completed, and the remainder was graded
except for five miles. The process of road construction
as ascertained from the reports to the Board of Internal
Improvement consisted of grubbing, or clearing of roots
and stumps; grading, or leveling, the roadbed; hauling and
'*^A. Maxwell to Board of Internal Improvement, no
date. Folder 30, Box 4, Record Group 5, Archives Section,
Tennessee State Library and Archives, Nashville, Tennessee.
^^William Watterson to F. K. Zollicoffer, 22 June
18 44, Folder 20, Box 4, Record Group 5, Archives Section,
Tennessee State Library and Archives, Nashville, Tennessee.
^^illiam S. Watterson and P. W. Davis to Board of
Internal Improvement, 9 January 184 5, Folder 1, Box 6,
Record Group 5, Archives Section, Tennessee State Library
and Archives, Nashville, Tennessee.
5S
breaking the rock into fine pieces; applying the first and
second coats of crushed stone and gravel; and, finally,
covering the road with dirt.^^ The contractors were still
working on completing the turnpike in 184 9.^^
The state government brought suit against the
Murfreesboro and Manchester Turnpike Company prior to 1852.
The General Assembly authorized the attorney general to
dismiss the suit provided the stockholders relinquish
interest that they had in the company. Once relinquishment
was completed, Lewis Garner, James Magill, and F. Henderson
were to be constituted commissioners on the part of the
state. They were to build a tollgate, hire a gate keeper,
and collect toll. They were to use the money to repair
additional five-mile sections of the turnpike. A suit would
be brought against those who did not relinquish their
stock. The suit might have been initiated because the
road was not completed and the portion that was finished had
fallen into disrepair, so much that the state had to inter-vene
to keep the road maintained. In 1858, the General
Murfreesboro and Manchester Turnpike Company,
"Semi-annual Report," 8 September 1845, Folder 11, Box 3,
Record Group 5, Archives Section, Tennessee State Library
and Archives, Nashville, Tennessee.
^^Murfreesboro and Manchester Turnpike Company,
"Semi-annual Report," 1 August 1849, Folder 11, Box 3,
Record Group 5, Archives Section, Tennessee State Library
and Archives, Nashville, Tennessee.
^^Public Acts (1851-1852), pp. 379-380.
59
Assembly allowed the Murfreesboro and Manchester Turnpike
Company leeway in not having to keep the road equivalent
in repair to the Nashville, Murfreesboro, and Shelbyville
Turnpike, but in "good traveling order." 54
The state incorporated the Fosterville Turnpike
Company on December 26, 18 37. William B. Morris, Alfred
Nailor, and Joseph Smith were authorized to open books for
raising capital stock of the company in Rutherford County.
The turnpike was to run from Fosterville to Davis's Mill
in Bedford County. ^^ No other references were found per-taining
to this company, so it is not known if the turnpike
was completed.
On January 23, 18 38, the General Assembly chartered
the Jefferson Turnpike Company. The legislature appointed
the following commissioners to open books for subscriptions
to capital stock of the company: Jacob D. Donelson, John C.
Gooch, Ransford McGregor at Jefferson; James Bevins, Joseph
B. Johns, Andrew M. McRee at Lascassas; John Moore, Benjamin
Gooch, and Allen T. Gooch at Milton. The route of the
Jefferson Turnpike was from the Nashville, Murfreesboro,
and Shelbyville Turnpike in the vicinity of Hart's Spring
to Jefferson. The commissioners had the authority to
^^Private Acts (1857-1858), p. 203.
SSpublic Acts (1837-1838), p. 81.
60
continue the turnpike to Milton or to a point between the
tovms according to the amount of stock subscribed. ^^
By July 1840, the company had constructed fifteen
miles of road. The capital stock of the company was $90,000,
of which individuals and the state each contributed half.^^
The state brought suit against the Jefferson Turnpike Com-pany,
and the case was adjudicated in Tennessee's Supreme
Court in 1843. The private stockholders were charged with
fraudulently obtaining the state's subscription for one-half
of the stock in the turnpike. The company was also charged
with making a fraudulent representation and obtaining $9,000
in state bonds. The state said members of the company
obtained contracts for building the entire turnpike at
prices greatly above the real value of the construction
work. The state wanted the connection between it and the
company dissolved and the value of the state bonds refunded
or wanted an audit to occur and deductions to be made to
bring the construction costs in line with the real value of
CO
the labor expended.-^
^^Public Acts (1837-1838), p. 438.
^^ "Financial Statements of the Jefferson Turnpike
Company," 25 July 1840, Folder 8, Box 2, Record Group 5,
Archives Section, Tennessee State Library and Archives,
Nashville, Tennessee.
^&#176;State of Tennessee v. Jefferson Turnpike Company,
no date. Folder 30, Box 6, Record Group 5, Archives Section,
Tennessee State Library and Archives, Nashville, Tennessee.
61
The stockholders denied the fraud charges leveled
at them by the state. They replied to the charges by
utilizing journals, receipts, and bonds as evidence.
According to the stockholders, the commissioners opened
books for subscription of stock in Jefferson on March 24,
1838. Eight individuals subscribed to stock valued at
$42,000. The stockholders appointed a committee to locate
and lay off the turnpike. The stockholders elected a
president and secretary on March 29, 1838. The commissioners
stated that the capital stock should equal six thousand
dollars per mile. On April 14, 1838, the turnpike was
publicly let out to the lowest bidder, with a condition that
the successful bidder was to be paid for one-half the work
in state bonds and for the remainder he was to take stock
in the turnpike. Those who had subscribed to the stock
became the contractors at an average cost of six thousand
dollars per mile. The stockholders stated that bids would
be received for another ten days from anyone willing to
receive stock for half the cost of construction. There were
no individuals desiring to bid for the contract with that
stipulation.
On May 5, 18 38, the stockholders elected directors
for the company, and on June 26, 18 38, the governor
appointed directors on the part of the state. The board of
59lbid.
62
directors met on July 21, 1838, and unanimously resolved
that the laying off of the road and contracting for road
construction be ratified. On July 28, 1838, the stock-holders
paid ten percent of the total subscribed amount.
Each of the stockholders, having contracted to construct
portions of the road, tendered a receipt to the company for
the amount of money that he would work out on the turnpike.
The company's directors then sent a certificate to the
governor verifying that the individual stockholder's stock
was well secured and ten percent had been paid. The
governor, as a result of the internal improvement act passed
in 1838, subscribed for one-half the turnpike company's
stock. By November 18 38, the state had invested nine
thousand dollars in the company.
The stockholders believed that, from all the exist-ing
evidence, the construction of the turnpike would have
cost four thousand dollars per mile if financed in prompt
payments. If contractors were paid one-half in state bonds
and the other half in money, it would cost about five thou-sand
dollars per mile. If the payment were one-half in
state bonds and one-half in company stock, the work could
not have been done for less than six thousand dollars per
mile. The contractors had an agreement among themselves
that they were to be paid in proportion to the amount of
eoibid.
63
labor and construction expense. The price was to be fixed
at six thousand dollars per mile for all the contractors,
with the actual price ranging from $4,618 to $7,350 per
mile.^1
The state's position raised the question of whether
the subscription for stock on the state's part and the
issuance of bonds were obtained by misrepresentation on
the part of the private stockholders. The state said that,
in order for the governor to make the proper decision as to
granting aid to the turnpike company, he must see private
individuals investing capital in it. The deposit of ten
percent of the total amount of subscribed stock was per-ceived
to be of sufficient evidence of the stockholders'
confidence in the company. According to the state, this
procedure was not followed in the case of the Jefferson
Turnpike Company. In the view of the state, "the payment
was the same as though there had been no payment at all."
No obligation on the part of the stockholders was created.
There was no bona fide payment of money as contemplated by
the legislature when it enacted the internal improvement
legislation. The governor was not apprised of the actual
situation. He was under the impression that the company
treasury had four thousand dollars in it when "in fact there
was not one cent. ..62
^llbid. ^^ibid,
64
The stockholders insisted that, in accordance with
the company's charter, they had the right to pay for their
stock in work upon the turnpike. As a result of this right,
they believed that the time to be worked out on the road was
equivalent to the transfer of money. The state retorted
that the stockholders might pay for their stock in work
after the company was organized and the state's subscription
had been obtained. The stockholder, who was also a contrac-tor,
might then work off the cost of the stock and obtain a
6 3
receipt as the work progressed to completion. The result
of the case was that the approval of the
. . . state directors to any act within the sphere of
their delegated powers was binding upon the state,
since the nature of the alleged fraud charged was in
the manner of letting contracts, which the court
declared was entirely within the jurisdiction of the
directors, the state had absolutely no recourse unless
actual collusion could be proved, which was manifestly
impossible. ^^
In January 1844, the General Assembly authorized the
stockholders of the Jefferson Turnpike Company to open and
construct a road from where the turnpike terminated to
intersect the Lebanon and Sparta Road or the stage road
leading from Murfreesboro to Woodbury or both roads. By
1849, the Jefferson Turnpike had been completed, and the
company would have distributed around five hundred dollars
^^ibid. ^^Folmsbee, p. 243.
^^Public Acts (1843-1844), p. 86,
65
had four bridges not been washed away by some "unprecedented
freshets in the winter of 1847 and spring of 1848."^^
In March 18 60, the charter of the Jefferson Turnpike
Company was amended to authorize the company to extend the
turnpike to Lascassas to intersect the Murfreesboro,
Lascassas, Milton, and Liberty Turnpike. The company could
increase its capital stock to aid in the extension of the
turnpike. Due to the Civil War and its impact on the
county, the extension of this turnpike was probably delayed.
The Cximberland and Stones River Turnpike Company was
incorporated by the General Assembly on January 25, 18 38.
Rutherford County residents Frank N. W. Burton, John Hoover,
Joseph B. Johns, James Holmes, and James Wade were appointed
by the legislature to open books for stock subscription in
the turnpike company. The turnpike was to begin at Murfrees-boro
and run to Lebanon in Wilson County. At the discretion
of the company's directors, the turnpike could continue to a
68 point on the Cumberland River.
In January 184 0, the General Assembly gave the
president and directors permission to surrender the company's
charter for the whole turnpike, except the portion between
Lebanon and Hunter's warehouse on the Cumberland River.
^^J. C. Gooch to W. B. A. Ramsey, 1 October 1849,
Folder 12, Box 8, Record Group 30, Archives Section, Tennes-see
State Library and Archives, Nashville, Tennessee.
^^ Private Acts (1859-1860), p. 423.
^^Public Acts (1837-1838), p. 286,
66
After this relinquishment occurred, four of the directors
on the part of the company and four on the part of the state
would be permitted to resign. The remaining directors,
three each in the interest of the company and the state,
would be constituted the Lebanon and Cumberland Turnpike
Company. ^^ The Cumberland and Stones River Turnpike Company
was still a legal entity, so the action must have been a
separation into two companies. In 1842, Thomas Rucker, Jr.,
the president of the Cumberland and Stones River Turnpike
Company, tried to get state bonds for the turnpike's con-struction.^
The Cumberland and Stones River Turnpike Company,
like the Jefferson Turnpike Company, got in trouble with the
state over the state's bonds. The turnpike company failed
to respond to interrogatories submitted to it by a joint
select committee appointed to investigate the internal
improvement companies of Middle Tennessee. The committee's
three members investigated the physical and economic condi-tion
of all the internal improvement companies that the
state had invested in stock.''' It was later disclosed in an
^^Ibid., (1839-1840), pp. 187-188.
^^Thomas Rucker, Jr., to Gov. James J. Jones, 10
September 1842, Folder 26, Box 3, Record Group 5, Archives
Section, Tennessee State Library and Archives, Nashville,
Tennessee.
"'Ipolmsbee, p. 247. ^^Ibid., p. 246.
67
examination by John W. Burton that the major portion of
$107,000 in state bonds which the Cumberland and Stones
River Turnpike Company had obtained had been embezzled by
73 its managers.
The state brought suit against the company in an
attempt to recover the embezzled funds. In an act passed
on February 24, 18 52, the state took over the management of
the Cumberland and Stones River Turnpike Company. "All
rights, powers, franchises, and privileges originally vested
in said company" were revived and vested in the state. The
General Assembly appropriated twelve thousand dollars to
complete the road. Wilson L. Watkins of Rutherford County
was one of the three commissioners who were appointed to
manage the turnpike company. They were required to work
within the guidelines of the original charter to contract
for the turnpike's construction.
In 18 54, the state required the commissioners to
make payment to the state of all collected tolls until the
twelve thousand dollars plus interest were returned to the
state. Once the money was returned, the stockholders could
elect directors who, with directors appointed by the
75 governor, would manage the company. As of February 18 56,
''^ibid., p. 247; Public Acts (1849-1850), p. 592.
"^^ Public Acts (1851-1852), p. 635.
''^Ibid., (1853-1854), p. 397.
6a
the state was still not reimbursed, but the private stock-holders
were allowed to elect three of seven directors of
the company. &#176; The turnpike was still not completed at the
outbreak of the Civil War, as in 1867 the General Assembly
was still investigating the reasons why the twelve thousand
dollars had not been returned as well as the condition of
77 the turnpike company. '
At some point during the antebellum period, the
Cumberland and Stones River Turnpike Company published, in
the form of a placard, the toll rates, rules, and regula-tions
of the turnpike. The placards were posted at the
turnpike's tollgates. The officers of the company included
Col. W. S. Huggins, President; Dr. G. S. Pierce, Vice Presi-dent;
W. D. Hancock, Secretary; and B. T. Wade, Treasurer.
Simpson Harris was the Superintendent. The Board of Direc-tors
included J. B. McHenry, Dr. J. B. Richmond, L. P.
Black, Jesse Collier, Ma j . Samuel Carter, T. C. Black, and
M. T. Bennett. ^^
The rules and regulations of the Cumberland and
Stones River Turnpike Company are interesting and give the
reader some insight into the actual operation of the
"^^ibid., (1855-1856), p. 374.
"^"^ Private Acts (1866-1867), p. 288.
7 RCumberland and Stones River Turnpike Company,
"Toll Rates," no date. Folder 38, Box 4, Record Group 5,
Archives Section, Tennessee State Library and Archives,
Nashville, Tennessee.
69
turnpike. Family travel rates were not required by law but
were granted at the option of the turnpike company. The
superintendent could withhold the lower rates from anyone
who was "unfriendly to the efforts to restore the road."
Every gatekeeper was required to remain at his gate at all
times. Every gate was to be kept closed and locked from
sunset to sunrise. This practice occurred during the day-light
hours when the gatekeeper thought it best for the
collection of tolls. The exact amount for each day's toll
receipts was to be entered in the toll book without delay.
The gatekeepers were required to refuse mutilated or frayed
currency. The traveler was required to make change. No
gatekeeper was to think himself or herself "too good to step
out in the rain, moonshine or darkness to get the toll."
If a gatekeeper failed to follow the regulations, he faced
immediate dismissal by the superintendent. The board of
directors hoped that "no reasonable gentleman or lady will
take any offense at the strict rules of this road, for they
are not intended for anyone who are [sic] willing to pay the
legal toll."^^
The Franklin and Murfreesboro Turnpike Company was
incorporated on January 27, 1838. The turnpike was to run
from Franklin in Williamson County to Murfreesboro. A
stockholders' meeting was to take place at Perkins
79 Ibid.
70
Crossroads for electing commissioners to manage the com-pany.
This turnpike company might have had a false start,
or it never materialized, as another Franklin and Murfrees-
8
1
boro Turnpike Company was chartered on January 24, 1850.
The Salem Turnpike Company was also chartered on
January 27, 1838. The General Assembly appointed John S.
Russwurm, James M. King, William F. Lytle, Benjamin Johnson,
and Lewis Garner as commissioners to receive subscriptions
for company stock. The turnpike was to begin at or near
Murfreesboro and run to Salem Crossroads. The stockholders
had the opportunity to extend the road to Versailles, at
that time in Williamson County, or to any point in the direc-tion
of Columbia, depending on the level of subscriptions. &#176;2
There are several categories of information that
will be compared in analyzing the Rutherford County turn-pikes
of the 1830s: roadbed, capital stock, leadership,
tollgates, toll rates, penalty for refusing to pay toll,
rate of completion, and maintenance of the road. For some
of these items no information was obtained on particular
turnpikes.
There were several types of roadbeds utilized for
the turnpikes in the 18 30s. The most frequently used one
^Qpublic Acts (1837-1838), pp. 283-284
^^Ibid., (1849-1850), p. 456.
^^Ibid., (1837-1838), pp. 284-285.
71
in Rutherford County was a roadbed graded at least thirty
feet wide with sufficient ditches on each side to drain off
water. It would gradually descend from the middle of the
road to the ditches. It was substantially paved or graveled
and had bridges where necessary. The graveled portion was
twenty feet wide and six inches thick. ^-^ The Nashville and
Murfreesboro Turnpike, the Nashville, Murf reesboro, and
Shelbyville Turnpike, and the McMinnville Turnpike were
patterned after this type of roadbed. Another type of road-bed
was only twenty feet wide and paved; this was utilized
by the Hoover's Gap Turnpike. The Murfreesboro, Manches-ter,
and Winchester Turnpike was required to be eighteen
8 5 feet wide and either graveled or macadamized. The first
twenty-mile portion of the road from Murfreesboro towards
Manchester was macadamized, and the remainder of the road
was graveled. ^^ The Franklin and Murfreesboro Turnpike
initially was to be paved or macadamized at least fifteen
feet wide. The turnpike that superseded it had a different
^^Ibid., (1829), p. 229, and (1832), p. 27; Private
Acts (1832) , p. 22.
^"^ Public Acts (1829), p. 232.
85ibid., (1837-1838), p. 291.
^^William S. Watterson and P. W. Davis to Board of
Internal Improvement, 28 January 1845, Folder 22, Box 6,
Record Group 5, Archives Section, Tennessee State Library
and Archives, Nashville, Tennessee.
72
roadbed and will be identified later. 87 The roadbed of the
Fosterville Turnpike was described as macadamized.^^
The turnpike companies during the 18 30s were
required not to exceed a certain amount of capital stock.
The Nashville, Murfreesboro, and Shelbyville Turnpike Com-pany
was limited to $200,000.^^ The Murfreesboro, Manches-ter,
and Winchester Turnpike Company was limited to $100,000
of capital stock after being decreased from $200,000.^^ The
McMinnville Turnpike Company's capital stock was limited to
$80, 000. ^'- The Fosterville Turnpike Company's stock was
confined to $40,000. 9 2 Several turnpike companies were
limited to $6,000 per mile for constructing the roads: the
Murfreesboro, Manchester, and Winchester Turnpike; Jefferson
Turnpike; Cumberland and Stones River Turnpike; and the
Franklin and Murfreesboro Turnpike.^ The dollar value of
the stock shares was one hundred dollars per share for the
Nashville, Murfreesboro, and Shelbyville Turnpike, the
McMinnville Turnpike, and the Fosterville Turnpike. ^^ Stock
Q'^ Public Acts (1837-1838), p. 284.
^^Ibid., p. 81. ^^Ibid., (1832), p. 72.
^^Private Acts (1835-1836), pp. 67, 189.
^&#8226;"Ibid., (1832) , p. 24.
^^Public Acts (1837-1838), p. 81.
^^Ibid., pp. 284, 285, 291, 438.
^^Ibid., (1831), p. 72, and (1837-1838), p. 81;
Private Acts (1832), p. 24.
73
of the Murfreesboro, Manchester, and Winchester Turnpike
Company sold for fifty dollars a share. ^ Several turnpike
companies gave their stockholders the option of paying for
the stock in money or labor. The turnpike companies with
this option included: the Murfreesboro, Manchester, and
Winchester Turnpike; Jefferson Turnpike; Cumberland and
Stones River Turnpike; and the Franklin and Murfreesboro
q c
Turnpike.
The leadership of the turnpike companies ranged from
nine commissioners in the Nashville, Murfreesboro, and
Shelbyville Turnpike Company to three commissioners in the
Fosterville Turnpike Company and the Salem Turnpike Cora-pany.
Those in control of the companies in the early
98
period were called commissioners and later, directors.
The individual stockholders upon the subscription of a cer-tain
monetary level of stock would hold an election. The
date and place of the election was required to be advertised
99
in a local newspaper at least three weeks in advance. The
board of directors elected a president and other officers
from among the board. If the state had subscribed to any
^^Private Acts (1835-1836), p. 189.
^^ Public Acts (1837-1838), pp. 284, 286, 291, 438.
^"^Ibid., (1832), p. 69, and (1837-1838), pp. 81, 284
^^Ibid., (1832), p. 27, and (1839-1840), p. 187.
9 9private Acts (1835-1836), p. 189.
74
stock or issued any bonds, the governor had the right to
appoint from one-third to one-half the board, depending on
the level of assistance. The board of directors and company
officers usually served from one- to two-year terms.
Many of those individuals who were appointed by the General
Assembly to open books for subscription to capital stock
were later elected to the board of directors.
Tollgates were permitted to be built and gatekeepers
were allowed to collect tolls after five miles of the turn-pike
had been completed. For every additional five miles of
turnpike completed, the turnpike companies were allowed to
erect another tollgate. Usually, tollgates were not per-mitted
to be built closer than one mile from the city or
town limits. ^^^ All of the turnpikes that had toll rates
mentioned in their charter followed the Nashville and Mur-freesboro
Turnpike Company's rates. The rates for this
turnpike included: for twenty head of hogs or sheep, 20
cents; twenty horned or neat cattle, 50 cents; every horse
or mule not in a drove, 6-1/4 cents; every horse or mule in
a drove, 2 cents; four-wheeled pleasure carriage, 25 cents;
two-wheeled riding carriage, 25 cents; loaded wagon, 25
^QQpublic Acts (1837-1838), p. 81, and (1855-1856),
p. 374.
^&#176;^Ibid., (1829), pp. 229, 232, and (1837-1838),
pp. 284-286; Private Acts (1832), p. 23, and (1835-1836),
p. 190.
75
cents; empty wagon, 12-1/2 cents; man and a horse, 6-1/4
cents; cart, 12-1/2 cents; and a hogshead of tobacco, 12-1/2
cents. 102 The Cvamberland and Stones River Turnpike rates
are interesting in that mill wagons paid the full toll one
way, and the return trip was free. All milling transported
on horseback went free. Funeral processions traveled free
on the turnpike. "-^
Some of the individuals who traveled on the turn-pikes
in Rutherford County were not always honest. Various
travelers refused to pay the toll; others attempted to run
the tollgates. There were individuals who took advantage of
crude roads or trails around the tollgates; these roads were
called "shunpikes." For those individuals caught avoid-ing
the toll, the turnpike company could obtain a warrant
from any justice of the peace in the county and recover five
dollars for every offense. 105
Usually, when the turnpike companies were chartered,
they were given a specific deadline to complete the road or
forfeit the charter. Initially, the Nashville and
^Q^Public Acts (1829), pp. 229-230, 232; Private
Acts (1832) , p. 23.
^^^Nashville and Murfreesboro Turnpike Company,
"Toll Rates," no date, Folder 38, Box 4, Record Group 5,
Archives Section, Tennessee State Library and Archives,
Nashville, Tennessee.
104Tayior, p. 28.
^Q^Public Acts (1829), p. 230; (1832), p. 29; and
(1851-1852) , p. 636.
76
Murfreesboro Turnpike was given five years to complete the
turnpike. ^^^ The Hoover's Gap Turnpike Company was required
to complete five miles of turnpike every two years. "' The
McMinnville Turnpike Company initially had that same
requirement for the first five miles, but once that was
108
completed, the company had to complete five miles a year.
The General Assembly was concerned that the turn-pikes
should be maintained and not fall into disrepair. If
a company failed to maintain a portion of the turnpike for
ten days and an individual complained to a justice of the
peace of the poor condition, the justice of the peace was
required to send three freeholders to examine the turnpike.
If the jury found the turnpike in poor condition, then the
nearest tollgate would be opened, and the travelers would be
109 allowed free access until the road was repaired. In
1836, the General Assembly enacted legislation requiring the
county quarterly court appoint three commissioners or super-intendents
to observe the turnpikes and to insure that they
were kept in repair as required by law. Whenever a majority
of the superintendents were of the opinion that a turnpike
was in bad condition, they had the authority to open the
gates until the road was repaired.
l&#176;^Ibid., (1829), p. 230. "'^^Ibid., p. 232.
^&#176;^Private Acts (1835-1836), p. 360.
^&#176;^Ibid., 1832), p. 24; Public Acts (1829), p. 230.
^^Qpublic Acts (1835-1836), p. 163.
77
Traffic safety was also a concern of the General
Assembly. In 18 38, the state legislature passed some
traffic rules for turnpikes and macadamized roads. It was
the duty of all drivers to give one-half the road to an
approaching wagon by turning to the right. This turning to
the right by the wagon driver was also required when another
wagon or vehicle was about to pass. The overtaking wagon
or other vehicle was to turn to the left and pass in a
"quiet, orderly and peaceable manner." Cracking the whip
or other loud noises were prohibited. No driver was to stop
his vehicle without turning to the right and leaving at
least half the road unobstructed. It was unlawful for any-one
to premeditate the disturbance of animals on the road.
For any free persons, the violation of any of these traffic
regulations resulted in a fine of not less than ten dollars
nor more than three months in confinement. Offenders were
also liable for damages. Any slaves guilty of the mis-demeanor
would receive from ten to thirty-nine lashes, and
their owners were liable for damages. Any vehicular homi-cide
resulted in confinement for the offender of from three
to ten years. In order for the travelers to be aware of the
rules of the road, the turnpike's directors or superinten-dent
had to place the traffic laws in a conspicuous place at
all tollgates. &#8226;'&#8226;''&#8226;
l^^Ibid., (1837-1838), pp. 178-180.
78
The decade of the 1840s had few turnpike companies
being chartered for operation in Rutherford County. Only
two turnpike companies&#8212;the McMinnville, Woodbury, and
Murfreesboro Turnpike Company and the Mill Creek Valley
Turnpike Company&#8212;were incorporated. The major factor for
the decline in incorporations was the state's tighter con-trol
on its aid for internal improvement companies. The
legislation enacted in 184 "attempted to surround the
operation of the state stock system with additional safe-guards,
in the hope that the interest of the state might be
more carefully protected. "^^2 The ^^t also approved the
state Attorney General's filing suits against companies that
might have fraudulently obtained state subscriptions and
bonds. -' The case against turnpike companies in Rutherford
County have already been mentioned. An act passed in 1844,
authorizing an investigative committee to examine the inter-nal
improvement companies in which the state had stock,
added to the climate of uncertainty. -^^^ This uncertainty
probably affected those individuals in Rutherford County who
could invest money in internal improvements . They saw that
many of the turnpike companies chartered in the 18 30s were
having a difficult time in completing the turnpikes and
remaining solvent.
^^^Folmsbee, p. 242.
^^^Ibid., p. 243. 114ibid., p. 246.
79
The incorporation of the McMinnville, Woodbury, and
Murfreesboro Turnpike Company on January 30, 1844, was an
attempt to revive the McMinnville Turnpike Company. The new
company was to commence construction at Murfreesboro and run
the turnpike through Youree's Gap. From that location, the
turnpike was to continue two miles beyond the corporate
limits of Woodbury or any location closer to McMinnville.
The company had ten years in which to complete the turnpike.
The stockholders were to elect five directors from their
number to manage the company. The state legislature stated
in the charter that the state had no obligation to subscribe
to stock in the company.
The Mill Creek Valley Turnpike Company was chartered
by the General Assembly on January 21, 1846. The legisla-ture
authorized Joseph Kimbro, William G. Roulhac, John
Shacklett, John C. Gooch, and Charles H. Walden of Ruther-ford
County and fifteen other individuals from Davidson
County to open books for the subscription of stock in the
turnpike company. The macadamized turnpike was to begin at
the four-mile mark on the Nolensville Turnpike and proceed
to Thompson's Mill; then it was to run up the Mill Creek
Valley and cross the creek near Rains's Mill. From the mill
it was to continue up the valley past Antioch Meeting House
115public_Acts (1843-1844), p. 245, and (1845-1846),
p. 177.
BO
and cross Collier's Creek. Its terminus was Bowling Green
in Rutherford County. ^^^
The capital stock of the company was limited to
thirty thousand dollars. The price per share was twenty-five
dollars, far below the price per share of the earlier
turnpikes. This lower price might have indicated that
the supporters of the turnpike hoped for more involvement
by those farmers or other investors who had been priced out
of the earlier turnpikes. A corporate organizational meet-ing
was to be held at the Antioch Meeting House when five
thousand dollars had been raised. The stockholders were to
elect seven directors, one of whom would be president of the
lift company for a two-year term.
The macadamized turnpike was required, in the char-ter
of the Mill Creek Valley Turnpike, to be twenty-five
feet wide and within five degrees of being level. Sixteen
feet of its width were to be covered with fine beaten stone
or gravel and to be nine inches in depth. 119 Utilizing the
description of a macadamized road presented earlier in the
chapter, the Mill Creek Valley Turnpike did not fit the
English specifications. This turnpike was probably an
adaptation of the macadamization process to the conditions
^^^Ibid., (1845-1846), pp. 160-161.
&#8226;''''ibid., p. 160. ll^Ibid.
^^^Ibid., p. 161.
Si
of the area. Like the earlier turnpikes, the company was
required to build five miles of road before it could build
its first tollgate. Additional tollgates could be built
at five-mile intervals. The company had five years in which
to complete the turnpike. ^ This time limit was extended
121 another five years in 18 48. In 18 52, the company was
granted another five-year extension, and the route to be
completed was from Antioch in Davidson County through
Mechanicsville to the head of Stewarts Creek in Rutherford
County. ^^^ The Mill Creek Valley Turnpike Company was
still constructing the road in 18 58, as it was given three
123 additional years to complete the turnpike.
This writer, in attempting to locate the early
public roads in Rutherford County, has noticed that many
turnpikes in the county follow the route of these roads.
This would be economical in the sense that the company
would not have to pay for land for rights of way and would
not have to enter legal battles over proposed routes. The
companies probably did a large amount of straightening out
of the old public roads' meandering routes. The General
120ibid. 121ii3i(j,^ (1847-1848), p. 86.
122ibid., (1851-1852), p. 333.
-"&#8226;^-^Private Acts (1857-1858), p. 153.
82
Assembly passed an act in 1840 prohibiting the turnpike com-panies
from building a turnpike and placing tollgates on it
. . . whether the building of the road has been com-menced
or not, upon part of any of the public county
roads in this state whereby any person (s) or property
shall be prevented from . . . using the road. 124
The turnpike company therefore had to get a majority vote of
the county court to obtain permission to use the public road
as a roadbed for its turnpike. Documenting this observation
for Rutherford County is difficult as the road books were
not located by this writer.
During the 18 50s, twenty-two turnpike companies were
chartered by the state for operation in Rutherford County.
Why was there increased interest in turnpikes, especially
after the last decade? There were two major legislative
acts passed in the 1850s that possibly could have influenced
investors in Rutherford County to construct more turnpikes.
On February 7, 1850, the General Assembly passed an
"act to authorize the formation of turnpike companies." It
was a very detailed piece of legislation and deserves some
consideration in evaluating turnpikes in Rutherford County.
Any number of individuals not fewer than five could, as a
result of this legislation, constitute themselves as either
a macadamized or planked turnpike company. Before they
could conduct business, however, those individuals interested
^^^Public Acts (1839-1840), rp- 189-190.
S3
in forming a turnpike company had to register a written
memorandum in the County Register's office. This memorandum
was to state the names of members of the company and their
place of residence; the company's name; the road description
which included the width of the roadbed, material, and grade
of the road; termini and projected route of the road; amount
of capital stock; and the value of the shares. A copy of
this memorandum was to be filed with the Secretary of
State's office. ^^^ This portion of the act was apparently
ignored both in Rutherford County and on the state level.
Only one semblance of a memorandum was found in the Ruther-ford
County deed books, and that was regarding the Murfrees-boro
and Liberty Turnpike. ^26 ;^n extensive examination of
the Tennessee State Library and Archives produced documenta-tion
on only one turnpike company in Rutherford County
chartered after 1839. There is the possibility that later
turnpike documentation was lost or destroyed. Why would
documents concerning the turnpikes of the 183 0s dated after
1850 still be in existence?
The turnpike company had to conduct a survey to
locate the turnpike route and begin construction within one
year of filing the memorandum with the county register. It
125ibid., (1849-1850), pp. 229-230.
^^^Rutherford County, Tennessee, County Register's
Office, Deed Book 5, pp. 165-167.
S4
had to complete the road within five years, although the
governor could grant up to ten years for completion provid-ing
progress had been made. The company had to file with
the county register a copy of the route survey and map or
plat of the location of the road. No alteration of the
termini or route exceeding two hundred yards from the
original location was permitted unless the county court
127 approved it.
When the turnpike's proposed route ran through the
lands of an individual who was unwilling or incapable of
agreeing on a price for the land, a jury of five disinter-ested
freeholders assessed the damages of the road. The
jury returned the verdict to the circuit court, and it was
implemented. The company could take possession of a cor-ridor
fifty feet wide through the land provided that it paid
the sum assessed by the jury. The turnpike could pass
through state-owned land and freely utilize the timber,
128
stone, gravel, and earth.
Macadamized turnpikes had to have a roadbed at least
twenty-four feet wide. The first coat of stone was to be
sixteen feet wide and six inches thick. The second coat of
stone or gravel had to be at least eight feet wide and six
inches thick. The final coat of stone had to be beaten to
^27pu]biic_Acts (1849-1850), p. 230.
^2^Ibid., p. 231.
^5
129
the size of one-half pound in weight. This specification
for the turnpikes was similar to John McAdam's process in
that there were layers of stone, and an attempt was made to
keep the stones of the top layer of uniform size. The
difference was in the number of layers and the size of the
stone. The turnpike companies continued to have the right
to take any timber, stone, gravel, or dirt needed to con-struct
the road provided they paid a reasonable amount for
it.l30
The practice of building a tollgate after completing
five miles of turnpike was continued. The company could
position them as best suited it, although the gates could
not be placed closer than four miles apart and 1-1/2 miles
from an incorporated town or village. The turnpike company
could purchase ten acres of land adjacent to each tollgate.
The authorized toll rates were: each hog or sheep, 1 cent;
each cow or horse in a drove, 2 cents; each horse or mule
not in a drove nor employed in drawing, 5 cents; loaded
wagon, 25 cents; each buggy, baroche, and similar two-horse
carriage, 15 cents; two-horse pleasure carriage, 25 cents;
and other vehicles used for transporting goods or produce,
10 cents. Anyone who forcibly or secretly passed the toll-gates
without paying the toll was liable for a five-dollar
f ine.-131
^^^Ibid. 130ibid.; and (1853-1854), p. 165.
^^"^Ibid., (1849-1850), p. 234.
86
If a turnpike or a portion of it developed bad road
conditions and was out of repair for twenty days, then any
person could complain to a justice of the peace, and he
would send a jury of freeholders to examine the road. If
it was found to be in a poor state of repair, the nearest
gate or gates were opened to free traffic. When the road
was repaired, the company could appeal to the circuit court
to have the gates closed for collecting tolls.
In January 18 54, the General Assembly passed some
amendments to the act, passed in 18 50, authorizing the forma-tion
of turnpike companies. The initial election of the
board of directors was to occur when ten percent of the
capxtal stock had been subscribed. ^^^ The turnpike company
could collect one-half of the toll authorized after it con-structed
2-1/2 miles of road. This was probably an
attempt to raise money quickly to finance the construction
of the turnpike. The gatekeeper could be fined up to fifty
dollars for unnecessarily detaining travelers or demanding
a larger toll than authorized. The turnpike company had
to reinvest all the toll receipts into the construction of
the road until it was completed. The company could issue
construction bonds up to an amount not to exceed double the
132ibid. , p. 235.
^^^Ibid., (1853-1854), p. 164.
^^^Ibid. '^^Ibid., p. 165.
B7
amount of the cost of the completed portion of the turnpike
which had tollgates. The interest rate payable was not to
exceed eight percent per annum. The issuance of bonds might
have been a reason for the increased incorporation of turn-pike
companies in Rutherford County.
Turnpike companies could construct branch lines to
their main route, extend their main road, or change their
route. The turnpike companies were</dc:description>
<dc:description>Publication is a partial republication of a Masters Thesis presented to the history graduate department at Middle Tennessee State University</dc:description>
<dc:description>Rutherford County Public Roads from Indian Trails to the Civil War -- The Turnpike Era in Rutherford County 1830-1860 -- Roads in Rutherford County during the Civil War and Reconstruction
</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.); Rutherford County Historical Society; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865; Roads--Tennessee; Indian trails;  Roads -- Tennessee -- Rutherford County</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Roads; Public Roads; Indian Trails</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>310 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-08; mt2011-02-10</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication20ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/25</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>