<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Advertisements from the program of the 1869 Tennessee State Fair held in Murfreesboro</dc:title>
<dc:contributor>Lynch, Rita Frost</dc:contributor>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 39</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>199?</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869;</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>ADVERTISEMENTS FROM THE PROGRAM OF THE 1869 TENNESSEE
STATE FAIR HELD IN MURFREESBORO
The ads shown here are from the printed state fair program owned by Rita Frost Lynch. The fair
was held one mile south of the Courthouse Square on Church Street.
Page 64
ADTERTISEMEKTS.
C^r^XT^L STOCK, siocooo.
OF MURFEEESBORO, TENN.,
Does a General Banlcing Business of Discount &amp; Deposit,
DEALS IN ALL CLASSES OF BONDS,
Mates Collections on all accessible points in Middle Tennessee
STOCKHOLDERS.
J. B. KiMBKO, A. M. Alexander, John W. Richaedson,
J. M. Havnes, M. C. Jordan, W. B. Lillaed,
J. B. Palm Ml, J. E. DroMGooLic, Jos. Ransom,
W. N. Doughty, J. R. Fekkell, Jno. G. Phimm,
W. P. Henderson, M. Pitts, C. B. Huggins,
M. H. Alexander, Jos. R. Dillin, M. L. Fletcuek,
W. B. Hill, James D. Pichaedson, J. M. Baird,
W. A. Ransom, S. II. Miller, J. A. Collier,
I. B. Collier, S. H. Singleton, R. C. Blackman,
Travis Winrow, HENKi' R. Kekby.
J, B. K-IItSBItO, President. \V. N. &#187;OC&#171;HXYi Ticc-fresidciit.
1. K. COI&gt;ME&#171;&#163;, Cashier.
DR. R. S. &amp; 'WM. WENDBL,
DRUGGISTS km PRESCRIPTIOmSTS,
East Side Public Square,
MURFREESBORO, TENN.,
Have DOW in store a full and Select Stock of
BHOGS, MEDICINES, CHEMICALS, PATENT MEDICINES,
Glass, Pesfumerj', Fancy and Toilet Articles, Lamps, etc
To which they respectfully invite the attention of their friends and the public gene-ral!
v.
ES^ Our prices shall be as lo-iv as any house in this city Our Coal Oil is to the
standard required by law. Pi-escription&#171; accurately compounded night or day. Terms
cash, or thirty davs time to punctual dealers.
E^" SUPERIOR bAKING POWDER MADE BY US.
E"WINa &amp; A-LLEN,
Vine Street, between Cliurch and Spring Streets,
MURFREESBORO, TENNE.5SEE.
Page 65
ADVERTISEMENT S'/
JOSEPH E. PALMER. JAS. D. RICHARDSON.
MrRFREESBORO, TERfN.
J". L. CA.NNON,
MURFREESBORO, TENN.
Admitted November Term, 1SC9.
:EI. N. RA.NSOM,
DEALER IN
FAMILY GROCERJES AND COUNTRY PROOyCE,
Keeps on hand a g^ood assortment of
TEl^NESSEE IR02sT, ITAILS, CASTINGS, &amp;c.
EAST MAIN STREET,
MURFREESBORO, TENN.
CandieSj Fruits, Nuts, Cigars, Tobacco,
"^^ ' AND
AT
One door SoutJvoftJie Postoffice^ Murfre-es'boro, Tenn.
Also, Baggage Barrows, Wai-ehouse Trucks, Copying Presses, etc.
F^^IJbiBA.NKS, MORSE &amp; CO-
139 Waluut Street, Cincinnati, Obio.
A. W. CADY, Asrent, Nashville.
Page 66
10 ADVERTISEMENTS.
JOHN IXT. BURTON,
MURFREESBORO, TENN.
Will Practice in the Counties of Rutherford, Bedford, Cannon, and in the Su-preme
Court.
AffOEllT Af lAW,'
31URFREESBORO, TENN.,
"Will Practice in Rutherford, Bedford and Cannon Counties, and in the Su-preme
Court.
Strict Attention Paid to the Collection of Debts.
F. R. B U R R U S ,
iffiiiif iii iiiisiiiii if iiWb
RICHARD BEARD,
ATTORNEY &amp; COrXSELLOK AT LAW,
MURFBEESBORO, TENN
Attends to the Collections of Claims^ etc.? etc.
MURFREESBORO, TENN.
Page 67
12 ADVERTISEMENTS.
MURFREESBORO SAVINGS BAS^K,
MURFREESBORO, TENN-
(Organized Oct. 1 , 1S6S,)
CA.PIT^A.L STOCK, ^100,000.
Does a General BankinirBusiiies!^.
BUYS AND SELLS
EXCHANGE, GOLD, SILVER, UNCURRENT MONEY, STOCKS, and
GOVERNMENT BONDS.
Sight Checks for any amount on all the principal Cities of Europe, for sale.
Bein^ supplied with aPire Proof Vault aud Burglar Proof Safes, we are prepared
to receive money on Depcsit subject to .sight cliecks.
It^" Special Depo.sits received from regular depositors free of charge.
&#8364;oIIection&lt;i made on all Accessible Points, and Proceeds Prompt-ly
Remitted or Held Subject to Check as Oirected.
&#8222; ^ -' &#163; L, JORDAN, President.
E. D. REED, Cashier.
STOCKHOLDERS:
E. L. Jordan, J. W. Cliildress, J. M. Jompi^ins, Ches. Williams, John Jones, Clerk,
Bcnj. Beaty, W. G. Garrett, R. D. Reed, W. Y. Elliott, H. H. Williams, J. AT. Avt-nt,
Gen. W. H. Smith, Thomas A. Elliott, Anderson Jones. E. D. Hancock, J. E.
Fletcher, Sr., E, .Mathews, Chas. Ready, W. C. Burt, John Woods, M. E.
C. Beasley, J. A. -Moore, Joseph W, Nelson, Wm. Barton, Dr. T.
C. Black, W. R. Butler, E. Rosenfield, Mrs. Sallie J. Fow-ler,
Jonn W. Thomas, Miss Adelaide Smith, Jas.
McCulloch, A. Van Hoos, John Baird.
DICKSON'S COTTON SEED,
DAVID DICKSON, OF GEORGIA,
With his improved and selected seed, makes from
TWO TO FIVE THOUSAND P0OTD3 PER ACRE,
And the Farmer on the rich limestone lands of Middle Tennessee, can do as well by
using his early maturing heavy boiling Cotton Seed. I have procured from Mr. Dick-sou
his select seed, and have acclimat~ed the seed to tiiis climate, and as 1 wish to ois-tribute
the seed through Middle Tennessee, I will All a limited number ol orders for
the seed in small quantities of two bushels to each purchaser at half the price Mr.
Dicksou sells his seed for.
On receipt of $5 I will forward to any address two bushels of the seed, selected and
warranted genuine, put up in good sound sacks. The seed will be ready for delivery
after the loth ol September.
Full Directions for Cultivating the Cotton will be sent -with each Sack.
MURFREESBORO,
TENNESSEE.
Page 68
14 ADVERTISEMENTS.
DR. SAMUEL EC. BEA]RE,
I&gt; E: TV T I &#171; T,
Graduate of the Baltimore College of Dental Surgery,
Office Up Staiks Over Savings Bank,
MURFREESBORO, TEIVW.
ATTORNEY AT LAW AND SOLICITOR IN CHANCERY,
MURFREESBORO, TENN.
B. L. KIDLEY. J. M. AVENT.
JRIDIuEY &amp; AVEJ\T,
A.TTOEIsrEYS A_T EA.'VSr,
MURFREESBORO, TENN.
.A. T T O IR n&gt;T E -"^ A^T IL. A. -^i;^ ,
OFFICE EAST MAIIV STREET,
IMURJB'tiEEISaSOlio. XEJVJSr.
1^^ Collection of Claims promptly attended to.
For 8ale, Valuable City Property,
WELL LOCATED IN MURFREESBORO, TENNESSEE,
CONSISTING OF
Fine and Taluable Dwelling^ and Business Houses.
Also, Thiriy nice UDimproved Lots near Union University, just outside the corpo-rate
limits of the city. Apply to
:S!- r3R MS TO SUIT PURCHASERS.
Page 69
16 A D VEKTISEMENT S.
J^ O O iT S E I^^T J^ T" I "V^ E 1= ^ IP E I^.
DEVOTED TO THE INTERESTS OF RUTHERFORD COUNTY.
THE IIURFREESBORO NEWS.
^2 I=&#187;&#169;r .^a^ixix-ULixi ; $1 for- S&#177;:x. TWIoxLtlajs.
OEFICE: Corner of Church and College Streets.
THE NEW8 JOB PRirVTIlVG OFFICE.
We have an entire new stock of Job Type, of the most approved kinds, and we re-
Rpectfully announce to our patrons and friends that we are prepared to execute every
description ot
Plain and Fancy Priating upon tbe Most Reasonable Terms.
Bill Hea.ds, Letter Heads, Business Cards, Prog-rammes, Circulars, "Way
Bills, Invilatioa Cards, Cbecks, Hand Bills, &amp;:c.,
JEXECUTED NEATLY AND WITH DISJPATCET.
It is our determination to spare no exertion to deserve the patronage of this county,
upon which we shall rely confidently for success in onr enterprise.
HENDERSON A: PRITCHETT,
inurlreesboro, Tenn.
J. H. ELLIOTT. ' E. 0. COX.
ELLIOTT &amp; cox:,
GROCERS ^ DEALERS IN PRODUCE,
COKIVER SqrARE AIVD CHURCH STREET,
TE IST 3Sr.
Page 70
18 ADVEKTISEMENTS.
IsT. C. OOXjI_iIE:R.,
NORTH-EAST CORNER OF PUBLIC SQUARE,
MFRFREESBORO, TERTIV.
AND DEALER IN
SUGAR, COFFEE, FEOUR, MEAE, BACOJV, EARD, SAET,
STA.PL1^] DRY aOODS,
BOOTS AND SHOES,
"^VHICH ^VILL OBE SOLD --^T LO^V KA-XES.
V^IImIm buy COUlffTRY PRODUCE
AT THE HIGHEST MARKET PRICE.
p. S.&#8212;WILL REMOVE THIS FALL, TO THE
NORTH-WEST CORNER OF THE SQUARE,
At the old and well-known COLLIER STAKD, where I shall have
.A-Iv^FLE E,OOlvr TO SXOK,E COTTOlSr, ETC,
GIVE ME A CALL.
Page 71
20 ADVEBTISEMENTS.
MURFREESBORO TIN FACTORY.
69
09
C9
C^
Si
CO
6*5
MANUFACTURER OF
Tii, raPPiiB, AH&#169; SHiif&#171;m&#169;fl WAii,
WHOLESALE A'ST) RETAIL DEALER IN
STOVES, CRATES AND KITCHEN WARE.
C^P- GUTTERS, PIPES and TIN-ROOFING, in the city and country, contracted
for on the most liberal terms.
IB. :E^;Os:E]I^^:E^E^l.I^,
DEALER IN
FANCY, STAPLE AND DRY GOODS,
SHOES AND BOOTS,
mm^ mmE oLifHiiic, hats mu oapi,
And a Fine Assortment of
QUEENSWARE AND CLASSWARE.
JUARANTEES TflE LOWEST PRICE IN THIS MARKET FOR ALL GOODS
Invites old friends to call and examine his stock before purchasing elsewhere.
East Side Public Square,
MURFREESBORO, TENN.
Page 72
23 ADVERTISEMENTS.
P. C. MOSBY. SAM. MOSBY.
GET THE BEST.
MANUFACTURERS OF
SAIBJLIS Al&#169; lAEHISS, ALL SIIIS,
ALSO, DEALERS IN
TlitllNKS, VAI^ISES AIST&#169; TRAVELING BAGS
OF ALL STYLES AKD SIZES,
HORSE-CANES, WHIPS, SPURS, BRUSHES, HALTERS,
In fact, everything that is kept ia a first-class Retail Saddle and Haekess
Manufactort.
^LL OK-DKR-S FTi03MI='TJL,"5&lt;^ j^TTKNDKD TO.
Eeferench.&#8212;Auy reliable Business House in the city.
WHOLESALE AND RETAIL DEALER IN
WATCHES, JEWELRY, BOOKS, STATIONERY,
JfBllSICAIi IIVSTRtJMEiVTS, .fcc,
HAS NOW ON HAND A LARGE AND WELL SELECTED STOCK OF
Watches, Jewelry, Silver Ware, Books, Stationery, Pianos, Organs,
Etc., ICtc.
M.4NUFACTURERS OF SOLID SILVER WARE, GOLD JEWELRY, Etc.
THIS REPAIR OF FINE JEWELRY, WATCHES AND CLOCKS SOLICITED.
E^" All work done by co-Tipctent workmen, and warranted, or money refunded.
Call and see this mammoth stock on the
MURFR.EESBOEO, TENN.
Page 73
24 ADVERTISEMENTS.
JESSE A. COLLIER,
I&#187;EAt,EK IIV
\LL KINDS OF FURNITURE,
LOOKING GLASSES,
HOUSE FURNISHING GOODS,
N. B.-&#8212;Goods Delivered to any part of the city free of charge.
JV. W. Corner Public Square,
MURFREESBORO, - - - TENNESSEE
ALSO,
COMITILSSION inERCHAIVT A]&#165;D DEALER IX
Iron, Castings, Iron Axle Springs, Anrils, Bellows, Tices, Chains, Domestics,
Osuaburgs, Hats, Caps, Boots, Shoes, Lead, Paints, Bacon, Lard,
Wheat, Flour, Corn Meal, etc. Dealer in Oroceries, Hard-ware,
and all kinds of Produce.
On the BTorthwest Corner of the Square.
A^, SIMITH cfe CO.
DE.4.LERS IN
FAWIIJLY GROCERIES AND PRODUCE,
BootS;, Shoes^ Hats, Hardware^ etc.
Next Door to the Sayings Bank,
CARPEIMTER AND BUILDER,
One Door East Methodist Church,
Will construct and superintend buildings of all kinds. Guarantee satisfaction in every
JOH[&gt;^ BELL, Jr., GENERAL INSURAIVCE AGENT,
]M U K F R E E S B K O , TENNESSEE.
Represents iSStna Life Insurance Go.
-AuSSETS OVER. SIO, 000,000,
Also Reliable Fire Cortipanies.
Page 74
26 ADVERTISEMENTS-JAMES
A LEIPER,
MURFREESBOItO, TEHIfESSEE.
H. H. CLAYTON, M. D. j. 3. MURFREE, M. D.
3D O O T O I^ S
CLAYTON &amp; MURFREE
Offer their services to tlie citizens ot Murfreesboro and vicinity, in the practice Of
Medicines and Surgery. Office on Main Street.
E.H.EWING. , E. D.HANCOCK.
E WIBMG 6l HANCOCK^
ATTORNEYS AT LAW &amp; SOLICITORS IN CHANCERY,
MUKFREESBORO, TENN.
JOHN PATTERSOItf, M. D.,
PHYSICIAN" Sd SURaEOIsr,
(OFFICE OYER P.. D. POADS' BOOEI STORE,)
NORTH SIDE PUBLIC SQUARE,
MURFREESBORO, TENNESSEE.
DR. GEORGE D. OROSTHWAIT,
PHYSIOBAN AND ACCOUCHEUR,
Office on ITIain Street"5
MURFREESBORO, TENN.
Page 75
28 A D V E K T I S E M E N T S .
S. H. HODGE. C. M. SMTIH.
HODaE &amp; SMITH,
FOPiWARDING AND COMMISSION
AND DEALERS IM
ALL KINDS OF PRODUCE AND GROCERIES.
Corner Wareroom, Jones &amp; Collier's New Block,
MURFREESBORO, ----- TENN-
^v\^. A.' REED,
NO. 7, NORTH SIDE PUBLIC SQUARE,
I^XJI^rB,EESBOE,0, TEISriTESSEE-Dealers
in
HARDWARE,
CROCKERY WARE,
GLASS WARE,
CARPETS,
OIL CLOTHS,
MATTINGS, &lt;StC.,
WHICH WILL BE SOLD
AT THE LOWEST CASH PRICE-Respectfully,
WT. A. REED.
Page 76
30 ADVERTISEMENTS.
]Mrs. Isl. J^. McDOXIGA-L,
WLMKIEY 41&#169; &#187;1ISS MMM'
EAST SIDE OF PUBLIC SCfclJARE,
jivo. J. iiA'wiiva &amp; soiff,
UNDERTAKERS,.
ETO., ETC.
WILL FURNISH
Fine Metalic and all ottaer Burial Cases.
We keep a supply of TINE COFFINS always on hand, and will attend burials in the
City or elsewhere, upon short notice.
OLD STAND, CORNER OF COLLEGE AND CHURCH ST3.,
MURFREESBORO, TENN.
FASHIONABLE MiLLINEBY AND DRESS-MAKING STORE,
ONE DOOR NORTH OF THE POST-OFFICE,
MTJRF'IiKESBOR.O, XEJSjNJ".
SOULE FEMA_LE COLLEaE,
]&gt;i:Ul?i3riiEESBOIiO, TEHVN.
This Institution will commence its next Collegiate Year on MONDAY, the 30th
AUGUST, 1SC9, with a complete corps of ihe mo-^t experienced and competent Teach-ers
in the State, and the must inoroufi;h course of instruction fuund in any Female
College in the aouth. Charges as low as such schools can afford. No extra charges
for either Latin or Greek. Boarders treated as daughters in the family. At least one
hundred can obtain boarding in the College on good terms. Rooms large, well fur-nished,
well warmed, well ventilated. Location beautiful and healthful. For lurther
particulars send for catalogue. Address
REV. D. D. MOORE, President.
Page 77
32 ADYERTISEMEJfTS.
J. P. RICE. n. C. WRIGHT.
DEALERS IN
FANCY AND STAPLE DRY GOODS,
We keep constantly on hand a complete assortment of
Boots, Shoes, Hats, Readj -made Clftthing,
TRAVELING BAGS, FINE TRUNKS,
UMBRELLAS, OIL WINDOW SHADES,
''OtNUINE'' LADIES' AND GENTLEMEN'S UNDERWEAR,
Lot of colored and &#8226;n hite Table Damask, ToTiels, Napkins &amp; Doylies, etc.
ALL OF THK BEST QUALITIES,
WHICH WE SELL AS
Cheap as the Same Quality of Goods can be Bought in this Mareet.
WE call special attention to our
I.ABIES' AIVD CHII.DRE?f'S FIIVE SHOES,
VVhicli we have maile to order, aud every pair warranted If they do not prove as rep-resented
the money will be returned in every instance.
All Goods Sold by us are Warranted to prove as Represented.
Call and examine for yourself. We are always ready and willing to show our goods.
RICE &lt;fc WRIGHT.
Page 78
ADVEBTISEMEKTS-BUTLER
&amp; oo.
GENEPtAL COMMISSION MERCHANTS,
IK THE LARGE
FIRE PROOF WAREHOUSE, ALONG SIDE RAILROAD TRACK,
MURFREESBORO, - - - - TENNESSEE.
Possessing superior facilities to any honse in this city or on this line of Railroad,
for all heavy handlings. The damage and expense incident to drayage all avoided.
AMPLE FIRE PROOF STORAGE ROOM FOR ALL CONSIGNMENTS.
And the locality well adapted for the exhiliition of the same. Consignments of Im-proved
Lavor Saving JNIachines and Agricultural Implements solicited. We are also
agents lor the
CES^EBKATED NORTVAY OAT,
A specimen of which is always at our office. To be convinced of the greatly superior
qualities of this Oat, you only have to see it. The yield is three times that of the best
Tennessee Oat.
CALL AND SEE FOR YOURSELVES.
Corn, Wiieat, Rye, Oats and Barley Bought all the time for Cash.
Also request all planters to carefully save all their
COTTONSEED AND SELL THEM TO US.
&#8212;ALSO&#8212;
ACJE?iT,S FOR THE FIXE IVOOBBtJRY MIEES,
AND GENEEAL BUTEP.S OF ALL THE
Page 79
36 ADVERTISEMENTS.
JOSEPH W. INELSON,
NORTH SIDE PUBLIC SQUARE,
MURFREESBORO, . . . - TENNESSEE.
DEALS IN
DRUGS, MEDICINES, CHEMICALS, OILS, PAINTS, DTE STUFFS,
WINDOW GLASS, SURGICAL AND DENTAL INSTRUMENTS.
FINE TOILET SOAPS, FINE HAIR &amp; TOOTH BRUSHES,
Pure Brandies and "Wines for Medicinal Purposes.
TBUSSES, SUPPOBTERS AND SHOULDER BRACES,
LAMPS AND LAMP CHIMNEYS,
And all of the most
A- ]&gt; p !&#8226; o &gt;' e d. I? a t e n t 31 edicine and Bitters-
I J. C. HAYNES,
GROCER AND PRODUCE DEALER.
ALL KINDS OF
PRODUCE AND FAULT SUPPLIES KEPT CONSTANTLY ON HAND AND FOR SALE,
SPIRITUO US LIQ UORS EXCEPTED.
East Side of Public .Square, Corner ITIain Street,
MURFREESBORO, - - - TENNESSEE.
Page 80
38 ADVERTISEMENTS.
L. M. MANEY. N. B. BLACE. E. L. TDRKER
MAIMEY, BLACK $c CO.,
DEALERS IN
FANCY AND STAPLE MY GOODS.
HOSIERY, ]\OTIOI^S.
BOOTS AND SHOES,
ilSfllli. lAElWlI
C3rI=tOOE;JFMESS, oto.
NORTH SIDE PUBLIC SQUARE,
MURFREESBORO, - - - - TENNESSEE.
Page 81
40 &#8226; ADVERTISE MKNTS.
TTECnE T^ JS^TyiJBlf^ ^TOIi^E:
Mrs. MARY S, IRTYGAItfT^
THE LATEST STYLES OF
ALWAYS ON HAND.
MURFREESBORO, - - - - TENN.
JEAST SIDE JPUBLIC SQUARE.
MANUFACTURER OF
MILLS, COTTON GINS, THRESHERS, HORSE POWERS, ETC.
SATISFACTIOIV GUARA7fTEEI&gt; IX ETERY CASE.
"West street, Murfreesboro, Tennessee.
THE NORTHWESTER MIITCIL LIFE mumi CO.;
The Largest Lite Insurance Company West oe the Seaboard Cities.
HjVS the: L-'VRGrEST ^SSKXS,:
And pays tbe LARGEST DIVIDENDS. Insures upon all approved plans. ALL
POLICIES NON-FORFEITING.
Gr. H. BA^SBZEXTE, .Agent,
MURFREESBORO, TENN.
L, H. iyBOO^RF'S SAL&#174;&#174;!!.
ElEEPS ON HAND
ALL KINDS OF LIQUORS, ALE, WIIv'ES, ETC.,
ALSO, :
EAST SIDE PUBLIC SQUAKE,
MURFREKSBCRO, TENN-Page
82
42 A D V E Jl T:I S E M.E K T S .
J. MicDBRMOTT,
Bl&#171;i&#174;SST 11&#174; PliSGlillFTIiMST,
East Side Public Square,
M:UJEiinK,3&#163;;E;SB0R,0, TENrv.
KEEPS CONSTANTLY ON HAND A LARGE STOCE OF -
PRESH DRUGS, OILS, PAINTS AND DYESTUFFS,
ALSO, A riNE ARTICLE OF ,
Which will be sold LOW FOR CASH.
FRANK W. WASHINGTON. THEODORE SMITH,
'm &amp; iiiifH,
DEALERS IN-STAPLE
AND FANCY DRY GOODS,
&#8226; BOOTS, SHOES, HATS AND CLOTHING.
KORTH SIDE SQUARE
CITY HOTEL,
Soutli Side l?iit&gt;lic Squai'e, - ]&gt;i;iuL'freest&gt;or-o, Teiua.
JOHN li. CROCKETT, PROPPJETOR.
Fare as Cheap as any first-class Hotel South. Give me a call.
WIOLESALi AND RETAIL BAKER &amp; CONFECTIONER,
Northeast Corner Public Square,
Has constantly on hand a complete stock of
CANDIES, CAKES, NUTS, CHEESE, CEACKERS,
FRUITS, Caimed and Fresli, PICEXES, OYSTERS,
And everything that you may find in a FIRST-CLASS CONJECTIONERr. Also,
keeps a fine assortment of
TOBACCO, CIG-ARS, PIPES AND SNUFF,
INICE NEW TOTS FOK THE CHII.WKEN, CHEAP.
PARTICULAR ATTENTION PAID TO THE FILLING OF WEDDING 4ND
PARTY ORDERS.
Will be on hand at all the Fairs given at the Grounds of the Central Agricultural
and Mechanical Association, with a coraolete stock of evervthinc- in iii&#171; linp
Page 83
</dc:description>
<dc:description>Depicts a sampling of print advertisements from the 1869 state fair program with a brief introduction by the RCHS</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.); Murfreesboro (Tenn.); Advertising</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>State fairs; Tennessee State Fair</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro;</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>20 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-01-25</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication39ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/5</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>