<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Griffith Rutherford</dc:title>
<dc:creator>McBride, Robert Martin</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 3</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1974</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>18th century; 19th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>40
GRIFFITH RUTHERFORD
by Robert Martin McBride
Family and Early Life
When we consider patriots of the American Revolution, we
should remember that&#8212;for most of them&#8212;their loyalty was origi-nally
to British institutions, and they were largely first or
second generation Americans&#8212;but, even so, they were provincial
citizens of Britain, and their loyalty belonged to George III,
rightful King of England, Scotland, Ireland, and America. Such
a man was Griffith Rutherford, for whom this county was named.
As the loyalties of Americans diverged from Great Britain to
their adopted colonies, the result was a climactic event, even-tually
resulting in the powerful force in the world that the
United States holds today.
The Scottish family of Rutherford was one of the most ancient
and powerful of Teviotdale, on the border of England. They
belonged to the lesser nobility&#8212;and Sir Walter Scott, whose
mother was a Rutherford, was related to them.-'- One of the Ruth-erfords&#8212;
unfortunately, we do not know his name although one
source states that it was John&#8212;was married, probably about 1718,
to one Ann Griffith. She belonged to a Welsh family who were
political refugees in Scotland. Very shortly after their marriage,
they removed to Ireland, again apparently for political reasons,
although the records do not indicate what they may have been.^
-&#8226;-Rumple, Rowan County , 105.
^Tennessee Historical Quarterly , V, 381-82.
41
Their oldest son, named Griffith Rutherford for his mother's
family, was born in Ireland in 1720. A few years after his birth,
when he was about nine years old, his parents took passage for
the American colonies. Unfortunately, both parents died during
the tedious voyage, and young Griffith arrived in Philadelphia
as a homeless orphan.
It is said that Griffith Rutherford arrived in
America with fine luggage and costly silver, and that
a German couple befriended him during his minority:
but that he never received any of his inheritance.
The generally accepted story is that he made his way to the
home of a cousin, Robert Rutherford, who made his home in the
Southside of Virginia. Still another account is that he was
educated in New Jersey, and became a surveyor. Another story is
that, at the age of nineteen, young Griffith took a horse and
bridle and rode from New York southward to Rowan County, North
Carolina, where his cousin, Robert Weakley, was then living.
There he settled and there the authenticated story of his life
begins.
^
In 1754, Griffith Rutherford took a wife, one Elizabeth
Graham, daughter of a prominent family which included James
Graham, a Royal Governor of North Carolina. The Rutherfords
had ten children. The Rutherford family have may descendants
living today, even, I think, in Murfreesboro. For the record,
their children were:
^ Ibid . , IV, 307
4 Ibid.,; Long, Rutherford and Allied Families , 64,
^Long, Rutherford, 65, 8 0-81.
42
1. Jane; married James Cathey
2. James; killed at Eutaw Springs
3. Blanche; married Francis Locke
4. Henry
5
.
John
6. Elizabeth; married James Wright
7. Alfred
8. Newton; removed to Texas
9. Margaret; married Elijah Chambers
10. Griffith Weakley; married Jane Johnson
While I cannot here go further into the genealogy of
the Rutherford family, I would like to mention that
Henry Rutherford was possibly the General's best-known
son. He was in Middle Tennessee as early as 1783 as a
surveyor and locator of land. He was the principal
surveyor of West Tennessee, basing his surveys from a
point known as Key Corner in Lauderdale County, where
a Tennessee historical marker stands. The town^of
Rutherford, in Gibson County, is named for him.
North Carolina
Griffith Rutherford represented Rowan County in the North
Carolina legislature as early as 1769 and about that same time
he was sheriff of the county. He was in the Assembly of 1770
and 1771 and was at the same time captain of militia. He
continued to represent his county in the Assembly in the legis-
7 lature of 1773 and 1774, and was a senator from 1777 to 1788.
P. T. Glass, "Sketch of Henry Rutherford," in American
Historical Magazine , V, (July, 1900) , 225-29.
7 . Cisco, Historic Sumner County , 293.
43
Originally of Royalist sentiments, Rutherford became,
possibly through the influence of his brother-in-law, James
Graham, a leader in the Regulator movement. By 1771 Rutherford
was joined to the struggle for American independence. "He did
not merely join the Revolution," said the late Edward Ward
Carmack, Jr., "he was one of those daring souls who made the
Revolution. "8 In all his activities, Rutherford showed "marked
abilities as a leader of men, (as) a level-headed lawmaker, and
as a general in the field. "^
In 1775 he was elected a member of the Provincial Congress
and was appointed a member of the Committee of Safety for Rowan
County, and Colonel of Militia.
In February of 1776, Rutherford attempted to take part in
the Battle of Cross Creek, the first armed conflict of the
Revolution in the South. He and his men arrived too late for
the engagement, which resulted in a decisive defeat for the
Tories. ^^
In August of 1776 the Congress, meeting at Halifax, North
Carolina, appointed him a brigadier general and authorized him
to proceed as far as Chattanooga in a punitive expedition against
the Indians. He was also to take 300 men from the Surrey
"One wonders why. Some explanation is suggested in the
author's Portrait of an American Loyalist , passim .
^THQ , V, 382.
&#8226;OMcBride, Portrait of an American Loyalist. . . ; in East
Tennessee Historical Society's Publication , II (1930), 72.
'-'-Cisco, Historic Sumner County , 294; Long, Rutherford , 20-22;
Rutherford File, Tennessee State Library and Archives.
44
County militia to rendezvous with Virginia troops on the Holston
River. Rutherford complied. ^
General Rutherford had, however, anticipated the Council of
Safety. On July 7, 1776, as general of the Salisbury District,
in command of the western districts of the state, he did not feel
warranted in taking his troops in pursuit of the Middle Towns of
the Cherokees , who were then around and threatening action against
the white people, his region, and asked for instructions. He
suggested that he should watch Virginia and South Carolina
soliciting movements against all the Cherokees by men of frontiers
of all the western provinces. Rutherford insisted that if such
confrontation should result, "I have no doubt of the final
destruction of the Cherokee Nation. -^ The route he took to the
Cherokee towns has since been known as "Rutherford's Trace. "'^
After that campaign, Rutherford was "given command of all
American forces west of the Alleghanies ,
" including a contingent
of 2,400 men to subdue an uprising of the Cherokees. "^^ During
this time Rutherford wrote to Colonel William Christain of
Virginia suggesting that "we center our strength. . . and pursue
the same means in marching at once."-*-^
l^North Carolina Colonial Records , XI, 333, 337; Williams,
Tennessee During the American Revolution , 50-51.
-'--^N.C.C.R . , X, 651; Williams, Revolutionary War , 48.
l^Ramsey, Annals of Tennessee , 164-65.
l^THQ, V, 383.
-'-^N.C.C.R . , XIII, 65; Williams, Revolutionary War , 44-49.
45
With this group, Rutherford and Campbell destroyed thirty-six
Indian towns and villages, laid waste their corn, and drove
off their cattle. This is the affair known as the Battle of
Island Flats-
Rutherford's next military exploits were in 1779 when he
marched with his brigade to Savannah to aid General Lincoln. In
June 1780, he and his 1200 men played a decisive role in dis-persing
the Tories who had assembled at Ramsour's Mill (near
Lincolnton, in Tryon County) .
'-^
Following the Battle of Ramsour's Mill, the army moved on
to Camden, where the patriots suffered a bad defeat. "Though
General Rutherford acted with distinguished gallantry, he was
captured. . . One of the dragoons gave him a sword blow cutting
through his beaver hat inflicting a severe wound across the top
in
of his head. Those captured were first confined in Camden,
then removed to St. Augustine, Florida, where General Rutherford
languished in a "dungeon prison" for almost a year. From lack
of sanitation, poor and insufficient food, Rutherford came near
dying. In August of 1781, he was taken to Philadelphia and
exchanged.
Rutherford returned to Rowan County ; reformed his brigade
and marched on to Wilmington, driving the Tories before him.
Before he reached Wilmington he heard of the surrender of Lord
Cornwallis at Yorktown.
-'-'Putnam, History of Middle Tennessee, 554.
1 p&#176;Cisco, Historic Sumner , 294; Long, Rutherford , 29-30;
Tennessee Historical Magazine , IX (1925) , 103, 106.
19^Account of Henry Rutherford to Lyman Draper, quoted in
Long, Rutherford, 41.
46
Back in Rowan County, General Rutherford led his third and
final campaign against the Indians, who were depredating the
western borders. Joined by General Charles McDowell and his
troops, he was successful in subduing the Indians without wanton
on
destruction. "
For the next decade Rutherford continued his political
career in North Carolina. At the same time he engaged in
extensive land speculations in the western country. As early
as 1783, William Bount wrote, "General Rutherford has agreed
to join adventures with us in the purchase of the Bend of the
Tennessee and I have this day given him an instrument in
writing." ^^ On three different occasions Rutherford sent
his son, Henry, to locate lands in the Cumberland region.
The time was coming near for a final adventure.
TENNESSEE
After the Revolutionary War, Rutherford was one of the
commissioners to survey the military land grant area in what
is now Tennessee, in 1783-1784. For these services he was
given a grant of 2,000 acres. Although he owned property in
North Carolina, and held a position of trust there &#8212; at times
being sheriff of Rowan County, a member of the North Carolina
Senate, and a member of the Constitutional Convention of 1788 &#8212;
he apparently was so intrigued by Tennessee that he liquidated
20
Long, Rutherford . 53.
21 . Williams, History of the Lost State of Franklin, 15.
47
22
his North Carolina holdings, and removed to Middle Tennessee.
The exact date of his removal to Tennessee has not been
firmly established, but it seems to have been about 1792. He
settled in Sumner County on a tract of land located about five
miles below Bledsoe's Lick and about two miles from the Cumber-
23
land River. Here he built a house and stockade.
He immediately became prominent in Sumner County affairs.
In 1794 he was appointed by President George Washington as
24 president of the Legislative Council of the Southwest Territory.
Whether or not President Washington knew Rutherford is not
certain, but he enjoyed the President's respect. One source
states that Washington presented Rutherford with a silver snuff
25
box, which is still cherished by his descendants.
Rutherford owned land, not only in Sumner County, but in
Maury, Davidson, Wilson, Williamson, and in what later became
Dyer County. In addition to his considerable land investments,
he maintained a prosperous plantation and flour mill in Sumner
County. When the county seat of Sumner County was laid out in
1797, it was first called Rutherford in his honor, although the
name was later changed, in 1801, to Gallatin.
22
Durham, The Great Leap Westward, 70-72.
^^Ibid. , 63.
Cisco, Historic Sumner , 295; Ramsey, Annals , 623,
25
Long, Rutherford , 67.
y 6Durham, Great Leap Westward , 77-78.
48
General Rutherford died in his sleep at his home on
August 10, 1805. Both he and his wife are buried in the church-yard
of Shiloh Presbyterian Church, near Gallatin. Their graves
are unmarked, and cannot now be identified.
Although Rutherford was originally a member of
the Church of England, he was a vestryman of St.
Luke's Parish in Rowan County; he and his wife
became charter members of the Shiloh Presbyterian
Church in 1793 (Durham, Great Leap Westward, 159-
60). However, most sources state that he was buried
in Wilson County, near Laguardo, on the Sumner-Wilson
County line, a supposition which I am inclined to
accept.
But the General has not lacked for monuments. During his
lifetime, two counties were named for him. In 1779, while he
was still living in North Carolina, the county of Tryon was
divided into two counties, Lincoln and Rutherford, the latter
being named for the General. Then, in 1803, the Tennessee
legislature created from Davidson and Williamson the county of
Rutherford, also named for the General. Although it is not
specified in the legislative records, it is likely that the
name of the new county was suggested by Robert Weakley, who
was in the Tennessee State Senate at the time and who was a
cousin of Rutherford.
Not until more than 140 years later was further public
recognition given to General Rutherford. On July 3, 1945, Judge
Samuel Cole Williams, then chairman of the Tennessee Historical
Commission, delivered an address in the James K. Polk Hotel,
in Murfreesboro, on General Rutherford. The meeting was
sponsored by local chapters of the D. A. R. , the U. D. C,
27
the American Legion, and the Rutherford County Historical Society.
^''thq, IV, 283.
49
Whether or not Judge Williams' paper has been preserved, I
do not know.
In that same year, 1945, as a part of its plans to celebrate
the sesquicentennial of the admission of Tennessee to the Union,
in 1946, the Tennessee Historical Society voted $1,000 toward
the erection of a monument to General Rutherford.
Since three counties claimed Rutherford &#8212; Siamner
for his residence, Wilson for his burial plot,
and Rutherford as his namesake, the Commission
specified that the county which contributed most to
the cost of the monument should have the honor.
Rutherford County was winner.
The monument was erected at a cost of $2,000 and officially
dedicated on October 29, 1946.
An account of the ceremonies at the unveiling on the
southwest corner of the public square may be of interest.
Collier Crichlow acted as master of ceremonies and after the
invocation was said by Dr. J. Herndon McCain of the First
Presbyterian Church, Crichlow presented the monument to the
county. It was accepted by Judge Hoyte Stewart. Stanley F.
Horn, president of the Tennessee Historical Society and a member
of the Tennessee Historical Commission, spoke briefly. The
principal address was made by the late Ned Carmack. Carmack's
eulogy of General Rutherford was in the fine literary and
oratorical tradition of both his father and himself. There is
not space to repeat it here; but it has been reprinted in the
Tennessee Historical Quarterly , December 1946.
Others taking part in the ceremony were Miss Libby Morrow
Murfree, Mrs. Ben Hall McFarland, Mrs. C. F. Partee, Mrs. James
50
B. Patterson, Mrs. Annie Youree, and Mrs. J. J. Edwards. Among
out-of-town guests were Mrs. John Trotwood Moore, Vernon Sharp,
Jr., and Mrs. John H. DeWitt, of Nashville, and Mrs. Samuel
Cole Williams, of Johnson City.
Several descendants of General Rutherford had parts in the
exercises. They inlcuded: Mrs. Mary Purseley Baum of Murfreesboro,
great-great granddaughter, who unveiled the monument; the Misses
Elaine and Elizabeth Rutherford Elliott of Nashville, who placed
wreaths; Haynes Cooney, Jr., of Nashville, who acted as flag
bearer; and William H. Owen of McMinnville, who pronounced the
benediction.
In closing, I should pershaps say something of the personal
appearance and character of General Rutherford. One contemporary
wrote of him:
General Rutherford was somewhat under-sized, about
5 feet 8 inches, but heavily and compactly formed
would weigh about 180 pounds, thin-visaged. When he
had formed an opinion he was not easily driven from
it. Was of a pleasant and social turn.
and another;
He was an affable man and showed a friendly spirit. .
.
He has red hair, and is an active, pleasant man,
and honest in his dealings... A man of strong character,
resolute and determined, and of unusual capacity and
sterling worth, he easily attained a position of
prominence. ^&#176;
28
Long, Rutherford, 66,
51
As a final summary of the career of General Griffith
Rutherford, I can not do better than to quote Ned Carmack again:
General Griffith Rutherford &#8212; immigrant, pioneer,
frontiersman, soldier, early settler, lawmaker,
&#8212;
was one of the founders of the civilization upon
which our nation has risen to pre-eminence.
</dc:description>
<dc:description>A short biography of Griffith Rutherford, for whom Rutherford County was named</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.); Rutherford County (Tenn.) -- History; United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1783</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>23 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-16</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication03ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/106</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>