<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Big Springs</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Powell, Margaret M.</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 22</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1984</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>18th century; 19th century; 20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>BIG SPRINGS
By: Margaret M. Powell
Big Spring is located in the Central Basin of southeastern Tennessee
nine miles from Murfreesboro and one and one half miles east of U. S. High-way
41 south. In 1776 this basin was Indian territory known as far back
as 1100 A.D. by the Greek Indians - and that these Indians were once here
is proven by the artifacts left by them. Other tribes such as Chickasaws,
Choctaws.and Cherokees moved in and in 1776 the Chickasaws and Cherokees
were still here.
The territory was claimed and annexed by North Carolina in 1776, then
returned to national government in 1784. The people resented being changed
about and were easily led to rebel and follow John Sevier in a revolt against
the government and set up the - State of Franklin - with John Sevier as
governor. This state only lasted about six months and Sevier was arrested
for treason; was never tried. Then it was again claimed by North Carolina,
then back to national government in 1790. It remained so until 1796 when
Tennessee became the sixteenth state of the Union. Tennessee was one of the
last to secede; and the first to rejoin the Union after the Civil War.
The years between 1776 and 1790 were action filled, chaotic in a way,
but definitely formative. This was the wrap up of the Revolution, the
French and Indian War, and constant skirmishes with the Indians - plus
political intrigue.
Everyone wanted a piece of territory. It was known as the - "Land be-yond
the Mountain" and the "Dimple of the Universe" and to the Long Hunters
a "Hunter's Paradise". They came alone or in groups, walking or on horse-back.
Most were looking for a future home as well as pelts. The hunters
28
were often led by such notables as Bigfoot Spencer and Daniel Boone. Bigfoot
was killed near Castalian Springs by Renegade Indians after the territory
was open for settlement - leading a band of settlers.
It was a rich and savage land so Fort Nash, named for Abner Nash, a
North Carolina politician interested in investing in the new territory, was
built in 1783-84 to protect travelers in the basin. Fort Nashboro had been
built in 1778-79 on the banks of the Cumberland River - named for Elijah,
brother of Abner, but really established by James Robertson and John Don-aldson.
It is not known exactly where Fort Nash was built. The marker at Beech
Grove says on Douglas Ridge in 1784-1810. A Historian in Coffee County places
it further south at Fugearound. Fort Blount was also built in 1784 on
Clinch Mountain - roughly forming a protective triangle around the basin.
With the erection of Forts, roads became a necessity. These roads were
built at least partially by soldiers who were given four hundred acres of
land of their own choosing as payment for their efforts. The roads had to
be at least ten feet wide and possible for military reasons. In some places
the so called "corduroy roads" were built. This meant they used cedar logs,
mainly, to build up low places so the coaches and army wagons would not get
stuck. Some remnants of these cedar logs have been dug up on the two roads
that went around J'i lot Knob.) These roads usually followed Indians or animal
trails. Travel was slow, dusty, and hazardous. Water was a necessity for man
and beast. Big Spring was between the coach roads and its crystal clear,
cool limestone water was impossible to pass up and soon became a favorite
stopping place.
An Inn was built to accomodate the timid souls who did not wish to travel
at night. As need grew - so did the village, better housing and stores to
supply the travelers needs. I rather think an intrepid young hunter helped
29
the idea along. He had spent the winter of 1783 in a cave above the spring
and he discovered, in this cave, the underground stream that surfaced one
half mile below a spring. He built the first log cabin in the settlement.
Where Mr. Green came from or where he went, it is not known but the remains
of his cabin is undeniable proof he had been there.
By 1790 the Forts were erected, roads were built, the Indians dealt with
and the territory was declared open for settlement. Who is to say who was
first or last, it really doesn't matter, except to be glad they came.
It is recorded in family records that William Summers left North Carolina
in 1811 and settled in Big Spring on a couple of sections of land.
Some of that land. Pilot Knob included, is still owned by the 6th and 7th generation
of Summers.
The Mankin family owned several hundred acres including the Elam Hollow
and were active in many of the industries, etc. as were the Lowe's of Virginia.
The Newman's brought in a saw mill and soon everyone had a real plank floor.
The logs were dragged to the mill by oxen. The first mill burned and a larger
one was built nearer the spring. It, too, burned in early 1900 and was not
rebuilt. Beside housing materials, the mill sawed cedar rails for the pencil
mill at Christiana. Wire fences were the in thing and cedar rails sold quickly.
Big Spring was divided into lower Big Spring and upper Big Spring by Big
Creek. Lower Big Spring had more on its business. Mr. Newman had a store and
a big scale behind the store so people could weigh their stock before driving
them to market. As roads improved and trucks introduced, these fell into dis-use
although still there. Mr. Newman died and his widow not wishing to run
the store, rented it to others then eventually closed it. You can see in the
rise and fall of the industries, how and when needed they were instigated and
how the changing needs also changed and then discontinued. The Blacksmith
Shop for instance, there were four at one time and kept busy, keeping the
30
horses, mules and oxen shod and making repairs on wheels, rims, and many
other things for the home and work. As cars took over, horses faded and so
did the shops.
Mr. Pirtle owned a blacksmith shop in Upper Big Spring and also the
only water mill. It was powered by channeled water from a spring in Elam
Hollow but as packaged flour and meal began to be marketed, grist mills
went out. The one in lower Big Spring was run by Mr. Week Haithcock and
powered by a gasoline engine. This lasted until 1930, when he closed it to
help build Red Fox Tourist Camp.
The Woolen Mill and Tannery built in Upper Big Spring filled a real
need in the early days, for everyone needed their linseys for the winter.
The wool was spun into hanks which could by bought and knit spun at home.
The pelts, hides and skins were tanned and made into all sorts of garments
from hats to shoes, but change crept in here, too, and soon the store bought
clothes, bolt material and real leather shoes were sold over the counter.
So the Mill and Tannery faded away.
The Inn that was first built in Big Spring burned and a larger one,
two-storied, was built on the corner of Cobb Road across from the spring.
It also housed two doctors offices - Dr. Dill and Dr. Hubbard and the upper
story the - Woodmen of the World and Masons held their meetings.
SCHOOLS
Lower Big Spring boasted a Saloon, Barbershop, Methodist Church and a
school. The first school was built on the left side of the road as you
entered Big Spring. A larger one was built later on the right side on land
given by W. M. Lowe. The third school was built on that site and closed in
1931 consolidating with Buchanan School.
Upper Big Spring had a school, too, but it was almost impossible for
31
for the children to go to school in the winter months because there were no
bridges. This was the only time they went to school. This ground was given
by W. D. Mankin. The following is a partial list of the teachers. I do not
know when they taught or in which school.
Mathias Parker
Beulah Parker
Jim Lowe
Bud Lowe
Kate Love
Alice Ensey
Ike Ensey
Ina Love Jernigan
Soule Ewell
W. J. Edwards
Olga Hoover Ellis
Jessie Shelton Mason
Effie Hoover
Ruth Dement
W. H. Robinson
Grace Gilly
Halloween McNabb Harney
Will Newman
Altie Orren Brown
Blanche Holland Jacobs
Eugene Hoover
Allie McKnight
Mary Robinson
Sue McKee
Grady Biggers White
Mamie Tilford
Maude Robinson Jacobs Chrisman
Attendance fell, a bridge was built so the upper school closed. Mr.
Robinson was the last instructor. Years went by, consolidation was the big
thing for schools, so since Big Spring had become a one teacher school it
was consolidated with Buchanan School. Old Buchanan out grew its shell and
a new school was built further down the highway, known now as John Price
Buchanan School.
Maude Robinson Jacobs Chrisman, daughter of W. H. Robinson, had the
honor of closing that school in 1934. The land on which it stood reverted
to the Lowe family who had given it. Walter Lowe bought the building and
ran a store from 1943 to 1945. So that ended the educational facilities of
Big Spring. Buses now take the little ones to Buchanan and the older ones
32
to Riverdale.
Mr. Carlock from North Carolina owned quite a bit of property, too
much it seems and had to have a sale.
From the Tennessee Telegraph, Murfreesboro
May 2, May 9, May 6, Sept. 12, Nov. 21, 1840.
Valuable Real Estate at Sherriff's Sale
On Saturday the 17th of October next I will sell to
the highest bidder for cash the following described
LAND AND LOTS lying in said county of Rutherford and
in the 24th district.
One tract of land containing 120 acres lying on Big
Creek, it being residue of the tract of land conveyed
to Epenitus Carlock by Charles F. Lowe, and adjoining
the land of John Mankin, Abner Summers, and others.
Also one lot of ground on which the Wool Factory stands
including said wool factory.
Also - one lot near said Big Spring, now occupied by
Dr. Hubbard.
Also - One lot on which Epinitus Carlock now lives
including the Store house. Big Spring and all other
improvements, containing about two acres, more or less,
bounded on the north and east by William Summers, on
the south by Clinton Jacobs and others, and on the west
by William Daniel, and the lot on said William Daniel
now lives bounded on the north by William Daniel and
the factory lot, on the east by the lot on which
Epenitus Carlock now lives, on the south by Lewis Herrell,
and on the west Perry Ellis, containing about one and
a half acres.
Also - One lot unimproved near said Big Spring containing
about one acre, bounded on the north by Basil Summers
and others, on the south by Lewis Herrell, on the east
by John Jacobs, and on the west by William Dejarnett.
33
Levied on as the property of Epenitus Carlock to satisfy
two Executions, one in favor of the Union Bank, and
the other in favor of Nichol &amp; Brothers, surviving
partners of Nichol, Dance &amp; Co. vs said Epenitus Carlock.
Sale Within the usual hours.
Sheriff of Rutherford County
Also at the same time and place one bay mare and one wagon.
Levied on for the purpose above specified.
Although Mr. Carlock sold most of his holdings, he retained a home in
Big Spring until his death in 1860. He was Post Master in 1852.
Abner Summers bought the store and hired Mr. Robinson, the
young teacher, as clerk when school was not in session. Mr. Robinson
fell in love with his boss's daughter and they were married. He con-tinued
to work in the store and on Mr. Summers retirement he bought
it and ran the store until 1931, when he built a brick house and the
Red Fox Tourist Court on the highway.
This was the last industry in Big Spring, except Walter Lowe
bought the school house and ran the store from 1943 to 1945. Mr.
Robinson ran his Tourist Court until his death in 1948. Eventually
it sold and the Court was soon torn down. The house burned in 1982.
Mr. Robinson was a very versatile man other than his teaching - busi-nesses,
he served 2 terms in legislation.
It is interesting to note that Frank Robinson followed in his
father's footsteps and entered the grocery business at an early age.
He introduced l.G.A. to Murfreesboro and since his death in 1980, his
sons, Wayne and Woody Robinson, his grandson, Phillip Robinson, are
very successfully carrying on their family tradition with a bigger
and better l.G.A.
34
The Cumberland Telephone and Telegraph service begun in Murfrees-boro
in 1901 to 1903. Big Spring, Christiana and others started their
own telephone service combined. Christiana sold out to Bell in 1941.
I do not know when Big Spring sold out, but F.A. Mankin started the
line and Miss Trudie Frizzell was our last service board operator.
The house still stands, wearily, on its last legs just above the spring
where "Miss Trudie" kept her milk, butter, and other perishables cool
in the cold spring water.
Mail was bought irregularly by a post rider who heralded his
coming by blowing a horn. As the town grew, a need for a Post Office
became apparent. So in 1848, one was established with Lewis Harrell
as Postmaster and the mail being delivered by stage coach.
The town had no real name, but became necessary to have one for
the Post Office. It was named Carlocksville for one of the earlier
settlers, Epenetus Carlock, and remained so until the Post Office
closed in 1904. Then the town was renamed Big Spring.
Others serving as Postmasters were:
Epenetus Carlock 1852
W. P. Jacobs 1866
Ephraim Jacobs 1867
Postal Service was discontinued in 1868 and reopened in 1876 with
Robert Lowe as Postmaster.
John Hobson 1877
John T. Kelton 1878
Newton Mankin 1879
N. B. Mankin 1881
William A. Kelton 1884
Walter Mc Nabb 1888
35
Joel Brewer 1889
N. B. Mankin 1890
William Newman 1893
T. J. Owen 1894
N. B. Mankin 1895
W. H. Robinson 1902
Mr. Robinson served until it closed in 1904, and mail was brought
from Christiana by Rural Carriers. Some of them were:
Bill Walker
Robert Comer
Walter Clark
Fred Kelton
Tom Covington
J. G. Suggs
Buford Holman
At persent Frances Suggs Becton and Lanier Lowe are Carriers.
BLACK COMMUNITY
By 1878 the population was 1,163 of which two hundred were blacks, ^
who came and quickly formed a community of their own. It is located
slightly west of Big Spring between the coach road and the turnpike.
Their village was on the hill sloping down to the pike where the school
and church was. The church was in the center of present Red Fox Camp-grounds.
The old dug well that supplied some of the families with
water is there today and its walls are still intact. The well was
near Monroe Green's house.
A few homes were built and among them were the Green's, Smith's,
Reddy's, Whitside's and many others. They had big families - were
strong and hard working and blessed with many talents. Aunt Lucy
was the Matriarch, advisor and doctor. Doctors were scarce and Aunt
Lucy doctored all on sundry with her herbs and potions, very success-
36
fully. Uncle Alex did make salve for eyes.
Mr. Green had a way with rocks and was soon in demand for chimneys.
He said a chimney he built never smoked. J. B. Reedy picked up rocks
and built fences for twenty-five cents a yard. Others were versatile
at blacksmithing, logging or whatever came to hand. Gradually the
young drifted off to wider fields and better opportunities. Homes were
deserted and fell into decay. The school went as the students did and
was torn down when the pike was widened in 1936.
A Mr. Haliburton from Rucker was the last to teach there. The
cemetery has grown over and few traces remain of their colony today.
A bit of history that I hope is not forgotten by some decendants who
might have a desire to know of their forefathers first home in Tennessee.
HOMES
There are many pre-war homes left in and around Big Spring. One
in particular interest me. Its windows and doors, etc. are hand planned
and pegged - no nails. Twas built near 1850 and is in excellent condi-tion.
Another home suffered a similar incident as to New Hope Church.
The people would heardoors open and close, chairs would rock, footsteps
were heard - nothing seen. They concluded they had build over a grave,
and so they moved the house and the ghost was exorcised. That house
still stands untenated by ghosts.
Another home pictured here is that of Dr. G. W. Robinson. He came
from North Carolina ait married Mary Elizabeth Mankin, daughter of John
Mankin. Dr. Robinson served as captain in the War of Rebellion, was
wounded and captured but not imprisoned. He helped in the hospital -
his wound became infected and he died in 1863 in Kentucky. His body
37
Dr. Robinson house built in 1848. Located near Big Spring
and U.S. 41. Picture made about 1895. William, Isaac, and
Margaret Summers in picture. This is now the Tom Jackson place.
38
Mr. W. H, Robinson, his wife Ethel Summers Robinson, Daughter
Mary N. Robinson, and Son Frank Summers Robinson.
Was a member of the state legislature.
39
Two views of Big Springs
40
41
V \'
II
: ri
i9
ul*'?i
Big Springs school, 1920, Eugene Hoover was principal.
beginning with top left: 1. Buelah Newman Summers, 2. Ozelle Haithcock
3. Mattye Sue Rowland 4. Pearl Newman Todd 5. Margaret Mc Knight Powell
6. Aileen Kelton 7. Mattye Sue Prater Newman, 8. Ashley Newman 9. Maude
Robinson Jacobs Chrisman 10. Calvin Lowe, 11. James Redmon 12. Willie
Bogle Messick, 13. Frank Robinson, 14. Henry Fox, 15. Buford Newman
16. Allie Mc Knight Hoover (teacher) 17. Hershel Prater 18. Evelyn
Fox Messick Evans, 19. ? , 20. Boyd Stewart, 21. ? 22. ?
24. Flora Lee Stewart Todd, 25. ?, 26. Paul Summers, 27.
28. Walter Lowe, 29. Frank Messick, 30. Wiley Messick, 31
32. Alberta Newman, 33. Louise Redmon, 34. Anna B. Sumars, 35. ?
36. Stanley Mc Nabb, 37. ?, 38. Tod Summers, 39. Claude Robinson,
40. Hall Mc Nabb
23. ?
Cecil Prater,
42
House on Claude Robinson's place, where the grist mill
once stood, Mr. Haithcock ran the mill.
Old house in Big Springs
43
Old house pegged together
Old telephone office above the spring
44
Robinson house, where Glen
Brewer now lives
W. H. Robinson
Big Springs Store
about 1920
Wiley H. Robinson
Big Springs Store
Wiley H. Robinson
operated store in 1930
pictures by Mary N. Robinson
45
Big Springs school , 1926-29, building stood near
Walter Lowe's barn, Lenior Lowe , Walter Lowe's son,
now lives near site.
Asa Todd's baby hearse
46
was brought as far as Lebanon under military escort, then turned
over to his wife who brought him home in a wagon. He was buried in
the family cemetery in front of his home, later moved to Evergreen
Cemetery. A bit of geneology here - He and Mary had a daughter,
Jenny, who married Luther Rice Jacobs. They had a daughter, Beulah,
who married John Woodfin, Sr., who was a mortician, beginning was
Woodfin and Moore. Then later the partnership dissolved and became
"Woodfin's". John, son of John Sr., took over and ran it until his
death and now "Bubba" or the third John is carrying on his father's
work.
I slightly degressed, but the Robinson home is of personal inter-est
to me as it became my grandfather's home. The old log smoke house
in the back brings memories of cured hams, homemade lye soap, and barrels
of molasses.
CHURCHES:
The New Hope Baptist Church was erected about 1814 on the left
side of the road in upper Big Spring. It was a community effort and
they were justly proud of it and decided to have a revival. One night
the house was crowded as usual, the churchyard filled with saddled
horses, buggies, wagons and such, the preacher had warmed to his subject
and was going strong - when a hush fell over the congragation. It seemed
a plate of coins fell in front of the pulpit. Almost at the same time
a sound was heard in the ceiling, described by some as though a barrel
of chains was rolling across the ceiling. It reached the back of the
pulpit and fell to the floor and slowly rolled down the aisle, paused
briefly, then rolled into the yard. All this was heard not seen. All
47
chaos resulted as horses squealed, kicked and reared to break loose.
You cannot imagine such a scene. Buggies were entangled, wagons over-turned
and bridles were hanging as the horses ran away. Parents were
frantically trying to get their families together - twas a mad house
so to speak. Most of them had to walk home and hunt the runaways the
next day. You can assume what the topic was for quite awhile.
A church council was called and they concluded that some ill gotten
money had been given to the building fund. A pack peddler had disappeared,
never found, and known to have had money, gold, mostly. The plate of
coins symbolized this stolen money to them. What to do - the answer
was debatable but they decided to move the church across the road,
which they did. It stands there today completely modernized and free
from ghost or malicious spirits.
Evidently the Methodist Church was built about the same time.
It was moved from Big Spring in the 1850 's to the Turnpike. It remained
there until 1935 when it burned to the ground. It was not rebuilt.
The congregation was divided - some going to Hoovers Gap others to
Cedar Grove and uniting with those churches. That situation still exists.
Mr. and Mrs. W. D. Mankin deeded land to the Big Creek Baptist
congregation on which to build a church and school. This deed was
dated 1878 stating in love and affection to members of the Big Creek
Baptist Church. Mr. E. A. Bowman has a copy of this deed. The church
was organized before 1946 and met in homes until a building could be
constructed. It, too has been remodeled and is well attended.
Near the church is a well tended cemetery. Head stones bearing
names of our settlers. Incidentally, there are at least twenty-seven
cemeteries in and around Big Spring. Most are family only and many
48
Modern Big Creek Baptist Church
New Hope Baptist Church
49
have been forgotten. Head stones are gone and vines and bushes have
lovingly hidden them from viewing eyes.
The Alexander Campbell movement reached Tennessee about 1853
according to . A Church was built in Lower Big Spring and in the
late thirties - forties the congregation united with the Midway
Church. When a road was built in 1859 the churqh building was moved.
There are no industries as such left in Big Spring, but for the
last three or four years the population has visably increased.
The spring has continued on its placid ways through the years
while the trees, vines, and bushes screened it from view. The Home
Demonstration Club ladies took the reclamation of the spring for their
community project and have at least brought it into view. Much has
been done and much more needs to be done. We have had spendid coopera-tion
in those with extra credit due - Robert Allman, Floyd Bowman, Wal-ter
Lowe, Ernest Winfrey, and Marion Simpson. With the reclamation
of the spring came the desire to know about the village. Nothing had
been written about it so, hence this story which is mostly family history
or passed down by word of mouth.
J. W. Cullen, Warm Hearts and Saddle Bags
50
BIBLIOGRAPHY
Goodspeeds
Ghost of the Garrison K. Jamison
Short History of Tennessee Robert Corlew
History of Rutherford County Dr. C.C. Sims
Warm Hearts and Saddle Bags J. W. Cullen
Encyclopedia Britannica
The Rebels
51
</dc:description>
<dc:description>A history of the area known as Big Springs, located nine miles from Murfreesboro</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Big Springs</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>24 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-02; mt2011-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication22ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/39</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>