<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>History of property at 214 East Main Street</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Forrest, Henry B.</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 34</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1994</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>19th century; 20th century;</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>History of Property
214 East Main Street
Murfreesboro, Tennessee
BY
Henry B. Forrest
62
Rutherford County and Murfreesboro, Tennessee are rich because of its people,
past and present, and because of their role in history. More historic homes and sites
have disappeared than are left. Some homes and families have already gone without
recognition. One of the remaining old homes is located at 214 East Main Street. In
tracing the history of this property, it was impossible to separate it from the lives of
those who owned it. Therefore this paper will focus on its owners and their lives; how
the owners used the property throughout the years and how they use it today.
The history of the property goes back into the earliest days of Murfreesboro.
William Franklin Lytie's parents were Scotch-Irish immigrants who came to America
in the great immigration of the 1700's. From all records the Lytles came before 1724.
They landed at New Castle, Delaware and from there went south to Pennsylvania.
William Lytle was born in Pennsylvania in 1755. His family moved to North Carolina
shortly after his birth. During the Revolutionary War, Lytle served as lieutenant and as
captain. He was with Gen. George Washington when Maj. Gen. Charles Cornwallis
surrendered at Yorktown, Virginia in 1781.^ He was transferred to the Fourth regiment
where he served under his brother, Lt. Col. Archibald Lytle, until the close of the war.2
Archibald Lytle received large grants of land in what is now Tennessee for his
distinguished service. One of the grants included 4640 acres of land on the west fork of
Stones River. Another grant of 2560 acres was located near the Harpeth River.3
Archibald Lytle, however, did not live long enough to occupy his grant. He never
married and willed his grants to his brother, William F. Lytle. Lytle's own land grant,
for his services in the Revolutionary War, included acreage in west Tennessee.
William Lytle came to Rutherford County sometime before 1800. He built a log
cabin, gristmill, and sawmill. He later added a cotton gin and warehouses. In 1810 he
began building a mansion near Lytle Creek. The mansion was razed in 1927. Haynes
Brothers Supply Company now occupies the site.^
63
Murfreesboro was originally called Cannonsburg in honor of Newton Cannon,
governor to be of Tennessee, but it changed names in honor of Col. Hardy Murfree, a
Revolutionary soldier. He held land granted by North Carolina as early as 1786.5 He
had succeeded Lt. Col. William L. Davidson after Davidson was promoted to Brig. Gen.
Griffith Rutherford's position. Davidson and Rutherford Counties were named in
honor of these two men, respectively.^
Little is recorded about the recreation in the early life of the county, but there is
reason to believe that in addition to hunting and target practicing, the men attended
cock fights and horse races. There was a Bradley's race track near Murfreesboro before
1820. Andrew Jackson is said to have won and lost small fortunes betting on races. A
wager aggravated the enmity between Jackson and Newton Cannon. According to
rumor, this wager cost Cannon all of his slaves.
^
The establishment of the Rutherford county court took place in 1804. The court
first met at the home of Thomas Rucker, about 4.5 miles from the present
Murfreesboro. The court continued to meet at various homes until a permanent seat
of government was established. ^ In 1811 the legislature appointed seven
commissioners to select a permanent seat of justice for the county. The legislature
directed them to consider central locations with an adequate supply of good water.
They were to secure sixty acres of land either by purchase or by donation.
Several localities competed to become the seat of justice, since it would be a
benefit to a successful community. Charles Ready offered Readyville. Also, Thomas
Rucker and William Lytle offered their places. The commissioners visited and
inspected the various places offered.
The donators made determined efforts to influence the commissioners. They
served sumptuous dinners during which the guests made many toasts and
"excitement reached the boiling point."^ Then William Lytle invited the
commissioners to his site. It is said that the lavish entertainment given and the
64
inducements offered accomplished the desired effect. The members voted in favor of
the Lytle place. The commission suggested naming the new town after Lytle, but Lytle
requested that they name it in honor of his close friend. Colonel Murfree, who had
recently died in Williamson County. On 29 November 1811, the county seat was
renamed Murfreesborough, later Murfreesboro.^O
Lytle made only one stipulation, and this was that one lot be redeeded to him.
The commissioners agreed, and he received the lot on the southeast corner of the
square. ^^ At that time the lot was what is now a full city block. It is bordered on the
north by East Main Street, on the south by Vine Street, on the west by Spring Street,
and on the east by Academy Street. ^2 William Lytle apparently used this as an
investment since he had already chosen his own homeplace. Throughout the years
this lot was divided and sold in separate parcels. Lytle's surveyor, Hugh Robison, laid
out additional lots from Lytle's property, and no doubt the financial returns on these
lots were considerable. ^3
According to the Central Observer 14 January 1979, the earliest Christian Church
in Rutherford County began meeting in a log house on Vine Street near Lytle Creek. 14
In 1860 the congregation bought the lot on the corner of East Main Street and Academy
Street from Robert McLane and W.W. Ross for eighteen hundred dollars. ^ 5 jhis lot
was part of the original lot redeeded to William Lytle by the agreement of 1811. In the
early 1900s the congregation of the Christian Church disagreed about several doctrines.
This is when the congregation at East Main and Academy Streets assumed the name of
East Main Church of Christ.^^
William Lytle owned the lot to the west of the present church building until 4
May 1840 when he sold it to Wilson Thomas for SISO.^'' Little is known about Wilson
Thomas except that he served as mayor of Murfreesboro in 1844.^8 On 24 March 1841,
four days after Thomas's deed was recorded, he sold the lot to William C. Fletcher for
$250.19
o5
Allen Tait Gooch gave three hundred dollars for the lot 13 January 1843.20 in
1814, when Gooch was eight years old, his family moved from North Carolina to
Williamson County, and later they moved to Rutherford County. He and his wife
made their home in Murfreesboro where he went into the mercantile business,
probably in 1829. He later took a partner, William McKnight, and the business became
known as "Gooch and McKnight Mercantile Business." In addition to his normal stock
of goods, Gooch purchased a great deal of furniture for his brother's home,
Goochland.21 Goochland was part of the property bought by the State of Tennessee in
1942 for the construction of Sewart Air Force Base in Smyrna, Tennessee.22
Allen Gooch sold three lots to his son-in-law, Jean Joseph Giers for five
thousand dollars 17 September 1850. Fifteen hundred dollars was "in hand paid,"23
and the balance to be paid in three notes for $1166.66, each note dated the deed date;
two of them payable at twelve months intervals and the third at two years. One of the
three lots adjoined lot eighty-two and was where Gooch's home was situated.24
Jean Joseph Giers was born in Bonn, Germany. His history is unknown until he
resided in Murfreesboro. He wrote music and poetry and gave music lessons. He and
Mary Lucinda Gooch were married 2 May 1849.25 in 1855 Giers purchased a resort hotel
and twelve hundred acres of land fifteen miles south of Huntsville, Alabama. He
named his holdings Valhermoso Springs which meant "beautiful valley" in
Spanish.26 Giers and his wife, and her parents, Allen and Elizabeth Gooch, all moved
to Valhermoso Springs in 1855. Evidentally, Giers and Gooch became partners and
made a successful resort hotel, where many dignitaries visited.27 Giers became a
member of the staff of the Washington Gazette in Washington, D.C.; he spent the
winters in Washington and the summers in Valhermoso Springs. All of Allen
Gooch's sons enlisted in the Civil War from that area of Alabama. They all fought for
the Confederacy, but their brother- in-law, Jean Joseph Giers, was a northern
sympathizer. Gooch affectionately referred to his son-in-law as "that damn yankee."28
66
Giers, most likely, had sold the three lots in preparation for his move to
Alabama. He sold them to Madison R. Alexander 17 July 1852 for the same amount he
had paid for them; five thousand dollars. Mr. Alexander was a native of Tennessee and
one of the early settlers of Rutherford County. He married Catherine Suttle of Virginia,
who was raised in a neighborhood near the one of Thomas Jefferson. She often spoke
of Jefferson in glowing words of praise. Alexander was a well-known and prosperous
farmer. 29
In the decade before the Civil War, Rutherford County experienced a high point
in agriculture. The agricultural expansion was the greatest ever known; nothing
comparable ever occurring in any other years.30 There was an increase in the
establishment of business firms in Murfreesboro, and also a rapid expansion of
turnpike companies. 31 This economic boom explains the enormous jump in land
value as evidenced by the selling prices of lot eighty-two.
Madison Alexander sold the three lots to James Bivins 6 November 1855 for the
sum of $5050.32 After that sale the lots were again sold separately; lot eighty-two
changed hands several times until John W. Burton bought it. Mr. Burton was an
attorney and was mayor of Murfreesboro in 1860 and 1861.33 After the Civil War, he
served as special judge of chancery, and as special judge on the State Supreme Court of
Tennessee from 1878 to 1883.34 He sold the house and lot 10 December 1860 to
Elizabeth Ledbetter Sublett for thirty-five hundred dollars.35 In this deed is the first
reference to a house being situated on the lot. Therefore, a house must have been built
there between 1855 and 1860.
Mrs. Sublett was a descendant of William Lytle.36 After almost twenty years, lot
eighty-two was once again owned by a member of the Lytle family. Elizabeth and
George A. Sublett had married 29 May 1821. Sublett and his brother edited and
published the first newspaper in Murfreesboro. It was the policy of the Courier to give
the news rather than to mold public opinion.37 Nevertheless, according to Carlton
6?
Sims, the Subletts were not averse to molding public opinion. In 1828 they founded the
short-lived National Vidette, vv^hose aim was to help elect Andrew Jackson president of
the United States. The paper was anti-administration and very opposed to the
reelection of John Quincy Adams.38 The Sublett brothers evidently did their share in
introducing "opinions of the west into Jeffersonian Democracy."39 George Sublett was
a charter member of the First Methodist Church of Murfreesboro.40 Elizabeth Sublett
must have been a determined woman, because she joined the First Presbyterian
Church 9 March 1834. The Subletts' four children were baptized there 1 October 1836.
There is no record of George Sublett being a member.^!
Elizabeth Sublett sold the house and lot to her daughter, Sarah A. Sublett
Stewart 17 December 1866 for four thousand dollars.'^^ Sarah Stewart was the second
wife of James W. Stewart who had been married to her sister, Mary M. Sublett, 30
November 1847.43 Sarah and James Stewart were married 28 November 1850.44 Mr.
Stewart had evidently died sometime before 1868 because Sarah Sublett Stewart was
married to James Turner when the house and lot was sold 21 September 1868.45 s. H.
Miller paid them thirty-five hundred dollars and sold it 7 September 1871 to J.F.
Vaughan for twelve hundred dollars.46 The economy had reached a peak in 1860, but
it was curtailed by the outbreak of the Civil War and the period of reconstruction that
was to follow. The recession is evidenced by the decline of the land value in the 1871
sale.
Sarah J. Richardson Fowler paid J.F. Vaughan $1550 for the house and lot 17
June 1873.47 Capt. Thomas B. Fowler and Sarah had married 6 February 1868. Captain
Fowler was born in 1838 in Cannon County, Tennessee. He left home when he was
twelve years old and came to Murfreesboro. He became a clerk in a bookstore and later
became a bookkeeper in a dry goods store. He served in the Civil War until after the
Battle of Franklin, where he lost a leg. He was revenue collector for Rutherford County
in 1866 and 1867. As soon as he was well enough, he became a bookkeeper at the
Savings Bank; later he became teller at the First National Bank. From 1870 to 1882, he
was circuit court clerk. His last known position was cashier of Stones River National
Bank.48
In 1901 the congregation of the Christian Church needed a larger building. The
elders were able to buy a section of land from Sarah J. Fowler. The parcel was ten feet
wide to the west side of the church and ran to the south along the west boundary
ninety-nine feet. The church paid five hundred dollars; one hundred dollars was the
down payment and $133.33 was to paid each year thereafter for three years.49 The old
building was razed, and a new building was erected.^0
Kate Bell Fowler Cranor, the adopted daughter of Captain and Mrs. Fowler,51
inherited the Fowler house and lot upon the death of her mother; the exact date is
unknown. Kate Bell Fowler was married to George F. Cranor.
The Church of Christ began renovation plans in 1920. George and Kate Bell
Fowler Cranor sold the elders of the church their house and lot for ten thousand
dollars 20 October 1920.^2 a wing was built on the newly acquired property, measuring
approximately fifteen feet in width and the same length of the original building.
The Fowler house, as it was known, was used as a home for the ministers and
their families. Minor changes were made in the matter of electricity, bathrooms, and
window air-conditioning.53
At the present time, the Fowler house stands vacant. It proved unsatisfactory for
the ministers to live in the house, because the families were disturbed at all hours of
the night by troubled people who needed help. For a while, the house was leased, but
this was not practical. The church was required to pay taxes on it if it was rented. After
paying taxes and repairing the damages made by the tenants, the church discovered
that using it as rental property was a losing proposition.54
It is believed that Captain Thomas Fowler and his wife, Sarah J. Fowler, had the
present house built sometime between 1875 and the early 1880s. Speculation is that the
69
original house was severely damaged during the Civil War and was in an irreparable
condition.
The Fowler house is a two-story, red brick building. The walls are four bricks
thick and stand on a rock foundation. These stones are twenty-five to thirty inches
long and twelve inches thick.55 The outside of the house is designed in the
asymmetrical form of the Victorian style. It has a small front porch with a double-door
entrance. On the left side of the porch, there is a two-story turret with three bay
windows at both levels. The turret has a pyramidal cap.56 The roof and cap were
originally made of pressed tin which had a design etched in it, but this has been
replaced by a modern tin roof.
The entrance hall leading to the stairway has an archway with the wood carved
in various designs. The front parlor on the left of the hall is separated from the back
parlor by two sliding doors, which reach almost to the fourteen feet high ceilings. The
library is on the right of the hall with a small office directly behind it. The kitchen was
originally a separate building, but now it joins the house in the rear.
There is a massive stairway leading to the second floor which has three
bedrooms; the master bedroom now adjoins a bathroom, which was probably once
used as a dressing room or storage area.
The floors are made of "fat" pine, and the wood molding is probably poplar. This
is an easy wood to work with and was used abundantly in the 1880s. The fireplaces are
srhall and shallow with low mantles made of cast-iron. The burning of coal and the
use of cast-iron was popular during this period.57 There is ornamental plasterwork on
the ceilings around the electrical openings. In the nineteenth century, coal oil lanterns
were suspended from the ceilings and lowered for use. There is elaborate wood detail
on the stairway newel posts. Other than this and the archway, there is little fancy detail
which is prevalent in most Victorian houses.58
70
This research project has been a most enlightening experience. The writer's
respect for historians has increased tenfold. While tracing the history of lot eighty-tv/o,
the novice researcher repeated many times, "If only land could talk!" Regrettably, the
writer has left some missing links in the line of ownership of the property. Also, there
is an abundance of unknown information about the owners and their families. The
research has found, until now, all the owners to be prominent and honorable citizens.
Nevertheless, it is always possible in tracing a family tree to find a horse thief hanging
from one of the branches or to roll some skeletons out of the closets. In any case, lot
eighty-two is well-worth investigating.
71
ENDNOTES
1 William F. Lytle, Biographical Sketch, 1755-1829. Daughters of the American
Revolution, Jackson-Madison Chapter Collection, William F. Lytle Collection, State of
Tennessee Archives, Nashville.
2 Mabel Pittard, Rutherford County. Tennessee County History Series, ed. Robert E.
Corlew III (Memphis: Memphis State University Press, 1984), 29.
3 Archibald Lytle, North Carolina land grant, 12 March 1784, original in
Archibald Lytle Collection, State of Tennessee Archives, Nashville.
4 William F. Lytle, Memoirs of the Lytle family, Lytle family genealogy 1703-
1829, Lytle family events and photographs, William C. Ledbetter Jr. Collection, 115
University, Murfreesboro, TN.
5 Carlton C. Sims, ed. , A History of Rutherford County (Murfreesboro: Privately
printed, 1947), 12.
6 Sims, 26.
7 Ibid., 31.
8 C. C. Henderson, The Story of Murfreesboro (Murfreesboro: The News-Banner
Publishing Co. , 1929), 4-5.
9 Ibid., 28.
^0 William C. Ledbetter Jr. of Murfreesboro, interview by author, 21 November
1988, Murfreesboro, 115 University, Murfreesboro, TN,
11 Ibid.
12 Sanborn Map Co., July 1891, Murfreesboro, TN. Map 3, 1888-1897.
13 Pittard, 26-27.
14 Murfreesboro East Main, Central Observer, 14 January 1979, 1.
15 Rutherford County Deeds, Transfer of title, Robert McLane and W.W. Ross to
Christian Church, 5 November 1860, Book 11, 476.
1^ East Main Church of Christ. Historical papers and photograph. East Main
Church of Christ Collection, Murfreesboro, TN.
17 Deeds, Transfer of title, William B. Lytle to Wilson Thomas, 20 March 1841,
Book Y, 366.
12.
18 Henderson, 142,
19 Deeds, Transfer of title, Wilson Thomas to William C. Fletcher, 24 March
1841, Book Y, 372.
20 Ibid. , Transfer of title, William C. Fletcher to Allen T. Gooch, 13 January
1843, Book 13 January 1843, Book 1, 102.
21 Virginia Gooch Watson, 'The Gooch Family in Williamson County,
Tennessee," Williamson County Historical Society, Publication 10, Spring 1979. 28.
22 Virginia Gooch Watson of Franklin, interview by author, 22 November 1988,
Franklin, Executive House, Franklin, TN.
23 Deeds, Transfer of title, Jean Joseph Giers to Madison H. Alexander, 17 July
1852, Book 5, 562.
24 Ibid.
25 Edythe Rucker Whitley, comp. , Marriages of Rutherford County, Tennessee:
1804-1872 (Baltimore: Genealogical Publishing Co., Inc., 1981 ), 119.
26 Watson, 29.
27 Watson, interview.
28 Watson, 29.
29 The Goodspeed Histories of Maury, Williamson, Rutherford, Wilson, Bedford, and
Marshall Counties of Tennessee (Nashville: The Goodspeed Publishing Co., 1887; repr.,
Columbia, TN. : Woodward and Stinson Printing Co., 1971), 1020.
30 PhiHp M. Hamer, ed. , Tennessee-A History: 1673-1932 (New York: The
American Historical Society, Inc. , 1933), vol. 2, 832.
31 Pittard, 63.
32 Deeds, Transfer of title, Madison H. Alexander to James Bivens, 6 November
1855, Book 19, 279.
33 Henderson, 142.
34 Sims, 83.
35 Deeds, Transfer of title, John W. Burton to Elizabeth M. Sublett, 10 December
1860, Book 11, 549.
73
36 Ledbetter Collection.
37 Henderson, 75.
38 Sims, 108.
39 Ibid.
40 Ibid., 196
^^ Edythe Rucker Whitley, comp.. First Presbyterian Church: Roster of Members
1812-1846. Rutherford County Collection, Williamson County Library, Franklin, TN.
^^ Deeds, Transfer of title, Elizabeth M. Sublett to Sarah A. Stewart Turner, 17
December 1866, Book 14, 403.
43 V\!hit\ey, Marriages, 114.
44 Ibid., 124
45 Deeds, Transfer of title, James Turner and Sarah A. Stewart Turner to S. H.
Miller, 21 September 1868, Book 16, 61.
46 Ibid., Transfer of title, S. H. Miller to J. F. Vaughan, 7 September 1871, Book
18, 88-89.
47 Ibid., Transfer of title, J. F. Vaughan to Sarah J. Fowler, 17 June 1873, Book 19,
279-80.
48 Goodspeed, 1035.
49 Deeds, Transfer of title, Sarah J. Fowler to Christian Church, 4 May 1901,
Book 41, 471.
50 East Main Church of Christ Collection.
51 Goodspeed, 1035.
52 Deeds, Transfer of title, George A. Cranor and Kate Bell Fowler Cranor to
elders of East Main Church of Christ, 20 October 1920, Book 64, 255.
53 James Bailey of Murfreesboro, interview by author, 29 November 1988,
Murfreesboro, 214 East Main Street, Murfreesboro, TN.
74
54 Judith Minnick of Murfreesboro, interview by author, 18 November 1988,
Murfreesboro, East Main Church of Christ, Murfreesboro, TN.
55 Bailey.
56 Lawrence Grow, ed.. Old House Catalogue (New York: MacMillan Publishing
Co., Inc., Collier Books, 1982), 20.
57 Ernest K. Johns of Smyrna, interview by author, 29 November 1988,
Murfreesboro, Ernest K. Johns Construction Co., Murfreesboro, TN.
58 Marcus Whiffin, American Architecture Since 1780: A Guide to the Styles
(Cambridge, MA. and London: Massachusetts Institute of Technology Press, 1969), 1 IS-IS.
75
BIBLIOGRAPHY
Bailey, James. Interview by author, 29 November 1988, Murfreesboro. 214 East Main
Street, Murfreesboro, TN.
The Goodspeed Histories of Maury, Williamson, Rutherford, Wilson, Bedford, and Marshal
Counties of Tennessee. Nashville: The Goodspeed Publishing Co., 1887; reprint,
Columbia, TN: Woodward and Stinson Printing Co., 1971.
Grow, Lawrence, ed. Old House Catalogue. New York: MacMillan Publishing Co Inc
ColUer Books, 1982.
Hamer, Phillip M., ed. Tennessee-A History: 1673-1932. Vol. 2. New York: The American
Historical Society, Inc., 1933.
Henderson, C. C. The Story of Murfreesboro. Murfreesboro: The News-Banner Publishing
Co., 1929.
^
Johns, Ernest, K., Interview by author, 29 November 1988, Murfreesboro. Ernest K.
Johns Construction Co., Murfreesboro, TN.
Ledbetter, William C. Jr. Interview by author, 21 November 1988, Murfreesboro. 115
University, Murfreesboro, TN.
Lytle, Archibald. North Carolina land grant, 12 March 1784. Original in Archibald Lytle
Collection, State of Tennessee Archives, Nashville, TN.
Lytle, William F. Biographical Sketch, 1755-1829. Daughters of the American
Revolution, Jackson-Madison Chapter Collection, William F. Lytle Collection,
State of Tennessee Archives, Nashville, TN.
Memoirs of the Lytle family, Lytle family genealogy 1703-1829, Lytle
family events and photographs. William C. Ledbetter Jr. Collection, 115
University, Murfreesboro, TN.
Minnick, Judith. Interview by author, 18 November 1988, Murfreesboro. East Main
Church of Christ, Murfreesboro, TN.
Pittard, Mabel. Rutherford County. Tennessee County History Series, ed. Robert E.
Corlew III. Memphis: Memphis State University Press, 1984.
Rutherford County Deeds. Transfer of title, Robert McLane and W. W. Ross to
Christian Church, 5 November 1860. Book 11, 476.
.. Transfer of title, William F. Lytle to Wilson Thomas, 20 March 1841. Book
Y, 366.
&#8226; Transfer of title, Wilson Thomas to William C. Fletcher, 24 March 1841.
Book Y, 372.
1(^
. Transfer of title, William C. Fletcher to Allen T. Gooch, 13 January 1843.
Book 1, 102.
Transfer of title, Jean Joseph Giers to Madison H. Alexander, 17 July 1852.
Book 5, 562.
. Transfer of title, Madison H. Alexander to James Bivins, 6 November
1855. Book 19, 279.
_. Transfer of title, John W. Burton to Elizabeth M. Sublett, , 10 December
1860. Book 11, 549.
Transfer of title, Elizabeth M. Sublett to Sarah A. Stewart, 17 December
1866. Book 14, 403.
Transfer of title, James Turner and Sarah A. Stewart Turner to S. H.
Miller, 21 September 1868. Book 16, 61.
Transfer of title, S. H. Miller to J. F. Vaughan, 7 September 1871. Book 18,
89-90.
Transfer of title, J. F. Vaughan to Sarah J. Fowler, 17 June 1873. Book 19,
279-80.
Transfer of title, Sarah J. Fowler to Christian Church, 4 May 1901. Book 41,
471.
Transfer of title, George F. Cranor and Kate Bell Fowler Cranor to elders of
East Main Church of Christ, 20 October 1920, Book 64, 255.
Sanborn Map Co., July 1891. Murfreesboro, TN. Map 3, 1888-1897.
Sims, Carlton C. ed. A History of Rutherford County. Murfreesboro: Privately printed,
1947.
Watson, Virginia Gooch. 'The Gooch Family in Williamson County, Tennessee."
Williamson County Historical Society. Publication 10, (Spring 1979): 4-50.
.. Interview by author, 22 November 1988, Franklin. Executive House,
Franklin, TN.
Whiffin, Marcus. American Architecture Since 1780: A Guide to the Styles. Cambridge, MA
and London: Massachusetts Institute of Technology Press, 1969.
Whitley, Edythe Rucker, comp. First Presbyterian Church: Roster of Members 1812-1846.
Rutherford County Library, Franklin, TN.
., comp. Marriages of Rutherford County, Tennessee: 1804-1872. Baltimore:
Genealogical Publishing Co., Inc., 1981.</dc:description>
<dc:description>A history of the owners of property at 214 East Main Street in Murfreesboro, TN. Also includes information about other settlers and property in Murfreesboro.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Murfree, Hardy, 1752-1809; Murfreesboro (Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>historic homes; Main Street historic district</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro;</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>16 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-01-26</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication34ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/123</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>