<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Soule College</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Sloan, Eugene H.</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 11</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1978</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>19th century; 20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>58
SOULE COLLEGE
by Eugene H. Sloan
Traditional Southern education for women in cultural studies and social
graces has long been associated with Murfreesboro.
A Female Academy was organized in 1825 by F. N. W. Burton, Dr. W. R.
Rucker, M. B. Murfree, and Dr. James Money. Misses Mary and Nancy Banks were
employed as teachers.
The Female County Academy was founded in 1829 and continued in successful
operation until after 185u.
Mrs. E. S. Bowles opened a school, Murfreesboro Female Seminary, in
January, 1835.
Midsylvania Female Academy, "located five miles southeast of Murfreesboro,
Tennessee" was granted a charter in 1834.
Reorganizations and consolidations resulted in the establishment of the
Tennessee Baptist Female Institute and Batons College for Women in 1853'
Soule College, the moat long lived and prestigious of all these efforts
to provide private schools for girls, was the outgrowth of a meeting held
July H, 1851 at the urging of a local Methodist minister. Rev. Thomas Madden.
Dr. J. R. Finley was named president of the proposed school, which was
named for Bishop Joshua Soule of Nashville.
The school opened work in the "old Female Academy" in September, 1851.
This gave credence to the Soule College Alumni Association claiming the school
was founded in 1825.
Work on the new building on Lebanon (North Maple) Street was begun on
July 3, 1853 and was ready for occupancy in November. The three-story building
cost $25,UUU. Dr. S. D. Baldwin, pastor of the Murfreesboro Methodist
5y
*-,
:
'
'-^ '- ;',' &#187; ,'&#8226;,&#8226;&#8226;
Bishop Joshua Soule for whom the college was n
t; . - . ; ji.*
60
Church, had succeeded Finley as president. He continued as president until
1856 when C. W. Callendar, a professional teacher, was elected president.
The Soule College site, four blocks south of the Court Square on Lebanon
(Maple) Street had been a Methodist church with a grave yard located south of
the church building. Middle Tennessee Electric Membership now occupies the
area.
Thomas Robertson acquired the church property and used it for the manufacture
of cotton gins. He conveyed it to the trustees of Soule College.
A study of the real property involved in Soule College as recorded in
Deed Books and Trust Deeds records in the Rutherford Courthouse reveals interesting
changes in street names, real estate ownership, and the fluctuating
value of property over the years.
Apparently the original tract, which included an old Methodist church,
with the possibility of an adjacent cemetery^ embraced about four acres.
On April 8, 1874- there was a conveyance to Joseph B. West from D. D.
Moore the tract with no metes or bounds description other than a statement,
"the Soule Female College grounds were bounded on the south by Walnut Street,
east by Lebanon Street, west by Railroad Street, and north by John C. Spence."
In the transfer by the F. W. Snead et al to A. M. Overall on September
10, 1907, the property was described as "4 1/2 acres more or less" bounded
on the east by Maple Street, west by Walnut Street, south by Burton Street,
and north by the property of James Moore.
Just two years later in April, 1909 the conveyance gave more minute descriptions.
The south boundary was owned by P. A. l4yon and Mrs. C. P. Campbell,
indicating that some of the Soule property had been sold for private development.
This is further indicated by 
The more minute linear bounds of 370 feet
along Maple Street and 300 feet westerly to Walnut Street. This was the first
conveyance mentioning insurance. The new owners (Miss Hopkins and Mrs. Hyde)
61
were to keep the property insured for $5,000 to protect mortgage holders.
In April, 1909 Martha A. Hopkins et al transferred the property to G. B.
Giltner, H. 0. Parker and B. L. Sims for the purpose of building a "white high
school" financed by a bond issue. An interesting clause in this deed conveyed
"war claims" to the School Commissioners. The property lines defined in this
transfer begin, "at the P. A. Lyon northeast corner, running with the Maple
Street line north 363 feet to James A. Moore southeast comer, thence Moore's
south boundary in a westerly direction 314 feet to the east side of Walnut
Street thence southerly 363 feet to Mrs. C. P. Campbell's lot, thence easterly
3H feet along the Campbell, T. L. Richardson and Lyons north boundary to the
point of beginning."
The charter of Soule was granted in 1854. Trustees were L. B. Carney,
B. W. Avent, D. D. Wendel, Levi Wade, W. R. McFadden, Joseph Watkins, William
Spence, W. S. Huggins and W. F. Lytle.
Soule College had many scholarly, highly dedicated, and widely recognized
administrators in its sixty-five years of service to education in the South.
Dr. J. Randolph Finley, who was a moving force in its incorporation, re-signed
the presidency of Soule Female College in a formal letter addressed to
the Board of Trustees December 1, 1852. He suggested that the vacancy be
filled by Rev. T. W. Randle or the Rev. S. D. Baldwin.
The Board accepted his resignation "since he had already received a transfer
to the Pacific Coast Conference". The Board voted to release "Dr. Finley
of his subscription of stock and commend him for his indomitable energy and
vigilant care to the institution". He was also complimented for his scholar-ship,
rapport with the community, and "extraordinary architectural skill in
drafting the plan and supervising to most speedy completion without
fee or reward the beautiful, spacious and well-constructed college buildings."
62
Some of the frustrations experienced by the Rev, Mr. Finley were revealed
in the research compiled by Frank Bass in his thesis for the ^faster
of Arts degree at Peabody College in 194.1.
Quoting from the Louisville and Nashville Christian Advocate, July 26,
1851, and the Minutes of the Board of Trustees Minute Book of 1851, Bass
wrote:
"It seems that schools always have had many difficulties and
Soule Female College was no exception. School was opened in the old
Female Academy, but owing to disagreement with trustees of that
institution, plans had to be rushed for a new building. It had
been agreed in the beginning of the movement for the school that
fifteen thousand dollars be raised by a joint stock company for the
erection and furnishing of the building. During the winter of
1851-52, events moved rapidly towards plans for erection of a suit-able
structure for housing a 'Female Institute of high grade and
liberal charter'."
Bass continued his account:
"On December 3, 1851, Dr. Finley and Rev. S, D. Baldwin were appointed
a committee to draft a plan for a building. At the same
time, in order to speed up the collection of funds, T. W. Randle
was appointed agent for the collection of such funds, and he was
allowed 2-^ per cent on $10,000, including the subscription already
obtained, and 5 per cent on whatever sum he may obtain over
$10,000."
On December 17, 1851, the committee for drafting a plan for a building
made its report, and it was approved by the Board. At the same meeting, a
committee was appointed to see the Trustees of the Murfreesboro Female Academy
and ascertain their view in reference to subscribing the present ground and
building as stock in Soule Female College. In a short time, this committee
made a favorable report, and a building committee was appointed.
The appointment of Rev. T. W. Randle as agent for the College must have
been temporary, because on January 30, 1852, the Board received an application
for this job from Rev. S. S, Moody. On February 3, the Board passed a
resolution to the effect that:
"Rev. S. S. Moody be employed as a traveling agent, whose
duty it shall be to collect funds for the erection of the building;
63
and to use his best energies to obtain pupils for the school
provided he will do so for ten percent, upon the amount of his
subscription. His pay to be retained out of said subscription;
and that the secretary address Mr. Moody and ascertain from his
views upon the subject."
On February 18, Mr. Moody appeared before the Board and accepted the
proposition. This appointment was approved by the Annual Conference, according
to the minutes of the Annual Conference of the M. E. Church, South, 1851-52.
This Board meeting brought the first disagreement among the members. Dr.
Avent moved that the Board proceed to make contracts "for the brick work of
the building, and for such wood work, and painting as will preserve the same."
All of the Trustees present voted for the motion except William Spence, and
the following week the brick work was awarded to William Summerhill, who had
made his bid in these words:
"To the committee of the Female Institute: I will erect the brick
work of the whole building of the Female Institute, after the
Banner and form of the drawing in the town of Murfreesboro: the
brick to be measured and counted according to the ruler of brick
work for SEVEN DOLLARS AND FORTS" CENTS, per thousand, counting the
openings out."
The contract for the wood work was given to Green Clay, who had made the
following proposition:
"I will furnish lumber, nails, locks, hinges, and do all the
carpenter work belonging to the Soule Female College according
to the plan as exhibited by Dr. Finley, and either cover the roof
with good cedar shingles, or with the composition, such as, the
railroad depot at Murfreesboro is covered with, (except the
observatory) for the sum of NINE THOUSAND FIVE HUNDRED DOLLARS.
School was in session, plans were well under way for the new building,
but it seemed that there was some doubt as to the ultimate completion of plans.
According to the 1852 Minutes of the Board of Trustees, Clay was awarded the
contract for wood work but agreed to take a per cent of his contract in stock.
In October, 1852, the Board made a special call upon the stockholders for the
first installment of twenty-five per cent upon their subscriptions. Apparently,
there was some difficulty with collections. In spite of all handicaps, however,
6a
plans went forward, and President Finley, in announcing plans for the first
commencement season stated that
"The corner stone of the new and commodious college edifice,
which is about to be erected by the Board of Trustees, will be
laid by the Fraternity of Masons, on Saturday, the 3rd of July
next."
Although no description of the interior arrangement of the building in
1851-52 is available, there is an excellent delineation of its appearance
appearing in an advertisement for a Chancery Court sale in the Murfreesboro
Monitor of August 22, 1868;
"For elegance, unity of design, and adaptation to educational
purposes this College edifice has but few superiors, if any. The
form of the house is that of a massive Ronan cross, three stories
high, 135 feet long, and 115 feet wide. The brick work is executed
in the finest style&#8212;the wood work on the exterior is tastefully
adjusted. A fine battlement cornice extends entirely around the
eaves, with a frontispiece facing the street. On the right of the
main entrance on the first story, are two family rooms, each twenty
feet square, and opposite are parlors corresponding in size. This
entry intersects a passage, from which doors open into a chapel,
laboratory, apparatus, and dining rooms. In the same wing are the
library and the Juvenile and Preparatory departments. The Study
Hall is 5U feet square, well lighted and thoroughly ventilated.
From this hall, glass doors open into the various recitation rooms.
The dormitories are twenty-six in number, twenty feet square on
average, and all fourteen feet high. The windows are large, opening
full length on hinges, and protected from without by Venetian
blinds. There is a beautiful lawn in front and on either side of
the building, well set in blue grass, and pleasantly shaded. All
necessary out-buildings, cisterns, etc., on the premises."
The first faculty consisted of Professor J. R. Finley, J. Hoffman, Jane
Raymond, Julia Knapp and Jane Wolf.
Little is known of Dr. Finley's work in the Pacific Coast Conference after
leaving Murfreesboro. That he returned to the South is evidenced by his being
listed as president of the Tennessee Conference Female Institute in Athens,
Alabama in 1885.
The first class graduated in 185^. It was composed of Amanda (Barlow)
Headers, Adelaide (Cooper) Malone, Georgiana Thompson (Gill), Keeble Thompson,
and Sue F. Dromgoole of Murfreesboro. Miss Dromgoole's sister. Will Allen,
become one of Tennessee's most famous writers.
65
.^T')i
66
The class of 1855 had 15 members including Kitty (Mrs. Doc Ledbetter)
and Anna Murfree. "Kit" must have been a popular pre-civil war name. The
only two members of the 1856 class were Kit Barlow and Kit Hall (Mrs. Thomas
Fletcher)
.
Mattie, Sallie, Lizzie, Lottie, Annie, and Nannie were other popular
contractions of given names of the period. Mattie Ready (Mrs. John Hunt
Morgan) had Lettie Pea, Mattie Woods, and Mattie Horton as classmates.
The school suspended operation February 1862 but was reopened in January
1866, and in June graduated a single girl, Jennie Ford (Mrs. Benjamin
Sawrie), of Nashville.
Conditions had apparently returned to some degree of normalcy by 1867,
when there were five graduates. There were ten girls receiving diplomas in
1868.
In the decade between 1870 and 1880 the influence of Soule College had
extended to list graduates from Texas, Florida, Indian Territory, Georgia,
^
Arkansas, Illinois, and Kentucky.
Hard times must have hit the school in the mid 1890*8. The class of
189A had only Eugenia Neilson of Murfreesboro graduating. The year before
Miss Neilson had been a "Laurel- crowned Student". There were two graduates,
Stella Cross and Lizzie Bates of Smyrna, in the 1895 class. Maggie Bock received
an "English diploma" in I896. There were no graduates in 1897.
In 1898 one of the largest classes to date was graduated. The class
included students from Korea, Cincinnati, Ohio, from Port, Oklahoma, and
Tennessee students from Martin, Cross Plains, Smyrna, Sweetwater, Jackson,
and Bell buckle. The fcUoway sisters, Nell and Anna Eliza (Mrs. Richmond
Jones), were graduates from Jefferson, Tennessee. Elodi&#169; Ross, Smyrna; Ivie
Mai Smith (Mrs. Guy McFerrin), Rosa Moore (Mrs. Tom Cannon), Adele Kimbro and
Neina Childress were among the Murfreesboro girls who were members of this
class.
67
Dr Samuel Davies Baldwin, then pastor of the Methodist Church in Murfreesboro, was elected to fill the unexpired term of Dr. Finley and was
re-elected in May 18^3. He was to receive an annual salary of $1,20U and a
"comfortable house to live in".
A native of iJorthington, Ohio, Baldwin had been graduated from Woodward
College. He was described as a "Knight Templar, critic, author, preacher,
pastor, revivalist and scholar". He had preached at Mt. Pleasant, Clarksville,
Lebanon and Edgefield in Nashville. His last pastorate was at McKendree
Church in Nashville, where he died in 1881.
Dr. Baldwin was a nationally known author and lecturer. Among the books
he wrote while president of Soule College was Armageddon . The Seventh Trumpet.
and The Millenial Empire also attracted national attention. His theories on
The Revelation of St. John was summarized on the title page of Armageddon ,
which reads:
"Armageddon: Or the Overthrow of Romanism and Monarchy; the
Existence of the United States Foretold in the Bible; It's
Future Greatness; Invasion by Allied Europe; Annihilation of
Monarchy; Expansion into the Millenial Republic and It's
Domination Over the World."
Since his writing and lecture toxic to the principal cities in America
came to occupy so much of his time, Baldwin surrendered his administration in
October, 1856.
Professor C. W. Callendar had been named vice-president in 1855, possibly
assuming the immediate executive duties. He was a native of Harrisburg, Pennsylvania
but had been associated with a Washington College at Hendersonville,
Tennessee before coming to Soule College. The school prospered under his ad-ministration,
reaching an enrollment of l00 in 1857. The next year Callendar-,
68
the first professional education to head Souls College, went to Franklin to
establish a girl's school there.
Callander was succeeded by the Rev. George E. Naff who came to Soule
from the presidency of the Tennessee Female College in Athens, Alabama.
A description of the 1859 commencement at Soule College was typical
of such exercises. The Sunday, June 19, commencement sermon was delivered
at the Methodist Church by Dr. Summers. "The examination exercises" were
conducted by a Conference Committee on Monday, Wednesday, June 22, was
the formal commencement day. Each graduate read an original poem, essay,
or delivered an address. President George E, Naff presented diplomas to
each graduate. Mrs. Naff presented a gold thimble to Fannie S* Allen of
Athens, Alabama for "having the neatest room during the preceding year".
The "station preacher" presented a Bible to each graduate. This Bible presentation
tradition seemed to have been renewed at various times during the
subsequent years. Petty Bostic of Triune gave the valedictory address and
two Murfreesboro girls, Martha J. Cox and Bettie S, Hoover, appeared on the
program at the 1859 commencement.
President Naff made valiant efforts to keep the college in operation
as the War Between the States approached. The school had an enrollment of
192 pupils at the close of the school year in 1861. In August of 1861, the
school was advertised as one "of safety and easy access from the South".
Opening on September 2, the Christian Advocate reported that the school was
prepared to "retain our reputation as a school of faithful and thorough instruction
... in healthful and comfortable quarters". Charges for 10
months was "about $175".
An example of the struggle to keep the school open as Federal armies
moved South, the Christian Advocate reported that: "For the past few months
69
women with "missions" have been migrating northward like geese in the spring-time
. . . Soule College is erect and flourishing".
But the vicissitude of war caused the school to close in February of 1862,
after the fall of Forts Donnellson and Henry. The school was used as a hospital
by both Federals and Confederates during the war. There are former students
of Soule College living in Murfreesboro who state that as late as 191", there
were blood stains ingrained in the floors of some of the rooms. Before the
war was over, the fences were destroyed, furniture carried away, and the
building defaced.
Six months after Appomattox, the Rev. James R. Plumer, a Methodist preacher
from Maury County, collected a faculty consisting of Mrs. E. M. Eaton, Jo Eaton,
Betty Wharton, Mrs. M. Henderson, Anna Ransom, R. T. Steinhagen, Mrs. H. Keeble,
with Mrs. Plumer as "matron". On January 1, 1866 the school reopened and was
described as having "no school marms" from the North. The faculty were all
"Southern magnolias".
An interesting excerpt from a letter written by a visitor at the i860
commencement described the Soule College as "alive with girls&#8212;well fed, well-taught,
and well behaved". There were I4.6 students, 114- of which were boarders,
in the 1866 enrollment.
Fiscal problems continued to vex Soule under the Plumer administration,
until it was necessary to foreclose in a Chancery Court sale as recorded in
Book 22, page 33 of the Rutherford County Register's office. The Rev. R. D-Moore
took charge of the school in the fall of 1868.
Records of the Christian Advocate and Tennessee Conference reports indicate
that the number of boarding students doubled in 1868-69, and that there
was an equal increase in students of music.
70
Moore's administration from 1868 until 1874 reflected a modernization of
the physical plant and curriculum. A reading room was established with "an
extensive stock of s\il table and tasteful books and selections of v/weeklies,
monthlies and quarterlies of America and Europe".
Physical plant improvements were made. Gaslights were installed through-out
the building. Apparently the toilet facilities of the school were installed,
as "modern city improvements including furnace heat for the recitation room and
study hall were advertized. "Sleeping apartments were more cheerfully warmed
by grate fires", according to the 1870 advertisements for the school.
In an advertisement in the July 9, 1870 Christian Advocate . Moore wrote:
"Having conformed our curriculum to the standards of good
male colleges, procured the services of some of the ablest and
most experienced professors in the country, as teachers of that
curriculum, especially designed as a finishing school for young
ladies of the South."
For one of the few times in the history of the school, the men faculty
members made up almost half the staff. The Rev. D. D. Moore was professor of
"moral philosophy", Rev. W. H. Bess A.M. taught Latin and Greek, and the Rev.
Lorenzo Lee, A.M. taught mathematics and modern languages. Kate S. Carney was
in charge of the academic department. Other faculty members were Sallie R.
Thompson, Mrs. R. K. Keeble, Mrs. G. T. Henderson and Willie Lea.
A diploma from Soule College hangs in the foyer of Linebaugh Library.
Apropos to the prevailing collegiate diplomas of the period, it is lettered
on a vertical 1/+ x 20 sheet of paper with a light blue ribbon in the lower
left corner, in lieu of a seal. It reads:
71
SOULE FEMALE COLLEGE
Murfreesboro, Tennessee
To All Whom It May Concern GREETINGS
Be It Knovm That
MESS SALLIE RAMSON
of Bedford, Tennessee
Having passed successfxillj the prescribed course
of English and Mathematics study has been thought
worthy of this
DIPLOMA OF (21ADUATI0N
by the President and his associates in consideration
of scholarship and purity of character, June 13, 1870
D. H. Moore
Mrs. H. A. Peabody
E. N, Eton
Joe Easten
Kent Gredg
_______ Dixon
Gassie &#163;. Deason
In 1873 a visiting committee from the Conference reported that attendance
at Soule College was not as large as it had been, and that free schools
had been established in Murfreesboro. These and other factors may have induced
Dr. Moore to sell the college and grounds to Dr. Joseph B. West on
April 8, 1874 for $12,000. The transfer is recorded in the Rutherford County
Register's Office, Book 22, page 333.
Dr. West had been president of Clarksville Academic^ before he came to
Murfreesboro for a four-year tenure (1874-78) as president at Soule College.
In 1876 the Rev. John R. ThoiiDDSon purchased a one-half interest in the school
for $6,500. The enrollment dropped to fewer than 90 pupils in 1878, and
T. A. Z. Adams was brought in to serve as president for one year. The next
Year J. R. Thompson became the '*^ief administrator at Soule College.
72
John Ransom Thompson, a native of Rutherford County, graduated from
Union University and received a law degree from Cumberland University at
I^ebanon. He later taught at Union University and then practiced law at
Shelbyville. In 1859, he joined the Tennessee Conference and was licensed
to preach.
In 1879 he became president of Soule College, and over a ten-year
period increased the enrollment to 175 and established the strongest religious
code the school had experienced.
Bible study was reqtdred of each student, and ten minutes of each day
was devoted to memorizing Bible verses. On Saturday nights the boarding
students learned and recited the S\inday School lessons for the next day.
Dancing was prohibited, and Sunday was Set aside for a period of meditation
witn no callers being permitted. Revivals were held and pupils converted&#8212;
3U in 1884.. In a later report the statement was made that all the 175
students and the faculty members were Christian.
Mrs. Thompson supervised the boarding students with a discipline that
"is strictly Christian and is exercised in the spirit of kindness". Tlioir.p-son
was twice married&#8212;first to Martha Lou Goodrich, who died in 1867. In
1873 he married Mrs. Addie Hill Swan, a native of Paris, Tennessee.
It is difficult to evaluate just how strongly the Methodist doctrine
was taught the pupils of Soule College before 1900. There are many references
to religious practices. As early as 1857, a report stated that eight
of the nine graduates were "professed followers of Jesus".
In 1871 the college reported:
"Almost every young lady of the College is a church member,
Many were converted during the past year. One of the chief aims
of this college is true piety, both by precept and example. 'Iny
young lady who enters here will be surrounded by the pure and
sacred influences of a well-regulated Christian home."
73
At some time during the more than a decade of John Ransom Thompson's
administration, W. P. Henderson had acquired a one-fourth interest in the
school. In July, 1889 Thompson conveyed his interest in the school for
$8,000 to John G. Paty. Henderson sold his interest together with personal
property listed in The Rutherford County Register's office Book 30, pp 621-62?
to Paty. The personal property inventory ranged from four pianos to fruit
jars. It included "22 small feather pillows, 13 bed comforts, H mattresses,
13 wardrobes, seven sideboards, eight bureaus, and 4-0 chairs."
Z. C. Graves, who had been associated with Mary Shap College at Winchester,
was secured as president of Soule College by Mr. Paty. Graves
remained in charge until Miss Virginia Oceania Wardlaw cam'; from the Price
School in Nashville. She was a "charter graduate of the Wellesley College
and had taught in Virginia before coming to Nashville." Miss Wardlaw and
her sister, Mrs. Mary Snead, operated the college until the oldest of the
three sisters, Mrs. C. W. Martin from New York, joined in the operation
in 1903.
During the Wardlaw administration much emphasis was placed on concerts,
lecturers, and visiting teachers. Piano, violin, organ, guitar, and voice
were offered in music. There were offerings in expression and drama. During
one graduaticHi period, there were four "commencement concerts".
Although Soule College continued to operate until 1917, if any one
year could be designated as the apex as opposed to the nadir of 189*7, it
would be the class of 190^. In February, 1903 Mrs. C. W. Martin, a sister
of Miss Wardlaw, acqiiired title to the school property for $9,000. Two
months later the title was transferred to Miss Wardlaw fo; ^^^^,,000 nnd the
assumption of a mortgage note for $5,000 held by Miss Carmine Collier. The
school then launched a program that attained wide scholastio recognition.
74
Miss Wardlaw's progressive ideas were apparently implemented by pro-fessional
enthusiasm, as she introduced dressmaking, bookkeeping, type-writing,
and commercial law into the curriculum. The Visiting Committee
early in her administration complimented the "practical manner in which
the sciences are taught in well-eqviipped laboratory in which pupils are
required to perform experiments". Geological field trips were conducted
by Professor Safford, the State Geologist.
"Latin and Greek are read with a fluency we have never seen equaled
in a female institution", the visiting committee reported.
Miss Wardlaw brought visiting lecturers from Vnnderbilt. She intro-duced
the use of the stereoptican in the study of literature and history.
French and German were taught. Constitutional history for seniors was
added to a four-year course that covered conventional United States hist0i.'y,
English, French, and modern European history. Civil government and polit-ical
economy placed emphasis on "application of principle? to personal
and home affairs".
The hiunanities were further einphasized by courses in ethics, aesthetics,
and Bible. The mathematics courses included arithmetic, algebra, plane
and solid geometry, trigonometry, analytical geometry, and calculus. Phys-iology
was designed to be practical with "resident physicins adding lectures
on eye, ear, brain, digestion, circulation, and respiration". The pupils
dissected animals to study the vital organs of frogs, chickens, rabbits, nnd
other small animals.
The faculty included Miss Virginia 0. Wardlaw, Mrs. Ma.ry Ward Snead, A.M.,
Mrs. Alice Foxworthy Glascock, Albert Charles Snead, Rev. C. S. Ware, Mrs.
William Browen Hamen, Miss Myrtice Jarrell, Miss I. M. Smith, Miss Anna E.
McFadden, Miss Elizabeth Gailbraith, Prof. Frany J. Strahn, Miss Abbie Speer,
Miss Margaret Hatcher, Miss Katherine Jones, Miss Alemeda Hughes, and Sadie
Fry.
The course of study outlined in a 1904. catalog stated: "A knowledge
of Latin and Greek is essential to a critical appreciation of the English
language". The study of these langviages began in the "academic" class for
Latin and the sophomore class for Greek. The method of instruction vras des-cribed
as "electic, embracing features of the inductive and analytic".
French and German offerings were available but not required.
The study in English classes required "etymological and sjrntactical
principles of the language". Much essay writing, the study of parliamenta-^v
law, argumentation, letter writing, book revievring, journalism, criticism!";,
and eachaustive reading in literature (including the Bible) were among the
requirements.
Miss Wardlaw published a collection of the work of her better stxidents
entitled, Original Work of Miss Wardlaw 's Pupils , Included in this book was?
a poetic version of the Book of Ruth, a dramatization of the Book of Esther,
and six poems based on The Idyls of the King,
Rules established by the Vfardlaw administration inclvided "Symplicity
in style and material of dress", the limiting of "pin money" to a definite
sum for a definite time, and a prohibition of "Sunday callers".
That students other than those of the Methodist faith were enrolled
is suggested by the request to parents to provide ''a Bible, a Hymn Book cf
their own church, and the sending of copies of their own church papers" to
the stiidents.
The girls were required to have "one hoxir of recreative exercise each
day in the open air, in good weather". Regular wallcs were varied with "ten-nis,
basketball, croquet, and other out-door games", according to the catalog.
The 1904. commencement wad held in the Soule Chapel on May 25. Dr. H.
C. Tolman of Veinderbilt University delivered the commencement address with
Dr. J. P. McFerrin awarding diplomas to 28 women, five of whom received the
76
Bachelor of Arts degree. Certificates in Teaching of music were avrarded
13 yo\ang women. Four qualified for certificates to teach elocution.
The I9O3-I9O4. school year provided Soule College women with ten major
social events, the attending of 13 off-campus affairs, and 68 lectures, re-citals,
concerts, dramatic productions, dinners, and entertainments- These
included a reception for the Confederate veterans reunion, a reception
for the students from Webb School and the senior class from Mooney School,
and an affair honoring former Governor Robert L. Taylor.
The names Wardlaw and Snead mean little to the present generation in
Rutherford County. Three quarters of a century ago these names were synon-ymous
with distinction in education in the South. In the period 1910-1913
the names were spread in headlines of newspapers over the world in a
bizarre Svengali horror&#8212;a puzzling mystery that has never been solved.
Virginia 0. Wardlaw was of distinguished ancestry, descended from the
royalty of Scotland. Her ancestral family included church dignitaries,
surgeons, bankers, judges, Revolutionary and Civil War military and civil
leaders. She was a "charter stuaent" at Wellesley College at Massachusetts
and came to Nashville vith her sister to teach at the exclusive Price School.
Her parents were John Baptist ./ardlaw and Martha Eliza Goodall Wardlaw,
There were four daughters, Caroline (Mrs. R. M. Martin), hbry (Mrs. Fletche-
Snead), Virginia, and Bessie and two sons, Albert and John, in the Wardlaw
family.
The Rev. John B. Wardlaw was for four decades a prominent Methodist
clergyman in southern states. In the early 1890's he and Mi-s. Wardlaw
moved to Murfreesboro, where he died in 1898. The widow, Martha Eliza
Wardlaw, moved to a room at Soule College.
Miss Virginia Wardlaw, a brillant woman, according to the testimony of
those who knew her, locally and professionally, was a woman of fine charactpi
77
and gentle demeanor. Her sister, Mrs. Nfery Snead, was a teacher-overseer-assistant
principal at the school. Two of Mi-s. Snead 's sons, Albert and
Fletcher, taught at the school. One son, Fletcher, was to play a strange
role in the events between the 1904 and 1907 period.
A third sister, Mrs. Caroline B. Martin came to the school from her
home in New York City. Weii^d tales began to develop among the impressionable
students at the college and among the black servants. Occult powers were
attributed to Mrs. Martin.
Dr. C. C. Sims in his History of Murfreesboro alludes to the bizarre
situation that developed in the last few years of the Wardl^w-Snead
administration.
Teachers were frightened, and students left the school or failed to
return. The sitviation worsened until 1907 when the College, in severe
financial straights, caused the sisters to turn their operation ovp/ to
local leadership and leave Murfreesboro.
The three sisters and their ciother next appear in East Orange, New
Jersey where Ocey Martin Snead was found dead in a bathtub in November,
1909. On December 22, I9O9 Virginia Wardlaw, Mrs. Snead, and Mrs. Martin
were indicted for murder and the trials set for the following spring in
Newark, New Jersey. The sensational affair was extensively covered by
reporters of the area press.
In June, I9IO the mother of the three sisters, Martha Eliza Jardlav,
died. Virginia Oceana d'd^pdi^u died two months later in the House of De-tention
at Newark, either of heart disease or pelfr-iioDposed malnutrition.
Mary Martin was found sane by the trial judge and charged vrith ths homicide
of her daughter.
Martin's trial in January, I9II resulted in her plea of noa viilb ',0 a
charge of manslaughter. She vra..T sentenced to a seven-year prison term.
78
Two years later she was removed to the New Jersey State Hospital fo- the
Insane, where she died January 2u, 1913.
Fletcher Snead has been described as a handsome, blonde youn;^ man in
his early twenties, while a resident-teacher at Soule College. He h.id Lhrec
separate wedding ceremonies with his first cousin, Ocey Martin. There w;ts
conside able speculation that Ocey was really the daughter ol' Virginia
//ardlaw, who had been reared oy Caroline Martin to avoid a scandle. Th's
innuendo was vigorously denied by Ifrs. Snead in a lengthy article in the
Murfreesboro News Banner in I93u.
Alvin Harlow published a book, h^ysteries Not Quite Solved , in which
he recounts some or his findings in a chapter entitled, "Three Sisters in
Black".
The Shadow and the '^eb by Mary :\llerton (Estelle Noble Gowan), the
popular author of children's books, used the Wardlaw-Snead story for the
basis of her first novel as a mystery writer. The plot and descriptions
of life in an imaginary Fenale Academy offers an interesting picture oi
what it may have been like at Soule College about 19U5 to 19U7.
Factually, the soundest work that has been done on the story is The
Three Sisters , written by Norman Zierold. It contains pictures of the
Wardlaw family and a good brief of the legal maneuvering of the Martin-
Snead-Wardlaw defense.
After leaving their quarters at Soule College, the './r\rdlaw faiidly
moved to the house of a Mr. Street located opposite the present site Ox
Citizens Central Bank. According to Mi's. N. C. Beasley, who lived next
door, the neighborhood children were frightened 1;/ the elderly women,
clothed in black and heavily veiled who could be seen wandering about it.
night.
vv
Soule College as it appeared around I9I6, See contrast photograph on pg, 65.
Virginia Oceania Wardlav Ocej Martin, neice of Virginia
Wardlaw.
80
Following a few months residence in the Street house, the women moved
to the upstairs rooms of the Searcey house located on the present site of
the Murfreesboro Electric Department at the comer of College and Walaiut
Street.
A great aunt, Oceana Seaborn Pollock, was owner of Montgomery College
in Christiansburg, Virginia. As the clan scattered, Virginia went to
Christiansburg to head that college. The Snead boys, Fletcher and John,
went to I^rnnville, Tennessee where they operated a saw mill and married
sisters. Mrs. Martin returned to New York City where she had been princi-pal
of an elementary school before moving to Murfreesboro in 1902. Mrs.
Snead went to Georgia "where she had relatives" to teach school. Bessie
Spindell, the fourth sister, lived near Christiansburg. John Snead later
went to Christiansburg to teach in the college and there died in a fire
under nysterious circumstances. Fletcher's wife in I^ynnville divorced him,
and he, subsequently, married Ocey Snead.
The denouement of this strange chronicle of Wardlav clan appeared in
the Murfreesboro News Banner in 1930 imder the banner headline:
THREE HEIRS TO JEWELS ARE NOW FOUND LIVING
Mary Snead Places Blame for Bathtub Murder on
"Irresponsible" Mrs. Martin
The last chapter in the Wardlaw-Snead-Martin nystery was
written yesterday when the last of three immediate heirs to the
Wardlaw diamonds were made known, and Mrs. Mary Snead placed full
blame for the death of Ocey Snead on her "irresponsible" and "insane"
sister, Carolyn Martin.
In less than one week after news broke that the jewels of
Virginia Wardlaw were reposing in the First National Bank vault
here, Mary Snead, a material witness in the fairous murder case
81
of 1909, was foxmd living in Oakland, California, and word of the
diamond find brought from her a complete statement that not only-exonerated
her and Virginia Wardlaw, but threw light upon the many-sinister
happenings that led up to the weird tragedy of twenty-one
years ago.
A brother and sister of Mary Snead were also foiond, the three
living apparently unknown to each other in different sections of
the country. Statements were refused by the brother, Albert
Wardlaw, living in West Palm Beach, Florida, and the younger sis-ter,
Mrs. R. S. Spindle, living in Christiansburg, Virginia.
But Mrs. Snead, a principal in the trial of I9IO, spoke after
twenty years of silence, and told how, out of pity, the insane
Mrs. Martin was taken into Soule College to live with her two sis-ters,
and how her increasing insanity resulted in strange happenings
credited erroneously to all three sisters. And how the tragic
death of Ocey Snead brought about by her irresponsible mother,
completely crushed the well-meaning sister, Virginia, and caused
her suicide. Said Mrs. Snead: "I was so happy when I learned
that the diamonds were found, but I had rather never see them
than to have their discovery reopen that chapter of my life."
"Yet, I think it is better that the simple truth should be
told, and all the nightmare of rumor and legend cleared away at
last."
"My sister, Virginia Wardlaw was an angel on earth. She
was good, almost too good for this world. Her school, Soule Col-lege,
in Murfreesboro was successful with 300 boardin;^ pupils.
It was her pity thr.t led her to take Mrs. Martin and her daughter,
Ocey, a sweet lovely child, into the school to live. The bare
LruLh ia, that Va-z. Martin wns insane and h;id been so for yvirc.
82
She should have been put into an asylum long before. She was the
only one of the three of us who was queer, but she caused so much
trouble with her increasing insanity that Miss Wardlaw had to give
up the school, I imagine that such gossip arose from Mrs. Martin's
queemess, which gave rise to all sorts of superstitions about the
place where she lived. We never wore black mits nor dressed
peculiarly except Mrs. Martin."
"The marriage between my son, Fletcher, and Ocey was not forced
but was voluntary on both sides. Mrs. Martin had a very strong
personality and will, but no occult or hypnotic powers. The terrible
mistake was in keeping her with us instead of having her committed
to an institution. When the tragedy of Ocey's drowning in the
bathtub occurred, all three of us, Mrs. Caroline Martin, Virginia
Wardlaw, and myself were held because we were all members of the
household. I absolutely know that Virginia was not guilty of the
murder of which she was accused. She was the best v/orean in the
world, but horror of it all simply crushed her. She could not
bear it, and that is why she killed herself before she came to
trial. It would be quite true to say that the shock is what really
killed her."
"I was never brought to trial. I was held as a material
witness, but I was able to prove that I was in New York at the
time of Ocey's death. I do not call it a murder. Mrs. Martin,
the girl's mother, was absolutely irresponsible and had been so
for a long time.
"Fifteen years ago I came to California to join iny son, who
has a teaching position here. The baby of Fletcher and Ocey is
dead. Virginia Wardlaw it dead, and Caroline Martin died insane
before the expiration of her sentence for the mxirder of which she
83
v/as convicted. And now after nearly a qioarter of a centvury,
that act of restitution has shown that after all, the past
cannot die, unless this explanation will lay its ghost at last
and forever," said Mrs. Snead.
The recovery of the jewels is in itself a nystery which
has p\izzled bank officials who declare that they have no idea
how the diamonds got into the safety deposit vault where they
were found and identified as the property of Virginia Wardlaw.
"I cannot say exactly what happened as a natter of probable
fact, but I believe that I know," Mrs. Snead said,
"I believe that I know who stole them from a secret drawer
in my sister's desk at Soule College in I9O6. I will not re-veal
that person's name, because she, too, is a member of a
fine Southern family in educational work, and I have no desire
to bring pain upon her. She had access to my sister's desk and
knew where she kept the diamonds, some of which were family heir-looms.
I believe that they were stolen out of spite and that her
conscience finally impelled her to attempt to restore them to the
family in this strange way. Miss Wardlaw never rented a safety
deposit box at the bank, and no members of otu- family has rented
one in Morfreesboro. All our connections with Tennessee were
severed when we left there for New Jersey. 1^ explanation, and
this is only inference and reasoning, is that the woman wno took
the jewels so long ago must have rented a box in ny sister's
name and placed them there. That is the only way I can account
for their discovery and for the fact that they -..-ere identified by
the bank as Virginia Wardlaw' 3 property."
^u
Mrs. Snead did not comment on what course she would follow in estab-lishing
her claim to the diamonds.
Thus endeth the loncanny story of the three "black" sisters whc
terrorized a populace with strange antics that hinted of black magic which
led to the weird bathtub murder of the daughter and niece that mj'stified
the country.
There are those who take the statements of Mary Snead as the true
story about a deranged woman. This would account for the circumstances
that brought tragedy into the lives of two benevolent sisters and caused
Carolyn Martin's death in an insane asylum while paying the penalty for her
daughter's death.
The post-Wardlaw era began July 8, 1905 when N. I). Overall bought
the property from the Wardlaws for $8,000 and became "Regent" of the col-lege.
Miss Alice Glascock was hired as the "Principal".
In 1906 Miss Martha Hopkins and Mrs. Ada B. Ryde rented the school
from Overall. Three years later the women bought the building for 111 i, 300.
Among the innovations of the new administration was a course in
"Pedagogies" designed for those who wished to become teachers.
As early as 1899 the school had laid much enphasis on encouraging
practical journaliatlc training in original literaiy efforts which were
published in "The Crimson and Gold", a monthly journal. Other original
works of students appeared in Miss Wardlaw's Book of Essays . In 1910 and
1911 yearbooks. The Gleaner , were published. Martha Ordway was editor of
the 1911 volume. Miss Ordway later became a teacher at Ward Belmont College.
Athletics were enphasized in "Physical Training" classes, with basket-ball,
tennis, and croquet being played. A "match game" of basketball with a
YWCA team was open to the public. The "public", however, was Jimited to
"ladles and children". For the first time in its history, the school
S5
The- last, ainainistratiors 0/ 3oule Coij
The members of the I9IO senior
class pictured i'rora bop left
downward were Maud CejHpbel.i
,
.iobbie Ring Hoover ^ Carrie
ffoorei Second Row: Louise
Leachj, Minerva Bond, Tessi^je
Swops I Bottx^ SSH' ^'^argarsv
&#8226;&#187;iiij Secretaj-j; Ajlne Norfch,
lYsastxrerj Laiira Clendea^m,
?.'. cs Presld&#174;nt| and Nadine
C^'-^'-rali, ! resident.*
86
adopted a uniform&#8212;white middy blouse and dark blue or brovm coat suit with
matching hat.
Altie McKalg Todd of Murfreesboro was a "boarding girl" who said she
had the best of two worlds. Her father would bring her good things to eat
from the farm, while she enjoyed the conviviality of living with three
girls in a big JlP-foot square room. The older girls in the room taught
her to "do her hair" and the proper method of dress and deportment.
At "recess", according to Mrs. Todd, a black woman brought in a basket
of sandwiches which the girls could buy. She and another "boarding girl"
had roller skates and a bicycle which they could use on the sidewalk for
the block in front of the Soule College.
Social activities for the girls were increased. Properly chaperoned,
the students watched the Mooney School football games. On Wednesday after-noons
Stanley Overall invited the young ladies to enjoy the facilities of his
skating rink.
"Teachers and pupils enjoyed the half hour intervening between supper
and study hour. Everyone gathered in the library around the open fire. All
kinds of games were played-flinch, muggins, proverbs, and charades being
favorites," according to the memory of another boarding student of the
Hyde-Hopkins era.
In addition to Mrs. Hyde and Miss Hopkins, the members of the last
faculty at Soule College were Margaret Rhea Daxji, science; Roxana Whitaker,
ancient languages and mathematics; Elizabeth Thompson, primary and kinder-garten;
Martha Quarles, assistant academic department; Daisy Leuhon Hoffman,
music; Gertrude Richards Schumacher, voice; Jennie Mai McQuiddy, expression
and physical tradning; Mme. Lorene Gobel, art and modern language; and
Catherine Reeves Bell, home department.
In February, 1917 the two women gave up the struggle against the com-petition
with public schools, Tennessee College, and the Normal. The city
87
of Murfreesboro bought the property for $4,000 end the aESV!r.ption of soeo
debts. The classes were moved to a house at 442 North Chtr.^eh &#163;'t::oct dd
the boarding students to the Church of Christ minister's building on Enst
Main Street. The final commencement v/as held in the Grand Theatre building
on May 27, 1917.
When Mrs. Hyde and Miss Hopkins took charge of the school, every
resident pupil for the first time v;as required to wear a school uniform~a
brown or dark blue coat and hat for winter; the unlforia skirt, white waist
and hat for spring. To insure uniformity, the uniforms vere ordered by
the school. The rules also provided that each young lady liave "a simple
vrtiite dress for school entertainments". Underscored in the catalog was
the strict rule that on "no occasion are low neck and short slcoves
permitted."
Every resident pupil and teacher was required to furnish "a confort,
a pair of blankets, a white coixnterpane, two pair of sheets, tv.'o pair of
pillow cases, towels, six table napkins, napkin rings, toilot soap, over-shoes
and an umbrella"
.
Board, literary tuition, furnished room, fuel. Lights, and laundiy
cost $275 each session, with additional fees for "optional studies". These
fees included $70 for individual piano lessons, $60 for voice or violin,
$50 for expression, $50 for art, and $25 for foreign lan^iages.
There were literary societies at Soiile as early as 1858, During the
1909-1917 period, organizations at the college included the Aletlxa Literary
Society, the Thespian Uterary Society, the Studio Club, tho Dranntic Club,
the Mozart Club, Choral Club, Y.W.C.A., and athletic teams and social
activities.
The ;:tugfa^'?3)?orQ MoSiS J-aumal of the period had reports of basketball
games between the "resident pupils an^ to;m pupils" to v/hdch only women and
children were admitted.
Cw;; Ball Tl^,.., ^ouls college.
athletic teams of 1903.
The Alethea Literary Society of 1911^
High draina at
Soule College,
Thespian Society
production, of
"Blue Beard" with
Augusta iiiggins
and Ethel Ilaney.
There are reports of "old-fashioned candy pulls, gamus, and charades."
Description of a "delightful reception" given by the young ladies and faculty
October 25, 1907 was reported in the Murfreesboro Home Journal ;
"The spacious old parlors of historic Soule presented a
charming scene with huge fires glowing in the grates, the man-tels
banked in flowers and autumn leaves. The young ladies
were gowned in light colors. The Seniors were assisted in
receiving by Kdss Hopkins and I'lrs. Hyde. All kinds of geunes
were played, flinch, muggins, proverbs, and charades being the
favorites. Delightful refreshments were served."
Mrs. Leiper (Richardsorj) Freeman, and the Licker sisters, Mrs. Ethel Haney ^'
and I-lrs. Esther Maxwell are among present residents of Mui-freesboro who re-count
many experiences of life at Soule College.
Mrs. J. D. McFarlin recalls her experiences at Soule College. Mattie
Lowe and her sister, Elizabeth, boarded with an aunt who lived in Murfrees-boro.
They spent the weekends at home. Each Monday morning they would get
up before daylight for a two-hour ride in a buggy driven by their mother to
return to the home of the aunt.
As a former teacher, Mrs. McFarlin is in an especially strong position
to evaluate the work of Soule College in its later years.
"The curriculum was more advajiced than children woula encounter today
in the comparable grade and much more advanced than the "public school"
children of that time could expect", she said.
The college work was probably equivalent to the first year of college
today. Scholastic standards were very high. The grading system was of the
E (Excellent), 3 (Satisfactory), and U (Unsatisfactory) t^-pe.
"Moral influence was outstanding", Mrs. McFarlin declared. The teachers
used the honor system which was meticulously observed by the students.
In the "Our Family" oonpilation of Fount Henry Rion, genealogist, is
a description of the effect of the Federal occupation of Soule on the neighborhood,
91
"Grandma's (Mrs. Fountedn Jefferies Henry) home at that time, was a
comfortable little brick cottage located diagonally across the street from
Soule College, She had a large brick underground cistern filled with rain-water,
the only source of water other than the 'town pump'.
Grandma told of the desolation as she stood on the porch, helpless,
holding the baby in her arms, and my mother by the hand, as she watched every-thing
she owned in the world being carried away," (Mrs. Henry's husband was
with the Confederate army in the retreat from Murfreesboro in early Jan, 1863)
Virtually all the moveable assets of the College were destroyed by the
contending armies or by vandals.
After the war, each dormitory room appeared to have been furnished by
double beds, two wardrobes, a study table, lan^JS, and at least four chairs.
This bare furnishing was supplemented by various amenities, including some
type of toiletry accomodation, llrs. Knox McCharen recalls that her mother
obtained some of the rugs or carpets at a dispersal sale when the school was
closed.
Mrs. Priscilla P. Weathersby of Clarksville has an eight-page hand-written
essay on "Ireland" coiqjiled by her grandmother. Pearl Frost. Such an
essay was apparently one of her requirements for gradup.tion from Soule College
in 1879. Mrs. Weathersby also possesses an autograph album signed by class-mates
of Pearl Frost,
Mr. and Mrs. Walter King Hoover have many mementoes of Soule College
students, including receipts signed by Miss V. 0, Wardlaw for $8 tuition paid
hy Anne Overall, A report card of Carmine Collier, signed by "John B. Thoup-son.
President", of Soule College in 1908 indicates the grading system was
based on points&#8212;180 points indicating perfection and below 100 points
unsatisfactory grades.
Andrena Briney owns a picture of the entire student body of 1903 stand-ing
in front of the inqjosing building. A white fence surrounds the property.
92
One amusing incident is recalled by Mrs. McFarlin about 1908 or 1909
on April's Fool Day. The girls decided to "cut classes", but they dared
not face the wrath of teachers should homework be unprepared. So the
girls slipped in early and left their homework on the teacher's desks
and left quickly. Later they learned the teachers had decided not to have
classes on that day.
A horseshoe hanging by the classroom door was used when one wished
to be excused to the bathroom. As one student replaced it, another would
take it without disturbing the class or raising a hand in embarrassment.
Bishop L. Gailor was the commencement speaker for the class of 1908.
The following year when Mrs. McFarlin graduated, Sawney Webb was the speaker.
Mrs. McFarlin remembers that Bishop Gailor spoke for only 20 minutes, but
she considered that address superior lo that of the Webb School head.
Such joyous nostalgia remains in the minds of alumnae still living,
yet they marked the beginning of the end. A decade later the headline in a
Murfreesboro newspaper read: "Soule is not dead, but liv^sl"
The single significant sentence "impressively uttered by Miss Hopkins
in her closing remarks before presenting diplomas" to the five last gradu-ates
of Soule College must have left a lasting impression on sympathetic
minds of those who witnessed the finale of the sixty- fifth commencement.
The commencement was formally inaugurated on Friday morning. May 18,
1917 with Class Day at the Grand Theater. There was the usual baccalaureate
Sunday morning service at the Methodist Church, with the Rev. Mr. Morgan
stressing the necessity of "earnest, honest toil, service to the world and
loyalty to the Savior".
Sue Gill Riggs, a member of the last class who lives in the Murfreesboro
Chelsea Apartments, has preserved the class day and commencement programs,
newspaper clippings of the events, and one verse of the class poem she de-livered
at the closing exercises. Recognizing the Soule College claim to
93
have been founded in 1825 as the "Female Academy", Miss Riggs recited:
For 93 years has Soule stood here
Watching the simrise from year to year
Facing the rain, the wind, the snow
Seeing the seasons come and go.
Her classmates were Jean Marie Faircloth, Ollie Mae Harrell, Mary lytle
Kelton, and Josephine Ramsey. Miss Ramsey was the class valedictorian. Miss
Faircloth gave the salutatory. Miss Harrell was the class historian, and Miss
Kelton, the author of the class will.
The Murfreesboro News Banner reporter wrote;
"The five beautiful girls in geirments of spotless white . . .
occupied the center of the stage, Mrs, Uyde and Miss Hopkins, the
guiding geniuses of the school, sat at the left front, and Mr. R.
W, Vickers, master of ceremonies, and the Rev, H, J, Mikell of
Nashville, were on the right front."
There is little review of the Reverend Mikell 's address, other than the
statement that it was of "high literary merit whilst presenting a lesson of
great value". Musical numbers by Mrs, Gertrude Richards Schumacher and Mrs.
Will C, Hoffman "gave great delight and occasioned prolonged applause". The
invocation was by Rev, G, Dallas Smith,
The closing remarks by Mrs, Hyde and Miss Hopkins occupied lengthy coverage in
the Murfreesboro News Banner, Mrs, Ifyde thanked all the friends and patrons
of the school, "For more than half a century Soule has closed her doors until
the fall&#8212;but on March 26th we went out and closed the doors of that grand,
historic old building. Not one stain has ever been upon the fair name. Here's
to the daughters of Soule, may your lanps shine bright as you shed your light .
, , . May the Master shower you with His love", she stated.
Miss Hopkins called attention to the graduates heritage and touched on
the troubled war years when she said, "Class of 1917, you v,lll enter the
greatest University in the world&#8212;a University that knows no nationality,
no race, no creed, I bid you be strong, I would not wish you all sunshine
94
and brightness, for that would lessen your appreciation for the fulness of
joy. Shun not the struggle, take it, 'tis God's gift! Be strong in the
power of his might, and all will be well with you".
Two tender and responsive sentiments live among the stories of this
graduation. Oae is a newspaper story of a note penned to a sheaf of roses
presented to Jean Marie Faircloth that read, "To Jean on her first real
turn in the road. May she continue as she has ever been, a comfort and
dependence to her mother,"
There is the episode story of the member of the class who had no near
relative to share her graduation Joy. A Murfreesboro resident sent her a
bovquet. The denouement occured many years later when this woman received
a present mailed from Neiman-Marcvis in Dallas. Such a gift continued to
come each year vaxtil this Murfreesboro Soule aluiana, who had remembered a
girl who was graduating without the traditional roses, died only a few
years ago.
According to Barbara Prentice, a librarian at Morris Harvey College,
the I9I6-I7 catalog lists both Mrs. I^e and Miss Hopkins as members of the
faculty at the Charleston, West Virginia institution. This sviggests that
the two women left Soule College in I9I6 instead of 1917 as indicated by
Murfreesboro records and the memory of local people. This same catalog
credits Mrs. Q^de as holding the A.B. degree from Soule College and having
"had courses at Peabody College". She taught logic and history at Morris
Harvey until 1920.
Miss Hppklns also came to Morris Harvey, according to the same catalog,
in 1916 and taught Bible and preparatory English until 1920.
Dr. Leonard Riggleman, president of Morris Harvey from 1932 to I964.,
stated in January 1978 that he remembered Mrs. Hyde and Miss Hopkins when
he was a student at Morris Harvey. He recalled that in the 1930 's the two
Lasv Classes of joule College vere held in this b-oixiing locatea on
Ch.-irch Strict in the spring semester of 1917.
Jean Marie Fairclotii
(MacArthur) as she
appeared in a Soule
College dramatic pro-duction.
96
women were teaching in a small school at Paintsvllle, Kentucky, called Mayo
College.
Soule College had a very active alumnae organization. As early as 1873,
The Christian Advocate reported that:
"At four o'clock a large assembly of the college alumnae
met in the college for their annual reunion. It was like review-ing
one's youth to meet with the happy bsmd of former classmates,
to witness attachment for their beloved Alma Mater. A beautiful
address was read by Miss Maggie Muirhead (listed in Frank Bass's
history as a member of the 1870 class)."
A complete list of gradviates was preserved by the Alumnae Association
through the class of 1910. Louise Richmond Freeman has supplied the names
of the class of 1915, of which she was a member. Other members of the 1915
class were Sophia May Bell, Hilda Margaret Creech, Susie Mae Harrell, Ora
Lee Haynes, Bessie Lee Hoover, Mamie Mullins, Virginia Patience, and Remina
Woods.
Sue Gill Riggs lists other members of the 1917 class as Jean Marie
Faircloth, Ollie Mae Harrell, Mary Lytle Kelton, and Josephine Ramsey. Miss
Riggs report card dated May 21, 1917 was signed by Mrs. A. B. Hyde and lists
grades in Bible 92, ethics 94-, history 90, grammar 98, trigonometry 83, and
French 96.
In comparison with modern college requirements, it is difficult to eval-uate
just how much Soule deserved the designation of a "College". Certainly
its coiirses included some coiirses still measured as college credit by modern
standards. In a 1916 advertisement, the school offered courses ranging "from
primary through one and one half years of college work" . According to the
evaluation by N. C. Beasley, dean emeritus at Middle Tennessee State Univer-sity,
Soule credits for transfer varied from year to year vrith individual
students. Students were accepted at Peabody College and Randolph-Macon Col-lege.
At least one other institution accepted credits up to two years
following completion of one year acceptable resident at the transfer school.
01 1909
Br K^n when this piec-ore was taken, the Fria&amp;ry Glass raembers had
ohan.'i^ed frojr. high button shoes ^ uiack cotton stockings and hair
ribbon bows to white u-nifors! dresses, the appearance of tnodlsh whit
stockiugSj ar;.,; Bustei- Browrs hair b&lt;:jbs.
98
The changing scene in Murfreesboro is dramatically revealed in reading
the yearbook advertisements in the Gleaners of the first decade of the
twentieth century. Professional men were not adverse to complimenting the
young ladies of Soule with free legal advice, dentists provided the best of
care, and the "Joys of walking" were encouraged by shoe store merchants.
"Early to bed and early to rise, mind your own business and advertise"
was an encouraging admonition introducing the advertising section of the
yearbooks
.
Sam Nirshbnjnner. Hackmen advertised rubber-tired busses that met all
trains. For those not sophisticated enough to ride the rubber-tired busses,
there was "livery stable" accomodations by H. H. Good, Butler and Company,
the Murfreesboro Livery Con^Miny, and Sam Hunt, whom one could call at Phone
10 or 100 and "save a dime".
There were mercantile establishments and professional people whose
names are still seen around town. Among those were Ridley and Richardson,
attorneys; J. H. Grichlow, insurance; W. R. Bell, jeweler and optometrist;
Woodfin and Moore, fxmeral directors; Leatherman ' s Women's Wear; A. L.
Smith, druggists; Christy and Huggins, coal and Coca Cola. This firm
promised to "please you winter or summer".
Someii^at unusual for a girl'p boarding school was a full page suggest-ing
the use of Ox Fertilizers for sale by Spain and Hudson. Misses E and M
Earthman used old English type to persuade the students to "Home Here and Buy
Yo\ir Gradviation Hat". E. H. Tatum had a oon^setitor ' s plea to "buy your
sunmer frocks for seashore and summer resorts".
The attorneys who offered legal services included E. H. Hancock, Ridley
and Richardson, 2. T. Caaon, Jesse W. Sparks, A. L. Todd. E. fl. Hancock was
also aunong the attorneys whose announcements graced the Gleaner . D. E. Logan,
W. W. Jones, and L. H. Tate were dentists whose advnrtisements were listed.
99
The Jordan Hotel with F. W. Miles as proprietor advertised rooms for
$2.00 per day, with bath $2.50.
Vickers Drug Store advertised Joy's cut flowers, while the Kerr Dnig
Store suggested it had the "best soda foTint in town" and urged the use of
Geny's cut flowers. R. F. Overall appealed to the girls to buy "Hay, Oats,
Corn and Bran" while shipping "timothy, clover and millet hay". Perklns-
Crichlow suggested one call phone 3 for "custom sawing".
Covington &amp; Conpany paid for a full page in the Gleaner to boast that
it was a "one price house" where one could select from the stock "larger
than any before shown in Murfreesboro."
Among the other champions of the Soule yearbook staff were J. T.
Rather, cotton, lumber, livestock; J. G. Smith and E. M. Littler, men's
wear; W. T. Gerhardt, merchant tailor; Clayton and Draper, fine shoes;
I^le and Hanson, produce house; Liveley's Art Studio; Frank Farris, staple
and fancy groceries; Hooper Shoe Coinpany; Henry Fleming of the Gilt Edge
Grocery; Home Jo\irnal Printers; C^_H. Byrn, hardware H. H. Morton, real
estate; Logan and King, real estate and insvirance; J. M. Naylor and Ellis
Rucker, grocers; Lewis Maney, confectioner; Blumenthal and Becker, jewelers;
Butler, Hooper Co., men's furnishings; Baker Lumber Co; E. C. Cannon and
Son, dry goods; J. B. Matthews, grocer; H. C. Turner, grocer; W. Goldstein,
dry goods; Spain and Hudson, hardware; A, G. and W. H. Tongjkins, poultry;
Avent's Drug Store; W. G. Batey, insxiranoe; K5-ng and Ragland, wholesale
groceries; Cem^ibell and Gannaway's Home Steam laundry; J. B. and J. W.
Gannaway, groceries; Ransom Brothers, millers; Baker Lumber and Manufactiiring;
Knox, Overall and Co., furnitvire and leather goods; E. H. Tatum, dry goods;
P. R. Miller, funeral directors, Cohn's Cafe; and Mrs. W. H. Haynes, milliner.
The First National Bank listed deposits at $5,000,000 with F. 0. Watts, pres-ident.
Other officers were D. S. Williams, vice-president; E. A. Lindsey,
2nd vice-president; J. M. Ford, advisor; Randell Currell, cashier; Frank
100
K. Houston, assistant cashier, and J. R. Johnson, assistant cashier.
The students were urged to visit the "swellest refreshment parlor In
the South" where they could get "dainty lunches, candies, and ice cream"
at the Ocean. Apparently the chief rival of the Ocean was the Gilt Edge
Grocery where Henry Fleming insisted, "College Girls can buy something
good to eat". Lewis Maney challenged both with his suggestion that
telephone orders wo\ild receive prompt attention for "table delicacies and
everything good to eat", inclxiding Lawney's chocolates and bon-bons. He
also had two phones to answer calls I
There were numerous Nashville firms represented in The Gleaner ad-vertiser.
The Methodist Publishing House apparently supplied the books and
stationery for the school. B. H. Shief Jewelry; Parrish ($2.98) Shoes
located on 4.21 Union Street; Phillips and Buttorff; Starr Piano Co.,
Royal Shoe Co. ($2.50), 314 Union Street; Ambrose Printing Co.; Standard
Printing Co.; Jaccard Solid Gold Jewelry of St. Louis nay have furnished
designs in jewelry and stationery for clubs and literary societies, as
well as programs and commencement invitations for the college.
Cumberland Telephone and Telegraph Company took a full page to insist
on everyone getting Cumberland Telephone service. "We have exchanges in
every important city in southern Indiana and Illinois and the entire states
of Tennessee, Kentucky, Mississippi, and Louisana", according to the
advertisement.
In his thesis, Frank Bass paid tribute to the "long existence which
had influenced the lives of nany fine people". Bass concludes, "Though
the buildings were torn down, the property sold (to the Murfreesboro School
Board for the location of the old Central High School Building), the memory
of Soule College still lives in the hearts of many, and they like to join
in the Toast to Soule".
staff members of the 1910 Gleaner posed in a way that a glimpse of the
study hall wall with its art work is revealed.
w
SOULE COLLEGE
OArcgaadneimzyedby16M2i5sseass Mo"Trhye&amp; FNeamnaclye
Banks. &amp; teaching rhetoric, phi-losophy,
belles-lettres, palntlnq.
needlework 6 music. It was Improved
In 1652 &lt;&#167;&gt;. named for Bishop Soulc
of the ME Church. South. It closed
during the Civil War. when Its
bulldlnqs were damaged. Reopening
thereafter. It closed finally in I9ld.
I hi
The Tennessee Historical Association marker on the north boundary of
the Middle Tennessee Electric Membership Corporation marks the Soule
College site in 1978.
102
Here's to the days we've spent at Soule,
Here's to the days to come,
Here's to the hours we've spent in work,
Here's to the hours of fun;
Here's to her fame through all the earth,
Spreading from pole to pole,
Here's to the College we all love best.
Here's to our dear "Old Soule".
103
Bibliography
Soule Female College . 1930, Master of Arts thesis, Peabody College
by Frank Bass.
Minutes . M. E. Church South Annual Conference . 1850 to 1858.
Reports of the Commissioner of Education . Washington, D. C. Printing
Office.
Reprinted material from the Louisville and Nashville Christian
Advocate .
Murfreesboro Home Journal. 1905-1916.
Murfreesboro News-Banner . 1930.
Soule College Catalogs, 1899-1901, 1904, 1910, 1915.
History of Rutherford County. C. C. Sims.
Rutherford County, Tennessee Registers Office Books, 22, 30, 43, 48, 59.
History of Murfreesboro . C. C. Henderson.
The Shadow and the Web . Mary Allerton.
True Detective &gt;fagazine . Jfeiy 25, 1940.
The Gleaner . Soule College yearbook, 1910-1911.
Three Sisters in Black . Norman Zierold.
Reprints Newark, New Jersey, Evening Star transcripts of trial, 1910-11.
Original materials and interviews contributed by Miss Catherine Clark,
Mrs. Leiper, Sue Richardson Freeman, Mrs. Annie Mary Beasley,
Mrs. J. D. McFarlin, Mrs. Jean Faircloth hkcArthur, Miss Sue Riggs,
Miss Bertha Licker, Mrs. Ethel L. Haney, Mrs. Esther L. Maxwell
in the form of letters, report cards, diplomas, pictures and
personal recollections.
The Aliunni Office of Morris-Harvey College.
Photographs by Gene H. Sloan, Dr. Bealer Smotherman.
</dc:description>
<dc:description>Describes the history and contributions of Soule College, located in Murfreesboro from 1854 to 1909</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.) -- History; Soule, Joshua, 1781-1867; Universities and colleges -- Tennessee</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Soule College</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>91 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-24; mt2011-02-28</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication11ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/57</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>