<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>The Nashville and Chattanooga Railroad through Rutherford County 1845 - 1872</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Johns Sr., Thomas N.</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 5</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1975</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1840-1849; 1850-1859; 1860-1869; 1870-1879</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>The Nashville and Chattanooga Railroad
Through Rutherford County 1845-1872
by
Thomas N. Johns Sr.
"The matter of more interest to our readers generally,
connected with the celebration of the opening of the rail-road
to Murfreesborough, would be the speeches of Messrs.
Ready and Stevenson. Although present on the occasion, we
made no effort to sketch these speeches, and unless the
speakers furnish a copy of their remarks f we shall not be
able to gratify the public curiosity to see them in print.
We suppose fifteen hundred persons passed over the
road from Nashville to Murfreesborough, and the citizens of
Rutherford and the adjoining counties were out in large
numbers. The crowd was generally estimated at ten thousand.
It was certainly a very large and a very happy one. The
barbecue was ample and excellent and the arrangements were
so judiciously made and executed that all were accommodated,
without confusion or crowding. Murfreesborough did herself
high honor in the preparations for feasting so large a crowd,
and we are sure that her hospitalities will long be remembered
by the citizens of Nashville.
-2-
It was a great day for both towns and for the enter-prising
gentlemen to whose herculean labors we owe the
success of the great work of connecting Nashville with the
Seaboard cities of the South. A tenth of the effort expended
by Col. Stevenson and his colleagues of the Board of Directors
in getting up this road, will secure the construction of any
other work in which Nashville has an interest. Both for
itself and for its influence we regard this road as infinitely
the most important enterprise in which the citizens of our
State have ever engaged. In honor and in profit may the
stockholders reap a reward commensurate with the benefits
they have conferred on the State."
The memorable event was the partial conclusion of years
of effort by Vernon K. Stevenson, a visionary, who dreamed
of a railroad stretching from the Northeast to the Southern
Seaboard Cities with the center of the system being Middle
Tennessee. His determination, endurance, and salesmanship
created the Nashville and Chattanooga Railroad Company
which in turn stirred the economic development of Middle
Tennessee and especially Rutherford County.
This article will attempt to postulate the role that
Rutherford County and Rutherford Countians played in the
development of the Nashville and Chattanooga Railroad and a
few of the events and incidents which occurred between 1845
and 1872 in and around Rutherford County. The N &amp; C Railroad
was the first bona fide railroad in the State of Tennessee,
and did not come under the so called land grant railroad
-3-
2 legislation. The N &amp; C was never in the hands of receiver-
. 3 ship because of the strong leadership and direction of its
three presidents, Vernon K. Stevenson 1848-1864, Michael
Burns 1864-1868, and Edmund W. Cole 1868-1873.^
In the early 1800' s, the land in Middle Tennessee was
newly settled and sparsely populated, and sufficient trans-portation
was provided by the river system (Cumberland,
Tennessee, Ohio and Mississippi Rivers) and stage roads.
However, by the early 1830 's the situation had changed.
Middle Tennessee's population had increased, more farmland
had been opened, and there were more products for market and
more markets for manufactured products.
The idea of a railroad through Nashville was first
presented, in 1835, to Nashville by Robert Y. Hayne of South
Carolina who proposed a route from Memphis through Nashville
to Knoxville but somehow remained only an idea. Two years
later William Armor, a resident of Memphis, proposed a
railroad from the Southeast to the Northeast, but the economic
depression of 1837 stymied any such venture and thus the
idea of the railroad remained dormant for almost ten years.
About 1831, a young man, V. K. Stevenson, moved to Nashville
and set up business as a merchant. He married well and made
many friends in Nashville as well as Murfreesboro and Ruther-ford
County. Stevenson was moved by the idea of a railroad
and realized as a merchant that a railroad would enhance the
marketable products of the area, as well as bring products
into the area.^
-4-
Some of the predominant reasons for the existence of a
railroad from Nashville to Chattanooga in 1844 were as
follows: (1) The eastern seaboard cities of Charleston and
Savannah offered ready markets for products and access to
other markets through these ports. Nashville and Middle
Tennessee products included tobacco, cotton, hogs, cattle,
mules, horses, wool, brandy and whiskey; also, 3 rolling
mills, 21 blast furnaces, and 11 forges, all totaling almost
13 million dollars per year. (2) The Western and Atlantic
Railroad owned and operated by the State of Georgia was
building a railroad north to Chattanooga from Atlanta scheduled
to be completed in the early 1850 's. (3) The Louisville
and Nashville Railroad was formalizing plans for their road
to Nashville. (4) A fast and efficient mode of passenger
transportation to the east coast was needed since stage
coaches required 3 1/2 days for the journey to the east
7
coast and 14 days to Philadelphia. (5) Accessible entry
into the deposits of coal in the Cumberland Mountains was
needed. (6) The overall economic development of Middle
Tennessee was urgently needed.
V. K. Stevenson enlisted the support of his friends,
James Overton of Nashville and James Whiteside of Chattanooga,
for the development of a railroad. Both men traveled about
making speeches advocating the building of the N &amp; C railroad.
The local newspapers of Nashville and surrounding towns,
through the urging of these men, added their support for
the N &amp; C. Also many small towns, particularly Murfreesboro,
supported the idea for economic purposes. Charleston, South
SnvRf^t
Tr/vi-S/J-^dej?^
'Ailv
^^/
//'
./.
^T09
//et/R^ QoeQCf^L
\ t /
&#171; eM' C)&#171;t'^^
It
.
i +
3 Ridlcf
1'
r.
;^y^ I &lt;f ,^^.^ -.^.c&#8212;.---
1/
&gt;k ^/M iff/ocfr^^^
^;\//^-Qd^/?'MA'^, &lt;&lt;
^S^ ;?AK-^ -s^
\A
If Tcro/*f/-s ^M|^ J,J .W#C/N^
w.H.0'Re9e&#187;y M
K^^.Ofl/vK-s
J. /^/c/e^ &gt;g^
r&gt;4}c;jLi u^a
-5-
Carolina, and other seaboard cities encouraged the building
of the N &amp; C. The State of Georgia and the Georgia Railroad
and Banking Company pledged their money and support for the
2 Nashville and Chattanooga Railroad Company.
Thus with much needed support and encouragement, the
Tennessee Legislature lobbied by all these interest, plus
many citizens, voted and approved the organization of a rail-road
from Nashville to Chattanooga.
After the charter was granted on 11 December 1845 by the
State of Tennessee, machinery was set into motion almost
immediately. The first Commissioners appointed were: John M.
Bass, John M. Hill, Francis B. Fogg, Andrew Ewing, A. 0. P.
Nicholson, V. K. Stevenson, John Bell, Willoughby Williams,
William Nichol, S. D. Morgan, Joseph T. Elliston, Joseph W.
Q
Horton, James A. Porter, James Overton and John Shelby. The
Commissioners were instructed to open Subscription Books
for the purpose of listing 60,000 shares at $25.00 each.
The power of eminent domain was granted the N &amp; C plus a
selection of a right of way 100 feet wide. Also the right
of slave ownership was granted. In addition the N &amp; C was
exempted from taxes on its building and property for twenty
years. But the most important task was the selction of a
feasible route from Nashville to Chattanooga.
V. K. Stevenson, on one of his many trips to Charleston,
engaged John Edgar Thomson, Resident Engineer of Georgia
Railroad and Banking Company, to survey a route for the N &amp; C
and report his findings to the Commissioners. Theodore S.
Garrett, C. E. , also of the Georgia Railroad and Banking
-6-
Company, undertook the actual instrumental survey of the
route. Thomson and Company commenced the survey at Chattanooga
some time in 1846 but since the terrain was rugged and
unchartered the survey took six months or more to complete.
By 1847 the Commissioners had Thomson's preliminary
survey and report. In the report he described the route
through Rutherford County as the least obstacled course on
the line. Thomson estimated that the line would be 152 miles
long, actual mileage was 152.6, with almost thirty miles in
Rutherford County. The line enters Rutherford County about
Mile 14 near LaVergne in the northeast section passing
through Murfreesboro and exits near the town of Fosterville,
Mile 45, in the southeastern section.
Thomson estimated the cost of the N &amp; C to be $2,810,000
with the actual cost being about $2,700,000. He even suggested
that the track and iron be made within the State thus creat-ing
jobs and the development of the resources of the State.
Unfortunately all rail and accessories were bought in England
and transported to New Orleans by ship where they were
transferred to barge for the final journey to Nashville.
John Thomson later became President of the Pennsylvania
Railroad. He took no compensation except for expenses for
the survey of the N &amp; C, because he realized the construction
of the road was vital to the Nation as well as Tennessee.
About 1854, the Board of Directors issued Thomson stock in
the company for his services.
-7-
With the survey report in hand, the Commissioners
solicited stock subscriptions from citizens and townships.
The City of Nashville agreed to $500,00 in stock, the town of
Murfreesborough $30,000 (a large sum for a town of only
2,000 people), the town of Shelbyville $50,000, the City of
Charleston $500,000, the Town of Winchester $25,000, the
Georgia Railroad and Banking Company $250,000 and bonds
guaranteed by the State for $500,000, plus individual sub-scriptions
all totaling $2,588,450.
Therefore, on 24 January 1848, the first stockholders
meeting of the Nashville and Chattanooga Railroad Company
was held at the City Hall in Nashville, and the corporate
organization was completed. Officers and a Board of Directors
were elected:
President - V. K. Stevenson Chief Engineer - James H. Grant
Treasurer - Orville Ewing Superintendent of Transportation
H. I. Anderson
Board of Directors
Vernon K. Stevenson James C. Moore)
Alex Allison William Spence) Rutherford Co.
John M. Bass Jeremiah Cleveland)
Francis B. Fogg John T. Neil ) Bedford Co.
Edwin Ewing William S. Waterson-Coff ee Co.
A. O. P. Nicholson) Peter S. Deckard-Franklin Co.
Samuel D. Morgan ) Davidson Co. A. M. Rutledge-Grundy Co.
James A. Whiteside-Hamilton Co.
The following Rutherford Countians owned 1975 shares of
stock in the N &amp; C with almost 12% of the voting power:
Alexander, J. D. Eaglton, Wm. Jamison, H. D.
Alexander, A. M. Edmundson, Jno. Kerby, James M.
Allison, Wra. Espy, Robt. Kerr, G. W.
Alexander, A. G. Elder, Joshua Kimbro, Joseph
Alexander, M. H. Fletcher, M. L. Killough, James
-8-
Alexander, Jesse
Anderson, Samuel
Alexander, Daniel
Abernathy, J. J.
&amp; wife
Blackman, Alfred
Bowman, Ben E.
Baird, Josiah M.
Baird, J. P.
Brittain, Jno.
Bowman, Daniel
Butler, W. S.
Baird, Jno.
Brown , Thos
.
Baugh, Jno. A.
Brashear, Jesse
Black, L. P.
Brown , Jno . , Jr
.
Bone, James
Bell, James, Estate
Beaty, Geo.
Burton, Hardy M.
Beaty, Benj
Binford, J. W.
Bar , Jane
Bryant, Charlotte
Burk, Francis L.
Brown , Jno
.
Butler, T. 0.
Brown, W. T.
Christy, S. B.
Conley, J. W.
Carlton, Kinton
Childress, Jno. W.
Cannon, Alanson
Cranor, Thos. B.
Covington, E. I.
Claud, F. N. , Jr.
Childress, Mary E.
Corporation of
Murfreesboro
Cowan, V. D.
Clark, Sarah
Crocker, Eugenie
Clay, Green
Conley, W. M.
Crosswaite, G. D.
Davis, Luckett
Dromgoole, E. D.
Dejarnett, D. M.
Davis, A. P.
Davis, J. W.
Dejarnett, James G.
Edwards , Thomas
Foster, James
Floyd, Rich'd. J.
Fulks, Jno.
Fletcher
Farris, Chas. B.
Grant, James H.
Garmnay , Wm
.
Gilliam, Jesse
Garner, Lewis
Gregory , Henry
Gilmore, J. D.
Gilmore, Peter
Gooch, Eliza A.
(Guardian)
Henry, Rebecca L.
Henderson, Jas. F.
Henderson, G. T.
House, Margrate
House, Ambrose
Hunt, W.
House, Geo. W.
Hill, Jno.
Hord, Thomas
House, Jno. C.
Henry, F.
Harris, Jno. C.
Huggins, J.
Huggins , Jonathan
Hall, Jno.
Hancock, E. D.
Hart, Thos. M.
Hall, Wm.
Hartwell, J. A.
Henderson, A. G.
Huggins, J.&amp;W.S.
Jarratt, Thompson
Jarratt, Jno. J.
Jarratt, Thos. S.
Jetton, James S.
Jetton, Rufus B.
Jones, Wm.
Johns, J. B.
Jetton, Lewis
Johns, Paul V.
Jordon, Blount
Jones, Jno.
Johns, R. V.
Johnson, D. H.
Job, E. C.
Jones, E. H.
Jamison, Thos. H.
Jetton, Maria
Jones, Scisley S.
King, Elias
Kerby, J. H.
Keeble, E. A.
Lamb , Thomas
Leiper &amp; Menefee
Lowe , Wm
.
Lytle, E. F.
Lawrence, James
Ledbetter, Wm.
Lytle, W. F.
Lyon, James S.
Landsburger, Moses
McCullough, R. D.
McFadden, Will R.
Martin, Kno.
Martin, Wm.
Mathews, E. L.
Maxey, Philip
McFadden, Sam
McLean, A. H.
McLean, C. G.
McCreary, A.
Mitchell, Daniel
Marable, Benj
.
Mankin, Jno.
Maxey, Joel
Mathews, Wm. R.
Miller, Alfred
Murphy , Jno
.
Maney, James
Murfree, M. B.
Minter, Jno. M.
Mason, P. M.
May, Frederick
Minter, Jeptha
Mullins Jno.
Morton, George C.
Marr, James A.
McElroy, A. M.
Miller, S. G.
Nance, J. N.
Nelson, A. W.
North, Theodrick
North, A.
Norman , Henry
Newman , E . D
.
Newsom, Thos. H.
Newsom, Jno. F.
Northway, H. K.
Oden, Jno. A.
Overall, Robt.
Overall, Asbury D.
Owen , Thomas
Osborne, Harvey
Overall , Sophia
Overall, Sophia &amp;
Mary J.
Peebles, Isham R.
Peebles, George
Phelps, Asa C.
Powell, Jno.
Powell, R. H.
Parker , Nehemiah
Powell, Thos. P.
Quarles, Jno. W.
(Trustee Ruth. Co,
Ready, Chas. Sr.
Ransom, H. D.
Rucker , James
Reed, James
Reed, Wm. A.
Ress, A. M.
Rooker, Wm.
Ransom, Elizabeth
Ransom, R. P.
Ransom, Wm. A.
Ross, Alfred
Rucker, S.R. ,Sr.
Rather, Martha A.
Ransom, B. F.
Rucker, Sm. R.
Rucker, Wm. B.
Ransom, Jno.
Ransom, David
Ransom, Sam'l.
Ransom, Benj
Ransom, Benj
.
Ridley, Moses
Ridley, Henry
(Estate)
Rucker, Joseph B.
Ridley, Eliza.
Rucker, Benj
.
Ransom, George
Ransom, Ann E.
Ross, James
Runnel, P. R.
Rucker, Susan C.
Rakes, R.
Ridley, B. L.
Smith, George W.
) Sharp, W. J.
Swann, Moses
Spence, Sarah
Sikes, Jesse
Smith, D.D.
Stroop, Jno.
Smith, Jackson
Summers, T. H.
Smith, W.H. (Whig)
Spence, D.H.C.
Smith, Wm. M.
Smith, W. Hunter
Smith, Joseph
Smith, W.H. (Dem.)
Smith, Jno. E.
(Estate)
Smith, Benj
.
Smith, Swinfield L.
Smith, Elizabeth L.
Smith, Elizabeth J.
Smith, Elizabeth M,
Snell, Robt.
Smith, A. J.
B.
H.
Stone, Wm.
Suttle, Ellis
Tray lor, Joel
Traylor, H. F.
Trimble, Joseph
Tucker, Silas
Thomas, Wilson
Thompson, George
Talley, P. C.
Tucker, P. C.
Wade , Levi
Watkins, S.
Ward, B.
Wright, W.
Watkins, Joseph
Wade, H. &amp; R.
Wade, O. H.
Watkins, Wilson L.
Walden, Jno.
Welch, Thos. (Estate)
Wade, Mordecai B.
Williams, Elisha
White, R. H.
White, B. G.
Weather ford, J. Q.
White, R. M.
White, W. N.
Wetherspoon, A. B.
Work, Jno. L.
Wharcy, L. C.
Williams, E.
Young, Hiram
Yandell, L. P.
Actual construction of the N &amp; C started at one of the
most unlikely spots along the route in August of 1848,
this being the tunnel through the Cumberland Mountains near
Cowan, Tennessee. The tunnel nearly half a mile long was
entirely through solid rock with approaches on either side
of the same material. The contract for the tunnel was let to
Thomas C. Bates on August 1, 1848. As work began on each end
of the tunnel, three shafts 11 x 7 feet were sunk 170 feet
-10-
deep from the top of the mountain and thus eight points of
the tunnel could be worked simultaneously 24 hours a day.
Slave labor and Irish emigrants composed the majority of
the work crews. The tools used for excavation were hard
drills, sledge hammers, picks, shovels, ropes, pulleys and
wheelbarrows. Light for working was provided by smoking
torches and the explosive used was black powder. The tunnel
was completed on 22 February 1851 when the Crow Creek heading
of the tunnel was blown. A large celebration was held in
Winchester to commemorate the completion of the tunnel. It
is said workmen, railroad officials and area residents
walked through the trackless tunnel carrying their own
5&amp;11
candles.
Actual letting of sections began on 20 December 1848
when thirty miles were let; 13 miles at the Nashville end
(to the Rutherford County line) , and the remainder in Bedford
County and in Alabama, terminating at the Tennessee River.
It was not until a more detailed survey by James Grant,
Resident Engineer, and the Engineering Department, that
other sections were let. On 19 June, at Murfreesboro, the
section from Fly's curve (Kimbro mile 13) to Murfreesboro
and from Murfreesboro to section 57 (to the Duck River) and
four sections between the Garrison and Barren Forks of the
Duck River were let, all totaling 45 miles. The work was
let to stockholders of the N &amp; C with few exceptions. A
brief description of the line from the Rutherford - Davidson
County Line to Murfreesboro follows:
-11-
"The located line after passing Fly's curve
to the left pursues a straight course for nearly
3 miles crossing the Murfreesboro Turnpike about
one quarter of a mile east of James Buchanan's,
thence crossing the Jefferson Turnpike near
William Davis' Horse saw-mill. From this point
the line runs perfectly straight 13 1/4 miles to
Murfreesboro, crossing Stewarts Creek about one-third
of a mile above Hardeman's Mills, and
recrossing the Murfreesboro Turnpike two miles
from town
.
As far as can be determined the route was divided into
152 sections with one section per mile. The section or sections
from Smyrna to Wade were let to Silas Tucker who owned much
12
of the land where Smyrna is today. He sold most of the
land to the N &amp; C and gave a plot of ground supposedly
13
for the public square for the town.
A notable individual, James Grant, who was born in Maine,
educated in the East and a civil engineer was working for
the Georgia Railroad and Banking Company with J. E. Thomson
when Stevenson visited the Georgia Company. Apparently
Stevenson was impressed with James Grant for he became the
first Chief Resident Engineer of the N &amp; C. James Grant had
worked six years with the Georgia Railroad and Banking Company
before he came to Middle Tennessee in 1848. He was charged
with actual location and construction of the N &amp; C Railroad
-12-
from Nashville to Chattanooga. To be near the center of
the line for supervisory purposes he chose a community,
Christiana, 42 miles from Nashville.
From Christiana he directed all construction, super-structures,
ties and rails, buildings and bridges of the
14
N &amp; C. It is said he named all the stations from Nashville
to Chattanooga including the town of Christiana. In the
. . 15
early 1850' s, he married and built his home in Christiana.
His home, which he designed and built within 1/4 of a mile
of the N &amp; C line, still stands. In addition, he was the
agent at Christiana and his wife opened the first Post
Office and store at Christiana. His descendents still
operate the Post Office at Christiana. In 1859, he left the
N &amp; C and worked for the Atlanta and Jacksonville Railroad
and subsequently he was Chief Engineer of the New Orleans,
Jackson, and Great Northern Railroad. After the war he
returned to the N &amp; C as Chief Engineer with his office at
Christiana.
Very little has been written or known about James Grant
(a third cousin to President U. S. Grant) , although his con-tribution
to Middle Tennessee and Rutherford County is
immeasurable. Today he lies buried with his wife behind
the Presbyterian Church in Christiana; however, there are no
markers identifying the graves.
As the line began to develop, points along the line
17
acquired names. Starting in Nashville the points are:
-13-
Nashville
Glencliff
Curry
Asylvim
Antioch
Mt. View
Kimbro
Lavergne
Smyrna
Wade
Florence
Russell
Murfreesboro
Winstead
Rucker
Christiana
Fosterville
Bell Buckle
Wartrace
Haley
Cortner
Normandy
Tullahoma
Estill Springs
Decherd
Cowan
T. C. Junction
Sherwood
Anderson
Bass, Alabama
Stevenson, Ala.
Bolivar, Ala.
Bridgeport, Ala.
Shell Mound, Tn.
Ladds
Vulcan
Whiteside
Etna Mines
Hooker, Ga.
Wauhatchie
Lookout
Cravens
Chattanooga
(Rutherford Co.)
Mile (Davidson Co.)
5
6
8
10
12
14
16
20
22
26
28
32
36
38
42
45
51
55
58
61
62
69
77
82
87
(Bedford Co.)
96
102
106
112
117
123
129
130
134
137
141
145
147
149
151
The 1850 Census lists Irish Emigrants and citizens of
18
Rutherford County working for the railroad.
Irish Laborours
Daniel Raden
Robert Wiseman
Jno. Cochran
Jno . Newman
Patrick Fitzgerald
John Loorney
John Hurley
Wm. Hurt
Thomas Burns
John Clancey
Lawrence Riley
John Face
-14-
Daniel Creden John Cannon James Hope
Wm. Stuart Timothy Godfrey V. G. McDonal
Arthur Mallory William Fin Patrick Armstrong
Nicholas Murray John Smith
Rutherford Countians
Jno. Gramps Superstructor R. R.
J. Hezekiah Oliver Engineer R. R.
G. W. Becton Railroad Contractor
Richd. G. Buchanan Overseer R. R.
F. Henry R. R. Contractor
John Sullivan Bedford David Peter Mason
Wm. F. Youree Wm. R. Davis Joseph Hays
Wm. Johnson Isaac Rouse John Armstrong
Adon Zumbro John Ramsey Jno. Canada
James Shepherd S. W. Belt Geo. Foreman
In 1849, V. K. Stevenson as President of the N &amp; C,
traveled to England and negotiated a contract for iron rails,
chairs and spikes for the line at 2&lt;: per pound. I believe
this rail to be the old "U" rail, or commonly known at that
1&#176;
time as bridge rail, weighing 80 tons per mile. The rail
recommended by John E. Thomson was the "U" rail weighing
100 tons per mile. The "U" rail was laid on cedar ties.
(These ties were cedar poles about six feet long.) The
rails were set five feet apart which was the standard guage
at that time.
In a letter to M. Burns, President N &amp; C Railroad, on
May 4, 1866, from James Grant, a description of the rail and
roadbed follows : "When the track was laid originally
the joints of the rails were held up by cedar stringers
(7x7 inches 20 ft. long) the rail joints being in the
centre of the stringers it was impossible for them to go
down unless the stringers broke (which they did not) and that
-15-
was one of the Great Advantages the Co. derived from the
stringers. We had no trouble in keeping up the joints on
the mud road bed ! The other great advantage derived from
continuous bearing timbers, was saving of the wear &amp; tear
of rails&#8212;by giving a uniform and elastic support to them,
they were not unduly strained, crooked and battered up at
the ends, and the "U" rails have lasted (with all the unneces-sary
&amp; fast running over them) twice as long as they would,
if they had been laid on crossties at fissures&#8212;where we did
lay them on crossties, on the Chattanooga end, we found out
by experience 15 years ago, that it was impossible to keep
14
the track up without rock ballast !
"
H. I. Anderson, who owned land in Rutherford County
where Florence is today, was the Super of all superstructures
(grading and leveling) from Nashville to Murfreesboro. Most
of the work was completed by a negro work force.
The "U" rail from the Tennessee River to Chattanooga
was laid on crossties, and the rails weighed approximately
100 tons per mile. The "U" rail from Nashville to the
Tennessee River was laid on stringers. Most of the "U" rail
lasted until about 1863 when a Federal work force rebuilt
the road.
The bridges across Hurrican Creek, Harts Branch,
Stewart's Creek, Overall Creek and the two Stone's River
Bridges were all constructed of cedar except for some white
oak stringers. The cedar was acquired from land throughout
Middle Tennessee.
-16-
By December 1851, many freight and passenger stations
had been built. A freight and passenger house combined
(third class) was erected at Smyrna and Wartrace. A freight
house was completed at Murfreesboro. Woodsheds and water
stations were constructed at Antioch, Smyrna and Christiana.
By December 1852, water stations were completed at Lavergne,
Murfreesboro, Bell Buckle, Wartrace, Normandy, Tullahoma,
Alisonia, Dechard and Tantalon. Water stations were supplied
as follows: Lavergne, Murfreesboro and Chattanooga, by
steam; Christiana, Estill's Springs and Cowan, by horse power;
Fosterville, Normandy Grade, Cumberland Mt. , Tantalon,
Anderson, and Stevenson by gravity. Murfreesboro Station
received its water from Murfree's Spring Branch.
As the road began to take shape, H. I. Anderson, the
Superintendent of Transportation, journeyed to Cincinnati
and acquired the first rolling stock for the N &amp; C. The
first engine arrived in Nashville 13 December 1850 along
with several passenger cars and freight cars, on the Steamboat
"Beauty." The engine bore the name "Tennessee" and was
built by Harkness and Sons of Cincinnati and was a 4-4-0
type engine weighing 20 tons. The engine was dragged by
mules from the wharf through the streets of Nashville to
the N &amp; C tracks on Cherry Street. This procedure required
four days and was watched with interest by the citizens of
Nashville. A trial run of one mile was made on the N &amp; C
line 27 December 1850. ^'"^^
-17-
By April 9, 1851, the "Tennessee" had pulled its first
train to Antioch, about 10 miles, where a large crowd greeted
21 the train. By April 1851, the train reached Rutherford
County. On 4 July 1851, the train ran to Murfreesboro
where a large celebration took place. About 1500 citizens
of Nashville traveled over the line to Murfreesboro and nearly
the entire population of Rutherford County turned out to see
the "train. "^
A second engine, "Gen. Harrison," commenced service
3 June 1851 and a third engine, "V. K. Stevenson," commenced
service 2 July 1851. When the celebration of 4 July 1851
was held, the N &amp; C had 2 passenger cars, 1 baggage car,
7 box cars, 18 platform cars and 9 repairing cars. Undoubtedly
all were utilized to bring the citizens of Nashville to
Murfreesboro, since many citizens wanted to ride the train.
By 1852 trains were operating as far south as Dechard
and the Shelbyville branch was opened. In February, 1854,
3
the line was completed into Chattanooga.
An interesting occurrence was noted on 6 November 1851
in a letter from J. F. Hibbett at Mt. View to son, Theophalis,
at school: "The locomotive Tennessee ran over a cow about
a week ago and turned a summerset and half killing 1 negro
and injuring several of the passengers, accidents are frequent
on the road occasioned by carelessness on the part of the
Engineer. They travel over about 60 miles of the road daily
backward and forward making 120 mile travel - we have not
22 taken a ride as yet."
-18-
The early engines were all named for prominent people, places
and towns. The entire list is as follows:
1 Tennessee 13 Shelbyville 25 H. Gourdine
2 Gen. Harrison 14 R. I. Moore 26 H. W. Conner
5 V. K. Stevenson 15 Gov. Sevier 27 John P. King
4 W. S. Waterson 16 Ctomberland 28 G. A. Trenholm
5 Tullahoma 17 Gov. Carroll 29 John C. Caldwell
6 John Eakin 18 Gov. Houston 30 Murfreesboro
7 Grampus 19 H. L. White 31 Winchester
8 Nashville 20 J. K. Polk 32 R;. Rogers
9 J. E.Thompson 21 Andrew Jackson 33 Geo. Peabody
10 Coweta 22 Daniel Webster 34 g. B. Lamar
11 Pollard 23 Henry Clay 35 J. T. Soutter
12 Chattanooga 24 John C. Calhoun 36 Wm. Moore
37 W. C. Smartt
The preceding list of locomotives were built by various
builders; Harkness and Sons, M. W. Baldwin, Niles and Company,
Nashville Manufacturing Company, Norris and Brothers, Rodgers,
Ketchiam and Grosvenor, Moore and Richardson, and the Rogers
Locomotive Machine Works. With the exception of one or two
pusher engines, all were 4-4-0 wheel type weighing approxi-mately
20 tons apiece.
The name "Tennessee" was applied to two other engines.
The first "Tennessee" was scrapped during the war. The
second "Tennessee" was the original "Chattanooga," and the
21
third was a rebuilt Rogers Locomotive built in 1855. It
operated until 1918 when it was sold to a South Georgia
Lumber Company. The engine was used extensively by the
Thomases (John and John, Jr.) as an inspection and pay train
from 1884 to 1912.^
The engine "Murfreesboro" was used primarily as a
freight engine. It was a 4-4-0 type and was built by Norris
and Brothers . The engine exploded in Kentucky during the
-19-
war and was scrapped. Apparently no photo was ever taken of
4
the engine "Murfreesboro.
"
Most of the engines could pull 11 or 12 cars success-fully;
and they took two days to reach Chattanooga from
Nashville with a layover at Dechard. It was not until 1870
that the N &amp; C acquired Rodgers built "16 car engines" (none
of these were named) . They were called 16 car engines
because they could haul 16 cars in about 16 hours between
Nashville and Chattanooga. -^
The N &amp; C operated profitably from 1854 until Nashville
fell to the Federal Troops.
Rutherford countians who worked for the railroad,
23 according to the 1860 Census were:
J. Latimer-R. Reader John Thomas-R. R. Agent
H. Prince-R. R. John Cumins-R. R. Supt.
A. B. Sanders-Engineer B. F. Norman-R. R. Overseer
Jos. Tatetum-Engineer Ben Mason-R. R. Hand
Jas. McGill-Engineer John Tilford-R. R. Supt.
Henry Brown-Engineer J. L. Cinse-Conductor
E. McGill-Engineer J. H. Grant-Engineer
M. H. Gowin-Bridge Bldr.
By 1860 the N &amp; C was rolling between Nashville and
10
Chattanooga with the following equipment:
Freight Engines&#8212;21 Coal Cars&#8212;26
Passenger Engines&#8212;
7
Gravel Cars&#8212;16
Light Engines &amp; Switchers&#8212;
9
Camp Cars&#8212;
8
Box Cars&#8212;225 1st Class Passenger Cars&#8212;
9
Stock Cars&#8212;31 2nd Class Passenger Cars&#8212;
8
Platform Cars&#8212;51 Mail &amp; Baggage Cars&#8212;
6
All the engines were wood burners so contractors along
the line furnished wood.
About 1858, John W. Thomas was employed on the N &amp; C
at Murfreesboro as one of the first freight agents. John
-20-
Thomas was born in nearby Wilson County but attended school
at Union University at Murf rocsboro. He graduated from
Union University and began a teaching career. But the rigors
of teaching were not good for his health. His doctor
recommended he resign and begin another occupation. Thus
he was employed to operate the local hotel in Murfreesboro
and in this capacity he became familiar with various railroad
officials. Recognizing his ability they hired him to operate
the Railroad Hotel at Murfreesboro and in 1858 he was
appointed Freight Agent at Murfreesboro. One railroad report
noted that the Murfreesboro Station was in good hands since
the agent there "repudiates the word fail." He gradually
climbed the ladder of management and became President of
the N. C. St St. L. Railroad from 1884 to 1906. His son,
John, Jr., was born in Murfreesboro and he, too, became the
President of the N. C. &amp; St. L. Railroad from 1906 to 1913
,24
and was known by railroad men as "little John.
By 1861, in anticipation of War and of a Federal block-age,
the N &amp; C was busy hauling goods south. Passenger
trains were cut to four daily and all freight engines were
working 24 hours a day. With the fall of Fort Donelson,
the N &amp; C began to evacuate the rolling stock and engines
south for safety. John Thomas was assigned the task of
getting the N &amp; C equipment south of Chattanooga which he
completed. V. K. Stevenson, as the Confederate Quartermaster
at Nashville, became alarmed, so he packed his belongings, sold
his home, and boarded a special train deserting Nashville
and its stores. On February 24, 186 2, the Federals took
-21-
Nashville without a battle. As the Confederates retreated
down the N &amp; C they destroyed bridges and roadway as far
south as the Tennessee River Bridge. They did not destroy
the big Tennessee River Bridge until Federal Troops attacked
and then they only bruned the south section. Union troops
later burned the northern end and rendered it unuseable.
Union construction corps rebuilt 113 miles of the N &amp; C.
General D. C. McCallum reports the condition of the N &amp; C
&#8212;
"The track was laid originally on an unballasted mud roadbed
in a very imperfect manner, with light "U" rail on wooden
stringers, which were badly decayed and caused almost daily
accidents by spreading apart and letting the engines and
cars drop between them. " Average train speed was about
8 miles per hour. Some of the "U" rail was ripped up and
25 replaced with "T" rail.
With the line opened 113 miles from Nashville to
Stevenson, Alabama, on 12 July 1862, the Federals planned to
advance upon Chattanooga. However, they had not planned on
N. B. Forrest attacking Murfreesboro on 13 July 1862,
destroying track near Murfreesboro. Later Forrest attacked
near Nashville on the N &amp; C and destroyed additional track.
The track was repaired again. General Buell, the Federal
Commander, feared an attack on Nashville so troops were
withdrawn to Nashville. Also about this time, Morgan was
destroying track and bridges on the L &amp; N in Kentucky.
General Braxton Bragg 's army had marched into Kentucky,
but after the Battle of Perryville the army retreated south
-22-
4
to Murfreesboro. Before the Battle of Stones River,
Jefferson Davis traveled to N &amp; C to Murfreesboro where he
conferred with Bragg. ^^ After the Battle of Stones River,
the southerners retreated down the N &amp; C and wintered near
Wartrace and Shelbyville. Thus the N &amp; C was opened and
operated from Chattanooga to Wartrace but not for long.
Rosecrans pushed south in the summer along the N &amp; C. As
the Confederates retreated, the N &amp; C was burned and des-troyed
for the second time. During the remainder of the
war the United States Military ran the N &amp; C with head-
10
quarters in Nashville.
The construction corps built forts at strategic bridges
along the N &amp; C. Most were built of wooden poles resembling
a western fort. Most were never attacked.
During the war John Thomas was the railroad agent at
Wilmington, North Carolina, where he directed the flow of
cotton and other products to Europe by way of the blockade
runners. V. K. Stevenson was also involved in this project
he used N &amp; C engines and equipment for the hauling.
14
Stevenson became a wealthy man from this operation.
In 1865 as Jefferson Davis fled Richmond with his
train, James Latimer, an early N &amp; C employee, was the con-ductor
on that train. Latimer whose home was Fosterville
Q
worked for the N &amp; C for many years. The engine that
pulled Jefferson Davis from Richmond was an N &amp; C engine,
"John C. Calhoun." Another N &amp; C engine, "Nashville,"
was one of the locomotives that hauled President Lincoln's
21
Funeral Train on its journey from Washington to Illinois.
-23-
The federal government returned the N &amp; C to the
management after the war, and Michael Burns was elected or
appointed President of the N &amp; C. James Grant returned to
Christiana and acquired his old job as Resident Engineer
of the road. He retained this position until his death
around 1870. James Grant was in charge of two changes on
the N &amp; C from 1866 to 1868. First, the roadbed was
ballasted for the first time and secondly the locomotives
were changed from wood burners to coal burners.
The Jasper branch was purchased in 1867 and according
to Jamse Grant the N &amp; C had practically owned and
the line for years. This branch brought accessibility to
14
the coal mines in that area.
Around 15 August 1868, an incident occurred in Ruther-ford
County which decided the outcome of the election of E. W.
Cole as the third President of the N &amp; C. Burns, who was
the President, was running against E. W. Cole. John Thomas,
then agent at Murfreesboro, was assigned the task of
delivering proxies from stockholders in Murfreesboro and
Rutherford County to the Stockholders Meeting at Nashville.
Apparently, Thomas was riding a train from Chattanooga to
Nashville with the proxies, but at Christiana the train
was sidetracked by Burns. Thomas learning of this wired
a friend at Murfreesboro to get a fast horse and rider to
Christiana for delivery of the proxies to Nashville. The
horse and rider arrived at Christiana, received the proxies,
and started its journey to Nashville. The horse dropped
-24-
dead at Lavergne where the rider promptly stole a horse in
a nearby field and delivered the proxies on to Nashville.
E. W. Cole was elected the third President of the Nashville
24
and Chattanooga Railroad.
The Rutherford County Courthouse was the site of all
stockholders meetings from 1849 to 18 58. The meetings were
usually held on the second Wednesday of December each year.
However, after 1858 the meetings were always held in
10
Nashville.
After the war, the N &amp; C managed the bankrupt Nashville
and Northwestern Railroad which ran from Nashville to
Johnsonville on the Tennessee River. In 1872, the Nashville
and Chattanooga Railroad purchased this road and in the
process changed its name to sound more prestigious to the
17
Nashville, Chattanooga and St. Louis Railroad.
25-
BIBLIOGRAPHY
1. "The Murfreesborough Celebration," The Nashville
American 6 July 1851.
2. Burt, Jesse C. Jr., "Four Decades of the Nashville,
Chattanooga and St. Louis Railway, 1873-1916,"
Tennessee Historical Quarterly.
3. "Seventy- five Years of Service," The Nashville Tennessean,
24 January 1923.
4. Prince, Richard E. "The Nashville, Chattanooga and St.
Louise Railway," Wyoming: 1967.
5. Hackworth, W. S. "Over a century of Railway Service
N, C &amp; St L," a paper delivered before the Round
Table Club of Nashville, Tennessee, 26 March 1953.
6. Clark, T. D. "The Development of the Nashville, and
Chattanooga Railroad," Tennessee Historical Magazine.
7. "More Goods by Express and Nashville and Charleston Line,"
Nashville Daily Union, 24 January 1848.
8. "Events in the History of the N, C &amp; St L Railway,"
The Nashville Banner, 24 January 1923.
9. Thomson, John E. , "Report to the Commissioners of the
Nashville and Chattanooga Railroad," February 1847.
10. Nashville and Chattanooga Railroad Company, Annual
Reports , Vol. 1-14, 1848-1861.
11. Jones, Sarah, "Half a Mile of History - L &amp; N Tunnel,"
Franklin County Historical Society.
12. Hughes, Mary B. , "Hearthstones,", Tucker Place is
Smyrna Landmark.
13. Hoover, Walter K. , "A History of the Town of Smyrna,
Tennessee, Nashville, Tennessee, 1968.
14. Grant, James H. , "Collection of Letters and Papers,"
1866-1868, Courtesy of Mrs. J. G. Sugg.
15. Hughes, Mary B. , "Hearthstones," Col. Grant, Easterner,
Builder of Railroads.
16. Sugg, Mrs. J. G. , Conversation with T. N. Johns,
January 1975.
-26-
17. DeBow, J. D. B. , "Legal History of Entire System of
Nashville, Chattanooga, and St. Louis Railway and
Possessions," Nashville, 1900.
18. 1850 Census.
19. Black, Robert C. , "The Railroads of the Confederacy,"
Chapel Hill, 1952.
20. State Historical Marker, "First Steam Locomotive,"
Located at the corner of Hart St. and 4th Avenue South,
Nashville, Tennessee.
21. Warner, Paul T. , "The Locomotives of the Nashville,
Chattanooga and St. Louis Railway," Baldwin Locomotives,
VI (July, 1927).
22. Hoover, Walter K. , Information from collection of rail-road
material.
23. Census of 1860.
24. John W. Thomas, A Memorial, (Nashville, 1906).
25. Abdill, George B. , "Civil War Railroads," New York.
26. The Tennessee Historical Chronicle, Vol I, No. 2,
"The First Train," January, 1975.
</dc:description>
<dc:description>A history of the Nashville and Chattanooga Railroad in Rutherford County between 1845 and 1872</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Nashville &amp; Chattanooga Railroad Company; Railroad stations--Tennessee; Rutherford County (Tenn.) -- History</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>53 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-15; mt2011-09-06</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication05ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/109</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>