<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Growing up in Milton</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Raikes, Rucker</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 23</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1984</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>GROWING UP IN MILTON
By: Rucker Raikes
My family grew up on a farm, on Porterfield Road, edge of Milton.
Milton was a great community to live in, everyone was everybody's
neighbor, in sickness, death, or health.
Here are a few names that had lots to do with my life, and many others
feel the same. John B. Groom farmer, Herbert Jennings farmer, Dennie Black
farmer, Dutch Bell farmer, Everett Knight farmer, Gus Raikes farmer, W.H.
Hooper U. S. Post Office, Ira Knight of telephone system, Andy Givens
grocery store, Rufus Williamson banker, Tom Morris blacksmith, Charlie
Sneed wheat thresher, Jack Mathews grocery store and trader.
Some of the great women of that day were Mrs. Delia Williamson, and
Mrs. Maggie Blankinship both Sunday School teachers, Miss Elsie Knox school
teacher, also Ruth Graham Mathews. Myrtle James telephone operator. Doctor
H. L. Mc Kee delivered both of my children. James Albert Baxter was our mail
carrier. Mrs. Meda Raikes, Nezzie Bugg, Bobbie Farny, Era Mai Jennings, Hattie
Mae Sneed, Mrs. Margie Higgins.
These are just some of the people that made Milton a great place to live.
We had some great baseball players in Milton. I will name a few, before I
started playing, Jack Mathews played in the major league, William Morris,
Wendell Porterfield, Jack Baxter, Mark Davis, Sam Youree, Fred Black, Dewitt
Williams, Frank Mc Knight.
58
This picture of the team Milton had:
front row, left to right: Hargis Rowlett, Lynn Knight, Alton Farm, Rucker
Raikes, Jimmy Mathews,
back row left to right: Jack Mathews (after he came home from the majors)
Frances Harris, Billy Rion, Frank Mc Knight, Melvin Knight.
These ball suits came from the Nashville Vol's.
Milton was a great place, great people, a great community, a great place to grow
up in. Many great memories still linger on.
59
The Milton baseball team was made up of local boys (or men). We played
all summer, only on Saturdays. We didn't play on Sunday. Later other teams
did play on Sunday.
We played places like Auberntown, Readyville, Denver in Cannon County,
Lascassas, Walter Hill, Pochanhuntis, in Cannon County, also at picnics
all over Middle Tennessee.
Jack Mathis, who played in the Majors , played with us as first baseman.
He was the father of Mary Francis Patterson, wife of the former Austin Lee
(deceased) Frank Mc Knight, and myself (Rucker Raikes) did most of the pitching.
Of the nine in this picture, five are deceased, Jack Mathis, Frank Mc
Knight, Alton Fann, Lynn Knight, Francis Harris. The four now living are Hargis
Rowlett, Melvin Knight or Murfreesboro, Jimmy Mathis, brother of Jack Mathis in
Tullahoma, Tennessee, and Rucker Raikes of Smyrna, Tennessee.
60
Pictures from Milton area - early 1900
William F. Brantley on Halls Hill Pike
Bridge over Stones River on Halls Hill Pike
61
Old Stone Spring House built by William Doran
He Mc Knight died in 1898 - born a slave of the Mc Knights
62
Stones River Presbyterian Church
Clayton Wi 1 lard Store in Milton,
Floyd Knight, Hue Hooper, James Mc Knight
Carse Blankenship, Beecher Perry
63
Home place - Frank Mc Knight, Goldie Mc Knight
Gustic B. Raikes, Rucker Raikes
&gt;riB
Yw
-&#171;*j-Wfc.
Rassie D. Fann &amp;
Jimmy Thomas in Milton
Rucker Raikes
in Milton 1931
64
Alfred &amp; Bessie Cooper
Frank &amp; Goldie Mc Knight at home
65
Henrietta Rion Thompson
Maggie Duff Mc Knight
James &amp; unknown
66
</dc:description>
<dc:description>Rucker Raikes writes about his memories of growing up as a child in Milton, Tennessee, supplemented with photographs</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.); Memoirs and biographies</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Milton</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>9 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-01; mt2011-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication23ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/34</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>