<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>A history of the Russell homeplace</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Russell, Tom L.</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 14</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1980</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>19th century; 20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>49
A HISTORY of the RUSSELL HOMEPLACE
By- Mr. Tom L. Russell
A cedar log house and its surrounding land was the home
and livelihood of several generations of Russells that descended
from Pinkney H. Russell (1816-1891) who migrated from North
Carolina prior to 1845 to Wilson County, Tennessee. The house
and land was located just South of Spring Creek and in the fifth
district of Rutherford County, Tennessee. It was the homeplace
of the writer, a location of many fond memories. Below is a
brief history of the place so near to the great-great-grandson
of Pinkney H. Russell, Thomas L. Russell.
In the year 1789, the state of North Carolina granted to
Stephen Brooks of Pitt County, N. C. several hundred acres of
land in Tennessee. Some of this land lay in what was to later
be Rutherford and Sumner Counties, Tennessee. Land that was
to later be the site of the Russell Homeplace was part of the
grants to Brooks.
Some time thereafter Brooks sold the land to a Richard
Evans of Pitt County. Evans in turn sold the land to Alexander
Evans in 1817-2,560 acres (640 acres in Sumner County and the
rest in Rutherford) for the price of $5,000.00 or about $2.00
an acre.
Later Alexander Evans sold the land to several men by the
names of John Barber, Joseph, Levi, William and Nathan Lannom
whose descendants still live in Rutherford and Wilson Counties.
In November of 1834 Laban Benthall, a hatter and perhaps
50
skilled in other trades, purchased part of the above land from
John Barber and Green B. Lannom, and heir of Joseph Lannom.
The land Benthall obtained included the site of the Russell
homeplace. Benthall 's boundary began where Fall Creek emptied
into Spring Creek, went south 1749 feet, then east 4092 feet,
then north 2359 feet and finally west 2275 feet to Spring Creek
and down the creek to the beginning of the boundary line. No
dwellings or stipulations was mentioned in the deed as was to
come later.
In October of 1836 Benthall sold the same land to Thomas
Rose with an exception of the way that the upper or northern
boundary ran. In the 1835 deed Benthall mentions (1) a dwelling,
(2) the reservation of one acre of land for the purpose of
building a meeting house for public worship and a school for
teaching children, and (3) a hatter's shop which was located
above Spring Creek Bridge. Benthall went to Dyer County in
West Tennessee apparently with Elisha Sanders of the first
district of Rutherford County, for the 1850 Census Benthall is
listed \inder the household of Elisha Sanders and a widower.
In March of 1872 William Rose, son of Thomas Rose who
died and was buried on what was to be the Russell homeplace,
sold the land to Patton A. McPeak who lived on Fall Creek, south
of the purchased land. This sale involved only 81 acres. Rose
either keeping some of the land or having already sold some of
it since the acreage had been cut in two. Again the dwelling
and reservation of one acre of land to build a meeting place for
public worship was mentioned. Another reservation was stipulated
in this deed&#8212;that of a family graveyard 32 feet by 40 feet.
51
This cemetery was located behind or north of the house with
a vegetable garden in between the two. Later Russell s and
other persons would be buried west of the plot stipulated by
the Rose family as a "family graveyard."
Mr. Ed Arnold, long time resident of the community, recalls
that one of the young men of the Rose family was killed by
another community resident in an argument&#8212;reason being unknown.
Most assuredly he was laid to rest along with his parents and
perhaps other members of the Rose family, a family which had
come from North Carolina.
From the above deeds and descriptions contained therein,
it appears that Laban Benthall built the cedar log house on the
Russell homeplace, a home for them from about 1878 until 1958
when the house burned. He would have built the home sometime
in 1835. The structure was made up of three rooms, one being
a kitchen setting away from the two other rooms, and half rooms
or pens over the front two rooms. A hall or breeze-way divide
the kitchen and two front rooms.
The hatter's shop built by Benthall could have been the
same structure used by W. D. Cook for a blacksmith shop since
both shops or businesses were located near and above Spring
Creek Bridge.
In January of 1878 William D. Cook and Wilson H. Russell,
son of Pinkney H. Russell, purchased a fifteen acre part of the
Russell homeplace&#8212;the part where the cedar log house stood.
This purchase was made from Patton A. McPeak, wife Martha and
David F. Hunter and wife Rebecca Rowlett. (David F. Hunter was
a brother of the wife of William D. Cook, Margaret Ann Hunter)
.
52
Seven months later, Wilson H. Russell and wife Jennie 0. Cook,
daughter of William D. Cook and Margaret Cook, became the parents
of a baby boy who was named William Pinkney Russell.
In February of 1879 McPeak and wife sold to Wilson Russell
61 acres of land joining the 15 acres purchased earlier by Cook
and Russell. This part contained the one acre reserved for the
meeting place of public worship. According to family stories
and a map of Rutherford County, a doctor's house or cabin stood
across the road from the main house. In the early 1900' s, this
cabin was moved next to this acre reserve. William P. Russell
was to raise his family in this cabin, it being located south
of the main house and near the public road on the east side.
William (Bill) Cook must not have felt the need for addition-al
acreage since he was a blacksmith and not a farmer like his
son-in-law, Wilson Russell who made the purchase alone this
time. Four years earlier, March of 1874, Wilson Russell had
written to a friend, W. B. Pafford, then in California. Russell
spoke of hard times and scarce money, and then spoke of his
farming activities of sowing oats and cleaning up some land
for cotton.
Bill and Margaret Cook, Wilson and Jennie Russell continued
to live together in the three room dwelling until Bill and
Margaret died near the turn of the century. Bill and Margaret
had only one child , Jennie who gave birth to several children,
three of which lived to adulthood. They were William Pinkney
who married Bertha Townes, Carrie who married Will Bridges and
Jesse who died before marriage. Jesse died in 1912; her funeral
was held in the front lot of the homeplace under the shade of a
huge oak tree. Jennie had died in 1894.
53
During the Cook-Russell occupation a front porch was
added along with a dining room on the East side of the kitchen.
Such was the structure for as long as the house would stand.
At the death of Wilson Russell in 1934 the homeplace
became the living place for William P. Russell, the only son
of Wilson. William's family was to live in the main house
until his death in 1944 when the oldest son of William, Clarence
Wilson Russell, would buy out his brothers and sisters, namely,
Robert Reed, Shirley Martin, Hollis Miller, Wyman Townes,
Helen Virginia and Marion Elizabeth Russell.
Clarence Russell who married Miralee Wright in 1938 and had
lived part of the time in the main house and part of the time
in the log cabin heretofore mentioned, was to raise his family
at the Russell homeplace and in the same log home built by
Laban Benthall in 1835. Clarence and Mira's children were
Thomas Lee, Kenneth Wilson, Rebecca Ann and Jennie Lynn. The
old log house was home for them until 1958 when it was destroyed
by fire. Thus, four generations of Russell s or five generations
of the same family had found home at the same place in the same
house in the fifth district of Rutherford County, south of
Spring Creek just a few hundred yards and east a few hundred
yards of the public road called Lamar Road.
Today, 1979, the knoll on which the house stood is part
of the south shore of the Percy Priest Lake which backs up into
the Spring Creek bed. Some of the maple trees of the yard and
one pear tree still stand. A new growth of trees and honeysuckle
vine cover the garden which was north of the house and the
family graveyard of the Rose family, gradually returning things
54
to a natural environment which Laban Benthall found on this
knoll in 1834. Gone but not forgotten because the Russell
homeplace holds many dear memories to one of her sons,
Thomas L. Russell, and I know for others as well.</dc:description>
<dc:description>A history of the Russell home; the land on which it was built near Percy Priest Lake, Fall Creek and Spring Creek; and the Russells themselves, as told by a Russell family member</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Family history; Memoirs and biographies</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>homes</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Smyrna</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>11 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-01</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication14ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/142</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>