<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Petition of Cornelius Sanders for Revolutionary War pension</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Sanders, Cornelius</dc:creator>
<dc:contributor>Farrar, Christine</dc:contributor>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 7</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1832; 1976</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1780-1789; 1830-1839</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>a?
Petition of Cornelius Sanders
for Revolutionary War Pension
Furnished by Christine Farrar
State of Tennessee
Wilson County Circuit Court October Term 1832
On this 25th day of October I832 personably appeared In
open court before the honorable James C. Mltchel Judge of said
court now sitting Cornelius Sanders, a resident of Rutherford
County State of Tennessee aged seventy years, who being first
duly sworn according to law doth on his oath make the following
declaration In order to obtain the benefit of the act of Congress
passed June 7th 1832.
That he entered the service of the United States In January
or February 178I In a company commanded by Capt. Dred Philips as
a volunteer for a term of three months. He cannot recollect
the precise day he volunteered his services, he was attached to
a Regiment of North Carolina mllltla commanded by Col. Thomas
Herndon, Maj . Curlee was their major when he first jolnded the
army they march from Halifax In North Carolina to Hillsborough
but before they got to Hillsborough Maj . Curlee for some cause
left them and returned home and after that Col. Hunter? returned
home and after that Col. Hunter? returned home owing to having
his house burned, and then Capt. Dred Philips was elected Major
In Curlees place and Axum Philips was elected Captain to Command
the Company. General Thomas Eaton had the command of Brigade
or division and marched the whole Force consisting as he thinks
of about two thousand through Hillsborough and jolnd General
Green's Army a few miles beyond Hillsborough, after our force
united with General Greens army. The American Army under the
command of General Green recoinoltred and persued the British
Army until the battle at Gilford in March I780, he was in that
battle and was in sight of Genl. Stephens at the time said Gen-eral
got his theigh broke and horse killed under him in that
engagement, said Stephens was a General of the Virginia Militia.
After the battle at Gilford he march with the American troops
to Ramseys mills on deep river where he remained stationed with
a part of the american troops until the experation of his three
months tour when he was discharged by his Capt. Axum Philips
which discharge he has lost.
A few weeks after he returned home there was a call for
twelve months men his company was divided into classes consist-ing
of twelve men and each class was to furnish one man to serve
the twelve months tour. In casting lots in his class it fell
upon him to serve the twelve months he march under the command
of MaJ . John Armstrong from Halifax, North Carolina with the other
troops raised in the Halifax district composed of Edgecome and
some other counties to the division under Genl. Green within
four or five miles of Camden. They had not organized any com-panies
until they joined General Green. The troops which
marched from Halifax district were divided and alloted to dif-ferent
companies in Green's army to make them complete, they
having been reduced by deaths and other causes, he was attached
to a company commanded by Capt. Joshua Hadlay - Pinch Eaton was
the Col. who commanded the Redgiment, Hogg, Dickson, Sharp and
Armstrong commanded as Majors at different periods during the
twelve months but at what periods they respectfully commanded he
cannot undertake to speak distinctly at this distant time he
recollects Maj . Hogg was most generally with them. After joining
B9
Greens army we inarched to a little tc^wn called CharloLLo, and
reconoitered, about Charlotte and Camden sometime, and then
marched to Ninety six and beseiged the British garrison enfort
at that place. He recollects the troops were employed in digging
a trench towards the British fort. It was (rumered) the design
was to blow up the fort during the seige. Col. Pinck Eaton was
sent round with a small detachment with fifteen or eighteen men
to a marsh or swamp near the British Fort to draw the attention
of the British to that quarter, there were also three men sent to
set fire to the British redoubts - Col. Pinck Eaton and all his
men except three got killed in that service, he thinks the three
men sent to set fire to the redoubt were killed also. After
remaining at Ninety Six from three to five weeks the British were
reinforced and General Green retired with the Force under his
command. We march from point to point watching the motions of
the enemy until the two armies met at Eutaw Springs where they
had a severe engagement. This applicant was taken sick and was
stationed at the house of one Spinks with eight or ten invalids
in consequence of which he was not in that engagement. He
remained at this place until his term or service expired and was
there discharged as he thinks by Captain Joshua Hadley which he
has lost. When he was discharged he had not recovered his
health and was scarcely able to walk.
He was upwards of two hundred miles from home and was a
month or more after he received his discharge before he arrieves ?
at home making a period of thirteen months or more he served
this tour counting the time he left home until he returned which
added to the former three months making sixteen months he was
90
in service of the United States. He cannot recollect the precise
day he entered the service the last time but thinks it must be
sometime in May I78I. He was employed as a drummer and was
sometimes attached to Capt. Joshua Hadley's Company and sometimes
to Capt. William Lytle's company.
In addition to the officers he has already named he also
knew Captain Coleman, Capt. Armstrong, Capt. Hatcher, Col. Mabry,
Col. Washington and Col. Lee of the light horse. He has seen
General Marion but never was with him in service, he was also
acquainted with Genl. Green the commander of the division, he
cannot state the day he was discharged from either of the terms
of his service. He further states he was born on the 30th March
1762 in Edgecome, North Carolina as he has been informed by his
parents, he has a record of his birth in a book at home which was
put down as he has always been informed by his Grandfather on
his mothers side, Cornelius Jordan, a few hours after his birth.
When he grew up he bought the book in which his birth was recorded
at the sale of his Grand Father's property after his death and
owns it yet. He lived in Edgecome County when he entered the
service, before the close of the war, however, there was a new
county established called Ash County, it included the place where
he lived. He resided in said county until the year 1808, as well
as he now recollects when he removed to Tennessee and settled
near the line of Rutherford and Wilson counties but rather in
the Rutherford side where he has remained ever since. He states
his residence is somewhat nearer Lebanon than Murfreesbourgh and
the clergyman that is best acquainted with him lived in Wilson
whose affidavit accompanies this declaration and who could not go
yi
with him convenietly to Murfreesborough is the reason he applies
at this court.
He further states he is known by Rev. Joshua Woolen, Moses
Woolen, John Curry, Augusta Edwards and Glower W. Banton, Esquire
and a great many others in his neighborhood. All he believes
would testify as to his character for veracity and their belief
of his services as a soldier of the revolution. He further
states that he has no documentry evidence and he know of no per-son
living at this time whose testimony he can procure who can
testify to his service. He hereby relenquished every claim
whatever to a pension or annenty except the present and declares
that his name is not on the pension roll of the agency of any
state whatever.
his
Cornelius X Sanders
mark
subscribed and sworn this 25th
day of October 1832
Wm. Martin clerk of the circuit
court of Law &amp; Equity for the County
of Wilson in the eleventh Judicial
circuit.
We Joshua Woolen a clergyman residing in the county of Wilson,
State of Tennessee and Moses Woolen residing in the same county
and state hereby certify that we are well acquainted with
Cornelieus Sanders who has subscribed and sworn to the above
declaration. That we believe him to be 70 years of age. That
he is respected and believed in the neighborhood where he resides
to have been a soldier of the revolution and that we concur in
that opinion . Joshua Woolen
Moses Woolen
Subscribed &amp; sworn to the</dc:description>
<dc:description>A reprint of Revolutionary War soldier Cornelius Sanders's 1832 petition to Rutherford County courts for a pension from his years of service</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Military pensions; United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1783</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>veterans</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>9 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-15</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication07ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/128</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>