<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>A story of Cherry Shade, LaVergne, Tennessee</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Chrisman, James L.</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 16</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1981</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>18th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>A STORY OF CHBRRY SHADE, LaVERGNE, TENNESSEE
during the timB of its occi^jancy
by the J. R&#187; Park Family
(By James L. Chrisman)
All of us lAo love to reftresh and enlighten our minds by breaking away
from the cares and tensions of the day, and glance back over the pages setting
forth the history of the trials and acconq)li3hments of those whose marks have
left an inprint upon the sands of time, cheerfully and willingly express our
thanks and gratitude to those who have already depicted much of the history
of this former splendid old home in LaVergne.
At the expense of repetition, I will set down only a few facts con-cerning
the house itself. It was built about the year I833 under the direction
and ownership of John Hill, a grandson of Green Hill, who migrated to the
Cumberland Territory from North Carolina, where he had been no doubt of high
political stature, haveing been at one time a member of the Continental
Congress of that state. The house was built on land that was part of an
original tract of 309 acres in a Land Grant to John Hill's father, Thomas
Hill, presumably in return for military service.
In addition to its attractive appearance from the front, its other
unique features were its U-shape in the back, with wide covered porches facing
toward the inside and running back from the front rooms on each side all the
way to the rear of the btiilding, where there was a covered walk-way to a well
located about equidistant from the points of the "U", so that it was convenient
to draw water with the rope and windlass in any kind of weather. Another
feature was the cedar sawdust insulation put between the inner and outer walls
of the house, believed to be one of the first homes so constructed in Middle
Tennessee.
60
Accounts have already been written about the fact that the house
was used as a hospital during the Civil War. We wouDxl like to en^)ha3i2e
the point that the location itself, on a direct line both by railroad and hi^"
way between Nashville and Murfreesboro, each of great strategic inportance
throughout the war, made it a prime target for being within easy sound or
distance of shot and sheU on many an occasion, leaving small wonder that
its only permanent damage was the large hole left in its lower right front
side made by a canon ball.
Now in regard to the J. R. Park family, as is the case with many
other fine old families in Middle Tennessee, no one took the time in his
family to maintain and pass on to us a con^ilete family history, so we cannot
delve as far into the past as we would like to with specific names and dates.
James Richard Park was of Scotch-Irish lineage. His father was Dr.
John E. Park, who was bom J\me 19, l8lU. He was a gradviate of the old
Louisville Medical College. James' mother was Rebecca Hubbard, who was bom
March 16, 1809. She was a daughter of Richard and &gt;tirtha Hubbard. Richard
Hubbard was bom October 9, 1769. Richard and Martha Hubbard had a large
family, consisting of nine dau^ters and four sons. One of their lineal
descendants was Father Hubbard, the Glacier Priest.
James Richard Psirk was bom November 16, I836, in Little Rock,
Arkansas. He was the oldest of seven children, there being five boys and
two girls. While he was quite young, the family moved to Seguin, Texas, a
small town made up principally of Germans. While there, Mr. Park learned to
speak German fluently, and years later he tried many times to teach his three
grand daughters how to speak German, but they never retained more than a
fragmentary knowledge of it,
I am indebted to Mrs. George Kinnard, formerly of LaVergne, for the
loan of an article which appeared in one of the Nashville daily papers in the
61
early part of 1919* containing some of the following interesting facta
about Mr. Park's early years, including some account of his services for
the South during the Civil Vfar:
While still in his early twenties, J. R. Park left Seguin and joined
a party of prospectors to follow the lure of silver into Old Mexico, Being
unsuccessful in the venture, he spent some time at Nassas, in the state, or
district, of Dui^ngo, Mexico, teaching English to a class of young lawyers,
Vfhen the Civil War came on, he hastened back to Seguin to enlist for the
South. He became orderly sergeant in Canvpaxiy B, 32nd Texas Cavalry, Captain
E, B. Millett corananding. At the same time he enlisted, his father and three
of his brothers enlisted in the Fourth Texas under Gen. John B. Hood, his
father becoming surgeon for his conpany. Two of the brothers made the supreme
sacrifice for the Confederacy; Thomas J. ^ark dying on the 5th of July, 1862,
of a wound received in the battle of Gaines' Mills, in his eighteenth year of
age, and John H, Park dying on April 23rd, 1863, in his twentieth year; an
Arkansas Post prisoner. James R. Park distingvdshed himself for braveiy at
the battle of Blair's Landing, when, \uider fire, he and his captain and
Alcnzo MiUett and Ed Elam returned to the field of battle and recovered the
body of Major General Tom Green (brother of Chancellor Green of Cumberland
Ifeiversity; also later Chief Justice of the Supreme Court of the State of
Tennessee) whose head had been torn from his body by a shell, Mr. Park was
in every battle in which his company engaged and was never left behind to
"hold Horses," He was honorably discharged near Richmond, Texas, in May, 1865,
and his discharge bears these words: "By order of Major General J, B. McGruder,
having stood to his colors to the last,"
The final bugle call has been answered for lo these many years by
the last svirviving Confederate veteran. While the night wind chants its
soleim dirge over their graves may we enshrine a special niche in our hearts
62
in grateful memory of all of them as chair^jions and defenders of their
hOTies and loved ones, who were willing to give their all for a cause they
believed to be just.
After the War, Mr. Park went to Georgia, where he resided for only
a short time, moving to Normandy, Tennessee, in the fall of 1866, where he
entered the service of the Nashville, Chattanooga &amp; St. Lo\iis Railway
Coii?&gt;any. At that time, messages about trains came through on an instrument
called a register, and were recorded on a strip of paper. According to Mr.
Park, there were then but five or six men in the service who could read the
Morse Code. In Normandy, Mr. Park received his first lessons in telegraphy
from Mr. Sam Blackman, the depot agent there. Being an apt student, he
quickly becane an expert telegrapher, and from then en he was a railroad
man to the core. Just as in?)ortant, while in Normandy he met and fell in
love with Miss Mary Catherine Scott, the lovely dau^ter of Dr. John H. and
Virginia Ewell Scott. Dr. Scott had seen service as a physician in the Civil
War, and he was later one of the original stockholders of the N, &amp; C. Railroad,
and had much to do with the building of the line to Chattanooga. Virginia
Ewell Scott was the dau^ter of Lt. Gen, Richard S. Ewell, who had rendered
distinguished service in the United States Army prior to the Civil War, and
subsequently as a commanding officer in the Confederate Army.
When Mr. Park asked for the hand of Miss Scott in marriage, her parents
registered strong objection on the grounds of the wide difference in the
religious beliefs of the prospective bride and groom, but on no other grounds.
To some people today that would present a pretty touchy and difficult problem,
but to a young man who had traversed the length and breadth of the middle south
more than once, plus forays into the far West and Old Mexico, facing danger
and even death many times, we need be but little surprised to learn that
he solved the problem in short order by espousing the religious beliefs
practiced by the Scott family, and the marriage took place in the fall of 1867.
63
Not long after Mr. Park married Miss Scott, he was transferred and
promoted to station agent in LaVergne. It appears that when they first
moved to LaVergna, he rented Cheny Shado and later purchased it. As there
cane to be about eleven acres of ground on the Cherry Shade property, it was
acquired in two different transactions by Mr. and Mrs. Park, The first tract,
and no doubt the one on which the house was then standing, was bought by
them by deed dated December 13, 1678, and of record in Book 2li, page 14i7,
Register's Office for Rutherford County, Tennessee. This deed was from
M. N. Cowden, Clerk of the Supreme Court in Nashville, and the recitals in
the deed indicate that he was selling it in obedience to a court order, and
further that the Birdwell's were involved j they being people who had had many
dealings with Thomas and John Hill, previous owners of the property. The
second tract, ccaitaining about five acres, was purchased by Mr. Park from
R. H. Dudley for the sum of $200.00, by deed dated October 18, l88l, as shown
of record in Book 26, page 23&#171; I have been reliably informed that in addition
to the above properties, Mr. Park at one time owned some acreage farther up
the Murfreesboro Pike, which he afterward donated as a building site for the
LaVergne Church of Christ.
There were eight children bom to Mr. and Mrs. Park, However, with
80 many deadly diseases prevalent during that period of time, such as
diphtheria, typhoid fever, etc., and so little knowledge of preventive
medicine, five of the children died either in infancy or while quite young.
The three who passed the childhood stage were Mary Virginia, John Thomas
(Named after John W. Thomas, once the President of the N. &amp; C. R.R .), AND
Clara Dodge Park. Clara died in 1915, and John Thomas about one year later.
More about Mary Virginia farther on in this article.
During the many years of their occupancgr of Cherry Shade, Mi'&#171; and
Mrs, Park became quite well known for their congeniality, friendliness and
61*
hospitality. Mre. Park reigned over the household with charm and efflciencyi
fuUy exeitplifying the best traditions of the Old South in every respect.
Their home soon became the accepted gathering place for their many relatives
and friends. Both Mr. and Mrs. Park were great flcwer lovers, so the big
yard was kept well stocked with many varieties of beautiful flowers, Mr.
Park even insisted that a suitable space near the railroad depot be set
aside for a nice bed of flowers, which always receive the best of attention.
Mr. Park was a man of high moral character aiKl unquestioned integrity-
He was one of the pioneers and builders of the Cumberland Presbyterian Chiirch
in LaVergne. He devoted himself assiduously to any task at hand, and
commanded the respect and admiration of those associated with him. His
inquisitiveness and desire to make inqprovements led him to become known as
an amatevir inventor. During his career with the railroad, being greatly
ccmcemed as a depot agent with his responsibility for the safety of passengers
and personnel within the vicinitgf of his station, he conceived the idea of
building a small framed double mirror contrivance which could be placed on
his desk in the depot, and from &gt;diich, without leaving his chair, he could
see at any time whether a train was coming down the tracks from either
direction. Conpany officials were so favorabley impressed with his "gadget"
that within a short time they made it standard equipment in stations all up
and down the line.
After having long since mastered the Morse Code, Mr. Park eventually
became entranced with the idea of how else it might be possible to send and
receive messages, and possibly to singly record and reproduce sound; for
instance, talking and singing or making music. Without the benefit of the
vast knowledge and e3q)erience available today on the subject, he spent many
an ho\ir experimenting and building different mechanical gadgets and machines,
\intil finally he came up with one which contained a cylinder and speaker lAiich
65
really worked. Many tlnies he would beg and cajole one of his granddaughters
to speak or sing In front of his cylinder, and then play it back to them.
Those closest to hin in and around LaVergne were much in9&gt;ressed with his
inventive prowess in gneral, and presumably mostly financial ones, he never
ventured into the contmercial field with any of his inventions, and it wasn't
long until Thomas Edison's talking machines and other inventions were sweeping
the country.
As a special tribute marking the end of his long years of service,
the railroad conqjany presented Mr. Park with a beautiful gold Elgin pocket
watch, with his name and the emblem of his Masonic Lodge inscribed en its
bade cover.
Mary Virginia Park was bom at Cherry Shade June 2, I876. Althou^
her parents were not wealthy, they did possess sxibstantial means, and she was
reared under favorable circumstances, which include schooling at Ward's
Seminary, later Ward -Belmont College. She became a beautiful and well-educated
young lady. In 190U she became the wife of James Buchanan Payne,
a s\irv^or-engineerj a resident of LaVergne, and a descendant of Major
John Buchanan, of Indian war fame in middle Tennessee. This couple continued
to live in LaVergne for a time, but before long Mr. Payne and his wife's
brother John, generally called "Jack" Park, also a civil engineer, succumbed
to the prevailing urge of those to "Qo West, young man," so they ended up in
far west Texas positions as surveyors -engineers connected with a big
crew of men building a railroad through Yaq\il Indian territory. Virginia
Piajrtie would stay with her parents most of the time, but as she could get a
pass on the railroad anyway, she would now and again take the train for &#163;1
Paso or some point near there to see her husband and brother.
Mr. and Mrs. J. B. Payne were blessed with four children; one son
and three daughters. However, the son died In infancy. The daughters were.
66
Mary A^ies, the oldest, bom June 2, 1906' Martha Virginia and Dorothy
Alice; all named after klnfold back along the family lines.
Mrs. Payne insisted on starting Mary Agnes to school at Ward-Belmont
grade school, so she and her girlhood chum, Marian Pearscai, now Kinnard,
would coranute on the local train each school day for their first year.
Before the start of another school year, fate had stepped in and changes
had to be made. Grandmother Park passed away; Mr. Pfiirk was suffering from
a heart ailment, and needed to be nearer quick medical aid. Also, James B.
Payne had died rather suddenly some years before; thus leaving Mrs. Virginia
Payne faced with the task of taking care of her father and her three small
children. Between father and dau^ter it was decided best to sell Cherry
Shade and move to Nashville, where they would be near a heart specialist,
and could send the children to city schools. So, by deed dated September 5,
1916, J. R. Park and Mrs. Virginia Park Payne sold (or in reality traded)
Cherry Shade to W. W, Dillon, Trustee, in exchange for a house and lot on
Sixteenth Avenue South, about one block south of Grand Avenue, which house
had beai built and occupied previously by tlie Thomas W. Wrenne family. In
the deed conveying Cherry Shade a part of the recital is as follows "
all of said land having been occupied continuously by J. R. Park as a home
for more than 3li years, and known as Cherry Shade the said Mrs. Virginia
Park Payne being the dau^ter and sole heir at law of J. R. and Mrs.
Park, the latter now deceased."
To bring this part of the story of Cherry Shade to a close, after Mr.
Park and his daughter Virginia sold the property, it changed hands several
times. Finally, the Tennessee Farmers Co-op built a large fertilie.er and
feed plant on the northerly adjoining tract of land. Because of the un-pleasant
odor from acid fumes originating in the fertilizer plant, together
with huge clouds of dust being blown from the plant when it was in full
67
operation. Cherry Shade became practically uninhabitable. Too late the
many other residents In the imnediate neighborhood reali-zed their mistake
in not Tising every avenue of protest against allowing the biiilding of this
type of industrial plant so near their former quiet and clean air homes.
Eventually, enou^ protests were made to cause an order to be issued requiring
the fertilizer plant to cut out the air pollution. In the meantime. Cherry
Shade remained xmoccupied for many mcaiths, and as usually happens in such
cases, vandals began to take over. First, vnndows were broken, doors smashed
in, and then general deterioration set in. Bushes and briars grew rampant,
and neglect showed its hand. Finally, on Friday night, June 25, 1971, fire,
set no doubt by vandals or arsonists, took the final toll and Cherry Shade
was no mor&#171;.
Ad with many another former pretty landmark in Middle Tennessee, to
those who remain who have enjoyed the warmth of friendship and hospitality
of Cherry Shade in days and years gcsie by, as well as to all who have senti-mental
ties connected with it, it can live hereafter only in pictures and
fond memories.
68
CHERRY SHADE - LAVERGNE, TENNESSEE
Those in Picture:
Seated; James Richard Park and wife, Mary Catherine Scott Park.
Children: from left: Annie , Clara Dodge, Mary Virginiaand JohnThomas Park, children of Jr.
and Mary C. Park.
Standing on porch: Mr. Park's sister, Martha Park Randall.
Servants: One of them (believed to be the one on the right) is Aunt Charity Cannon Hibbet. Name of
the other not knowN.
</dc:description>
<dc:description>The history of a home called Cherry Shade in LaVergne, during the time it was occupied by the J.R. Park Family</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Family history; Historic buildings; Rutherford County (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>LaVergne</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>19 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-15; mt2011-02-16</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication16ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/42</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>