<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Specifications for the first court house in Murfreesboro</dc:title>
<dc:contributor>Watson, Virginia Gooch; Wray, Henry</dc:contributor>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 1</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1973</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1810-1819</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>SPECIFICATTONS FOR THE FIRST COURT HOUSE
IN WIRFREESBORO
The notice that follows appeared in The Nashville Whig on
Wedneaday, November 25, 1812. Mrs. Virginia Gooch Vfatson,
of the Williamson County Historical Society, discovered the
notice in the Tennessee State Library and Archives and
forwarded a copy to Henry Wray, Rutherford County' Archivist.
NOTICE
On the 25th day of January next, to be let to the
lowest bidder, the building of a COURT-HOUSE, for the county
of Rutherford, in the town of MURFREE'S BOROUGH, the
dimensions as follows, to wit: 100 feet square; the wall of
brick; the first story to be 15 feet in the clear, two feet
thick; the upper story to be 12 feet in the clear, 18 inches
thick; the foundation to be of stone, sunk two feet under
ground, and raised two feet above, the stone above ground
to be neatly dressed; the lower floor to be raised and laid
with brick edge up; the joists to be 4 by 1^ inches, and
placed two feet apart from center to center, in a girder
through the middle of the house, 1^^ inches square, all to
be of good durable wood; the girder to be supported by two
neat-tumed walnut posts, and set on stone pillars of
sufficient size, not to be seen above the floor; the under-edge
of the joists that are over-head to be ceiled with
poplar quartered plank, neatly planed and beeded, and
joints broken. Three doors on the lower floor, h feet wide
and 9 feet high, with f ron tis-pieces and circular sash, in
48
the .same manner of that of Franklin court-houae, Williamson
county; with pannel shutea well lined; with a sufficient
lock to one door, and good bolts to the other two doors;
with sufficient hinges to each door; with sills and steps
to each door, neatly dressed; ten windows v.ath rock sills,
and frames of good poplar of same thickness of the wall,
with double architrive facings on both aides; ."ash of the
same wood; the lights to be 10 by 12 , ^ 2U lights to each
window; the lower story to be wainscotted neatly as high as
the window-sills, and plaistered and whitewashed above to
the ceiling. The upper story, 13 windows, done and finished
as below; that is 2U lights to each; the floor to be laid
with good poplar plank, one ^ a half inches thick, well
tongued and grooved; an entry of ten feet through the
middle of the upper story, and partitions, so a a to make
two rooms on each side of the passage, and a fire place to
each room of common size; in such cage the nartitions to be
made of plank one and a half inches thick, to be rabbeted and
beeded; with a pannel door to each room; with sufficient
locks and hinges; neat chair and wash boards. The upper
joists to be 4 by 1?, supported by sufficient girders, and
ceiled as below; box and cornished with joints and modillion
cornish, in proportion. A hip'd or square roof, that is
carried up from all sides, with a principal frame to support
the same, a cupalo on the top 1^+ feet high, and floored;
a six light window in each square; the remainder to be open,
hand railed, and banistered; a bell roof, a steeple of
15 feet long, with an eagle, etc. The roof to be of yellow
poplar shingles, 18 inches in length, 4 in breadth, and
3-U thick, and to be well shea ted with at least three-quarter
plank; all to be nailed on with good and suitable nails.
The staircases to run from the lower floor to the cupalo;
the lower stair case to be bracketed and banistered. A
neat court-bench, jury-box and bar; all to be done in the
same manner as the court-house in Franklin. The whole to be
painted in an alegant, durable, fashionable manner. The
roof to be painted red; the boxing and comishing white;
and door and window-facing a and sash also white. The whole
work to be done and executed in a neat workman-like manner.
The wainscot, wash-board and ceiling to be neatly painted
of fashionable colors, and stars.
H. ROBINSON )
H. HAMILTON ) p&#8222;&#8222;&#8222;,,- &#8222;a-f ,.&#171;^t.o
OWEN EDWARDS )
Commissioners
JOHN THOMPSON )
N. B. Should the lowest bidder fail to give sufficient
security on the day of letting, the letting will be continued
from day to day until let to such as will comply
H.R.
H.H.
O.W.
J.T.
November Ik
</dc:description>
<dc:description>Reprint of a notice appearing in The Nashville Whig in 1812 advertising for a builder for the Rutherford county courthouse</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Courthouses -- Tennessee -- Murfreesboro; Rutherford County (Tenn.) -- History; </dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>5 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-16; mt2011-09-06</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication01ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/117</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>