<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>The Manson family</dc:title>
<dc:creator>James, Rosalind Manson</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 19</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1982</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>18th century; 19th century; 20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>^ 43
THE MANSON FAMILY
by . Rosalind Manson James
For the benefit of posterity I am putting down In writing what I
have heard; what I have read; what I have learned from research In
vaxrLous areas; w^t I know f!rom my years of living; and possibly irtiat
I have imagined about ny father's family. - - - The Hansons , There
is much information here and seme mis-lnformatlon&gt; no doubt, and there
are many gaps to be filled in so I leave it to future generations to
complete. Try it. It*s fun after you get started!
Our first immigrant ancestor to this country by the name of Manson
came from England into St. Charles Parish, York County, Virginia about
1680. He was married twice - - first to Miss Scnarin by whom he had a
child Otis (bom Nov. 1, I69O and died Dec. 9, I69O). He later married
SLlzabeth (name \inknown) by whom he had eight children, five sons and
three daughters;
1. Peter, Jr. (bom Aug. 25, 1697}
2. Anne (bom June h, 1699)
3. Elizabeth (bom April 3, 1710 - married Monroe or
Merriwether Shelton-Ollllvan,
no issue )
h' John (bom Feb, lli, 1702 - married Martha
Lewis, a widow, moved to Bin-widdle
County, Va about 1730)
5. James (bom Jan. 13, 170U)
6. Frances (bom July 28, 1707 - died Dec, 25, 1707)
7. Nathaniel (bom April 10, 1710)
8. Walter (bom Dec. 8, 1713)
Peter Manson was rather prominent and owned property in Virginia from
the time of his arrival in America, but this docimentation I do not have.
Ity information has come from Mr. Lawrence Gardiner, I832 Cowden Avenue,
Memphis, Tenn. &gt;Aio is related to us through the Manson-Pkrdaway line and
who has done quite a bit of research on this line. He is writing a book
49
on the Hardavasrs and is includijig a chapter on the Mansons. The two families
Intermarried in Dinniddle and BnmsHlck Counly, Virginia where they had
moved after the Revolutionary War.
John Manson married Mrs. Martha Lewis
Issue: Cfqjtain Peter Manson, bom Dec. 2U, 1733-Bri.stol Parish
Registry, died 1793, Dinwiddie Co. - (Will registered)
Married twice Susanna Hardaway - bom Sept. 27, I7I4O
Dinwiddie Co. Va. and Ames Hardawgy-bom March 30,
17U9, Dinwiddie Co, Y&amp;. (^BLble)
Captain Peter Manson was a large landowner and slave holder in Din-widdie
Co. 7a. and was prominent in many ways in the county.
Issue:
1. Ma.ior Thcmas Manson, bom 17^7 Dinwiddie Co. married
Anne Pegram, bom Jtily U, 1762. He died I806 in
Brunswick Co., Va. He was Major In the Revolutlonazy
War. Was given land in Brunswick Co. by father and
was prominent.
2. Mary Manson, married Major Baker Pegrow
3. John Manson married Elizabeth Rogers Jan 25, 1790 in
Brunswick Co.
U. Martha Manson married John Alfriend
5. Peter Manson Jr. married Miss Epps
6. Captain Hardaway Manson married Joanna Parker
7. Nathaniel Manson - never n&amp;rried
8. James Manson - never married
9. Agnes Thweatt Manscm married Dr. Peter Manson Hardaway
10. Elizabeth Mans&lt;m - unknown
Ma.ior Thomas Manson aiKJ Anne Papram
Issue: Mary Baker Manson, bom 1783 and Edward Jones Tarpley
Aug U, 1800, Brunswick
2. Susanna Hardaway Manson bom 1785, married Benjamin
Ingram Dec. 20, 1802, first and (2) Abraham Bedford
Nov. I80i4 Brunswick bond
3. Edward Manson bom 1781^, died I833, Brunswick - - married
Nancy Walker MacUn-bom July 11, 1797 (Bible)
U. Martha Pegram Manson bom Aug I8, 1791, died April 29,
1827, married Thomas Buford Dec. 22, I8O8. He was
bom in 1786, died I820
5. Aqaes Thweatt Manson bom Dec. 9, 1792, married Col
Isham Pratter on Dec. 19, I8I6 in Brunswick Co. He
was bom Jan. 1, 1792 and died Oct 30, I856 in
Brunswick Co
6. Thomas James Manson bom 1795&gt; married Susan James
Maclln May 18, 1826 (Bible). She was bom Oct. 17,
1806. (Bible)
50
Issue: Joseph Richard Manson
Caroline Manson married Peter CogbUl
Susan Manson married Robert Borden
Edward tfanson bom 1787 Brunswick Co., mairried Dec. U, I8l5-
dled 1620 in Brunswick, married Nanp7 Walker Maclin-bom
July 1, 1797 (Bible) died Mar. 7, 1880. Ruth Co Tenn
Issue;
1. Lucy F. Manson bom l8l6, married Benjamin S. Orgain
en Nov. 2li, 1831* in Brunswick Co.
2. Martha J. Manson bom I8I8, married Henry N. Mason (l)
Nov. 2ht l83lii Brunswick; married John H. Neal (2)
Aug. 30, 1837, Williamson Co., Tenn.
3. Susan Manson bom 18^ - unmarried
k, James Edward Manson, M. D., bom June 30, I82U, Bruns-wick
Co., Va., died Jan 6, I888 in Rutherford County,
Tenn. married Anne Eliza Crockett June 30, iQhk. She
was bom Jan . 6, 1825, Rutherford Co, died Mar 6,
1880 in Rutherforf Co., Tenn.
$. Joseph J. Manson bom I826, married Martha Anne White
6. Agnes Manson married James Owen
Edward Manson died in Brunswick Co. where he spent his entire life,
but his wife Nancy Maclin came to Tenn. with her two married daughters-
Martha and Lucy, and her two younger sons-James Edward and Josej^. She
purchased land at Nolensvllle, WLUianson Co., Tenn. In deed book "F",
page 221, we saw registered where Nancy Manson bought 128 acres for
$900.00 on Mill Creek. This is dated Nov. 19, I838. Also, in l81i2 she
bought slaves. She also sold four acres. Witnesses to the first transact,
ion were J. E. Manson, Benjamin L. Organ, (?), Rrince, James Shownum.
First deed Book "Q", page 576, shows that on May U, I8ii2 she bought 3
Negro Slaves-Ned, aged two years, Mary aged three, and Louisa, aged 25,
and paid $100.00 for them.
Edward Manson* s WHl of the Probate irecords of Brunswick Co., Va.
shows the inventory on Edward Manson, dec, recorded Feb. 1833* He had a
large estate for that period with the personality totalling $5,317.75 and
his largest holdings in real estate. Evidently his wife Nancy W. left
51
ulth her children for Tennessee and first irent to Williamson Co. where
she bought the 128 acres In I838. She may have Uved there the rest of
her life, I am not sure. I find onLj the marriage of one of her children
there, - the second marriage of the daughter, Martha J. Hanson Mason and
John H. Neal on Aug. 30, 1837. By 1857 I find Benjamin S. Orgain
witnessing deeds for James Edward Hanson in Rutherford Co. So it is
possible that the Orgains moved to that county also.
NOTE; Williamson County adjoins Rutherford County
and the line may have been moved. Dr. Hanson's property is near
the Une.
Dr. James Edward Hanson, bom June 29, 1823, Brunswick Co.
died Jan 6, I888, Rutherford County, Tenn-^narried
Anne Eliza Crockett June 3&#171; I8I4I;. She was bom
Jan. 6, 1825 in Rutherford County, died March 7,
1880 in Rutherford. She was the daughter of Julia
Granville Smith and Fontaine Posey Crockett of
Frankfort, Ky. of French Huguenot family Czvchetagne-
(descendents eligible for Huguenot Society of Va. I
am a menber as is Paul HcGee JamssJ.
Issue: 1. Robert Granville Hanson bom 1859
2. Anne Hanson married James Owen
3. Katherlne (Kitty) Hanson married Thcnas Bass
1|. James Edward Hanson married Hary Jane (Jennie) Jenkins
Dr. James Edward Hanson was my father's grandfather, my great grand
father and ray grandchildrens great great grandfather. I remember many
stories told about him and all show him to have been a Virginia gentle-man
and an educated man. According to family tradition and told me by
Miss Isabella Washington, a cousin of my fathers and of mine, he had
diversified occt^iation. He was a doctor who had younger men study under
him (as did Dr. James J. Rucker who married the sister of ny grandmother);
a teacher while he was getting his medical degree; and later a hortl-cultarist.
He received his medical degree from the IMiversity of Penn.
so we have always been told, but proof went out the end of a metal con-tainer
in the form of gelatin ^en we tried to open the cylinder which
52
contained the old sheepskin. We need to doctnent his degree at Harris-burg,
Pa. (that's for future generations! I). We do know, however, that
he purchased the practice of Dr. Wilkerson and also the WiUcerson tum-pLke
which ended at his large two-story colonial hone. It then became
"Hanson Pike", as it is today and the old home place still stands and is
owned by &amp; descendant of Dr. MansonrJanes Batey. It was Dr. Manson who
put out the beautiful hoUy and magnolia trees which are now large and
magnificent.
A story is told of how a Mr. Addison vajLlye, inmigrant from Canada
to Louisiana came by and asked to spend the night, and remained for UO
years. He was a nurseryman so he and Dr. Manson started a nursery in
I8I4I and planted every varlely of fruit trees, flowering shrubs, and
berries that would grow in that area. Isabella Washington said they
put out boxwood all over Middle Tennessee, but said it was then called
"boxtoush" not "boxwood". I can reniamber avenues of lovely trees, grape
arbors, and mazes of "box-bush" at all of the pretty old home places
along the Manson Pike. &#163;ven now evidence remains that someone in that
area was interested in landscaping.
Anne Eliza Crockett and Dr. James Sdward Manson were married on
June 3, 18UU in the garden of Anne SUza's Aunt United America Smith and
Ifticle William Hunter Smith. He was her guardian after the death of her
father, Fontaine Posey CrocKett who as a young lieutenant went to Join
Andrew Jackson at New Orleans and stopped on Manson Pike, and met Anne
Elllza's mother JuUa Granville o After having many children, using up
most of the resources given Julia Granville when she married him, he
gently died still thinking he was a wealthy landowner and slave holder.
(This is Isabella's version - - perhaps true since he was a heavy drinker
and toberonlar, we hear). William Hunter Smith and "Aunt Mac" left
53
itone Eliza 200 acres, etc, etc, (WiU Book 2U&gt; page 3lSt Rutherford
Cotnty, Tenn. County Clerk's office).
Dr. Hanson was a tall handsome nan devoted to his Masonic brother-hood.
A story was told me hy one of his fratemily that dtirlng the Civil
War a CoBiq&gt;any of Iftiion soldiers came by the house and were preparing to
bum it. The young captain would not accede to Dr. Hanson's request that
because of his wife's illness they pass them b7&#187; and were preparing to
start the fire. At that moment Dr. Hanson gave the Hasonic distress
signal and the jroung obtain saluted and marched his soldiers away.
In the family today the name James Edward Hanson remains down to
the sixth generation and there still remains an intense interest in the
Masonic faith. A picture is on the wall of the Hasonic lodge in Hurfrees-boro,
Tennessee of four generations of James Edward Hansons in their
Kni^t Ten^ilar regalia carrying their SMords. There are also other
TenQ&gt;lars and Shriners among direct descendants. The masonic sword of
Dr. James Edward Hanson was given by me to ny son Janes Edward Hanson
Janes to be given later to his son, Janes Edward Hanson James, Jr.
Today, Hay 26, 1972, I received an invitation to the graduation
from medical school of James Edward Hanson, the great, great grandson of
the First Dr.. A great grandson, William Gresham Hanson Jr. is also an
H. D. in San Francisco, California. So tradition and training carry on.
James Edward Hanson bom June 18, 1853, Rutherford County, died
Dec. 19, 1919 in Rutherford County, married Hary Jane (Jennie) Jenkins
Hay 27, l87li. She was bom Oct 25, l85U, Rutherford County, died Dec.
19, 1937"^inchester, Tennessee.
Issue: 1. Ninmie Hanson married Guy Fercival Bagwell
llieir Issue:
A. koDle Quy married Robert Jackson- No issue
B. Virginia Bagwell married RoUo Every
(a) Rollo Herritt Every
(b) Hirian Anne Every
54
Dr. James Edward t'lanson &amp; his daughter Kitty
55
2. James Edward Manson, Jr., bora Mar 7, l877&gt; Ruther-ford
County, died May 26, 1926, RussellvUle, Ala.
Married Dec. St 19W&gt; Rutherford Counly to Lucy
Miles-bom March 6, 187$, Rutherford Counlgr-died
Jan. 21, 1963 iQ Rutherford County.
3. Virginia (Jennie^Manson married Ellis Hudgens
Their Issue:
A. Flndley Hudgens
B. Eugene Hudgens
C. Anne P^gens
D. Jean Marie lixdgens
U. Katherlne Manson married Bmest Sugg
Their Issue:
A. Ernest Sugg, Jr.
B. James Edward Sugg
C. Mary Katherine Sugg
5. Wtniam Gresham Manson married Madge Jackson
Their Issue:
A. WHliam Gresham Manson, Jr.
married Elizabeth Spragus
(a) Jeffrey Spragus Manson
(b) Carolyn Curtis Manson
(c) Elizabeth Jackson Hanson
6. Annie Manson married Irving Martin
7. Marvin Cullum Manson married Nelle Thcnapson
Their Issue:
A. James Edward Manson
B. Marvin Manson
C. Elaine Manson
8. Three children died in infancy - ( Joe, ELla, Walter)
Issue of James Edward Manson and Lucy Miles:
1. Camilla Manson bom March 7, 1902 in Rutherford Coxnty,
died March 12, 1957
2. Rosalind Virginia Manson bom April 1, 1903 married
John Hilsman Jsnes on March 1$, 1926, in Daytona
Beach, Florida. He was bom Sept. 12, 1901 in
Albany, Georgia.
3. Allie Manson bom July 22, 1909, Rutherford County.
Issue of Rosalind Manson and John Htiam^n James :
1. John Hilanan James Jr., bom Oct 29 1 1928, St Louis,
Mo., married Rebecca Ruth Seat on Aug. 28, 19l$ in
Rutherford County. She was bom April 13, 1928 in
Rutherford County, Tenn.
Their Issue:
A. Deborah James bom Sept 1931* married Bradford
Plonkey in Davidson County, Tn Aug 1972
B. Margaret Allison Janes bom Oct 6, 1951; married
Micheal Vietti in Davidson Co, July 1973
2. James Edward Manson James bom Nov. 30, 1930 married
Marcy Rider of Texas on Dec. 26, 1953 in Huntsville,
Texas. She was bom Aug. 25, 1935
Their Issue:
A. James Bdward Manson Janes &gt; Jr.
B. WlUiam Frssk James
C* Lucy Caroline Janes married Richard EUls
D. Camilla James
3* Paul McGee Janes, bom Aug. lU, 1935 In Waycross, Oa.
married Sarah AUce Turner from Selma, Alabama on
Dec. 26, 1961. She was bom i^rll 8, 19&#8212;.
Their Issue:
A. Rosalind Turner James, bom Oct. 29 &#187; 1962
B. Paul McQee Janes, Jr., bom Aug. U, 196U
The second James Edward Manson, ray grandfather who married Mary Jane
(Jennie) Jenkins was always Interested In fruit trees, grapes, real estate.
Insurance &#8212; never faming &#8212; althou^ all of his life he lived on the
farm. His wife had Inherited property on the Manson Pike from her father,
Nlmrod Jenkins, and here "Papa" and "Mammy" Mianson reaz&#171;d their ten
chlldren&gt;&#187;seven of vham lived to be married and have children of their
own.
Many stories are told of how "Fapa." would "take-off" to Texas to see
his relatives (Cousin Hal) and also to sell fruit trees. Hs just was too
kind and gentle to rear all those boys and girls. "Mammy" was a dynamo&#8212;
jtist barely five feet tall, beautiful and dainty, but quite quite force-full
In later years when I was in social welfare work and visited many of
the old age negro families I would be told stories of how *'Mamny Manson"
and "Miss Jennie" acted and how "Miss Jennie" gave the orders on the large
farm while "Mr. Manson" went to the office in town&#8212;driving his "Horse-n-buggy"
down Manson Pike through the "toUgate" ytbere a five cent fare had
to be paid by everyone else, but he "owned" the road. Actually the road
was owned and kept up by a groiq&gt; of landowners along the road.
}fy father, "Jim-Eddy", as his mother called him, was a dynamo also.
He began in early life to trade. An early venture was in having Cousin
Hal Manson, or someone in Texas ship a carload of Texas Ponies to him and
he'd sell at a profit. This trading in everything&#8212;ponies, cattle, farm-
57
lands, tijnber&gt; produce, and real estate took him at such a fast oUp that
In Florida during the big "booan" he died at the age of U9. hypertension
cotild be a family characteristic, so watch for it.
At the honeplace vhere Pop and Manny started housekeeping they had
everything that grandchildren would desireo-even an "office" in the yard
where we&#187;d be allowed to play when weather was really bad and %rtiere I
think I was actually bom although my earliest recollection is on the
porch of the pretty cottage (of about eight roomsj that daddy and mother
built when I came Into the world. It is still standing, but the constantly
enlarged hone of ray grandparents has been torn down and an interstate
road goes by. Still standing, however, is one of the old Jenkins home-steads
with the beautiful coltmns and tree shaded lawns.
In the "Depression Years" everything was lost-except family solid-arity.
Property manipulation proved disastrous, but the family helped
each other again and again and although some moved away and some passed
away always there remained the feeling of "belonging" to each other.
That's why I&#187;m writing this to the youngsters - - to help them understand
that the old saying "blood is thicker than water" is not trite. It is
true.
5g
REFBUENCSS
Correspondenoe from Mr. Lattrenoe B. Gardiner
in possession of Rosalind M. Jcones
- }ty Colonial Danes Papers -
Rosalind M. James
- }fy Huguenot Fapere -
Rosalind M. James
- Buford Family in America
by MUdred, page 363 on Manson Buford Mlnter
- William and Mary College Fraternity
Volume IO4 page US
- Virginia Magazine of History and Biography
Volume 31&#171; page 93
Registrars Office of Rutherford County^ Tenn
&gt; Family keepsakes
such as death notices^ old newspaper clippings, etc.
</dc:description>
<dc:description>A short history of the Manson Family of Rutherford County</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.); Genealogy</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Family histories</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>11 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-08;mt2011-02-28</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication19ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/56</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>