<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>The Harding house</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Coleman, Ellen Snell</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 23</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1984</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>19th century; 20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>THE HARDING HOUSE
By: Ellen Snell Coleman
When Giles Scales Harding and Mary Hollowell Blackman married they moved
to their two story log house. It was located in the Blackman area just off
the Manson Pike. This house served the family well for many years.
Sometime before the War between the States, Mr. Harding decided to
build a fine brick home for his family. He planned his house to excel 1 that
of his Uncle John Harding's home "Belle Meade" mansion in Davidson County.
Mr. Harding had the brick made on his farm and all his plans were made to
build his brick mansion, but the War started and that shattered all Mr.
Harding's plans for building his fine brick home.
When the Union soldiers first arrived at the Harding house, they immediately
took all the bricks which Mr. Harding had planned to use for building his new
home. The Union soldiers used the brick for breast work to protect their
own soldiers.
Giles Scales Harding married 10-7-1840 Mary Hollowell Blackman
born 11-13-1819 Davidson County born 4-24-1822
died 1-29-1892 Rutherford County died 8-8-1913
One day several Northern soldiers came to Mr. Harding's home, put a rope
around his neck and were ready to hang him on a tree, but several Union
officers rodeup just in time to save his life. They told their soldiers to
"turn that man loose, that he had not done anything to cause him to be hanged. "
The soldiers obeyed their superior officers and Mr. Harding went free.
The Union soldiers took Mrs. Harding's chickens and geese and her
smokehouse keys. To get meat from the smokehouse she would have to ask the
soldiers for her keys. She was a small lady and very spunky. She would fuss
at them and tell them she had to have meat from the smokehouse for her children.
Often they would dangle the keys over her head and she would have to jump up
to grab the keys and argue with them.
Before the Union soldiers came to take Mr. Hardings horses, Mrs. Harding
went to the barn and wrapped a cloth around the ankle of her favorite horse.
The Union soldiers came and took all the horses except the one with the wrapped
ankle.
Finally the Union soldiers took over the Harding house and used it for a
hospital for their wounded soldiers.
The Harding family was forced to leave their home, Mrs. Harding took her
children and went to her parents home. Her parents were Alfred Blackman and
Elizabeth Crawford Blackman. The Blackman community was named for Mrs. Harding's
father Alfred Blackman.
One day when the Yankee soldiers were using the Harding house for their
hospital they made a mistake and fired a cannon ball into the parlor and
killed several of their own soldiers who had been wounded and were lying on the
floor around the wall. The cannon ball also hit the leg of the Harding's
grand piano which was in the parlor. The soldiers called it the wounded piano.
After the war was over the Harding family came back to their home. All
the Union soldiers had gone except one. He was too weak to leave. His
comrades left him in one of the rooms of the Harding house. None of the older
members of the Harding family wanted to go near the Yankee soldier, but Mrs.
Harding said she did not want anyone to starve in her house even if he was a
Yankee. She made her daughter Ellen Amy take food and water to the soldier.
As soon as he gained enough strength he left. When he started to leave
he said he had a 2% dollar gold piece and he wanted to give it to Ellen Amy.
The family said no indeed they would not allow her to accept it. After the
soldier insisted they let her take it. The 2% dollar gold piece was dated 1851.
When Ellen Amy became a young lady she had the jeweler in Murfreesboro set
the 2% dollar gold piece in the center of a silver medallion which was given
to her by her great Uncle John Harding of "Belle Meade". The silver medallion
was from the saddle of Ellen Amy's great grandfather, Giles Harding Sr. He
used the saddle during the Revolutionary War. His initials (GH) were engraved
on the medallion.
The jeweler added a pin to the medallion with the 2% dollar gold piece in
the center. Ellen Amy used it as a pin or a belt buckle the rest of her life.
When she died her daughter Willie May Hill, who married Thomas Blackman Snell,
received the pin, and now Willie May's daughter Ellen Snell Coleman has it.
She is proud to have the pin not only because it was made from a relic of the
Revolutionary War, and a relic from the Civil War, but also because it was
cherrished by her grandmother and her mother as long as each of them lived.
Several years after the war was over some of the Yankee soldiers came back
to Murfreesboro to view the battlegrounds. Some of them took pictures of Mrs.
Harding's piano, and had the picture of the piano put on post cards and sold
the cards. They called it the wounded piano. The post cards were made for
them by Blumenthal and Becker, Publisher, in Murfreesboro. Many of the cards
were sold by the merchants in Murfreesboro.
This is one of the cards which Ellen Amy used to tell her daughter Emily
in Nashville to be sure to come to Murfreesboro to attend the fair and see
a cousin and his family who were visiting her. This note was written in 1906.
&#8226;J
I
u.
(J
. I &amp;*&lt;JLl&#163;&#8212;'JL
Pit&#163;&#171;-
*&#8226;*&#8226;
'&#171;
...r-^ &amp;**&#163;&#187;&gt;* ,^tl -V&lt;
r&#171;
\
C &#163; r*\ \
\
Cc \\\r
tec',
C. x l Tc &lt;* is*
H o ^ - *
s.V. &lt;
The old two story log house as well as the family went through many trials
and tribulations during the war. The house and the family stood through it
all until the late 1870's, when someone set a cedar bucket of hot ashes outside
and that caused the house to burn.
By the 1870's Mr. Harding had given up the idea of building a brick man-sion.
Three of their daughters had married, one infant daughter had died, and
one young son was kicked by a horse and died.
When the old two story house burned, Mr. Harding replaced it with a frame
house.
Mr. Harding died in 1892, Mrs. Harding lived until August 8, 1913.
Harding House of Later Years
This picture was taken September 18, 1895. Mrs. Harding was sitting in
a chair on the porch near the front door, and her daughter, Julia, was standing
on the porch near the banisters.
JOHN HARDING OF BELLE MEADE
John Harding married August 1, 1806 Susannah Shute
born 1777 Goochland County, Va. born 1785
died 1865 Davidson County, Tn. died 1845
Mr. Davis Garvin who was a Union soldier came back to Murfreesboro several
years after the war to view the old battlefield.
He went by the Harding home to apologize to Mrs. Harding for taking her
chickens and geese during the war. The Hardings accepted his apology and
showed him their southern hospitality.
Many years later Mr. Garvin come back to Murfreesboro and courted the
youngest Harding daughter, Julia Harding. They were married October 8, 1910.
The Harding family liked Mr. Garvin and said he was a good man.
Julia and Mr. Garvin lived with her mother until Mrs. Harding died in
1913. After Mrs. Harding's death Julia and Mr. Garvin moved to Raleigh,
North Carolina and lived there the rest of their lives.
.J
i /Is '
/fc?T y&#163;*/&lt; -/^&gt;* /^ft^c^t^ codfirsi*^
Z^ir+oJuJ^* cl y &lt;*&#163;** svurf^ shv-* ^^l_ I
11
Back of Mr. William Browning's letter
/Shr1&gt;-*lA&gt;-T&lt;**4si^ V^
"I
J &gt;
^J
12
The twelve children of Giles Scales Harding and Mary Hollowell Blackman Harding:
1. Mary Harding(born 1842) married M.P.G. Allen April 19, 1870
2. Elizabeth Harding (born 1843) married Samuel G. Patterson Dec. 19, 1866
3. Charlotte Harding died young
4. Ellen Amy Harding married November 9, 1871 Albert Gallatin Hill
born Feb. 22, 1848 born March 8, 1843
died Jan. 27, 1910 dies Aug. 18, 1910
5. Alfred Harding (born 1850)
6. George Harding (born 1858) was kicked by a horse and died young
7. Giles Scales Harding married Nov. 3, 1885 Lorena Peck Ransom
born 1854 born 1862
died 1922 died Feb. 18, 1932
(Lorena Peck Ransom was the daughter of Dr. Medicus Ransom
and Temperance Crawford Peck Ransom)
8. John Harding married March 2, 1887 Pricellar "Dee" Dickerson Self
born Dec. 28, 1855 born Dec. 29, 1859
died Nov. 1, 1943 died Feb. 25, 1921
9. Julia Harding married October 8, 1910 Davis Garvin
born 1860
died 1958
10. Thomas Battle Harding married Oct. 25, 1893 Mary Ellen "Mollie" Bell
born Feb. 3, 1863 born Jan. 19, 1870
died Aug. 31, 1957 died May 21, 1937
11. Morris Harding never married
born 1865
12. William Harding married October 30, 1889 Mattie S. Hall
born December 1, 1867 born July 4, 1869
died May 10, 1931 died April 12, 1926
Sources: census records, cemetery records, marriage records and oral history
from family
</dc:description>
<dc:description>A history of the Harding House in the Blackman community</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.); Historic buildings</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Blackman</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>13 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-01; mt2011-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication23ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/33</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>