<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>A history of Rutherford County railroad depots</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Green, Judy Lee</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 18</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1982</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>19th century; 20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>A HISTORY
of
RUTHERFORD COUNTY RAILROAD DEPOTS
by
JUDY LEE GREEN
This paper is not meant to be a definitive
statement on the history of depots in Ruth-erford
County but can best be utilized as a
stop along the line of road, much as the
depots themselves were passenger stops along
the railroad track I am continuing to col-lect
information relating to Rutherford Coun-ty
railroad stations .whether it be written
documentation, photographs, post cards, or
memories. Please contact me if you have
something you would like to contribute &lt; To
share history is to preserve it.
Judy Lee Green
893-0973
October, 1981
A HISTORY
of
RUTHERFORD COUNTY RAILROAD DEPOTS
The iron horse first burst through Rutherford County in
1851, huffing, puffing, smoking, shrieking, whistling a song
that signaled the beginning of an era for Middle Tennesseans.
It brought visitors, strangers and relatives alike; news}
mail; merchandise; and promises of economic opportunities and
social activities. It gave birth to the railroad depot which
sprang up in its wake and, in turn, spawned towns, produced
industry, and created the legendary station agent whose accom-plishments
will be preserved in the collective folklore of
railroad pioneers.
In the mid-eighteen hundreds there were no railroads op-erating
in Tennessee. James A. Whiteside, a member of the
state legislature from Hamilton County, and Dr. James Overton
from Nashville, Tennessee, were responsible for the charter
that the Nashville and Chattanooga Railroad received in 1845.
Vernon K. Stevenson, who was named president when the rail-road
was organized in 1848, went from house to house solic-iting
funds in support of the proposed organization. Residents
of Murfreesboro contributed $30,000 toward the purchase of cap-ei
3
2 ital stock, so eager were they for the railroad to be routed
through their town
In December, 1848, a contract was let to build the road
from Nashville to the Rutherford County line, and on June 19
of the following year the sections from Fly's Curve at Kimbro
to Murfreesboro and from Murfreesboro to the Duck River were
let.*
4" When completed in 1851, nearly thirty miles of track
extended from the northwest corner of Rutherford County at
LaVergne to the southern- portion of the county at Fosterville.
During the next fifty years, woodsheds, water stations, flag
stops, and an undetermined number of depots, both freight and
passenger, were constructed at strategic spots along the track
that ran through Rutherford County.
The first passenger train arrived in Murfreesboro on July
4, 1851. A crowd of fifteen hundred people from Nashville
joined the entire population of Rutherford County to welcome
the Tennessee . A great celebration was held to commemorate
the event that was predicted to open up a whole new world of
business, not only for the railroad but for farmers and busi-nessmen
as wello
The exact date and location of the first depot in Ruther-ford
County is not known. A freight house, however, had been
constructed at Murfreesboro in 1851. 7 Utilized by both armies,
if this structure survived the Civil War, it is possible that it
was razed by the Nashville and Chattanooga Railroad when a brick
freight and passenger depot was constructed in 186? at the
Salem Pike crossing. This building became strictly a freight
house when a brick passenger station was erected at the end of
West Main Street in 1887&#8222; Constructed by the Nashville, Chatt-anooga
and St. Louis Railway, this simple, rectangular-shaped,
This 1863 map of Civil War Murfreesboro is the only evidence I have
found that establishes the location of the 1851 depot. Note struc-ture
south of Rio Mills.
one-story complex featured a passenger terminal and baggage
house adjoined track side by a butterfly train shed. Though
it is now a freight agency and no longer a passenger stop, the
Murfreesboro depot, with few exterior alterations, still stands
today, a property of the Louisville and Nashville Railroad, The
following physical description will be of interest to future
historians.
A concrete foundation supports the Murfreesboro depot, which
features a brick exterior of common bond design and a hipped com-position
roof which, prior to 1968, was of the original roofing
material, slate. Fenestration includes multi-paned windows with
concrete sills and plain surrounds. Single leaf, glazed, and pan-eled
doors are enhanced by transoms. A small projecting bay on the
west side of the structure originally served as an operator's office.
Three concrete bands or courses completely surround the
depot. The doorways and four corners of the building have ver-tical
concrete reinforcement areas located between the two lower
courses. In addition, at the corners and doorways are conical-shaped
cast concrete decorative components approximately three
feet high. Utilitarian as well as decorative, they served as
bumpers to protect the building from damage done by railroad
wagons
.
The broad projecting eaves of the hipped roof are charac-terized
by exposed rafters and wooden brackets which rest on con-crete
corbels. The roof itself is enhanced by two conical-shaped
dormers featuring louvers on the east and west sides and bearing
the date of construction, 1887, on the north and south ends. Al-terations,
which include the removal of two cross gables on the
east facade, a larger cross gable over the operator's bay, two
chimneys, and decorative ridge trim, were made when the building was
reroofed in 1968.
The interior of the former NC&amp;StL RR terminal featured eight-een
feet ceilings, potbellied stoves, wainscoting, and decorative
bulls-eye motif corner blocks on door surrounds. Segregated waiting
rooms and restroom facilities were provided for blacks and whites.
The ticket office and operator's bay were located in the center of
the spatial arrangement. Though the interiority of the building
has suffered major alterations including lowered ceilings, tiled
floors, the addition of walls, and the application of green paint
on woodwork and even window panes, evidences of an earlier day
when steam was king can still be found. The integrity of the depot
has not suffered irreversible changes, only unsympathetic ones.
Located approximately thirty feet from the depot and connected
by a continuous butterfly shed, which features steel posts and
wooden beams and braces, is a smaller replica of the passenger
station, the baggage house. Currently it is used as a signal main-tainor's
office and storeroom. Though there Is some controversy
as to whether this building was erected in 1887 or was built a
few years later, it features the same characteristics as the depot*
the three encircling bands, the multi-paned windows, a brick ex-terior,
and a hipped roof. The interior of this building, however,
is brick, and its doorways include two sliding service doors of
d
diagonal boards. Prior to 1968 this building also featured a
chimney and decorative ridge trim on the roof.
At least three depots have served the citizens of Murfrees-boro.
Built 1851, 1867, and 1887, the latter one still stands in
its now-neglected garden-like setting, a silent reminder of an
unique American architectural form,
C. C. Henderson, in The Story of Murfreesboro , identifies
o
the first railroad ticket agent as William (Doc) Ledbetter,
Henderson seems to imply, however, that Ledbetter served the depot
constructed in 1867 and makes no reference to the 1851 depot or its
agents.
Perhaps the best known and most celebrated agent was John W&#171;
Thomas* who began his career as manager of the railroad hotel in
Murfreesboro and served almost fifty years in the employ of the
N&amp;C and (after 18?2) the NC&amp;StL Railroads, In November, 1858,
Thomas was appointed agent at Murfreesboro because of his famil-iarity
with railroad details. In due time he was recognized as
keeping the most accurate records on the line of road. As local
agent it became his responsibility to attend to the movement of
supplies and munitions for the Confederate forces when the Civil
War became a reality in Middle Tennessee. He distinguished him-self
by removing to the South and protecting valuable records and
rolling stock belonging to the Nashville and Chattanooga Railroad.
For the return after the war of railroad property, Thomas was pro-
12
moted to auditor and paymaster, the first of many promotions
which culminated in the presidency of the NC&amp;StL Railroad, a position
In 186? this brick passenger depot was constructed at the Salem
Pike railroad crossing by the N&amp;C Ry. This photograph was taken
in 1971. The depot was later razed by the L&amp;N RR&#8222;
This NC&amp;StL Ry station was erected in I887. It still stands at the
end of W. Main St&#8222; in Murfreesboro. (1976 photo)
10
1
3
he held for twenty-two years until his death in 1906.
MUrfreesboro was founded in 1811 and named for Col. Hardy
Murfree prior to the coming of the railroad. Other points along
the road, however, developed as a result of the railroad's in-fluence.
Stewartsboro, located on Stewart Creek near the Nash-ville
Pike, was a busy little community whose business was trans-
15
ferred to Smyrna after the railroad was completed,, A freight
and passenger house combined, designated as third class, was erect-ed
in 1851. By December of the same year a woodshed and a water
station had also been constructed. 1 Adjoining land, purchased by
the railroad company, was subdivided into sixty-four lots and offer-,
ed for sale at public auction. 17 Silas Tucker, former owner of the
land, may have been given the honor of naming the station and, sub-
1 ft
sequent ly, the town of Smyrna. On May 13, 1850, he donated four
acres of land for the establishment of the present town, after
19
selling thirty-six and three-fourths acres to the railroad company,.
The fate of Smyrna's first depot is not known. In 1873, how-ever,
a brick structure, a combination freight and passenger depot,
was erected by the newly merged Nashville, Chattanooga and St.
Louis Railway. 20 This building still stands today though it has
been remodeled extensively. An increase in rail traffic during
World War II brought many alterations. Also, a train wreck in July,
1950, damaged much of the building and demolished the entire south
A 21
end.
Today the Smyrna depot is located between the main line and the
house track of the Louisville and Nashville Railroad, east of the
11
old business district and west of Highway kl . A rectangular-shaped
structure with a brick exterior of common or American
bond design, it sits on a concrete foundation with a six inch
concrete course surrounding its entirety at ground level. A
split roof line is the only commentary on its boxcar-like ap-pearance.
A chimney punctuates the roof line on the west,, the
most original and least altered of the four sides of the build-ing.
Although exposed timber rafters and wooden brackets project
from beneath the eaves of the gabled depot roof, four original
brackets, more decorative than the others, still remain on the
west side. Likewise, four iron braces support the brick wall,
their tie rod plates visible on the interior. The Smyrna rail-road
station also features flat concrete lintels, brick sills,
and simple, uncomplicated fenestration (^A, large windows; 3/3,
small windows with glazed transoms above). Service doors are
located on the north and south ends and the west side. The north
opening has an original eight foot by eight foot sliding door
with diagonal boards.
The interior of the former Nashville, Chattanooga and St.
Louis Railway depot originally featured a freight house on the
south end; waiting rooms, restrooms, and office space in the cen-tral
portion; and a baggage room on the north end.
The freight house, or warehouse, on the south end is accessible
by two of the service doors mentioned above. Originally the in-terior
of this section was brick covered by a hard thick plaster.
Walls have now been stabilized by concrete blocks. The ceiling
12
is twelve feet high in this end of the building. A large floor
scale for weighing freight remains in the room.
The central section of the depot formerly contained separate
waiting rooms for blacks and whites with ceiling heights of ten
feet and concrete floors; restrooms, which were modified in space
configuration during World War II, making larger facilities avail-able
for the many soldiers who traveled by rail; and an agent's
office featuring a ticket counter. Prior to the train mishap in
July, 1950, an operator's bay was located on the west side of the
depot It was destroyed by the derailment, however, and was not
reconstructed when repairs were made to the building.
The north end of the depot was the baggage room, a temporary
shelter for trunks, suitcases, and mail bags. The third and orig-inal
service door is still operative here. During the 19^0s a
low-pitched gabled roofed (carport-type) shed was constructed off
the baggage room on the extreme north end of the buildingo Sup-ported
by six square wooden pillars, the roof provided protection
from the elements for the many traveling soldiers who could not
be accommodated in the small waiting room of the station during
World War II.
The Smyrna depot is no longer utilized as a passenger station,
nor does it provide office space for agents and operators A
L&amp;N Railroad signal maintainer and local train crew use the build-ing
on a limited basis today. Formerly an important station and
a busy stop on the railroad, the tr^in depot with its peeling
white paint, crumbling brick walls, falling plaster, and decaying
wood trim is an embarrassing conclusion to the history of rail-
13
road architecture in Smyrna. As the oldest depot in Rutherford
County still standing today, it deserves more consideration than
it has received in the past few years. Never an elaborate or
superfluous structure, the architectural contribution of the rural
railroad station is based on the very nature of its ubiquity.
Smyrna was not the only railroad station constructed in 1873
by the newly merged Nashville, Chattanooga and St. Louis Railway
Company. Florence, a combination passenger and freight depot,, was
erected in the same year midway between Murfreesboro and Smyrna
&#8222;
Named for the daughter of a station agent, 22 Florence was a brick
structure measuring twenty-five by fifty feet and constructed at
a cost of $2,647. The railroad retired this building in 1927&#8222;
Adjoining stock pens built in 1900 were retired in 19^6. 21
Christiana, a small settlement located near the Fosterville
community, was originally called Jordan's Valley. Apparently the
name Christiana was given to a Nashville and Chattanooga Railway
depot erected when the railroad passed through Rutherford County.
Eventually the area became known by that name
It has been alleged that James Grant, construction engineer
for the building of the railroad, was responsible for the naming
of all stations between Nashville and Chattanooga, Historical
evidence does not support this contention, however, in regard to
Rutherford County depots.
Whether Christiana was named in honor of a black railroad
cook, Christie Anna; or for a black child, Christ Daniel; or for
u
Smyrna, constructed in 1873. is Rutherford County's oldest existing
depot. Built by the NC&amp;StL Ry, it has been altered extensively
&#8222;
(1976 photo)
Fosterville, built in 1890 by the NC&amp;StL Ry, was the second depot
in the small community to suffer a tragic conclusion,, (1976 photo)
15
25
the wife or sweetheart of an early railroader Is not known.
It Is known, however, that James Grant was the first railroad
26
agent at Christiana. Though the construction date of the
first depot appears not to have been recorded, a woodshed and
27
horse-powered water station had been erected by December, 1851.
James Grant left the service of the Nashville and Chattanooga
28
Railway in 1859 but returned to their employ after the Civil War.
29
He passed away in 1869 before the second depot was constructed.
Therefore, the first Christiana railroad station was erected bet-ween
1851-1859 or between I865-I869, probably the earlier date. It
is reasonable to assume that a structure erected after the Civil
War would not have been replaced by a new building in 1882, If
the depot was built before the war, however, it may have been
damaged or unavoidably neglected by the railroad during the conflict.
The second Christiana depot, a combination passenger and
freight station, was erected in 1882 by the Nashville, Chattanooga
and St. Louis Railway.-^ A frame building of board and batten
construction, it featured a low-pitched gabled roof of tin, over-hanging
eaves supported by decorative brackets, simple fenestration,
and doorways graced by transoms. A wooden platform around the
building was enhanced by a picket underpinning. The structure was
31
retired from service by the railroad company in 19^2.-^
The following notice appeared in the Murfreesboro Free Press ,
Friday, September 27, l889i "The long-wished-for new depot is in
32
course of construction at Rucker." J No other information was
given, and subsequent newspapers available revealed no additional
16
Information. One can only speculate as to whether the word "new"
indicates the existence of an "old" depot.
The new Rucker train station, however, was a combination pas-senger
and freight depot. It was erected at a cost of $2,199#00 by
the Nashville, Chattanooga and St. Louis Railway. Rucker was re-tired
from service in 19^2 after serving more than fifty years..
Adjoining stock pens built in 1911 were utilized until 1923.
Old Fosterville, located in the southeast corner of Rutherford
County, was incorporated in 1832. It is thought to have been named
after John Poster, an early settler. When the Nashville and Chatt-anooga
Railway was completed in 1851, however, the small community
was relocated to advantage itself of the railroad. Responsible for
the move and the present site of Fosterville was Thomas Edwards,
3^
postmaster, station master, and railroad express agent.
No construction date is available for the first depot served
by Thomas Edwards and built by the Nashville and Chattanooga Rail-way.
Did this building survive the Civil War? Was it the same
depot still standing in 1886 when Goodspeed recorded that railroad
business at Fosterville amounted to $5t000 a year?-^ If so, this
depot was destroyed in March, 1890, when a ravaging cyclone demol-
36
ished the Fosterville community.
The Nashville, Chattanooga and St. Louis Railway erected a
combination passenger station and freight depot to replace the
decimated structure after the storm in 1890. The floor dimensions
of the new building measured twenty-four by seventy-five feet. It
was constructed at a cost of $3,531.00., Of board and batten con-
17
structlon, the building was simple and typical of rural railroad
stations. It featured a low-pitched gabled roof with wide over-hanging
eaves, decorative scrolled brackets reinforced by iron
rods, transoms, and doorways of diagonal boards..
The railroad retired the Fosterville agency in 19^2, Adjoin-ing
stock pens, built in 1911 &gt; were retired in 19^. The depot
was purchased by a private individual, moved from its original
site and relocated nearby. There it stood until March 26, 1977t
when Fosterville lost its second depots The building was con-sumed
by fire, apparently the work of arsonists who saw no architec-tural
value in the diminished splendor of the agrarian railroad
station, a tragic end to depot history in the Fosterville community.
The completion of the railroad through Rutherford County
brought prosperity soon after 1851 to a small community located
in the northeast corner. LaVergne, named for an early settler,
W
41
Francois Leonard Gregoire de Roulhac de LaVergne, 4o was incor-porated
by an act of the General Assembly in 1861,
By December, I852, a steam-powered water station had been com-pleted
at LaVergne , though the construction date of the first
depot is unknown. It seems reasonable to assume, however, that in
order for the railroad to have an effect on the economy -* in the
area, a railroad station must have been in use. This was probably
the same building acknowledged in December, 1862, by General William
Starke Rosecrans as he advanced with his Federal forces towards
Murfreesboro preceding the Battle of Stone's River and found La-
Vergne "to be a small village with a desirable railroad depot that
id
could move men and supplies closer to Murfreesboro."
There is no evidence at this time to suggest that the La-
Vergne depot was destroyed during the Civil War. Assuming that
it withstood the use and misuse of an occupying army, it was prob-ably
still standing in late I867 or early 1868 when James Richard
Park, an employee of the Nashville and Chattanooga Railway, was
promoted to station agent at LaVergnc Cherry Shade, located
across from the railroad station, became the home of Park and his
new bride. Not only did the dedicated railroad employee keep his
own home and yard neat and attractive, but he planted flowers to
make the depot pleasant and more enjoyable for the many people who
traveled by rail before the turn of the century.
The fate of LaVergne's first depot is unknown. It was prob-ably
razed by the Nashville, Chattanooga and St. Louis Railway in
1901 when a new passenger terminal and freight station was erected.
The frame building, of board and batten construction, measured
thirty by eighty feet. It stood between the main line and the
house track of the NC&amp;StL Railway, near the present site of the
Tennessee Farmers Co-op. Constructed at a cost of $3176^000,,
LaVergne^ second depot served the community for fifty years be-
^6
fore it was retired by the NC&amp;StL Railway, in 1951.
Shelters for the comfort and convenience of revenue passengers-were
constructed by the railroad at intervals throughout Rutherford
County. Known as flag stops, they were designated as points for
trains to receive passengers when flagged or to discharge them
along the line of road. Caretakers were sometimes employed by the
19
railroad, but agents were not assigned to these locations.
Winstead, located four miles south of Murfreesboro, was a
flag stop though no shelter seems to have existed at that loca-tion.
It is not known at this time whether a shelter stood at
Russell, located north of Murfreesboro on the railroad line. A
flag stop existed at the National Cemetery though the date of
construction is unavailable. The Jefferson Pike stop, located
between LaVergne and Smyrna, was built in 1902 o
The Wade flag stop was constructed in 1905. A tiny fourteen
by sixteen feet, it featured a board and batten exterior and was
erected at a cost of $632.00. Its small size and physical appear-ance
was probably typical of the other shelters constructed along
the railroad line. Wade was located two miles south of Smyrna and
four miles north of the Florence depot. The railroad retired the
structure in 1936.
The depot or railroad station for almost a century was the
focal point of many small towns. In Rutherford County, March 15,
1968, marked the end of an era in railroad history. As the last
passenger train regularly scheduled to stop at Murfreesboro pulled
into the station in the early hours of the morning, not even the
local agent was on hand to greet it. The last "All aboard*" must
have echoed off the empty walls, quite a contrast to the hulla-baloo
created by the arrival of the first passenger train in
Murfreesboro more than a hundred years earlier.
Gone are the steam engines, the passenger trains. The
clickity-clack of the "limiteds," the "expresses," and the "flyers"
20
has been replaced by the roar and the rumble of the 7*4-7s and
the DC9s. Gone are the station agents, and gone are eleven of
the thirteen depots that have served as the economic and social
centers throughout Rutherford County,, We must rejoice in our
nostalgic moments, however, for through the preservation of dim
records, faded photographs, and tales of old men, our children
and grandchildren will be able to recapture the romanticism of
the railroad era and re-create the glory of the depot in its
finest moment.
Mufreesboro Depot about 1 300
21
RAILROAD ROUTE
Nashville
^LaVergne - 2 depots - c.1851; 1901
jJefferson Pike - flag stop - 1902
^Smyrna - 2 depots - I85I1 I873
Wade - flag stop - 1905
Florence - 1 depot - 1873
Russell - flag stop - shelter unknown
National Cemetery - flag stop - no date
Murfreesboro - 3 depots - 1851; 186?; 1887
Winstead-f lag stop - no shelter
Rucker - 1 depot - I889
Christiana - 2 depots - C.I85I; 1882
Fosterville - 2 depots - C.I85I5 1890
JJ Chattanooga
This map Identifies the locations and construction dates of 13
Rutherford County depots and 5 flag stops. (I suspect there were
others. This is not meant to be a scaled drawing. JLG)
22
FOOTNOTES
^Richard E. Prince, Nashville , Chattanooga and St . Louis
Railway (Green River, Wyo.&#171; Richard E. Prince, 1967) t P&#171; &#176;.
2
T. Do Clark, "The Development of the Nashville and Chatt-anooga
Railroad," Tennessee Historical Magazine , III, No. 3
(1935). P. 167.
^Goodspeed's General History of Tennessee ( Nashville t Good-speed
Pub. Co., 1887), P. 816.
Thomas N. Johns, Sr. , "The Nashville and Chattanooga Rail-road
through Rutherford County, 1845-1872," Rutherford County
Historical Society , No. 5 (1975). P. 10.
-'Goodspeed.
Johns, p. 17.
7 Ibid., p. 16.
Q
Structures Section, Engineering Dept., L&amp;N Railroad,
Louisville, Ky.
"c. C. Henderson, The Story of Murfreesboro (M*Boro.t News-
Banner Pub. Co., 1929), P. 115o
1 John W. Thomas (NC&amp;St.L Ry., no date), pp. 7-8
11 Ibld., p 11.
12
Ibld., pp. 8-9.
13 Ibid., p. 10o
Goodspeed, p. 826.
15 Ibid. f p. 83*+.
Johns, p. 16.
'Walter K. Hoover, History of the Town of Smyrna , Tennessee
(Nashville: McQuiddy, 1968), p. 5.
l8Ibid., p. 74.
19Ibid., p. 338o
20
Structures Section, L&amp;N RR.
21 Hoover, p. 344,
23
22Grlfflth (Rutherford Co. Bicentennial Commission, 1976).
^Structures Section, L&amp;N RR.
c*Johns, pp. 11-12.
25Grlfflth .
26
Johns, p. 12.
27 Ibld , P. 16.
28
Ibid., p. 12.
29Mary B. Hughes, Hearthstones (M&#187;Boro.&#187; Mid-South Pub. Co.,
19^2; reprint ed., I960), p. 5^&#187;
30Structures Section, L&amp;N RR.
31 Ibid
o
3 2Free Press . 27 Sept. 1889, P. If (MFM 84, 1820-1950 Newspapers).
33Structures Section, L&amp;N RR.
^Elvira Brothers, "The story of Fosterville," Rutherford County
Historical Society . No. 16 (1981), pp. 44-46.
3 *Goodspeed, p. 819.
5 Brothers, p. 47.
37Structures Section, L&amp;N RR.
38Ibld
39"Fires Strike County; Old Depot Bums," Dally News Journal,
27 March 1977, p. 1. cols. 2-3.
Griffith.
Gbodspeed, p. 834.
Johns, p. 16.
43Shirley Chaney, "History of LaVergne," Rutherford County
Historical Society , No. 6 (1976), p. 63.
^Ibid., Po 64.
^5James L. Chrlsman, "A Story of Cherry Shade, LaVergne, Term-essee,"
Rutherford County Historical Society, No. 16 (1981), PP. b*-b5,
^Structures Section, L&amp;N RR. 7Grifflth
Structures Section, L&amp;N RR.</dc:description>
<dc:description>A short history of railroad depots in Rutherford County</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Railroad stations--Tennessee; Rutherford County (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>transportation</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>23 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-15</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication18ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/172</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>