<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Memoirs of James M. Tompkins</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Tompkins, James M.</dc:creator>
<dc:contributor>Walkup, William Tompkins</dc:contributor>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 2</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1888; 1973</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>19th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>32
MEMOIRS OF
JAI4ES M. TOMPKINS
* Written by Himself
JAMES M. TOMPKINS, son of Wm. and Sarah Tompkins, was born
in the County of Fluvanna, Virginia, on Adren's Creek, on the
18th day of October, 1807. He remained with his Father, (who
lived in Fluvanna County, Va. , except the years of 1818 and 1819,
in which years he resided in Albemarle County, Va., two miles
North of Charlottsville, ) until the year 1827. His recollection
cannot go back when he did not have a firm belief in the truth
of the Christian Religion. In October, 1826, he made a public
profession of Religion, and was baptized by the Rev. Moses Brock,
and became a member of the Methodist Episcopal Church, at the
Union Mills Church, in the county of Fluvanna. On the 25th day
of October, 1827, he was married by the Rev. John Goss , to Kitty G.
Rucker, daughter of Elza and Mary P. Rucker, of Orange County, Va.
In December, 1827, he left the County of Fluvanna, and settled in
Orange County, Va . , near Caves-Ville, and joined the Orange Church
in that neighborhood. He resided in Orange County until December,
1830, at which time he moved and settled in Albemarle County, Va.,
six miles South of Charlottsville, and became a member of the
Church at Temple Hill Church, He remained in Albemarle County,
Va., until September, 1831, at which time he left the State of
* An original copy of this document is the property of William
Tompkins Walkup of Smyrna, Tennessee. Mr. Walkup claims Mayor
Tompkins as an ancestor of his.
33
Virginia and moved to the State of Tennessee, and settled on
Overall's Creek in the County of Rutherford, and became a member
of the Church at Asberry Church. In March, 1836, he was elected
a Justice of the Peace for the Sixth District of Rutherford
County. In July, 1837, he was elected Surveyor for the County
of Rutherford by the County Court of said County. In June, 1812,
he petitioned and was accepted and became a member of Mount Moriah
Lodge, No. 18, of Ancient Free and Accepted York Masons. He
received all the degrees in the Blue Lodge, Chapter and Council.
He was elected several times Master of said Lodge, which he
esteemed the highest honor ever conferred upon him. In March,
1816, he was elected by the people of said County Sheriff for
Rutherford County. In March 1818 and in March 1850, he was
re-elected to the same office. In March, 1852, he retired from
said office, having served as long as the Constitution of the
State would allow, and having discharged the duties of said office
with satisfaction as far as he knows and believes to all, except
evil doors. In August, 1855, he was elected by the people of
the County of Rutherford a member of the State Legislature of
Tennessee, for the Session of 1855 and 1856. This was an office
he did not seek nor desire it, never having any desire to engage
in political life. In December ,' 1859 , he sold out his farm in
the country known as Cherry Flat, four miles North-west of
Murfreesboro, moved to Murfreesboro and settled in Town, and
became a member of the Methodist Episcopal Church, (South) in
Murfreesboro, and was appointed one of the Stewarts of said Church.
He having raised and educated the children, being seven in number.
34
one daughter and six sons, to-wit:&#8212;Sarah Margaret, Benjamin C,
William R. , Robert T. , James E. , George T. and Albert G. Tompkins,
and becoming old and infirm in health, and being desirous of
leading a quiet and peaceable life the balance of his days, and
not any more engage in the busy scenes of life- and at peace with
all men. But, alast wicked and designing men. North and South,
not having the fear of God before their eyes, and being instigated
by evil and selfish designs, determined to brake up and ruin our
once happy and beloved country and government, if they could not
govern it to suit their own views. They brought on and instigated
an uncalled for rebellion and civil war. He was opposed to all
this procedure, and done all in his power to prevent it, believing
that it was our duty to seek redress for all our wrongs by law,
in the Congress of the United States, and not to go out of the
Union and resort to arms for redress, until all other ways and
means should fail; he believing and so argued, that if we separated
from the Union and went to war, that nothing awaited us but defeat,
distress and woe. The State of Tennessee voted to go out of the
Union in May, 1861, by a large majority of votes. He being a
Southern man, born and raised in the South, all his sympathies
being with the Southern people, and all he had among them, and
although it was like rending soul and body asunder to see the
beloved Union of the United States, that had been established and
cemented by the blood of his ancestors, torn asunder, and a civil
war instituted, he quietly submitted to the fate of his State and
Country, and only acting in doing all the good he could to relieve
the wants and distresses of the people among whom he lived; daily
35
asking God to guide, preserve and protect us. His course and
views gave displeasure to some, and caused ill-feelings to be
engendered in a few towards him; but his course of conduct and
acts was directed by his judgment, and what he conscientiously
believed to be right, and therefore, he acted regardless of
consequences. He believed that the South had been imposed upon
and our rights invaded and denied us, but he never believed in
the doctrine of secession or the right of States to secede from
the Union at will. In December, 1861, he was elected one of the
Aldermen of the town of Murfreesboro. In 1862 he was elected by
the Aldermen, Mayor of Murfreesboro, and acted as Mayor until
all civil and municipal law ceased by the action of the war. In
October, 1861, he took an active part in restoring Civil Law in
our country, and re-establishing and opening the Courts, at which
time he was appointed by Chancelor John P. Steele, Clerk and
Master of the Chancery Court of Rutherford County, Tennessee; and
he appointed his son, Robert T. Tompkins, Deputy Clerk and Master
of said Court, which office they still fill at this date, (1888).
In 1882, owing to some ill-feelings engendered in the minds of some
of the members of his Church, (which he had been a member of for
upwards of forty years; which Church he loved and reverenced as
a Mother,) he withdrew from said Church, and obtained a letter
of withdrawal, which letter he kept, hoping, wishing and praying
that the cause of his withdrawing might be satisfactorily adjusted,
but seeing advances made in that way by the offending parties,
and after giving the subject a long, careful and prayerful
36
consideration, and feeling it to be the duty of every Professing
Christian to belong to and be a member of a Christian Church, in
August 1888, he presented his letter to the Cumberland Presbyterian
Church in Murfreesboro, and became a member of that Church, having
full faith in its being a genuing Christian Church in Orthodoxy,
and believing he could serve God acceptably in the same.
I have written this condensed Memoir as a present to my
Children, a Memento to my memory&#8212;hoping and praying that they
may all make good and useful citizens, and do more good than I
have done; that they may fill their stations in life with honor,
and never disgrace the humble character and name of their Father-hoping
we all may meet in Heaven.
December 16th, 1888. JAMES M. TOMPKINS</dc:description>
<dc:description>Personal memoirs of James M. Tompkins, who stood up as Murfreesboro's mayor during Union occupation</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Memoirs and biographies; Murfreesboro (Tenn.) -- History; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>mayors; public officials; Tompkins, James M.</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>9 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-16</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication02ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/131</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>