<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>The diary of F.E. Henderson</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Henderson, F.E.</dc:creator>
<dc:contributor>Matheny; Betty; Matheny, Jim; Woodfin, Virginia</dc:contributor>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 10</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1864; 1978</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>THE
DIARY
OF
F. E. HENDERSON
1864.
INTRODUCTION
On January 1, 1864 a pocket diary x:ao preoented to F. E. Henderson by
her father. Hot nuch is knOTjn about F. E, Henderson. She tjas the doi'shtor of
Albert Gallatin nendcroon, a cotton broker, and Elizabeth Love Henderson and
va3 one of eight children. Most of the days were spent at her much loved homo,
"l/hitehall", one of the stateliest and best furnished homes on the Nachvillc-
Uurfreesboro Turnpike. F. E. Henderson was the great aunt of Mrs, Virginia
VJoodfln, an active and loved member of the Rutherford County Historical Society.
It is by her generosity that this diary is being published.
The pages of the diary are yellowed and show the one hundred plus years,
but the reading divulges even more compassion and love by this young lady for
her family and fellow man. The contents of the diary cover a scope from sewing,
ironing, etc, , to helping soldiers from both the South and the North. Realizing
the fact that conething &#171;ill be lost for the reader by not having the opportunity
to feel, hold, and decipher the actual daily entries, we are printing two samples.
The first, August 9, 1864, was written in ink with great flair and the style
indicative of the era. It suggests a quill or old type pen with split point.
The second, December 31, 1864, was done in pencil and let the person use one
single stroke and almost make the entries appear to be two different handwritings.
After spending many, many hours with this diary and a magnifying glass,
F, E. Henderson became very much a part of our lives, as though we lived each
day of 1864 with her, Ue feel that it will be as meaningful to all who read it.
Betty and Jim Matheny
1864. DIARY of F. E. HENDERSON
Aunt of Mrs. Virginia Woodfin
Transcribed by Betty and Jim Matheny
Presented to: F. E. Henderson
By: Her Father, Albert Gallatin Henderson
Friday. January 1. 1864. Very cold. I don't think I ever saw such cold
weather,
Saturday. January 2nd One gown. Many men to see for cold yet. Many men
to see for cold yet. One pair stockings, one apron.
Sunday. January 3rd Snowing today. I think it has turned warmer.
Monday. January 4-th Raining. The rain is melting the snow. Esq. Johns
came over and brought a note to me from Tommie. I sent her comb to her.
Tuesday. January 5th Snowing again. Grandma is sick. She was taken with
a pain in her side-suffered much.
Wednesday. January 6th Still cold. Have not seen a lady until today.
Aunt Nansie Smith came. Grandma has got better,
Thursday. January 7th Snowing again today. Buddy is setting his trap to
see if he can't catch some little snow birds. Squire Wade was married.
Friday. January 8th Esq. Bridges came over to see Pa on business. First
time I ever saw him.
Saturday. January 9th Pretty day. Snow on the ground. Mr. Jack Ward came
over in the evening.
Simday. January 10th Pa went to Mr. Tuck Davis, also Mr. Bryant. Uncle
John went to Mr. Harlen Gilly. Harlen has the measles. Dick Wade came to
see Pa.
Monday. January 11th Pa went to Nashville, also Uncle John. Did not go
back to school, Coramenced to make Ma a dress. Uncle John got us a guard,
Mr. Haverfield. John Thomas came,
Tuesday. January 12th Mrs. Warford sent after her things that Pa got her
in Nashville. 1-tr. Hagar got a load of cotton,
V/ednesday. January 13th 1-trs, Ward came over. Told us she heard Jimmie
was a prisoner. Sister went home with her, came back in the evening, and
I went home v/ith the girls.
Thursday. January lAth Cloudy and cool. Stayed at Mrs. Wards until
everybody came home. The girls came home with me but went back. Miss Addie
Sikes and Aunt Nansie Smith to sew.
Friday. January 15th Cousin Frank Atkinson was here today. Buddy went
home with him. Cousin John Thomas left today. Mr. Haverfield has left.
Snow still on the ground,
Saturday. January 16th Went to Mr. J. J. Ward. Had quite a nice time with
those girls playing Old Maid with cards. Commenced to crosia some for a
skirt.
Svmday. January 17th Raining all day. Ma and Pa went to Mr. Walden. Heard
Mr. Donagon was dead of Nashville.
^bnday. January 18th Pa went to Mr. George House. Mr. Peoples, Mrs. Peoples,
Mss Mattie People, Miss Kate McMurray came to go to Nashville with Pa.
Tuesday. January 19th Mrs. Peoples came over to see if the girls wanted
to go to Nashville. They went dovm to the station and waited until after
dark. &gt;frs. Uilson and Capt. W came.
Wednesday. Jamjary_20th Pa went to Nashville. Mrs. Peoples and the
girls left. Isabelle Ward and Vie cane. Mrs. Johns and Mi-.. Johns came.
Fannie ;irrote to me. Cannonading at Franlclin.
Thursday. January 21 nt Mr. Ward came over. Cannonading in the direction
of Nashville. Pa returned from Nashville. Alley went home with Jimmie.
Friday^ JamjarY_22nd Ma went to Mr. J. J. Ward's&#8212;took Sister and the
baby. Isabella came home with her. Nearly finished my dress. Col. An-derson
here today,
Saturday. January 23rd V/ent to Mr. VJards. Isabella and I went to Mr.
Bryan. Stayed all night with Isabella. l-Irs. Vardell was here. Mrs. Ben
Ward was here,
Sunday. January 2Z.th Came home, found the house full of men as usual.
Monday. January 25th Did not go back to school. Mr. George House was
here, Mrs, Beet Ward was here.
Tuesday. January 26th Pa went to Nashville also Mr. Prater. Mrs. Hut son
and her sister here today. Sister went to Mr. Ward to stay all night.
V/ednesday. January 27th Sister came back. Beth and Mr. Ward came with
her. Stayed all day. Mr. Prater and Pa got home from Nashville.
Thursday. January 28th I'trs. Vanderford, Nat Nelson, Miss Tea Allen, Mrs.
Davis, Mss Mollie Johns, 1-frs. Johns, f'tiss Kate Jobe, Miss Ann Jobe, Sam
Maththis buying goods.
Friday. January 29th Mrs. Standavar, Mr, Col. Mannon, Mr. Captain Wilson
were here yesterday. Mandy, Mary, Ward, Fannie, Seward, Mrs. Ben Ward were
here. Sister went to Mrs. Donaway's.
Saturday. January 30th Miss Sallie White was here. The Federals are going
to leave the Stockade and go front to Chattanooga. Mrs. Ward and Josephene
were here.
Sunday. JanuarT^llst Raining a little. Mrs. Ben Ward was over. Mr.
Bryan and Pa v;ent to Lavergne, Miss Tea Allen, Mrs. Davis were here.
Monday. February 1, I864. Sister and I went to school. Mrs. Blackmoore
had many new scholars since I was there. Mrs. Blackmoore employed an
assistant, Mr. McClain. I got home sick the first day.
Tuesday. February 2nd Pa has gone to Nashville. Miss Sallie Edwards and
Mass Jobe came to see Mia and came to trade. Miss Addle sent me my head dress.
Wednesday.. February 3rd Pa has returned from Nashville. Vxs. Ridley and
Mrs. Thurston went to Nashville. Tommie Johns and Leroy stayed all night
\-d.th us.
Thursday, February ./^th Cousin Dick Henderson got here from the Southern
Army. Says the Rebels have got possession of Knoxville. Heard from brother.
Is well--he is Lieutenant,
Friday. February 5th Cousin Tom Atkinson came after us to go home. IVhen
we were coming, ny horse tried to run away. Cloudy, turning very cold.
Saturday. February 6th Went to Mrs, Best Ward to get Mandy' s Algebra.
V/rote my composition. Raining this morning.
Sunday. February 7th Cousin Dick, Sister, Buddy, and my self went to
Cousin Frank Atkinson's to see Cousin Sue. She seemed very glad to see us.
V/ent to Mrs. Donaway.
Ifenday. February 8th V/ent to school. Mrs. Blackmoore was sick. Went
to see Tomnie Johns and Lucy. Saw R-uf" Johns.
Tuesday, February 9th Mr. McClain taught. Commenced studying Algebra.
Mrs, Blackmoore not much better,
Wednesday. February 10th A case of Small Pox at Mr, Mitchell's. Very
much frightened,
Thursday. February 11th No school. Uncle John and Buddy came after us.
Stopped to see Isabella, Saw a conpany of Negro soldiers.
Friday. February 12th Cousin Dick and Uncle John went bird hunting. Sister
and I v/ent over to I^. Ward's. Isabella and Victoria came to spend the
night,
Saturday, February 13th Mrs. Ward came over. The girls went hone. VJent
bird hunting again. Cousin Dick, Uncle John, Mr. Hickman Weekley here,
Mr, Bryant.
Sunday. February Hth Cloudy and cool. Ma and Uncle John went to Mrs.
Best Ward, Alice and Bessie have the measles,
Monday. February 15th Turning cold, but rained, Mrs. Vaughn and 1-lr.
Vaughn v;ere here, Dick VJade here.
Tuesday, February I6th Very cold. No one here but Miss Sallie White and
Mdss Johnson,
Wednesday. Febrxxary 17th Very cold. Pa and Cousin Dick went to Nashville.
Cousin Tom and Sue went after Mandy Ward to come and stay all night with us,
Thursday. February 18th Cold, yet beautiful day. Sister and myself walked
with Mandy home. All quiet when we left, but very soon we heard that they
were conscripting negroes, and all of ours ran away.
Friday. February 19th Many men to see Pa, but he did not come home as we
expected.
Saturday. February 20th Spent the night at Mr. Ward's.
Simday. February 21st Cousin Dick came over. Isabella and Vic came home
with us. Cousin Dick and Ma went to Mr, Marlin's, Uncle John came. Walked
home with Isabella.
Monday. February 22nd Miss Bettie Pratt to see us. Pa went to Mr, George
W. Smith, Carried sister and I as far as Mr. Sikes&#8212;had a pleasant visit,
Mr. Cook and Will Wade here,
Tuesday, February 23rd Pa and Mr, Cook went to Nashville. Heard Rebel
Morgan attacked Gallatin. Mr. White came to guard us.
Wednesday, February 2Ath Cousin Tom and I went to Mr. Alden's. Went to
Mrs, Donaway to get her to knit my rebel. Walked over to Mr. Ward. He was
better, I think,
Thursday. February 25th Mrs. J. J, Ward came over to get Uncle John to
go with her to Lavergne to see Col, Smith about her negroes they pressed.
Mr, Sikes came.
Friday. February 26th Mrs. Huggins and Mrs. Hall came. Miss Lois Jobe and
Miss Mollie Carter came. Mrs, Lieutenant Hoke and Sergeant Stansel came to
get a bed to take to camp.
Saturday. February 27th Sister went to Mrs. Ward to see the girls. Stayed
all night. I went to Mr.. Ward's to get some of the girls to stay all night
with me, but could not stay. They came to see us.
Sunday. February 28th I went to Mrs. Ward to see how the girls were. Drought
sister home. Ma and Pa went to Mr, Sikes.
Monday. February 29th Raining,
Tuesday. March 1 st 1 86^ Rain, hail and snow. Made Ida a apron and Eugene
a pair of drawers.
Wednesday. March 2nd Mr. Bryant came over. He and Pa went to Nashville,
Cousin Dick and sister went over to Mr. Ward to get the girls to stay all
night, Isabella came,
Thursday. March 3rd Big frost. Cousin Dick was sick last night. Isabella
went home. Pa got home&#8212;brought my braid,
Friday. March 4-th Mrs, Ward and Victoria came. Vic brought sister's crosia
braid. Gave her the braid to make mine,
Saturday. March 5th Warm day, A Yankee came to hear us play. He paid
us five cants apiece. He was drimk.
Sunday. March 6th Cousin Tom, sister, and myself went to Mr. Waldens.
Lost my knife, but found it again. Miss Strand.
Monday. March 7th Stayed all night with Mr. Chip. Serance and sister are
playing smart now. I went home with Miss Seranah Highton. Pa came after me
in the evening,
Tuesday. March 8th Miss Bettie Pratt and Mss Hoke came over&#8212; stayed until
after dinner. We all walked over to Mr. Ward's. Mrs. Hoke wanted a Confed-erate
bonnet.
Wednesday. March 9th Mj-s. Hord and Mrs. House v;anted to buy cotton seed.
Sister, Cousin Dick, and myself walked to Cousin Mat,
Thursday. March 10th Commenced to make me a dress. Sister finished her
dress. Went to Mr, Ward's and got Vic to stay all night with us.
Friday. March 11th Finished my dress. Pa and Ma went to Mr. Davis'. We
did not go home until evening. Sister and I went and stayed all night.
Saturday. I4arch 12th Mrs, Davis and Miss Tea Allen came to Mr. Ward's&#8212;
stayed all day. In the evening Ma and Pa came after us.
Sunday, March 13th Sister, Pa, and myself spent the day at Col. Anderson's.
Saw painting of Mr. and Mrs. Anderson that Mr. Macy painted.
Monday. March Uth Went to school. Mrs, Marlin and Mrs, Hoke came. Uncle
John and Cousin Dick went to Murfreesboro,
Tuesday. March 15th Pa and Cousin Dick went to Nashville. Ma sent Ida
and Ann over to l^trs. Ward's to get Isabella to stay all night.
Wednesday. March I6th Pa and Cousin Dick came from Nashville. Got a letter
from Aunt Mat&#8212;all's well.
Thursday. March 17th Pretty day. Turning cool, Mrs. Ward came.
Friday. March 18th Pretty day. Miss May and Mrs, Thomas came. Came after
us very late.
Saturday. March 19th Cousin Dick, Ma, and Ida went to Mr. Ualdens. Sister
and myself went and spent the night. Saw Mrs. Owens.
Sunday. March 20th Came home-sister and myself. Cousin Dick and Uncle
John and I and V W Mandy V/ard all went to church over the river. Grandma came.
Monday. March 21st Went to school.
Tuesday. I^farch 22nd Cool today. Bad rainy weather.
Wednesday. March 23rd Isabella and Victoria V/ard came. Esq. Sikes and
Miss Addie came.
Thursday. March 24.th Grandma and Ida spent the day at Mrs. Marlin's.
Mrs. Ward and I'frs. House came,
Friday. March 25th Raining. Esq. Sikes and Miss Addie came&#8212;took Allie
home with her. Pa came after us in the buggy.
Saturday. March 26th Went to Mr. Ward's. Vic cajne home with us and stayed
all night.
Sunday. March 27th Went to Mr. Marlin's. Finishing writing my composition.
Miss Bettie Pratt spent the night with us.
Monday. March 28th Went to school as usual. Miss Lucy Donohue and Jimmie
came to stay all night in order to go to Nashville the next morning.
Tuesday. March 29th Pa went to Nashville. Mr. and Mrs. Bryant came to go
to Nashville. Mrs, Ward came over. Charley quite sick. Miss Serena stayed
with Ma,
10
Wednesday. March 30th Pa came home from Nashville. Jim Creach's baby died.
Thursday. March 31st Mrs. Creach's baby was buried. I attended the burial.
Sprinkling rain in the evening,
Friday. April 1. 1864. Raining all day. Uncle John came after us. Mrs.
Vaughn came to our house.
Satvirday. April 2nd Mrs. Best Ward, Mary, Sister Jarrel, and Mrs. Rolston
were here,
Sunday. April 3rd Isabella and Vic, sister and myself, and Cousin Tom
went to Mr, .Walden's.
Monday. April /th I was sick&#8212;did not go to school. Mrs. Best Ward came.
Good deal of rain and hail.
Tuesday. April_5th Pa went to Nashville. Mr. Davis came.
Vfcdnesday,. April_6th Beautiful day. Very much like Spring. Pa came
from Nashville.
Thursday. April 7th Mr. Sikes and Miss Addie came. Grandma came. I ^
crociaed a net for Ida,
Friday. April. 8th Rained. Charley and Katy sick.
Saturday, j^pril 9th Sister and I stewed some molasses. I and V came,
Mandy, Mary had quite a nice time pulling candy, I went home with I,
Stayed all night,
Sunday. April 10th Came home. I and V came. I stayed at home all day.
11
Monday. April 11th Going to school. Grandma went to Mrs, Ward's. Monday
evening Mrs, Marlln came.
Tuesday. April 12th Pa went to Nashville. Mrs. Farmer and Mrs. Hooker came.
Sqiiire Wade and Mr, Bryant came.
Wednesday. April 13th No one came to our house. Mrs. Ridley went to Nash-ville.
Pa returned from Nashville. I took the song, Lilly Dale.
Thursday. April 14.th Grandma went to Mrs. Best Ward's and spent the night.
Friday. April 15th Grandma came home. I returned from school. Mrs. Jack
Ward came and spent the day.
Saturday. April I6th Pretty day. Grandma, sister, and myself went to
Mr, Marlin's.
Sunday. April 17th Mrs, Vanderford came, Mrs, Ward, Isabella, and Vic
came. Raining, We went to Sq, Johns' and spent the night.
Monday. April 18th Pa and Mr. Ward went to Nashville. Miss Serana stayed
with Ma tonight,
Tuesday. April 19th Miss Serana went home, Ida went home with her. Mary
and Eliza House came from Nashville with Pa,
Wednesday. April 20th Warm&#8212;very pretty day. Sister, Lucy Johns, and my-self
went to Mrs, Allen's,
Thursday. April 21st I'lrs, Blackmore went to Nashville, Tommy Johns and
I taught school. Ma, Pa, and Buddy came after us. Isabella and Mrs. Ward
here,
Friday. April 22nd Went to Mr, Ward's to get Isabella to help me make a
dress. Did not finish it, Fannie Seward came here.
12
Saturday, April 23rd I am sick today. Went to Mrs. Donoway'so Stopped
at Mr. Walden's.
Sunday. April 24.th Raining. In the afternoon Uncle John, sister, and my-self
walked over to Mr, Ward's. Ifeny Ward, Bettie Jarrel, and Bettie Ward
were there.
Monday. April 2$th Went to school. Miss Serana came down and finished
our dresses.
Tuesday. April 26th Isabella came and stayed all night with Ma. Beautiful
day.
Wednesday. April 27th Raining. Isabella went home. Took Katie with her
to stay all night,
Thursday, April 28th V/ent home with Tommie. Walked down on the river bank
where Ruffus Johns was fishing. He was going to bring to carry us home, but
Uncle J came,
Friday. April 29th The day of oiir picnic has come at last. I never enjoyed
myself more in my life. Had quite a nice ride back. Tommie came home with. me.
Saturday. April 30th Raining all day. Miss Serana went home. Mrs. Ward
and Mary came. I had a severe headache.
Sunday. May 1. 1864. Sick again. Many and Isabella Ward came, Tommie went
home. Isabella stayed all night with me. Pa and Ma went to Col. Anderson's.
Monday. May 2nd It is cool this morning. Sister did not go to school. She
went home with Isabella. Vic came home with her.
Tuesday. May 3rd Beautiful day. Pa went to Nashville.
13
Wednesday^. May /^th Pa brought me a nice pair of cloth garters and a muslin
dress.
Thursday. I-lay 5th Mrs. Vanderford, Miss Leda, Addie Sikes, Miss Bass,
Mandy, and Mary came. Sister and I went home with them and spent the night.
Friday. Ifey. 6th Aunt Nancy Smith, Miss Mary Donoway, Miss Bettie Pratt,
Mrs. Jack V/ard, Vic, Mrs. Rooker, and Mrs. Spy Ward came. Sister sick.
Saturday^_ May,. 7th Pa and sister went to Nashville. Miss Bettie Pratt sent
me two little pigeons. Miss Kate Jobe came and spent the day.
Sunday. May 8th Pretty day. Mr. Ward, Isabella, and Vic Ward came and spent
the evening. We all walked over to the old fort.
Mionday. May 9th Sister and I did not go to school. Miss Tea Allen commenced
teaching school. Alley, Ida, and Eugene went to school. Mrs. Vanderford
brought Carlie hat home. Mandy and Mary here.
Tuesday. May 10th Raining all day. The children did not go to school.
Charlie is sick.
Wednesday. May 11th Cloudy and raining. The children did not go to school.
Mrs, Best Ward.
Thursday. Miay 12th Pretty day. Mrs. Coleman here.
Friday. May 13th Beautiful day. Mrs. Ward, Bessie, Mrs. Ward, and Victoria
came. Sister went and stayed all night with Vic.
Saturday. May Hth Pa and I went to Nashville. Saw lie, and Mrs. Sheperd
and Willie Grigg. Received a letter from brother.
u
Siirday. I^y.lSth Pretty day. Sister and myself went to Fir-s. Ward's. I am
very sorry to say that Eugene is a bad boy, and that when he goes to school,
he idles away his time. He is called a bad and lazy boy.
Monday, Fay I6th Went to school. Raining in the evening.
Tuesday.. May 17th Raining again.
Wednesday._.Mayi1 8th Itrs. Best Ward came over to see Ma and Grandma.
Thursday:,_May;_1 9th Pretty day&#8482;very v;arm. Brother a prisoner. Went dovm
on the cars, threw a note off.
Friday. May 20th Beautiful day&#8212;very' warm. Came home from school&#8212;heard
Brother was a prisoner.
Saturday., MayiSI r,t . Very pretty day. Mrs. Blackmore came and left Ibllie
Thurston. Her and she v;ent to Walden's. Ma went to Mrs. J. Ward's, Ida
and Charley.
Sunday,. May ..22nd Pa returned from Nashville. Did not get to see Brother
but a fev; minutes. He v.'as well. Sister and I v/ent to Mrs. Sikes'.
Monday, May 23rd Went to school. Mrs. Blackm.ore sick. Toramie and I taught
school.
Tuesday. May..2/,.th Mrs. Blackmore still sick. Toramie and I still teaching.
Raining, thundering. Tonmiie and I went over to get Mir. Bell to get him to
teach, but he '.rould not.
Wednesday, . .t'nyi.25th Mrs. Thurston and lies. Ridley went to Tommie, Mrs.
Blaclcmore right sick. Raining in the evening. I came hom.e from school.
15
Thursdayt. .^^ay 26th Sister came home. Lucy and Mr. Johns came home with
her. We all walked over to Miss Tea Allen's school house.
Friday. May 27th Mr. Sikes came. Ma and Pa went to lAr, Sikes'. I expect
to go home with Lucy and stay all night. Walked down to the sulphur springs.
Saturday. MayiJSth Still at Esq. Squire John's. Enjoyed nyself very much
indeed. Mr, Johns, Tommie, Lucy, and myself took a ride down the pike.
Came back and went to the sulphur springs.
Sunday. Viay 29th Miss Mollie Johns sick. I went to church&#8212;heard a very
interesting sermon, l^fr. Johns and Tommie and Lucy came home with me.
Monday. Viay 30th Beautiful day. Mr. and Mrs. Vaughn came and spent the
day. I tucked some sleeves for sister. Did not go back to school.
Tuesday. Ma;^Jl3t Very cold this morning. Some appearances of rain. I
wish I could see Tommie, I feel quite lonesome. This is the last day of May.
Wednesday. June 1st Beautiful day. Helped Ma to make her dress.
Thm-sday. June 2nd Mr, Hickman Weakley came here. Ma, sister, Charlie, and
Eugene went visiting. Raining very hard. Ma and the children could not get
home, Vic and Isabella stayed all night.
Friday. June 3rd They have gone home, and I am so onesome. I wish I could
see Tommie, my dear school mate. Mr. Garret was here from Nashville. Ma
and the children came home.
Saturday. June 4.th Cloudy, I think it will rain. Ann and Mary went to the
Yanks.
16
Sunday. June $th In the evening Cousin Dick, sister. Uncle John, and my-self
went to Sqxiire John^' and ^f^. Johns, Miss 1-bllie, and Toininie went down
to the Spring.
Monday^ June 6th I went to school. Rained in the evening.
Tuesday. June__7th Aunt Nancie Smith came, Mr. Weekley and Gather went to
Nashville. Raining in the evening.
Wednesday. June 8th Raining in the evening. Pa returned from Nashville.
Thursday. June 9th Mss Tea Allen sick. The children did not go to school.
Mr. J, J. Ward also Frances Seward. Raining in the evening.
Friday. June 10th Sick yet, I came home from school. Aunt Nancie came
here. Rained very hard,
Saturday,_.Jun e^ 1 1 th Pa went to Nashville. Cousin Dick, Mia, and I went
to Mr. Sikesl. Cousin Dick went to Murfreesboro. I stopped at Mrs. Donoway
to give 1-lary my dress to make,
Sunday, June 12th Meda Davis and Mr, Davis came. Uncle John, Meda,
sister, and myself went to Mrs. V/ard's. Grandma went to Jack Ward.
Monday. June 13th Beautiful day. Mrs. Ward and Mandy came. Mass Tea Allen
sick yet. Eugene sick yet. Tommie is sick,
Tuesday. June Hth Pretty day. No lady came. Very warm. Tommie is sick yet.
Wednesday. June 1!;th Beautiful day. Mrs. J. Ward here. The Yankees
searched Mr. Ewing Jones and Mrs. Ridley's house for arms&#8212;found none.
I went to see Tom.
17
Thursday. June I6th Miss Luda Sikes and Miss Bass here. Tommie is better.
Friday. June 17th We had compaxiy at school to hear us read our coinpositions.
Sister and I came home from school. Eugene is sick.
Saturday. June 18th Made me a dress.
Sunday. June 19th Went to Mr, Ward's. Looking for Tommie.
Monday. June ?Oth Went to school. Took a piece of music called Prize
Banner Polka. Tommie is sick, and I am distressed.
Tuesday. June 21st She is yet. I wrote her a letter.
Wednesday. June 22nd Sister and myself went to Squire Johns' to see Tommie.
We all went down to the sulphur springs.
Thursday. June 23rd Pretty day.
Friday. June 24.th We had a great deal of company to hear us read our com-positions.
Miss l^bllie Johns and Mister Ruffus Jolins came.
Saturday. June 25;th Grandma at Mr. Ward's. I made me a dress.
Sunday. Jtme 26th Uncle John went to Mr. Ward's. He is very sick with the
bilious fever.
Monday. June 27th Went to school. Rode from hom,e, went to Mr. Walden, and
to Mrs. Donav/ay to get my dress.
Tuesday. June 28th Went to school. Pretty day.
Wednesday. June 29th Raining. Last day of school.
18
Thursday. June 30th Pa and Miss Eugenia A went to Nashville. Grandma uent
to Mr. Ward's. He is a little worse. Pretty day.
Friday. July 1 . 1 864- Beautiful day. Uncle John went to the picnic. Sister
and I did not go. Pa and Cousin Dick returned from Nashville.
Saturday, July 2nd Delightful weather.
Sunday. July 3rd Raining. I'fe, Cousin Dick, Sister, and Buddy went to Mr.
V/ard ' s
.
Monday. July 4-th Cloudy.
Tuesday. July 5th Pretty day. Esq. Sikes and Guard came. Grandma went to
Mr. Ward's. Pa, Kate, and myself went to Squire Sikes',
Wednesday, July 6th Mrs. Jarrel and Sister came. Mrs. J. J. 'Ward came.
Thursday. July 7th Raining. Grandma came home. Vars. B. Ward came.
Friday. July 8th Raining. Cousin Dick went to Mr. Luck Davis' to see
Miss Drucia Davis. I wish I could see Tom, my husband. I am so lonesome
this evening. Tom came to see me.
Saturday, July 9th Cousin Dick went after Miss Drucia to go to the picnic.
I cried all day because I could not go. Beautiful day. I wish I was in
Heaven. Miss Mollie and Tom came Saturday evening. Had a very nice time.
Tom and I did not go to sleep until U o'clock.
Sunday. July 10th Uncle John came, and I went home with him.
Monday. July 11th Sister and I busy at work on her body. Got it done.
Mrs. Ward, l^s. Farmer, and Mrs. Blackmore came. I wish to the Lord I could
see Tom, my first my lasting only and my all, with the exception of Izonia.
19
Tuesday. July 12th Made my body.
Wednesday. July 13th 14ade me an under dress and tucked it.
Thursday. July l^th Commenced me a body.
Friday. July 15th Pa and Squire Wade came from Nashville.
Saturday. July I6th Miss Blackmore came over. Sister and myself went.
Mass Pattie Burton and Miss Ellie Winter came from Lebanon.
Sunday. July 17th Took a ride in the morning and also in the evening and
came home. Got home about dusk.
Monday. July 18th Grandma, sister, and Ma have gone to Mr. Sikes. I v;rote
a letter to Cousin Lou Beasley.
Tuesday. July 19th V&amp; went to Mr. Sikes'.
Wednesday. July 20th Pa and Sister went to Nashville. Sent Brother a box
of provisions. Sister stayed all night at Mr. Read's. Mrs. Judge Ridley's
house burned.
Thursday. July 21 st Sister dined at 14r. Jeff French's. Started home.
Friday. July 22nd Pretty day. Grandma and Uncle John started up the
country. Hear Esq. Jobes house was burned.
Saturday, July 23rd I went to Mr. Sikes'&#8212;stayed until after dinner. Miss
Addie and I iient to l-hirfreesboro. I went to Mrs. Elliott's&#8212;saw Miss Jimrnie
and Mrs. Will Elliott.
20
Sunday. July 24.th Uncle John and I went to Church. Went froi?. there to
Squire Johns!. Tommie not there. Saw Mrs. Dlackmore, Mrs. Ridley, and Mrs.
Brantwell. Lucy came home with us.
Monday. July 25th 14a and Pa went to Col Anderson. Spent the day. Some
ladies called to see Cousin Dick.
Tuesday. July 26th Made me a dress to have my photograph taken in. Pretty,
warm day. Oh! Hov; I could hug Tom if he was here. That letter from Tom&#8212;how
I long to see it.
Wednesday. July 27th Pa and I went to Nashville. Went to Mr. Jeff French
and spent the night. Enjoyed myself exceedingly v;ell. Had my photograph
taken.
Thursday. July 28th Mrs. French and I ^/ent to Dr. Reed's. Saw his lady
&#8212;
very much pleased l.^dth her. Carae home from Nashville.
Friday. July 29th Sister and Lucy v;ent to Squire Johns'. Uncle John
v;ent to a picnic on Surges Creek.
Saturday. July 30th Mrs. Ward and Mandy came and stayed until after dinner.
Uncle John and I had a frolic throwing water on each other. Uncle John and I
went over to Mr. Ward's. He is better.
Sunday. July 31st Rainy, bad day. No company at all. Had fish for dinner.
Monday. August 1. 186^ Mrs. Ridley came. I went up to Mr. Walden's after
Miss Pattie Bur low. '//hen I got back, Sister had arrived from Squire Johns'.
Looks very much like rain.
Tuesday. Auf-ust 2nd Pretty day, very warm. Firs. J. J. Ward canie over.
Sister went home with her. Isabella came home with her. I went to Col A.
Wednesday. August 3rd Isabella went home. Pa went to Nashville. Rained
very hard about dinner. I scolloped some cuffs.
Thursday. August ^th Pretty day, very warm. Pa returned from Nashville,
Received letters from Aunt I-lat and Brother.
Friday. August $th Col. Anderson went down to our house to get the papers
and letters. Brought me my photograph. Tommy, Lucy, and 3cott Winter came
dovm to see me.
Saturday. August 6th Warm, pretty day. Yesterday Mrs. Vanderford and I
went to Mr. 3ikes~saw Delia and Louise Watkins. Pa and Uncle John went to
town.
Sunday. August 7th Mss Eugenia and Col. A and myself went to Mr. lord's.
I'b. and Sister went to Mr. Wards. Saw Mandy and Kary, the two Rebel Commanders.
Monday. August 8th Kiss Eugenia commenced Mrs. A a dress. Fa came for me.
Sister at Mr. Sikes. Miss Addie went to Dr. Richardson.
Tuesday. August 9th Made one sleeve of Mrs. a. dress. I learned a new piece
of music, "Grand Russian March". Pretty, warm day.
Wednesday. August 10th Pa went to Nashville with Squire Wade. K-r. Ilite
came over and told us that Miss Lottie White shot a negro. She went on the
train this evening, Isabella stayed all night.
22
Thursday. Au.g:ust 11th T made a starch bag for I. She gave me a black
ring. Mrs. J. Ward came over and Judge Tinsley came. Commenced me a clove.
Pa came from Nashville.
Friday. August 12th Col. A. came down. Mr. Bryant came over. Ma and I
went to see Mrs. Dlackmore&#8212; she is very sick. Went to Esq. Johns'. Tom
came home with me.
Saturday. August 13th Uncle John, Tommie, and myself went over to Mit, Ward's.
Sister came home from Mr. Sikes. Pa went to Murfreesboro. Somebody stole
I4andy W, horse. Bod.
Sunday. August Kth Raining nearly all day. We all took a ride and got some
peaches. Tommie went home. Vic and Ifr. Ward and Charley came.
Monday. August 15th Mrs. Ward came. Rained. Mrs. Farmer and Mir. James'
little daughter came. Uncle John moved to his house. Nearly finished Uncle
J's pants.
Tuesday. August 16th Mrs. Vaughn and Mr, Vaughn came, some men froii: Nash-ville
came, I-lrs, Vanderford and Eugene came, and Uncle John and Grandma came.
It rained,
Wednesday. August 17th I made a pillow slip for Uncle John. Raining yet.
Pa and Mr, Kible went to Nashville.
Thursday, August 18th Mr. King here, Mr. Vanderford, Sister, Cousin Tom,
Uncle J, and myself went over to Bachelor's Rest to see the house. Went to
the cave. We got some peaches. Pa returned from N. Got a letter from Brother.
Friday. August 19th Miss Fannie Sev/ards, Miss Farmer came. Col. ilnderson
came after Mrs. Vanderford. Very lonesome after she left. Ma, Pa, and Ida
went to Jim Basken's, Cousin Narcissy came.
23
Saturday. August 20th Jimiiiie Jones and Granville Ridley came. Buddy and
Eugene went home with Granville and got some pears. Pa and Sister went to
Murfreesboro
.
Sunday. ^Au^st 21 st Raining yet. Sister and nyself bought a watermelon.
I wrote a letter to Brother.
MondaYjt._Au^st_ 22nd Very cool for August. Pa and Mr. Charley Alley spent
the day at Dick V/ade's. Mr. Coleman and Mr. Ward came. I finished my
underbody. Wrote a letter to Aunt Mat,
Tuesday, Aupust 23rd 1-lrs, Johnson and Mr, Sikes here. Several men here.
Grandma went to Mr. Marlin's, Cousin Dick and I went to Mr. Sikes. I made
a body to vsy dress
&#187;
Wednesday. August 22^th Pa went to Nashville. Pretty day.
.Thursday, August 25th Jimmle W. arrived at Johnson's. Cousin Dick, Sister,
and nyself went to ^b?. Ward's. Went to see John. Miss Kate Hicks, Miss Ellen
Hicks, and Vic stayed all night. Pa got back from N. Pa received a letter
from Brother,
Friday. August 26th The ladies went to Mr. Furgerson. Mrs. Ward, Mandy, and
Isabella went to Murfreesboro. Pretty day. Somebody tried to get in the
house tonight. Uncle John stayed all night with us.
Saturday. August 27th Great many men. Col. Anderson, Miss Eugenia A. and
Eugene came. Miss Eugenia married. Uncle John stayed with us again tonight.
Sunday. August 28th Magnificent day. Miss Eugenia and inyself wrote a letter
to Willie, V/e all went to the sulphur springs. Had a delightful ride on
horseback. I-lr. Ward here.
2^
Monday. August 29th Finished Kate's dress. Pretty day, little cool. Pa,
Miss Eugenia, Sister, and myself took a ride. Col. Anderson came, brought
Eugene Vanderford with him.
Tuesday. August 30th Mr. Sikes and MLss Addie came before breakfast. Mr.
Huggins and Allie Ridley came.
Wednesday. August 31st Pa and Uncle John went to Nashville. Wheeler, the
Rebel, came in with 8,000 men. Pa saw Tommie Black and a little fellow
called Saterfield.
Thursday. September 1 . 1 SGU Pa came home. Did not see any more rebels.
They have gone doim towards Nashville;
Friday. September 2nd Cloudy. Miss Eugenia went home. Ma went home with
her and stayed nearly all day. Granville Ridley, Allen Gooch, and John Espy
joined the Rebels. Hurrah for them!
Saturday. September 3rd Saw some Yankees and in a short time, some Rebels.
Then I saw some more Y. They were very much excited. Wanted to knov; if there
had been any grey-backs here. They formed in line of battle in front of the
house. They went on to Jefferson. Gen'l Steadman and his staff dined at
Squire Johns'. They came back about sundown. Said that they had driven
Wheeler out of the state.
Sunday. September /4th Gen'l Steadman and staff suppered here. I played on
the piano for them. Sunday, all quiet.
Monday. September gth Beautiful weather. Rain before dinner very much
unexpected. Grandiria moved over to King house.
Tuesday. September 6th Pretty day. No one to see us. Evening gathered
some cucumbers for pickles.
25
Wednesday. Septeinber 7th Mrs. Anbross Bass and I-1iss Eliza Dass car.e and
stayed until after dinner. I rained very hard, thundered and lightning.
A tree v/as struck very near the house.
Thursday, Septeinber 8th Cloudy, cut Ida out a dress, nearly finished it.
Cut out Buddy two shirts. Johnny came over in his cart. I played for
some Yanks.
Friday. September 9th Via. finished Ida's dress. I'x. V/ard and Vic carae.
Stayed until nearly dinner. Meda Davis and Miss Kate Hicks came. Vx.
Huggins and Allie came. The wagon started to N with a bale of nev; cotton.
Saturday. September 10th Cousin Dick' and Pa went to Nashville. Big
Caroline went to Murfreesboro. Got a letter from Brother. He sent Pa a
very nice ring.
Sunday. September 11th Ifrs. Hord came. Col. A sent a letter dovm here
from Leakward Anderson stating that Aunt Mat and family had gone to Craw-fordsville.
V/e all went over to see Grandma.
I-fonday. September 12th Vxs, Slkes, Mss Luda, Miss Addie, Jeannie J.,
and Jessie J. came. Commenced to make Ma a dress. Uncle John came over.
Tuesday. September 13th Expected to go with Pa to Murfreesboro, but when I
got to Mr. S. Miss Addie was sick and would not go. Mrs. B came to car
house. Sister went with her to Mr. Walden's to spend the night. Mi's. V
came over to Vx, S. I came home.
Wednesday. September Hth Pa and Cousin Dick went to Nashville. Miss M^ary
and Martha Donav/ay came. Col. Anderson and several men came. Cousin Tom
and myself went to Mr. Walden's after sister. Pa and Cousin Dick and Mr.
Herman Weekley here, just returned from Huntsville, Alabama.
26
Thursday. September 15th Governor Johnson has called out the militia of
Tennessee&#8212;from 18 to 4-5. Kiiss Eugenia and Col, A came. Vxs. Sikes and N'lss
Addie and Dr. Black came and told us lirs. Watkins will take us to board to
go to school to Miss Sallie Nelson.
Friday. September I6th Miss Tea Allen, Mrs. Davis, Mrs. Ward, Miss Mary,
and Martha Donaway came. Sister and myself went over to see Grandma. Mrs.
Best Ward, Mr, Ward, and Vic came. The latter stayed all night. I wrote a
letter to Brother.
Saturday. September 17th I went to Murfreesboro with Miss Addie. Got
several little things. I stayed all night with Miss Addie.
Sunday. September 18th Uncle John and Ida came after me. Pa, Mr. Watkins,
Grandma, Sister, and myself went over to Mr&#171;oWard.
Monday. September 19th Uncle John brought Sister and myself over to Mrs.
Watkins'. Went down to the school room. Miss Sallie Nelson is the teacher.
Tuesday. September 20th Knew all my lessons. I am studying history of
France. Spell and define Arithmetic. Beautiful day!
Wednesday. September 21st tollie Watkins came to school. Cloudy. I passed
under and over a natural bridge yesterday evening.
Thursday. September 22nd Cloudy. Went to school as usual. Knew all my
lessons well.
Friday. September 23rd Rained very hard in the night and some rain about
12 o'clock.
Saturday. September 24.th We all quilted right smart. Mj. Watkins went to
Dr. Black. He was better. I looked for Pa.
27
Sunday. September 25th. Dobb went home. I wrote a letter to Ma. I spent
the morning writing to Brother and Tom. Got my lessons in the evening.
Ktonday. September 26th Beautiful day. Two new scholars, Sallie Patent
and Mary Eliza House,
Tuesday. September 27th Cloudy. Coming home from school it rained, and we
all got ringing wet,
Wednesday. September 28th Pretty day. Pa came to Dr. Black's, and I
came down to Mrs. Watkins' with him. He brought us some clothes.
Thursday. September 29th Pretty day. I am very well satisfied up here.
I wish I could see Tominy,
Friday. September 30th Cloudy. Looks very much like rain. It rained
very hard in the night.
Saturday. October 1. 1864. Cloudy again this morning. I hope it won't
rain. It has rained.
Sunday. October 2nd Pretty day. Delia, Mary Eliza House, and myself went
to Mrs. Rucker. Miss Sue came down to see Mollie Wilkinson.
Monday. October 3rd Rained when we rode home from school.
Tuesday. October 4-th Rained all day. We rode to and from school. Aunt
Nancie Smith stayed all night at our house.
Wednesday. October 5th Cloudy day,
Thursday. October 6th Pretty day,
Friday. October 7th Delightful day.
Saturday. October 8th Most delightful day.
Sinday. October 9th Mrs. Watkins, Delia, and Mary Eliza House vent tn churrh
at Mr. Michelle. They saw Miss Mollie Pubbs.
Monday. October 10th All went to school. Most pretty day.
Tuesday. October 11th Very pretty day.
VJednesday. October 12th Pretty day. Brother is sick in prison. Ter V.'-idp.
Thursday. October 13th Pretty day. Heard Grandma was dead.
Friday. October 14.th Pretty day. Pa. came after Sister and myself to j^o
home. Mary Eliza went home.
Saturday. October 1 5th Pa and Cousin Jo Irby went to Nashville. I.'ncle
Pleasant and Uncle John went to Murfreesboro,
Sunday. October I6th Uncle Pleasant and Uncle Johnny went to Fellowship
to church. Great many men at our house.
Monday. October 17th Uncle John brought Sister and myself to V.rz. Wntkins.
Mary Eliza had come.
Tuesday. October 18th Went to school. I got a bad cold.
Wednesday. October 19th Cold yet. Mass Nannie Black and Miss Sullie Nelnon
stayed all night.
Thursday. October 20th Sister and Delia came home. Sister cut her dress
body. Miss Sallie walked home with us.
Friday, October 21st Pretty day. 'Willie and Sammy Butch knocked the
girls some hickory nuts.
29
Saturday. October 22nd I cut out my dress body. Hemmed Sister's d'^ess
skirt. She made my dress body. I sent a note to Ma by Dobb.
Sunday. October 23rd I got my lesson wrote off the definition. V/rote n
letter describing my visit south.
Monday, October 24.th Went to school. Callie Pajton had come back.
Tuesday. October 2$th Pretty day. Knew all my lessons. Sewed my dress
on the body and the sleeves in.
Wednesday. October 26th Rained. Mrs. Watkins sent the carriage after us.
Thursday. October 27th Rained all night. Mary House would not sleep with
me. Delia and myself came home. I called Jane and they would not let her
come with me.
Friday. October 28th Pretty morning. Mary Eliza House went hom.e.
Saturday. October 29th Cloudy and cool. Pa came to bring our clothes. We
finished our calico dresses.
Sunday. October 30th Pretty day. Mrs. Watkins, Louise, and Sister went to
Mrs. Rucker's&#8212;spent the evening. Louise and Sister stayed all night.
Monday. October 31st Pretty day. Mary Eliza House came back from home.
Tuesday. November 1. 1864- Beautiful day!
Wednesday. November 2nd Rained very hard.
Thursday. November 3rd Raining. We did not go to school. I cut my delain
dress out and made the body.
Friday. November /i^th Raining. Miss Mollie sick.
30
Saturday. November 5th Pretty day. Very cool. Miss Sue spent the night.
Miss Nannie Black and Miss Sallie Nelson came. Received a letter from Brother.
Sunday. November 6th Pretty day. Miss Mary &#163;, House and Miss Delia Watkins
went up to Mrs, Rucker's to spend the night. Miss Sue sent for me to come.
We saw a rebel ,
Monday. November 7th Rained all day. We came home and went to school in
the carriage, .
Tuesday. November 8th Rained all day,
Wednesday. November 9th Raining all day, I am perfectly sick of rainy
weather
,
Thursday. November 10th Beautiful day, I am very glad it has quit raining,
for I ajn expecting to go home,
Friday. November 11th Beautiful day, Mary &#163;, House' Brother came and we all
went to Mrs. Watkins in a few minutes. Pa came after dinner. We were off
for home. We stopped in town and got two silk handerchiefs for Sister and
nyself and two con^josition books,
Saturday. November 12th Pretty day, I cut my calico body out and fitted it.
Mrs, Blackmore died at eleven o'clock Saturday night.
Sunday. November 13th Beautiful day. Uncle John, Sister, and myself
started to see Mrs, Blackmore and met Tonmie and Mrs, John. John's cousins,
Addie and Nelly, came to our house,
Monday. November Hth Uncle John, Ma, Sister, and nyself went to the funeral.
Mrs. Nevals stayed at our house while we were gone. Cousin Sue and Lucy came
to our house.
31
TuesdaYj_ Noveinber 1 5th Raining, Uncle John brought us back to school.
We stopped in Murfreesboro at Mrs. Elliott's&#8212;saw Miss Lilly Brown.
Wednesday&#8222; Noveimber _1 6th Raining.
'Thursday,, NoveTiber. 17th Rained all day. I cut out my under dress and
Eade it.
Friday;, November _1 8th Rained all day, I cut out my blue dress and run
up the skirt, hemmed it, put the trimming around the skirt, and made the sleevcf
Saturda.y\t_ November 1 9.th Rained all dayo I sewed on my dress.
Sunday,_November_20th Rained all day. The river is rising. It is nearly
even vd.th the Mill Dam,
Monday_,_ November 21 sjt Went to school. It snowed very hard.
TugsdaY,,_ November_22nd Very cold. Snow on the ground.
Wednesday.__ Nov ember 23rd Very cold. Sister and I came home from school to
take a music lesson. Mary E. House is having her teeth fixed.
Thursday.,. November_ 2/i.th Dr. Walsh has not finished her teeth.
Friday, November 2 gth Pleasant. I'irs. V/atkins went to town. Mary House
went home. I am looking for the rebels.
Saturday... November _26th Raining all day. Finished my calico dress. I
washed my silk handkerchief. Little Sue came to see us. Dobb went home.
Sunday. November 27th Raining nearly all day. Miss Sue came. I was kept
busy getting my lessons and writing my letter.
32
MondaV. Nov ernb er 28th Cloudy. I took a piece of music called "General
Stonewall Jackcon". Mary Eliza did not come back. Miss l-follie went to Dr.
Black's to spend the night. Heard good nev/s for all rebels. Got two letters
from Brother, Pa uent to Nashville.
Tuesday., Noveraber 29th Cloudy. The rebels are coming. Vlss Kollie came
home. Dr. Black started to I4irfreesboro, but the pickets told hira that he
could not bring out anything.
Wednesday._November .30th I'^ary Eliza came. Very warm today&#8212;did not wear
my shawl to school. Cannonading very distinct. Received a letter from Ma,
I am going home in two weeks.
Thursday., December 1 . 1 864 Beautiful day. Heard some cannonading. Very
warm for the season. Pa is coming after us tomorrow,
Friday,. December 2nd Raining. Pa came after us. Met Judge Tinsley. He
and Pa had a long talk. 17e came by Mr, Sikes' and stopped. Brought Charley's
sack Kdss Addie braided for him,
.
Saturday., Decem-ber 3rd Very cold. Uncle John went after Grandma. Judge
Tinsley and lady to see us. Some men here, not as many as usual. Rebels
came here in the night.
Sunday, December /.th Nice day. Some rebels spying around the block house,
iimong the squad was Dr. Ridley, The Yankees shot at him, but did not hurt him.
Monday. December $th Pretty day. The Federals evacuated the block house.
Rebels everyv;hcre. They burned the bridges and block house. Miss Addie
came and brought Annie with her.
33
Tuesday. Pecember_6th Beautiful day. General Forrest came up from Nashville.
Wednesday^_ December_7th Pa and Sister went to Esq. Sikes' to hear the
news. MTo Vanderford went home.
Thursday,., December, 8th Very cold. Uncle Charley went to camps, but came
back and spent the night. Enjoyed myself finely.
Friday._._DeGnmber^_9th Cold. Uncle Charley WEnt to camp, but came back .Jith
General Forrest and spent the night. I had the honor of mending his pants.
Saturday.._Dec ember lOth Sleeting. Very cold. Went to camps.
Sunday.&#8222;. Dec ember _ l.l.th Uncle Charley spent the night with us.
Mondayv^ December, 12th Snow on the ground. Uncle Charley took dinner with us.
Tuesday., Deceraber^l 3th Cloudy&#8212;very cold. Uncle Charley and Capt. Painter.
My l6th birthday. Was presented a ring from Ma.
V/ednesday .&#8222; December 1 Ath Very cold. Uncle Charley spent the night.
Thursday. December 15th Warm, Uncle Charley went to camps. Thomas
attacked Hood. Great many Yankees killed. Fear Rebels.
Friday,^ December I6th Warm, Uncle Charley and Major Strains came for his
last time. Hood retreated.
Saturday._December 17th Raining all day.
Sunday,. December 18th Raining all day. Cousin Dick and I went to Mr. Ward's.
Monday,..&#8222;December 19th Raining all day. Yankees ventured out to work on
the railroad.
3^
Tuesday. December 20th Very cold indeed, I-k and I are working en r;y dress.
Rained and hailed. All the rebels gone.
V/ednesday. December 21 st Snowing. Pa and I went to Mrs. V/atkins' after my
trunk. A good many federals here today and dined.
Thursday, December 22nd Very cold ineeed. Ma and I were working on n.y dress,
Friday. December 23rd Pa and Cousin Dick went to Nashville. Squire Johns
and Vjr. King here. Sewing on my dress. Getting ready for Christm^as.
Quite cold.
Saturday. December 2Z.th Pa and Cousin Dick returned from Nashville v/ith
Christmas goodies. I made a pound cake and was kept quite busy preparing
for Christmas, We had a nice eggnog.
Sunday. December 25th Christmas Day. Ida and Buddy were invited to Vx.
Suggs to a Christmas Tree, I went to Mr, Johns' and Lucy, Isabella, Vic,
and Miss Lanny Burrus came,
Monday, _Dec ember_ 26th Cloudy. Buddy and Ida were Invited up to Vx. Griggs
to a Christmas Tree, I went to see Tominie. Got home late. Uncle John,
Sister, and myself went to Mr, Wade's to a party, my first attempt at dancing.
Tuesday,, December 27th Still cloudy, Ida came home. Mrs, Ward here.
Cousin Dick went to see Mass Drucia Davis. Ida came home from Vx. Griggs'.
Lucy came home with her, Mrs, V/ard here.
Wgdnesday.._. December 28th Beautiful day, I sewed on my bonnet. Emma Walsh,
Nelly Wade, Willie, and Tom Wade came. Also Miss' Settle Wade. and Cousin
Addie Vaughn spent the, night,
Thursday^. December 29th Cousin Addie, All of them left. Watt Wade here.
Made Jane clean up the parlor, Mir. Wade and Cousin Jo Irby here.
35
Friday, Decerriber 30th Kiss Bettie McLaughlin came to go to Nashville with
Pa. Raining a little. Grandma came home from Mr, Ward's. Mr. Vhrd shingled
Ida's and Kate's hair.
Saturday. December_31 st The whole face of the earth covered with snow.
It is shoe mouth deep, I finished my bonnet.
</dc:description>
<dc:description>Printing of a year's worth of entries in a diary belonging to a Murfreesboro teenager, great-aunt of one of the current members of the Historical Society</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.); Diaries; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865;</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>73 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-16;mt2011-02-17</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication10ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/45</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>