<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>The history of Kittrell</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Hall, Mary</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 2</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1973</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>19th century; 20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>45
THE HISTORY OF KITTRELL
by Mary Hall
Kittrell is located seven miles east of Murfreesboro on
Highway 70 S, which was the original Stage Coach Road from
Knoxville to Nashville.
It was named for Major Marion B. Kittrell, who was born in
Wilson County, July 17, 1820. He married Ellen Johnston on
January 27, 1853. She was born in Wilson County, June 24, 1829,
and died in the Kittrell Community, October 10, 1890.
Their daughter, Lura, married Judge W. C. Houston of
Woodbury. Their children were Frank Kittrell, W. C. Jr., and
Simpson Fugitt who died in Murfreesboro, October 2, 1967.
Major Kittrell served in the Civil War as a Major in
General Joseph E. Johnston's Brigade.
After the Civil War, Major Kittrell left Wilson County and
moved to Woodbury in Cannon County.
In 1874 he sold his property in Cannon County and purchased
a tract of land on Cripple Creek in the 19th Civil District of
Rutherford County. The deed was signed July 18, 1874. He lived
on this farm until he died December 31, 1893. He was buried in
the family graveyard near his home.
The Federal Government established a Post Office in the -
Community in 1884. They named it "Kittrell" in honor of one
of its most respected citizens. Major Marion B. Kittrell. The
46
Post Office was discontinued when Rural Free Delivery was
established.
(Sources: Interview with Mrs. S. F. Houston; Records from
the Houston Family Bible; Sims: History of Rutherford County ;
Brown: History of Woodbury and Cannon County ; U. S. General
Services Administration; Letter from Mr. Victor Keene.
EARLY SETTLERS
Major Kittrell did not come to this community until 1874,
however there were many settlers before that time.
One of the largest streams in Rutherford County is Cripple
Creek. Legend tells us that a man, probably an Indian, was
badly crippled from falling into the stream, and he called it
"Cripple Creek." It meanders around the hills and through the
valleys of this area. The rich land near its banks enticed men
to settle wherever they found a spring.
Records show John Beasley bought land in the area in 1803.
Jonathan Hall paid taxes in Franklin County, Virginia in
18 05, and in 1807 he bought land in Rutherford County. He had
640 acres on Cripple Creek.
Elihu Jones came from Virginia about the same time as
Jonathan Hall, and was one of his nearest neighbors.
Andrew Carnahan bought land in the community in 1810.
Thomas Blair came from Virginia in 1812. He later sold his
land to Henry Bowling and moved to Arkansas.
Henry Bowling continued to enlarge his holdings by buying
his neighbors land. A friend said, "Henry, how much land are
47
you going to buy?" Mr. Bowling answered, "I just want what
j ines me .
"
Jesse Brashear, another large land owner re^corded a purcliasc
in 1814.
Alfred Conley carved the date, 1832, on the jam of his fire-place
when his house was built. It is still there, and it is
known today as the Uncle Dave Macon house.
David Barton Hall came to this community in 1806, with his
father, Jonathan Hall. In 1818 he purchased land at the foot of
Pilot Knob, the highest hill in the area, and built a log house
near a large spring. He sold his home in the 1840 's to his
oldest son, Franklin, and with his four younger sons, Ferdinand,
Fleming, Preston, and David, Jr. moved to West Tennessee. Their
settlement was called "Halls", and is in Lauderdale County.
Other people known to have been in the District at an early
date are verified by the Census Reports of 1810-1850 and by an
1878 map of Rutherford County.
A partial list follows
&#8212;
Samuel Fulks came from Maryland and settled behind Pilot Knob.
Joseph McCrackin came from North Carolina and settled on the
west side of Pilot Knob.
Robert E. Richardson, was a wagon maker and came from Virginia.
C. O. Abernathy, David Batey, G. W. Benson, J. S. Bowling,
Lee Freeman, Franklin D. Hall, John A. Herrod, Keele Herrod , John
Hoover, Charles Hunt who owned the south side of Pilot Knob.
48
Andrew and Samuel Jimmerson, Thompson McCrackin, who
helped survey the stage coach road, David and Issac Parker,
William H. Smith, Joseph Thompson, William W. Wilson.
David Columbus Witherspoon was a surveyor and went to
Alaska when gold was discovered there. He joined the U.S.
Geological Survey and helped survey the entire region. One
of the highest peaks in a long mountain range was named
"Mt. Witherspoon" in his honor.
(Sources: Family records. Bibles, deed books in Registrars
office. Census Reports 1810-1850.)
CHURCHES
Haynes Chapel Methodist Church
In the summer of 1884, the noted Methodist Evangelist,
Sam P. Jones of Cartersville , Georgia, conducted a revival in
Murfreesboro. There was a large number of converts. Among
them was a group of people living seven and eight miles east
of Murfreesboro on the Woodbury Pike.
A movement was started then to build a church in the
community. J. C. Haynes bought an acre of land from W. M.
Freeman and gave it for the church. In 1887 the Haynes Chapel
Church was built. The trustees were: J. C. Haynes, John Coleman,
R. N. Justice, W. M. Rogers, James Weeks, John A. Collier, J. B.
Palmer, and W. T. Overall.
The people in the community gave their time, labor, money
and logs. The church was dedicated in August, 1887. Rev. W. M.
49
Rogers preached the dedication sermon. A large crowd was in
attendance. There was "dinner on the ground," an afternoon and
evening service, and many more were added to the church that day.
The original church was built of donated logs and lumber.
The roof was handmade of wooden shingles. The windows had
wooden blinds. There was an aisle on each side of the house,
one for the men, the other for the women, with no middle aisle.
There was a mourners bench in front of the pulpit.
A partial list of the early pastors were: W. H. Rogers,
1887; Felix W. Johnson, 1888; John R. Thompson, 1889-1890;
D. S. Osteen, 1891-1892; J. W. Taylor, 1893; C. R. Wade, 1894;
W. T. Walkap, 1895.
During this time fifty-five people were added to the church,
and within the next few years twenty-six more were added. Mr.
Dave Macon and Mr. George Cranor made up money for a church
organ and Bible.
Mr. J. K. Lee was pastor from 1907-1909, and during that
time he organized the first children's program.
From 1919 to 1922 Rev. H. E. Baker was pastor. While he
was there the Epworth League with fifty members was organized.
A new roof was put on and thirty-one new members were added.
For many years the Seventh Day Adventist Church paid two
dollars and a half per month rent for use of the church on
Saturday.
Due to the rotation plan of the Methodist Church conference,
pastors usually serve two or three years. In 1953 Rev. O. H.
Lane came back after several years absence for a second pastorate.
50
In 1960 the last charter member of the church, Mrs. L. D.
Bowling, died at the age of eighty-nine. Some of the older
members of the church living today are Mrs. Lizzie Early,
Mr. and Mrs. Will Weeks, Miss Bertha Puryear, and Mrs. Lizzie
Saums.
During the last few years many improvements have been made
to the building. Mr. Archie Macon wired it and put in electric
lights, heat has been changed from coal to gas, the floor has
been sanded, new seats and pulpit furniture purchased, concrete
steps have been added, and rock siding has been put on the
outside.
In 1958 the members of the church built a parsonage on
the lot adjoining the church and the entire area was landscaped.
Rev. Leon Harris is the present pastor, and the membership
is now approximately one hundred and twenty-five.
(Sources: Mrs. Wendel Stegall, Mrs. Ruby Jennings,
Mrs. Will Weeks, and Misses Mamie Sue and Lou Benson.)
Seed Tick-Hickory Grove Baptist Church
It is not known when a log house was built for a Negro
church and school in the woods on the side of Tinch Hill.
It was called "Seed Tick" Baptist Church, and was the only
Negro church and school in the east end of Rutherford County.
It is likely that it was built near the time of 'the Civil
War. Alice Wright's daughter remembers her mother, who was born
in 1867, telling her about walking as a child, three miles to
Seed Tick school and sitting on logs for seats.
51
No record or remembrance has been found of the early
ministers, but Mr. Frank Ferguson is remembered as being one
of the early teachers. Other teachers were: Cordie Douglas,
Mattie Crockett, and Frank Knight.
The log house was later torn down, and a frame building -
was erected at the same place.
Children came from many miles to school there until bus
routes were established. Children were then taken to Woodbury
and Murfreesboro.
From the beginning church services were held on the first
Sunday in each month with revivals in the summer. Baptizings
were conducted in Stones River below the bridge at Readyville.
Early pastors remembered were: Bro. Will Henderson,
Bro. Les Womack, and Bro. George Hughes.
Elders were Zeke Brandon, Bud Brandon, and John Knight.
Deacons were Cas Brandon and Oda Brandon.
Church Mothers were Ruthy Davis who walked seven or eight ^
miles from Bradyville and seldom missed a service and Delia
Knight.
In 1938 a lot was bought near the highway at the foot of
Peak's Hill and a new church was built. The name was changed
to "Hickory Grove."
As they were moving into the new church. Aunt Delia Knight,
who was born in 1866, said, "I wonder who will have the first
funeral?" It was hers in a few weeks. Rev. A. F. Murray was
the pastor. She was buried in the Helton Cemetery at the foot
of Pilot Knob where most of the members have been buried.
52
Other members were: Oscar Bowling, Frances Bowling,
Uncle Zeke Brandon's family, the John Knight family, Foster Lyon,
Fannie Lyon, Hattie Lyon, Cas Swafford and family. Josh Swafford
and his family. Uncle Boss and Aunt Liz Walkup and their
children. Aunt Chloe Goodman, Becky Dickens, Betty Sutton, Uncle
Simon and Aunt Dink Wright, Alice Wright, Granville Dobbins,
and Florence and Lollie Taylor.
Within recent years the house has been improved by
installing electric lights and gas heat and painting inside and
outside.
Some of the present members are: Pastor, Rev. John Wiser.
Deacons: Gilbert Brandon, Jim Henry Newsom, Luther Russell.
^ Teacher: Andrew Dunn.
Church Mothers: Willie Swafford, Willie Bell Dunn.
Among other members are: Lawyer Brandon, Amanda Brandon,
Lorelle Brandon, Anne Dunn, Aline Newsom, Jerry Newsom, Audie
Robinson, Alpha Knight Robinson, Lizzie Weatherly.
(Sources: Church Record Book; interviews with Mrs. Willie
Swafford, Mrs. Willie Belle Dunn, and Mrs. Alpha Robinson.)
Science Hill
Science Hill was the second Church of Christ organized in
Rutherford County.
Alexander Campbell and Barton W. Stone came to Rutherford
County in the early thirties (1832-33) and organized groups
which were known as the Christian Church.
Alexander Campbell stayed in Murfreesboro, but Barton W.
Stone went out into the country. He met with Andrew Carnahan
53
and David Barton Hall in a log house on David Hall's place. They
accepted his explanation and theory of the "Back-to-the-Bible"
Restoration Movement. They and their families were baptized and
started the church there.
They met every Sunday for worship in that log house, and
Andrew Carnahan would spend the entire day reading and studying
the Bible with all who wanted to hear. They soon had a consid-erable
congregation.
About the time of the Civil War that building burned and a
larger one was built on a hill nearer the Stage Road on Franklin
Hall's farm. It was also used for a school. This building
burned in the 1880' s, and a still larger two-story building was
erected to serve as a church, school, and lodge hall.
As the school enrollment increased the curriculum expanded
from reading, writing, and arithmetic to include science and
several other academic areas. It was from the interest in
science that it came to be called "Science Hill Academy".
Although it became the largest and most outstanding school -
in the eastern part of Rutherford County, it was equally well
known as a Christian Church.
As the Kittrell and Readyville schools developed. Science
Hill stopped being a school, but it continued to grow as a church.
The building deteriorated as the years passed, and in 1950
Mr. Claiborn Harrell offered to give an acre of ground in front
of the Kittrell High School if they would move the church down
there.
54
The offer was accepted, and the old building was torn
down. Much of its material was found to be in good condition.
A new, modern brick building was erected, which has rafters,
joists, and sub-floor made from the old building. This became
the fourth building to serve the congregation in the one hundred
and forty years of its existence, and although it is now nearly
two miles from the hill where it was started in 18 33, the church
will always be called "Science Hill."
The Bateys, Beasleys, Bowlings, Breashears, Carnahans,
Craigs, Dunns, Earlys, Halls, Hoovers, Kittrells, Richardsons,
Smiths, Travises, Wilsons, Yourees, were among the early members.
The fourth generation of some of these families still attend
church there.
Among the early ministers were: J. L. Bryant, Jesse Sewell,
F. B. Shrygley, W. H. Sutton, T. B. Larimore, E. A. Elam, J. W.
Shepherd who held a meeting every other summer for fifty years.
C. M. Pullias alternated with Bro. Shepherd in his last years.
Science Hill never had a full-time minister until after World
War II. Joe Netherland began preaching monthly in 1941 and has
been the full-time minister since his military service ended in
1946.
Among the early elders were: Frederick Craig, Franklin Hall,
Andy Hoover, W. H. Smith.
Elders today are: Mose Boyd, Roscoe Brown, Jim Laws, Ed
Parnell, Mac Wilson, and Arthur Young.
55
Deacons are: Ray Donnell, Robert Adams, Fay Upton, William
H. Walkup, and Gentry Whitworth.
Secretary-Treasurer: Ray Arnold.
(Source: Church records; Goodspeed's History of Tennessee .)
Wilson Hill Baptist Church
In 1850 a Baptist Church was established at the foot of a
hill west of Pilot Knob owned by an early settler named Wilson.
The charter named it "Wilson Hill Baptist Church of Christ."
J. J. Jackson was the Pastor, and a record shows the charter
members to be Ed Crosslin, John Cross, Jane Croslin, Mary (Polly)
Cross, Rachel Burnett, Jane Mullins, and Emaline Gillum.
The church was burned with all the other records.
A new house was built in 1865 and most complete records
have been kept from that date to the present time except from
1900-1913. No records are in the books for that period.
The church met in conference July, 1865, and elected Jesse
Jonnigan (later spelled Jernigan) Pastor and Moderator. He held
this position until 1886.
Deacons elected at that time were Henry Arnett and Thomas J.
Burnett. Henry Mullins was elected Clerk. He continued to be
church clerk until his death in August, 1868. At that time Ichabod
Daniel was appointed to take his place.
On November 27, 1868, he wrote "I. B. Daniel this day returns
this book to his beloved Brother George T. Brandon. So, farewell
beloved brothers and sisters."
A letter of dismissal was given him November 28, 1868. He
must have moved from the community.
56
George T. Brandon continued as clerk from 1868 until 1898.
He was ordained a deacon in 1884.
In 1900 T. A. Jamison was the clerk, but there is no record
of who followed him until 1913 when R. P. Wilson became a clerk.
Others following were A. R. Hoover, Thomas Hoover, Gaither Hoover,
and Mrs. Louise McElroy.
Pastors and Moderators
A Pastor was elected by the church conference to preach
monthly and moderate at the business meetings.
A visiting minister was invited to assist with an annual
protracted meeting, or revival, in the summer.
Among the Pastors were Jesse Jernigan (1866-1886) , James
Jernigan, J. W. Jamison ordained in 1890, J. E. Tassey, R. A.
Taylor (1913-1965), J. T. Casey and Lester F. Shelton.
Some of the visiting ministers were Hardy Bruer, H. C.
Haley, Jason Ray, J. P. Simes, H. T. Montgomery, J. W. Cooper,
J. W. Anderton, W. H. Whitlock, and Marion Davenport.
Members
Complete records were kept of the members as they came into
the church&#8212;by experience, baptism, or by letter. The following
is a partial list of some of the early members: Henry Arnett,
E. Barnes, Thomas J. Burns, Edward Croslin, John Cross, Jesse
Daniel, Thurston Daniel, Henry Mullins, David Bivins, Jesse Bowlin,
James Cox, A. P. Helton, Peter Helton, Thomas Herrod, Andrew
Jimerson, Ed Jimerson, Marshall Pitts, and Wilson Todd.
Female members were listed separately from the male. Among
them was a Negro woman named Sely Wright.
58
Although the house was built over a hundred years ago, it
is in excellent condition today having recently been remodeled
and modernized by paneling, painting, storm doors, electric
lighting, and gas heat.
The present Pastors and Moderators are: W. C. Banks,
Artie Roberts, and Clyde Roberts.
Deacons are: Malcolm Pitts and Charlie Bryson. Clerk:
Mrs. Louise McElroy.
Delegates: Charles Bryson, Malcolm Pitts, Thurman Pitts.
(Sources: Church record books; interviews with Thomas
Hoover, Mrs. Louise McElroy, and Mrs. Gaither Hoover.)
OUTSTANDING INDIVIDUALS
Captain Robert Ray Boyd
Bobby Boyd was the son of Mr. and Mrs. Mose C. Boyd.
He attended Kittrell Elementary School, MTSU Campus
School, and Central High School, where he graduated with honors
in 1959.
In May, 1964, he received a B. S. degree in chemistry
from Middle Tennessee State University and Second Lieutenant
rank from ROTC. He was a member of the Sigma Club, Track and
Sabre Club, and the Chemical Association.
He was one of six Distinguished Military Cadets at MTSU,
and he was assigned to the 101st Airborne Artillery at Fort
Campbell. He completed that course in October and went to Fort
Sill, Oklahoma. He graduated from the Field Artillery Officers
Basic Course and was sent to Viet Nam in July, 1965.
59
On October 24, 1965, he was awarded the "Certificate of
Merit in Recognition of Outstanding Performance of Duty."
On March 16, 1966, he was awarded the "Bronze Star Medal
for Heroism." The citation states: "Lieutenant Boyd moved
under heavy enemy fire to the platoon which was receiving the
brunt of the new attack. He directed extremely accurate
artillery fire upon the Viet Cong while exposing himself to the
murderous fire so he could observe and direct the artillery.
Disregarding the fact that the Viet Cong were directing their
fire at him. Lieutenant Boyd continued to direct artillery fire
for approximately five hours. His actions contributed greatly
to the defeat of the Viet Cong forces. First Lieutenant Boyd's
outstanding display of aggressiveness, devotion to duty, and
personal bravery were in keeping with the highest traditions of
the military service, and reflect great credit upon himself,
his unit, and the United States."
Following some of the demonstrations against the war, a
woman in Pennsylvania wrote a letter to the soldiers in Viet
Nam, expressing her appreciation for what they were doing.
Bobby answered it. Her letter and his were published throughout
the army bases and the United States.
He said, "I consider it not only a duty, but a great
privilege to be able to serve so that your boys may grow up in
our wonderful country and enjoy all it has to offer. I am
serving now, and your husband has served, in defense of our
country so that we might enjoy the freedom of America. Now it
is my turn to guarantee your children the same promise. May
God bless you and your family."
60
Lieutenant Boyd was promoted to Captain in January, 1967.
He was stationed at the Bein Hoa Air Paso near Saiqon and was
the Communications Officer for the 173rd Airborne Division.
He came home in February for the first furlough he had
had. It was a wonderful month for his parents, relatives, and
friends, and Bobby enjoyed every minute of it.
He was a member of Science Hill Church of Christ. On
Sunday night before he went back to Viet Nam he had charge of
the service. He showed slides, described the life of the
people there, and told with enthusiasm some of the experiences
which he had.
He signed up for another tour of duty before he came home,
and on February 22 he said a happy "Goodbye" to his parents and
family and returned to his base unit on February 23rd.
On May 17 Captain Boyd was preparing for a convoy when a
shell from a hostile mortar round hit him. He was killed
instantly.
After a military funeral, he was buried in the Coleman
Cemetery on the Woodbury Road.
On July 15, 1967, the United States Army presented posthumous
awards to Captain Robert Ray Boyd. The Purple Heart , which was
established by General George Washington in 1782, and is presented
"to heroic men who have shown gallentry and devotion in the
service of his country." The Bronze Star Medal and The Air
Medal with First Oak Leaf Cluster were also awarded.
61
"Robert stands in the unbroken line of patriots who have
given their lives that our Nation's goal of freedom and peace
may be maintained."
Judge A. L. Carnahan
A. L. Carnahan was reared near Bradyville in Cannon County.
He attended community schools and later graduated from Winchester
Normal.
In 1897 he bought the David Batey farm and moved into the
Kittrell Community. He soon became one of the active leaders
in church, school, and civic affairs.
He was a member of the School Board for some time and was
influential in getting a high school located at Kittrell. He
was a member of Science Hill Church of Christ.
He was elected magistrate for the 19th Civil District and
held that office for several years. In 1918 he was elected
County Judge, and presided over the Rutherford County Court for
some time.
Dr. Joseph David Hall
Dr. J. D. Hall, son of Franklin D. Hall and Elizabeth
McCrackin Hall, spent all of his life on the farm, "Piedmont,"
at the foot of Pilot Knob where his grandfather, David Hall,
settled in 1818. His great-grandfather, Jonathan Hall, came to
Rutherford County from Virginia in 1806 and settled a few miles
away on Stones River and later on Cripple Creek.
62
Dr. Hall was born in 1854 and grew up during the difficult
years of the Civil War. As a child he walked three miles each
day to and from "Pap" Huddleston's school at Readyville.
When Science Hill Academy started on his father's farm,
he went to school there. The curriculum was extremely broad
for those days.
The principal was a highly educated man, a graduate of
Princeton University. He also had some well-educated assistants.
They offered Greek, Latin, science, trigonometry, calculus, in
addition to the usual subjects of English, history, and geography.
He took all these subjects. He worked on his father's farm and
saved his money.
When he finished school at the Academy, he apprenticed
himself to Dr. A. P. McCullough at Milton for two years. In
those days they called it, "Reading medicine under an old
Doctor.
"
When he was not helping Dr. McCullough with his patients,
he worked in a drug store and learned about medicine.
In 188 he entered Vanderbilt Medical School and graduated
in 1883. One of his classmates begged him to go into a partner-ship
with him in Nashville, but he chose rather to come home and
become a country doctor.
In December, 1883, he married Miss Ella Lowe. They continued
to live with his mother and father.
In the early days of his practice, he road horseback with
saddlebags across his saddle. He always kept good horses.
"Old Joe," a sixteen hands, strawberry roan which he rode for
63
thirty years, was considered one of the best walking horses ever
in Rutherford County. In the 1890' s he began using a buggy some,
and about 1914 he got a car.
His practice had a wide range from the Bradyville to the
Hall's Hill Pikes, and from 1920 when the last doctor left
Readyville, he was the only doctor between Murfreesboro and
Woodbury. The nights were never too dark, nor the weather too
bad for him to go when he was called.
He was a member of the Church of Christ, a Mason, and was
active in all civic and community affairs.
He was an avid reader and was well posted on many subjects,
especially on things pertaining to the medical profession. He
belonged to the A. M. A., State and County Medical Associations,
and served as President of Rutherford County Medical Society at
one time. He was always interested in politics, and served on
the County Democratic Committee.
After practicing medicine for over fifty-five years he died
of pneumonia at the age of eighty- four , and is buried in the
garden of his home, "Piedmont."
Uncle Dave Macon
The most widely known citizen of the Kittrell community was
"Uncle Dave Macon."
David Harrison Macon was born near Smart Station in Warren
County in 1870. In 1883 when he was a young boy, his parents
moved to Nashville and ran the Broadway Hotel. After his father
died, his mother sold the hotel in 1886 and bought the Charles
Ready farm at Readyville.
64
In 1889 he married Miss Matilda Richardson and moved to a
farm in the Kittrell community where he lived until his death in
1952. In 1901, in addition to farming, he started a wagon freight
line from Murfreesboro to Woodbury. He had two wagons. Hatton
Sanfrod drove one, and he drove the other until Archie, the oldest
of his seven sons, was big enough to help.
They went to Woodbury one day and to Murfreesboro the next,
handling and delivering materials all along the way. He knew
every man, woman, and child along the twenty mile route and kept
up with everything that happened. When a truck line started in
1920, Mr. Macon decided it was time to stop his wagons.
He always loved to sing and play the banjo. After the boys
go big enough to help with the freight line, he had more time
on his hands.
On rainy days he would take his banjo to the neighborhood
store and entertain all who came by. Soon he started going to
schools on Friday afternoons. School children began calling him
"Uncle Dave."
It was not long until he was called on to help raise money
with school programs, box suppers, pie suppers, cake walks, picnics,
and all kinds of community affairs. If it were advertised that
"Uncle Dave Macon" was going to be on a program, there was sure
to be a crowd, for everyone loved his humor and ready wit as well
as his music.
In the early twenties he played some at Lowe's Theatre. In
1924 he went to Knoxville and did his first recording.
65
When the "Solemn Ole Judge," Mr. George Hay, started the
WSM "Grand Ole Opry" in 1925, Uncle Dave Macon became one of
the first artists on the program.
During the next twenty-seven years he seldom missed a
Saturday night being there. He began calling himself "The
Dixie Dew Drop."
He was one of the first Grand Ole Opry artists to begin a
traveling program during the week. He went all over the South
&#8212;
New Orleans, Atlanta, Birmingham, Mobile, and many small towns,
also New York and other northern cities. He drew large crowds
wherever he went.
He was a member of Haynes Chapel Methodist Church.
He died of pneumonia in 1952. He is buried in the Coleman
Cemetery on the Woodbury Road. One hundred and twenty-five
Grand Ole Opry stars contributed to the erection of a three
thousand ton granite monument to his memory beside the highway
on top of the hill overlooking Woodbury.
Today his name stands among the great of the music world in
Nashville where a plaque has been placed in his honor in the
Grand Ole Opry Hall of Fame.
(Sources: Interviews with Mr. Archie Macon and Mrs. Ruth
Wood; Magazine Section, NASHVILLE TENNESSEAN.
)
P. M. Puryear, Educator
Portious Moore Puryear was born in Oxford, Granville County,
North Carolina, November 26, 1839. He moved with his family to
Walker County, Georgia, in the early part of 1860. He soon
66
enlisted in the 23rd Georgia regiment Confederate Army and served
until it surrendered. He was under Stonewall Jackson and in the
battle when that officer received the wound that caused his death.
He later joined General Robert E. Lee's regiment and was with him
at the surrender of Appomattox.
He was a graduate of Princeton University. In 1867 he married
Miss Margaret Gunn and came to the Kittrell community of Rutherford
County, Tennessee.
In 1870 he became principal of Science Hill Academy and taught
there for seventeen years. It was the only school in that part of
Rutherford County. Students came from other communities and
boarded to go to school there. Professor Puryear, being a highly
educated man, developed a very broad curriculum. He taught Greek,
Latin, higher mathematics and science. He had two or three
assistants who taught the basic skills of reading, writing, and
arithmetic.
He became a magistrate from the 19th Civil District in 1876.
He took an active interest in the proceedings of the Quarterly
Court and seldom missed a meeting.
He belonged to Haynes Chapel Methodist Church which he helped
build in 1884 and was a faithful worker there and "a public
spirited and liberal, earnest supporter of all propositions for
the good of the public" until his death on November 30, 1891.
(Sources: Interviews with Miss Bertha Puryear; Family
records; Copy of Resolutions passed by the Rutherford County
Quarterly Court, January, 1892.)
67
SCHOOLS
The first school in the Kittrell-Readyville area was taught
in 1810 by James Barkley, a Revolutionary soldier, who moved to -^
Danville, Virginia, in 1833. It is not known where the building
was.
Soon after that Mr. W. B. Huddleston built a log house in
the corner of his yard, where Mr. Leslie Justice now lives, and
started a school known as "Pap Huddleston' s School."
Children walked for many miles to this school, getting there
by eight o'clock in the morning when "books took up" and staying
until four in the afternoon. The curriculum was entirely the
three "R's".
Another school known to have been before the Civil War was
in a log building at Wilson's Hill on the northwest side of Pilot
Knob. It seems to have been discontinued when the war came on.
The people in the community realized that their children's
education had been neglected during the war years, and a need was
felt for another school.
Everybody joined together and erected a large building on
Franklin Hall's farm. It became the outstanding school in the
east end of Rutherford County. This was a big step forward in
education as "academies" were being established throughout the
state. The curriculum was expanded beyond the three "R's" to
include science, Latin, Greek, higher mathematics, literature.
68
and history. Due to the innovation of science into the school
program, the school came to be named "Science Hill Academy". It
was used as a church on Sundays.
In 1870 Mr. P. M. Puryear moved into the community. He was
a graduate of Princeton University. For the next seventeen years
he was principal of Science Hill Academy.
He brought in as his assistants, several other well educated
persons. Among them were Mr. Sam Billingsley, Mr. Smith Denton,
Mr. Pollard Runnels, and Miss Nannie Stanley who taught music
and art.
The fame of this school spread, and students came from all
neighboring communities and from far away. Several homes in the
community were opened for boarding students.
This building burned, and the school moved to a new building
on the hill above the mill at Readyville. This school grew and
prospered for several years, but it burned down in 1902.
About 1895 the people in the Kittrell community decided
another school should be started there. Mr. CO. Abernathy and
Mrs. P. M. Puryear gave the land, and a two-room schoolhouse was
built.
For some time the school term in the county was only three
months. Usually a subscription school would follow in the winter.
After some years the community extended the term to five months
and then to eight.
Some of the early teachers were: Mr. Sam Nelson, Miss Ella
Pitts, Mr. Tom Jamison, Mr. Henry Barton, Miss Willie Goodloe,
69
Mr. Charlie Elkins , Miss Betty Hayes, Mr. S. A. Youree, Miss
White Jetton, Mr. Walter Kirby, Miss Jennie Speer, Mr. Genoa
Bowling, Mr. Flint Speer.
In 1909 the State Legislature passed a bill establishing
four normal schools in Tennessee and a high school in every -^
county .
Mr. Flint Speer was the principal at Kittrell. He visited
leaders in the community and called a meeting of all the parents.
They voted to petition the county court to build a two-year high
school at Kittrell. The court granted the request provided a
certain amount of money would be raised by the community. The
people responded and raised the money within a few weeks. A
sawmill was set up on the school grounds, and people donated logs
for the framing. Ceiling, flooring, window and door frames had
to be bought. It was discovered that reduced prices could be had
in Nashville. Wagons and teams were donated and men drove down
one day and returned the next with these building materials.
People in the community donated their services.
In the fall of 1911 Kittrell opened a new high school. The
first graduates in 1913 were: Esther Couch, Mary Hall, Sam Jones,
Ervin McCrary, Emmett Travis, Alline Youree, and Annie Youree.
The following served as principals of the two-year high
school: E. T. Stern, Flint Speer, C. F. Holt, Mr. Bryant, Clyde
E. Richards, and Mr. Briar.
In 1923 Mr. Flint Speer was principal for a second time and
Kittrell became a four-year high school.
In 1925 Frank Bass was principal. By this time the old frame
building would no longer accommodate the increased number of pupils,
70
The parents launched a drive for a new building, and the present
brick building was erected.
Mr. Bass served as principal from 1925 to 1927 followed by
Ross Shelton, Clyde Riggs, James Woodfin, Thomas Holden, Esten
Macon, David Youree, R. V. Reynolds, and Thomas Tenpenny.
It was through the efforts of Mr. Youree that Kittrell
became an A grade school in 1953.
The first gymnasium was built in 1927 principally from the
lumber of the old building, but it was inadequate. Again, the
community spirit was demonstrated by donating $3,000 for a larger
and better gymnasium.
Home economics was made a part of the curriculum in 1922.
Mrs. J. J. Northcutt was the first home economics teacher. Miss
Ruby McKnight held that position for twenty-eight years.
The present agriculture room and shop were built by the
county in 1948, and typing and shorthand were added to the curric-ulum
in 1945.
A new building for the primary grades was built in 1953.
Since that time seven additional classrooms and a new home economics
department have been added. A new agriculture building has also
been constructed.
The school now (1972) has an enrollment of 700, grades one
through twelve, employing twenty- three teachers.
The high school curriculum has been broadened until it con-sists
of four years of English; three years of mathematics; two
years of typing and shorthand; one year of business mathematics and
71
business law; home economics; agriculture; American history;
general science; biology; chemistry; psychology; sociology; civics;
health and physical education.
As the school has improved, so has the mode of transportation
advanced. In 1914 Mr. Ode Hoover drove the first school wagon to
Kittrell. He purchased a new wagon and George Ralston constructed
an overhead frame, covered it with canvas, and built benches along
the sides. A black and red mule, "Tobe" and "Tige: pulled the
wagon from behind Pilot Knob to Readyville and down the pike, now
Highway 7 S, to Kittrell School.
Other wagon drivers were: Jim Arnett, Elmer Carnahan, and
Black McGill. Craig Youree and Roy Good drove wagons down Cripple
Creek Road, and Will Weeks and Powell Hall came from the Loafers
Rest area.
The school was served by wagons until 1923. That year
"Uncle Jack" Coleman got a stock truck for the school truck. He
built seats along the sides and enclosed it with pine ceiling on
hinges that could be let up and down for the comfort of the pupils
in summer and winter. He drove the school truck as long as he
was able.
As wagons were replaced by trucks, trucks were replaced by
buses.
Since the program of consolidation came to the county, Kittrell
as a four-year high school served the communities of Readyville,
Halls Hill, Sharperville, Shiloh, Loafers Rest, Dilton, Murray, and
Donnell's Chapel.
72
Five large buses, each having two routes, make two trips
each day into these communities.
(Sources: Kittrell School records: School Superintendent's
Office; Report for Alumni by Miss Maggie Lowe.)
FRATERNAL ORGANIZATIONS
During Governor Robert L. Taylor's administration, farmers
throughout the state began asserting their rights.
In 1890 the Grange, or Farmers Alliance, was organized.
They met in the upstairs room of the Science Hill Church.
It was a strong organization for several years, and practi-cally
all the farmers in the community belonged to the Grange.
Among them were: David Batey, Frederick Craig, G. M. Dunn, Bud
Brashear, J. D. Hall, Bud Helton, Andy Hoover, R. H. Kittrell, Jim
Smith, and W. H. Smith.
Several men in the community belonged to the Masonic Lodge.
Records were destroyed in a fire, but J. D. Hall and W. H. Smith
were among the members.
SPORTS
Fox Hunting
One of the earliest sports in the community was fox hunting.
Several men in the area had large packs of hounds. Mr. Ed McElroy
had twelve. "John" and "Old Blue" were considered champions. Mr.
Andy Hoover had nine hounds; among them were "Bugle" and "Trumpet".'
Dr. J. D. Hall was another fan. At the time of the Spanish-American
73
War he had two dogs and named his hounds "Dewey" and "Schley" after
heroes of the war.
The area around Pilot Knob and Peak's Hill provided a very
fine hunting range.
The baying of the hounds "coming ' roung the mountain" filled
the night air with music to the fans.
In 1932 Harold Earthman (Doc), Broadus Maples, Wash Powers,
and a few others organized the Rutherford County Fox Hunters
Association.
Mr. Earthman was the Representative for the Fourth Congres-sional
District at the time. Being a democratic person, he disliked
the possibility of this association's becoming a "Gentlemen's Social
Organization," as they are in England. He wanted the love of fox
hunting to be the ground for belonging, rich or poor, black or
white, and not one's wealth or social position.
In 193 3 he suggested that the name be changed to the "One
Callus Fox Hunters Association."
Mr. Earthman had several friends in Congress who were
interested in fox hunting, and being very proud of Tennessee, he
decided that he wanted to show those people what a real Tennessee
fox hunt was like.
In 1934 he came home from Washington and suggested to the
other members of the One Callus Association that they put on the
biggest fox hunt that had ever been in the United States. The
other members joined readily in his plans.
They chose the harvest moon time in October, and the area of
Pilot Knob, Peaks Hill, and Craig Hollow for the hunt.
74
The camp was set up in Craig Hollow, and Mr. George Lassiter
was put in charge of the food. He barbecued thirteen hogs and
made coffee and other things in proportion. A news syndicate in
Chicago announced the hunt all over the country, and people came
from many areas. The Fox Hunting Magazine of England sent a
reporter from London, one came from Chicago, a representative for
Time, and the National Fox Hunters Association, and the state and
local papers covered it.
Some of Mr. Earthman's friends from Washington, Chicago, and
New York came as well as fans from all over Tennessee, and a large
representation from Rutherford County. There was an estimated one
thousand people there and two hundred dogs. Most of them stayed
all weekend.
It was a huge success, and everyone said that there had
never been such a fox hunt in the United States. The One Callus
Fox Hunters Association has a clubhouse now near Eagleville.
They still have annual hunts, but never another like that one.
(Sources: Interviews with Mrs. Sam B. Dunn, Mr. Harold
Earthman, and Mr. Broadus Maples.)
Baseball
Baseball was a part of the life of the community from the
days of the first school, but it did not become very important
until about 1911.
Mr. Flint Speer was principal of Kittrell High School at
the time.
Walter Norris came home after being discharged from four
years of service in the U. S. Army where he had been an outstanding
pitcher on an army baseball team.
75
The school program at that time gave an hour for lunch.
Walter came to school every day at lunch to play ball.
There was a fine group of large boys in school, and acting
as coach and pitcher, Walter soon developed a champion team.
They practiced in the afternoon after school and on Saturdays
until a schedule of games was filled.
From that time they had no open dates during the season for
the next two or three years. They played all teams in the county
and surrounding areas.
It was the first time a curved ball was ever pitched in this
area. Community fans followed them wherever they went. There
were always big crowds. Fans went many miles to see the games.
The team went far and near to play schools, at picnics,
county fairs, and on Sunday afternoons all summer.
One man from Smithville said, "I would go anywhere to see
a ball game if I knew Walter Norris was going to pitch."
The members of the team were: Walter Norris, Will Early,
Jesse Helton, Sam Jones, Frank Lowe, Ervin McCrary, Aubra McCrary,
Walter McKnight, Orville Tilford, and Youree Perry.
Basketball
In 1923 when Kittrell became a four-year high school,
basketball bounced into the school and into the hearts of
Kittrell fans.
Mr. Flint Speer was the principal, and Mr. Oscar (Uncle Bud)
Baskin was the coach.
On this team was one of the best players the school has
ever produced, Powell Early. After playing four year at Kittrell
he went to college (MTSU) and made the varsity team. Other players
76
during the first few years included Samuel Youree, Marcus Brandon,
Maurice McKnight, Rush Palmer, Hall Woodward, Robert Abernathy,
Robert Kerr, and Deward (Foots) Compton.
In 1925 Frank Bass came to Kittrell as principal and coach.
The boys succeeded in going to the finals in the District Tourna-ment
for the next several years.
An outstanding girls team was developed when Miss Sadie Mae
McMahan became coach. She had an excellent team in 1920 with
Katie Alexander, Sarah Rion, Odell Sneed, Bertha McFerrin, Jenny
McElroy, and Ruby Gates. They won both the District and Regional
Tournaments.
The boys had a slump for some years, but in 1938 "Foots"
Compton led the team as a great point maker with Adam DeBerry as
defense man. They went to the state tournament in 193 9 and broke
all scoring records. Compton went on to college and was named
"All American.
"
Mr. Jack Jarrett was the boys coach for the next few years,
and Ruby Sanford, a past star, was the girls coach. She developed
such good players as Elaine Milligan, Juanita Hollandsworth, Ella
Jo and Marie Herrod.
Mr. Kenneth Colston became coach in 1958 and Kittrell really
came into the limelight. Jimmy (Monk) Montgomery was one of the
most exciting players the state has ever produced. He broke all
records for the most points scored in the state. He had great
help from his teammates Ben Gates, Bobby Jones, Jimmy and George
Nipper.
77
In 1962 no coach was hired for Kittrell, and "Foots" Compton,
a former star, gave his time to come and coach the boys. He
developed another winning team.
Bob Burden became coach in 1963. He had a record of 190
wins and 74 losses in the next nine years. Better things began to
happen for the Kittrell girls when Ben Gates became their coach.
In 1971 they went to the state tournament for the first time,
having won the county tournament, second place in both district and
regional tournaments and first place in the sub- tournament. The
leading scorer in the state was Connie Vance. She had splendid
help in Jo Love and Emma Newsom.
The Kittrell girls finished the 1972 season with 28 wins
and 3 losses. They were runners-up in the district tournament and
winners of the regional and sub-state. They went to the state
tournament for the second consecutive year and were rated one of
the finest teams in the state. Members of the team were: Connie
Vance, Sandy Vance, Stella Milligan, Gale Robinson, Jean Lynch,
Brenda Eaglen, Debbie Duke, Emily Vance, Dannette Duke, Claudia
Hollandsworth, Kahty and Cindy Tolbert. They did credit to the
school.
Coach Gates and all the Kittrell fans had great hopes that
they would win the tournament. They had defeated every team they
played except Gallatin. They easily won their first rounds in the
tournament but were defeated by the strong Lewisburg team which
won the tournament.
Connie Vance was recognized as the best player in Rutherford
County history. Her jersey. No. 33, has been retired along with
78
"Monk" Montgomery's, No. 43. She was the leading scorer in the
state in 1972 and was chosen by the Nashville Banner as being the
Most Valuable Player in the state.
1972 ended forty-nine years of basketball for Kittrell.
There have been many thrilling moments, close games, exciting
wins, comparable losses, and tournament champions during these years.
Good coaching has been demonstrated, sportsmanship has been
shown, and great players have been developed to linger in the memory
of the players and fans as Kittrell High School comes to a close.
(Sources: Mr. Joe Gates, Kittrell School Records.)
GENERAL STORES
There were two stores in Kittrell. They were on opposite
sides of the road. Mr. Burgan Jamison and Mr. Billy Smith had a
store on the north side of the road for several years, but closed
some time before the other one did.
Across the road a few yards from the blacksmith shop was
Mr. Lewis Bowling's store.
In 1884 the U. S. Government established a Post Office at
Kittrell. They put it in Mr. Bowling's store and appointed him
Postmaster.
Both stores were the typical general country store with pot-bellied
stoves, J. P. Coats thread, cracker barrels, nail kegs,
pins, domestic and calico, smoking and chewing tobacco, sugar, salt,
coffee, and all commodities to meet country people's needs.
79
The Post Office was closed when Rural Free Delivery was
established. Route #5 came out from Murfreesboro. The store
continued in operation until Mr. Bowling became ill in 1923. He
died in 1925.
INDUSTRIES
Blacksmith Shop
One of the best blacksmith shops in this part of Rutherford
County was at Kittrell. It was run by Mr. Jack and Mr. Will
Coleman. In addition to shoeing horses, "Uncle Jack," as he was
called, could fix anything.
Mr. Will lived some distance from the shop, but Uncle Jack
lived "just a stone's throw" from the shop in the tollgate house.
From the early days of the stage coach road, which later was
called a "turnpike", until the state took it over, a tollgate was -
placed about every five or six miles.
The first one out of Murfreesboro was where Mercury Boulevard
now runs into Highway 70. The second one was at Kittrell, a third
one just above Readyville, and a fourth one was just below the
bridge at Woodbury.
A house was built with a porch reaching the road. A long log
would be put across the road about four feet from the ground with
a rope on one end which could be fastened to a post on the porch.
The other end rested on a frame and had weights on it which would
make the pole go up when the rope was unfastened.
A toll was charged of 5&lt;: for horseback, 10&lt;: for buggies, and
15-25&lt;: for wagons according to the load.
80
Mrs. Coleman ran the tollgate during the day when Uncle Jack
was in the shop and he took care of it at night, and thus they
were able to keep up with where everybody went.
The first tourist who came up the road in a car ran into the
tollgate and smashed his windshield. As long as Uncle Jack lived
he enjoyed telling about the "cussin out" which that man gave him
for having a pole across the road.
Uncle Jack could fix anything from a clock to a steam engine.
They made plows, wagons, hoes, rakes, and any other kind of tool
used on the farm.
When the state highway changed the road the tollgate and
blacksmith shop were done away with. Mr. Will began farming and
Uncle Jack drove the school wagon.
Sorghum Hill
As soon as "frost was on the pumpkin," and leaves began to
turn, people started stripping their sorghum cane and bringing it
in great wagon loads to Mr. Pitts' sorghum mill.
Mr. M. E. Pitts owned a farm on the banks of Cripple Creek.
He grew the usual corn, cotton, wheat, and a large patch of sorghum.
He built a mill to grind his cane under a big oak tree between his
house and the creek.
The mill consisted of a grinder which was turned by a pole to
which a mule was fastened. He went in a circle around the mill
and furnace^.
A large pan, several feet long, caught the juice as it was
ground out in the mill. The pan extended over a furnance which
was kept hot by a wood fire underneath. After the juice was
81
squeezed from the cane the remaining pulp, called "chawings," was
put in a big pile near by. Farmers frequently took it home to
feed cows, and children loved to play on it.
It took several hours to cook the juice "down" to molasses;
therefore, the cooking lasted until in the night. As it was done
in the season of the harvest moon, the nights were usually pretty
and bright. It was one of the interesting entertainments for the
young people of the community to go to the sorghum mill in the
evenings with their buttered biscuits for the first taste of the
sweet syrup.
Later in the year, molasses candy pullings, helped many
evenings pass happily for the young people.
People came for miles with their jars, jugs, and kegs to get
Mr. Pitts molasses. The sorghum mill was discontinued when he
died in 1913.
Weaving
Mrs. John Sanford, called "Miss Sine" by her family and
friends, had a hand loom in her home. For many years she wove
blankets, carpets, rugs, and linsey cloth for people in the
community and neighboring areas.
One afternoon in the spring of 1911 after a hard rain and
thunder storm, her husband came home from the field and found her
lying in the road in front of the house. She had been killed by
lightening.
Weaving is still being done in the community. Mrs. Lizzie
Saums has a loom which she has used for many years. She helped
82
her mother and grandmother thread their loom when she was a child,
and when they were not looking she shot the shuttle across. As
soon as she was tall enough to reach the treadle, they taught her
to weave and she has been doing it ever since. She does custom
weaving of rugs and carpets at her home on Mt. Herman Road where
she has lived all of her life.
LANDMARKS
The outstanding landmark in the Kittrell-Readyville communities
is Pilot Knob.
It is said by Dr. Edward Baldwin, geographer for many years
at Middle Tennessee State University, to be the highest point in
Tennessee east of the Mississippi River until the foothills of
the Cumberland Mountains in Cannon and Warren counties.
No one knows who named the hill "Pilot Knob." It was called
that when the first settlers came to the area. They said that the
Indians had used it as a guiding point, a lookout place, and a
smoke signal station. It can be seen for an area of twenty or
more miles in every direction.
During the Civil War the North and South considered it of
sufficient importance that they had several skirmishes in the
area to get possession of the hill. One of the armies built a
"lookout" up in a large tree which stayed there until after 1920.
It was used as a signal station, and with a telescope one could
see a distance beyond Murfreesboro. It was a very important point
when the battle of Stones River was fought.
83
For many years it provided a recreation area for hunters and
youth in the community. The south side of the Knob has always
been covered with grass and used as pasture. People frequently
entertained visitors by taking them up to view the landscape which
was especially magnificent in the fall and spring.
One day some bright youngsters took some wide planks and
nailed a foot rest on one end. They took them up to the crest of
the hill and rode down on the planks. From that day for a long
time to come it became one of the chief recreations for the young
people to go to the Knob on weekends and ride down the "shoot-to-shoot"
on the south side.
The east, west, and north sides had some tillable land and a
lot of woods which provided hunting grounds for all kinds of
animals. Boys made their money during the winter months hunting
and trapping coons, opossirms, polecats, and foxes whose homes
were in the woods.
At one time Mr. Bob Lytle had a famous peach orchard on one
side of the Knob, and people came for miles for the choice fruit.
One of the best Girl Scout camps in Tennessee, Piedmont Camp,
is at the foot of Pilot Knob and serves girls from Rutherford and
surrounding counties.
FOLK LORE
Thomas Blair came from Virginia and settled on Cripple Creek.
His daughter, Elizabeth, married Jonathan Hall's oldest son, David
Barton Hall. She died in 1815 when their son, Franklin Donald was
born.
84
Thomas Blair sold his land to Henry Bowling and moved to
Arkansas. David Hall and his young son, Franklin, went with them.
He soon decided to come back to Tennessee.
On the way he stopped at a trading post and left the little
boy with the horse. It took him some time to purchase the food
and supplies he needed. When he came back to his horse, Franklin
was no where to be seen.
After searching all over the area, a traveler came along and
said that he had seen a little white boy in an Indian camp some
miles away. They had kidnapped the child and had taken him to
their camp. David rode in agony as fast as he could, but it took
some time for him to find the camp.
All his fears were allayed when he got there and saw a very
happy little boy having a grand time standing on a stump dressed
as a little Indian chief with the braves dancing around him singing
a song.
After assuring the Indians that he was the child's father and
that he had not been abandoned, then laden with gifts, Franklin
and his father bade the Indians good bye and were soon again on
their way home.
The experience remained a pleasant memory of his childhood
which Franklin loved to tell about as long as he lived.
</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.) -- History</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>community history; local history</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Kittrell</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>77 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-16</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication02ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/71</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>