<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Murfreesboro's Old City Cemetery:a record of the past</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Wilgus, Mary H.</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 17</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1981</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>19th century; 20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>53
MURFREESBOBO'S OLD CITY CEMETERY;
A RECORD OF THE PAST
BY
MARY H. V7ILGUS
54
MURFREESBORO'S OLD CITY CEMETERY:
A RECORD OF THE PAST
The Old City Cemetery, located on Vine Street not far from
Murfreesboro' s public square, provides a doon&gt;7ay to the city's
past. Like an old, restored home, personal diaries of long,
deceased relatives, early newspapers, or carefully preserved
deeds and wills, an old cemetery offers much information about
the history of a family, town, or county. This is the enormous
value of the Old City Cemetery. Much data on its stones are
legible: ages of the people interred there, their places of
origin, societies to which many belonged as well as family
groupings. The burial ground on Vine Street is a valuable
primary source for the historical study of Middle Tennessee
because it is the final resting place of many of Rutherford
County's founding families.
The names inscribed on the tombstones, family plots, and
pertinent dates are the ravj materials available to begin a
journey into Murfreesboro and Rutherford County's past. VThen
these names are used with other local sources--census reports,
old newspapers, deeds and wills--many questions can be answered;
what were their professions, political affiliations, social
and economic positions in the community*^ VThat emei-ges is an
historical expose of not only the families but the city as a
55
whole: white, middle-class, professional, and economically
diversified. The cemetery attests to a slave population. The
"peculiar institution" was the basis of Rutherford County's
economy and society.
Rutherford County was established officially on 25 October
1803, with its county seat at Jefferson. On 17 October 1811, an
act of the Tennessee General Assembly founded Murfreesboro. At
first it was named Cannonsburgh, after the governor, but on
19 November 1811, its name was changed to "Murfreesborough" to
honor Col. Hardy Murfree. He provided the land for the neces-sary
public buildings v.'hich became the square. Soon the new
1
town was Rutherford's county seat.
According to the United States Census of 1810, there were
many peoples settled in the area. The Jettons, Andersons,
Killoughs, Subletts, Huggins, Burtons, Dicksons, Ruckers,
Bairds, and Rankins were established families before 1810. The
2
Maneys appeared in the 1820 census. All of these families are
interred in the Old City Cemetery.
These people brought prosperity and culture to Rutherford
County. They founded religious institutions, schools, and a
viable economy. Murfreesboro' s first church, the First
Presbyterian Church, vjas organized as early as 1811, and the
brick structure was completed in 1820. The cemetery was located
3
next to the church. A private school for young men, Hopewell
Academy, held classes in the early 1820s and was followed by
Soule's Female Academy. Various banks and businesses appeared
to provide services, merchandise, and emplojTnent for a growing
56
town. The record of these pioneers is found in the Old City
Cemetery.
The Jetton family plot contains eleven markers from its
patriarch, John Jetton, through numerous grandchildren. As
early as 3 November 1803, the Jetton family purchased property
in Rutherford County. John L. Jetton bought 250 acres near Lytle
6
Creek off Stones River from Joel Childress for $250. John was
born in North Carolina on 11 December 1778 and moved into
Tennessee v.'ith his family to remain until his death on 25 June
7
1854. John's brother, Robert, came also. He and his wife,
Nancy Wilson Jetton, settled in Rutherford in 1806. Robert
8
bought 125 acres from John for $500. After farming six years,
Robert opened a tavern in a log structure on South Main Street.
The tavern remained one of Robert's businesses from 1812 until it
9
burned in 1853. Between his farm and the ever popular tavern,
Robert was financially able to take advantage of a foreclosure
sale and turn a profit. On 4 February 1812 Sheriff M. McClanahan
held a public auction, and Robert purchased Jeremiah Wright's 186
acres on Stones River for $331. The next day Robert sold the
10
land to Archibald Shanks for $450--a profit of $119.
\^^len the War of 1812 began, Robert formed Captain Jetton's
Troop in December. It v:as part of the Tennessee Volunteer
Cavalry under Col. John Coffee. From September 1813 through
January 1814, Jetton's Troop served under Col. John Alcorn.
Robert returned to Murfreesboro but saw action again in the first
Seminole Expedition, 1817-1818. He was now Col. Robert Jetton,
and his commanding officer was Gen. Andrew Jackson. During this
57
Florida expedition, Jackson created an international incident
11
when he executed two British citizens as spies.
During his civilian interlude, 1814-1817, and after 1819,
Robert diversified his business. He and John purchased a
tanning business or tanyard in Murfreesboro, lot thirteen, from
Joel Childress for $800. In 1819 Robert bought John's interest
for $1000. Robert was a slave o\cner. In the 1820 census he
registered one slave, but the number grew. In July 1822 he
bought a twenty-five year old Negress, Peggy, and her infant son
12
from Samuel L. Black for $600.
V7ith a farm, slaves, tavern, and tanyard, Robert was wealthy
and politically oriented. He served in the Tennessee General
Assembly for Rutherford County, 1817-1821. Later he was elected
senator to the legislature, 1823-1825 and 1831-1833, a Jacksonian
13
Democrat.
The Jetton families prospered and grev; with Murfreesboro
and the county. Robert and Nancy had a son, Robert B. He chose
to become a tailor and formed a oartnership with a Mr. Farmer.
14
They advertized their business in the local paper in 1835.
Robert B. married Joanna L. Jetton, and their marriage produce
15
a son who died in infancy. \-7hen Robert B. Jetton's parents
died, he became more wealthy, but he continued as a tr-^ilor V7ith
16
Josiah W. Floyd in 1843. As the times changed and the slavery
issue grew into a national controversy, many Tennesseans had to
make difficult decisions, and Robert B. wa'^ no e/ception. He
offered his lands for sale and stated his r&gt;urpose--a desire to
17
go south.
56
From 1803 the Jetton families added much to Murfreesboro and
Rutherford County. As members of a church they helped to organ-ize,
the First Presbyterian Church, they utilized the adjacent
18
cemetery. Robert Jetton, the farmer, slave owner, solder,
businessman, and politician, died in December 1840. He and his
brother, John, and their family members filled the Jetton plot
in the City Cemetery: Anna, Sue, William and his wife,
Elizabeth, Rob H. , Margaret, Elizabeth Brenard, and Mary E.
Their death dates began with Rob H. in 1836 and ranged through
19
1895. The Jetton families of North Carolina were truly pio-neers
in Rutherford County.
The Anderson family occupies a sizeable plot in the Old
City Cemetery. Unlike the Jettons, the Anderson partriarch was
born in Virginia. Samuel, the third son of William Anderson of
Rockbridge County, Virginia, came to Rutherford County in 1810.
The Andersons were from an agricultural and Presbyterian back-
20
ground. He helped his father on the farm, but like his two
brothers, William E. and Robert, Samuel studied law. He received
his licence to practice in Tennessee in 1810. After moving to
Murfreesboro in 1811, Samuel met and married Elizabeth, daughter
of Col. Joseph and Sophia Rucker Burras. This marriage produced
21
several children.
In 1818 Samuel purchased half of lot twenty-three in
Murfreesboro from William E. Butler for $500. His law practice
led to an elective office in the Tennessee General Assembly.
Samuel's financial circumstances improved, and he increased his
property holdings. In 1820 he bought 200 acres at public auction
59
for $157.50 plus $10.22 damages. In the 1820 census he regis-tered
the ownership of five slaves, and the number grew as he
Drospered. On 12 December 1822 Samuel bought a Negro girl,
22
Phyllis, from James Shinalt for $150.
In 1834 a constitutional convention met to amend Tennessee's
original document of 1794. Samuel Anderson represented Rutherford
County at this convention. One of the issues to be decided was
the election of judges. He publicly stated his opposition to this
change on the grounds that it would obligate the judge and com-
23
promise bis objectivity in case decisions. Undoubtedly his
position held because he was appointed judge to the Fifth
Judicial Circuit in 1835; however, he ran again for this office
when the selection method changed. He was a successful candi-
24
date and served until his retirement in 1851.
In 1850 Elizabeth, his wife, died, and his eldest daughter,
Sophia Ellis, soon followed in 1851. The family plot was fenced
so thai: all could rest in peace as they had lived--as a family.
Samuel died on 29 July 1859 and left an extensive estate to his
heirs. To his granddaughter, Elizabeth El] is, he bequeathed 263
acres, eleven Negroes, and all that had been deeded to his
deceased daughter, Fophia. To '.'^illiam J. Anderson, his son,
Samuel gave the land on which VJilliam lived if he paid the $4,000
balance left owing, slaves, plus equal amounts of money in the
estate after all debts were paid. Mary Elizabeth, his younger
daughter, inherited his home, an equal portion of money, land not
already bequeathed, and the slaves of her choice as long as she
did not separate husband, v/ife, and children. As his V7ill attested
60
Judge Anderson died a wealthy man, yet one who had given much pub-lic
service in return. He joined his family in the fenced
25
Anderson area of the City Cemetery on Vine Street.
The family plot near the center of the graveyard belongs to
the Killoughs. Samuel Killough left North Carolina after the
Revolutionary War and crossed the mountains into Tennessee.
Born on 10 September 1763, Samuel and his wife, Mary, came to
26
Rutherford County in 1804. In 1807 he bought 640 acres from
an attorney, David Deadrik, for $700. His plantation was not far
from what became Murfreesboro. Samuel's nroperty was prosperous,
27
and in the 1820 census he claimed eighteen slaves. Perhaps he
needed the money or had no use for the land, but in 1823 he sold
272 acres to James Stewart for $200. The City Cemetery became
the final testimony and resting place for another nrominent
28
Rutherford County family.
The graveyard testifies to the presence of Murfreesboro'
s
first newspaper o^^ners and editors, G. A. and A. C. Sublett.
George Allen Sublett was born on 7 September 1792. He and his
brother printed their first newspaper, the Courier , on 16 June
29
1814. Murfreesboro' s government hired the Subletts to print
30
the city ordinances for $98 in 1818. In 1819 they bought a
lot in town for $500 from Mr. R. Ganav7ay to provide a permanent
home for their printing business and newspaper. Both brothers
o\&lt;Tied farm land outside of tovm; they registered six slaves in
the 1820 census and cleared a deed title with F. N. V/. Burton
for 750 acres. In 1822 George bought thirteen slaves at public
auction for $595.86 and purchased a Negress, Millie, and her
$1
four year old son, Randal, from Polly Morgan's estate for $626
in 1824. George diversified further in 1827 when he bought and
managed the Green House located on the west side of the square.
As newspaper owner and editor George advertized his new enter-
31
tainment business in the paper.
Sometime between 1824 and 1827 A. C. Sublett sold his interest
in the Courier to George, and the paper's name became the
Murfreesborough Courier . The yearly subscription fee for the
weekly edition remained the same, $3.00. Another change took
place in the newspaper in 1828; it took on a definite, publicly
declared, political stand x-jhen George changed its name to
National Vidette . On the front page George published:
George Allen Sublett, 14 years an editor,
subscriber to the principles of the 33
republican doctrine of Jefferson and Madison.
Undoubtedly the paper supported Andrew Jackson's presidential
candidacy. On 15 January 1828, five days after the paper's
release, Jackson came to Murfreesboro to be the guest of honor
to celebrate the Thirteenth Anniversary of the Battle of New
Orleans. As president of the committee for the celebration,
George Sublett invited the fam.ed Tennessee general. The event
was a great success with thirteen regular toast? offered and
twenty- four additional ones enjoyed. Most of the town's 955
34
population shared "Old Hickory's" visit.
The Sub]ett brothers brought a newspaper to Murfreesboro.
It \7as a success although the name changed ^^everal times for
various reasons. The to\\Ti grew intellectually, politically, and
geographically as had the fortunes of the Tubletts. Although
62
the marker in the cemetery did not declare George Sublett's pro-fession
and contributions, it recorded the fact that he was here.
35
George died on 26 March 1855.
The Old City Cemetery attests to Murf reesboro' s growth and
wealth. The town supported a newspaper and numerous merchants.
One of the general store o\\Tiers came from the Huggins family who
settled in T^utherford County in 1807. UilMam Huggins bought
200 acres from Thomas Donell for $A50. The property lay :n
Rutherford and Davidison counties along the west waters of Stones
36
River. Jonathan Huggins, a relative of William, bought lot
three on Lytle Street for $600 from Samuel H. Laughlin. The
store was located on the southwest corner near a house formerly
37
occupied by Gideon Jarratt. Jonathan advertized his "cash"
grocery store in the local newsnaper, Tennessee Telegraph , in
38
May 18A0. The City Cemetery marked the nassing of VJilliam
39
Huggins' wife, Mary Elizabeth, and Elizabeth Huggins.
The Spence family offered free enterprize competition in
the dry goods business. J. Snence came to Murfreesboro from
40
Jefferson, Tennessee. He opened a store in 1813. Marmon and
Brent Spence continued the family tradition in 1833 when they
entered a partnership vjith Willis Snell. By 1834 the Spence
brothers dissolved their business with Snell and advertized
41
their new store as "M. &amp; B. Spence &lt;^.- Co." in the local paper.
Marmon remained a merchant until his death on 24 February 1847,
at the age of fifty-nine. His wife, Sarah, who V7as born in
Ireland, lived ten years after her husband. She v.'as buried
42
beside him in the City Cemetery in 1857.
63
The general merchandizing business expanded when the Leinau
family came to tovm. Daniel Leinau managed a store one door
north of the Washington Hotel. As late as 1840 the Leinaus adver-
43
tized their business as a "cash" store in the newspaper. Daniel
married Eliza and they had a daughter, Lavinia. Lavinia married
a Hilliard. Mrs, Milliard memorialized her deep affection for her
mother when she erected a large, elaborate stone to mark Eliza
44
Leinau' s grave in the City Cemetery in 1855.
The Burtons entered Rutherford County later than some of its
more prominent families, but they came with more wealth. For the
"sum of one dollar and considerations," Frank N. W. Burton received
sizeable property holdings from Leonard Henderson of Granville
County, North Carolina. In Tennessee, Burton was given: 1240
acres in Williamson County; one tract of land in Rutherford
consisting of 400 acres which had been a Revolutionary War land
grant, number 196, originally deeded to Henry Windburn and
located near Murfreesboro; 216 acre? on Stones River near the
same town and part of a war land grant that had belonged to John
Butler, number 162; 640 acres in Montgomery County on the north
side of the Cumberland River, Baker Archer's v.'ar land grant,
number 211; 256 acres on the south side of the Cumberland in
Davidson County, part of a 640 acre land grant originally
belonging to John Pearce; and 228 acres in Wilson County which
had been granted to Mason Williams. In Tennessee, Burton's pro-
45
perty sprawled over five counties and contained 2390 acres.
Frank N. W. Burton was born in North Carolina on 2 May
1779. He married Lavinia B. Murfree, Col. Hardy Murfree's
64
daughter. She was born 3 April 1795. Their union produced six
46
children, four daughters and two sons, Frank Burton was a
gentleman farmer in Rutherford County and took part in various
cultural and social activities. He was a founder, board member,
and trustee of Soule's Female Academj'-, begun in 1825 and staffed
by Mary and Nancy Banks. The young ladies who attended were
taught rhetoric, philosophy, belles-lettres , painting, needle-work,
and iTiusic--all the subjects gentile southern ladies should
47
know
.
Frank and Lavinia's first son. Hardy Murfree Burton, became
well known in political circles. He was born 7 June 1818 and
married Mary D. Hoggatt. As a member of the VJhlg Party he sat
in the Tennessee General Assembly for Rutherford County, 1841-
1843. Hardy was a Mason and served as the Grand Master of the
Grand Lodge of Tennessee in 1848. He was also a member of the
Knights Templar. Hardy was one of the incorporators of the
Murfreesborough Savings Institute, founded in 1850. Under
President Millard Fillmore, young Burton served in the West
Indies during 1852. Soon after his arrival, he died on 15
December. His body was returned to Murfreesboro, and he was
48
interred in the Burton family plot in the City Cemetery.
The Burtons were wealthy, respected, and added much to the
economic, cultural, and social life of Murfreesboro. In the
City Cemetery their family plot was located near Vine Street and
received the infant Robert in 1821. Frank N. W. Burton died in
1843; Sally M. Dotson, a daughter, in 1850; Hardy in 1852; Eli^a
F. Crosswaithe, a daughter, in I860: and Finie in 1862. Lavinia
65
Burton saw her large family laid to rest and joined them in 1881.
49
She died in Kentucky at the age of eighty-six.
Before the wealthy Burtons arrived in Middle Tennessee, Gen.
Joseph Dickson settled in Rutherford County. He vias born in
Chester County, Pennsylvania, in April 1745. With his parents
he moved to Rowan County, North Carolina, attended college, and
received a law degree. In 1764 Dickson married Margaret McEwen
and they had nine children. Joseph owned a cotton and tobacco
plantation. ^'Then the American Revolution began, he was an active
member of the Committee of Safety in Rowan County. Dickson was
commissioned a captain in the American army in 1775 and fought
at the Battle of Kings Mountain. Capt. Dickson became a major
and led the Lincoln County Men. They opposed Lord Cornwall is'
invasion of North Carolina in 1781. Because of his bravery and
commendable service to the new nation, Joseph Dickson was pro-moted
to colonel. By the end of the war he was a brigadier
general. Dickson served as general to the state militia and sat
in the North Carolina convention which ratified the United States
Constitution in 1789. He was a member of the state senate and a
commissioner v:ho helped to establish the University of North
Carolina, 1788-1795. He was a United States Congressman for
50
North Carolina and served from 4 March 1799 until 3 March 1801.
'vTien Dickson arrived in Tennessee in 18' '3, he settled in
what v.'as then Davidson County, but with the creation of a nev;
county, his property lay in Rutherford near Murfreesboro, w'lere
he oracticed law. From 1807-1809 he sat in the state legirlature
51
and became Speaker of the House, 18'19-1811. In 1812 Josenh
66
and Margaret worked to establish the First Presbyterian Church.
He lived long enough to see the brick structure go up on Vine
Street. The church was organized by Reverend Robert Henderson,
a relative of Margaret Dickson. The building was completed in
5 2
1820, forty by sixty feet with a gallery and cupula.
Margaret Dickson died 10 November 1814 and was interred in
the family cemetery on their plantation. \Then Joseph passed
away, he was buried next to his wife. The stone v/hich the family
erected was very large and imposing, as Joseph had been in life.
But as the cemetery filled, the Dickson marker overpowered all
others, and the family was asked to move the monument. It
seemed befitting that this huge tombstone be placed in the City
Cemetery, facing Vine Street, with the other markers which bore
53
the names of Murfreesboro' s founding families.
The growing town did not lack for medical services because
several doctors settled in the area, Drs. Henry Holmes and
William R. Rucker. They brought with them a religious conscious-ness,
and interest in education and politics. Dr. Holmes and his
vjife, Sarah, were one of the founding families of the Methodist
Episcopal Church which met on College Street in 1821. Rrverend
Robert Paine led the services. By 1823 the congregation bought
a brick house for $1800 to be used as the church building. Its
membership included another physician. Dr. Rucker, v.'ho was
interested also in education for young women. He aided in the
establishment of Soule's Female Academy. The lot on v.'hich the
Methodist Church house stood became the site for the school.
Rucker tock part in politics and supported the presidential
67
candidacy of Andrew Jackson in 1828. Drs. Rucker and Holmes,
54
along with their v;ives, were buried in the City Cemetery.
Dr. Jonathan Bostick added his name to the available physi-cians
when he came to Murfreesboro. Like the other doctors he
had more than enough business to remain in the area. He and his
wife, Margaret, had four children, but medical knowledge and
skill did not avert the tragedy recorded on the stones in the
cemetery: Margaret Bostick, born 10 November 1843, died 28 July
1856. She was twelve years old. Marietta Bostick lived little
more than a month and died 19 July 1852. Jonathan succumbed
before his first birthday. Times were very hard on young child-ren
and v;omen. Mrs. Bostick oassed away in 1858, at the age of
55
thirty-three.
Another prominent doctor, plantation o\'mev , and businessman
settled in Rutherford County. Dr. James Maney v.'as born in
Hertford County, North Carolina, on 9 February 1790, and remained
in that area until he married Sallie H. Murfree, daughter of Col.
Hardy Murfree. Murfree gave his daughter ^74 acres in Rutherford
Countj' for a wedding present. James and Sallie cam.e to Tennessee
and moved into a four room, two-story structure which they
56
expanded and beautified rs their family and fortune grew.
From the beginning James was a phj'sician and slave ovmer.
His estate grev; because of his profession and the demand for cotton,
In the 1820 census he registered fiftj^'-five slaves, quite a large
number for the times. Not all of his business ventures were suc-cesses.
Maney bought the failing Washington Cotton Factory in
1841. He and his son, Thomas, advertized cotton yarn produced at
6d
the factory for a very "reasonable" price. But the business was
doomed. It changed hands several times before it folded com-
57
pletely and v/as sold for $1500.
Maney's family size kept pace with his businesses. He and
Sallie had the children to fill the ever growing house which they
called Oaklands. Their first child was a daughter, Frances, born
in 1813; their second, James H, came in 1818; Thomas in 1821;
David Dickinson in 1828; William B. in 1832; and John B. in 1835.
However, most of the children were not as physically strong as
their parents. Frances died in 1838, twenty-eight years old;
James H. died at twenty in 1838; Thomas reached his twenty-eighth
year, married and saw the birth and death of his son before
he died in 1847; William was six years old when he passed av7ay in
58
November 1838; and John B. lived only four years and died in 1839.
David Dickinson Ma.ney reached the age of seventy-one and
outlived his father. David was educated in and around Rutherford
County and married Mary E. Bell, daughter of John Bell. Like his
father-in-law, David adhered to the political principles of the
Ivhig Party before the Civil War; he edited the Rutherford
Telegraph , the party paper, in 1853 and undoubtedly supported John
Bell's presidential candidacy in 1860 for the Constitutional Union
Party. After the war David became a Democrat and served as
Rutherford and Bedford counties' senator in the state legislature,
1877-1879. Along with his brothers and sister he was buried in
the family plot on Vine Street. His mother died in 1857 and his
father in 1872. The family v.'as complete again in 1899, not at
the old home, Oaklands, but under the large tree in the Old City
59
Cemetery.
69
The burial ground on Vine Street testifies to the economic,
political, and social maturity of Murfreesboro and its citizens.
The people interred there were farmers, merchants, politicians,
and bankers. However, the banks suffered or grew as the economy-fluctuated
before the Civil War. The town's first bank,
Murfreesborough Tennessee Bank, was chartered in 1817, but due to
the money situation in general, it began to clo^^e down after five
years. William and Joseph Spence, merchants, opened the Exchange
Bank, based on the free banking system, in 1853. By 1857 it
closed because of mismanagement. It opened again in 1858 to
60
close completely the same year.
Besides banks, plantations, legal services, and medicine, the
cemetery attests to other educational, religious, and economic
establishments. Reverend Robert Henderson, organizer of the First
Presbyterian Church, was the master of n private boy's school,
Hopewell Academy. Several of his students published a letter of
appreciation for his services during the spring of ^8?U. The
letter dated 13 April 1824 v.'as signed by Robert J. Rucker, the
physician's son, and Lemuel M. Baird, son of a local businessman.
The Bairds had been in the area for some time. V/. D. Baird adver-tized
his carriage making business in the local paper. VJil lion's
vJife, Amada, v;as buried in the City Cemetery, and lemuel, her
61
son, was interred there in 1851. A member of the P.ankin family,
James Porter Rankin, became a minister. Hip father, Da^n'd, c?me
to Murfreesboro during its early years. Reverend '^ankin married
Ermina, but she becam.e a widow in 18 31. James died at the age of
tv7enty-six. Alexander Rankin was a merchant who advertized his
70
general store and its location on the south side of the souare in
62
1834. Others in the to\'m attempted to establish a public water-works
system which used cedar tubes, but the Rose Water Works
failed. Dr. John Holmes and his brother financed the first
Nashville, Murfreesboro, and Shelbyville Turnnike vjhich began in
63
1832 and opened in 1842.
Yet the Old City Cemetery holds many more stories. Violet L.
Alerander, consort of J. D. Alexander, was buried there in 1853.
Hov.'ever, Violet was not John's only wife. In September 1827, John
advert! red the fact that hi'^ v/ife, Polly, had left him, and he
vrarnod the public that h.e would not be responsible for any debts
or bills that she might incur if someone "harboured' her.
64
Perhaps that v.'as V7hy she left him.
Murfreesboro' s citirens v;ere a social people, and the tomb-stones
marked this fact also. As early as 1817 the Masonic Order
was in '".utherford County. Mount Moriah Lodge, Number IS, was
formed; its peti'rion was signed by F. N. IJ. Burton, M. B. Murfree,
B. F. McCulToch, John Lytle, A. C. Tub! ett , and Jo^n L. Jetton.
The lodge v.'ps nuite .active until the Anti-Mason ^arty entG'''ed
the presidential campaign of 1831. The Masons d'' ^continued
nieetip.gs because of adverse feeling in the comTiuinty. The 1'-&gt;d!:^c
65
resumed its activities in 1841.
However, the Temperance Society \':as not suspect, e- cept [)er-haps
by the tavern keepers and those who distilled Tenncr^^oe sip-ping
v:hiskey. The group crimed themselves the ^Jashingtcn
Temperance Society v.'ho met at the First Presbyterian Ch'jrcli. They
convened on 5 October 1827 and formally s\?nre:
71
Resolved, that they will abstain from the use of
distilled liquors; that they will not permit them
to be used by their families or servants except
for medicine; that they will not provide them as
articles of entertainment for their friends, and
they will discountenance the use of them in their
community.""
Probably because of a weakening of the will and the ever-tempting
memories of the good times at the tavern, interest in the society
waned. It was reorganized in 1847 during the nationwide tem-perance
movement. They called themselves Sons of Temperance.
Lucas Oslin w-'s an active member during his life as his tombstone
attested: Born October 25, 1799; died January 8, 1851; erected
67
by Rutherford Div. No. 5 Sons of Temperance.
These many grave stones with their nar.es established the
fact that the community and county's hi-^tory v;as shaped by the
people whose graves they marked. Yet none spoke more simply nor
clearly than two very rough stones, hand-hewn and chiselled by
amateurs. These undoubtedly belonged to tV70 slaves: Phebe,
4 August 18 37, 8 May 1863, and Joshua, of the Reeves family.
These two markers represented the economic base of Murfreesboro
and Rutherford County. However, the war which brought the death
to slavery did not destroy the community. The Civil VJar only
slowed its growth inspite of the fact that it was occupied
several times by the Union Army. The First Presbyterian Church
was torn do\\Ti to provide bricks and lumber for Fortress Rosecrans.
Yet the graveyard vrhich stood beside the church remained, more
68
poignant and important than ever.
All of these events were part of the lives of those people
V7ho now lie in the Old City Cemetery. Because they made this
72
history--the Jettons, Andersons, Killoughs, Subletts, Huggins,
Spences, Leinaus, Burtons, Dicksons, Holmes, Bosticks, Maneys
,
Ruckers, Bairds, Rankins, Alexanders, Oslins, Phebe, and Joshua
&#8212;
the Murfreesboro of early nineteenth century was a bustling,
living community. Their achievements, failures, friends, and
enemies are entombed and marked by the presence and preservation
of the Old City Cemetery. The graveyard on Vine Street stands
as a monument and enshrines a segment of Tennessee and American
history.
Perhaps better than an old, restored home, diaries, deeds,
wills, and old newspapers, a cemetery provides the names of not
one family but many who comprised a very young to\&gt;m of a new
state. The names on the stones are the raw material that is used
with other local sources from which history is written. These
peopled whose lives are represented by the markers in the Old
City Cemetery made history, even if in a small v;ay, by reflecting
the character, prejudices, and life-styles of the times. They
made history by the mere fact that 'hey lived to build the foun-dation
on which present-day society is based.
73
FOOTNOTES
Goodsneed Histories, History of Tennessee (Nashville: The
Good-peed Publishing Co., 1886}, p. 826; hereinafter cited as:
Goodsneed, History .
?
U. ?. Bureau of the Census, State of Tennessee, Tvutherford
County, 1810 (Microcopy. Middle Tennessee State University,
Murfreesboro, Tennessee), pp. 2-28; hereinafter cited as: U. S.
Census, 1810; U. S. Census Office, 4th Census, 1820, State of
Tennessee: Giles, Maury, Rutherford, Shelby, Stev.'art, Sumner
Counties (Microcopy, Middle Tennessee State University, Murfreesboro,
Tennessee); hereinafter cited as U. S. Census, 1820.
3
Homer Pittard, Ph. D. , private interview. Middle Tennessee
State University, Murfreesboro, Tennessee, October, 1974; herein-after
cited as: Homer Pittard, interview; Goodspeed, History ,
op. 838-39.
4
The Courier , 15 April 1824, Murfreesboro, Tennessee;
Goodspeed, History , p. 836.
Tombstones, Old City Cemetery, Vine Street, Murfreesboro,
Tennessee; hereinafter cited as Tombstone, Old City Cemetery.
6
Rutherford County Deed Book, ABCDEF, 1804-18-''9 (Rutherford
County Court House, Murfreesboro, Tennessee), A, p. 36; herein-after
cited as R. C D. B. , .ABCDEF .
7
Tombstone, Old City Cemetery.
8
Dan M. Robison, State Librarian and Archivist Emeritus,
Biographical Directory: Tennessee General Assembly. 1706-1967
(Preliminary No. b) Rutherford County (.Nashville; Tennessee
State Library and Archives, 1968), p. 31; hereinafter cited as:
Robison, BioRraohical Directory ; R. C D. B. , ABCDEF, B, p. 176.
Q
Goodspeed, History , n. 827.
in
R. C. D. B. , H, np. 2^^5-98.
11
Robison, Bj o:;raphical Directory , d. 31.
12
R. C. D. B., K, p. 463; L. , p. 479; 0, p. 492; U. S.
Census, 1820.
13
Robison, Bior.ranhical Directory , p. 31.
14
Ibid.; The Monitor, 19 August 1835, Murfreesboro, Tennessee.
74
15 ^ t. T &#8226;
Jeannette Tillotson Acklen, compiler, Tombstone Inscrip-
Mons and Manuscripts (Nashville: 1st pub., 1933; reprint ed.,
Baltimore tGeneolbgical Co., 1967), p. 357; hereinafter cited
as: Acklen, Tombstone Inscriptions .
The Jeffersonian . 10 June 1843, Murfreesboro, Tennessee.
Murfreesboro News . 8 December 1858, Murfreesboro,
Tennessee.
18
Goodspeed, History , pp. 838-3^-.
1&lt;^
Tombstones, Old City Cemetery; Acklen, Tombstone Inscrip-tions
, p. 357.
^Joshua W. Caldvjell, The Bench and Bar of Tennessee
(Knoxville: Ogden Brothers &amp; Co., Printers, 1H^)&#171;;, pp. 248-51;
hereinafter cited a=: : Caldwell, Bench and Bar .
21
Robison, Bio,&lt;;raphical Directory , p. 1; 'tombstone. Old City
Cemetery.
22
P.. C. D. B., L, p. 251; M, p. 37^; 0, p. '-"2.
23
Central Monitor , 18 January 1834, Murfreesboro, Tennessee.
24
Robison, Biopjraphical Directory , p. 1.
Tom.bstones, Old City Cemetery; Pajtherford County VJill Bool",
Number 2 . Samuel Anderson, \7ill (Rutherford County Record^,
^ October 185^, Murfreesboro, Tennessee!^, pn. l84-8'^'.
26
Ac^'len, Tombstone Inscrlnt Ions , n. "^"'f^i.
R. C. D. B., ABCDEF, E, p. 436; U. ^. Census, 18?'',
Rutherford.
28 ^ . .
R. C. D. B., 0, p. 538; Ac''--len, Tombstone In'^criptions ,
D. 356.
2^
Tombstone, 0]^^ City Cemetery; Goodspeed, 'li^iiory , p. 8^1.
3
Goodsoeed, Hi story , o. 827.
31
U. S. Censu'5, 1820, Rutherford- R. C. D. B. , N, po. ll^-2f',
27'': 0. p. 540; &#163;, p. 12^: Murfrec^borou-h Courier , "'7 '^cpt ember
1 82"^ ,~Murfree&lt;^bnro, Tenre'^'"ee.
32
The Courier, 15 April 1 "''''&#8226;, Murfreesboro. Tenne^-^ee*
Mur^rec^borourh Comier .
" 2^ f'ep'ember K'^"^- Murrrec^bo-rO;
Tenne=:^ee.
33
National ''idette, 10 ^anuary 1828, Murfree'^boro, Tenne'^'^ee.
75
34
Good^peed, Hi.gtory , p. 328.
35
Tombstone, Old City Cemetery.
36
U. S. Census, 1810; R. C. D. B., ABCDEF, E, p. 406.
37
R. C. D. B., ^, p. 250.
38
Tennessee Telegraph , 2 May 1840, Mnrfreesboro, Tennessee.
39
Acklen, Tombstone Inscriptions , p. 356.
40
Goodspced, History , p. 827.
41
Central Monitor . 25 January 1834, Murfreesboro, Tennessee.
42
Tombstones, Old City Cemetery.
43
National Vidette, 10 January 1828, Murfreesboro, Tennessee;
Tennesrce Tel e;;raph . 2 May 1840, Murfreesboro, Tennessee.
44
Tombstone, Old City Cemetery.
45
R. C. D. B. , L, op. 61-63.
46
Tombstones, Old City Cemetery.
47
National Vidette , 10 January 1828, Murfreesboro, Tennessee;
Goodspeed, History , p] 8 36
.
48
Robison, Biographical Directory , pp. 9-10.
49
Tombstones, Old City Cemetery,
50
Robison, Bio;r;raphicfn Directory , pp. 14-15.
51
Ibid.
52
Worth S. Ray, Tennessee Cousins (Baltimore: Geneological
Publishing Co., I960), p. 616; Goodspeed, History , pp. 838-39.
53
Homer Pittard, interview.
54
Goodspeed, Histons pp. 827, 836, 839; National Vidette .
10 January 1828; Tombstones, Old City Cemetery.
55
Tombstones, Old City Cemetery; Acklen, Tombstone
Inscriptions, p. 357.
3t
'
Oaklands Society, "Oaklands, 1786-1865," brochure,
Murfreesboro, Tennessee.
76
57
U. S. Census, 1820, Rutherford; Goodspeed, History ,
p. 8?8; Tennessee Telegraph, 6 February 1841, Murfreesboro,
Tennessee.
58
Tombstones, Old City Cemetery.
59
Robison, Biographical Directory , p. 39; Tombstones, Old
Ci^y Cemetery.
60
Goodsneed, History , p. 830.
61
Courier , 15 April 1824, Murfreesboro, Tennessee;
Tennessee Telegraph , 2 May 1840, Murfreesboro, Tennessee;
Tombstones , Old City Cemetery.
62
Tombstones, Old City Cemetery; Central Monitor ; 11 October
1834, Murfreesboro, Tennessee.
63
Goodspeed, History , op. 816-17, 828.
64
Tombstones, Old City Cemetery; Acklen, Tombstone
Inscriptions , p. 355; Murfreesborough Courier , 27 September 1827,
Murfreesboro, Tennessee.
65
Goodsneed, History , p. 832.
66
Ibid., p. 839.
67
Ibid., n. 832; Tombstone, Old City Cemetery.
68
Tombstones, Old City Cemetery; Homer Pittard, interviev;.</dc:description>
<dc:description>A historical analysis of the Old City Cemetery in Murfreesboro</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Cemeteries; Rutherford County (Tenn.); Murfreesboro (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>47 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-15</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication17ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/171</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>