<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Alfred Blackman</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Baskin, Robert</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 27</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1986</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>19th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Alfred Blackman (1790-1872) was born in Clinton,
North Carolina and came to Rutherford County with his parents,
James Blackman and Elizabeth Gates, in the Spring of 1800. The Blackmans had lived in and around Clinton, li ,C . for
at least four generations a nd ware closely associated with
the Kin(^ and Jiieil fauiilies there. Ann Snell.tha dau_Mter of
ROf^er and Ann 3nell,was married to a Kinij and they had children.
Later, '..idow L'-nell married Stephen .ilackman, the father uf
Ja&gt;'ies Blackman and the grandfather of Alfred 'ilacinnan, therefore
the Kin[^ and lUackman children by Ann ::,ne ll-Aint:--&gt;lackman were
half brothers and sisters, Ann an i :')tephen nau two sons, John
and Bennett ulaclaaan who cai.io to Davidson around 130J an(i later
were c/tensive iandholJers in Davids jn,v;illia'riS .m and uaury
couaties. The ilackman-'i'r liable liouso,now ^trjndin^ and ouilt by
Bennett .iluckman, is said to be the oldest hour e in ilai.u'y County.
Their :ji'other, James a. id son^ settled on a 7'., odd acre tract in
the area later to be known as Blackiaan Community. The '.injs
and Blackmans (half brutbers ) and their kin, the Snells all
came iiito Kuti.erford County in the early 1-iJJs and were the pioneer
settlers in ohe western part of this co'onty. Most of the land
upon which tee^-a peoale settled was called tii. .^rinstron^ Brant
of 7,^JJ acres, .-rtiistrong never came here but some of iiis cniidren
did.
113
Alfred Blackman, ^ly Great-Jreat .;ra.,dratlie.r , was just
eighteen years of age when he arrived in oui beautiful county
one hundred and seventy six years a^^o. About I8II lie was
married to ^jiizabeth Crawford, the daaji,ter of Lazarus Crawford
of Rutlierford, County , They became the parents of the following
children:
I. ifaiford Crawford iilackman -rb-Ann Aebecca didout -I053.
I this writer's ^reat grand perents
)
II. Hillary Oat^s Blackman
III. Temperance l''annin^ Blackman
IV.iarah Jane M i-lcLane
V . Lazarus Blackman I'l liatson
(ancestors of the Bateys, Lassiters, Huddlestons of
this county .
)
VI. James Blackman,
Vll.V.'illiam Blucki'ian.
Vlll.Ollen Bluckrnan.
( Jreat-Grandfather of the Actress, Loretta Youti^)
VIV. Benjamin BlacKman.
A . Julia Ann blackman I'i Hezakiah Kov;se
( parents of Miliary li. liowge, mayor of Nashville ,Tenn,
for about yj years-cir . 1910-iyU^.
)
Blackman Cominunity was named foi' Alfred, not his father who
settled here. Alfred (iunown as"i:isquir6"becauso he was a magistrate
in his district for a long time) became the honoree due to the
fact that he lived a long life and was prominent in the affairs
of his community.
The old family home,lon,,_; destroyed, was located on Vaughn
Road, about one mile south east of the crosn roads and one hundred
yards south of the cemetery which still stands.
114
.i.lfredjhis sons and the slaves^ t^row an enorrnua amount of
cotton on the large plantation when "cotton was king" in
itutherford, County, He owned the blacksmith shop that stood in
the south east quadrant of the cross road and it was operated
by one of his slaves. The iron jjate now at the cemetery was
handcrafted by the slave blacksmith. The shop was a very important
facility because all farm equipment was repaired there and even
some thin^-s built at the shop. Custom work was performed for the
public. iJxaraple of charges to the public: "i'oinuing a plow" S^-
cents. (this writer has many papers wuich represent the life
and times of the family),
Alfred, his wife, his mother, and and most of the children are
buried in the old cemetery mentioned above. The story of the
cemetery, as told to me by Uncle Horace liluckmun, was as follows.
After selecting a high place in the field one hundred yards back
of the house that drained in all directions, he hired a contractor
at a cost of $J0 dollars to build a rock wall to enclose an
eternal resting place for the family, liocks were hand hewn and
pulled to the location by oxen. Those square cut stones art
from two to sixteen feet long and one foot thick. The wall measures
fifty feet on foui side^ and is foui- feet high.
All the tall spire shaped grave markers , pointing to last resting
places, have fallen to the ravages of time and neglect.
The graveyard is involved in the story of the" lost gold".
During the Civil War, Alfred and Elizabeth had a consideraole
amount of gold in coin aind being fearful that it might bo confiscated
by the Yankees, looked for some &#8226; f-rife place to hide tne
115
money. They first considered hidini^ the gold in the graveyard
but, being fearful that it inijht be found, they finally decided to
hide their money among a large amoiAnt of sweet potatoes stored
in the basement of one of the slave cabins nearby, v^hen Alfred
went into the base.iient the slave family living there became
suspicious. During the night the slaves found the gold, loaded
their belongings onto a mule cart and left. As luck would have
it, he lost the gold, his slaves, and a mule.
Alfred was over seventy years old at tue beginning of the
Civil War so, in this brief account of his life and times, we will
not attempt to tell of the ravages inflicted upon this farnily and
others in the area.-"- Blackman, being a very fertile country,
was foraged upon severly by the Yankees. Destruction was complete,
neighbors who suffered like fates were the Bateys ,Bee3lo -'s ,his
son,H.C. who had married Ann Hidout and owned a farm, and many
others.
About 1811, soon after Alfred and ijJlizabeth Crawford were
married. Rev. Stone from Kentucky came into the community to
preach and, because of his influence , the young cuuple wei-e
converted to the Church of Christ and remained strong advocates
for the rest of their long lives.
-"- I have the King Papers, a story by Wm.H.King who was II). years
of age who tells the story of the horrors inflicted upon a
family of neighbors to the Black;(ians
.
116
Alfred and his wife had a leadin^ roll in ostablishintj
the first Ghurcn of Christ in Rutherford county, i'^ormed in
1812, the group met on the banks of uverall creek in the
Blackman area. Eventually this coui^rb^^ation became a part of
the iiiast Main Uoiitjrogation in iiurfrees boro,Tenn , Alfred was
a trustee and elder in l8bJ when the new church was built on
ii^ast Main Street, Carol iioberts, (u'^^i--' Pub. I'Jo.22j states
Alfred Blackman paid most of tho cost of the lot upon which
the present i^ast Main Street (Jhurch of Christ now stands.
During his tenure as eider, he was personally acciuainted with
many prominent persons who attended &#177;^ix3t riain before, durin^:,
and after the Civil V/ar.
Alfred Blackman died in 1372 at the ago of 02. His will
provides, in part, that two a;;ed loinisters of his faith be
hired and paid two hundred dollars tj preach his and his family's
f ur:ieralS and that they preach for two days.
The villu;:;e of Blackman contained, in addition to the
blacksmitij shop, a storu,post of f ice, anothci' blacksmith shop;
by Dr. Hanson's house/ and two doctors offices, ivll that remains
of this once bustling villar^e is a small stoe^at the crosr. roads.
117 !
ALFRED BLACKMAN, DECEASED WILL !
I
I
Novombor 25, 1B7O, I, Alfred Bluckman of the State of Tonneasoe,
i
Ruthorford County, aa I havo given uli my proporty and monoy to my
j
l-'amlly up to thly proaont date to i.iy uutisfaotion, I appoint my j
Sua Hillory 0. Blackwan and William B. Lillai-d to divide the bal- I
i
aiicu of my uiOiioy that I may leave at my uuatli amongat my hoira eq- I
ually that I \/ill xiame beloa, after paying my burial oiiponaoa and I
ruaei'ving two hundi'ed dollai'3 to pay two good proachora to preach I
my funeral, uy wlfoa, my iviothora, and children v/hich are all bur- 1
ied m my graveyard together. Thoje I wish to preach Owo days for '
I
U3 a I am aatiafied frun experiencej that I have had for fifty years
I
that we ai'e on th&gt;3 true foundation of the Apoatlea and i-'rophota
j
Je3U3 CnrlJt being the chief corner Stcnu&#171; Thoae preachers I wlah
to b3 out oi' my o\iTi doiiuininaticn and u/jed uxporiencad mono I pro-ceed
no&#187;/ to uaoie my hoira^ flrjt iioiri O il on M, Blackmanj, t\io gi^and-children
by the name of Jenny and Robert Royal, Second holri^Raforcl
C&#171;' Blackmanj, third heir3lai:aru j Blaokiuan^ thre&lt;! children by the i
name of Alfx'ed, Elizabeth, and l.artha, fourth holry.H ilier y 0&#171;
j
Blaclcnian, flfbh he ir.-4 James A, Biackinan, daughter named oamea, sixt
hulr^. Julia House, seventh hoir-Tl^lla Lillurd, eighth lioir^Sarah
Jane IJcClanos, foui* chlldi'ea by the nauio of Alfred, Charloa, Julia '
and Sally, ninth heirgi|-ary Harding, tenth helri^'f OLiperonc o t- axmings ,,'
Son by the name of William h, mannings, hiLs money to be received
when he is twenty- one years of ago and if ho should die before that
time then all the money that I have given him must return to the 1
balance of my heirs that is named above. Last 1 give myself to
i
God in whom my hopes of Heaven depends*
I
/s/ Alfred Blackman '
V/itness: i
118
M o
o &lt;
02 o
t- 'S
^' o
3
&gt;
I?
r-S
p.- m
-
':&#8226;';;'.' I'M
_:.- ' i^if^^'jJ""^^'*'
119
Blackman Cemetery ( Cir 1850!
Blackman, Tennessee
Rutherford County
120
Alfred Blacknan- 1/9J-1-72
iwaikin&#163;j; cane now owni.-. d by .\',vB.)
121
c 5 &gt;-b TO 6 o M 1-3 '-&lt;
O TO
^. c+ "^ (3. M- &#8226;-tl 1 h
&#163;- 5^ m pi n. 3 &amp; O W (0
^^ o &#163;6 M (B ^^ H- tn o t-" td i-^ a. M t-^ M^ &#8226;i rn M -^l o M t.^d M o" a. M -n r,i TO ^ ID
2 S (T) m (D o H- a H O
(T) O-. CL ^ &#8226;i
y
M re n wP' dd oTO '-b CH-9
a* o
o o TO
"D
o
r3 S
TO
TO ir TO rn
3B &gt;&#8226; rt-
&#8226; &#8226; o w -^ O TO M O 4
m I':
O
f1 ^ a rT) 3
H&#171;&lt;1 M 3 ro
s A'
&#171;D h- O. tl g? &#8226;-^ rr
(D M ID rn &#8226;3'
&#8226; ^
&gt;&#171;&#8226; H- M P-
03 H rn W c+ &lt;-&#187;- 1&#8212;
&#8226;
ro 5 &lt;+
5^ p:
rn
O
s
iB
g:
TO
o CI 3 H- (t
r+
^
n
a-
&#167; O
(!) tr TO (l&gt; M i-b ^&#8212;
^
Ct&gt; 4 tn Cb TO
o
'i3
^
3
p. B"
&lt;
H
(B
c+
e
TO n 2
CT '0
CO (B
a rfl
.f!]
&lt;! ti-er
[0 ro O &gt;S H i-b D o4
C &amp;
-/^*:irf
fiV;
.'"i\ 122
iJ'Vi. ^
/
7.'7-
V.^ /
r^,
7
&gt;*t'^.Ti.&#171;j|&#171;v.' :".-^!y fT. -"&#8226;':"'rif^ l^^'f"^'
'S'y.\4.k- J.i:-Xy 1 &gt;&#8226;/'/'&#8226;
.&#8226;'..'., lln-i^- i ^1 .
'.' ^'
II 1 ,
;
-'^/ --/2_
"]/(".-' ' .T/ f
'' /' i '/ /
)lcii
7-.-
I
:
.
,
'/
/ / . W-il:
2. ^'
V 1 /,:},
I /.
&#8212;/
/
'J ^
\ / / &lt;y ..
Items sold at an atl'ction sale.
123
\
&#8226;!&#171;:
O
fl&#187; 124
Mh
.; li
</dc:description>
<dc:description>Provides a history of Alfred Blackman and his family, early settlers of the Blackman community</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Blackman, Alfred</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Blackman</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>13 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-01; mt2011-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication27ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/40</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>