<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Archaeological and anthropological aspects of the prehistory of Rutherford County</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Smotherman, Travis E.</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 3</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1974</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>Prehistory</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>17
ARCHAEOLOGICAL AND ANTHROPOLOGICAL ASPECTS
OF
THE PREHISTORY OF RUTHERFORD COUNTY
by Travis E. Smotherman
Rutherford County, Tennessee, when considered as a poli-tical
entity, was organized in 1803; thus its complete and
recorded history spans some 17 decades of time. Yet, it
possesses an earlier, unwritten history untrammeled by arti-ficial
boundaries, shrouded in the dim mists of time past and
obscured by the uncertain knowledge of man's earliest antiquity.
To quote A. W. Putnam, writing of the area in his History
of Middle Tennessee :
In unknown ages the heathen were here; these wild
woods were once inhabited, or the race of man was before
these forests. The bones of thousands rest beneath the
very roots of our gigantic oaks. . . But again the living
are here; tumuli and earth - works are throughout the
land. But when came the one, or wherefore the others,
none can tell. Our questions obtain answers obscure as
those given by the pyramids and their builders.
PHYSIOGRAPHY
A brief glimpse at Rutherford County's physiography is in
order before undertaking a purview of its prehistory. Ruther-ford
County comprises 580 square miles, with elevations ranging
from 570 feet to 1, 352 feet&#8212;the elevation at the courthouse
is 617 feet. More than half the county lies in the Central
'A. W. Putnam, History of Middle Tennessee (first published
Knox^
^C. C,
1929, p. 3,
1859) Knoxville, 1971, p. 5.
C. Henderson, The Story of Murfreesboro , Murfreesboro,
18
Basin of Tennessee, with a ring of hills almost surrounding
the county, especially to the east and southeast. Murfreesboro
lies in the central plain. Almost the entire county is drained
by Stones River and its tributaries, with the Harpeth rising
in the southeastern portion of the county, near Eagleville,
and, with its tributaries draining a small portion thereof.
R. S. Bassler describes the predominant geological feature of
the county as " . . .a level plain (with) fertile brick red
soil.
PREHISTORIC CULTURES
Rutherford County shares a general identity with the pre-historic
cultures which once flourished in this region. For
the benefit of those persons unacquainted with the anthro-pological
classification of these cultures, a brief summari-zation
of their most salient features will be undertaken.
Generally speaking, the span of time covered by these cultures
4
is roughly from 11,000 B. C. to 1,600 A. D.
Subsequent to the discovery by Dr. Louis Leaky and his
associates in Tanganyika of substantial evidence to indicate
the existence of a very ancient "pebble tool" user, the anthro-pologist's
conception of this progenitor man as a distinctive.
^R. S. Bassler, The Stratigraphy of the Central Basin of
Tennessee (Tennessee Division of Geology), Nashville, 1932, p. 54
'^Emma Lila Fundaburk and Mary Douglass Fundaburk Foreman,
Sun Circles and Human Hands , Luverne, Alabama, 2nd Printing,
1965, p. 9. (Unless otherwise noted, all prehistoric culture
dates are taken from this source.)
19
thoughtful and designing creature was thrust back into the vast
ages of antiquity, of fossil bone and long extinct life forms.
And in support of Dr. Leaky and his theories, some scholars
have cited evidence to support the existence of a new world
pebble user. Such a man, if he ever lived in North America,
must have lived here well before 11,000 B. C. , and perhaps as
long ago as 50,000 B. C.
Paleo man : The oldest generally recognized North American
aboriginal culture is classified as "Paleo" by archaeologists.
The epoch of paleo man would roughly encompass the span of time
from 11,000 B. C. to 5,000 B. C.^ Paleo man coexisted with the
extinct wooly mammoth, with his distinctive spear points being
found in the western United States in association with the bones
of these creatures. Paleo man was nomadic and followed large
herds of bison, elk and deer, as well as the mammoth. He
fashioned a large, very well made, fluted point.
Archaic man ; Archaic man is generally dated as occupying
the period of time from 5,000 B. C. to 2,000 B. C. He hunted
smaller game than did Paleo man, and was less nomadic, with
his populations tending more toward concentration. He was also
a gatherer of seeds, nuts, fruits, berries, edible roots, fish
and shell fish. His major weapon was the atlatl (or two-part)
throwing spear, and his projectile points were generally smaller
and sometimes cruder than those of his predecessor.
Woodland man ; The culture subsequent to that of archaic
man is described as "woodland," and lasted from about 2,000 B. C.
Fundaburk does not assign a definitive date to the Paleo
period's earliest beginnings; however, she considers it well-established
by 8,000 B. C, and transitional with the archaic
period by 5,000 B. C.
FLINT PROJECTILE POINTS - Cripple Creek
(Coll., F. C. Youree)
FLINT PROJECTILE POINTS - near Smyrna
(Coll., Ernest Johns)
FLINT PROJECTILE POINTS - Cripple Creek
(Coll. , F. C. Youree)
LATE WOODLAND AND MISSISSIPPI
PROJECTILE POINTS (Coll., Steve Maloney)
PROJECTILE POINTS - Transitional Paleo,
Archaic, and Woodland (Coll., Steve Maloney)
FLINT PROJECTILE POINTS - Stewart's Creek
(Coll. , Ernest Johns)
^A^^-
)OTH NECKLACE - Cripple Creek
;on Collection at Vanderbilt
sity)
ADENA PROJECTILE POINT, Lavergne
(Coll., Richard Grabowski)
POTTERY VESSEL
Circa 500 B.C.
Bradley Creek
(Coll., Randy
Abernathy)
PRE- HISTORY
ARTIFACTS
&#8226;"Nt^
SANDSTONE TURTLE EFFIGY, Smy
(Coll., Richard Grabowski)
ARCHAIC AND WOODLAND PROJECTILE POINTS
Eagleville, (Coll., Travis Smotherman)
CHUNKY STONE, GREENSTONE PIPE, THROWING
WEIGHT, Cripple Creek (Coll., F. C. Youree)
THREE STONE CELLS FOR AXES, Cripple Creek
(Coll., F. C. Youree)
ARCHAIC PROJECTILE POINTS - 5,000 B.C.
(Coll., Steve Maloney) RUTHERFORD COUNTY PALEO IM'OJECTILE POINTS
(Coll., Steve Maloney and James Powers)
20
to about 400 A. D. Lewis and Kneburg, in Tribes That Slumber
term this culture a neolithic import from Asia centered in
the woodlands and hardwood forests of eastern North America.^
These people were the first Americans to use the bow and arrow,
to weave, and to manufacture pottery. Very likely, they also
began the first organized agriculture in the new world, while
continuing the gathering and collecting of food and the hunting
of game animals. Some ornamentation and elaborate burial
customs also characterized these people. Projectile points
were smaller and frequently crudely fashioned.
Mississippian man : The Mississippian culture was the
last and most recent prehistoric North American Indian culture
and generally covers the years 400 A. C. &#8212;1,600 A. D. These
people continued the refinements of their woodland predecessors.
Agriculture became much more advanced, and artistic ornamentation
in clothing, pottery and ceremonial objects became commonplace.
The development of agriculture permitted sufficient leisure for
the perfection of quite sophisticated art forms and the con-struction
of large temple mounds. Life was more settled and
large, palisaded villages sprang up. Very small, triangular
points for their arrow tips typify their projectiles. (In the
Cumberland River area, these people are frequently designated
as the "stone box burial" people.)
"Thomas M. N. Lewis and Madeline Kneburg, Tribes That
Slumber , Knoxville, 1958, p. 39.
21
RUTHERFORD COUNTY, 1600-1780
How did the area now comprising Rutherford County appear
just before the appearance of the first Europeans about 1780?
What sort of land did they survey as Rutherford County pre-history
suddenly merged into a historical perspective ranging
from the meager and uncertain first sources of retrospective
narrative and secondhand accounts right down to the present
day with its multifold and exact historical references? What
tribes of historic Indians ranged the area prior to 1780, and
what relation to these historic tribes bear to their prede-cessors,
Mississippian man? Such questions, unfortunately, do
not obtain easy answers for the historian or the researcher.
From all accounts, however, it must appear that there were
no permanent Indian settlements in Rutherford County in the
middle 1700' s, and probably there had been no such settlements
for two or three hundred years. It must also be obvious that
the Mississippian mound builder was culturally extinct in the
Middle Tennessee area when the first Europeans arrived.
To quote Carlton C, Sims, in the History of Rutherford
County , "... the Indians (did not) make settlement here (in
Rutherford County) , though the abundance of fish and game and
the large springs in the region make it a favorable hunting
ground as is evidenced by the large number of arrow heads found
7
on or near the surface."
^Carlton C. Sims, Editor, A History of Rutherford County ,
1947, p. 4.
22
Judge John Haywood, in his Civil and Political History of
the State of Tennessee , first published in 1823, says that the
first settlers in the Middle Tennessee region found no signs
o
of villages or of cleared lands.
However, there appears to have been no logical reason why
the area could not support a substantial population just prior
to 1780. Henderson cites the abundance of game, including
bear, elk and deer, which made the Rutherford County area a
q frequently visited territory by wandering Indian hunters.^
Thus, if the Rutherford County area had no permanent
Indian population in the years just prior to 1780 and the
first European contacts, then under what tribal suzerainties
did the area fall?
James Adair's map, to accompany his 1775 London publi-cation
of The History of the American Indians , shows the area
of Tennessee to have been populated by Cherokees in the east,
Chickasaws in the southwest, and the Nahchees in the north-west,
with a void indicated in the middle Tennessee region.
Carlton Sims says:
The Shawnees were probably the only Indians to make
permanent homes during the Colonial period in what is
now middle Tennessee. It appears that part of this
tribe, which originally lived in the Savannah River
area, settled on the Cumberland about 1670
Marquette, in his journal of 1673, refers to many Shawnee
^John Haywood, The Civil and Political History of the
State of Tennessee , reprinted Knoxville, 1969, p. 108-109.
^Op. Cit . . p. 6,
lOjames Adair, The History of the American Indians (First
published London, 1775) , Nashville, 1971 reprint.
23
villages on the lower Cumberland, the largest having
500 people. They are known at one time to have had
a town in the sight of Nashville, though there is
no evidence that they ever settled in what is now
Rutherford County. The Cherokees and Chickasaws
,
however, expelled the Shawnee about 1714. The
majority of the displaced Shawnees seemed to have
settled north of the Ohio on the Wabash. &#8226;'-1
To quote Burt and Ferguson, " (The) Cherokees and Chicka-saws.
. . cooperated in 1715 and again in 1745 to forcibly
expel bands of Shawnees from the rich hunting lands on the site
that is now Nashville, Tennessee."^
Gentry McGee, in his A History of Tennessee agrees that
the Shawnees once lived near Nashville, but says they "...
were driven out by the Cherokees, Creeks and Chickasaws. The
Uchees once lived around Nashville, but were killed out by the
Cherokees." He says further that the Cherokees and their
kinsmen, the Chicamaugas, and the Creeks, the Chickasaws, the
Shawnees of Indiana and even the Iroquois of New York claimed
hunting rights in the Middle Tennessee-central Kentucky area,
with none daring live there for fear of attacks from rival
claimants. -^^
Goodspeed's 1886 History of Tennessee offers still another
group contending for dominion over the Middle Tennessee and
Rutherford County areas. To quote:
-&#8226;^Op. Cit. , pp. 4-5.
-'-^Jesse Burt and Robert B. Ferguson, Indians of the South-east;
Then and Now, Nashville and New York, 1973, p. 41.
-'-^Gentry R. McGee, A History of Tennessee from 1663 to
1930, (Facsimile reproduction), Nashville, 1971.
24
Previous to 1780, the Indians had undisputed
sway in this (Rutherford) county. The old trace
leading -from Nashville to Chattanooga is still to
be seen. Along this route, the Choctaws, Chicka-saws
and particularly the Cherokees held undisputed
sway from time immemorial.-*-^
Two historians mention hostilities between the Cherokees
of East Tennessee and the Chickasaws of West Tennessee. Sims
writes
:
. . . the land, as a result of hostilities which
had broken out between the Cherokees and Chickasaws,
was seldom visited by the Indian hunters during the
middle of the 18th century. . . the Indians to the
south would not allow the Shawnees to establish perma-nent
settlements on their hunting grounds, and even
fought among themselves for hunting rights.-*-^
And, in Robert H. White's Tennessee: Its Growth and
Progress , we are told that the Cherokees from the eastern part
of Tennessee disputed Middle Tennessee with the Chickasaws of
West Tennessee, with the Creeks occupying the land to the
south. ^6
Thus, it may be observed that several Indian tribes are
credited with some control over the middle Tennessee area at
one time or another during the 17 00' s and just prior to the
first white visitations to the area of Rutherford County,
which Henderson dates as sometime just before 178 0, stating
that only a few adventurous whites had prospected the section
prior to this date, and of which visits no reliable records
are now available. 17
1'^ (Goodspeed' s) The History of Tennessee , Nashville, 1886,
p. 811.
'^0&#163;. Cit . , p. 5.
l6Robert H. White, Tennessee; Its Growth and Progress y
Nashville, 1936, p. 10.
17op. Cit . , p. 10.
25
Then, obviously the area was largely unsettled and sub-jected
only to the forays of various Indian hunting groups,
frequently contending with each other. It must, however, be
noted that most recorded incidents of Indian attacks on white
settlers and settlements in the middle Tennessee area may be
credited to warriors from the Creek nation to the south.
ARCHAEOLOGY
Having discussed the general cultural and tribal prehis-toric
background which Rutherford County shares with its
surrounding area, the writer will now attempt to support the
relationship with the archaeological evidence and theory
available.
Generally speaking, Rutherford County does not offer the
rich and varied archaeological sources of some of her sister
counties. There are, for instance, no sites to compare with
the mound complexes on the Harpeth River in Williamson and
Cheatham Counties, nor the vast "stone box" village sites
generally distributed throughout Davidson County, nor the
significant Spring Creek site in Wilson County. Nor, indeed,
is there a site comparable to Coffee County's Old Stone Fort
nor even Cannon County's multi-component site at Short Mountain.
Nonetheless, abundant archaeological evidence exists to
establish that representatives of each generally recognized
prehistoric culture once lived in and traveled over the area
now comprising Rutherford County, although there is some diver-sity
of opinion as to the relative value of this archaeological
evidence.
26
Leroy Camp, of Lavergne, Tennessee, a former president of
the Tennessee Archaeological Society and prominent Rutherford
County archaeologish, considers the scarcity of important archaeo-logical
site to be the most significant feature of any consid-eration
of Rutherford County archaeology. Camp said that a
two-week survey, in which he participated, under the sponsorship
of the University of Tennessee and the Corps of Engineers could
not find a single site worthy of excavation on Stones River,
prior to the flooding of the area with the construction of the
Percy Priest Dam. 18
Camp, of course, is not the only local archaeologist to
have made note of this sparsity of archaeological source
material in Rutherford County. In this connection, the writer
wishes to advance the theory that the large number of cedar
glades, with their thin, rocky soil and scarcity of plant and
animal food sources may have tended to hinder the development
of large aboriginal populations. R. S. Bassler says that in
Rutherford County the red cedar glades occupy an area of about
160 square miles. -'-^ In prehistoric times, these cedar glades
may well have covered a more extensive proportion of the county's
580 square mile total area.
James Powers of Murfreesboro, Tennessee, also a prominent
local archaeologish and former president of the Tennessee
Archaeological Society, offered a more generous opinion of the
value of the county's archaeological site, describing the county's
1 p '"Personal interview, April 7, 1974.
1^0&#163;. Cit. , p. 58.
27
sites as old, archaeologically speaking, and primarily of the
archaic period. 20
Published Archaeological References to Rutherford County
The first important writer on the subject of Tennessee
archaeology was Judge John Haywood. In his 1823 publication.
The Natural and Aboriginal History of Tennessee , two references
are made to Rutherford County and three to Murfreesboro. Judge
Haywood describes the physical location of the county and
mentions the abundant relics of testacious animals therein.
Murfreesboro references relate to the presence of quartz geodes
between Murfreesboro and McMinnville; the location of a
quantity of charcoal ten feet below the surface twelve miles
southeast from Murfreesboro, at a Mr. Ready's, on the bank of
the East Fork of Stones River; and the discovery of two brass
coins, two and one-half miles from Murfreesboro in an easterly
direction, in a garden about eighteen inches under the surface. 2**
' 25
^Opersonal interview, April 13, 1974.
2 '-John Haywood, The Natural and Aboriginal History of
Tennessee , (first published Nashville, 1823), Mary V. Rothrock,
Editor, Jackson, 1959, pp. 2-3.
22ibid. , p. 32.
23ibid. , p. 53.
24 Ibid. , pp. 169-170,
2 5 Ibid. , p. 420, footnote "k" , quotes Madeline Kneburg
,
former professor of anthropology at the University of Tennessee,
as saying that such coins as Haywood describes were also found
at Fort Loudon, and were used for part of the payment to soldiers
during the 1750' s. This properly places the coin discovery in
the context of historic archaeology.
28
Explorations of the Aboriginal Remains of Tennessee was
first published by the Smithsonian Institution in 1876. Its
author, Joseph Jones, M. D. , was health officer at Nashville
during the years 1868 and 1869, during which time he gathered
his relics and information. ^6 An illustration of a very fine
pipe, from the vicinity of Murfreesboro appears in this volume. 27
Dr. Jones describes the relic thusly: "... The large parrot-shaped
pipe, carved out of chocolate-colored steatite, is twelve
inches in length, and was discovered in the vicinity of aboriginal
remains, near Murfreesboro. " ^^
Camp believes this artifact was most likely a trade item,
especially considering the great distance to the nearest natural
habitat of the parrot. The writer, however, considers it also
likely that the aboriginal craftsman fashioned the piece as a
stylized representation of some local bird of prey, with its
hooked beak suggesting a hawk or eagle.
A third important writer on the subject of Tennessee
archaeology was Gates P. Thruston, whose The Antiquities of
Tennessee first appeared in 189 0. A former Union general who
2'6'^Robert McGaw, "Tennessee Antiquities Re-Exhumed,"
Tennessee Historical Quarterly, Summer, 1965, p. 124.
2'This pipe drawing is reproduced as the cover illustration
for this publication.
28joseph Jones, M. D. , Explorations of the Aboriginal
Remains of Tennessee (first published by the Smithsonian Insti-tution,
1876) Reprinted Knoxville, 1970, p. 76 and p. 138.
2^The present whereabouts of this outstanding relic is
unknown to the writer who considers it regrettable that it does
not grace the display case of some local museum.
29
married a Nashville girl and remained in Tennessee after the
Civil War, Thruston was an avid collector and student of Indian
artifacts and conducted many excavations in the vicinity of
Nashville. One reference appears which related to Rutherford
County: an illustration of various beads contains thirteen
drilled and strung canine-type teeth, which Thruston describes
as being "the teeth of the wolf, or of some wild animal." In
a footnote, Thruston says: "We are indebted to Zach. Patrick,
of Rutherford County, for this rare string of ancient beads. '
In the early part of the present century, William E. Myer
conducted several archaeological investigations in the middle
Tennessee area and published reports on his work. His "Indian
Trails of the Southeast" appearing posthumously in the 4 2nd
Annual Report of the Bureau of American Ethnology, 1928, lists
three Indian trails as traversing Rutherford County.
The first mentioned is the "Great South Trail, "-^ which
entered Rutherford County just above Eagleville, proceeded in a
30Gates P. Thruston, The Antiquities of Tennessee (first
published in Cincinnati, 1890) , reprint of Second Edition (1897),
Knoxville, 1964, p. 319.
^-"&#8226; Ibid . , p. 319.
^^Mrs. F. C. Youree, of Readyville, a current member of the
Rutherford County Chapter of the Tennessee Archaeological Society,
reports that Zach Patrick was her uncle, and according to family
tradition, the string of beads was found on the Patrick homesite
on Cripple Creek in Rutherford County where many other fine relics
have been unearthed.
^-^Haywood, in his Civil and Political History of the State
of Tennessee , p. 217, 2nd edition, says the trail was worn down
by buffaloes to a depth of one or two feet and to a width of
three or four feet.
30
southeast and easterly direction and exited the county just
southwest of Fosterville. This trail is shown on a map circa
1795, drawn by General Daniel Smith. The trail began at the
Great Salt Lick at Nashville, proceeded southward along the
Harpeth River, then easterly to the head of Wartrace Creek (to
which it gave name) , and then southward to the Tennessee River
in northern Alabama. ^'^
A second trail described by Myer is the "Cisca" or "St.
Augustine Trail" (or the "Nickajack Trail", as it was known by
the whites near Nashville because it led to Nickajack Town on
the Tennessee River). The trail entered Rutherford County from
Davidson County, just west of Smyrna and Lavergne, passing close
by Murfreesboro, and exited the county just north of Beech Grove,
in Coffee County. -^^
The third trail is listed as the "Black Fox Trail." it
began at the Cherokee settlements along the Hiwassee River in
East Tennessee and entered Rutherford County at the approximate
location of the Woodbury-Murfreesboro turnpike, then proceeded
westward to the Black Fox Spring, near Murfreesboro. At the
spring, it split into two trails, one joining the Nickajack Trail
and the other continuing on into Nashville at about the location
of the Murfreesboro-Nashville turnpike. ^6
Rutherford County Archaeological Sites
Certain references are made in the archaeological writings
cited to intriguing mounds, aboriginal breastworks, corrals, etc..
William E. Myer, Indian Trails of the Southeast. Nashville,
p. llfi&#8212; 117 " '
35
1971, pp. 116-117
'Ibid., pp. 112-113.
36ibid. , pp. 103-105.
31
formerly located in Rutherford County and of which no traces
can now be found. To cite an example, where was the location
of the "aboriginal remains" near which Dr. Jones obtained his
"parrot pipe"? Unfortunately, the records of many of our
earliest archaeologists are inexact or even nonexistent, and
more specific locations are not likely ever to be identified.
A map entitled "Aboriginal Map of Tennessee," included in
Goodspeed's History shows only "Black Fox's Camp" within the
confines of Rutherford County. -^^ W. E. Myer's 1923 "Archaeo-logical
Map of Tennessee," however, shows a number of otherwise
unidentified archaeological features in Rutherford County. These
include a burial cave near the mouth of Overall Creek; a burial
cave at the junction of Bradley Creek and the East Fork of Stones
River; a mound on Overall Creek about five miles north of its
mouth; an aboriginal cemetery about three miles south of Florence
on Overall Creek; a mound about two or three miles west of Murfrees-boro,
adjacent to Overall Creek; and "undefined antiquities"
about three miles north of Murfreesboro, on the West Fork of
Stones River. 3 8 While some of these archaeological features may
still be located, others seem to have passed into oblivion.
Another site, possibly a natural geological formation, is
described by Henderson, in his History of Murfreesboro , as follows:
About two miles south of Murfreesboro was located
one of the camping grounds of the Indians, a scope of
land sparsely timbered, but having a luxuriant pasture
of wild grasses. The "corral", as it has been called
from that day, was watered by Lytle Creek. The grounds
37Op . Cit . , map, frontispiece.
^^0&#163;. Cit . , map.
32
were high and rolling and the open space of the corral
was entirely surrounded by heavily timbered lands and
an impenetrable tangle of undergrowth and wild vines.
The Indians could turn out their ponies here to graze,
knowing they could not escape the natural barrier. -^^
This is likely the same spot described in Goodspeed's
History of Tennessee , as follows:
About three miles from Murfreesboro is the old
Bradley racetrack. . . near this old racetrack is the
old Indian dance ground, which is a circular track dug
out of the earth and rock. Neither history nor tradition
tells of its origin. ^&#176;'^-'-
Camp cited only one important site in Rutherford County,
which he identified as a pre-ceramic site on Stewarts Creek,
just west of the old Nashville Highway, near Smyrna. He
described a midden composed of occupational buildup, encompassing
42 an area of about one acre m size.
Powers located Rutherford County sites on Cripple Creek,
Bradley Creek, Overall Creek, Fall Creek, Concord Branch, and
the Harpeth River as well as a number of sites, generally dis-persed,
on all three forks of Stones River. He described an
important site at the confluence of the East and West Forks of
Stones River (now under the waters of Percy Priest Lake) , and
located another site at the juncture of Town Creek and Stones
River at Murfreesboro, now destroyed, where some burials were
uncovered by construction activity.
^^Op. Cit . , p. 9.
^'^The Goodspeed Histories of Maury, Williamson, Rutherford ,
Wilson, Bedford and Marshall Counties of Tennessee (originally
published 1886). reprinted from Goodspeed's History of Tennessee ,
Columbia, 1971, p. 813.
4lThe exact location of this feature, whether man-made or
natural, has not been determined by the writer.
42Leroy Camp, personal interview, April 7, 1974.
33
Powers characterizes most of the Rutherford County sites
as Archaic, with some exceptions. Pottery sherds from the
Woodland period have been found in the southeastern portion of
the county, and a sherd of "Wheeler Plain" pottery (which is
the earliest known regional clay pottery, dating circa 1500 B. C.)
was found near Murfreesboro on Stones River. Mississippian
sites are also located near Murfreesboro on Stones River and
43 on Stewarts Creek near Smyrna.
Notable Rutherford County Artifacts
Once more citing the "parrot pipe" of Dr. Jones as perhaps
the finest Rutherford County artifact known to the writer of
this paper, it is possible to briefly mention other local
discoveries.
A very well-made Clovis or fluted point, about 3 3/4" in
length, is illustrated in Ten Years of the Tennessee Archaeo-logist
, and is described as having been found in the vicinity
of Murfreesboro and from the collection of H. H. Hassler.
This point represents perhaps the first of a number of
Paleo projectile point finds made in the county in recent
years, being in such quantity as to allow Powers to describe
Rutherford County as somewhat of a center of southeastern Paleo
man activity. 4S
^^James R. Powers, personal interview, April 13, 1974.
T. M. N. Lewis and Madeline Kneburg, "Early Projectile
Point Forms, and Examples from Tennessee," Ten Years of the
Tennessee Archaeologist , Chattanooga (n. d.), pp. 128-129.
'^^James R. Powers, personal interview, April 13, 1974.
34
James W. Cambron, in his Handbook of Alabama Archaeology ,
Point Types , assigns an approximate date of 13,000 B. C. for
these points, ^6 which suffices to establish that the earliest
known people ever to have lived in eastern North America were
not strangers to the grazing lands of what is now Rutherford
County and over which prehistoric mammals foraged.
Other local discoveries include a number of fine relics
located on his farm on Cripple Creek by F. Craig Youree and
now reposing in his collection. Richard H. Grabowski , of
Connecticut, made two remarkable finds while stationed at
Stewart Air Force Base at Smyrna during the late 1960 's; the
first, a large, black flint Adena point, 5" in length, and,
the second, a small, light brown sandstone turtle effigy,
about 2J5" in length, and of problematical usage. Both finds
were from the west bank of Stones River, near the air base.
Two youthful Murfreesboroans , Randy and Mike Abernathy,
brothers, located a very well-made ceramic pot, while searching
for fossils, underneath a ledge, in northeastern Rutherford
County. Their find was made in 1972.
Copper beads were recently discovered in a burial near
Smyrna, and the major portion of a large steatite vessel was
the noteworthy find of Steve Maloney, of Murfreesboro , whose
collection of artifacts also includes several Paleo points
from Rutherford County fields.
^^James W. Cambron and David G. Hulse, Handbook of Alabama
Archaeology, Part 1 - Point Types , Archaeological Research
Association of Alabama, 3rd printing, 1969.
35
Other fine, discovered artifacts from Rutherford County,
but unknown to the writer, undoubtedly exist. A number of
local archaeological enthusiasts do have fairly extensive
collections of points and other relics which certainly include
a significant percentage of Rutherford County material; and,
almost surely, some items are possessed as mere chance finds
by farmers, sportsmen, and the general public. Hopefully, more
and more of these Rutherford County relics may be located and
recorded, so as to make the record of the county's prehistory
as complete and accurate as possible.
Local Archaeological Activities
So far as the writer is aware, no major, organized archaeo-logical
excavations have ever been undertaken in Rutherford
County. The county abounds, however, in interested amateurs,
ranging from the relic collector, with his uncomplicated
pursuits, to the serious and knowledgeable activities of other
more scientifically inclined and motivated individuals.
In the early 1960's a group of local archaeological
enthusiasts banded together to organize the Rutherford County
Chapter of the Tennessee Archaeological Society. Leroy Camp,
of Lavergne, was the first chapter president; the late Jordan
Caldwell was named vice-president; and Mrs. Leroy Camp served
as secretary-treasurer. Most of the early meetings were held
at Smyrna.
The chapter charter has been renewed every year since,
and the chapter continues its activities in the current year,
36
with monthly meetings and informational programs. All interested
persons are cordially welcomed to attend functions and to partici-pate
in chapter activities (which have included excavations in
years past, although never in Rutherford County.) Meetings are
now held in Murfreesboro.
In addition to Camp and Powers, both former presidents of
the Tennessee Archaeological Society, the Rutherford County Chapter
has included in its membership the following individuals, who have
made contributions to the local chapter and to archaeology by
reason of tenure, educational pursuit, publication, field work or
service: Mr. and Mrs. Alfred White, Murfreesboro; Mr. and Mrs.
F. Craig Youree, Readyville; John Dowd , Nashville; H. C. Brehm,
Nashville; Steve Maloney, Murfreesboro; Claude King, Murfreesboro;
and Donald Ball, Manchester. The writer of this paper makes modest
pretension to inclusion with this worthy group, on the basis of
longevity.
The present chapter membership numbers 33 persons, among
whom serious interest, dedication and a desire to promote careful
and scientific archaeological activity are common traits.
Thus is concluded this survey of Rutherford County's prehistory,
It is the hope of the writer that this paper may have contributed
in some small measure to the knowledge and understanding of the
historically obscure people who once lived among the fields and
woodlands and near the streams of our county.
37
It is further hoped that this paper may encourage more
persons to be aware of the value of reporting and having recorded
archaeological relics and sites from throughout the county, which
are now rapidly disappearing under the bulldozer's tread and the
subdivider's and road builder's proliferating activities.
And lastly, if this paper has even slightly stirred a new
appreciation for our county's first inhabitants and their some-times
simple and basic life pursuits, and a corollary respect
for their culture and artifacts, then even the common and some-times
scorned "arrowhead" can only become a marvelous relic of a
way of life now thousands of years extinct and scarcely to be
understood or even imagined.
38
THE PREHISTORY OF RUTHERFORD COUNTY
QUOTED SOURCES
Bibliography
Adair, James. History of the American Indians (first published
London, 1775) , reprint of the Samuel Cole Williams edition
of 1930, reprinted by the Blue &amp; Gray Press, Nashville, 1971.
Bassler, R. S. The Stratigraphy of the Central Basin of Tennessee ,
Bulletin 38, Tennessee Division of Geology, Nashville, 1932.
Burt, Jesse and Robert B. Ferguson, Indians of the Southeast;
Then and Now , Abingdon Press, Nashville and New York, 1973.
Cambron, James W. and David C. Hulse, Handbook of Alabama Archaeo-logy,
Part 1 - Point Types , published by the Archaeological
Research Association of Alabama, Inc., 3rd Printing, 1969.
Fundaburk, Emma Lila and Mary Douglass Fundaburk Foreman, Sun
Circles and Human Hands , Luverne, Alabama, 2nd printing,
1965.
History of Tennessee , the Goodspeed Publishing Company, Nashville,
1886.
The Goodspeed Histories of Maury, Williamson, Rutherford, Wilson ,
Bedford, and Marshall Counties of Tennessee (originally
published 1886) reprinted by Woodward &amp; Stinson Printing
Co., Columbia, 1971.
Haywood, John. The Civil and Political History of the State of
Tennessee (first published 1823) , reprinted by the Tenase Co.
,
Knoxville, 1969.
Haywood , John . The Natural and Aboriginal History of Tennessee
(first published 1823), reprinted, Mary U. Rothrock , Editor,
McCowat-Mercer Press, Inc., Jackson, 1959.
Henderson, C. C. The Story of Murfreesboro , The News-Banner
Publishing Co., Murfreesboro, 1929.
Jones, Joseph, M. D. , Explorations of the Aboriginal Remains of
Tennessee (first published by the Smithsonian Institution,
Washington, D. C. , 1876), reprinted by Tenase Explorers,
Knoxville, 1970.
Lewis, T. M. N. and Madeline Kneburg, "Early Projectile Point
Forms, and Examples from Tennessee," Ten Years of the
Tennessee Archaeologist , Chattanooga, (n.d. )
.
39
Lewis, T. M. N. and Madeline Kneburg, Tribes that Slumber ,
University of Tennessee Press, Knoxville, 1958.
McGee, Gentry R. . A History of Tennessee from 1663 to 1930 ,
Facsimile reproduction, Charles Elder, Publisher, Nashville,
1971.
McGaw, Robert. "Tennessee Antiquities Re-Exhumed," Tennessee
Historical Quarterly , Summer, 1965.
Myer, William E. Indian Trails of the Southeast (first published
in the 4 2nd Annual Report of the Bureau of American Ethnology ,
1928), reprinted by the Blue &amp; Gray Press, Nashville, 1971.
Putnam, A. W. History of Middle Tennessee , or, Life and Times of
Gen. James Robertson (first published 1859) , reprinted by
the University of Tennessee Press, Knoxville, 1971.
Sims, Carlton C, Editor, A History of Rutherford County , 1947.
Thruston, Gates P. The Antiquities of Tennessee and the Adjacent
States, (first published 1890) , reprint of the 2nd (1897)
Edition, by Tenase Explorers, Knoxville, 1964.
White, Robert H. Tennessee: Its Growth and Progress , published
by Robert H. White, Nashville, 1936.
PERSONAL INTERVIEWS
Leroy Camp, Levergne, Tennessee, April 7, 1974.
James R. Powers, Murfreesboro, Tennessee, April 13, 1974,</dc:description>
<dc:description>Explores the prehistory of Rutherford County using archaeology, anthropology, and geography</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.) -- History; Rutherford County (Tenn.); Tennessee, Middle</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>archaeology: anthropology; geography; land formations; prehistory; Native Americans</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>49 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-16</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication03ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/149</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>