<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Union: Murfreesboro's other university</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Pittard, Homer</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 1</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1973</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>19th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>UNION: MURFREESBORO' S OTHER UNIVERSITY
By Dr. Homer Pittard
The Baptists generated a grand plan at their meeting
in Nashville, Tennessee on October 13, 1839. By resolution
it was decided that a denominational university was needed
for educating young ministers for the gospel. Not only was
a university essential but, in addition, were several
smaller institutions to "feed" the mother school. It was
envisioned that the mother campus would serve as a nucleus,
or in the nature of a hub, with the sub-schools positioned
in a circumference for comfortable and convenient commuting.
Although the plan was sparse in details, there was some
evidence that the smaller schools would operate at the high
school level with the possible addition later of two years
of college. The larger campus would offer four years of
collegiate study. The prospective minister had his choice
of entering at the lower levels and then advancing at his
own pace to the "seminary" level.
Minutes of this historic meeting record that the plan
was enthusiastically received. Many of those whose voices
were loudest in praise of the magnificent scheme probably
occupied the impoverished pulpits of the Tenneseee and the
Alabama hinterlands--but this was religious business and
"the Lord would provide."
29
since auch an educational plan would bring together
many diverse elements in Baptist faith and would thereby
unify the Tennessee and Alabama denominations, it was
decided that the then unborn principal institution should
bear the name, "Union University."
To administer the sterner aspects of Union, that of
fund raising, B. F. Farnsworth, former president of George-town
College in Kentucky was employed to initiate and com-plete
a gifts campaign. Farnsworth reasoned that prospec-tive
donors would be more receptive to solicitation if the
institution, still on paper, had a charter. Therefore,
during the next three years, his principal energies were
devoted to preaching from many pulpits and to the details
of organization as he put it, and to writing and petitioning.
In 1842, the elusive charter was captured and granted.
Thereby, Farnsworth had possibly made his only contribution
to Union. There were scarcely any funds, pledged or cash
in tiand, to the credit of the school.
Nevertheless, anticipating great things from Brother
Farnsworth, optimistic Baptists, and other S3mpathetic
bodies, the Baptist hierarchy, in early 1840, opened a
school in Somerville, Tennessee. Although it proudly bore
the aegis of "Union University," it offered study only at
the primary level and was poorly financed and patronized.
Seeking a more central and receptive location. Union
moved to Murfreesboro and opened on May 2, 1841. Its
quarters were the grubby old Bradley Academy building. Hie
Bradley trustees had long since abandoned the two- story
log structure to homeless religious sects in the community
and to diverse groups that needed an assembly hall. The
structure, gaunt and unprepossessing, rested on a slight
eminence near the southeast limits of the town. However,
it had had its moment of glory, at least a moderate after-glow
from former years. James Knox Polk had attended the
institution twenty-seven years before as a young man and
biad later married Sarah Childress, one of the town's
several eligible and attractive belles. Polk had served
one term as governor of the state but near the moment that
Union moved into Murfreesboro, he had lost his bid for a
second term. The memory of the Bradley years, however,
assumed added if not renewed significance when, four years
later, Polk became the eleventh President of the United
Sta te s
.
Itie glories of the past campus did little to diminish
the grimneaa of the task ahead for the Baptists as they
took their first steps to implement the 1839 plan.
The diminutive faculty corps could hardly bear the
burden of the name "university" but, nevertheless, Union
opened with the traditionally heavy classical curriculum
and began advertising for students. Joseph Haywood Eaton
was appointed the president and professor of Latin. The
specialist in Greek was D. G. Snith. This constituted the
full faculty with the exception of William Williams who
UNION UNIVERSITY
Appeared in The Tennessee Register (18721 as part of an advertisement.
JOSEPH HAYWOOD EATON
First President of Union University
JAMES MADISON PENDLETON
Controversial President of Union
University just prior to the
War Between the States
was listed as a tutor. A spate of additional courses was
taught by these men who doubled as janitors and repairmen.
"Hie President (a pretentious title for a most unpre-tentious
venture) was a remarkable man. Born in Berlin,
Ohio on September 12, 1812, he was educated at Georgetown
College in Kentucky and at Hamilton Academy near Columbus,
Ohio. From 1837 until his emergence on the scene in
Murf reesboro, he was a journeyman teacher with schools in
Nashville and in Fayetteville, Tennessee. In 1843, he
became the first pastor of the fledgling First Baptist
Church in Murfreesboro as well as that of continuing his
presidency of Union. Both institutions were horribly
impecunious. Each operated on a salary schedule of a sort
but payments were rarely in the stipulated amount which,
if paid, usually were in arrears. This situation apparently
did not deter Eaton in his dedication to his two awesome
challenges. He occupied his own pulpit and supplied many
others. He made long, arduous safaris, by houseback, into
the hinterlands in search of students and financial support.
His energy was unlimited for a time at least until the two
flames at each end of his life candle burned closer
together.
Unwary students who happened to wander onto the campus
during the infant years, found lodging in the town. Tuition
was listed in three categories based on coats for each of
two sessions: preparatory classes - $18, academic - $22
and collegiate classes - $26. Matriculation was $2 per
session. Generous trustees established the policy of
granting ministerial students free tuition.
The educator-preacher, from his citadel of learning
near the town limits, was forever alert. In the November
Itennessee Baptist of 1844, he made this appeal: "There
have been two young men here within a week past to enter
the institution who have the ministry in view, but they are
poor in this world's goods, and they have been obliged to
return home again. One of them resides in north Alabama
and the other in Wilson County. There are now two here
and two more desire to come, making six. What shall be
done? The brethren have concluded to rent a house, fix
it up and put them in it. Will the brethren in Nashville
aaaiat? This church (Murfreesboro' s First Baptist) is
willing to furnish all of the e stables, if the other
churches will pay the rent and the servants here. It will
not only be a shame but a sin if the churches refuse to aid
these young men who are panting to proclaim the unsearchable
riches of Christ to a perishing world--we leave this with
you and your final judge."
Itie ardent petition for the "panting" young men in
educational distress struck a responsive chord for on
February 11, 1845, William H. Barksdale, a Nashville friend
of Eaton, wrote this soaring panegyric in the Tennessee
Baptist : "Need I say that it would be utterly vain were
I to attempt to express the grateful, the glowing, the soul-cheering
emotions which dwell within our hearts, when we
3U
contemplate the kindness and liberality of our endeared
brethren; for where can we find language to express that
which is inutterable? Vfe can only adapt the words of
Samuel: 'Hitherto hath the T.ord helped us'."
In June it was reported that Andrew Jackson "had been
laid in the narrow house in the Hermitage garden where he
will rest until the sound of the last trumpet." The
trumpet for the Baptists, however, sounded loud and clear
that June month. Bradley Kimbrough was employed to promote
the cause of Union University by launching a gifts campaign.
B. F. Famsworth, the previous promoter-, who had labored
with marked deliberation in the vineyard, had now returned
to Kentucky. Kimbrough, in addition to his travels among
the denominations, bombarded the Tennessee Baptist with
urgent pleas. In November, he placed the issue squarely
on the line: "Can we do anything without proper schools?
And can we have schools v/ithout expense? Brethren, friends,
V7e nray you, think of this matter, pray over it, be united
throughout the state, and when you are called upon, be
ready to act with a liberality worthy of the great interest
involved." Kimbrough devised a pledge system whereby
payments could he made in four installments. His goal was
$50,000 in endowment. He reported that Murfreesboro would
provide $10,000 for the erection of a building. In a
letter to the Tennessee Baptist late in 1845, he wrote:
"Not one sister has refused to subscribe." Truly there
were many pledges, some of a generous nature. The problem
apparently was not the subscribing of the sisters&#8212;and the
brethren--but collection of the pledges. Kimbrough had
aroused the Baptists to new heights and had served one noble
purpose, if no other: Alabama and Tennessee Baptists were
at last aware of the existence of the little school in
Murfreesboro.
Meanwhile, President Eaton was expending his frenetic
energy in keeping alive the educational institution as well
as the Baptist church. In addition, he was siring a large
family, moat of whom did not survive infancy. Esther, his
wife, a granddaughter of Ihomas Treadwell, a signer of the
Declaration of Independence, was equally remarkable as her
husband. During the intervals when she was not delivering
children or mourning the loss of one, she was busy with a
school of her own. Utilizing the Fletcher schoolhouse where
the Murfreesboro Baptists conducted services, she organized
a small faculty and offered courses of study at the upper
elementary and high school levels. Later she was instru-mental
in establishing an institution of collegiate rank
in a new building near the northern town limits on land
purchased by the Baptists from the Oakland s estate. First
designated in 1853 as the Baptist Female Institute, it was
renamed Eaton College in 1859. This highly talented woman
also found time to launch a monthly magazine. The Aurora .
Published at the Murfreesboro Telegraph , it was designed as
a "Monthly magazine for the Mothers and Daughters of the
36
South and Vfeat." It waa a kind of an early Ladies Home
Journal . Sample articles were: "Be Just to Your Stomach;"
"Restored Affections;" and "letters to Young Wives."
Subscription was $2.00 per year. Devoted spouse Esther was
ideally suited for her perambulatory educator-preacher-husband.
It was a magnificent instrumentation that she
reflected in holding home and fireside together, bearing
and rearing children, writing copiously, and nurturing an
evolving educational institution of her own.
With the assurance of $10,000 from the City of Murfrees-boro
and the treasury some richer from a few scattered
pledges in various stages of payment, the Baptists decided
to proceed with the erection of a permanent home for the
University. The trustees at the time were William Martin,
Robert Boyd, R. B. C. Howell, J. H. Marshall, C. G. Trabue,
J. H. Shepard, D. W. Dickinson, Burrell Gannaway, Howard
Maney, J. J. Whi taker, W. W. Searcy, B. F. Norfleet,
Lawrence Reneau, Charles Watkins, and Lee Abernathy. This
official body announced in January of 1848 that the insti-tution
was "chartered, officered, and ready to begin." An
eighteen -acre campus located on the Vfoodbury Pike, just
east of the town limits, had been purchased from Matthias
Murfree. Sale price waa $2,121.25. It was described as
"beginning at a stake in the center of the stage road
leading from Murfreesboro to McMinnville. " On April 9, 18W,
the trustees "voted to invite the Masons, the Oddfellows,
and the Sons of Temperance to assist in laying the cornerstone.
37
Construction proceeded slowly in a pattern proportionate
to the reception of pledge payments. There were resurgent
periods when President Eaton returned from reasonably
successful financial forays into the denomination's hinter-lands.
Early in 1850, it was announced that the building
was partially "closed in." By Christmas of 1851, construction
had progressed to the point to allow occupancy. Union's
permanent home was 80 feet by 110 feet. Its three stories
of gray brick were decorated by six wooden half columns at
its front. Placement of the columns began at the second
story. The two recessed wings continued the columned motif
with two each. The structure was capped by a hip roof. A
small yard was enclosed by a board fence and two privies
were hidden from each other at the east and west ends of
the building. These two stations were partially and taste-fully
obscurred from the turnpike by cedars planted by the
woricmen. To the north was a small hitchbam for use by
students who commuted from their homes in the country.
In early January, President Eaton led the one hundred
students along with his faculty, now mushroomed to three,
to their new home.
Once ensconced in its new home, the University began
to attract a large clientile. By 1855, enrollment had
climbed to nearly three hundred. At the time, the faculty
advertised J. H. Eaton as the teaching President along with
faculty members David Bridenthall, 3. R. Vfestbrooks, T. W.
Woodson, and G. W. Jarman. The curriculum was generally
implicit in the faculty choices of textbooks which included
Ray's Algebra , Dillaway's Cicero , Anthon's Horace , Kendrick'a
Greek, Bullion's Caesar , Cooper's Vergil , Daviea' Surveying
and Analytical Geometry , Mitchell's Geography , Vfeld's
English Grammar , and Fowler's Mental Arithmetic . University
faculty minutes nor promotional materials made any direct
references to works of theology. It can be assumed that
these basic course areas provided, in the vernacular of
twentieth century pedagogy, the "general education" founda-tion
for both the minis teral student and the disinclined.
Doubtless, all of the emotional and academic trappings of a
true seminary were found at Union.
An unnamed and unheralded writer, probably a member
of the faculty or Eaton himself, made this promotional
assessment of the institution: "It is situated in the midst
of rural scenery, calculated to inspire the young with the
love of nature; sufficiently retired to invite study and
reflection and unsurpassed in regard to health by any
section of the Union, why may we not invite hither those
who are in search of knowledge?" To assure that the "search"
would be beneficient, the faculty adopted the policy that no
student could enter any class without first being subjected
to a rigid examination.
Comfortably situated in a new building, delighted by
increasing enrollments, and undergirded with what appeared
to be a sound academic policy. Union to the casual observer
and to the ardent Baptists, was the emerging institution that
had been anticipated.
But, the bright academic horizon had its detracting
clouds. On April 9, 1855, the faculty requested President
Eaton to inform the Board of Trustees that "the payment of
salaries is needed." Requests of the nature became a
recurrent plaintive plea in successive faculty minutes.
Eaton, likewise, suffered from the casual salary program
of the trustees. What little financial security he had came
from sporadic payments from the governing body since he
bad separated himself from the Baptist Church in 1849.
Therefore, it was not a minor miracle that enabled him in
1856 to construct a president's home on the east campus.
A two-story brick, it was financed principally from his
limited funds, those his wife Esther siphoned from her
returns from the Aurora , and from a few cash gifts made by
sympathetic Baptists in the area.
In addition to financial problems, the students played
their role in partially obscurring the bright theological
atmosphere to the east of Murfreesboro . During the spring
of 18 55, a Union student was killed in a drunken brawl on
the public square. In the fall of the same year, a University
disciplinary pledge: "We promise during our connection with
Union University to obey the rules and regulations" and a
forthright enforcement of this, led to a student strike.
During the period of the incident, Union boys milled around
the public square thereby causing considerable problems for
the merchants and, in particular, the saloonkeepers. On
July U, 1857, an altercation near a cobbler's home resulted
in the death of one student and the wounding of another.
David Thompson, in a violent disagreement over a shoe
repair bill, was shot to death by John Fly, the cobbler's
son. Another student, standing nearby, was critically
wounded when young Fly began to fire indiscriminately.
Aside from the catalog, the principal publication of
the University during its relatively brief life was Itie
Classic Union . Issued semi-monthly, it averaged twenty-eight
to thirty-two pages per issue. It was printed at
the offices of the Rutherford Telegraph located at the
southeast comer of the square. Matthew Hillsman, a faculty
member, served as the editor during the publication's
two-year existence. Contributions from faculty members and
students consisted principally of Baptist doctrinal articles,
general interest stories, poems or, as it was expressed in
its masthead: "Devoted to Religion, Literature, and General
Intelligence." In commenting on a local event. The Classic
Union editorialized the coming of the railroad: "The rail-road
has been completed to this place and we hail the event
as one highly auspicious to the commercial interests of our
town--and yet there is one deep shade upon the otherwise
bright picture of prosperity which the achievement of the
work pre sent 3- -blowing of a train whistle on the Sabbath."
The Union continued in a similar vein one issue later:
"Vfe deeply and sincerely regret that the management of the
affairs of the company has been entrusted to the hands of
those who fear not God nor His Holy day." And another:
"Are not the men who are engaged in running the railroad
cars for pleasure trips on the Sabbath either Catholic or
under Catholic influence?" Successive issues of the maga-zine
carried no further references to the unholy whistle
thereby leaving the answer in limbo as to whether the
engineers had muted their Sabbath rousers or that Editor
Hillsman had ceremonially washed his hands of the affair.
An awesome tragedy struck the campus on January 12,
1859. President Eaton died. Only forty-seven, his cause
of death was attributed principally to exhaustion and exposure
aggravated by long and difficult hours expended in main-taining
some resemblance of solvency in the institution.
His full commitment to Union carried him in search of funds
and students to the rough hinterlands of Middle Tennessee
and North Alabama. Frequently, he travelled by horseback
and was thereby exposed to all of the hazards of inclement
weather and rigors of extended hours in the saddle. Eaton
had literally worked himself to death for Union. Probably
in truth, whatever success had been achieved by the bright
new theology school and whatever future the institution
might have, lay in the casket at the president's home on the
east campus.
Possibly the funeral and attending obsequies, a magni-ficent
tribute to Eaton, were the most resplendent in the
histary of Murfreesboro. After lying in state for two days,
the remains of the departed president were placed in the
horse-drawn hearse which then moved to the turnpike and west
toward Murfree aboro. On foot inimediately to the rear were
faculty members who served a a pallbearers. These were
followed by the family and relatives in carriages, the
University trustees on foot, the University students, the
members of the Preparatory Department, and citizens of the
town. As the long cortege entered the town limits, there
still remained many of the citizens who had not fallen into
line. The procession turned left at Spring Street, one
block from the public square, and moved south two blocks
to the Baptist Church at the comer of Sevier Street.
After a soaring funeral sermon by James Madison Pendleton,
a Union faculty member, the remains were conveyed to the
City Cemetery for temporary interment. Two days later,
the University students, faculty, and many citizens, still
full of the tragic grandeur of the moment, launched a
campaign to erect an imposing tomb on the University campua.
The funds were collected in a few days and arrangements
were made for the construction of the tomb. By June 15 it
was completed. It was "reared in the shadow of the Uni-versity,"
lying some twelve feet to the southeast of the
building. Constructed of native limestone, it contained
two compartments, one for the President's remains, and the
other reserved for his wife, Esther. Mounted atop the front
of the tomb was a three -foot stone figure flanked by two
urns. One June 16, the black hearse, accompanied by Uni-versity
students as an honor guard, made its second visit
to Eaton's grave. The body was disinterred, placed in the
hearse again, and with much ceremony, the procession moved
back to the campus. While the students formed a wide
cordon around the new tomb, the undertaker slid the coffin
into its new compartment. A flat rectangular slab,
previously inscribed, was placed over the opening and
sealed. The inscription was a genealogical epitaph with
the words
:
Sept. 10, 1812 Jan. 12, 1859
JOSEPH H. EATON LLD
"Know Ye Not That There is A
Prince and Great Man Fallen This
Day in Israel"
He was the Son of Joseph Eaton
Who was the Son of David Eaton
Who was the Son of John Eaton
Who was the Son of Joseph Eaton
Who was the Son of John Eaton
Who Emigrated from WSales
A.D. 1686.
After the obsequies and the resolutions had run their
course; after the inevitable campaign to endow a chair in
memory of President Eaton had proved somewhat futile; and
after the Female Institute had been renamed Eaton College,
a more mundane problem presented itself. The moment came
to settle Eaton's estate. This appeared to be a very
simple matter since Eaton tiad no visible estate. However,
the University was delinquent in salaries to the late
President in the amount of at least $5,000. Since no
funds were available, Esther Eaton was given a lien on
the University property. Shortly thereafter, H. G. Scovell,
prominent Nashville druggist and University benefactor,
assumed the lien by payment of the $5,000 to Mrs. Eaton.
Scovell then transferred his interests with an additional
PRESIDENT EATON'S HOME
Subsequently used as a residence, as housing for Linebaugh Public
Library, and as classrooms for retarded children.
EATON TOMB
Constructed on the Union University Campus in
1859, it was removed to Evergreen Cemetery in
1907.
DK\OTIJ&gt; TO HfLKiH
" MI'RKRKKSlK)m&gt;ri;iI. AIIjIST 1
of lb* pofr and 4r&#171;tiii
people
I
Kor &#171;&#171; atl lno&#171; that .1 &#187; f
, wLcfi ngb( bMiM xhool txNun &#187;nd
&gt;i&#171; ^ai dim MbooU iban it ii lo &#8226;nf^port
&#8226;nd Suu pnvn&#171; f
goi6 It bvi droM &#171;b&gt;n n
&#8226;hi^h ,
tb.B) &#171;ILh
1 lU po&#171;c
&#8226;&#8226;Ij lafc uiUlli^ni Bia lu M
&#8226;&#8226;d ;&#171;t fn&gt;p&#187; is ite
|ib&#171;bwlor7o{ Um pm4 wd (b
CLASSIC UNION
Faculty-Student Publication at the University.
luu iho vltiBkl* ap- 1 Ihr i^rral worth &#171;/ bnowMg* and
I b&#187; MMi&#171; on ail of U&#187;&#171;r urral aad tn- , tVful kDo&#171;ln]|(r. diSuM
Ml ifMaUoa* &gt;hicb &#171;lll at ltov&lt;-&#171; &lt;&#8226; of p^ptc. ii o&#171;r m
tftndaftrtlbc *tul iBUiT*(a of Khc ^crd, and ibc oaU drfi i
aa Iliaib&#171;Bol Um sIboM t&#171;por- &#8226;&#171; a fM&#171;t&#171;&#171;&#187;&#171;ir o/ CT&#187;r Ubrrur* Lri &#8226;*' ^
&#8226; tbat mM(d kftovM^ b* dtfcard frMroJ adoeatMO be *&lt;lbb&#171;td trtm ibaldarhi
M^ all elMan of people.
|
p&#187;opW&#8212;Wi Um nrfas |&#187;Mnlk&#171; fro&#187; ^1 ^f b
ll&lt;- cti.lJrr&#171; of lh&#171;
lid not onlj hf the aaaw eemne of n'ai
it would b&#171; &#171;hwlv pvopte abovld be
r unr mooff. Ifw ar&gt;fuacnt raa nrt&gt;
r tliripcr lu *n.&#187;U frvfn ijfnonnK i&#171;t
ii'Uin )fDoJ &lt;'*( iB(li&#171;idw&#171;l &#171;h&lt;ac luwv nui^ b&#171; bt
&gt;i ttltt all. ai
nparvd &#187;iih &lt;ri&gt;&#171; and rifUir ao li^nonitl pmpW.
BAPTIST FEMALE INSTITUTE
Renamed Eaton College in 1859, it later housed the
Normal and Scobey's School, and still later it was a
residence before its razing in 1965.
$5,000 to the Baptist Educational Society. Under the
presidency of James Madison Pendleton, the University
continued its operation, spasmodically, until the outbreak
of the Civil War.
Pendelton, a controversial figure in religious dogma,
came to Murfreesboro from Hopkinsville, Kentucky on
January 31, 1857. He ascended the pulpit of the First
Baptist Church and doubled as a professor of theology at
Union University. Religiously, he espoused the cause of
the somewhat obscure principle of Landmarkism, a rigid
theological interpretation that focused principally on
authorized baptism and vigorously opposed the principle of
infant baptism. The reaction of townspeople and the Uni-versity
to this position was minimal. However, Pendelton'
s
stand on slavery quickly drew fire from the town and it
was darkly hinted that the president- preacher would soon
be the principal in a lynching party. Curiously, Pendleton
styled himself as an emancipationist rather than an aboli-tionist.
Yet, the housekeeper for the Pendleton house was
a Negro girl, a bequest from the will of his father.
According to Pendleton, his father on his deathbed had
elicited the promise from his son to care for the girl
"during her natural life."
Sometime in January, 1861, the University closed its
doors. Gathering war clouds had drawn most of the young
men to the training camps. During the next four years,
the University building was used alternately as a hospital
by Blue and Gray troops. Several students were casualties
of the war. A partial list of Confederate dead included
William A. Arnold, Henry P. Halbert, Francis W. Middleton,
Jesse Sparks, and John M. Pendleton. The latter was the son
of the University president and this family schism ending
in a battlefield casualty brought Pendleton many hours of
anguish. Late in 1861, the president made a hurried exit
from Murfreesboro just an hour or so before a mob gathered
at his home near Oakland s. His family followed later and
he remained as a exile in Hamilton, Ohio during the remainder
of the war.
During the four years of conflict, the University
building was horribly vandalized by occupying soldiers.
General Lovell Rousseau, commander of the garrison, issued
at least one order late in the occupation that prohibited
the destruction of the property but the damage had already
run its course. All of the equipment had been destroyed and
books had been crated and sent north. In addition, most of
windows, doors, and much of the woodwork were converted to
firewood.
For some three years following Appomattox, the building
stood bleak and unoccupied in the rubble left by the soldiers.
In 1869, after some minimum repairs to the roof and the
replacement of most of the windows and doors, classes were
resumed. During the five years of spasmodic operation,
D. F. Self, George Jarman, and Charles Manley tried brief
stints as president. The first postwar commencement class
in the spring of 1870 consisted of two members.
Uien the Itennessee Baptist Convention met for organi-zation
in Murfreesboro in April 10, 1874, there was a ray
of hope that Union would be regenerated. The local citizens
petitioned the visitors to resume its support of the insti-tution
in order that it might regain and continue its
antebellum preeminence. However, the arguments against
such action by the Baptist were ominous.
The enrollment had been reduced to a trickle; there
remained locally a residue of the cholera scare; the country
was in financial straits; and free school leaders were
mounting their pressures. A highly important argument,
according to the Baptist hierarchy, was the need for a more
central location to serve the Baptist involved and a site
in Wfest Tennessee appeared to be the most logical. Conse-quently,
on October 1, 1875, the University doors were
closed and the base of operations was moved to Jackson,
Tennessee.
During the next five years, the old building housed
in sequence an academy of sorts and a military school.
By 1880, its delapidated condition made it unsafe for
occupancy and it was abandoned. Until the coming of
Tennessee College for Wbmen in 1907, it was the habitat
of youthful vandals and the other hazards that are plights
of unoccupied buildings.
For twenty- seven years, the building languished in
the midst of sedgebrush, weeds, and briars. In 1886, Esther
Eaton died in Louisville at the home of her son, Thomas
Treadwell. Her remains were brought to Murfreesboro and
interred in the tomb by the side of her husband. When
Tennessee College was established on the old Union site in
1907, the tomb was moved to Evergreen Cemetery.
The trustees of Union University were predominantly
Rutherford County citizens. In 1875, they were vehemently
opposed to the closing of the institution and its subse-quent
reestabliahment in Jackson, Tennessee. Consequently,
the old Union site remained in the hands of the majority
trustees. In 1915, the federal government finally acted
on a claim for damages suffered by Union during the Civil
War period. Payment of the settlement in the amount of
$15,000 was made to the Murfreesboro trustees. Subsequently,
this sum was transferred to Tennessee College.
</dc:description>
<dc:description>A history of Union University while it was located in Murfreesboro before and during the Civil War</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Murfreesboro (Tenn.); Murfreesboro (Tenn.) -- History; Union University (Jackson, Tenn.); United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Baptist church; Higher education</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>41 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-16</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication01ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/74</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>