<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>The story of Fosterville</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Brothers, Elvira</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 16</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1981</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>18th century; 19th century; 20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>THE STORY OF F03TER7ILLE
by
Elvira Brothers
This is the story of the small corauunity, Fosterville, in Ruther-ford
County, Tennessee.
Using the historical approach the writer went back Into the history
of the consminity to discover how it started and some of the developments
down to the present day. Being a resident and former teacher of this
little village she has had a good opportunity to know the people and
their problems and their way of life. She has drawn upon the knowledge
she has gained from her father and older members of the ccsranunity in
writing this story. After mudi reading and research it is found that
there is not much written history on a small conmunity, but when time
permits a further study is to be made.
Fosterville, the locale of this coiiBTiunity study is located in the
extreme Southern part of Rutherford County, Tennessee, on the Nashville,
Chattanooga and St. Louis Railway. It is near the Bedford Comty line.
It is one mile off the Murfreesboro and Shelbyville Highway which is
Highway 231. The Fosterville road Joins the highway Just about half way
between Murfreesboro and Shelbyville which makes both towns approximately
thirteen miles away.
A small historical village located at the foot of a beautiful row
of high hills on the eastj the largest of which is "Old Soap Stone,"
getting the name from the kind of rock formation found &lt;&#171; it. Young
people for generations have enjoyed climbing to the top of this high hill
and viewing the surrounding coimtry. On clear days one can see the smoke-stacks
of Murfreesboro. It is always interesting to look over into the
U3
beautiful valle^r' below and vatch the trains coming around the curve at
Christiana and on through Fostervillej and then around the curve and out
of sight toward Bell Buckle.
On descending the hlU it is such a wonderful thing to quench one's
thirst at the foot of the hlU at "Aunt Mat's Spring" which flows out from
under the bluff, on the side of the hill. The spring got its name from
Mrs. Harb Gllroore. The QHmore's were early settlers and lived near this
spring and were lovingly called by everyone, "lAicle Ikrb and Aunt Mat."
"Aunt Mat's %&gt;ring" has been, through the years, a place of gathering for
young and old; picnics, fish fries, Easter egg hunts, wiener roasts and
other amusements.
The water from "Aunt Mat's Spring" joins what is known as Bally'
s
Branch to form Dry Fork Creek which is the headwaters of the West branch
of Stone's River.
According to Ooodspeed, previous to 1780 the Indians held undisputed
sway in this territory. Traces of the old trace leading from Nashville to
Chattanooga can still be seen.
No one knows the date vhea "Old Fostervllle" was first settled but
the name Fostervllle was given it in honor of a man named Foster, believed
to be John Foster, listed 1820 census in this district, he no doubt being
the first one to establish a home as well as a "Trading Post," on the trail
that leads south from Murfreesborough, now spelled Murfreesboro; to Shelby-ville,
being located about halfway between these settlements.
As civilization advanced and people traveled more, the stage coach
came into use, there were as yet no hard surfaced roads and travel was slow
along this trail through the wilderness from settlement to settlement, but
what few people were in this area would gather at Fostervllle when the
1. Originally known as Jordan's Valley. See old map.
Uh
stage coach was due to arrive, to get news from friends and klnfolks
of other points.
There is no record available as to wbat became of Poster, however,
it Is believed that he sold to a young man named Thomas Edwards and moved
south.
!niis Thomas Edwards being joung and a man of vision was to ray mind
the most outstanding man in the history of Fosterville. Being a trader
as well as a merchant he saw the need of all settlers in regard to news,
80 he asked the Government to grant Post Office service at his store.
He was appointed poatmaster, he also operated a wagon train service to
the South, hauling meat and lard etc., and returning with a load of sugar
and all kinds of cot ten goods.
"The first turnpike in Rutherford County was the Nashville, Murfrees-boro
and ShelbyvlUe Pike. The charter was granted I83I. The road was
conpleted and gates erected and ready for business in l8Ii2."
"The toll gates were placed every five miles to which a fee was paid
for travel. By now stage coach travel was dally both ways, as well as daily
mail . . .Rutherford was ona of the last counties in the U. S, to dis-continue
the use of toll gates. The only evidence Is an occasional house
2
still standing by the side of the road."
"Prior to the Civil V7ar a number of prosperous towns and communities
sprang up in the county. The Tennessee Gazette of I83U lists the towns of
3
Murfreesboro, Jefferson, Readyvllle, Milton and Fostervilla."-^
"Fosterville was authorized by the legislature to incorporate iii I832,
In 1838 a group of enterprising citizens including Thomas Edwards and others
1. Qoodspeed, History of Tennessee, Qoodspeed Publishing Co.,
1886, p. 816.
2. Ibid ., p. 56.
3. Carlton C. Sims, History of Rutherford Coun^, p. 39.
'U5
received a charter for the eatablishment of the Fosterville Steam Mill
Co. This part of the county had no water power sites and turned to steam.
FosteinrLlle, however, failed to maintain a substantial growth and remained
a village.
2
Mr. Edwards married Miss Martha Vaughn. T^e ceremony being said
by Esq. J. D. OiLnore. Ten children were bom to this co\4&gt;le, five boys
and five girls.
Through his ability as a biisiness man and merchant, he acquired
numerous acres of real estate, most of it by homestead rights of the U. S,
Government, some by trading, "all a total of about 2liOO acres. He also
owned a number of slaves.
In 1851 the Nashville, Chattanooga and St. Louis Railway was com-pleted.
The new railroad touched the east border of Mr. Edward's property
and having the guarantee of the con^jany he saw better possibilities in
sight near the Railroads, so he set about to move his home to the new
location.
With consent from the Government he moved the Post Office and store
to the site where Fosterville now stands, still acting as Postmaster,
Station Master for Railroad and express agent for the Express Company.
Moving his residence from the old location to the place overlooking
the railroad was done by an efficient carpenter and the slave labor, moving
the sills and floors intact by means of ox carts. The material in this home
is of the best red cedar selected and sawed out on this plantation by the
mill he owned and operated mostly by slaves. After more than a hvindred
years have elapsed, this home is in good condition; it being the only land-mark
to greet you of days gene by, and to remind you of its master (Mass
1. Sims, Ibid . , p. UO.
2. Most of this information of the Edwards was siqjplied by T. D,
Gilmore, grandson of Thomas Edwards.
1^6
Tom). It Is known today aa the Edd Brothers home.
In i860 the war between the states&#8212;^FostervlUe recalls many
thoughts of those days of Thomas Edwards&#8212; hj.3 sons in the Southern army,
his lands invaded by the Union soldiers, often taking his horses and mules
and wagons to satisfy their own desires. General Rosecrans demanded that
he have quarters in the house so he and his wife occi;^ied the front room
on the left as one enters the front door.
When the war was over there was little left of any value in the way
of farm animals and tools; Mr. Edwards viewed the situation with care and
set about to free his slaves, giving them what he coiild to start them out on
their own, Mose and Sylvia refused to go; so did Uncle Pannell who was
rather old and faithful. He kept these three, set up Mose and Sylvia in a
house all their own, and Uncle Pannell lived in the slave house in the
Northwest corner of the yard, and served as yard man and gardner for the
remainder of his life, always humble and obedient.
Thomas Edwards was a very gentle, quiet person, a mason of high rank,
a Presbyterian by faith and helped to build the first church in the village.
It was a union church and was located a few feet from the present locaticxi
of the Church of Christ.
In March, I89O a violent cyclone blew away the heart of the village
&#8212;
the stores, post office, depot, Presbyterian church, the mill and other
dwellings. The village never fully recovered from that storm, A few days
later Mr. Edwards suffered in a fall, a broken hip and in August he died of
the effects of this injury. Thus ended, the life of a man who meant so
much to the history of Fosterville.
1. Home of the writer's family,
2, Accoixiing to tradition
U7
Very little information is given of the early schools at Poaterville,
however the first achool known to be built was on tiie hi^way at Old
Fosterville. It was a one room log house with puncheon floors. This was
referred to as "Seed Tick School" because it was built in the woods.
Two old teachers were recalled. Miss Rucker Harris and Miss Molly Hale.
Also a one armed teacher. Miss Betty Webb. What is left of this old
building was later used as a com crib.
There was a graded school prior to 1886 because Ooodspeed says, "The
public schools were put into effect soon after the war. The average salary
for teachers for 188$ was $25 per month. The average length of term for
2
the year being fotir months.
The Fosterville Educational Institute was chartered in I883,
Another teacher referred to by William Robert Moore, was a man by
the name of Roberts.
Mr. Moore is among Rutherford county's contribution of statesmen to the
state and nation since the Civil War. Hs was bom in Huntsville,
Alabama, March 28, I83O. His father died when he was 6 months old. His
mother moved to Beech Qrove, Tennessee and when he was six years old his
mother married John Mills Watkins and went to live at Fosterville. There
he attended the coitmon schools of the county for about ten years. He was
elected to the Forty-Seventh Congress on the Republican ticket serving from
1881 to 1883. In 1890 he declined the nomination for Governor of the
6
State. He died in Memphis June 12, 1909.
1^ According to an older citizen, Mr. Edd Edwards.
2. Goodspeed, loc. cit., p. 8$$,
3. Carlton C. Sims, History of Rutherford County, p. 159.
U&#187; The poem by W. R. Moore elsewhere in this study.
5, William Robert Moore, Odds and Ends of Poems , p. U5.
6. Sims, 22. cit ., p. 76.
U8
The following poem u&amp;s coplad from his book, "Odde and Ends of
Poems," in which he tells of his school days at FosterviUe.
RETROSPECT, INTROSPECT, PROSPECT
Standing on expectation's Mount today.
And looking back through life's long devious way,
A thousand treasured Memories o'er us rush
And thrill us with a deep oppressive hush.
We seem to see, with retrospective eye.
An artless boy, whose hopes e'en than beat high.
As through the cedar glades he trudged to school
With stern resolve to shun the Dunce's Stool
That Teacher Roberts -siirple guileless man&#8212;
Had set in front for lazy boys to scan.
Ahi those were days of innocence and ease.
When wants were few and boys not hard to please.
The days \^en stage coach drivers blew their horn
To 'rouse the sleeping postmaster at mom.
And notify him of the approaching mail
As down "Lee's Knob" their teams would fairly sail
With chaiTq&gt;ing bits and foaming nostrils wide.
Drawing their human freight, worn cut with ride.
To Fosterville&#8212;the village of the rocks.
Cedars and Sinkholes&#8212;village of hard knocks.
The village school house, built of cedar logs.
Between vAose cracks mi^t crawl the boys and dogs
With Webster's speller. Pike's arithmetic.
And "rule of three," (where stupid boys would stick)
And Murray's Grammar&#8212;seemed enough to know
For any modest boy on earth below.
This good old teacher taught, and oft would sing.
That too much learning was a dangerous thing;
And thqt to read, and cipher and to write.
Was all boys needed, if not too much quite,
"These college notions," he would often say,
"Are apt to lead our country boys astray";
And then, to illustrate his sage advice.
And would, to himself refer, "look here, how nice."
But that was more than sixty years ago,
When ox carts ruled and all the world went slow,
Before steel rails were laid or wires were strung
That now fill space and talk in every tongue;
Before a "Trust" or Millionaire was known
Within our tenperate sublunary zone.
h9
Old FostervUlel' Wb look back on thee now
VJith tender thoughts, and often wonder how
And why it was that we, together thrown,
ShoTxld ever to the outer world be known.
We caU to mind those far back halcyon days.
The 'Possum and the 'Coon hunts joyous ways.
And all the boys&#8212;they called one "Butting Ram"
Others, John^Bill and Jim, Steve, Bob and Sam.
But all are gone, strange things have come to pass.
These boys are scattered, dead, alac, alasj
One of them fought in blue, ihe others gray.
But all now sleep in church yards, far awayj
Their strifes, then fierce with bitter angry hate.
No longer live to vex our noble State.
No matter now, the rushing world goes on.
Nor heeds, nor recks the rayrids who are gene.
Vfhere then, "a hundred thousand" almost stunned,
"A billion" now seems but a common fund;
Our Nation then, (Dnparatively weak.
Stands strong today, ready when called, to speak;
And no great move, dare other Nations make
Ihitil of us they careful council take.
These things may well impress the thoughtful mind.
And charge the philosophic how to find
The cause of these marvels~how they came--
And will proportioned futiire growth be same?
But after all, it may be best that we
Shall not the future's far off secrets see;
"Twere wise, perhaps, to hug the happy hope
That all good things will ccwie within our scope.
If, patiently, we justly bide our tine.
And work, and wait, in prose as well as rhyme.
Judging our progress by the century past.
We ask ourselves the question, "Can it last?"
Yet reasoning fairly from analogy.
No optimistic mind can fail to see.
That no far off, remote, or distant date.
Aerial palaces floating through the State,
Making their daily landings without jars.
At all Earth's ports, and e'en, perhaps, at Mars.
But these things pass our Con5&gt;rehension, Stop
Let us retmrn to homely, commonplace.
And meet our hum drum duties face to face.
Let us consider what we may owe
To help the others as we cheerfully go,
Along our tortuous journey through this vale
&#8212;
Sonwtimes, it may be, with a loss of sail.
50
Our duties, if wa will, are plain and clear.
The "Oolden Rule," should to ua all be dear;
Its simple teachings point the unerring way.
Which, if daily kept, no man need fear
Qod, man or devil, hereafter nor here.
Keep out of debt, owe no man anything,
Then you need envy Potentate nor Kingj
And when the tins to lay your burdens down
Cones on apose, you will have earned the crown
Of honor; and the music will begin,
&#8226;Hi/ell done, thou good and faithful Servant,
enter in."
JanTiary 10, 1903
&#8212;copied from "Odds and Ends"&#8212;^book of poems written
by William Moore , pages 21, 22, 23, 2U and 25.
At this time he was 73 years of age.
The following article was copied form a Bedford Cotmty newspaper.
RURAL DELIVERY in 1923
&#8212;Dick Poplin
Mrs. Eula Smith, 212 Edgemont Dr. has let me see an old clipping
ffom a newspaper with a date line of Fosterville, Tenn., Feb. 2, 1923. The
clipping is a letter from James W. lliomas trtio was a rural mail carrier from
Fosterville and secretary-treasurer of the Tennessee Rmral Letter Carriers
Association. Fosterville was jiist outside of this county, but the mail route
extended over into Bedford, and I remember Thomas well when he was still
delivering the mail around Caters Crossing and Longvisw.
Some of the accounts of his 20 years of service, up to that time,
shoxild be Interesting the the readers of this column.
"Just 20 years ago today," Mr. Thomas wrote en Feb. 2, 1923, "I hitched
yxp my gray steed to a new mail wagon and drove to the little post office at
FosteirviUe to make my first trip for Uncle Sam.
"On my first trip I carried about 2U pieces of mail and only three men
51
on the route were subscribers to a daily newspaper. I now have over 70
dailies. The first month's delivery and collecticai ran over 600 pieces of
mail and now ray average is around 7^000 per month. On ray first trip I
carried two locked pouches, one for Midland and csie for Longview, but they
were discontinued long ago.
"During the 20 years' service, I have handled approximately 1,700,000
pieces of mail and have traveled about 160,000 miles. In 20 years I have
worn out lU buggies and 6 sets of single harness and one double set. I have
owned 12 different horses, but had one real good one on the job and I drove
him more than 12 years, having traveled about 70,000 miles over the same road.
"On my first trip I had only 32 boxes, and some of the patrons refused
to erect boxes, saying the R.F,D. service (will not last) six months. VJhy,
it win bankrupt the country. Some actually wrote their Congressman, Mayor
James D. Richardson, and wanted him to do all in his power to have this
foolishness stopped. They scoffed at the idea of delivering every farmer's
mail at his door, but the service has grown by leaps and bounds and is today
the most popular branch of the great postal system.
In the 20 years of ray service I have used 175 j 000 pounds of hay, U,000
bushels of com and 500 bushels of oats, I have used 200 barrels of flour, 2U0 bu
bushels of com meal, 20,000 pounds of meat besides a dozen yearlings and
5,000 pounds of lard, hence the patrons can have some idea of what it costs a
canrier to nm a rural route,
"Twenty years ago it took about $12,000,000 to run the service, now
it takes $88, 000, 000...we had only a few thousand routes, but now v;e have Uli,000
which penetrate every nook and comer of our great country and bring newspapers,
magazines, catalogs, merchandise, medicines and letters to 30,000,000 of our
population.
"R\iral delivery has been called 'the greatest civilizer and educator' of
anything in recent years
52
"I have been one of the great force of men, for 20 years, who has done
his very best to get the mail to his patrons, and the route I serve has not
failed to be gone over a single day during this period, and I have not missed
the train, on which the evening mail is dispatched but one time.
"I am a native of Rutherford County, having been bom and reared near
Rockvale, and have spent every year of my life in my native county except
three. I am the eldest of 23 children, by one man and one woman, the father
of nine, four boys and five girls, the grandfather of four, three girls and
one boy.
OF INTEREST TO PEOPLE OF OUR VILUGE, NOW AND BY-GONE YEARS:
(The following information was given to me by Mrs. Forde Bingjiam,
which she has had in her possession for many years. F.B.)
POSTMASTERS DATE APPOINTED
(This office first known as Melons Mills)
David M. Anders April 11, 1826
Ephriam B. McLean Nov 19, 1827
(Name of office changed to Middle ton)
Ephriam B. McLean July 27, 1837
Thomas Edwards J'lly 1&#176;37
(Neune of office changed to Fosterville)
Thomas Edwards July 27, 1837
Andrew McElroy July 8, 1865
Leander H. Edwards Hay 5, l86l
Hugh Neely July 10, 1897
Alice Edwards Feb 27, I9OJ4
vailie Newby Sept 3, 1913
Lillian Vaughn Aug 17, 1918
T. E. Kerr Aug 17, 1927
Carrie Kerr May 10, 1929
Johnny Williams Nov $, 1936
Johnny Williams March 2, 1939
Mable Harris June 22, 1939
Annie Chrisman June 30, 19U8
(Miss Annie now (1978) serving as postmaster here)
53
NBaiOES OF FOSTERVILLE
by
Elvira Brothers
1970
There are no negroes living ri^t in Fosterville now. They have
either died or moved away. Some of their descendants live on the highway
MP on the hiU toward Christiana. The following are some of the negroes who
have lived here.
One of the most interesting ones being "Uncel Sijne" Landrum and his
wife "Aunt Tennie" as they were lovingly called by everyone. They lived down
on the creek. They owned their own home and lived there unUl their deaths.
"Uncle Sime" was an ex-slave and claimed to be about 108 years old. He was
part Indian. He didn't know when he was bom or who his people were. He Just
remembered being sold as a little boy. He wouldn't talk about it much. He
worked on the railroad with the section crew and as track walker to inspect
the track, even after he was too old to work he still would walk the track
every day as long as he was able. You could see him with his tow sack over
his shoulders coming home about four o'clock. He picked up lun?)s of coal
along the track. Sometimes he would have a big bundle of grass or hay
bringing it hone to his cow. As long as he lived he burned a red railroad
lantern at his front gate. He received a small railroad pension. For many
years he was caretaker for the Woodfin Cemetery. He had always said he
wanted to be buried there. When he died in 19U9, he was buried as he requested
in the left corner of the cemetery as you enter the gate, with his white
friends. He had a tragic death. Aimt Tennie died a few years before he did
and he was living alone. They had no children. He was found one cold morn-ing
in his yard frozen to death. His clothes were burned off and his body
badly burned. It was thought that his clothes must have caught fire and he
Sk
ran out in the yard and wasn't able to get help. He always sat close to the
open fireplace and it was so cold that he may have fallen asleep and fallen
in the fire.
"Uncle Sirae's" wife "Aunt Tennie" whose name was very long, I wish
I co\ild remember all of it but it ended in Kentucky Alabama Tennessee Watkins.
Her ancestors got their name from lir, Al Watkins grandfather. She was loved
by everyone. She always wore a smile. She was "Black Mama" for so many
children around Fosterville, especially for the Kerr children and the Brothers
children. Aunt Tennie washed and ironed for us for many years and I can j\ist
see her now at the wash place in the back yard, washing with a tin wash board,
three tin tubs and the old black pot, with a big fire made from wood from the
wood pile just outside the backyard gate. The children would bring water
from the cistern to fill the tubs and pot. We had to be saving with water
so the water wovild last all sximmer. Sometimes the cistern would be dry and we
had to haul water. I can almost smell the octagon soap she used or the lye
soap made from the leftovers from the "hog killing." Aunt Tennie always wore
a big apron with a big pocket. She wore it wrong side out and carried her
switch toothbrush and her can of Bruton's snuff. After lunch she would sit
and rest for awhile and have her 'dip of snuff. Sometimes she would try to
hide it and if we saw her, she would say, "Now don't tell anybody, I just have
to have ray dessert."
She would usually come on Monday to wash if it was a pretty day to wash.
She was slow and it wotild take her most all day but she didn't care. She was
making her own money and she loved her "whitefolks" as she would say. She had a
heart of gold. On Tuesday or Wednesday she would come back to iron the clothes.
She irotied the clothes with four old fashioned flat irons. Her favorite was
a homemade one made by Mr. Matt Edwards in his shop, (l still have this iom.)
We would have a fire in the big old open fireplace in the big old Kitchen,
55
Daddy would put on a big back log in the momlug and pull the coals out front
on the hearth. When Aunt Tennle came she would stand her irons up in the hot
coals on the hearth. She would clean the smoke and ashes off the irons by
rubbing them on a cedar branch or salt on a piece of paper. When she would
finish ironing, she would sort her clothes and put then away in drawer or on
hangers. She would say she didn't want anyone messing up her nice clothes.
When she would be ready to go home Mama would gather things for her to take
hone with her. Vegetables from the garden and meat from the smokehouse. She
would have her supper already. Daddy would give her fifty cents which was
good pay at that time. She would go home happy.
Aunt Tennie loved her flowers and so many times she would bring a
bouquet of flowers all squeezed up in her hand with just the tops and no stems.
She had sore beautiful peonies but they would always have short stems.
She like to piece Quilts. Lots of times Mama would buy bundles of
remnants for her, and would give her scraps of material from her sewing.
She wouldn't set them together. She just wanted to piece the squares. She
pieced each of us four children one and Mama one. I have mine, it is a nine
patch mostly blue print set together with red. Mama's is a big star pattern.
She also made each of the Kerr children one.
She had a little walnut table vdth one drawer in it, which I compli-mented
one time when I was down at her house and said, "Aunt Tennie when you
get through with that little table I want you to will it to me." She said,
"All right Vily,you can have it but Simon keeps his insurance papers in it,
but some day you can have it. One day an antique dealer came to see her
and wanted to buy that little table. She said No, No, that is Viley's little
table. I promised it to her. Not long after that she came up and wanted me to
coma and get the table. She had found a dresser she wanted at Mrs. Eliza Clark's.
She wanted me to buy the dresser for her and have Benny Maupin (the negro man
56
\
who was helping Daddy on -ttie farm) to take the wagon and bring the dresser
to her hoTise and get the table. I gave Benny the three dollars and he went
and got the dresser and brought my little table. I had the table refinished
and am using it in my living room, I wouldn't take anything for it. She died
not long afterward. She was buried at Christiana.
Uncle Joe Murphy and Aunt Mat lived in a house back of the old Post
Office near the old Lee Edwards house, known as the Aunt Dolie house. Both
houses are gone now. They had several children who have long since married
and moved away. Among them were Bettie M\xrphy who married John Ella Daniel.
They had three children, Veatrice, Herman and Sam Henry. They moved to
Nashville, Lillie Murphy married Luke Kelly. They moved with several
children to Detroit, Michigan.
Anderson Tucker and his wife, Hester lived down the railroad. They
had three children, Tom, Jim, and Frances Tucker. V/hen Anderson died, Hester
went to Nashville to live with her children \iho had married and gone, Anderson
worked on the railroad.
Many people would remember Hester Howland, wife of Dee Howland and
their son, Jimmy Dee Howland. Hester stayed with ray mother when her children
were bom. Poor Hester stuttered. She was hurt when she was a girl when the
bad cyclone blew Fosterville away. She was staying with the Elams. Hester
and Dee were living near the Webb Crossing when Dee died.
Uncle Will Rucker and Aunt Molly lived down on the creek. They had
three childrai. Bill Rucker, Henry and Jennie Anne who married Millar Wade.
Bill Rucker married Beulah Mai Bracey. They had five children. The two girls,
Mary Anne and Alberta died when their house burned after Bill and Guy Lewis
died. Beulah May was the daughter of Bertie Wade who died young and Beulah
Mai's grandmother. Aunt Anne Wade and Uncle Will Wade raised Beulah Mai and
her brother Billy Sunday and sister Katie Lee. Uncle Will Wade had a wooden
57
leg. He died at Beulah's and Bill's when they lived next to Brandon's
Chapel Church, Atint Nancy North and her daughter Frances also lived
down on the creek.
Brandon's Chapel burned in September 1973.
58</dc:description>
<dc:description>A short history of the community of Fosterville</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>local history; community history</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Fosterville</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>31 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-15</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication16ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/121</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>