<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>A researcher's guide to Rutherford County records</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Rowe, David L.</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 32</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1989</dc:date>
<dc:description>A RESEARCHER'S GUIDE TO RUTHERFORD COUNTY RECORDS
by
David L. Rowe
Compiler and Editor
for the
Murfreesboro Heritage Committee
Homecoming ' 8 6
Published by
The Rutherford County Historical Society
Winter I989
Foreword
Ever since Alex Haley published Roots and a film version of
the book appeared on television, Americans in the thousands have
gone treasure hunting, searching in public records for clues to
the lives of their ancestors. Dozens of geneological guides and
"how to do it" books have appeared, all of them more or less
helpful to the nonprofessional historian who has to learn from
scratch about censuses, wills, vital statistics&#8212;where to find
them and how to use them. All of these publications reach out to
a general audience to assure wide sales to cover printing costs,
so they necessarily discuss generally available resources in
general terms.
It has long been obvious that a different kind of
publication was necessary to complement these guides&#8212;a book that
discusses specific records available in a specific community,
where they are located, what information they contain, how to get
that information, and how to interpret it. To make such a book
readily available requires a publisher who can present it to an
audience limited in number and geography and one who can present
it in a less formal format affordable to the general public. In
other words, the key to a successful guide to the records of a
particular locality is a partnership between historians who know
about and have used these records and the local historical
- 1 -
society which can make this information available.
Such a partnership is already an old one here in
Murfreesboro. Local historians have for decades been researching
the story of families, events, and institutions of the city, and
the Rutherford County Historical Society has a long- and well-established
series of publications that distributes this history
to the public. It is to celebrate this partnership as well as to
serve the public interest, therefore, that this guide to local
records is presented.
Any time is propitious for compiling a document like this,
but Tennessee Homecoming '86 provided the incentive for beginning
and completing this project. What the longterm benefits and
effects of Homecoming '86 will be is unclear, but Murfreesboro '
s
Heritage Committee began its work determined to produce a lasting
contribution, a gift to the people of Murfreesboro and Rutherford
County that would exist possibly long after the reasons for
Homecoming '86 are forgotten. The best gift we could give was
shared knowledge. So in this spirit we present this guide to the
Rutherford County Historical Society and, through them, to you.
- 2 -
Table of Contents
1
.
Foreword - page 1
2. How to Use County Records for Research. .. .page 4
3. Recording Information page 9
4. Personal Information page 13
5. Property Information
A. Conveyances page 23
B
Taxes page 38
C. Wills and Estates .page 41
6. Business Information page S'^
7. Legal Information
A. Chancery Court page 60
B. Circuit Court page (i6
C. County Judge and County Court page 72
D. General Sessions Court page 76
8. Administrative Information page 78
9. Materials in Linebaugh Library page 83
-3-
How to Use County Records for Research
Anyone researching information in county records for the
first time feels lost. There are hundreds of records produced by
a dozen agencies and stored in any number of locations. Just
finding a particular record seems difficult enough, let alone
finding the information in that record that we are seeking. In
reality, though, researching in county records is easier than
other kinds of historical research, for the materials are
together in one community (although perhaps in more than one
building) rather than spread all over the country. And finding
information in those records is easy, too, once one becomes
accustomed to two things. First is the structure of local
government. Once we know that, then finding specific records is
simply a matter of deducing which agency would have created it.
Second is the specific method by which agencies wrote
information. From one record to another, and from one agency to
another, there is a decided consistency in the kinds of
information recorded and in the manner of recording it. Let's
look at each of these considerations in turn.
The Structure of Local Government
Each county agency has defined functions, and each has
generated records in fulfilling those functions since the
establishment of Rutherford County in 1803. Both the structure of
the county government and the kinds of records generated derived
from traditional American and British models, and although county
government and the records it keeps have increased in size and
complexity over the years, the outlines of that model are still
clearly recognizable.
American county government derives from British county
administration, the most important unit of local government in
England. (Louisiana, the only American exception, derives its
local parish form of government from the French model.) The form
of English county administration evolved over centuries with
influences from the Anglo-Saxons before the Norman Conquest in
1066 and then from the French afterwards. For instance, the
chief Saxon administrator (reeve) for the county (shire) was
known as the shire reeve, a word that evolved into sheriff; the
chancery (from the Old French chancelerie ) was the court that
heard cases involving equity, and from this has evolved our
Chancery Court; the local judicial official in Britain and in the
North American colonies was the justice of the peace. There were
other forms of local government in Britain as well&#8212;incorporated
cities, boroughs, ports&#8212;and it was from these "inferior"
municipalities that northern colonies in North America derived
their township and borough governments. In the southern
colonies, though, population was distributed so thinly that
larger geographic areas, counties, became the most important
units of local government, and this tradition carried on when
settlers principally from North Carolina and Virginia populated
the interior of their colonies, the areas that became Kentucky
and Tennessee.
The functions of county government in America remained much
the same as well&#8212;essentially to maintain order and to raise
money for public purposes. Along with these two functions ' ave
always gone the two kinds of power needed to execute them, the
power of the sword (military and police) and the power of the
purse (taxing). All county government essentially derives from
these two functions and powers. Exercising these powers falls to
the three structural branches of government&#8212;legislative,
executive, and judicial. It is in this structure that the
greatest evolution of local administration has taken place.
The county legislature evolved from what was originally a
regional meeting of Justices of the Peace. These officials were
responsible for maintaining the peace and so were directly
associated with the local militia. Each captain's company had
two justices, whom the legislature appointed. Eventually the
office became elective. All the county's Justices of the Peace
met four times a year in the Quarterly Court whose functions were
administrative (recording deeds, bonds, licenses), judicial
(probating wills, establishing guardianships and trusteeships).
and legislative (levying taxes). Eventually the administrative
duties fell to a monthly meeting of the Court called the Quorum
Session. The Clerk of the Court became the chief registrar of the
county and the County Judge its chief executive. In 1978 county
government was reorganized, and the County Court replaced with
the County Board of Commissioners.
Several officers serve the county's legislature in specific
ways. The Register of Deeds records deeds and other official
instruments; the Superintendent of Schools administers the public
school system; the Highway Superintendent supervises road work
and the county workhouse; the Director of Accounts and Budgets
maintains proper financial records; the County Health Director
administers public health projects and keeps vital statistics; a
Planning Director and Building Inspector administers zoning and
health and safety codes in the construction and renovation of
buildings; the Register-at-Large runs the county Election
Commission office. Many of these officers work with appointed or
elected commissions.
Until 1978 the chief executive official of the county was
the County Judge, principally an administrative rather than
judicial officer. Today, the chief county administrator is the
County Executive. Enforcing laws has fallen to a series of
officials over time. The Sheriff is the chief county law
enforcement agent, the Coroner inspects causes of death, the
County Attorney advises the local government in legal matters.
In the past the Constables served warrants and the Ranger rounded
up stray and unmarked animals. The chief fiscal officer is the
County Trustee who collects taxes and disburses county money.
Associated with him is the Assessor of Property. Challenges of
assessments go directly to a Board of Equalization.
Judicial functions fall to a series of courts. Tennessee's
system of local courts is one of the most complicated in the
nation, made more so by the unclear lines of jurisdiction among
them and by jurisdiction that often overlaps that of state
courts. In general, however, cases involving local law are heard
in one of three courts. The Court of General Sessions sets bail
and bond and gives judgments in minor civil and some criminal
cases. The Chancery Court (over which presides an elected
Chancellor) hears all civil cases involving adoptions, divorces,
child support and custody, delinquent taxes, guardianships and
trusts, bankruptcies, and forced sales. The Chancery Court also
administers naturalization proceedings locally. The court's
clerk is called the Clerk and Master. The Circuit Court hears
criminal and civil cases (involving more than $10,000) . All cases
involving juveniles are referred to the Juvenile Court which used
to operate under the County Judge but that today is served by an
elected judge. The District Attorney General is the county's
prosecutor.
Recording Information
The records of all these agencies contain information that
can be helpful to us whether we are tracing our lineage,
discovering the history of our house, researching the evolution
of an institution such as a church, business, or civic club, or
learning about a local historical event. Once we become familiar
with the structure of local government, the next step in finding
this information is to ask ourselves what KIND of information we
are seeking.
A specific record contains the information required for the
agency to fulfill its mandated responsibilities, so to find a
particular kind of information we need to determine which
agencies would have maintained the kind of information we need.
For instance, if we want facts about school attendance in
Rutherford County we would logically look at records of the
Department of Education; if we wanted a list of registered voters
we would look at the Election Commission's records; if we wanted
to find the minutes of a trial we would look at the minutes of
the appropriate court. But there is a great deal of unexpected
information in these records as well. For instance, the list of
registered voters also indicates each voter's occupation, perhaps
a handy fact to have; a church deed lists the members of the
vestry or building committee at the time the congregation
10
purchased the land; executors' reports list an estate's creditors
which provides clues to how a specific person lived.
The purpose of this guide is to awaken the researcher to
these hidden treasures. It may well be that a genealogist who
has lost track of an ancestor in traditional sources will find
that person in a court action, listed as a jury member, or
claiming tax exemption for delivering fox scalps to the county.
To do that, we must organize our material in the most helpful
manner, not according to the agency that created each record but
according to the principal kind of information each record
conveys. Each county record conveys information of one of five
kinds
:
1. PERSONAL INFORMATION (vital statistics): facts about
individuals' birth, marriage, death, naturalization, adoption,
guardianship;
2. PROPERTY INFORMATION: facts about the ownership,
conveyance, and improvement of property;
3. BUSINESS AND PROFESSIONAL INFORMATION: facts about how
individuals made a living and functioned in commerce;
4. LEGAL INFORMATION: facts about personal conduct, trials,
civil suits, serving on juries;
5. ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION: facts about how county
government functions and who administers the agencies of county
government.
11
Of course, these five categories overlap. A jury trial
(LEGAL INFORMATION) also conveys facts about persons' lives
(PERSONAL INFORMATION), as does a merchant's bond (BUSINESS
INFORMATION), or a will (PROPERTY INFORMATION). What we are doing
is assessing the principal kind of information a record conveys
and organizing this guide accordingly. The researcher who wants
to find out absolutely everything about "John Smith" should
consult all the records; someone wishing only to find information
about a civil suit involving "John Smith" needs consult only the
section on LEGAL INFORMATION.
For every record included in each of these five categories
the reader will also find listed the agency that created the
record and the years each record covers. This guide also tells
where the record is located. Most appear in the County Archives,
on the second floor of the Court House, or in the office of the
agency that created the record. The Tennessee State Library and
Archives (listed as TSL&amp;A) has microfilmed many of these records,
and complete sets of these microfilms are available at the State
Library. Linebaugh Library received 100 reels of this collection
and purchased an additional 6 reels. Each county agency has
copies of the microfilm of records that agency created and/or
maintains. Also, Middle Tennessee State University has purchased
some rolls of microfilm from the large set of Rutherford County
records. Each record description lists all locations where the
12
record may be found and used. This guide also describes the
record's index (if it has one) and how to use it. Finally, a
description of each record states what kinds of specific
information the record conveys. At the end of this guide you
will find a cross-referenced index by subject matter which will
indicate which records to use to find specific kinds of
information.
Now with patience and imagination mining facts out of this
body of material becomes principally a matter of work. Like any
detective the researcher will find dead ends, but there is no
greater satisfaction than after long hours of searching finding
just the information we are seeking tucked away in a dusty
ledger. Have fun!
13
PERSONAL INFORMATION
1. Record: Birth Records (County Court Clerk) , 1881-1937
Location: 1881-1912, 1915-1937&#8212;County Clerk's Office
1924-1936&#8212;County Archives
Microfilm: 1881-1912; 1915-1935&#8212;at TSL&amp;A, County Clerk
Birth records contain the name, sex, and race of the newborn, the
place of birth by civil district number or ward, the names of the
parents and their places of birth, the name of the physician, the
father's occupation, and the date the birth was recorded. An
index appears in the front of the record books for 1881-1912 and
1925-1937, listing alphabetically the names of the newborn
children and the page number on which the birth is recorded.
Records for 1924-1936 are not indexed. Currently, the Department
of Health maintains birth records, but all records for the last
fifty years are kept confidential.
2. Record: Death Records (County Court Clerk), 1881-1937
Location: 1881-1912, 1925-1937&#8212;County Clerk's Office
1924-1936&#8212;County Archives
Microfilm: 1881-1912&#8212;at TSL&amp;A, County Clerk
Death records contain the name, age at death, race, and sex of
the deceased along with his or her marital status (in some record
books only). One also finds here the deceased's place of birth
14
including the civil district number if born in Rutherford County,
the place of death by civil district number, and the date and
cause of death. Books are arranged alphabetically, but within
each book names are not arranged in alphabetical order. The
record of "John Smith's" death would appear in the book marked
"S", but within that book the clerk would have written in the
record of his death chronologically. To find it, simply keep
looking; or if you know the year he died then turn pages until
you come to records of death for that year, and his record will
be there.
3. Record: Discharges [Military] (Register of Deeds),
1919-present
Location: Register of Deeds Office
Microfilm: 1919-1958 (1937 missing) &#8212;at TSL&amp;A, Register's
Office
All honorable discharges from the armed services from World War I
through today are listed here. The information eacha record
contains varies over time, and in general the amount of
information decreased over time. But in 1919 a discharged listed
the soldier's name, serial number, rank at time of discharge,
company, regiment, branch of the military, the reason for the
discharge, birth place, age at enlistment, occupation, the color
of his or her eyes and hair, complexion, height, place and date
of discharge, and the signature of the commanding officer. Early
15
discharges also contain an enlistment record including notes on
the soldier's marksmanship, horse- manship, battles and
decorations received, wounds, physical condition at the time of
discharge, marital status, and remarks about his or her personal
character
.
4. Record: Enumeration (Department of Education), 1912-1913
Location: County Archives
This is a ;edger containing statistics on school population in
each school district. It contains the name of the school, the
district number, name of the parent or guardian, name and address
of the student, his or her distance from school as well as race,
physical condition, and age, the total school enrollment, and the
number of students who can read and write. There is no general
index to this register; names appear by district number. To find
a specific person one would have to read through the record.
5. Record: Fox Scalp Exemptions (County Trustee) , 1879-1889
Locaiton: County Archives
The state authorized a tax deduction, or exemption, for anyone
producing fox scalps to encourage the limitation of the fox
population which had either grown too large or too susceptible to
rabies. This document records those people in Rutherford County
16
who claimed such a tax exemption. It lists the name of the
applicant and the number of scalps presented. An alphabetical
index by last name of the applicant appears at the front of the
book giving the page number on which the exemption appears, but
names do not appear alphabetically under each letter division.
"John Smith" would appear in the index on the "S" page, but his
name might be listed after "John South," for instance.
6. Record: Guardian Settlements (County Court Clerk),
1914-present
Location: 1914--County Archives
1940-present&#8212;County Clerk's Office
Settlements prior to this date appear in the
County Court Minute Books
Microfilm: 1940-1963&#8212;at TSL&amp;A, County Clerk
This records the establishment of guardians and the reasons for
doing this. It contains the name of the guardian and of the
dependent, the reason for the establishment of the guardianship
(minority, incompetence, retardation, etc.), the source of the
money for the dependent, the purpose and amount of money spent,
and the guardian's salary. A financial record lists all receipts
and disbursements in the dependent's account. Yearly reports
often list the release of the guardianship and its reason. If
the dependent has died then funeral expenses are listed. Volumes
appear chronologically, and at the front of each is an
alphabetical listing by last name of the dependent showing also
17
the reason for the establishment of the guardianship and the page
number on which the settlement may be found.
7. Record: Guardian Bonds (County Court Clerk), 1874-present
Location: 1874-1973&#8212;County Archives
1948-present&#8212;County Clerk's Office
Microfilm: 1848-present--TSL&amp;A, County Clerk
1877-1948&#8212;Linebaugh Library
This is a listing of bonds filed by guardians to ensure faithful
administra- tion of his or her responsiblities . The record
includes the names of the guardian and the dependent, date of the
bond, status of dependent (minor, retarded, incompetent, etc.),
the guardian's oath, the clerk's name, and the court term and
date. Sometimes also a power of attorney appears taped onto the
page. At the front of each volume appears an alphabetical index
by last name of the dependent, though names do not appear in
strict alpha- betical order within each letter division ("Smith"
may follow "South," for example). The index lists the page
numberof the oath, and sometimes the name of the guardian.
8. Record: Guardian Minute Book (County Court Clerk),
1874-1910
Location: County Clerk's Office
Microfilm: 1874-1910&#8212;TSL&amp;A, County Clerk, Linebaugh Library
This is an index to the location of guardian settlements
contained in the County Court Minute Books where they were
recorded before 1914, giving the book and page number. The index
is arranged chronologically and gives the name of the guardian
and the dependent and the location of all references to the
guardianship. At the front of the book is an alphabetical index
of this index arranged by last name of the guardian and the
dependent.
9. Record: Guardian's Receipts (County Court Clerk),
1855-1914
Location: 1954-1914&#8212;County Archives
Microfilm: 1855-1914&#8212;at TSL&amp;A, County Clerk
The record lists receipts in each account for the dependent and
provides the names of the guardian and of the dependent, and the
amount received for the dependent. Some pages have powers of
attorney attached.
10. Record: Marriages (County Court Clerk), 1804-present
Location: County Clerk's Office
Microfilm: Index, 1899-1914; 1804-1963&#8212;at TSL&amp;A, County
Clerk
Index, 1899-1914; 1804-1907&#8212;at Linebaugh Library
1804-1881&#8212;at MTSU
Listings of marriage licenses and actual marriages providing the
names of the bride and groom, date of the license, date of the
wedding, and the names of any sureties. Each book contains an
19
alphabetical listing at the front of grooms and brides (some
books only list the grooms) , but within each letter category
names do not appear in strict alphabetical order. There is also
a separate "Index to Marriages" from 1804-1881.
11. Record: Marriage Licenses (County Court Clerk) , 1902-1909
Location: County Clerk's Office
Microfilm: 1902-1904&#8212;at TSL&amp;A, County Clerk
A listing of marriage licenses arranged chronologically and
providing the name of the groom and the bride and the date of the
license. This is not indexed.
12. Record: Motor Vehicle Registration (County Court Clerk),
1930-1939
Location: County Archives
This record lists motor vehicle licenses providing the name of
the licensee, his or her address, and the registration number.
The record is not indexed. Entries appear in chronological
order
.
13. Record: Naturalization Record (Circuit Court), 1924
Location: County Archives
This record provides a wealth of information about each person
20
naturalized in Rutherford County in 1924 including a certificate
of arrival, port of entry into the United States, date the
certificate was issued, name of the alien, date of arrival, name
of vessel or steamship line, declaration of intention to become a
citizen. This latter lists the state and city where the
intention was filed, name of the alien, birth place, age, country
of origin, date of arrival, name of previous head of state,
intention to renounce previous allegiance, signatures of the
alien and the clerk. It is truly unfortunate that records for
additional years are not available.
14. Record: Power of Attorney (County Court Clerk),
1804-present
Location: Register of Deeds Office
Microfilm: 1804-1814&#8212;at TSL&amp;A, County Clerk
Powers of attorney are included with Trust Deeds (see the next
section, "Property," to learn how to find specific documenys).
These documents convey agent status for another person allowing
the holder to sign documents, give receipts, make sales, and
collect and disburse funds in the interests of the dependent.
Documents record the name of the appointee, name of the
dependent, date of the appointment, notarization, and signature
of the clerk.
21
15. Record: Power of Attorney [Receipts] (County Court
Clerk) , 1854-1914
Location: County Archives
This is a set of receipts recording activities by those holding
power of attorney for another.
16. Record: Registered Voters (Election Commission), 1938,
1941-42, 1947
Location: County Archives
These volumes contain lists of registered voters for the 13th
civil district (Murf reesboro) providing the name, sex, age,
address, and vocation. Two volumes are separate listings of
"Colored Voters" and provide the name, address, age, and
vocation. Volumes of white voters are arranged alpha- betically
by last, though names do not appear in strict alphabetical order
within each letter division. "Colored Voters" lists, containing
about 250 names in each volume, list names in no particular order
and are not indexed. All volumes are annual listings.
17. Record: Insanity Record (County Court Clerk), 1919-1975
Location: County Clerk's Office Microfilm: 1919-1964&#8212;at TSL&amp;A,
County Clerk
These volumes contain commitment papers and record of
proceedings listing the name of the hospital to which the patient
is committed, name of the patient, nature of the process by which
22
he or she was committed, a physician's report, description of the
patient, nature of the illness, and a description of the
patient's behavior pattern.
23
PROPERTY INFORMATION
A. Conveyance
Record: Deeds (Register of Deeds), 1804-present
Location: Register of Deeds Office
Microfilm: Indexes; 1804-1963&#8212;TSL&amp;A, Register's Office
Indexes; 1804-1902&#8212;Linebaugh Library
Indexes, 1804-1890; 1804-1838, 1864-1879&#8212;MTSU
Deeds are records of transactions between people, often involving
property, and they are the most voluminous records the county
maintains. There are several types of deeds. The best known is
the deed of conveyance, the document that records the purchase of
your home and property and the conveyance of fee simple title to
you, but there are also deeds of trust, deeds of easement, and
others. Each record, though, contains a great deal of
information that can be of help to the researcher, so we will
discuss this particular record at length.
Finding the Correct Deed : All deed transactions involve a
grantor (seller or lender) and a grantee (purchaser or debtor).
A person who buys land or takes out a loan today is a grantee,
but tomorrow when he or she sells the land or loans money the
person becomes a grantor. Every piece of land in Rutherford
County has a record of purchase and sale extending back in time
to the earliest settlement periods, and assuming that all land
24
transactions have been recorded (which often is not the case)
,
then the record of the land's ownership appears in the deeds.
This is true of mortgages, too, which appear in the deeds of
trust
.
Establishing the chain of ownership of a specific parcel of
land is not difficult. Begin with the current owner. If you do
not know who that is go to the Tax Assessor's office and refer to
the plat maps of the county. Each property has a tax map number,
and the Assessor's Office maintains a card file arranged by
property number that lists the current owner of record and also
the deed book number and page number on which appears the most
recent deed of conveyance. Tracing the ownership back through
time now becomes a matter of identifying previous owners.
All deeds that are recorded appear in two indexes, each of
them divided into chronological periods. The Direct Index lists
each deed according to the last name of the seller (grantor); the
Indirect or Reverse Index lists each deed according to the last
name of the purchaser (grantee) . Each deed appears in each
index. If John Smith now owns the parcel of land you are
researching and you locate the current deed, you will find him
listed as the grantee. This deed will give you the name of the
grantor, the person from whom he bought the land. Let's say that
person was "Sam Jones". While Sam Jones was the grantor in this
transaction, at some time in the past he was the grantee; he
25
bought the land from someone else. Your next step is to refer to
the most recent Reverse Index ( 1955-present) , I-J, to find the
deed that first conveyed title to the property to Sam Jones. On
the inside cover appears the alphabetical system by which names
are arranged in the index. In this volume the system looks like
this:
II Jp Jv
Jq Jw
Jb Jo Jr Ju Jx 7
Ja Jc 3 Js Jy
Jd Jt Jz
Jf Jj .
Je Jg Ji Jk 5
Jh Jl
Jm
Jn
All last names beginning with the letter "I" are indexed
beginning at section 1 (technically this is a page number, but
these "pages" go on for many sheets) . The name "Jones" begins
with the letters "J" and "o" and those names are indexed in
section 7. When we turn to that section we will find all the
names beginning with the letters "Jo" through "Jz". Here one
finds the last name of the grantor appearing in the left hand
column and then a series of columns divided alphabetically in
which first names are recorded. To find our person we need to
look at all the "Joneses" and then check to see that we have
"Sam" Jones. People who do alot of abstracting of deeds often
26
find it actually easier to look for the first name rather than
for the last name, because that automatically disqualifies most
of the names included in this part of the index. There are fewer
"Sams" than there are Joneses or other names beginning with Jo
through Jz . You will notice that these names DO NOT appear in
strict alphabetical order; in fact, they are listed in
chronological order according to the date the deeds were
recorded. So you must search through the pages until you find
Sam Jones's name.
Next, you must be sure that the deed listed in this index is
for the same piece of property in which you are interested. Sam
Jones may have purchased more than one parcel in the time period
the index covers. The only way to be sure is to look at all the
deeds recorded for Sam Jones. (If you know the date when he sold
this land the job becomes somewhat easier, but in most cases you
won't know this.) Also, there may well have been more than one
Sam Jones buying property--Sam Jones, sr.; Sam Jones, jr.; Sam
Jones from Murf reesboro; Sam Jones from Eagleville. They're not
the same person, and you'll have to note all references to "Sam
Jones" to make sure you get the correct deed. You will notice
that the index itself lists the grantor along with the grantee, so
if you know you have the correct person and the correct piece of
property you will not have to refer to the deed to get the name
of the grantor.
27
If you need to check this, and it's a good idea to do that,
the index will provide you with the liber (book) number and page
number where you will find the deed recording each transaction of
Sam Jones as grantor from 1955 to the present. All deed books
are in the Register of Deeds Office, and they are arranged
numerically. The lower the number, the older the deed, until you
get back to the very first deed books which have alphabetical
labels. When you find the correct deed the document will tell
you from whom Sam Jones purchased the property. That person, in
turn, was once previously a grantee of the property, so you
retrace your steps, looking at earlier indexes until you find the
deed that records his or her purchase of the property. In this
way you follow the chain of transactions back through time
hopefully until the earliest record of conveyance.
Before the creation of Rutherford County all transactions
were recorded as part of Davidson County, and before that time
all transactions were handled by the Southwest Territory
government and then the state of North Carolina. These records
contain transactions between the first white owners and the
municipal authority who controlled this region before Tennessee
and Rutherford County existed. The records have been microfilmed
and are available at the Register of Deeds office.
You can follow the chain only so long as deeds were
recorded. As one regresses in time the possibility increases
28
that one or more deeds to your property were not recorded, in
which case you hit a dead end. You are always free to read all
deeds back in time until you pick up a missing link, but most
people lack the time and patience for that. There are some other
steps you can take depending on how far back you have been able
to go so far.
Nashville city directories exist from the 1860s until well
into the 20th century. Many of the older directories list
Murfreesboro residents and businesses at the back of each book,
and this list may give you a name to attach to your property if
you have reached a dead end. Also, the History Department at
MTSU has created a complete photographic collection of Sanborn
Fire Insurance Company atlases of Murfreesboro from 1886 to 1945.
These maps show every property in the city of Murfreesboro
including buildings, property boundaries, dimensions, building
material, etc., and sometimes the name of the owner or resident
appears as well. Again, if your property is in the city, old
maps often list the names of property owners.
It is also possible that your chain of conveyance apparently
comes to an end because the property was involved in an estate
settlement of some sort. Be sure to check estate settlements,
guardian records, and other documents that relate to wills and
inheritances which are all listed farther along in this section.
Also, it is possible that the missing owner of your property took
29
out a mortgage, had a lien applied against the property, or
awarded a deed of easement. All these encumbrances would have
had a special deed of trust created for the transaction, and this
would appear in the deeds of trust along with a property
description (boundaries, size of property, etc.) See item #19
below for a description of deeds of trust. Also, it is possible
the deed was a subject of a court test (probation) . Check the
Probated Deeds (see record # 20)
.
There is one other step you can take if all else fails.
Very often a deed describes the boundaries to a property by
naming the owners of neighboring properties, "north along the
property owned by Henry Jackson," for example. It's possible
that by tracing Henry Jackson's property ownership you can find a
deed that describes his property boundaries by the name of the
person who owns your lot, again providing you with your missing
link in the chain. Once you have this new name you can precede
with your deed search.
Interpreting the Information : A deed of conveyance provides
a great deal of valuable information. The purpose of a deed of
conveyance is to record the transfer of title of real property
from one person to another. That property usually consists of
land and the buildings on it, but before 1865 the definition of
property included people&#8212;slaves&#8212;as well. A common assumption
about deeds is that they describe buildings, so people often look
30
to deeds for building descriptions. These records do on occasion
mention buildings and perhaps even their building material, but
not all deeds provide a list of structures sitting on the
property. Also, deeds sometimes mention the names of chattel
slaves being sold, but sometimes they simply mention their sex
and age. Essentially, we look to deeds of conveyance to inform
us about specific pieces of property, and whatever additional
facts the deed provides are a bonus.
All deeds will state the name of the grantor, of the
grantee, the amount of land or exact nature of the item being
conveyed, the consideration (price) , and terms of conveyance.
The document also lists any encumbrances on the conveyance (liens
and easements that go along with the property, for example)
.
When title to property is being conveyed the exact dimensions and
boundaries of the property are "carefully" defined. From the
mid-nineteenth century to the present these boundaries are
relatively precise. Before this date deeds often describe
boundaries by referring to natural objects as landmarks such as
trees, creeks, and boulders. Dimensions are rendered in various
ways. The accepted surveyor's units include
A deed that mentions buildings is particularly valuable,
because often it is the structure we are researching, not the
land on which it sits. But interpreting this information can be
tricky. The structures standing at the time of the land's
31
conveyance may not be the same ones standing on the property
now. If the deed mentions a stone structure where a wood frame
barn now stands, we need to note that. On the other hand, if the
deed mentions a wood frame barn where a stone barn now stands,
the two may be the same building. Perhaps the wood barn had a
stone facade added to it at some point.
If the deed does not mention structures we may not assume
they did not exist on the property at the time of the conveyance
of title. One way to judge if a building was constructed on a
piece of land during the time a particular person owned the land
is to compare the size of the property and the purchase price
between the times the person purchased and sold the property.
For example, we might be sure that a house in the Queen Anne
style was built on a city lot sometime about 1890. Our deed
search shows that John Brown sold the property to Sam Smith in
1888, and Sam Smith sold it to William Perkins in 1915. The
question is, was the house standing on the lot when Sam Smith
purchased it in 1888? We notice that he paid $450 for the lot in
1888 and sold the same size lot for $5800 in 1915. Almost
certainly Sam Smith built the house, although the deed does not
say precisely in what year. Still, we can narrow down the person
who owned the lot at the time when the house was built and the
broad time period during which he had the house built. Referring
to other records (tax records, Sanborn atlases, directories) can
32
narrow down the date considerably.
But here, too, we must be careful. What if Sam Smith bought
the property in 1888 for $5000 and sold it in 1915 for $6000?
This could mean one of many things. Perhaps the house was
standing on the lot when Smith bought it, making John Brown the
builder (man for whom it was built). Or, perhaps a different
house stood on the lot, Sam Smith tore it down and built the
Queen Anne style home. Then again, perhaps Sam Smith took an
existing house and modernized it by having it remodeled in the
Queen Anne style. Again, by referring to other records,
particularly property tax accounts, we might be able to solve
these mysteries and arrive at the correct answer.
Changes in land values over time can reflect things other
than improvements on the property. Inflation over time raises
land values as does someone else's improvements that make our
property more valuable even if we do nothing to it. Reassess-ments
have the effect of raising the value of everybody's
property. So we must interpret this kind of information very
carefully, and we do not want to rely solely on the information
from deeds to inform us about our property. But by taking the
information the deed conveys and matching it with information
from other sources we can compile a fairly clear record of land
transactions and improvements on it.
33
19. Record: Church List (Register of Deeds), 1804-present
Location: Register of Deeds Office
This is simply a card file index providing a list of church
property and the book and page number on which the deed conveying
that property to the religious institution is located. The file
index is arranged by church denomination, then by civil district
under each denominational heading, and finally by the name of the
church.
20. Record: Trust Deeds (Register of Deeds), 1804-present
Location: Register of Deeds Office
Microfilm: Indexes; 1864-1963--TSL&amp;A, Register's Office
Indexes, 1864-1962; 1868-1901~Linebaugh Library
Trust deeds are records of financial and personal transactions
that do not convey title to real property but that encumber
property in some way. These include mortgages, liens, bonds,
guardianships, partnerships, and limited partnerships, and
corporate charters. These records also state when the trust was
released (because the mortgage was paid off, the lien expired,
the trusteeship came to an end, a partnership was dissolved)
.
This information appears in a marginal notation stating the
location of the release located in release books (see below #21)
.
Trust deeds are indexed in the same manner as deeds of conveyance
(see above #18) . When the deed involves property it contains
34
boundary descriptions. All deeds of trust include the name of
trustor and trustee (equivalent to grantor and grantee) , the
nature of the encumbrance, amount of consideration, and terms
under which the trust is to continue. The index provides the
book and page number where the deed is recorded.
21. Record: Chattel Mortgages (Register of Deeds), 1934-1964
Location: Register of Deeds
Microfilm: 1934-1964&#8212;at TSL&amp;A, Register's Office
Chattel Mortgages record loans and bonds on personal property
(non-real estate) such as buildings, crops, cattle, house
trailers. They record the names of the mortgager and mortgagee,
date of the transaction, and the nature of the property being
mortgaged. Chattel mortgages were indexed with the Trust Deeds
until 1962 when a separate index was maintained until 1964. These
indexes are direct (by name of grantor) and reverse (by name of
grantee) and also provide the date of the deed, the date the deed
was filed, and the book and page number where it can be found.
In 1964 these records ceased to be used, and the Uniform
Commercial Code Filing Notebook replaced them. These records
contain the date, the filing number, names of the debtor and the
secured party, and the filing fee.
35
22. Record: Probate Deed Book (County Court Clerk), 1917-1919,
1921-1927, 1942-1944
Location: County Archives
The word probate comes from the Latin word meaning "to prove." A
probated deed is one that has been tested in court, and this
record lists these transactions. It contains the names of the
parties, date of the tested deed, date the deed was filed, amount
of the consideration, number of acres, location of the property
by civil district, type of deed, before whom the deed was
acknowledged, state tax, and amount of the clerk's fee. There is
no index to this record, but they appear chronologically by the
date they were probated.
23. Record: Lien Book (Register of Deeds), 1932-present
Location: Register of Deeds Office
Microfilm: 1932-1963&#8212;at TSL&amp;A, Register's Office
The Lien book records liens placed on properties by court
action. Each record contains the name of the court, nature of
the lien, reason for placing the lien, the name of the creditor,
amount of money or nature of the consideration involved, name of
the property owner, description of the property, and any other
condition to be met before the lien is removed. Lien books from
1931 to 1980 are indexed alphabetically at the front of each
volume. The index is arranged by direct references (name of
creditor or "lienor") and reverse or indirect references (name of
36
debtor or "lienee"). Names do not appear alphabetically under
each letter division, however, so you must search th3 page for
the person you are seeking. From 1980 to the present separate
lien book indexes have been maintained but arranged in the same
manner
.
24. Record: Release Books (Register of Deeds), 1925-present
Location: Register of Deeds Office
These volumes register releases of trusts, liens, mortgages, and
other temporary encumbrances on property. It is in this record
one finds the release indicated in the margin of the deed of
trust. The release contains the name of the trustee and reason
for the release. Releases are indexed in separate direct and
reverse volumes published for specific chronological periods
(1977-present , for example) . Each index is divided into
alphabetical pairs of letters ("AB", "CD", "EF"), and all names
beginning with these two letters appear in that section otherwise
without any alphabetical arrangement.
25. Record: Affidavit Release (Register of Deeds), 1973-1982
Location: Register of Deeds Office
This record provides a release of a lien or other temporary
encumbrance when the original trust document has been lost. It
37
contains the names of the creditor and the debtor, nature of the
obligation, amount of the obligation, and an oath that the
obligation has been met. An alphabetical listing by the last
name of the trustor appears at the front of the book.
26. Record: Developers-Subdividers Index (Register of Deeds),
1935-present
Location: Register of Deeds Office
The index contains cards for each developer/subdivider or
property, the property name and/or location, its civil district
number, plat book (listed as "pb") and/or deed book and page
(listed as "db"). The file is arranged by last nameof the
developer/subdivider.
27. Record: Restrictions [on Subdivisions] (Register of Deeds),
1804-present
Location: Register of Deeds Office
A card file index lists any restrictions on subdivions of
property, almost all of which are of recent origin. The index is
arranged alphabetically by name of the restrictor and contains
the location and civil district number of the property, the deed
book and page number on which the restriction is described.
38
28. Record: Notes of Completion. (Register of Deeds), 1970-
present
Location: Register of Deeds Office
The record lists the completion of construction, improvement, or
demolition of property and includes the name of the contractor,
the date the work was completed, and notarization. At the front
of each book is an alphabetical index by last name of the
contractor which also contains the name of the property owner.
Names do not appear in strict alphabetical order within each
letter division.
II. Taxes
29. Record: Tax Books (County Trustee), 1809-1813, 1867,
1871, 1875,
1877-present
Location: 1877-1973 (original), 1877-1935 (duplicates) &#8212;r
County Archives
1974-present (original ) --County Trustee's Office
Microfilm: 1809-1813, 1867, 1871, 1875, 1877-1963--TSL&amp;A,
Register of Deeds
Tax records convey the most precise information about buildings
of all county records. The books are created annually and are
arranged by civil district number with entries appearing randomly
by last name of the property owner. They are not indexed.
Beside each property owner's name appears a series of columns
39
listing the location of the property, number and value of town
lots (if any), number of acres of farm land, value of the land,
value of other personal property, amount of state and county
taxes owed, and the date the taxes were paid. The original tax
books also contain property descriptions, which the duplicate tax
books omit. These descriptions are often detailed and in the
case of city buildings may include improvements to property to
explain tax assessment increases.
30. Record: Minutes [of Tax Cases] (Chancery Court),
1851-1856, 1899-1901
Location: County Archives
The volume contains pre-printed forms for registering state
actions against defendants in delinquent tax cases. The form
lists the name of the defendant, nature of the court's decree,
and the report of the Clerk and Master in the case. The volumes
provide an alphabetical listing in the front by last name of the
defendant, though names do not appear in strict alphabetical
order within each letter division.
31. Record: Delinquent Tax Docket (Chancery Court), 1904
Location: County Archives
The docket lists delinquent tax property assumed by the state and
40
conveys a description of the property, whether the property was
redeemed and if so by whom, the amount of taxes owed, date and
decree of the court. An alphabetical index appears at the front
of the volumes by last name of the delinquent tax payer; names do
not appear in strict alphabetical order within each letter
division of the index.
32. Record: Sale Book (Chancery Court), 1920-1937
Location: County Archives
The Court maintained this record of land sold because of failure
to pay delinquent taxes. It contains the name of the court,
title of the case, location and description of the property sold,
by what process the property was sold, the name of the purchaser,
and the amount of tax collected as a result of the sale. The
volumes are indexed alphabetically by last name of defendant, but
names do not appear in each letter category by strict
alphabetical order.
33. Record: Sale Book (Circuit Court), 1896-1897, 1900,
1907-1913
Location: County Archives
The Circuit Court record is much like that of the Chancery Court,
Here we have an indication of the apparent overlapping of court ,
41
jurisdictions. All sales of property ordered by the Circuit
Court are recorded here in much the same manner as in Chancery
Court ordered sales.
34. Record: Land Sold for Taxes (County Court Clerk),
1897-1918
Location: County Clerk's Office
Microfilm: 1897-1918&#8212;at TSL&amp;A, County Clerk's Office
III. Wills and Estates
35. Record: Record Books [Wills] (County Court Clerk), 1804-
present
Location: 1804-present (original, some xeroxes) &#8212;County
Clerk's Office
1804-1820, 1827&#8212;County Archives
Microfilm: Indexes; 1804-1914&#8212;TSL&amp;A, County Clerk
Indexes; 1804-1914--Linebaugh Library
1868-1879&#8212;MTSU
Record: Will Books (County Court Clerk), 1879-1963
Location: County Clerk's Office
Microfilm: Indexes; 1879-1963&#8212;TSL&amp;A, County Clerk
Indexes; 1879-1925&#8212;Linebaugh Library, MTSU
Record books primarily contain wills and inventories of estates,
but one can find here also records of indentures, sales, and
other transactions involving property. They are contained in
annual volumes in which the documents are arranged
42
chronologically. Each volume contains an index in the front of
the book arranged alphabetically by last name of the deceased,
the estate, owner of the indenture, etc. In addition, there is a
separate index volume for the years 1883-1947.
Wills are highly personal documents. While their writing
follows a certain formula, the way in which a person disposes of
his or her property says a great deal about the deceased's
particular social status, family and personal relationships, and
participation in civic affairs. The specific terms of the will
tell us about people who were important in the life of the
deceased including members of his or her family, friends,
neighbors, wards, and members of the extended family. Who is not
mentioned in the will is of significance, too. Often people left
bequests to civic organizations such as churches, clubs, and
schools. How much the deceased bequeathed tells much of the
person's wealth and social status as well.
Interpreting this information can be tricky. We tend to
assume that the person receiving the greatest bequest was the
person the deceased most loved. Actually, common and civil law
often regulates who gets what property, and if someone is not
mentioned in a will it may well be that the deceased had already
given him or her a bequest outside the terms of the will before
dying. Still, wills do contain fascinating hints about personal
relationships if we read these documents carefully.
43
Inventories often appear in the record books, as well.
These documents list assest and liabilities in the estate. An
asset can be a material possession like land, buildings, saleable
goods (in the case of a merchant); it can be stocks, bonds,
money, insurance policies, investments of any sort; it can also
be debts owed to the deceased. All will be included. Some
inventories even indicate furniture items from each room, thereby
illustrating at least one person's (and perhaps a common) pattern
of living.
Liabilities are any charges against the estate. In these
lists we sometimes find hints about how the individual, and
average people, lived in the past. One will, for instance,
listed debts owed to a man who painted his house, attached new
numbers on the porch, and installed a new picket fence. Prices
charged showed what the cost of living was like as well as
proving that at the time of his death houses in Murfreesboro were
numbered.
But again, interpreting this information calls for care. In
the past, historians have incorrectly assumed that the inventory
of an estate included the bulk of the deceased's possessions, and
some house museums have decided in what rooms to place particular
pieces of furniture based on inventories. But a person often
gave away much of his or her property before dying. And before a
will could be probated it was possible for family members to take
44
away prized items, thus skewing the inventory. Still, if used
carefully inventories can reveal much about an individual's life
and a community's culture.
36. Record: Executors Bonds (County Court Clerk), 1874-1960
Location: County Clerk's Office
Indexes, 1907-1914, 1910--County Archives
Microfilm: 1874-1945&#8212; TSL&amp;A, County Clerk
1906-1945&#8212;Linebaugh Library
Executors of estates were required to post a bond for faithful
fulfillment of their responsibilities. These records contain the
name of the executor and of the deceased (estate) , whether the
estate was bonded and if so the amount, dates of the court's
approval, the judge's name, county of the executor's residence,
court costs, date the estate was settled, book and page number of
the County Court Minute Books in which the settlement appears,
and often a power of attorney attached to the bond. Books are
arranged chronologically by year, and an alphabetical listing
appears at the front of each volume by last name of the
deceased. A separate index also exists in the County Archives
for the years 1907-1914 and 1910.
37. Record: Administrators Bonds (County Court Clerk),
1873-1965
Location: 1873-1900, 1910&#8212;County Archives
1900-1960&#8212;County Clerk's Office
45
Microfilm: 1873-1965&#8212;TSL&amp;A, County Clerk
These are similar to executors bonds as described above, and they
provide the same kinds of information.
38. Record: Inventory Records and Books (County Court Clerk),
1828-1829, 1883-1963
Location: County Clerk's Office
Microfilm: 1828-1829, 1883-1963&#8212;TSL&amp;A, County Clerk,
Linebaugh Library
1828-1829&#8212;MTSU
39. Record: Insolvent Estates, Minutes and Records (County
Court Clerk) , 1853-1886, 1900-1960
Location: 1853-1886, 1900-1926&#8212;County Archives
1926-1960&#8212;County Clerk's Office
Often estates lacked the resources to pay off creditors. In this
case the County Court established an administrator to handle all
assets and claims. This record lists transactions in such
cases. The left hand page includes a record of the court
proceedings in the matter. The right hand page lists the name of
the deceased, name of the administrator, the case number, how the
case was proven, the names of all creditors with the balance due
each one plus interest, and the name of the receiver for the
account. Volumes from 1900 to 1960 are indexed in the front of
each volume, with alphabetical lists of the last name of the
deceased. Within each letter division of the index names do not
46
appear in strict alphabetical order
40. Record: Administrative Rule Docket (County Court Clerk),
1939-1942
Location: County Archives
This records claims against administered estates listing the name
and address of the administrator and name and former address of
the deceased, the date the case was filed, pleadings, exceptions,
orders of the court and dates they were filed, court costs, and
the reason for assessing costs against the estate, names of
creditors, amounts of their claims, and remarks. Pages often
include newspaper clippings of public notices regarding the
settlement of the estate. Each book contains, in the front, an
alphabetical index by last name of trhe deceased, though names do
not appear within each letter division in strict alphabetical
order
.
41. Record: Claims Against Estates (County Court Clerk),
1921-1929, 1959-present
Location: 1921-1929&#8212;County Archives
1959-present&#8212;County Clerk's Office
Microfilm: 1921-1929&#8212;TSL&amp;A, County Clerk
As the name suggests, these documents list all claims made
against estates and contain the name of the deceased, date the
claim was filed and by whom, type and amount of the claim.
47
interest and costs, and the total amount due, as well as any
receipts made for payments toward the debt. The more recent
records (after 1959) present the same information in a simpler
format. Each volume from 1921-1929 is indexed at the front of
the book by the last name of the deceased. Records maintained by
the County Clerk's office must be requested.
42. Record: Probate Docket and Record of Claims (County Court
Clerk) , 1943-1960
Location: County Clerk's Office
Microfilm: 1939-1943, 1947-1960&#8212;TSL&amp;A, County Clerk
Very similar to the Claims Against Estates, these documents
record the name of the deceased and of the administrator or
executor, the deceased's former place of residence, amount of the
bond issued, names and addresses of creditors, nature of the
claim, and the amount of the claim. There is an alphabetical
listing by last name of the deceased at the front of the book,
though within each letter division names do not appear in strict
alphabetical order.
43. Record: Estate Sales (County Court Clerk) , 1883-1954
Location: County Archives
Listed here are the names of the deceased and of the
administrator, the date of the sale, items sold, who bought the
48
items, and the price paid for each. The document is indexed in
the front by an alphabetical listing by last name oaf the
deceased; again, names do not appear in strict alphabetical order
within each letter division.
44. Record: Distribution of Estates Book (County Court
Clerk) , 1900-1904
Location: County Archives
This volume contains receipts made to the county court clerk for
money he paid out in transacting the business of the court which
included payments made in estate settlements, sales of land to
settle estate cases, etc. The record contains the date of
payment, clerk's signature, names of plaintiffs and defendants,
amount of payment, and the reason for the payment. At the front
of the volume is an alphabetical listing of plaintiffs showing
the page number on which receipts for that case may be found.
45. Record: Estate Settlements (County Court Clerk),
1883-present
Location: County Clerk's Office
These records list receipts and payments made to settle the debts
of estates. Each document includes the name of the deceased
(estate), total debts of the estate, names of creditors,
deceased's holdings, time and date of filing the claim, a list of
49
heirs and their relationship to the deceased along with each
one's share of the estate, and a record of disbursements of
money. A separate index exists for books 1 through 9 (to 1949)
listing the names of the deceased in alphabetical groupings, but
not alphabetically within each letter division. From 1949 to the
present an index is located at the front of each volume.
46. Record: Administrator's Settlements (County Court Clerk),
1868-1889
Location: County Clerk's Office
Microfilm: 1868-1889&#8212;TSL&amp;A, County Clerk
47. Record: Administrators and Executors Minute Books (County
Court Clerk) , 1876-1909
Location: County Clerk's Office
Microfilm: 1876-1909~TSLS&lt;A, County Clerk
48. Record: Inheritance Record (County Court Clerk), 1898-1919
Location: County Clerk's Office
This is a record of payments of inheritance taxes providing the
name of the deceased (estate) , the date the inheritance tax was
paid, the type of property in the estate, amount of tax paid, who
paid it, and the number of heirs. This record is not indexed.
50
BUSINESS INFORMATION
49. Record: Merchants License Applications and Oaths (County
Court Clerk), 1836-1860, 1870-1899
Location: County Archives
Each merchant had to post apply for a license in order to engage
in business, and these invaluable documents record these. The
include the type of license applied for, the name of the
applicant, duration of the license, date the application was
filed, signature of the applicant, and often an oath of a referee
attesting to the soundness of the applicant. Licenses from 1870
through 1884 also provide the place of business and amounts of
state, county, and school taxes paid. The volumes are arranged
chronologically with no index. The 1898-1899 volume also is
arranged by type of business, and the first 89 pages of this book
are indexed alpha- betically by name of applicant.
50. Record: Merchants Bonds (County Court Clerk), 1842-1848,
1872-1904, 1908-1920
Location: 1842-1848, 1872-1877, 1889-1892, 1896-1904, 1898-
1899, 1908-1920--County Archives
Microfilm: 1842-1848, 1873-1888, 1892-1903--TSL&amp;A, County Clerk
These records provide the name of the merchant bonded, the date
when the bond was presented, and the amount of the bond. All
51
volumes except those for 1842- 1848 and 1898-1899 are indexed at
the front of the book alphabetically by last name of the
merchant, and then within each letter division chronologically by
date of the bond.
51. Record: License Expirations (County Court Clerk) , 1879-
1901 [now called the Business Tax Book records
exist in the County Clerk's Office for 1971-1974]
Location: 1879-1901&#8212;County Archives
The expirations contain the name of the licensee, the type of
business being licensed, and the expiration date of the license.
The recent Business Tax Book includes the date of the license,
license number, description and name of the business, expiration
date of the license, class of the business, license minimum, and
the amount of the fee. An alphabetical index by last name of
license holder appears at the front of the volumes, but within
each letter division names appear chronologically by date of the
license rather than in strict alphabetical order.
52. Record: Partnership Agreements (Register of Deeds), 1804-
present
Location: Register of Deeds Office
A file card index lists partnerships, agreements that appear in
the Trust Deeds. Each card, arranged alphabetically by name of
52
partners or of partnerships, contains the book and page number of
the trust deeds on which the agreement appears.
53. Record: Charters (Register of Deeds), 1804-present
Location: Register of Deeds Office
A file card index lists the book, and page number in the trust
deeds on which appears the charter of organizations including the
name of the corporation, its purpose, status (for profit or
not-for-profit), and powers of the board of directors. It also
often includes the names of the founding members.
54. Record: Dentist Register (County Court Clerk), 1891-1919
Location: County Archives
The register lists all dentists, the county in Tennessee in which
he previously practiced, the date of registration, names of the
president and secretary of the State Board of Dental Examiners
who registered him to practice, and the date the license was
filed. The record is not indexed. Certificates are listed
chronological ly
.
55. Record: Physician's Register (County Court Clerk), 1907-
1962
Location: 1907-1946&#8212;County Archives
1947-1962&#8212;County Clerk
53
Microfilm: 1907-1962&#8212;TSL&amp;A, County Clerk
License certificates for physicians contain the physician's
license number, name, the college from which the physician
graduated, the date of his diploma, date the license was issued,
names of the president and secretary of the State Board, amount
of the license fee, and the date the certificate was recorded.
In the front of the volume is an alphabetical listing by last
name of the physician.
56. Record: Contractor Licenses (County Court Clerk), 1980-
present
Location: County Clerk's Office
This is a book of preprinted forms with actual licenses taped
into the book. The license contains the name of the company, the
date the license was recorded, and the date of the license. An
alphabetical listing of contractors appears in the front of the
volume.
57. Record: Beverage Bonds (County Court Clerk) , 1952-1958
Location: County Archives
These are bonds of surety presented by persons seeking a license
to sell alchoholic beverages. Each contains the name of the
licensee, the surety, an address where the beverage will be sold,
'the name of the deceased, the date the inheritance tax was paid, the
type of property in the estate, amount of tax paid, who paid it,
and the number of heirs. This record is not indexed.
5^
the day the license was signed, amount of the bond, the state
registration number, and the county permit number. An
alphabetical listing appears at the front of the volume by last
name of distributor.
eg Record: Liquor Shipments Record (County Court Clerk),
1915-1916
Location: County Archives
Liquor shipments received in the county are recorded including
the date received, the type of liquor shipped, date of the
shipment, destination, the quantity of liquor, name and address
of shipper, number of the waybill (the document describing the
shipment) , name and address of deliverer, and the name of the
receiver. The record is not indexed.
&#163;.^, Record: Privilege Licenses (County Court Clerk) , 1884-
-^-^' 1909
Location: County Clerk's Office
Microfilm: 1884-1909&#8212;TSL&amp;A, County Clerk
5''
BUSINESS AND PROFESSIONAL INFORMATION
60. Record: Merchants License Applications and Oaths (County
Court Clerk) , 1836-1860, 1870-1899
Location: County Archives
Each merchant had to apply for a license in order to
engage in business, and these invaluable documents record
these. They include the type of license applied for, the
name of the applicant, duration of the license, date the
application was filed, signature of the applicant, and often
an oath of a referee attesting to the soundness of the
applicant. Licenses from 1870 through 1884 also provide the
place of business and amounts of state, county, and school
taxes paid. The volumes are arranged chronologically with
no index. The 1898-1899 volume also is arranged by type of
business, and the first 89 pages of this book are indexed
alphabetically by name of applicant.
Similar in nature to these are the Privilege Licenses
(1884-1909) maintained by the County Court Clerk and
available on microfilm at the Clerk's Office and at the
Tennessee State Library and Archives. These records provide
the name of the merchant, amount of state, county, and
school taxes paid, the nature of the business, number of
months the license will run, the date of the license and of
56
its expiration, the residence of the applicant, and casual
remarks. At the front of this volume is a listing of types
of business in no particular order and the page numbers on
which licenses for these enterprises appear.
61. Record: Merchants Bonds (County Court Clerk), 1842-1848,
1872-1904, 1908-1920
Location: 1842-1848, 1872-1877, 1889-1892, 1896-1904, 1898-
1899, 1908-1920&#8212;County Archives
Microfilm: 1842-1848, 1873-1888, 1892-1903&#8212;TSLS.A, County Clerk
These records provide the name of the merchant bonded, the
date when the bond was presented, and the amount of the
bond. All volumes except those for 1842- 1848 and 1898-1899
are indexed at the front of the book alphabetically by last
name of the merchant, and then within each letter division
chronologically by date of the bond.
52. Record: License Expirations (County Court Clerk), 1879-
1901 [now called the Business Tax Book records
exist in the County Clerk's Office for 1971-1974]
Location: 1879-1901&#8212;County Archives
The expirations contain the name of the licensee, the type
of business being licensed, and the expiration date of the
license. The recent Business Tax Book includes the date of
the license, license number, description and name of the
business, expiration date of the license, class of the
business, license minimum, and the amount of the fee. An
alphabetical index by last name of license holder appears at
the front of the volumes, but within each letter division
names appear chronologically by date of the license rather
than in strict alphabetical order.
63- Record: Partnership Agreements (Register of Deeds), 1804-
present
Location: Register of Deeds Office
A file card index lists partnerships, agreements that appear
in the Trust Deeds. Each card, arranged alphabetically by
name of partners or of partnerships, contains the book and
page number of the trust deeds on which the agreement
appears.
^l^ Record: Charters (Register of Deeds) , 1804-present
Location: Register of Deeds Office
A file card index lists the book and page number in the
trust deeds on which appears the charter of organizations
including the name of the corporation, its purpose, status
(for profit or not-for-profit) , and powers of the board of
directors. It also often includes the names of the founding
members
.
58
65. Record: Dentist Register (County Court Clerk), 1891-1919
Location: County Archives
The register lists all dentists, the county in Tennessee in
which he previously practiced, the date of registration,
names of the president and secretary of the State Board of
Dental Examiners who registered him to practice, and the
date the license was filed. The record is not indexed.
Certificates are listed chronologically.
66, Record: Physician's Register (County Court Clerk), 1907-
1962
Location: 1907-1946&#8212;County Archives
1947-1962~County Clerk
Microfilm: 1907-1962&#8212;TSL&amp;A, County Clerk
License certificates for physicians contain the physician's
license number, name, the college from which the physician
graduated, the date of his diploma, date the license was
issued, names of the president and secretary of the State
Board, amount of the license fee, and the date the
certificate was recorded. In the front of the volume is an
alphabetical listing by last name of the physician.
6^7. Record: Contractor Licenses (County Court Clerk), 1980-
present
Location: County Clerk's Office
This is a book of preprinted forms with actual licenses
59
taped into the book. The license contains the name of the
company, the date the license was recorded, and the date of
the license. An alphabetical listing of contractors appears
in the front of the volume.
68. Record: Beverage Bonds (County Court Clerk), 1952-1958
Location: County Archives
These are bonds of surety presented by persons seeking a
license to sell alchoholic beverages. Each contains the
name of the licensee, the surety, an address where the
beverage will be sold, the day the license was signed,
amount of the bond, the state registration number, and the
county permit number. An alphabetical listing appears at
the front of the volume by last name of distributor.
69. Record: Liquor Shipments Record (County Court Clerk).
1915-1916
Location: County Archives
Liquor shipments received in the county are recorded
including the date received, the type of liquor shipped,
date of the shipment, destination, the quantity of liquor,
name and address of shipper, number of the waybill (the
document describing the shipment) , and names and addresses
of deliverer and receiver. The record is not indexed.
60
LEGAL INFORMATION
I. Chancery Court
70, Record: Appearance Docket, 1923-1939
Location: County Archives
This record lists the first appearance of all cases in
court. It contains the date the case was filed, the names
of attorneys, the title (style) of the case, any security
posted, and any actions taken. The record is not indexed,
and cases are listed in chronological order of their
appearance before the court.
r^l^ Record: Enrollment, 1866-1888, 1892-1898
Location: County Archives
The enrollment is a list of civil cases before the chancery
court containing the names of the defendants and plaintiffs,
the cause of the legal action, dates of trial, disposal of
the case, nature and text of any process filed in the case,
and the date the case was recorded. An alphabetical index
listing the last names of plaintiffs and defendants appears
in the front of each volume, but names do not appear in
alphabetical order within each letter division.
61
oo Record: Rule Dockets, 1843-1852, 1866-1963
Location: 1843-1852, 1864-1866, 1887-1893, 1912&#8212;County
Archives
Microfilm: 1866-1963&#8212;at TSL&amp;A, Chancery Court
1866-1909&#8212;at Linebaugh Library
These are records of original processes issued and
filed relative to each case appearing before the court. It
contains the names of parties and their attorneys, the kind
of action taken, orders of the court relative to the case,
volume and page number in the minute books where the hearing
appears. The types of cases heard include divorces, writs
of injunction, collections, partition sales, forced land
sales, enforcement of liens, foreclosures, and the removal
of guardianships. All but the 1912 volume are indexed
alphabetically by last name of defendants and plaintiffs in
the front of the book, but names do not appear
alphabetically within each letter division.
Record: Trial Docket, 1897-1911
^^* Location: County Archives
The docket is the trial agenda for the court containing the
charges in each case, the names of defendants, and any
remarks. An alphabetical listing of last names of
defendants and plaintiffs appears at the front of each
volume, each page being given over to two letters ("A-B,"
, 62
-ON.-
"C-D," for example). Names are not arranged alphabetically
within each division.
74. Record: Minutes, 1845-1860, 1864-1964
Location: 1851-1855, 1900-1901&#8212;County Archives
Microfilm: 1845-1860, 1864-1964&#8212;at TSL&amp;A, Chancery Court
1873-1877 (Books K-N) &#8212;MTSU
Minutes of all trial proceedings in the chancery court
appear here. They contain for each case the names of
defendants, offenses and charges, date of the trial, verdict
of the court, and the court's sentence. Volumes for 1900
and 1901 are for tax cases only. An alphabetical listing
for all volumes other than 1900 and 1901 appears in the back
of each volume listing the last names of plaintiffs, but
names do not appear alphabetically within each letter
division.
75. Record: Exhibits, 1876-1889
Location: County Archives
The record lists trustee's payments to creditors,
principally in relation to the case of Dromgoole vs
McCul lough. Each record contains the date of the payment, to
whom paid and for what purpose, the receipt #, amount of the
payment. Also, at the end of the volume, pages 500-525,
appears a long deposition of Robert J. Tompkins in the
6-3
case. The book is not indexed.
76. Record: Judgment Index Book, 1916-1949
Location: County Archives
A list of judgments, this contains the name of the person
ordered to pay a judgment, the date of payment, the case's
docket number, the cause of the judgment (case citation),
and the amount of the payment. An alphabetical index lists
the name of persons orderes to pay judgments, and directs
the reader to the minute book and page number where the case
record appears.
r^r^
^ Record: Execution Docket, 1871-1893, 1899-1935
Location: County Archives
Execution dockets record financial transactions in each case
before the chancery court containing the date of the court's
term, the names of parties involved, the title (style) of
the case, nature of actions taken, amount of judgments
rendered, and the amount and date paid. An alphabetical
arrangement of last names of defendants appears in the front
of each book, though names do not appear alphabetically
within each letter division.
64
78. Record: Miscellaneous Bond Book, 1921-1933
Location: County Archives
This is a record of bonds posted for various purposes in
action before the court. Each record contains the names of
the principals and their sureties, the title of the case,
amount and date of the bond, and the specific condition the
bond was intended to ensure. An alphabetical listing by
last name of each person bonded appears at the front of each
volume, though names do not appear in alphabetical order
within each letter division.
79. Record: Distribution Docket, 1887-1905, 1919-1921, 1937-
1940
Location: County Archives
These volumes are records of funds belonging to an estate or
collected by the court and then distributed to creditors.
Each record lists the case number, names of parties in the
case, the date, judgment rendered by the court, costs of the
court, receipts, and testimentary letters. An alphabetical
listing of last names of defendants or deceased (in the case
of estates) appears at the front of each volume, but names
do not appear in strict alphabetical order within each
letter division.
80. Record: Cash Book, 1929-1938
e&gt;5
Location: County Archives
Daily records of receipts listing on the left page the date
of the receipt, the title of the case, and the amount of
money received and on the right page the date, from whom
money has been collected, the check number, and the amount.
These records are not indexed.
81- Record: Cash Journal, 1877-1887
Location: County Archives
Record of receipts and disbursements by the Clerk and Master
showing the date of receipt, the amount received, the source
of the money and for what purpose it was paid, the amount of
the debit or credit in the account, the name of the account,
and the person or case to whom the money is to be credited.
These records are not indexed.
82. Record: Ledger, 1886
Location: County Archives
Record of receipts and disbursements of money acquired
through litigation including the date the money was received
or disbursed, from whom it was received or to whom it was
disbursed, the amount, by whom it was received or disbursed,
and a list of items purchased with the money. These records
are not indexed.
ee
II. Circuit Court
83- Record: Appearance Docket, 1807-1808, 1833-1836
Location: County Archives
Records the first appearance of all cases in court,
containing the date the case was filed, names of attorneys,
the title of the case, any bond that may have been posted,
and actions taken in the case. The volumes are not indexed,
each case being recorded in chronological order.
84. Record: Enrollment Book, 1845-1847, 1855-1858, 1864-1886
Location: County Archives
Copies of original processes relating to civil cases before
the court. Each contains the names of plaintiffs and
defendants, causes of legal action, dates of trials held in
the matter, final disposition of the case, nature and text
of the process, and the day the case was recorded. Some
records include bills and petitions, answers and pleas, and
depositions. The records for 1864-1886 are indexed
chronologically and then alphabetically by the last name of
the defendant, showing the page number of the docket in
which the case is listed.
.67,
85- Record: Rule Docket, 1923-1948
Location: County Archives
These volumes record state (criminal) cases before the court
showing the names of defendants, offenses and charges
against them, defendants' attorneys, state witnesses, the
justice of the peace involved, any bonds posted, nature of
the indictment or presentment returned from the grand jury,
subpeonas issued for state witnesses, grand jury term that
indicted the defendant, mileage, term, attendance record of
jurors, and remarks. Types of charges brought included
murder, larceny, manufacture of whiskey, etc.
Q^ Record: Trial Docket, 1816-1818, 1867-1871, 1874 (index
only), 1881-1915
Location: County Archives
Record of all cases set for trial containing the date of the
court term, the case number, names of attorneys, plaintiffs,
defendants, date the case was filed, rules and orders of the
court. The volumes are not indexed.
87. Record: General Index to Civil [Criminal] Minutes and
Execution Docket, 1893, 1952
Location: Circuit Court
Microfilm: TSLfi.A, Circuit Court, Linebaugh Library
An index by title of case (defendants and plaintiffs) for
- 68
trials appearing before the Circuit Court.
QP, Record: Civil or Criminal Minutes, 1849-1851, 1865-1892,
1898-1963
Location: 1i_cuit Court
Microfilm: 1849-1851, 1865-1892, 1898-1963&#8212;at TSL&amp;A,
Circuit Court
1873-1883&#8212;at MTSU
1849-1903&#8212;at Linebaugh Library
Trial minutes for cases appearing before the Circuit Court.
Record: Minute Book, 1879-1898, 1913-1915
Location: 1879-1890&#8212;County Archives
Microfilm: 1890-1898, 1913-1915&#8212;TSL&amp;A, Circuit Court
Minutes of trials containing the proceedings, names of
defendants, offenses charged, date of the trial, verdict of
the jury, and the sentence of the court. An alphabetical
index by last name of the defendants appears at the
beginning of each book.
90. Record: Recognizance, 1885-1886, 1889
Location: County Archives
This records bonds posted to assure one's appearance in
court, and it contains the names of defendants, sureties
(the holder of the bond) , the sum owed to the state, the
date of appearance in court, charges against the defendant,
69
and the clerk's name. In the front of the book is an
alphabetical listing of defendants by first letter of the
last name, but names do not appear alphabetically within
each letter division.
91- Record: Jury Book, 1936-1958
Location: County Archives
A record of jurors serving in cases before the circuit court
showing the date of the court term, the title of the case,
the nature of action being taken or the offense, and the
names of jurors. This volume is not indexed.
92. Record: Jury List, 1826-1841, 1898-1933, 1935, 1959-1965
Location: County Archives
Microfilm: 1826-1841&#8212;at TSL&amp;A, Circuit Court
These volumes list jurors and the dates they served on the
jury. There is no index, and names appear in chronological
order by date of their service.
93. Record: Witness Book, 1866-1893
Location: County Archives
The information conveyed varies over the years, but in
general these records contain names of parties in trials,
types of cases reported and charges made, days the witness
70
served and the distance he or she traveled to appear. In
the front of the book is an alphabetical listing by last
name of the witness, but names do not appear alphabetically
within each letter division.
9^. Record: Judgment Book, 1869-1873, 1880-1912, 1929-1948
Location: County Archives
A record of judgments rendered by the circuit court
containing the book and page numbers of the docket in which
the case is recorded, the number and title of the case,
names of plaintiffs and defendants, the judgment rendered in
the case, and the amount of the court's costs. Indexes are
arranged alphabetically by last name of defendant and
plaintiff, though names do not appear alphabetically within
each letter division.
95- Record: Execution Docket: Civil, 1855-1861, 1866-1948
Location: 1855-1861&#8212;Circuit Court
1866-1948&#8212;County Archives
Microfilm: 1855-1861&#8212;at TSL&amp;A, Circuit Court
Financial records of trials in civil cases showing the date
of the court term, the title of the case, the nature of the
action taken in each case, the amount of the judgment and
court costs, and the amount and date of payment. Execution
dockets are indexed with the court minutes (see record #66
71
above)
.
96. Record: Execution Docket: Criminal, 1855-1861, 1873,
1877-1923, 1928-1938
Location: 1855-1861&#8212;Circuit Court
1873, 1877-1923, 1928-1938&#8212;County Archives
Financial records of transactions in criminal cases showing
the date of the court term, the title of the case, nature of
the action taken or charges made, the amount of any judgment
and court costs, and the amount and date of payment.
Execution dockets are indexed with the court minutes (see
record #65 above.)
97. Record: Cash Journal, 1957-1962
Location: County Archives
Record of receipts and disbursements for accounts involving
court action showing the date, the amount of disbursement
from money received and the reason for the payment, the
amount of the debit or credit, name of the account and bank
where the account is located, and the person or the case
being credited. These records are not indexed.
Record: Grand Jury Docket, 1902-1903
Location: County Archives
72
This lists actions placed before the grand jury including
the names of defendants, offenses with which they were
charged, and the date of the indictment or finding of no
true bill. This record is not indexed.
no Record: Grand Jury Notes, 1889-1901, 1905-1908,
1911-1922, 1927-1930
Location: County Archives
These are random notes made by grand jury members during
deliberations on disposition of cases. They are not
indexed.
III. County Judge and County Court
100. Record: Juvenile Court Records (County Judge), 1912, 1937
Location: County Archives
These are records of cases before the juvenile court,
originally under the jurisdiction of the County Judge. They
provide the date, number and title of the case, offenses
charged, the age, race, and sex of the defendant, orders of
the court, dates of arrest and trial of the defendant, and
the final disposition of the case. The 1937 volume is
indexed in the front of the book by last name of the
defendant.
73
102. Record: Bills of Cost, 1911-1916, 1934-1958
Location: County Archives
A record of payments in court cases containing the name of
the defendant, the date of sentencing and the offense, from
what court the defendant was sentenced, name of the officer,
amount of the fine, whether the defendant was sent to the
road detail, costs of the justice of the peace, the
officer's costs, cash paid, and any remarks. This record is
not indexed.
103. Record: Enrollment Docket [Cases], 1867-1893
Location: County Archives
Microfilm: Index, 1867-1893&#8212;at TSL&amp;A, County Clerk,
Linebaugh Library
Index, 1867-1872&#8212;at MTSU
A narrative record of proceedings principally in disputes
over land and sales before the county court, containing the
names of plaintiffs and defendants, a description of events
and circumstances relevant to the case, and a record of the
court's final disposition. A separate index was maintained
listing names of defendants and plaintiffs alphabetically by
last name, but names do not appear in alphabetical order
within each letter division.
7^
10/+. Record: Rule Docket, 1818-1821, 1828-1842, 1851-1909,
1918-1949
Location: 1818-1821, 1828-1842, 1851-1909, 1808-1949&#8212;
County Archives
1918-1949&#8212;County Clerk
Microfilm: 1918-1949&#8212;at TSL&amp;A, County Clerk
A listing of suits for sale of land, partitioning of
estates, and habeas corpus showing names of petitioners and
defendants, the date of the petition and of the hearing,
names of jurors, names of attorneys, dates when bonds were
filed (if any), decree of the court, and the final
disposition of the case. Some volumes are indexed at the
front by last name of defendants and petitioners.
105. Record: Execution Docket, 1865-1878, 1924-1950
Location: County Archives
A record of judgments rendered in the county court showing
the term and year of the court, names of parties involved,
the court's judgment and costs, amounts paid and when
payments were paid. Volumes for 1924-1950 are indexed at
the front of each book alphabetically by last name of
plaintiff, though names do not appear alphabetically within
each letter division.
106. Record: Jury Claims, 1856-1885
Location: County Archives
75.
Lists of jurors serving on cases before the county court
arranged chronologically by the dates of their service
showing their names, dates of service, and amounts due to
them. These records are not indexed.
1.07.. Record: Cash Journal, 1918-1936, 1968-1973
Location: County Archives
A record of receipts and disbursements by the clerk of the
probate and quarterly courts showing the date, from whom
money was received, the title of the case, and the amount
received. If the money collected is to satisfy a state tax,
the specific tax satisfied is also indicated. The 1918-1936
records are indexed by an alphabetical listing in the front
of the volumes by the last names of defendants and
plaintiffs, but names do not appear alphabetically within
each letter division.
108. Record: Trial Sessions, 1807-1808
Location: County Clerk
Microfilm: 1807-1808&#8212;at TSL&amp;A, County Clerk, Linebaugh
Library
A listing of court cases containing the names of parties,
the cause of action taken, the name of sureties, rules and
orders of the court. This volume is not indexed.
76
109. Record: Trial Docket, 1842-1852
Location: County Clerk
Microfilm: 1842-1852&#8212;at TSL&amp;A, County Clerk, Linebaugh
Library
A record of trials before the County Court listing the date
of trial, the case #, parties involved, the amount of
judgment, names of returning officers, bills of cost, and
the date of the execution order.
IV. General Sessions Court
A^r. Record: Magistrates Docket: Civil Cases, 1842-1852,
1884-1947
Location: County Archives
Record of trials before the General Sessions Court showing
the date of the trial, the case number, names of plaintiffs
and defendants, the decision of the court, amount of the
court's judgment and the court costs. Some volumes are
indexed at the front alphabetically by the last name of the
plaintiffs.
111. Record: Magistrates Docket: Criminal Cases, 1901-1947
Location: County Archives
A record of criminal trials showing the date of the trial,
the case number, names of defendants, action of the court,
11
and a list of witnesses claiming fees. Some volumes have an
alphabetical index at the front of the volume by last name
of defendants. The index provides the case number, not the
page number.
78,
ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION
This section of the guide describes records associated with
the administration of county government. Here one finds the
principal records of the county court acting as a legislature,
receipts and disbursements of county agencies, bonds and oaths of
appointed county officials, and other records like these.
Records in this section are arranged by the county agency that
created them.
112. Record: Receipts for Papers (Chancery Court), 1911-1924
Location: County Archives
This records files and papers removed from the court office by
lawyers for their review and then returned, containing a list of
the specific items removed and the date removed, the name of the
borrower, the case name or number, and the date the material was
removed. An alphabetical listing appears at the beginning of the
book giving the last names of borrowers; each page indexes two
letters, but names do not appear in alphabetical order within
each two letter division.
113. Record: Minutes of the County Board of Health (Circuit
Court Clerk) , 1930-1964
Location: Circuit Court
79
Microfilm: 1930-1964&#8212;at TSL&amp;A, Circuit Court
These minutes record the deliberations of the County Board of
Health under the authority of the Circuit Court.
im. Record: Index to Minute Books (County Court Clerk)
,
1804-present
Location: 1804-present&#8212;County Clerk
1804-1824 (Books A-T) &#8212;County Archives
Microfilm: 1804-1963&#8212;at TSL&amp;A, County Clerk, Linebaugh
Library
1804-1898&#8212;MTSU
115., Record: Minute Books (County Court Clerk) , 1804-present
Location: County Clerk's Office
Microfilm: 1804-1962&#8212;TSL&amp;A, County Clerk
1804-1904&#8212;Linebaugh Library
1804-1898&#8212;MTSU
This is the official record of the county court containing
debates and discussions on all matters pertaining to the
legislative functions of this body. The bound indexes are
arranged A manuscript index to books A through T
is maintained in the County Archives, but it is in very fragile
condition. Fortunately, it has been microfilmed, so the original
will not have to be used. This index is confusing to use since
each letter division begins on one set of pages and then
continues farther along in the index. So anyone using this
document must be careful to review the entire index to find the
subject for which he or she is looking.
80
116. Record: Index to Quarterly Meetings (County Court Clerk)
1880-present
Location: County Clerk's Office
Microfilm: 1880-1963&#8212;at TSL&amp;A, County Clerk, Linebaugh
Library, MTSU
117-. Record: Quarterly Minute Books (County Court Clerk),
1879-present
Location: County Clerk's Office
Microfilm: 1879-1963&#8212;at TSL&amp;A, County Clerk,
1879-1918&#8212;at Linebaugh Library
1879-1899&#8212;at MTSU
As with the daily minutes, these record the proceedings of the
quarterly court
118. Record: Magistrates Bonds and Oaths (County Court Clerk)
,
1872-1911, 1942-1956
Location: County Clerk's Office
Magistrates were required to swear an oath of faithful service
and to post a bond to ensure that, and this volume records such
oaths and bonds. Volumes to 1942 are indexed alphabetically at
the front of the book by last name of the magistrate, but names
do not appear alphabetically within each letter division.
119. Record: Notary Public Bonds (County Court Clerk),
1947-present
Location: 1947-1952--County Archives
1953-present&#8212;County Clerk's Office
Notaries were required to post a bond to ensure fulfillment of
81
their duties, and these volumes record these bonds and oaths.
They contain the name of the notary, the surety company, the date
of the certificate, and the date the commission expires. An
alphabetical listing at the front of the book contains the last
names of notaries, but names do not appear alphabetically within
each letter division.
120.. Record: Revenue Docket (County Court Clerk) , 1828-1900,
1961-present
Location: 1828-1900&#8212;County Archives
1961-present--County Clerk's Office
This is a general ledger accounting for sales tax revenues and
the distribution of moneys including the date of the transaction,
the name of the firm or individual from whom money was received,
the nature of the sale, duration of the license, disposition of
the tax to state and county funds, the total amount of the tax
paid, and the clerk's fee. These records are not indexed.
121. Record: Warrant Register (County Court Clerk) , 1899-1930
Location: County Archives
A record of disbursements of county money on warrant (bills)
showing the warrant number, to whom the payment is made and for
what purpose, the amount paid, and the date the warrant was
issued.
82
122.- Record: Cash Journal (County Court Clerk), 1918-1936,
1968-1973
Location: County Archives
This records all cash receipts and disbursements by the County
Court Clerk as a state revenue agent and as a clerk of the
probate and quarterly court. It contains the date of payments,
the name of the person paying and the purpose of the payment, the
amount, the account to which the payment is credited, and the
amount deposited. Records of disbursement show the date, the
name of the payee, the purpose of the payment and amount paid,
bank withdrawals, and the current balance in the account. The
record was succeeded by the Daily Cash Record Book. Each volume
from 1918-1936 contains an index of transactions in chronological
order. Other volumes are not indexed.
123^ Record: Daily Cash Record (County Court Clerk)
,
1960-1972
Location: County Clerk's Office
124. Record: Index to Sales Record Books (County Court
Clerk)
Sales Record Books (County Court Clerk)
,
1883-1954
Location: County Clerk's Office
Microfilm: Index, 1883-1954&#8212;at TSL&amp;A, County Clerk,
83
-125
Linebaugh Library
Record: Audit Report (County Court Clerk) , 1916-1925
Location: County Archives
Annual audit reports appear here containing remarks and
statements on how well each county official was maintaining
records
.
126. Record: Road Orders (County Court Clerk), 1871-1893
Location: County Archives
The volume contains all orders of the county court relative to
road work done in the county including the appointment of road
overseers, juries of view which served in condemnation
proceedings, and authorizations for classifications of roads.
There is an alphabetical index in the front of the book by the
last names of road commissioners. The index only covers pages
336 to the end.
127. Record: Road Bond Book (County Court Clerk) , 1881-1887
Location: County Archives
This record contains contracts between road commissioners, the
County Judge, and contractors and contains the names of
84
commissioners, the County Judge, and contractors, the road
district number, location of road sections to be covered by the
contract, the descriptions of any bridges included, cash
allowanced allowable to contractors, the date of the contract,
sureties, and the date of the bond. An alphabetical index by
last name of the person bonded appears at the front of the
volume, but names do not appear alphabetically within each letter
division.
1PQ Record: Road Appointment Book (County Court Clerk)
,
1889-1890
Location: County Archives
This volume is a record of appointments of road overseers
containing the road district number, name of the road, the names
of road teams, the width and specification of the road, the date
of appointment, name of the overseer, names of road hands, minute
book citation, and the date of appointment. The record is not
indexed.
129.. Record: Index to Files (County Court Clerk), 1924-1941
Location: County Clerk's Office
Microfilm: 1924-1941&#8212;at TSL&amp;A, County Clerk
85
5^30. Record: Receivable Warrants (County Judge), 1954-1955
Location: County Archives
These are stubs of duplicates of money receipts for funds
received by the county showing the date, the warrant number, the
amount of money received, by whom it was received and to whom it
was distributed, and the name of the Judge. The record is not
indexed.
131, Record: Warrant Register (County Judge), 1915-1939
Location: County Archives
This is a record of warrants registered for general county
expenditures showing the name of the claimant, the date and
number of the warrant, and then categories of specific
disbursements. These include items such as the justice of the
peace's per diem, circuit court bills of cost for jail accounts,
interest, and county farm expenditures, election commission
costs, expenses keeping vital statistics, miscellaneous purposes,
and then a column for total amounts. This record is not
indexed.
132. Record: Receipt Book (County Trustee), 1891
Location: County Archives
The volume contains duplicate receipts for revenue collected, and
86
it contains the name of the payee, the date money was received,
the amount and purpose of the payment, the account to which it
was credited, and the signature of the clerk. receipts include
moneys collected through various taxes and funding programs, and
this is indicated in the record. The volume is not indexed.
133. Record: Cash Journal (County Trustee) , 1920-1954
Location: County Archives
A record of recipts and disbursements including the date of the
transaction, the amount and source of money or purpose of the
payment, the amount of debit or credit, the account to which the
money is credited or charged. The record shows the purpose of
the disbursement including payments to state and county officials
and agencies, payments for schools, roads, health agencies,
libraries, the milk plant, and others. The record is not
indexed.
I3Z4,, Record: School Fund Book (County Trustee), 1870-1895,
1923-1924
Location: County Archives
Microfilm: 1870-1895&#8212;at TSL&amp;A, County Trustee
These are Trustee's receipts and a record of disbursements of
school funds showing the date, the amount paid or disbursed, and
the source of the money collected, the warrant number, the amount
^7
and purpose of the disbursement. The record is not indexed.
135' Record: Account Book (Department of Education),
1927-1929
Location: County Archives
The book records the nature and amount of supplies provided from
the central school office to schools in district 16, and it
contains some school census information. It is not indexed.
j^-^^ Record: Notebook (Department of Education), 1913
Location: County Archives
The notebook contains statistics on the number of white and
black, male and female students in county schools representing an
informal school census showing changes in school population from
1912 to 1913.
13^. Record: School Board Minutes (Department of Education),
1929-present
Location: ?
Microfilm: 1929-present&#8212;at TSL&amp;A, ?
138. . Record: School Superintendent's Correspondence
(Department of Education) , 1945-1947
Location: ?
Microfilm: 1945-1947&#8212;at TSL&amp;A, ?
139. Record: Note-Books (Register of Deeds), 1931-present
Location: Register's Office
This is the receiving book for all instruments (deeds, bonds,
etc.) arriving at the Register's office. It shows the name of
the grantor and the grantee, the date, and where the original
record went (to whom it was delivered). The record is not
indexed.</dc:description>
<dc:description>A resource for local geneaological researchers introducing them to historical research of documents generally, and to Rutherford County documentary resources specifically</dc:description>
<dc:description>Foreword -- How to use County records for research -- Recording Information -- Personal Information -- Property Information -- Business Information -- Legal Information -- Administrative Information -- Materials in Linebaugh Library</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>county records; historical research; geneaology</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>177 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-01-26</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication32ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/157</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>