<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Rutherford County, Tennessee abstracts of record books 1 - 7 1803 - 1829</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Daniel, Susan G.</dc:creator>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>199?</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1800-1809; 1810-1819; 1820-1829;</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>Abstracted by:
Susan G. Daniel
County Genealogist
Rutherford County, Tennessee
Rutherford County Historical Society
Publication No. 36
Digitized by the Internet Archive
in 2010 with funding from
Lyrasis Members and Sloan Foundation
http://www.archive.org/details/publication36ruth
I.
Rutherford County Historical Society
Publication No. 36
Published by the
Rutherford County Historical Society
Officers
President Charles L. Nored
Vice President Neil Blankenship
Recording Secretary Ed DeBoer
Treasurer Mary Cox
Publication No. 36 is distributed to members of the Society. The annual mem-bership
dues are $15.00 per family, which includes the annual publication and
the monthly Newsletter to all members. Additional copies of this and other
publications may be obtained by writing to the Society. A list of publications
available is included in this publication.
All correspondence concerning additional copies, contributions to future
issues, and membership should be addressed to:
Rutherford County Historical Society
P.O. Box 906 MTSU Library
Murfreesboro, TN 37133-0906 Middle Tennessee State University
&#8226; &#171;.._&#8226; ~w^r^ Tonnp&lt;?s&#171;e 37132
io-
Publication No. 36 of the Rutherford County Historical Society
is dedicated in memory of
SUE MUNGER RAGLAND
Sue was among the first members of our society, past-president (1975-1976)
and an outstanding supportive member through the years.
Dedication of this book is only a small token of a great appreciation
to a wonderfully wise, dedicated LADY with a brilliant smile.
The Rutherford County Historical Society
would like to express its appreciation to
for researching and writing
this manuscript.
The following publications are for sale by:
THE RUTHERFORD COUNTY HISTORICAL SOCIETY
P.O. Box 906
Murfreesboro, TN 37 133-0906
(All publications are $5.00 + $2.00 postage and handling)
Publication 1
Publication 2
Publication 3
Publication 4
Publication 5
Publication 6
Publication 7
Publication 8
Publication 9:
Rutherford County Marriage Records,
(1851-1853), Bride Index, Rutherford County
Militia Commissions 1807-1811, Rutherford
County Offices and Officers (1804-1973), and
Union: Murfreesboro ' s Other University.
Rutherford County Marriage Records,
(1854-1856), Bride Index (continued),
Rutherford County Militia Commissions
1812-1820, Mayors of Murfreesboro, and a
History of the Kittrell Community.
Rutherford County Marriage Records
(1857-1860), Bride Index, Griffith
Rutherford, 1803 Census of Rutherford County,
and Rutherford County Militia Records
.
History of Readyville, Artists Depict Battle
of Stones River, and Census of 1810 and List
of Taxpayers not in Census.
The Nashville and Chattanooga Railroad
(1845-1872), Rutherford County Post Offices
and Postmasters, and the Rutherford Rifles.
A History of the Link Community, History of
Lavergne, Fellowship Church and Community,
and The Sanders Family.
Hopewell Church, Petition by Cornelius Sanders
for Revolutionary War Pension.
History of Bethel-Leanna Community, the
Crowders of Readyville, A view of the
Battlefield of Stones River from New York
Times (Sept. 2, 1865), Record of Jordan
Williford, Revolutionary War Soldier from
Records in U.S. Pension Office, Company Roll
of Major Hardy Murfree (Sept. 9, 1778 from
the National Archives )
.
History of Dilton Community.
Publication 10: 1864 Diary, Peter Jennings, Henderson Yoakum,
Early Methodist Church, and Overall.
Publication 11:
Publication 12:
Publication 13:
Publication 14:
Publication 15:
Publication 16:
Publication 17:
Publication 18:
Publication 19:
Publication 20:
Publication 21:
Publication 22:
Publication 23:
State Capitol, Ben McCullough, Petition of
Michael Lorance, Country Store, and Soule
College.
History of Smyrna, Sewart Air Force Base,
Goochland, Index of Some Actual Wills of
Rutherford County, 1802-1882.
Tennessee College, Coleman Scouts, New
Monuments in Old City Cemetery, and James
Bole's Revolutionary War Pension.
Murfreesboro Presbyterian Church, Kirks and
Montgomerys, Russell Home, John Lytle's and
John M. Leak's Revolutionary War Pension.
John W. Childress Home (1847), Whigs in
Rutherford County (1835-1845).
Hart, Childress, Miles, Fosterville, Cherry
Shade, William Cocke.
Jefferson 1803-1813, Will Abstracts (1803-
1814), Old City Cemetery.
Railroad Stations in Rutherford County, Rion
Family, Stones River.
Footprints ... at Smyrna, V.A. Medical Center,
Manson Family, Jenkin ' s Homes, Will Abstracts
(Record Books 3 &amp; 4), Rutherford County
Historical Society, Early News, Sketch from
Macon County, Illinois, 1981 in Rutherford
County.
Roads and Turnpikes of Rutherford County,
includes many Rutherford County names.
Jefferson Springs Resort, Lascassas Baptist
Church, John Price Buchanan, Will Abstracts,
1836 Tax Records of the 25th District.
Ft. Rosecrans, Big Springs, East Main Church of
Christ, Tax Records District 23 &amp; 24 for 1836,
1837, and 1849, Mathias Hoover.
Harding House, Milton, County Stores in the
Jefferson Area, Will Abstracts Book 7, Tax
Record of Districts 15 and 16 (1836, 1837, and
1849) .
Publication 24: History of Medicine in Rutherford County,
Publication 25:
Publication 26*
Publication 27:
Publication 28:
Publication 29:
Publication 30:
Publication 31:
Publication 32:
Publication 33:
Publication 34:
Legends and Stories of the Civil War in
Rutherford County.
A Yankee in Rutherford County, Literary
Interest Expressed by Women in Rutherford
County, Mt. Olivet and Hoovers Gap Methodists,
My Years at Linebaugh Library.
History of Central Christian Church, Alfred
Blackman
.
Coleman Scouts (Henry B. Shaw, Leader; Sam
Davis, Dee Jobe, Williams Roberts, William
Manford Street, and others.)
The Churches of Christ in Rutherford County,
History of the Salem Methodist Church, and
Municipal Officers of the Town of Murfreesboro
(1818-1891)
.
History of Rutherford County Farm (including
insane asylum and the pest control center).
Architecture of Rutherford County Farm.
The Rutherford County Rifles (a group of 150
young men from Rutherford County who
volunteered for service in the Confederacy).
Includes a list of these men and what happened
to them. Article on Violence in Rutherford
County.
A Researcher's Guide to Rutherford County
Records by David Rowe; Jerry Sneak by Homer
Pittard (discovered after his death).
Census and Tax Records for First District.
Mattie Ready-John Hunt Morgan Wedding; Dement
Family; Two Gallant Leaders at the Battle of
Murfreesboro.
Publication 35: Uncle Dave Macon
The following publications are also available through the
Society:
History of Medicine in Rutherford County , Part II (A collection
of Biographies of Physicians Who Practiced in the area during
the Nineteenth Century.) Robert G. Ransom, M.D.
$16.00 + $2.00 postage
Westbrooks, Williams, and Related Smothermans of Rutherford
County. $14.50 + $2.00 postage
Brothers and Others and Fosterville $21.00 + $2.00 postage
(OUT-OF-PRINT)
History of Versailles - OUT OF PRINT
History of Rutherford County by C.C. Sims (pub. 1947)
$12.00 + $2.00 postage
History of Rutherford County by Mabel Pittard (pub. 1983)
$12.50 + $2.00 postage
A History of Rutherford County Schools, Vol. I (Northern
section of the County) $12.00 + $2.00 postage
A History of Rutherford County Schools , Vol II (Southern
section of County, including Murfreesboro)
$12.00 + $2.00 postage
1840 Rutherford County Census with Index
$5.00 + $2.00 postage
Deed Abstracts of Rutherford County, 1803-1810
$5.00 + $2.00 postage
Cemetery Records of Rutherford County;
Vol. I (Northwestern third of County and part of Wilson
and Davidson Counties, 256 cemeteries with index and maps)
$10.00 + $2.00 postage
Vol. II (Eastern third of County, cemeteries with index and
maps) $10.00 + $2.00 postage
Vol. Ill (Southwestern third of Rutherford County and the
western part of Cannon County, 241 cemeteries with index
and maps) $10.00 + $2.00 postage
The History of Rutherford County . Vol. I, 1799-1828
by John C. Spence $25.00 + $2.00 postage
The History of' Rutherford County . Vol II, 1829-1870
by John C. Spence $25.00 + $2.00 postage
A Civil War Diary by John C. Spence $25.00 + $2.00 postage
The Pictorial History of Rutherford County by Mabel Pittard
OUT OF PRINT
Map of 1878 Rutherford County (shows land owners)
$3.50 + $2.00 postage
Available from Mrs. R.A. Ragland, P.O. Box 544, Murf reesboro,
TN 37133-0544
Marriage Records of Rutherford County
$10.00 + $2.00 postage
The Record Books of Rutherford County, Tennessee begin in 1803 the year
the County was formed. The County Court was to meet in quarterly sessions or
terms throughout the year to dispose of the probate and civil business of the
County. All business brought to the Court's attention was listed in the Minute
Books of the County. Any documents submitted to the Court during these sessions
were recorded in the Record Books. In the early years the Clerk recorded these
items as he found time to do so. Therefore, many items took their time appearing
in the record books. There may be a gap of several months between the official
appearance in Court (Minute Books) and the actual recording of the documents
(Record Books) produced at the Court appearance.
The first-named individual in each item recorded is usually deceased. The
estate was in need of investigation by the Court, who in turn either heard the
deceased's representative, an Executor, or appointed an individual, an
Administrator, to process the deceased's estate
The Record Books contain documents involving the following:
1. Bills of sales of slaves
2. Powers of Attorney - allowing another to represent you in dealing
with the courts of Rutherford County^
3. Divisions of lands associated with heirs of an estate.
4. Apprenticeships
5. Prenuptial agreements
6. Surveys - usually prior to 1810.
7. Wills - Wills were not placed in a separate book until well after
the Civil War.
8. Widow's Allowances - usually an allotment of foodstuffs, clothing,
etc. for the support of the widow and her family for at least one
year following the decease of her husband or until the estate could
be settled.
9. Inventories of estates - an itemized list of all property, personal
and real, owned by the deceased, as well as outstanding debts to the
deceased or debts the deceased owed another individual.
10. Sales of estates - an itemized list of the buyers of all goods and
property sold by the Executor/Administrator.
11. Settlements of estates - statement of expenses in the settling of
the estate as reviewed by a commission composed by three or more
outstanding citizens named by the Court to the final accounting of
the Executor/ Administrator.
12. Guardian's Returns - A named guardian's yearly reports of money spent
on the minor heirs of the deceased, or income received for the heir's
support.
13. Division of Property - this entailed the apportioning of the valued
items to heirs of an estate, usually slaves.
A sincere attempt has been made to spell the words correctly as they have
been written. However, in some instances a name will be spelled several
different ways within a single record. A notation is usually made concerning
the variations. Also, 19th century handwriting is difficult to read at best and
errors of deciphering the names, in some instances, is next to impossible.
Every attempt was made to give the correct name.
SYMBOLS
RB = Record Book and its number
p = Original page number in the Record Book
A/Ax: Administrator/Administratrix - appointed by the Court to administer
the estate if not named by the Will
B: Buyer
BOS: Bill of Sale
C: Commissioner
d: Daughter
Div: Division
DOW: Date of Will
E/Ex: Executor/Executrix - named in Will to administer estate
EO: Estate owed money to this individual
F/P: Filed or Probated
G: Guardian
gd: Granddaughter
gs: Grandson
Inv: Inventory of Estate
L: Landowner - usually adjoining landowners of estate
N: Named in Will but relationship not provided
0: Owing individual in debt to the estate
POA: Power of Attorney
R: Recorded
Ret: Return - report to Court
s: Son
S: Slave/s
Sett: Settlement of estate
W: Witness
Wid. Allow: Widow's allowance/allotment
RECORD BOOK NO: 1
1. RBl,p3 - Record of Sheriff's Bonds for 1804 and 1805 - 2 Jan 1804 - C: Saauel HcBride, John Howell and
Jaies Titus - Samuel HcBride, appointed Sheriff of Rutherford County.
2. RBl,p4 - Bond recorded - Thoaas Bedford and Robert Weakley to Hilliai Gillian (Bedford and Weakley of
District of Hero of State of Tennessee and Gillian of Charlotte Co., 7A) - 30 Nov 1803 - W: Peter
LeGrand.
3. RBl,p5 - BOS: Saauel HcBride to Williaa Hope - 13 Aug 1803 - S: woman, Hinty and her 3 children, Dick,
Ann, Perry - W: Leauel Wright, Jaaes Whitsett.
4. RBI, p6 - BOS: Joseph Cannon to Joseph Bowaan - 19 Oct 1803 - Joseph Cannon, Sr. of Mecklenburg Co.,
NC aoving to TN - Joseph Bowaan of Mecklenburg Co., HC - John Bowaan of Suaner Co., TN, Jaaes Sharp
of Davidson Co., TN - W: John Hill, Theophilus A. Canon.
5. RBl,p7 - BOS: Robert Matthews and wife, Sally Matthews to Benjamin Edwards - 1 Oct 1804 - W: Williaa
Laughlin.
6. RBl,p8 - POA: Richard Waugh to Anthony Foster - 5 Oct 1803 (Waugh of Amherst Co., VA &amp; Foster of
Davidson Co., TN) - L: John Cavill, Densey Jenkins, Howell Tatua - conveyed to Waugh 14 Oct 1799 -
B: Searcy - W: Williaa Richards.
7. RBl,plO - Collector's Bond: 3 Jul 1804 - Saauel HcBride, Sheriff, Alexander HcCulloch, Williaa
Mitchell.
8. RBl,pll - POA: Williaa Cocke to Thoaas Mitchell - 7 Aug 1804 - Cocke purchased lands froa John Culan
Vance - W: Williaa Mitchell, Richard Mitchell.
9. RBl,pl2 - BOS: Joseph Herndon to Thoaas Stuart - 11 Jan 1805 - S: girl, Little Hilly - W: Peter
LeGrand.
10. RBl,pl3 - BOS: Michael Kinnard, Jr. to Solomon Beasley - 14 Feb 1805 - S: boy, Ben - W: Hugh Robison.
11. RBl,pl4 - BOS: Williaa Arnold to Jonathan Hagness - 29 Nov 1804 -S: boy, about 14 years, Bob, dark
coaplexion - W: John Arnold.
12. RBl,pl5 - Collector's Bond: 2 Jul 1805 - Saauel HcBride, Williaa Hope and Edward Moore.
13. RBl,pl6 - BOS: Jaaes Ferguson to Francis Jones - 24 Aug 1805 - John Donison, lessee - W: John Bunkley,
Abner Deaent.
14. RBl,pl7 - BOS: Joseph Boyer (also Beauyer) to Andrew HcHicking -8 Hay 1805 - in trust for benefit of
Williaa A. Sublett - W: R. Bedford, Stephen Bedford, Polly C. Bedford.
15. RBl,pl9 - BOS: Francis HcBride to Joseph Herndon - 3 Sep 1805 -S: aan, Harry, about 28 years - W:
Saauel HcBride, Alfred Wallis.
16. RBl,p20 - BOS: Saauel Long to John Dickson - no date - L: Edward Radford -W: Saauel Cowan, Edward
Radford.
17. RBl,p21 - Division of lands for heirs of Col. Saauel Hosbey - 23 Har 1805 Heirs: Kittey Hosbey, Lucket
Davis, Robert Hosbey, Williaa Hosbey, John Hosbey, Salley Hosbey, Robert Lewis, Cally HcDaniel, Jane
Hosbey - C: Jaaes Whitsett, Jesse Clark and Hugh Robertson.
18. RBl,p23 - Division of land of Thoaas Bedford, deceased - no date - L: Robert Weakley, Harrison Parson,
Joseph Hartin, John HcNairy, Joseph Herndon, Peter LeGrand, Robert Branch, Joseph Motherill - C: Jaaes
Sbarpe, Joseph Herndon, Harrison Gilliaa, Saauel Long, Constant Hardeaon.
19. RBl,p28 - Bond: Williaa Harlin of Davidson Co. to John Winston and Anthony Winston - 24 Jun 1803 - W:
Jesse Johns - L: Saauel Wilson, Niiarod Henefee, Aron Jenkins.
20. RBl,p29 - Bond: Matthew Talbott of Davidson Co., TN to Janes HcCutchen of Logan Co., KY - 10 Nov 1794 -
W: Nicholas P. Hardeaon, Oliver Williaas.
21. RBl,p30 - POA: John Wallis of Iredell Co., NC to Theophilis A. Canon of Rutherford Co., TN - 15 Feb
1806 - W: Janes Sharpe.
22. RBl,p31 - Collector's Bond: 10 Jul 1806 - Obadiah H. Benge, Williaa P. Anderson, Robert H. Dyer,
Williaa Mitchell and Peter LeGrand - W: Joseph Herndon.
23. RBl,p32 - Sale: John Cumins, deceased - 3 Jan 1806 - S: nan, Tob to Frederick Barfield - W: Joseph
Herndon.
24. RBl,p32 - Line of Division: 12 Feb 1805 - Col. Christaas, surveyor - W: Williaa Christias - Between:
Robert Searcy, Lewis Anthony.
25. RBl,p34 - Apprenticeship: Williaa Phillips and Martha Phillips - 10 Feb 1806 - bound their son, George
Phillips, till age 21 who will be 9 years of age 8 April next to Robert Jetton - W: Wilson Kerr, Janes
Patton.
26. RBl,p35 - Gift: Reuben Windhaa of Rutherford Co., TN - 11 Jan 1806 - nephew: Ediund I. Bean, son of
George Bean and Prudy Bean of Rutherford Co., TN - W: A. Higginbothaa, Thoias Eastes, George Bean.
27. RBl,p36 - POA: Aron Jenkins of Green Co., Ohio to son, Ninrod Jenkins of Rutherford Co., TN - 20 Nov
1805 - W: John Woodaan, Baldwin Jenkins, Josiah Springer.
28. RBl,p37 - Articles of nuptial agreenent - 16 Hay 1806 between Saauel C. McNeese and Elizabeth CUMins,
widow of John Cumins - W: Sally Sublett, Williaa A. Sublett.
29. RBl,p38 - Sett: John Hiller, deceased - 9 Jul 1806 - J. P.: Hugh Robinson, Charles Ready - E: Prudence
Miller.
30. RBl,p39 - BOS: Abner H. H. Bush to Saauel Henderson - 30 Aug 1806 - S: girl, Cherry, about 4 years -
W: Jaaes Henderson, Zettro Gallin.
31. RBl,p40 - BOS: Abner H. H. Bush to Saauel Henderson - 15 Jul 1806 - S: girl, Rachel, about 14 years -
Naaed: Saauel Williaas, deceased, E. Gernigan, J. B. Reynolds, John Patton, Wilson Cage, Williaa
Mitchell, John Brothers - W: Jaaes Henderson.
32. RBl,p41 - POA: Henry H. Rutledge to Williaa P. Anderson and John Strother (Rutledge of Charleston,
S.C., Anderson and Strother of Rutherford Co., TN) - 22 Apr 1806 - W: Alex Hunter.
33. RBl,p43 - Sale to highest bidder froa Francis Locke - 6 Apr 1807 - S: boy, age 11, Horgan and boy, 18
nonths, Isaac to Hinchey Pettway, who sold saae slaves to Jaaes Locke - W: Alexander HcCulloch.
34. RBl,p43 - Lease: Abrahaa Scott to Francis Youree - 5 Nov 1804.
35. RBl,p45 - Sale: Francis Locke - 1st Monday in Jan 1807 - S: woaan, Cate sold 6 Apr 1807 to Joseph
Herndon - N: John D. Garrett - Sheriff: Obadiah M. Benge - W: Jno. Dickinson.
36. RBl,p47 - Suit: John D. Garrett, Assignee of Robert Weakley - 6 Apr 1807 - Goods and chattels of
Francis Locke - S: boy, Isaac, boy, Horgan sold to Hinchey Pettway - Sheriff: Obadiah M. Benge - W:
Jno. Dickinson, Joseph Herndon.
37. RBl,p49 - Sale: Francis Locke to Jaaes Locke - 10 Har 1807 - S: woaan, Hinty; aan, Frazier - W: Joseph
Herndon, Saauel Bowaan.
38. RBl,p50 - BOS: Roger Snell to Ben Carr - 10 Jun 1806 - S: wonan, Perry -W: Charles Snell, Jaaes Snell.
39. RBl,p51 - EOS: George Doggett of Oglethorpe Co., GA to Saauel Campbell of Rutherford Co., TN - 1 Feb
1807 - S: Esther, 5 years old; Chaney, 2 years old - H: Frederick Barefield.
40. RBl,p52 - BOS: Francis Locke to Hargaret Locke - 10 Har 1807 - S: Baird, boy - W: Joseph Herndon,
Saauel Bowaan.
41. RBl,p54 - Signed by Robert Hancock - 26 Jun 1807 - S: girl, Sail who waits on my wife belongs to ay
father-in-law, Charles Kavanaugh.
42. RBl,p54 - BOS: Herbert Lanier to Williaa Burgess, Sen. - 8 Jun 1807 - S: boy, Ben - W: Joseph Burgess,
Richard Burgess.
43. RBl,p55 - BOS: Charles Kavanaugh to Grandsons, Stephen Kavanaugh Hancock and Charles Harchents Hancock,
sons of ty d: Zale Hancock, wife of Robert Hancock - 6 Jul 1807 - S: girl, Sail, 15 years - W: Stephen
Bedford.
44. RBl,p56 - BOS: - Janes Harley to Jaaes Snell of Saapson Co., HC -1 Jun 1807 - S: girl, Esther - H:
Jesse H. Yendue, Rocjer Snell.
45. RBl,p57 - BOS: Joseph Dickson and John Orr and Nancy Orr, Executors of John Price, deceased to Jaaes
Henderson - 20 Apr 1807 - S: tan, Adaa - H: John Dickson, Hargarett Dickson.
46. RBl,p58 - BOS: Jaaes Barefield to Williaa Barefield - 20 Nov 1806 - S: boy, Charles, 7 years - W:
Frederick Barefield.
47. RBl,p59 - Collector's Bond: 10 Jul 1807 - John Griffin, John Dickson, John Bradley - 9: Joseph Hemdon.
48. RBl,p59 - BOS: Henry H. Harahle to Edaund Jones of Halifax Co., NC - 8 Oct 1807 - 3S: Ban, Bob; aan,
Peter; woaan, Dorcas - I: Charles Locke, Jr.
49. RBl,p61 - POA and BOS: Edaund Jones, P. of A. of Luck Mathews sold S: aan, Bob; aan, Peter; woaan,
Dorcas to Henry H. Harahle - 8 October 1807 - W: Charles Locke, Jun.
50. RBl,p62 - BOS: John Counce to Jaaes Henderson - 4 Sep 1807 - S: aan, Lote; woaan, Gean were purchased
froa Thoaas Greere - W: John Elliott.
51. RBl,p63 - BOS: John Bradley to ibid Parkhurst - 5 Oct 1807 - S: girl, Aay about 16 years - W: Robert
Higgins.
52. RBl,p64 - BOS: Benjaain Wilson to Thoaas Frost's widow, Hanna Frost - 6 Apr 1807 - S: girl, Silve -
W: Andrew HcMickin, Jaaes HcKee.
53. RBl,p65 - BOS: Peter Grayson to John Reid - 14 Dec 1807 - S: boy, Jack - H: S. Bedford and J. A.
Caapbell.
54. RBl,p66 - BOS: Joseph Hemdon to Williaa Hope - 13 Dec 1807 - S: aan, Dick 24 years; girl, Holly 10
years.
55. RBl,p66 - BOS: Hark Hitchell to John Howell - 18 Hay 1807 - S: aan, Pruse W: Williaa Howell.
56. RBl,p67 - BOS: Robert Bean to Cado Deaent - 23 Dec 1807 - S: girl, Har/ 12 or 13 years - W: Hinchey
Petway, Jno. Spence.
57. RBl,p68 - Collector's Bond: 5 Jan 1808 - John Griffin, Hinchy Pettway, Robert H. Dyer, Niarod Jinkins,
Williaa Hitchell, Jesse Bean.
53. RBl,p69 - BOS: William Hope to Joseph Herndon - 13 Dec 1807 &#8226; S: woaan, Hinty, 29 years and her 3
children: Perry, Mary and Harry - W: John Johnston.
59. RBl,p70 - BOS: Hicajeh Peacock to Norton Guh - 9 Feb 1808 - S: HOian, Hannah - W: Saauel HcBride.
60. RBl,p71 - BOS: Ben Smith to Joseph Dickson Smith - 7 Oct 1807 -S: boy, Lewis, about 13 years - W: Hary
W. Saith, James Henderson.
61. RBI, p72 - HILL: John Ford of Burke County - DOW: 27 Oct 1804 - R: 12 Jan 1809 - Wife: Judith Ford -
N: "children" - leave also to: John Payne, Charles Duncan - E (2): Jacob Ford, Jaaes Ford (friends) -
W: Sally Payne, Lucinda Payne, John Godfrey.
62. RBl,p73 - Partition of land: 22 Jan 1807 - Petitioner: Benjaain HcCulloch Assignee: Joseph Hontford
Saith - Divisee: William Heur, Joseph Hontford "land granted by North Carolina to Joseph Hontford" -
W: Peter LeGrand, Jaaes Henderson, John Dickson.
63. RBl,p74 - Partition of land between William Jordan and Joseph Jordan - 8 Oct 1807 - Land grant: Isadore
Scarett, Alexander HcKnight, Charles Ready, David Rogers.
64. RBl,p75 - Assignaent of Hortgage: Robert Searcy to J &amp; W Jackson - Land sold to Searcy by William Nash
10 Jul 1806 - L: Williaa Arnold, John Arnold, William Lannoa - tract granted to: Stephen Brooks - this
assignaent: 26 Aug 1809 between Searcy and Jaaes Jackson and Washington Jackson - W: John Dickson,
Felix Grundy.
65. RBl,pp80 &amp; 81 - POA: William Slade to John Strother - Sale to: Williaa Christmas - 21 Jul 1809 - W:
Williaa Neal, R. H. Dyer.
66. RBl,p81 - POA: Robert Burton of Aaite Co., Mississippi Territory to John Burton of Aaite Co., Missis-sippi
Territory - 11 Dec 1809 - W: Charles Burton, Robert HcFarlen.
67. RBl,p83 - Apprenticeship: 2 Jan 1310 - Thoaas Harlin, Administrator of Williaa Harlin, deceased -
Apprentice: Jaaes Harlin to Jaaes Olliphant -W: B. Coleman.
68. RBl,p84 - Sheriff's bond: 2 Jan 1810 - John Griffin, Williaa Mitchell, Robert H. Dyer, Alexander
HcCulloch, Peter LeGrand.
69. RBl,p87 - Collector's bond: 2 Jan 1810 - John Griffin, Williaa Mitchell, Robert H. Dyer, Alexander
HcCulloch, Peter LeGrand.
70. RBl,p89 - POA: Thoaas Grishaa of Rutherford Co. to Thoaas Terrell of Wilkes Co., GA - money due froa
estate of Daniel Pruce, deceased 7 Feb 1810 - W: Daniel Bowman, Thomas Yardly.
71. RBl,p90 - POA: John Nasb Read to John H. Read - 4 Jul 1810.
72. RBl,p91 - Clerk's Bond: 2 Jan 1810 - Blackman Coleman, appointed Clerk, John Strother, Alexander
HcCulloch, Williaa P. Anderson, Joseph Herndon.
73. RBl,p94 - POA: Henry Robison to son, Hugh Robison - 5 Sep 1810 - L: Robert Harris - W: Solomon Beesly,
John Henderson.
74. RBl,p95 - Survey: for William Carter, Assignee of Alexander HcKeen - 7 Sep 1810 - Surveyor: Jesse
Brashear.
75. RBl,p96 - Williaa Carter assigns land to Joseph Ship - 18 Sep 1810 - N: Williaa Staaps, Siaon Ship -
W: Robert HcCoabs, Jesse Brashear, Herbert Lanier.
76. RBl,p96 - Survey: Williaa Carter, assignee of Alexander HcKeen - 17 Sep 1810 - L: Robert HcCoabs -
Surveyor: Jesse Brashear.
77. RBl,p97 - William Carter assigns land to William Pybas - 18 Sep 1810 - W: Robert McCombs, Jesse
Brasbear, Herbert Lanier - tl: Joseph Ship, Tarter Dottery.
78. RBl,p98 - Bond: John Cummins of Territory of the United States south of River Ohio and Suiner County
to Thomas Harrison, Davidson County - 22 Hay 1792 - N: General Jaies Robertson, Col. Saiuel Barton -
H: Matthew Talbott, R. Weakley.
79. RBl,pl00 - POA: Gross Scruggs of Rutherford Co., TN to William G. Pendleton of Richiond, VA - 1 Apr
1811 - Children and heirs of William Arthur, deceased: Gross S. Arthur; Elizabeth Arthur, late
Elizabeth Goodwin; Hezekiah Goodwin "who was intermarried with Elizabeth Arthur and Amhrose Arthur,
guardian for William Arthur, Jr. and Nancy Arthur"; William Arthur, deceased "who was devisee of Gross
Scruggs, deceased.
80. RBl,pl01 - Survey: John Montgomery, assignee of Jesse Bean - 9 Oct 1808 -L: Thomas Duggins, Joel
Dyer[s] - Surveyor: Henry Harrison CC (chain carriers): James Rogers, Alexander Craig - assigned to:
Peter Arnold 23 Oct 1810 - W: Harbert Sugg, Timothy Sugg, William Sugg.
81. RBl,pl03 - POA: John Webb to Herriman Landrum of Williamson Co., TN - 1 Jul 1811 - John Webb's wife:
Patsy, her father, Reuben Landrum of Union Co., NC - W: Joshua Haskell, William Stokes.
82. Rfll,pl04 - POA: James Bradly of Washington Co., VA to George Simpson, Jefferson, Rutherford Co., TN -
9 May 1811 - W: James Shelby, D. Campbell N: Hatthew McClanahan, John R. Acklin - Washington Co., VA
J.P.'s: James White and John HcClellan - Washington Co., VA Clerk: John Campbell - Washington Co., VA
Justice: Robert Campbell.
83. RBl,pl07 - Bond: 13 January 1312 - C: Charles Ready, Hugh Roberson, Hans Hamilton, James Armstrong,
Owen Edwards, Jesse Brasher, John Thompson, Sr., William Nash, Chairman - J. P.: Frederick Barfield -
W: Joseph Dickson, Blackaan Coleman.
84. RBl,pl09 - POA: William Christmas of Williamson Co., TN to William Mitchell - 29 Jun 1810 - Deed:
Christmas, Joel Dyer, R.H. Dyer and William Hitchell to William Loftin - W: Riddick Bridges, Thomas
Mitchell.
85. RBl,pll0 and 112 - Sheriff's and Collector's Bond: 7 Jan 1812 - Hatthew McClanahan, Sheriff, Constant
Hardeman, John Parks, Zachariah Posey, Claiborne Goodwan, Alexander McCulloch, John B. Hogg, John
Anthony
.
86. RBl,pll4 - Survey: Grant of Samuel Pike by Secretary of NC 1785 - 21 Jul 1809 - William Slade, assignee
of heirs of Samuel Pike - L: John G. Blount, T. Blount, Absolui Tatum, _L Wiggins - Surveyor: Henry
Harrison CC: James Keeler, William Caldwell - Slade to William Christmas - W: John B. Hogg, Blackman
Coleman.
87. RBl,pll5 - Survey: 28 Mar 1809 - [same as *86] - W: Abell Purnell, Edward Pinch.
33. RBl,pll7 - Survey: 25 Hay 1809 [same as /86] - L: John Overton, Kader Bankhans, Hatthias Hoover - CC:
Hardy Williford, Hiram Hammonds.
39. RBl,pll9 - POA: John Fonville to Asa Fonville of Bedford Co., TN and Richard Fonville of Craven Co.,
NC - 7 Har 1812 - Lewis Fonville, Senior, deceased - A: Jeremiah Fonville, Charles Sanders.
90. RBl,pl20 - POA: Samuel Griffin of Bedford Co., VA to John Reed - 26 Dec 1808 - W: J. Steptoe of Bedford
Co., VA - J. P.: Thomas Logwood of Bedford Co., VA.
91. RBl,pl23 - Order: 18 Feb 1811 - C: Stephen White, Daniel Green, James Johnson "take deposition of
William Nash... in fall of 1783 marked a tree which he surveyed for William Jones" - L: William Hankin -
Recorder: John Warren.
92. RBl,pl24 - Deposition: 20 Feb 1811 [same as J91] "a tract or survey made by William Nash for Joshua
Hadley in 1788" - L: Gilford Dudley, Matthias Hoover, Joseph Branch, John Branch.
93. RBl,pl29 - Bond: 7 Apr 1812 - C: Alexander HcCulloch, Isaac Shelby, Walter Keeble, Ishaa N. Read,
William Nash, Chairman.
94. RBl,pl30 - Bond: 3 Apr 1810 - C: .Alexander HcCulloch, John Hash Read, Isaac Shelby, Willian Nash,
Chairman.
95. RBl,pl31 - Prenuptial Agreeaent: 3 Dec 1811 - Isaac Butler of Davidson Co., TN to Jennot King of
Rutherford Co., TN - Trustee: Ezekiel Hoore of Rutherford Co., TN - W: Charles Hayes, John Moore.
96. RBl,ppl40 &amp; 141 - Certificate of Freedoa: 7 Dec 1812 - Henry Jackson, a free Ban of color, age 23,
slave of Joseph Boyers, originally of Virginia W: James Daughity, Robert Hancock, Cader Deaent, Thoaas
Donnelly, John Baker, Abner Deaent, Benjaain Hancock, Williaa H. Searcy - 22 Dec 1812.
97. RBl,pl41 - POA Knox Co., TN: Williaa Tyrrell of Rnoxville, TN to Charles HcClung of Knox Co., TN - 9
Mar 1798 - W: Hugh L. White, John Hillsaan -J. P.: Janes Park, Knox Co., TN - 16 Hay 1807.
98. RBl,pl48 - POA: Armajor Childress to Jaaes Childress - 6 Jul 1813 - "of Charles HcClain, late of Adaas
County, deceased, in Mississippi Territory" Armajor Childress' wife: Ebe Childress, sister of Charles
HcClain - W: Joshua Barton, Thoaas Berry.
99. RBl,pl50 - POA: 16 Jun 1813 - Heirs of Williaa Kelton, deceased of Burke and Buncoabe Counties, NC:
Elizabeth Kelton, Sen.; Robert Kelton; Jaaes Kelton; John Sloan in right of wife, Polly; Alexander
Lackey, in right of wife, Peggy; Elizabeth Kelton, Jun.; Saauel B. Kelton; Archibald Kelton, in right
of wife, Nancy; all of Rutherford and Smith Counties, TN - W: Williaa S. Mitchell, Williaa Harris.
100. RBl,pl53 - Surveys: Saauel Grey, assignee of Alexander Aspey - Surveyed 3 Jul 1813 by Jesse Brasher -
L: Jason Thoapson, John Sageley - SCC: Hoses Glascock, Joseph Sageley to John Sageley - W: Alexander
Aspey, Joseph Sageley.
101. RBl,pl57 &amp; 158 - Survey: Grant to Jaaes HcCord by Secretary of NC - 17 June 1807 - Surveyed: 27 Hay
1809 by Henry Harrison - Williaa Russell, assignee of Jaaes HcCord - L: Williaa Slade, Lewis Staunton -
CC: Edward Finch, Williaa Bobbitt to John Brothers - W: Jaaes Henderson, Williaa S. Mitchell -
Principal surveyor: W. R. Anderson.
102. RBl,pl59 - Survey: Grant to Robert Whitlock on 19 Nov 1784 by Secretary of NC - entered 11 Jan 1812 -
Robert Dyer to Robert Clark - Surveyed: 7 Dec 1812 by Jesse Brasher - CC: John Clark, George Grishaa -
W: John Clerk, Thoaas S. Harris - Principal surveyor: John B. Hogg.
103. RBl,pl61 - POA: Ann Kinnard of Jessaaine Co., KY to Frederick Barfield -7 Nov 1811 - Wife of Michael
Kinnard, deceased formerly of Rutherford Co., TN - Administrators of Estate of Michael Kinnard: Lewis
Stephens, Michael Kinnard - W: Daniel Harshall, Saauel Caapbell, Ben Smith.
104. RBl,pl63 - Sale: Huaphrey C. Nelson, deceased - 4 Apr 1804 - A: Sarah Nelson, Williaa Edwards.
105. RBl,pl63 - Widow's allotment: Harah Howell - 12 Feb 1814 - C: Isaac Shelby, J. Davis, Constant
Hardeman.
106. RBl,pl64 - POA: Hugh Siapson to Ben Carr - 30 Har 1812 - Assignor: Henry Stevens - land to David McKay
W: W. Snell, Jaaes Snell.
107. RBl,pl64 - Sale: Hartha Pogue, deceased, executrix of Jaaes Pogue, deceased - A: James Gillispie - R:
26 Hay 1814.
108. RBl,pl65 - Sett: Hat Miller, deceased - 31 Jan 1814 - Adainistrator of estate of Williaa S. Dansy,
deceased: John Miller - N: Moses HcQuiter, John Just, George Pinckny - C: E. B. McCoy, Williaa Mankin.
109. RBl,pl66 - Widow's allowance: Wilson Kerr, deceased - 28 Jan 1814 - C: Thoaas Hubbard, Jaaes Henderson,
John Johns.
110. RBl,pl67 - Widow's support - Matthew Miller, deceased - 15 Jan 1814 - Widow: Marah Miller - W: John
Miller - C: John B. Pruett, Daniel Eppes, John Brothers.
111. RBl,pl68 - Division of land: Benjaiin Ledden, deceased - 1 Jun 1814 - Heirs and children: Williai
Abraham Ledden and Benjaain P. Ledden (2 and only children of deceased) - land to: Sarah Jane
Henderson, wife of William T. Henderson - C: Furney G. Norman, Williai Henderson, Ja&#187;es Neeley, Saiuel
Wilson, Daniel Marshall - J. P.: Hance Hamilton - CC: William Yearwod, Frederick L. Sulivan - Surveyor:
Jesse Brashear -
L: _L Rhodes.
END OF RECORD BOOK 1
RECORD BOOR NO. 2
112. RB2,pl - Inv: John Cuiiains, deceased - Apr tern 1804 - S: 3 - A: Jaaes Cummins, Elizabeth Cumains, John
Hoover.
113. RB2,p2 - Inv: Thoias Bedford, deceased - Jan tera 1805 - S: 7 - A: John R. Bedford.
114. RB2,p3 - Inv. Richard Searcy - R: 20 Jul 1804 - A: Elizabeth Searcy.
115. RB2,p3 - Inv of Sales: John Cuaiins, deceased - Date of Sale: 26 Oct 1804 A: John Hoover - S: girl,
Edney; boy, Luke; nan, Toby - all to Elizabeth Cumains - B: Obadiah M. Benge, Thoaas Yardley, James
M. Lewis, Henry Hoover, James Norman, James Doherty.
116. RB2,p5 - Inv: William Harlin, deceased - R: 10 Apr 1805 - A: Thoaas Harlin, Rachel Harlin.
117. RB2,p5 - Add'l inv: Thomas Bedford, deceased - 10 Apr 1805 - A: John R. Bedford.
118. RB2,p6 - WILL: Jeremiah Thacker of Davidson Co., TN - DOW: 7 Oct 1803 - R: 12 Apr 1804 - Wife: Mary
Ann Thacker - d: Cashandy - s: Siar Thacker -s: Larkin Thacker - 'my 4 children: Charles, Drsellus,
Larkin, Cashandy Thacker" - E: wife and Larkin Thacker, son - 0: Williaa Payne - L: Cuamins - W:
John L. Jetton, Jonathan Rucker, Henry Rucker.
119. RB2,p7 - WILL: Isaac Barr of Rutherford Co., TN - DOW: 10 Mar 1804 - E: wife, Elizabeth - 'iy 4
children": Enoch, Robert Steel, Isaac Ross, Mariah S: Simon, Pat (to be sold) - W: Robert Smith,
Williaa Smith.
120. RB2,p3 - Inv: John Miller, deceased - F: 7 Oct 1805 - S: girl - S: Prudence Hiller.
121. RB2,p8 - Inv: George W. Harney, deceased - A: Samuel McFadden.
122. RB2,p9 - Inv: Jeremiah Thacker - 30 Nov 1805 - E: Mary .Ann Thacker, Larkin Thacker.
123. RB2,pl0 - Add'l Inv: Thoias Bedford - 5 May 1306 - A: John R. Bedford.
124. RB2,pl0 - Add'l Inv: John Cuaiins - F: 5 May 1806 - A: Jaaes Cummins, John Hoover.
125. RB2,pl0 - Inv: Edmund Burnett, deceased - R: 12 Jun 1806 - S: woman -A: Joseph Burnett.
126. RB2,pll - Inv: Thoaas Frost - R: 12 Jun 1806 - A: Joseph Frost, Hannah Frost, Benjamin Wilson.
127. RB2,pll - Inv: Robert Marley - R: 12 Jun 1806 - A: Williaa Haban.
128. RB2,pl2 - Inv: Robert Smith - R: 12 Jun 1806 - A: Reuben Scott.
129. RB2,pl2 - WILL: Samuel Williams of Rutherford Co., TN - DOW: 2 Dec 1805 -F: 15 Apr 1806 - Wife:
Elizabeth - "lawful children, until they shall become of age" - "a child I had by Betsy Tinker" - "a
child I had by Nelly Buckridge" - E: wife and Robert Williams - W: William Mitchell, Nancy Mitchell -
when proved: Executrix sworn, Executor dead.
130. RB2,pl3 - Inv of Sales: Thomas Frost - taken 28 Apr 1806 - A: Joseph Frost, Hannah Frost, Benjamin
Wilson - B: Hannah Frost, Jaaes Cochrene, Joseph Frost, William Edwards, Frederick Talbott, Jesse
Wilson, Benjamin Wilson, Allin Chissoa, John Fry, John Rogers, Thomas Cotter, Joseph Holman, Henry
Prichard, Francis Pearce.
131. RB2,pl4 - Inv: Henry Kirby - F: 29 Sep 1806 - A: Ann Kirby.
132. RB2,pl5 - Inv of sales: Edmund Burnett - F: 29 Sep 1806 - A: Joseph Burnett - B: Smith Oglesby, Robert
Oliver, William Williams, Joseph Burnett, William Goodwin.
133. RB2,pl6 - WILL f CONTESTED
j
: John Price of Rutherford Co., TN - DOW: 17 Jan 1806 - R: 29 Sep 1806 -
Wife: Nancy Price - d: Polley Carr (not yet 18) -E: wife and friend, Joseph Dickson - W: John Dickson,
Henry Davis.
134. RB2,pl8 - WILL: John Cason of Prince Edward Co., VA - DOW: 20 Jun 1806 -R: 5 Nov 1806 - brother: Seth
Cason - N: Edmond Harris - sister: Susanna Adcock and her children... "money in hands of Elisha Bennett
upon Thomas Huddleston" - sister: Mary Arnold... "Paid out of money in hands of Thomas Armstrong" -
sister: Lucy Bennett, her children - S: Charles to Lucy Bennett - sister: Hilly Armstrong and children
S: Rose and child, Wiatt to Hilly Armstrong - S: Hannah to Seth Cason - E: friend, Edaond Harris -"ay
sisters and sisters' children in Virginia" - W: Ishaa Harris, William Hunter, Wilson Hunter.
135. RB2,p20 - Inv: Prudence Miller - F: Oct Session 1806 - S: girl, 11 or 12 years - A: John Arnold.
136. RB2,p21 - WILL: Bradley Gambill of Rutherford Co., TN - DOW: 19 Jun 1806 -F: 1806 - s: Benjaain
Gaibill, Hetton [?], Jaaes, Jordan (unearned) - Wife: not named - 2 youngest sons: Bradley and
Hourain/Hovraa [?] - daughters: not named - E: son, Benjaain Gambill, Joseph Horton - W: Bird Nance,
William Nance.
137. RB2,p22 - Inv: John Cason - F: 6 Nov 1806 - S: Charles, Hannah, Rose, Wyatt - A: Seth Cason - W: Robert
Bedford.
138. RB2,p23 - Inv: Bradley Gaabill - F: 5 Har 1807 - E: Benjamin Gambill, Joseph Horton.
139. RB2,p23 - Property sold: George W. Harney - 9 Oct 1805 - at Mrs. Jenny Harney's - E: Saauel McFaddon -
B: Jane Harney, Joseph Gowen, Jesse Bean, Joseph Youree, Francis Youree, Samuel McFaddin, Jacob Graves,
William Counts, William Baker, Henry Harney, George Rolin, John Hukey, Thoaas McFaddon.
140. RB2,p25 - Inv of Sale: Prudence Miller or Gowen - 23 Oct 1806 - A: James Sharpe - B: Thomas Drennon,
William A. Sublett, Nicholas Titin, Charles Hyres, Samuel Bigson, John Drennon/Drinnon, Theophilis A.
Cannon, Jaaes Miller, Nathan Riddin, John Button, Edward Moore, John Stockird, Joseph Knox, William
Drennon, Jaaes Wade, William Pittaan, Williaa Arnold, Charles B. Harvey, Josiah Davidson, Hurray Loury,
Williaa Robinson, Alfred Wallis, Williaa HcPeaKe, Henry Miller, Saauel Wilson, Hinchy Pettway, Williaa
Gilliaa, Andrew HcMickin, Thomas Sappington, Thoaas Mitchell, Levy Lanhai, Nathan Lanhaa, James Tivour,
Daniel Boatright, John Spence, Norton Gum, John Arnold - 3: (Sold 18 Dec 1806) John W. Alexander, David
Drennon, Nicholas Peter, Williaa Hash, Joseph Kennedy, James Stewart.
141. RB2,p28 - Inv: John Cuaains - F: 1 Apr 1807 - A: John Hoover - C: Thoaas Rucker, Robert Bedford - EO:
Deaderick Tatua, Thoaas Sappington, O.M. Benge, Bennett Searcy, Jesse Wharton, Joseph Burnett, Jaaes
Bayer, Williaa Titton, Saauel HcBride, Edward Radford, Andrew Ewing, Jaaes Lewis, Williaa Robinson,
? HcKain, Jesse Searcy, John Coffey, Jaaes Beavers, John Dickinson, 0. Williams, Niarod Hennifee,
William Gamer, John Thompson, John McNairy, Timothy Deaonbreua, John Boyd, Isaac Nevins, Jaaes W.
Jackson, Doctor Claiborne, William German, Williaa Lytle, James HcKain, J. Norman, Bell T. Stothart,
A. Hoore, King and Caron, Anthony Soffington, P. Leaore, Black and Williams, Joseph Herndon.
142. RB2,p30 - WILL: William Baker of Bedford Co., TN - DOW: 6 Nov 1806 - R: 20 Auq 1307 - Wife: Martha
Baker - E: wife, John Nail, John Baker - S: Eve to wife - d: Temperance - "children": James, Mary, John
and child ay wife is carrying - W: Richard Baily, Robert Baker, Jonathan Bailey.
143. RB2,p32 - WILL: John Tilly - DOW: 20 May 1807 - R: 4 Nov 1807 - Wife: Jane S: Rhodey to be free at
wife's death - N: John Billinqsly. . .have one-half land at wife's death; Robert Bean; Thomas Blair;
Doctor Jonathan Edwards -W: Robert Bell, Thomas Douqan - Copy given to: William Wright.
144. RB2,p33 - Sett: George W. Harney, Jr. - R: 4 Nov 1807 - E: Samuel HcFaddin EO: James Hulhera, Jesse
Wharton, F. Youree, John Graves, John HcKean, Doctor F. May - C: William Nash, O.W. Edwards.
145. RB2,p34 - Inv: William Baker - taken 6 Sep 1807 - S: woman - E: Martha Baker.
146. RB2,p35 - WILL: Francis Wright of Rutherford Co., TN - DOW: 3 Dec 1807 -R: 7 Feb 1808 - Wife: Nancy -
"dear children" - E: wife and Jacob Wright Ramsey - W: James D. Partrick, Francis Youree.
147. RB2,p36 - WILL: William Robertson of Davidson Co., TN - DOW: 19 Oct 1802 -R: 7 Feb 1808 - Wife: Nancy
Robertson - sons: Matthew Robertson, Benjamin Robertson, Samuel Robertson, Joseph Robertson -
daughters: Elizabeth, wife of Thoiaas Thornton; Isbel, wife of John Kinkade; Margaret, wife of William
Plumber; Mary, wife of Moses Robertson; Dinah, wife of George Buchanan -E: son, Matthew Robertson -
W: John Buchanan, William Philips.
148. RB2,p38 - Sett: William Marlin - F: 12 Feb 1808 - C: John Thompson, Hugh Robinson - A: Thomas Marlin,
Rachel Harlin - EO: William H. Robinson, John Anthony, William A. Sublette, John Thompson, David
Williams, W. Hunt, John Johns, John Nevin.
149. RB2,p39 - Inv: Thomas Sanders - taken 26 Dec 1807 - A: Lemuel Wright.
150. RB2,p39 - Inv: James Arnold - R: 12 Feb 1808 - A: James Taylor.
151. RB2,p40 - Inv: John Andrews - taken 2 Apr 1808 - A: Saauel Donnell, David Andrews.
152. RB2,p41 - Sales: Thomas Sanders - R: 13 Apr 1808 - B: Widow, Edward Burton, Cornelius Sanders, Hicajah
Peacock, William Nash, Isaac Sanders, Samuel HcBride, Thomas Sanders (son of Isaac Sanders), John Guin,
George Browing, John Roberson, Williaa Arnold, Jr., John Flowers, Sarah Flowers, Jeremiah Hedgpath,
Elisna Sanders/Saunders, Thoaas Rushing, John Bruce, Joseph Wright, Leauel Wright, John Nicholas,
Olsten Solomons, John Nichols.
153. RB2,p44 - Inv: Francis Wright - R: 13 Apr 1808 - A: Jacob Wright Ramsey -0: James Wright, James Neely,
Henry Loftin - Bond on: Thomas Shute.
154. RB2,p45 - Inv of sales: Francis Wright - R: 13 Apr 1308 - A: Jacob Wright Ramsey - B: Nancy Wright,
Joseph Young, William Talsil, Nathaniel HcCallister, Daniel Howell, Thomas Wright, Joseph Gowen,
Lcdwick Moore, Williaa Kelly, Donelson Caffery, Jaies Cuaains, Elisha Smith, John Orr, Samuel Jacobs,
.Alien White, Martin Fryley, Williaa Gowen, Elijah Smith, Alexander Farenton, Williaa Ciily, williaa
Hickinqbottoa, James iauqhiin, Reuben .Angle, Walter Pool, John Jacobs, Williaa Raasey, John Counts,
Gold-Smiti Hewit, Ellas Raasan, James Titus, Williaa Roberts, David Allen, George Martin, Zcaund
Recoil, Sccert C. Reaves, Edward Chicauhalt, Richard Williaason, Mark Black, Elijah Sinkhom, James
Bell, Robert Henderson.
155. RB2,p49 - WILL: John Howeil, Sr. of Rutherford Co., TH - DOW: 16 Dec 1807 F: 20 Apr 1808 - Wife: Sarah
s: Williaa Howell, Gwin Howell - On wife's death, equal shares to: Williaa Howell, Gwin Howell, Nancy
Nelson, Peggy Whitsett - gd: Patsy McBride (not yet 16) - S: girl, Shaw to wife; man, Purse to 3win
Howell; boy, Jerry to G&#187;m Howell; woman, Seel to Patsy McBriae - E: James Whitsett, Thoaas lelson,
Williaa Howell - W: John Stockird, Sr., Hugh Shearwood, Alexander Martin. CODECIL: 4 Jan 1308 - Wife:
Sarah - s: Gwin - 1: Nancy Nelson, Peggy Whitsett - W: John Stockird, Sr., Hugh Shearwood, Alexander
Martin.
::
156. RB2,p54 - Inv: John Andrews - taken 1 Jun 1808 - A: Saiuel Donnell, David Andrews - B: Widow, Janes
McKnight, David Andrews, Henry Goodlove, Alexander McKnight, Joseph Tennison, Peter Hoone, Samuel
Rosbrough, Joseph McKnight, Charles Carrol, Janes Laughlin, John Witherspoon, Alexander HcEwin, John
HcKee, Jaaes Raasey, Sweatt, William McKnight, John Doak, Alexander Daniel, Samuel HcDaniel, David
McKnight, Alexander Orr, Sasuel Habury, Williaa Saith, John Shorry, Jaaes Porterfield, Thoaas Coyle,
Solonon Wren, Charles Ready, Saauel Donnell.
157. RB2,p58 - Sale: Jaaes Arnold - F: 14 Jul 1808 - A: Jaaes Taylor B: Jaaes Taylor, John McCoy, Jaaes
Bass, Williaa Matthews, Widow, Absolaa Taylor, Dorcas Arnold, Soloaan Basby.
158. RB2,p60 - Inv: John Killough - R: 13 Jul 1808 - A: Thoaas Killough.
159. RB2,p60 - Inv: Thoaas Bedford - R: 13 Jul 1808 - A: John R. Bedford.
160. RB2,p60 - WILL: Harrison Gilliaa of Rutherford Co., TN - DOW: 10 Jun 1808 R: 17 Jul 1808 - S: Ban,
Anthony made free - brother: Thoaas Gilliaa's children - E: William Gilliaa, William Thweatt - W: Rhoda
Benge, Polly Thweatt, Elizabeth Thweatt, Mary Tarpley.
161. RB2,p62 - WILL: Matthew Patton of Rutherford Co., Til - DOW: 16 Sep 1808 -F: 13 Oct 1808 - Wife:
Katen/Katea Patton - "ay children" [other than Hargarett and Rhodah] - d: Hargarett, Rhodah - E: Wife
and brother, Jaaes Patton - W: John Ferguson, Williaa Hanna, Jaaes Cochran.
162. RB2,p63 - Inv: Harrison Gilliaa - A: Williaa Gilliaa.
163. RB2,p64 - WILL: Jaaes Morton of Rutherford Co., TN - DOW: 28 Jan 1807 - R: 21 Nov 1808 - Wife - s:
Joseph, Jaaes - d: Judith, Lucinda, Tabitha -S: boy, Dennis to Joseph; boy, Jack to Jaaes; girl, Edy
to Judith; Fanny, Curry, Clary to Sally; girls, Lucy, Saby to Lucinda; Isaac, Corbis, Winna to Tabitha;
Daniele, Abrahaa, Ag, Rose to Wife - E: sons, Joseph Morton, Jaaes Morton - W: Thoaas Shute, Williaa
Still - L: Allen Nance.
164. RB2,p65 - WILL: John Ford of Burke County - DOW: 27 Oct 1804 - F: 12 Jan 1809 - Wife: Judith - "ay
children" - N: John Payne, Charles Duncan - E: friends, Jacob Ford and Jaaes Ford - W: Sally Payne,
' Lucinda Payne, John Godfrey.
165. RB2,p66 - WILL: John Noraan of Rutherford Co., TN - DOW: 12 Nov 1808 - R: 12 Jan 1809 - Wife: Harget -
"the children when coae to age of aaturity" -E: Wife and Theophiles Cannon - W: John Stockird, Jr.,
John Irwin.
166. RB2,p67 - Inv: Jaaes Morton - R: 12 Jan 1809 - A: Joseph Morton, Jaaes Morton.
167. RB2,p68 - Inv of Sales: John HcFerrin - R: 12 Jan 1809 - A: Jaaes McFerrin B: John Gillespie, David
Jones, Jaaes HcFerrin, John Pain/Payne, Jaaes Gillespie, Thoaas Washington, Jaaes Wills, John HcFerrin,
Jaaes Billingsley, Jacob Pain/Payne, Robert Baldrige, Saauel HcFerrin, Mary HcFerrin, Williaa McFerrin.
168. RB2,p71 - Inv: Thoaas Hutchinson - Oct Session 1808 - A: Sarah Hutchinson 0: Williaa Gesture.
169. RB2,p72 - Inv: Saauel HcCulloch - sold 4 Feb 1809 - A: Benjamin HcCulloch S: sen and boys , Tony, Dick,
Sirus, Abraa, Jubiter, Francis, July, Saa, Ben, Little Dick, Little Saa, Bill, George, Jack, Jobe;
woaen and children . Betty, Elsey and her 2 children, Young Betty, Lucy and 2 children, Violet and 2
children, Easter, Marina - B: Hatha* HcClanahan, Hordecia Lillard, Alexander HcCulloch, Thoaas Bedford,
Jaaes Espey, George Siapson, Joseph Coaleaan, John R. Bedford, John P. Lenoir, Benjaain HcCulloch,
Sarah HcCulloch, John Arnold, Williaa Cunninghaa - Negroes were hired to: Hathew HcClanahan, Alexander
Caraichael, Patton Anderson, Williaa Edwards, Jaaes Sharp (Town), Benjaain Shipley, John Strother, John
Griffin, Jaaes Arastrong, Benjaain HcCulloch, Sarah HcCulloch - the following bonds were left with
Duncan Caaeron of North Carolina for collection: John HcCanal, John Santon, Saauel Benton, John Flick,
L. Prather, Jaaes Loftin, Jaaes Hoore, Jaaes Steel, Saauel Thoapson, Thoaas Whithead, A.L. Hurphrey,
John White, Jaaes Webb, Jaaes Palaer, John Tyrell - Collector: Thoaas Burges (NC) - O: Thoaas Watson,
John D. Fley - EO: Willie Jones, Halcot Spriote, John Haywood, Nelson Haael, Deaderick and Pettway,
Benjaain HcCulloch.
170. RB2,p74 - Inv of Sett: Prudence Miller, alias Prudence Gowen - A: Jaaes Sharp - EO: Williai Black,
Black and Williams, William HcKey, Henry HcPeak, John HcPeak, John Button, Ruth Null, Nicholas Mull,
John Null, James L. Armstrong, David Drennon, John Arnold, Deaderick S Pettway, Jonathan Hagness, Jaies
Sheards, William Read, Moses Shears, William Arnold, William A. Sublett, Jaaes Miller, Samuel Gibson,
John Miller, William McPeak, Jane HcKey, William Nash - C: Peter LeGrand, Williai Nash.
171. RB2,p75 - Inv: Michael Hott - Apr Session 1809 - A: Susanah Hott.
172. RB2,p75 - Inv of Sales: John Noman - Apr Session 1309 - A: Margret Norman, Theophiliss A. Cannon -
B: Margret Norman, William Cunningham, John Stockard, Thos. A. Cannon, William Stockard, William
Eavins, David Deaky, Zacharia Posey, Thomas Beanes, Iham Beanes, Joseph Martin, Robert McParlin,
William Pate, Edward Moore, Stephen Nobles, James Sharp, Jaaes Martin, Peter Garrison.
173. RB2,p76 - Inv: Joel Northcott - Apr Session 1809 - A: Margaret Northcott.
174. RB2,p77 - Inv of Sales: Charles Ray - Apr Session 1809 - A: Sarah Ray, David Williams - S: 1 woman,
1 girl, 1 boy to Sarah Ray - B: Sarah Ray, William Ray.
175. RB2,p78 - Inv: John Miller - Apr term 1809 - A: John Arnold - C: James Sharp, Willian Nash - EO: Henry
Miller, Nicholas Coonrad, Jaaes Burdin, ? Dickson, William Yourey, James Sharp.
176. RB2,p79 - Apprenticeship: Margret Callahan's son, Daniel Callahan to John Miller - 13 Mar 1809 - W:
Robert Miller, Isaac Miller, William Speakioore.
177. RB2,p80 - Inv: Elias Browning - R: 11 Jul 1809 - A: Elizabeth Browning -0: Willian Edwards, Sherrod
Harris, Joseph Price.
178. RB2,p80 - Add'l Inv: Harrison Gillian - Jul Session 1809 - S: man, Anthony to Major Dyer - A: William
Gillian.
179. RB2,p81 - Inv of Sales: Samuel Smith - July Session 1809 - A: William Smith - B: Abner Dement, John
Roach, Alex. Carmichael, William Siith, Mrs. Polly Snith, Sanuel Lovelss, John Win, Robert Smith, Jr.,
Drury Rives, Nathan Redding, Mrs. Mary Smith, Robert Snith, Sen., William Jones, Thomas Donnell, James
Vann, Robert Warnick, Edward Good, John Seratt, John Beadley, George Gibson, Jones Sowel, John
Goodrich, Alex. McCulloch.
180. RB2,p82 - WILL: Thomas Welch - DOW: 14 Hay 1809 - F: 11 Jul 1809 - verbal will to James Noman, again
on 18 May 1809 - W: James Caldwell, Aaron Oliphant, Joseph Noman - Wife: Rachel - 4d: Rachel Welch,
Lydia Welch, Rabekah Welch, Catharine Noman and her husband, John Noman.
181. RB2,p83 - WILL: Francis HcBride, Senior of Rutherford Co., H - DOW: 19 Dec 1807 - F: 20 Oct 1809 -
Oldest s: Isaiah HcBride - d: Martha Sianons -gs: Francis HcBride - gd: Hartha L. HcBride (not yet 15)
s: Samuel HcBride - E: Janes Sharp, Theophilus Cannon, Sanuel HcBride - W: John Stockard, David
Magness.
182. RB2,p85 - WILL: Elizabeth Davis of Rutherford Co., TN - DOW: 11 Sep 1809 -F: 30 Oct 1809 - d: Elizabeth
Davis - s: Henry Bishop - s: Willian H. Davis - sons-in-law: Robert Elliot, John Irwin - S: girl, Silla
to Eliza-beth; boy, Sampson to Henry Bishop; woman, Dolle to Williai - E: John Irwin, Robert Elliot -
W: Janes Sharp, Harcus Sharp, Isabella Hartin.
183. RB2,p86 - Inv: Sanuel Williams - R: 20 Oct 1809 - A: Elizabeth Williams -S: 10.
184. RB2,p87 - Hartford Co., NC 15 Oct 1806 - David Dinery, mulatto lan age 21 years is free bom reioving
to State of Tennessee... signed: Cardall Bynun, Thomas Williams, William Stephenson, Benjamin Howell,
Benjamin Brown.
185. RB2,p87 - Inv: John Richnond - taken 30 Dec 1809 - A: Joseph Bownan.
13
186. RB2,p88 - Sales: Harrison Gillian - R: 14 Jun 1810 - A: Williaa Gillian -Hire: 2 negroes - 0: Capt.
Burriss, Janes Henderson, Obediah H. Benge, Thonas Mitchell, Thonas Threat - C: Jaaes Sharp, Daniel
Bowaan, Theophilis A. Cannon - EO: Janes Henderson, John Spence, Obediah M. Benge, Thonas Gillian,
William Huaphreys, Thonas Mitchell, "Deaderick the silver-saith in Nashville", George Sinpson, Hathew
McClanahan, Thonas Threat, John Henderson, Alex. Porter, Hat. Haley, Robert Hancock, W.A. Sublet, L.
Mcintosh, _? Ladford, W. W. Searcy, Norton Gwin, Jonathan Hale, Thonas Sappington, John Griffin -
B: Thonas Mitchell, Hilliaa Laughlin, Daniel Boatright, John Tarpley, Joel Dyer, Benj. Shipley, Alex.
Carnichael.
187. RB2,plOO - Inv: Hilliaa Tucker - sold 31 May 1810 - A: Susannah Tucker, Jaaes Sharp - B: Susanna
Tucker, Saauel Bowaan, Gwin Howell, Robert Hudspath, Janes Sharp, Jaaes Bass, Henry H. Marable, Lewis
Whitley, Elvender Squares, John Stockard, Isaac Shelby, John McPeak, Alexander Keraikel [Carnichael],
Jaaes McKee, Hilliaa Bennett, Cader Deaent, John Gasaway, John Hill, John Griffin, George Douglas, John
Hague, Jaaes Wills, Alfred Hallis, Lodowick Hilliaas - 0: Radford Gun, Saauel Hebane, Thoaas Evans,
Joel Dyer, Jaaes Favour, Janes Bulla, John Howell, dec'd, Richard Ballard, John Anthony, A. HcCrevin,
George Carridine, Jaaes Rodgers, Patrick Callahan, Caleb Burton, M. L. Stilley and Elizabeth, John
Tench, Isaac Hants, Hilliaa Locke, Hilliaa Bowen, Thos. Nelson, Zachariah Posey, Spencer Bevers, Abraa
Bevers, Capt. McClannahan.
188. RB2,pl06 - Sett: Charles Ray - 26 Sep 1810 - A: David Hilliaas, Sarah Ray C: John Thonpson, Hugh
Robison - EO: Doctor Bedford, Doctor Armstrong, Doctor Soffington, David Hilliaas.
189. RB2,pl07 - Inv: Elizabeth Davis, Junior - R: 26 Nov 1810 - A: Hilliaa H. Davis - B: Hilliaa H. Davis,
Easter Bell, Fanny Dickson, Robert Elliott, John Irvine, Henry Bishop, Asahal Dickson, John L. Davis,
Hannah Irvin -S: girl to Hilliaa H. Davis - "one note of hand on Jaaes E. Davis a legacy left her by
Walter Davis, deceased, ? the hands of the executor of Elizabeth Davis, Senior, deceased".
190. ?J32,pll0 - Inv: Elizabeth Davis, Senior - R: 8 Dec 1810 - Heirs: Elizabeth Davis, Junior; Henry Bishop;
John R. loin; W. H. Davis - S: 1 girl to Elizabeth; 1 boy to Henry; 1 woaan to John and W. H.
191. RB2,plll - Sett: Thoaas Hutchinson - R: 27 Dec 1810 - A: Sarah Hutchinson EO: John Swift, Charles
Kavanaugh, Nathaniel Overall, Beal Parkhurst, Henry Goodloe, John Griffin, Hilliaa Thoaas - C: Hilliaa
H. Searcy, John Miller, John Edwards.
192. RB2,pll3 - HILL: Major Hilliaa Buckner, Junior of Suaner Co., TN - D08: 9 Sep 1807 - F: 3 Jun 1811 -
Wife: Polly Buckner - "ay children" - S: Hinney, Nelly, Austin and Grace to be sold - E: friends,
Edward Sanders, Janes Sanders - H: Wiley Lassiter, Austin McWade.
193. RB2,pll4 - WILL: Jaaes Sharpe of Rutherford Co., TK - DOW: 30 Sep 1809 -F: 3 Jun 1811 - Wife: Rachel
Sharpe - "our children" - s: Marquis Sharpe (eldest); Theophilus A. Sharpe; Alfred Sharpe; John Sharper
Jaaes Horriss Sharpe -daughters: Sana Sharpe; Peggy Cassile [?Carliie] Sharpe; Jeaiaa Alexander Sharpe
3: Candis, Aaos, George, Milton, Dorcas, Daniel, Marg, Levi, boy Aaos to Theophilus; boy, Milton to
Marquis; boy, George to Alfred; boy, Daniel to John? boy, Levi to Jaaes; girl Candis to Eaaa; girl
Dorcas to Peggy; girl, Nancy tc Jeaiaa - "Cordance/?Candis, Aaos, George, Milton, Dorcas, Daniel,
Nancy, Levi first to wife... then to children" - "when the boys are 20 years of age and the girls are
18 years of age" - E: Friends, John Sharpe, Theopbilus A. Cannon, Marquis Sharpe - W: Henry Bishop,
Williaa H. Davis, Theophilus A. Cannon - CODECIL : 1 Dec 1810 "prospect of another legatee to be added
to the faaily by ay wife Rachel Sharpe" - W: Jaaes Martin, Nancy Wilson, John Sharpe, Theophilus A.
Cannon L: Jaaes Ascey, Jaaes Roseberry.
194. RB2,pl22 - Sett: John McFerron - 12 Jan 1811 - A: Saauel HcFerron - C: John L. Jetton, John Miller,
E.3. McCoy - EO: John Gillespie, George Colber, Jaaes Gillespie, Thoaas Sappington, Jaaes Sharpe, Owen
W, Edwards, Thcnas Washington, Susanna Cain, George Siapson, Hilliaa H. Searcy, John Miller, Hilliaa
Ward - B: Saauel McFerren, John Gillespie, Jereaiah McFerren, David Jones, Robert Ross, Jaaes McFerrin,
John Pain/Payne, Jaaes Wills, Mary McFerren, Williaa Hountgoaery, Jaaes Billingsly, Jacob Pain/Payne,
Robert Baldrige.
14
195. RB2,pl28 - Sett: Robert Marly - 1 Apr 1811 - A: William Haben - C: John L. Jetton, John Miller -
Security: Prichard Alexander - B: William Haben, John L. Jetton, James Horaan, Isaac Shipman, Samuel
Sebastian, Andrew Bale, Prichard Alexander - EO: David Gordon, William May, "by the hands of Samuel
Haben", Samuel Long, John Anthony, John Spence, John Davis, Henry Davis, George L. Gray, Francis B.
McCoy, John Cragg, Francis Saunders, Wilson Kerr (school teacher).
196. RB2,pl30 - Inv: James Sharpe - July 1311 - E: John Sharpe, Theos. A. Cannon, Marquis Dl. Sharpe - S:
10 negroes remaining as per will - 0: Judgient against John Ervin, John HcPeak, Clement N. Peal, Peter
LeGrand, Joshua Phelps, Thomas Mitchell - open accounts: Thomas Mitchell, John Ervin, Ephraia Phelps,
Nicholas Biler, Francis A. Ramsay, Peter Garrison, National Barksdale, John Sharpe, Hark Mitchell,
Theophilus A. Cannon.
197. RB2,pl31 - Estate: Prudence Miller - R: 4 Sep 1811 - A: James Sharpe, dec'd - Guardian of heirs:
William Gowen - 0: John William Arnold, William Nash, William Tucker, Theophilus A. Cannon, William
Gillian, Thomas Gillian, John Bradly, Andrew McMeekin, Samuel Bowman, Nicholas Biler, Alfred Wallis,
John Hutton, Thomas Mitchell, Mark Mitchell, William Drennon - E: John Sharpe, Theo. A. Cannon, Marquis
Dl. Sharpe.
198. RB2,pl32 - Sett: Elias Browning - 1 Jul 1811 - allowed $40 for Elizabeth Browing maintaining 3 orphans
of Elias Browning for 2 years - EO: Burwell Pusy, Thomas Pully, William Collister, Hugh Crofford, John
Sowell - C: David Fleming, John Edwards, James Gillespie.
199. RB2,pl33 - Inv: James Freeman - 25 Jun 1811 - 0: G. Rideout.
200. RB2,pl34 - List of estate: Thomas White - 18 Apr 1811 - A: John L. Jetton "sold at auction at dwelling
house of Elizabeth White" - B: Elizabeth White, Aaos McCoy, Robert Kelton, Ezekiel Dickson, John L.
Jetton, William Pace, John Jetton for wife, William M. Hall, George Wallace, James Neely, Isaac Jetton,
James Noraan, James Wilson - 0: Hugh Kirk, John Griffin.
201. RB2,pl36 - Inv: Richard W. Caswell - R: 12 Oct 1811 - A: Sarah Caswell -38 S: Dick, Wile, Robin, Bill,
Cardina, Jim, Binah, Kate, Rachel, Jude, Aaey, Clara, Rhoda, Grace, Silvia, Violet, Cinthia, Robin,
Tom, Jenny, Cesar, Catzey, Rose, Mary, Addick, Princes, Henry, Charity Dryden, Edaond, Albert,
Shadrach, Evelina, Jack, Bob, Sineca, Kate - "of the above Bob and Sineca have been sold to Joel
Childress and Kate is dead" - "4 more slaves bom since death of Richard Caswell": Levina, Fanny,
Letitia, Jellark.
202. RB2,pl38-146 - Sett: Thomas Bedford - Oct Session 1811 - R: 17 Dec 1811 -HEIRS: William H. Bedford,
Thomas Bedford, Benjaain Bedford Littleberry Bedford, George A. Bedford, Nancy Bedford - Guardian for
heirs: John R. Bedford - EO: J. P. Wiggins, John Dickinson, Littleberry Bedford, Jaaes William Cuaains,
Jaaes Colesan, John Hemdon, King and Carson, Robert Searcy, Robert Weakly, Jaaes Burnett, J. L.
.Armstrong, J. Pitt ? wine, John Griffin, Glover Banton, Fountaine Lester, Samuel HcNeese, Saauel
Henderson, M.P. Currin, David Fleaaing, Benjamin Bedford, Jaaes Rucker, John Caulfield, George A.
Bedford, Doctor Kemp, William Lentz, Haj. McCoraaJc, Doctor Heraan, George Poyzens, Mrs. Cathy J. Beard,
Capt. Robert Purdy coiaonly called Caslin, George Ridly, Doctor Armstrong, A.H. Harris, N.W. Williaas,
Thoaas Talbott, Aquilla Suggs, Robert White, Jenkins Whiteside - "Fortiscue (Post) Whittle,
Adiinistrator of Williaa Davis, dec'd, appoints Daniel Doby of Mecklenburg County, attorney, for debt
owing by Thoaas Bedford and Joseph Coleaan formerly of Mecklenburg" -Witnesses on a note: Ann Bedford,
Sr.; Ann Bedford - C: George Siapson, John Coffar, William Nash.
203. RB2,pl46 - Add'l return on estate: Thoaas White (deceased 22 Aug 1811) -R: 18. Dec 1811 - A: John G.
Jetton - 0: Jaaes Coason, Alexander Gregory, Robert Duckworth, Williaa White, John Cook.
204. RB2,pl46 - Inv: Benjaain Bugg - R: 18 Dec 1811 - A: Tabitha Bugg.
205. RB2,pl47 - Inv: Jaaes Thompson - R: 13 Dec 1811 - E: John Thoapson, Lewis Stevens.
206. RB2,pl47 - Inv: Williaa Buckner - 7 Oct 1811 - R: 18 Dec 1811 - S: 4 sold as per will - E: Jaaes
Sanders.
L5
207. RB2,pl47 - Sale of prop: John Norman - 27 Aug 1811 - E: Tho. A. Cannon, Joseph Whitsett - "the 2/3 of
the property bequeathed to his wife, Margaret Noraan, at her marriage is directed to be sold for use
of children" - B: John Stockird, Joseph Whitsett.
208. RB2,pl49 - Sett: Jaaes Morton - R: 18 Dec 1811 - B: Joseph Morton, George C. Booth, Guilford Dudley,
Thomas A. Claiborne, Charles Collis, Edward Haly, John Bostick, Owen Edwards, David Dicky, John Chisae,
Lewis Garner, Jaaes Morton, John Smith, Jaaes Garner, John Covinton, John Howell, Bird Nance, Gwin
Howell - S: 1 negro, Fanny bought by Joseph Morton; 2 negroes bought by Owen Edwards; one negro bought
by William W. Searcy; 1 negro bought by Williaa Season; 4 negroes bought by Joseph Morton - A/C: L.
Davis, James Wills, James Whitsett.
209. RB2,pl51 - WILL: Jaaes Thompson - DOW: 12 Sep 1311 - R: 18 Dec 1811 - half brother: Lewis Stephens -
"whole blood brothers and sisters'1 - W: H. Haiilton, Aron Webb, A. Kinnard - E: Lewis Stephens, John
Thompson.
210. RB2,pl52 - Inv: Williaa Lofton - R: 18 Dec 1811 - S: 7 - E: Levina Lofton, William Lofton.
211. RB2,pl53 - Sale of Inv: Jaaes Freeman - R: 13 Dec 1811 - A: John Anthony, Jaaes Wells - 0: Gordon
Redcoat
.
212. RB2,pl54 - Inv: John Cavcate - R: 18 Dec 1811 - A: Samuel Bowman, Joseph Bowman.
213. RB2,pl55 - Sett: Samuel McCullock - [no date] - A: Benjamin McCullock - d: death of Lucy, youngest
child - widow's dower delivered to James Jackson's wife's "1/3" negroes: Syrus; Big Dick; Francis;
Jobe; Easter; Betty, Tony/Sing's wife; Elsey and 2 children - "to child's 2/3 portion" negroes: Little
Dick; Sam; Abraa; Jubiter? July; Little Sam; Ben; Billy; George; Jack? Simon; Young Betty; Lucy and
Abraham her son; Violet and her 2 children, Hariah and Sarah - EO: Dement "for hiring negroes",
Deaderick and Pettway, Nelson Haaaill, Thomas Talbott, Williaa Boyland, Williaa Seaton, Harwood and
Willard, Thomas Hall, Williaa Burt, Elisa Ashe, Duncan Caisson, Elisha T. Hall, Alexander McCullock,
James Webb, John Reid, Clei Nash - O: Thoaas Watson, John D. Fly, Nelson Haaail, Harvey Nevil, Matthew
Fray, Williaa W. Jones, Joseph John Daniel, Duncan Cameron - C: Jaaes L, Armstrong, William W. Searcy,
Theo. A. Cannon.
214. RB2,pl58 - WILL: Edmund Johns of Rutherford Co., TN - DOW: 20 Mar 1811 -Proven in part Oct Session 1811
P.: 24 Feb 1812 - Wife: Sarah Johns - brother: John - s: Jack Haden Johns, Madison Johns, Frederick
Johns - d: Martha Johns - S to wife: aan, Bill; aan, Joe; girl, Jane (pregnant - S to Madison: girl,
Clary - S to Frederick: Jane's unborn child - S to Martha: girl, Ab'oy? boy, Saa - S: wife and my
brother, Abner Johns - W: Gross Scruggs, John Johns.
215. RB2,pl60 - WILL: Williaa Roberts of Rutherford Co., TN - DOW: 21 Oct 1311 R: 14 Mar 1812 - Wife: Nancy
Roberts - s: Jesse - d: Lucy, Nancy, Betsy -"other children not named in this will" - S to wife: aan,
Harry - S to Jesse: man, Harry [this slave aight be the same as one to wife ed.] - 9: Toliver Siapson,
Williaa Siapson.
216. RB2,pl62 - Sett: James .Arnold - 6 Dec 1311 - A: Jaaes Taylor - E0 Josian Elliott- Davis and Washington
Jackson, Thoaas Washington, Thoaas Thompson, Mrs. Arnold, Stephen Taylor - C: H. Robison, 3, Beesiy,
John Henderson.
217. RB2,pl63 - Inv: Benjamin Bugg - 15 Nov 1311 - A; Tabitha Bucg - B: Henry Seat, Brooking Burnett,
Jonathan Jones, Jersaiah Burnett, Robert Burnett, Joseph Burnett, Williaa Stokes, Braxteh Marable,
Jesse Ward, Williaa Burnett, Williaa Finnery, John Waddell, Williaa Griffin, John Balden.
213. RB2,pl65 - WILL; Hugh Prior Brawly of Rutherford Co., TN - DOW; 12 Nov 1311 F: not shown - Wife: Ruth
Brawly - s: Hugh Brawly, Levi Brawly, John Brawly, Prior Brawly - S; wife and son, John Brawly - &#187;:
Joshua Barton, John Bankhead, Daniel Webb - CODECIL : 12 Nov 1311 - d: Polly Crownover, Ruth Brawly,
Cintha Brawly.
219. RB2,pl67 - Sale: Richard H. Caswell - 28 Dec 1811 - A: Sarah Caswell - B: Williaa Lytle, John Lytle,
John Thoapson, Joseph Lawrence, Thoaas B. Saith, Benjaain Ransoa, Enoch Head, Robert Jarratt, John
Tilford, Thoaas F. Thompson, Bennett Saith, Jaaes Pace, John Irvine, Janes B. Arastronq -0: Hilliaa
Howell, Janes Whiteside, J_ Loony.
220. RB2,pl72 - Inv: Ahrahaa Paltet - F: 14 Mar 1812 - A: Jane Paltet, Thoaas Knox, Jaaes Berry - 0: Williaa
Collins, Hilliaa Ingraa, Janes Beaty, John Stites, Joseph Young.
221. RB2,pl74 - Sales: William Loftin - Jan Court 1812 - E: Williaa and Levina Loftin - B: Jesse
Featherston, Henry H. Hutson, Thoaas R. Ivy, Saauel Gillespie, Jaaes Higgins, Jaaes John, Thoaas
Killough, Willian Loftin.
222. RB2,pl74 - Sett: Thoaas White - 6 Jan 1812 - A: John L. Jetton - C: John Miller, David Fleaaing, Jaaes
Sharpe.
223. RB2,pl76 - Inv: Edmond Johns - taken 25 Har 1812 - E: A. Jo^ns -S: Will, Joseph, Jenny, Clary, Abby,
Saa, Stephen - EO: John Thoapson, Daniel Parker, Abraa Thoapson.
224. RB2,pl77 - Inv and sales: Saith Ogilve - 6 Nov 1811 - R: 22 Apr 1812 - A: John Ogilve, Frances Ogilve -
B: Haryaan Landroa, Frances Ogilve, Charles Wade, John Adcock, Henry Walker, Beverly Harris, Janes
Allison, Jaaes Wright, Andrew Adcock, John Ogilve, Holbert Higgins, Henry Green, Alsea Harris,
Nathaniel Robertson, Jaaes Reay, Archibald Harris, Richard Ogilve, Jonathan Heflen, Luke Tippit,
Richard Wright, Barnes Adcock, John Laab, Charles Holden, Spencer Holden, John Webb, Williaa Newson.
225. RB2,pl80 - Sale: Prestly Featherston - 18 Jan 1812 - R: 22 Apr 1812 - A: Jesse Featherston - B: Jesse
Featherston, Eldry Lofton, Nancy Featherston, Williaa Hayfield, Jacob Curry, Aaos A. HcCoy, David
Thoapson, Williaa Claton, Jesse Perry, Alexander Gregory, Williaa Wright, Saauel Gillespie [spelled
"Glaspie" ed.], Williaa H. How, David Mayben, Frances B. McCoy.
226. RB2,pl82 - Estate: John Noman - R: April Court 1809 - E: Theo. A. Cannon Widow: Margaret Noraan - "his
children should receive 2/3 upon her narriage" - W: Jaaes L. Arastrong, Williaa Searcy - EO: John
Spence, Jaaes Sharpe, Jr., John Dickinson, Theos. A. Cannon, Brackaan Coleaan.
227. RB2,pl84 - WILL: Williaa Loftin, Rutherford Co., TN - DOW: 17 Jun 1811 -R: Oct tern 1811 - Wife: Levina
Loftin - s: Thoaas Loftin, Eldridge Loftin, Williaa Loftin, Henry Loftin - d: Polly Brothers, Elizabeth
Cole, Nancy Featherston, Levina Loftin, Lucy Loftin - S to wife and then to Thoaas: Matt and his wife,
Sail; woaan, Darkis; boy, Saa - S to Polly: woaan, Nelly - S to Elizabeth: woaan, Tener; girl, Annebar
S to Nancy: girl, Kirlinda - S to Eldridge: boy, Jack - S to Levina: girl, Mary; boy, Hatt - S to
Lucy: woaan, Darkis - L: Jaaes Johnston, Saauel Hands, Jaaes Higgins - E: wife and sons Williaa and
Thoaas - W: Jesse Featherston, Jaaes Barfield, A. Pearce.
228. RB2,pl88 - Sett: John Andrews - 1 Jul 1812 - R: 20 Jul 1812 - A: Alexander McCune/HcEwin, Joshua Barton
"sale and hire of negroes".
229. RB2,pl88 - Inv: Absolua Williaas - R: 20 Jul 1812 - A: John Wallace -S: Ban, Will.
230. RB2,pl89 - Estate: Richard W. Caswell - R: 20 Jul 1812 - A: Benjaain McCullock on behalf of wife - S:
2 sold - EO: Elihu S. Hall, Thoaas Caap, Phillip L. Lowe, Joel Dyer, Saauel Caapbell, Jaaes Caapbell,
Abraa Thoapson, John H. Road, Jaaes Henderson, Williaa Warren - C: Jaaes L. Arastrong, Robert McCoabs,
Theo. A. Cannon.
V)
231. RB2,pl90 - John Coffee, Alexander HcCullock and Blackman Colenan appointed to April term 1812 to
receive the books and papers in the Registers Office fron John Dickson fomer register with true list
following: Deeds - 145, Grants - 146:
William Nash and Janes W. Jackson to Janes Merry - 25 Jun 1811.
Janes Neely to Isaac Craid - 30 Jul 1804.
Jaaes HcGoughey to Williaa Gannill - 24 Aug 1809.
Sanuel HcBride to Jonathan Ball - 5 Apr 1809.
Janes HcGoughey to John Kiabro - 24 Aug 1809.
John HcPeak to Janes Miller - 25 Feb 1808.
Daniel HcKissick to John Moore - 15 Aug 1806.
John M. Foulin to John Stoss - 25 Dec 1804.
Charles HcCord to William Batey - 31 Oct 1811.
Sanuel McBride to John R. Bedford - 7 Oct 1805.
Janes H. Lewis to Conaissioner of Jefferson - 9 Apr 1807.
Collin HcDaniel to Lucket Davis - 12 Jan 1807.
Janes Mulhevin to William flicks - 13 Dec 1804.
Sanuel Lang to Daniel Boatright - 29 Mar 1805.
Michael Kinnard to William Matthews - 3 Jan 1809.
Williaa Jones, Jr. to Williaa Mankin - 9 Nov 1809.
Robert Irvin to John Henderson - 27 Jun 1799.
John Jones, Executor of John Jones, deceased to John Overton and Jenkin
Whiteside - 12 Feb 1806.
Edward Moore to Jaaes Espey - 5 Apr 1809.
Michael Kinnard to Charles HcCord - Oct 1806.
Michael Kinnard to Nathaniel Kinnard - 4 Jul 1807.
Robert C. Kennedy to Robert C. Foster - 3 Nov 1808.
Anthony Kinnard to Aron Webb - 14 Mar 1810.
Robert Hancock to Williaa W. Searcy - 30 Sep 1809.
Robert Hancock to Charles Kavanaugh - 30 Sep 1809.
William Hope to Daniel Nelson - 4 Oc 1809.
William Howell to Miles Truman - 13 Hay 1809.
Hanhon Hunt to Jonathan flail - 6 Jul 1807.
Clement Hall to Thomas Washington - 29 Apr 1807.
Henry Killin to Morgan Killin, Darkis Killin, Cashomoy Thacker Killin -
2 Jul 1810.
John McCoy to John Harris - 13 Jan 1806.
Ebenezer Alexander to Jaaes HcGoughey - 25 Dec 1805.
Jonathan Anthony to John Anthony - 20 Mar 1806.
Nathan Allen to Solomon Wren - 28 1808.
Aaos Balch to Archibald White - 26 Aug 1789.
Samuel Barton, Sr. to Saauel Barton, Jr. - 10 Mar 1798.
O.H. Benge to Jesse Wilson - 14 Jul 1808,
Williaa Blackmore to Wallis Eastel - 23 Jul 1306.
O.M. Benge to Deaderick &amp; Petway - 5 Aug 1807.
James Blackman to Bess Carr - 16 Apr 1806.
Owen Edwards to John Anthony - 6 Apr 1807.
John Benton, lawful attorney of Robert Benton to William Tucker - 18 Jan 1810.
David Fleming to Thomas Jarrall - 17 Sep 1808.
William Gillian to Daniel Boatright - 8 Aug 1808.
Joseph Gowen to Williaa Gowen - 1 Har 1807.
Bill of Sale: O.M. Benge, Sheriff to John HcNairy for S: Patience, Daniel,
Rachel, Ephraim, Lysh, flannah and John - 30 Jun 1806.
Frederick Barfield to Janes Barfield - land and 2 S: boys, Ishaa and Charles - 17 Jun 1807.
Aron Gaabill to Joseph Morton - 30 Jan 1809.
John Grayson to Gross Scruggs - 1 Jun 1808.
232. RB2,pl90 continued
James Gillespie to John Coventon - 8 Feb 1810.
Coaaissioners of Jefferson to Robert Weakley - 26 Dec 1805.
Coaaissioners of Jefferson to Joseph Cook - 26 Dec 1805.
Coaaissioners of Jefferson to William Carlisle - 26 Dec 1307.
Coaaissioners of Jefferson to Harrison Gillian - 26 Dec 1305.
Coaaissioners of Jefferson to Williaa P. Anderson - 26 Dec 1305.
Coaaissioners of Jefferson to Norton Gun - 26 Dec 1805.
James Clement to Lewis Banton, Guardian of the heirs of John Carter, deceased
- 24 Apr 1809.
Amos Balch to Charles HcCammon - 26 Aug 1789.
John Boyle to Gross Scruggs - 27 Dec 1808.
Amos Balch to Jaaes Bradshaw - 25 Aug 1789.
John R. Bedford to Fountain Lester - 9 Oct 1805.
John Blair to Samuel HcFaddin - 4 Jan 1806.
John Brown to Thomas Johnson - 29 Aug 1803.
Jesse Bean to Jesse Barton - 9 Jan 1808.
Frederick Barfield and Williaa Barfield to Benjamin D. Wills - 27 Oct 1808.
James Barfield to Wiiliau H. Hall - 16 Feb 1808.
John Caffrey to Reuben Sanders - 2 Jul 1805.
Theophilies A. Cannon to Robert Weakley - 2 Oct 1309.
Commissioners of Jefferson to Thomas Stone - 7 Jan 1803.
Jaaes S. Conway to Jackson and Caffery - 3 Apr 1809.
Charles Carroll to Jaaes Matthews - 30 Jul 1310.
Charles Carroll, Sen. to James Matthews - 17 Mar 1809.
John Davis to Jaaes Morton - 3 Jul 1310.
John Dcnnelson to Francis Pennington and others, heirs of Jacob Pennington,
deceased - 5 Dec 1809.
Benjaain Edwards to Presley Edwards - 11 Jun 1308.
Anthony Foster to Jesse Bean - 16 Feb 13C2.
Hugh McCaivey to Obediah M. Benge - 20 Dec 1809.
Sen;eil Ward to John 3eniiaon - 19 Sep 1310.
George Moore to Richard N. Teco - 19 Nov 1310.
Williaa Thweatt to Williaa Rowtson - 22 Hay 1811.
Robert HcConbs to Joseph Tennesson - 2 Oct 1810.
Saauel Richardson to Thoaas Hopkins - 31 Aug 1811.
John Griffin, Sheriff to John Wallace - 19 Jan 1311.
George Douglass to John P. Jaies, Sen. - 10 Jul 1311.
Williaa Hash to Henry McPeak - 16 Fab 1311.
John Coffee to Jaaes Bole - 2 Apr 1311.
Williaa Caldwell to Jaaes Morton - 1 Jun 1811.
Williaa Lofton to Jaaes Johnson - 1 Mar 1811.
David Fleaing to Moses Swan - 1 Jul 1811.
Saauel Brown to Jonathan Jones - 1 Sep 1809.
Jaaes and Elizabeth Matthews to Richard I. Cora - 30 Oct 1810.
Joseph Bowaan to Ben Carr - Nov 1310.
L. Sanders and George Saith to John HcKnight - 25 Dec 1310.
L. Sanders and George Saith to Jaaes McRniqht - 25 Dec 1810.
L. Sanders and **2orge Saith to Joseph Witherspoon - 25 Dec 1810.
? Arthur to John Fulton - 8 Jan 1811.
Saapson Sawyers to George R. Nash - 24 Jan 1809.
George R. Nash to George Siapson - 2 Mar 1809.
Williaa P. Anderson to George Simpson - 21 Jan 1811.
Luke Sanders to Cornelius Sanders - 15 Feb 1808.
Williaa Nash to John Johnson - 16 Nov 1809.
John Saith to Thoaas Hendrick - 3 Jan 1311.
Robert Cartwright to Jaaes Russell - 22 Sep 1310.
Saauel Caapbell to Edaund Jones - 5 Sep 1811.
:?
233. RB2,pl90 continued
Batey Armstrong to Frederick E. Becton - 30 Oct 1806.
John Crawford to William Beaty - 2 Jun 1810.
Robert Weakly to Theo. A. Cannon - 19 Aug 1809.
Joseph T. Rhodes to Jenkin Whitesides - 10 Nov 1806.
Robert Weakley to C: James Sharpe, John Hill, Hark Mitchell and Peter LeGrand
- 16 Feb 1806.
Best Ward to William Pope - 29 Sep 1809.
Best Ward to Berwell Ward - 10 Sep 1806.
Best Ward to Henry Stevens - 10 Feb 1808.
Jesse Wilson to John Swift - 23 Hay 1309.
James Wilson to Jackson and Caffery - 1 Dec 1809.
Reuben Windham to Edmund [I. or J.] Bean (cattle &amp; household furniture) -
11 Jan 1806.
Jenkins Whiteside to Samuel Brown - 4 Hay 1809.
John White to William Thweatt - 3 Oct 1809.
John Warrick to Joshua Zackery - 14 Jul 1808,
John Wills to Hardy Hurfree - 15 Jun 1805.
Robert Weakley and Thomas Bedford to Robert Hagness - 13 Jun 1303.
Jenkins Whiteside to Joel Dyer - 26 Jan 1807.
Jesse Wilson to Herbert Lanier - 15 Har 1808.
John P. Wiggins to Thomas and Morris Garrett - 22 Mar 1805.
Robert Weakley and Thomas Bedford to William Bowen - 13 Jun 1803.
Robert Weakley and Thomas Bedford to James Titus - 13 Jun 1803.
James Wade to James Stewart - 11 Jan 1809.
BOS: Hicajah Peacock to Norton Gum - S: girl, Hannah - 9 Feb 1808.
Elisha Prewett to Joseph Gowen - 28 Feb 1809.
John to Philip Saunders - 9 Feb 1307.
William A. Robison to Jaaes Blackian - 15 Nov 1809.
John Smith to Joseph Morton - 15 Jun 1807 and 17 Feb 1810.
Reuben Sanders to John Robins - 8 Apr 1806.
John Smith to Truman Williams - 20 Jun 1808.
John Griffin, Sheriff to William Arnold, Sen. - 13 Aug 1809.
Isaac Sebastian to Benjamin Shipley - 4 Jul 1808.
John Griffin, Sheriff to William Tail - 3 Oct 1810.
Thomas Sappington to Benjaiin Shipley - 19 Apr 1807.
James Titus to Isaac Sebastian - 26 Jul 1806.
Robert Weakly and Thomas Bedford to James M. Lewis - 13 Jun 1803.
Best Ward to Ishaa Revel - 30 Jan 1806.
Michael Gleaves to Martha and Rachel Turner - 22 May 1806.
William Martin to J_ Williamson - 10 Jan 1811.
William Martin to William Anderson - 10 Jan 1811.
William Anderson to Walter Keeble - 10 Jan 1811.
Alexander Hass, Administrator of Patrick Home, deceased to Samuel H.
Peyton - 9 Oct 1805.
State of TN to William W. Searcy.
State of TN to Jaaes Henderson.
State of TN to Richard Wright.
State of TN to William Thomas.
State of TN to John Taylor.
State of TN to Hatthew Miller.
State of TN to Jaaes Henderson.
State of TN to Robert Rankin.
State of TN to Green Hill [2 pieces of land].
State of TN to Robert Thompson.
State of TN to William Foster.
State of TN to John Buchanan and Moses Ridley.
State of TN to the heirs of John Patterson.
234. RB2,pl90 continued
State of TN to James Henderson.
State of TN to Abraham Paltet and Joseph Young.
State of TN to William Christmas.
BOS: Herbert Lanier to Richard Benges for S: girl, Creese - 28 Mar 1808.
BOS: Newit Ramsey to Lewis Banton - 16 Oct 1808.
BOS: John HcNairy to William Mitchell - S: woman, Hannah and her 2
children, Jack and Adar - 1 Apr 1809.
BOS: Obediah H. Benge to Jackson and Caffery - S: girl, Phillis -
5 Apr 1809.
BOS: William Eastin to Joel Dyer - S: 5, Patience and her 4 children -
14 Jun 1808.
BOS: Peter Grayson to John Reid - S: boy, Jack - 14 Dec 1807.
BOS: Peter Grayson and wife to John Reid - S: man, Dick - 19 Jul 1810.
BOS: Robert Bumpass to William HcFerron - S: boy, Thomas - 30 Oct 1809.
BOS: Janes Cummins to Thomas Yardley - S: woman, Jenny - 6 Aug 1808.
William Davidson to Abraham Tennison - 26 Mar 1811.
Thomas Roberts to Isaiah Renshaw - 1811.
Agreement between: Jonathan Anthony of Indiana Territory and Cleaent Hall
of Davidson Co., TN - 19 Mar 1806.
BOS: Hark Mitchell to Jonathan Jones - S: girl, Siller - 20 Feb 1808.
John Dickson to James HcKniqht - S: boy, Isaac - 31 Dec 1810.
POA: Thomas Ryan to Thomas Sappington - 20 May 1807.
POA: Thomas Taylor to John Bedford - 10 Apr 1807.
Edward Cox's survey processioned 27 Jul 1811 by Henry Conway, D.S.
Edward Harris to Robert Dickson - 26 Jan 1811.
William Gammill to John Kimbro - 15 Mar 1809.
William Nash to Isaac Saunders - 19 Apr 1810.
Hardy Pope to William Pope - 14 Dec 1809.
Joshua Hadley to Drury Vaughan - 26 Aug 1811.
William Loftin to Samuel Hand - 7 Jun 1311.
William Carlisle to John H. Gibson - 23 Sep 1311.
James McEwin, Sen. to Josiah HcEwin - 2 Jan 1811.
William Pope to Hardy Pope - 14 Dec 1809.
Simon Miller and Thomas Rucker to Lewellin Jones - 24 Jul 1811.
John Griffin, Sheriff to Charles Burruss - 8 Apr 1809.
William Nash to Joseph Gowen - 1 Oct 1810.
Joseph Dickson to Thomas Sherwood - 14 Aug 1811.
235. RB2,p200 - Sett: Elizabeth Davis, Junior - 8 Oct 1812 - R: 20 Nov 1812 -A: William H. Davis - EO: John
R. Irwin, Executor of Elizabeth Davis, Sen., William H. Davis, Jaaes L. Armstrong - C: Theo. A. Cannon,
James L. Armstrong, William Locke.
236. RB2,p201 - Inv: .Absalom Williams - 4 Jan 1813 - A:. John Wallace - O: Lewis Watson, Sen. of Franklin
Co.; Lewis J_, Jun.
237. RB2,p201 - Estate: Elizabeth Davis, Senior - EO: Robert Elliott, John L. Davis.
238. RB2,p201 - Estate: John Anders - 10 Nov 1812 - A: Saiuel Donnell, David Anders - S belonging to
legatees: Simon, Isaac, Ben and Seal - G: Charles Ready of John, Peggy HcKnight, Saauel, Henry, and
Persser[?] .Anders.
239. RB2,p203 - Estate: Robert Gasaway - A: George Furr - O: William Bowlen, John Warren.
240. RB2,p204 - WILL: John Gasaway of Rutherford Co. - DOB: 5 Dec 1812 - Wife: Peggy Gasaway - "Hy
children": Elenor Gasaway, Thomas, Nicholas, William, John, Patsy, Hannah Gasaway, Nancy Gasaway - E:
George Furr - W: William Bowman, Henry Ward, Hordecai Lillard.
::
241. RB2,p205 - HILL: Jacob Stroup of Rutherford Co., TN - DOW: 17 Aug 1310 -Wife: Elizabeth Stroup - s:
John Stroup "not yet 13" - "Hy children when they coae of age" - E: Wife and friend, Abraham Schriver -
W: George Wallace, Fielder Bevins.
242. RB2,p206 - Inv: Jaaes Ferguson - A: Elizabeth Ferguson.
243. RB2,p208 - Explanatory of an Inv: Richard W. Caswell - 5 Oct 1812 -R: 6 Mar 1813 - d: Jane C. Caswell -
s: William R. Caswell - A: Wife, Sarah Caswell, Benjaain HcCullock - S conveyed to Jane E. Caswell by
her father: Anny and her 2 children, Edaond and Albert; Violet; Jenny - S conveyed to William R.
Caswell "only son of said Richard": Grace, Addick, Princes, Henry, Rose - Note: Kate is a young child
of that naae has departed this life.
244. RB2,p208 - Sale: Absalom Williams - 3 Aug 1812 - R: 6 Har 1813 S: man, Will to Jaaes McMillan - 3:
Charles Williams, Constant Hardeaon -A: John Wallace.
245. RB2,p209 - Inv: William Dancy - R: 6 Mar 1813 - Widow - 0: John Jewel, George Perieloy[?] - A: John
Miller.
246. RB2,p209 - Inv: John Curlee - A: Cullin Curlee, Calvin Curlee - S: girl, age 14 or 15; boy, age 11 or
12; girl, age 9 or 10 - 0: Joseph Warren, Thoaas Knox, David Arnett, Sen., David Amett, Michael
Austin, William Stokes, Calvin Curlee.
247. RB2,p210 - Sett: Elizabeth Davis, Sen. - R: 7 Jun 1813 -E: John R. Irvin (one of the executors) - C:
John Johns, Sol. Beesiey, Jno. Edwards - 0: Henry Bishop, Robert Elliot, Porter Spence, Doctor Clement
H. Read, John L. Davis, Asahel Dickson - Justice of Peace: Williaa Nash, Thos. A. Cannon N: William
H. Davis.
248. :&lt;32,p214 - WILL: John Smith of Rutherford Co., TH - DOW: 27 Jul 1312 - F: 20 Apr 1313 - Sife: Polly -
d: Betsy, Patsy (not of age), Anna (not of age), Polly (not of age) - s: Jaaes (not of age) - 3 to
wife: Bob, Dave, Silvey, Hilly - S to Betsy: Mary, Lydia - 5. to Patsy: Charles, Saster - S to Anna:
Celph, Reuben - 3 to Jaaes: Jinny, George - S to Polly: Bill, Silecy - E: John Fulton, Joseph Morton,
James Morton - B: Samuel Watkins, John Fulton.
249. RB2,p215 - Inv: Saauel Killough - April ten 1813 - R: 1 Jul 1813 -A: John Killough - 0: David HcKen,
William Siapson, Jaaes Hoaes, Saauel Wallace, John Nerres. George P. Wallace.
250. RB2,p216 - Inv: John Gasaway - 3 Apr 1813 - R: 1 Jul 1813 - A: George Furr.
251. RB2,p219 - Add'l Inv: Edmund Johns - R: 1 Jul 1813 - E: Abner Johns.
252. RB2,p219 - Inv: Joseph Tweedy - R: 1 Jul 1313 - A: David Fleaaing -S: man, Harr;; woaan, Betty with
2 children, Quincy and Anderson; woaan, Phillis? child, Maria; boy, Hoses; boy, Tom; boy, Orange; girl,
Barbary; girl, Lucy; girl, Charity.
253. RB2,p220 - Inv: Jacob Stroup - Sale: 25 Jan 1813 - R: 1 Jul 1813 -E: Elizabeth Stroup, Abrahaa Schriver
3: Fielder Bevins, Sarah Halone, Robert HcCoabs, Allen Stroud, Wallace Stuart, A. Schriver, David
Fortenberry, W. Pace, Jonathan Hale, Richard L. Fleaing, John Pace, James Pace, Frederick Replage,
Joseph Stroup, John Bradly, B. Yardley, Leonard Keling, Joseph Thompson.
254. RB2,p221 - Inv: Ann Johns - 7 Apr 1813 - A: John Johns - S: aan, Thoaas; woaan, Betty; girl, Sinthy;
girl, Clary; boy, Rubin; child, Agness - 0: David Abbott, John Hoover.
255. RB2,p222 - Sales: Jaaes Ferguson - 10 Feb 1813 - A: Elizabeth Ferguson -B: David Patton, Enoch Dickson,
Horning Hobson, John Wade, James Vaughan, Jaaes Dickson, Deauculd Ferguson, William Dancy.
256. RB2,p224 - Sales: Ann Johns - 4 Sep 1813 - A: John Johns - B: John Edwards, Williaa Edwards, Walker
Ganaway, B. Coleman, Roger Ouarles, Abner Johns - C: E. Robison, John Thoapson, Thos. Hucbard - EO:
Doctor Sappington - S: Ton (hired froa Haj. Abbott).
22
257. RB2,p226 - WILL: Edward Eppes of Rutherford Co., TN - DOW: 24 Aug 1813 -R: 8 Nov 1813 - Wife: Rebecka
Eppes - "ay children not of age" - E: Rebecka Eppes, Daniel Eppes - W: John B. Prewit.
258. RB2,p228 - WILL: Jaaes Brookshire of Rutherford Co., TN - DOW: 16 Apr 1813 R: 8 Nov 1813 - Wife: Martha
Brookshire - "ay children" - 2 youngest children: Williaa and Joseph - E: friends, Thoaas Brown, George
Uselton, Thoaas Ashley - W: Daniel Green, Stephen Chalton, Frederick Brady.
259. RB2,p230 - Inv: John Thoapson - R: 8 Nov 1813 - 0: Cullin Blacknan, John Everist, Thoaas A. Bass, Hance
Haailton, Williaa Bennett, Urich Bass, David Thoapson, Jaaes Thoapson, Nathaniel Kinnard -.BO: Robert
Saith, Henry Thoapson, Anthony Kinnard, Enoch Head, Robert More, Joseph Matthis, John Kinnard, David
Thompson, John Fleming, Thomas Killough, William Ransom, Anson Webb, William Matthis, Daniel Potts,
Williaa Hill, Joseph Allen, Hary Landna, Williaa Rutledge, Robert Potts, Patrick Sutton, Sally
Thompson, Michael Kinnard.
260. RB2,p232 - Inv: William Kelton - 28 Sep 1813 - A: Elizabeth Kelton, James Kelton - 0: Benjaain Gilbert,
Joseph Biddley, Robert Jarrott, Edward Burgis, David Harris, Walter Sonils, Israel Gable, Caleb
Stovall, Hugh Kirk, Millaton Runnels, James Daugherty, Robert Kelton, Alexander Caruichael, Alexander
Lackey, Samuel B. Kelton, Elizabeth Kelton, Thomas B. Smith, John Davidson, John Drake, Jaaes Crosby,
William Smith, Sherwood Harris, John Coats, Robert Haabrick, Henry Conway, Talbott Mannen, Jases
Elliot, John Hewill, John Read, Robert Cartwright, John Griffin, George P. Wallace, Williaa Carter,
Patrick Sullivan, John Jetton, Adainistrator of Thos. Whiteside, James Kelton, Patton Anderson, Jaaes
Cumins, William Rutherford, John Jenkins, Jesse Rogers, Frederick Bradley, Reuben Scott, Reuben
Saunders, Thoaas Miers, Jereaiah Cloud, Cornelius Deliney, John Harden - EO: Jaaes Neely, Jaaes Benson,
Saauel Wallace - S: boy sold.
261. RB2,p235 - WILL: James Espie/Espey - DOW: 27 Dec 1811 - R: 10 Oct 1813 -s: Williaa and his wife,
Cynthia (only daughter-in-law); George; Robert -d: Polly Overall; Rachel Goodloe; Caity Espy; Harget
Youry and husband, Francis Youry - gd: William's oldest daughter "no sons as of writing of will" - gs:
Jaaes Car Bradshaw - Wife: Catey Espey - "my four youngest children": George, Robert, Caity, Sally -
E: friends, Nathaniel Overall, Henry Belah, Williaa Espey - S: wife is to have choice, rest divided
aaong children - W: J. Posey, Isaac H. Overall.
262. RB2,p239 - WILL: David Rogers of Rutherford Co., TN - DOW: 6 Jan 1313 - R: Apr tera 1813 - Wife: Peggy
oldest s: Robert - Wife to raise children "until boys wants to do for theaselves" - 2nd s: Williaa -
3rd s: John 4th s: James Barnet - d: Nancy, not carried - E: wife and brother-in-law, William Raasey -
S: woaan, Lydia, not to be sold out of family - W: James Raasey, Robert Raasey.
263: RB2,p241 - Sales: Jean Laughlin - R: 22 Nov 1813 - A: Joseph Duncan, Hugh Porter - B: Head Laughlin,
Elizabeth Smith, Joseph Young, Jaaes HcFerron, Joseph Duncan, Alexander D. Laughlin, Hugh Porter, John
Swift, James Laughlin, Williaa HcFerron, Ann Duncan, Jacob Rite, Patrick Scott, Susanna Cox, Willisson
Cox - S: 1 negro wench and child to Joseph Duncan.
264. RB2,p243 - Inv: Isaac Eaton - 2 Jul 1813 - A: Daniel Eaton, Rebecah Eaton.
265. RB2,p245 - Sales: Mary Stephens - R: 22 Nov 1813 - A: Henry Goodloe.
266. RB2,p247 - Inv: John Smith - 12 Jun 1813 - A: Joseph Morton, James Horton, John Fulton - S: 15.
267. RB2,p243 - WILL: Humphrey Nelson of Rutherford Co., TN - DOW: 24 Jul 1813 F: 19 Mar 1814 - Wife: Sally
Nelson - s: Beverly Nelson, Ambrose Nelson -d: Matilda Nelson -"rest of the children" - "younger
children" - S to Beverly: girl, Betty - E: Daniel Nelson, Beverly Nelson - W: Williaa Vaughan, Williaa
H. Wade, Williaa Edwards.
268. RB2,p249 - WILL: Elijah Fan [Fannj of Rutherford Co., TN - DOW: 6 Dec 1313 R: 19 Mar 1814 - Wife: Jane
ay 2 d: Jaaiaa, Tabitha - E: Benson Coulter, .Anderson Coulter, Jaaes Sutfin - W: Anderson Coulter,
Jaaes Sutfin.
269. RB2,p250 - Property Account: Elijah Fann - 11 Dec 1813 - F: 19 Har 1814 -"There is also coming to the
aforesaid Mr. Fann one part of his father's estate'1 - E: Jaaes Sutvin.
23
RB2,p251 - Aden Inv: wiiiiao Kelton - 18 Dec 1813 - "first inventory 28 September'1 - &#163;: Elizabeth
Kelton, James Kelton - B: Alexander Lackey, Robert Kelton, William Kelton, James Kelton.
271. RB2,p252 - Inv: James Moore - R: 21 Har 1814 - "killed in the Battle at Tallushatchee" - N: Alexander
McCane - A: James Higgins.
272. RB2,p253 - Inv: John Craig - R: 21 Har 1314 - A: Hugh Craig.
273. RB2,p253 - Inv: James Pogue - 10 Jan 1814 - E: Martha Pogue - A: James Gillespie - both James Pogue
and Martha Pogue are deceased - 0: Insolvent man being run away named Barborree.
274. RB2,p255 - Inv: James Espey - 24 Nov 1813 - E: Nathaniel Overall, Henry Belah, William Espey - The hire
of negroes: William Ramsey of Jim; Robert Ramsey of Gracy; Nicholas Whitelow of Richard; David Patton
of Winny; John Stockard of Sinai; William Espey of Washington; Thomas Mitchell of London 0: William
Smith, Philip Crowder, John Winnsett, John Arnold, P. Arnold, Leonard Miller, Alexander More, Cambell
Tucker, John Coffee, John R. Irwin, John B. Vaughan, William Bloodworth, William Espey, Zachariah
Posey, Benjamin Morrow, William Clare, John Harris, Overton Harris, Robert Bruce, John Espey, James
Stewart, Alexander HcCulloch, William Cunningham, Isaiah HcBride, John Hutton, William Burnett, Basil
West, Nancy Bedford, William Lannom, Hordecai Liilard, John Bruce, Capt.Williai Arnold, Francis
HcBride, Nathan Lannom, Isaac McBorey, Joseph Seratt, Tenis Moore, William HcBride, John Robertson,
John Lowrey, Joseph Wright, Lemuel Wright, Alfred Sharp, John Nash, Levi Linum, Thomas Bedford, Matthew
McClanahan, William Nash, Alfred Wallace, John Arnold, Junior, John P. H. Lenook, John Hepie-ton, John
Lemons, Andrew Mason, Suruy Linum, Jerry Akins, Francis Dickson, John Johnson, Henry HcPeake, John
Stuart, John McPeak, Brewery Warren, William Davidson, Leah Wade, William Phelps, John Marry, Joseph
Linum, John B. Irving, John Sharpe, William Robertson, Henry Clarke, Thomas Mitchell, William McKey,
William Davis, John Garrison, John Hogg, John Still, John Alexander, Sally Cunningham, Jno. William
Bradway, James HcHillen, William Poe, David Logan, Edaond Grenoye, Nicholas Beter, Benja-min Wilson -
B: Sam Bowman, Benjamin Ward, Joseph Wallace, Zachariah Posey, David Patten, William Gasoway, John
Stockard, John Carter, Robert Overall, Searce Gocdloe, Robert White, Strother Key, Matthew McClanahan,
Alfred Wallace, George Buchanan, Michael Lawrence, Robert Carden, Nyroe Bechard, Matthew Wells, William
Espey, Nat. Overall, William Blackaaore, Thomas Brevard, William Thomas, Thomas Whitsett, Dan. Hunens,
Atta Cantrell, William Lannui, Abner Dement, C. Dement, Thomas Evans, John Wallace, John Richards,
Best Ward, John Fonville, Nicholas Whitlow, Thomas Rutherford, John B. Irvin, William Ramsey, John
Gasoway, Braxton Harable, James Cunningham, Jaaes Eandarly, Charles Lower/, Walter Keeble, John
Bedvers, James HcMillen, George Furr, James Vaughan, Isaac Overall, William Drenon, Henry Hutton, Enoch
Dickson, Matthew Halley, Pheleaon G. Cothorn, Joshua Phelps, Joseph Whitsett, Jaaes Whitsett, Robert
Ramsey, Nathaniel Barksdale, Jases Daugherty, Joseph Wallace - 0: Henry Head, Williaa Harris, John
Harris.
275. RB2,p261 - Inv: Edward Eppes - R: 22 Har 1814.
276. RB2,p262 - Inv: Jaaes Brookshire - 8 Dec 1814.
277. RB2,p263 - Inv: Matthew Miller - R: 22 Mar 1814 - Inv by wife - A: Isaac Miller - 0: Thomas Stone,
Robert Balla, Dossin Adcock, 7_ Rushing, William Wevar, Nathan Nickles, James Rissen, Thomas T.
Harris, Caleb Stovall, Lewis Anthony, Isaac Miller - S: girl, Hannah.
278. RB2,p264 - List of Estate: Humphrey Nelson - 28 Dec 1813 - S: man and woman and 3 children - A: Sarah
Nelson, William Edwards.
279. RB2,p265 - Sale of Property r William Dausy or Dosy - 3 Oct 1812 - A: John Miller - B: Caty Dosy, Firney
Norman, Elkin Hand, William John, Margret Miller, Isaac Norman, Nicholas Woodfin, John Miller, Robert
Miller, Isaac Miller, John Simmons, Tiny White, James Hand, William Hall, William Mayfield, Benjamin
Waller, Matthew McClure, John Cole, John Botchell, Epps Taylor, John Johnson, William Gregory, Moses
McQuirtor.
280. RB2,p268 - Inv: William Knox - R: 1 Apr 1814 - A: Margret Knox, Joseph Bellew.
281. RB2,p269 - Inv: William Howell - R: 1 Apr 1814 - A: Mary Howell, John Gambill - 0: Asariah Kimbrow.
24
282. RB2,p270 - G to minor heirs of Janes Freeman, deceased 8 Jan 1814: Samuel Freeman.
283. RB2,p27l - Heirs of John Andrews: John Andrews, Perses Andrews, Peggy He. Andrews, Samuel B. Andrews -
3 Nov 1813 - G: Charles Ready.
284. RB2,p272 - Inv: John Wilson - R: 28 Apr 1814 - A: Robert Jetton, Samuel Wilson - B: Henry Trott, Robert
Jetton, Samuel HcHurry, Adkins Massy, Henry HcBroom, John Wilson, Samuel Wilson, Benjamin Hay berry,
Abraham Thompson - 0: John H. Patton.
285. RB2,p273 - Inv: William Smith - R: 29 Apr 1814 - A: Burwell Gasaway -S: man, George (not sold) - B:
John HcPeak, William Mitchell, Frederick Barfield, David Fall, William Gable, John Fill, William
Dickinson, William Lytle, Thomas P. N. Carny, John Daisy, John Flemming, John M. Tilford, Henry Winrow,
Samuel Kelton, William Allen, John P. Webb, Thos. G. Wadkins, Ezekiel Dickson, William Foster, Robert
Jetton, Thomas Hamilton, William Lewis, Gideon Jarratt, Abraham Thompson, John Allen, Ota Cantrell,
Andrew Griffin, Samuel F. Glass, William HcCall, Isaac Johns, Daniel Parker, James D. Corithers, B.
Ganaway, G. P. Wallace, John Smith.
286. RB2,p277 - Articles sold: William Howell - 12 Feb 1814 - A: Polley Howell, John Gambell - B: Isaac
Shelby, Gwin Howell, Shadrack Davis, Williaia S. Webb, Robert Harris, Thoaas Nelson, David Patton,
Samuel Asbery, James Morton, Henry Kirby, John Sanford, Constant Hardamon, Walter Jenkins, James B.
Edwards, Peter Reed, Thomas Harris, Thoaas Bass, Jesse Clark, Mary Howell, Ezekiel Pope.
287. RB2,p279 - Sale: John Craig - 28 Jan 1814 - A: Hugh Craig - B: Hugh Craig, John Sanford, John Beavers,
John Stockird, John Neal, Russell Sullivan, Robert Fanboro, Johnathan Cox, Josiah Davidson, Humphrey
Pope, John Smothers, Sarah Craig, Joseph Morton, James Beavers, Nathaniel Barksdale, David Gordon,
Obadiah Gamer, Braxton Marable, Willie Russell, John Richards, John Finch.
288. RB2,p282 - Inv: William Norman - R: 30 Apr 1814 - A: Henry Norman, James D. Wooten.
289. RB2,p283 - Sales: Dudly Matthew - 11 Apr 1814 - A: Joseph Newman.
290. RB2,p284 - Sales: William Knox - 1 Feb 1814 - A: Joseph Belew/Ballew/ Bellew, Margaret Knox - B: Thomas
Moore, James Manahan, James Gilleland, Henry Goode, James Thompson, John Waddell, Ambrose Petty, Thos.
Phillips, Isaiah Renshaw, William Youry, Jaaes Bellew, George Gillespie, Jane Thompson, John Barkley,
Elizabeth Thompson, Jonathan Hall.
291. RB2,p285 - Inv: Wilson Kerr - R: 2 May 1814 - A: Rachel Kerr, Robert Jetton - B: James Hayberry, John
Wilson, Lewis Anthony, Samuel Warren, Thoaas Marlin, Edward Crawford, Robert Jetton, David Flemming,
Daniel Hacrary, James Henderson, Robert Farabrow, Samuel Wilson, Henry Trott, William H. Robertson,
Ezekiel Ward, William Lewis, William Owen - S: negro boy, Bony, hired by Rachel Kerr - 0: Thoaas Smith,
Samuel Wilson, James Henderson, Allen Straiton, Walker Ganaway, James Childress, Alexander Cumains or
Cumins, Thomas Pinkerton, Alpha Kingsly.
292. RB2,p288 - WILL: Mary Whitnell of Rutherford County, Tennessee - DOW: 3 Jan 1814 - R: 2 Apr 1814 -
"being old and sick" - d: Mary Wadley, Lenaresa Wadley, Elander Wadley - s: Daniel Wadley, John Wadley,
Thomas Wadley, Samuel Wadley, William Wadley - E: Thoaas Nash - W: Thoaas A. Sikes, Jesse Sikes.
293. RB2,p289 - Estate: Edaund Johns - 12 Apr 1314 - E: Abner Johns - C: H. Robinson, J. Anderson, Solomon
Beesley - EO: Pritchett and Shall, Elliot Rucker, Burrel Ganaway, Cader Dement, Tilford and Gibson,
David Flemming, William Hall, Abram Thompson, Hugh Robinson, John Thompson, John Dickinson.
294. RB2,p291 - Inv: William Arnold - R: 29 Aug 1814 - E: Amy Arnold.
295. RB2,p292 - Inv: Mary Whitnell - R: 29 Aug 1814 - E: Thomas Nash.
25
296. RB2,p293 - Inv: Isaac Noman - R: 30 Aug 1314 - A: William Norman -"...a discharge for a tour of 3
months and 22 days in Capt. Carson's Co. in the 2nd Regiment of Militia; commanded by Col. A. Cheetam
under Haj. General Andrew Jackson on an expedition in the Creek nation..." - 0: Samuel Galaspy or
Gillespie, Bareman Norman, Daniel Keel, Pressley Norman, William Norman, James Norman, Alexander
Gregory, James Pritchards, John Johnson, Perry Moore.
297. RB2,p294 - Sale: James Moore - R: 30 Aug 1814 - A: James Higgins - B: Elizabeth Ann Umphreys or
Humphreys, James Higgins, William Morris, Jobe Dean, Matthew Johnson, Isaac Mayfield, Anthony Kinnard.
298. RB2,p295 - Estate: Gwillua Heloy - 23 Apr 1814 - "...set aside enough of crop for 1 year for widow and
family" - C: John Thompson, Abner Johns, John Anderson.
299. RB2,p295 - Humphrey Nelson, deceased - 4 Jun 1814 - Widow: Sarah Nelson -"...to lay off dower right
of Sarah Nelson and her 3 children" - C: William Vaughan, Joseph B. Johns, John Baker.
300. RB2,p298 - WILL: John Winn of Rutherford Co., TN - DOW: 8 Dec 1813 - R: 2 Nov 1814 - Wife: Pennelope
Winn - d: Harriot [apparently not of age]; Margaret [apparently not of age]; Ann HcKinney; Mary
Kirkland - s: Miner Winn; John Winn; Richard Francis Winn; William Wright Winn; Joseph T. Winn -
"...other 8 sons": Peter Winn; Daniel Winn; David Winn; Jefferson Winn, Robert Winn; Obed Winn; Zacko
Winn; Edward G. Winn - E: two sons, Joseph and Peter, and wife - S: girl Febe [Phoebe] to Harriot;
girl, Jane to Margaret - W: Charles Kavanaugh, James Dorothy [Daugherty], Peter Metheny.
301. RB2,p300 - Allowance to widow/family: Joseph McLaughlon - 12 Aug 1814.
302. RB2,p301 - Inv: William Arnold - R: 3 Nov 1814 - A: Amy Arnold - B: widow, John Wretton, John Brown,
William Mankins, William Norton, William Jacobs, William Mayfield, Joseph Gowen, John Newman, William
McFarlan, Jeremiah Jacob, Nicholas Edwards, Charles Lowe, Reuben Scott, Joshua Cates, Robert Miller,
William Brown.
303. RB2,p302 - Inv: James Thompson - R: 3 Nov 1814 - A: Jonathan Hall, Joseph Thompson - B: Joseph
Thompson, Calvin Curlee, Andrew McCabe, Randolph B. Hall, John Gilleland, Charles Ready, Robert Kirk,
Wright Whitfield, Anul Whitfield, Joshua Askill [Haskillj, Abram Tennerson, Thomas Burry, Jonathan
Sherry, William HcFerrin, Joseph Youry, Ambrose Petty, James HcGill, Jesse Brashear, Joseph Howell.
304. RB2,p303 - Inv: John May - 3 Nov 1814 - A: Woodson Hay, Robert Hay.
305. RB2,p304 - Inv: James Andrews - R: 3 Nov 1814 - A: Charles Ready -"...one ninth part of 4 negroes which
he hired from his father and are to be divided."
306. RB2,p304 - Sett: John Curlee - 23 Jul 1814 - A: Calvin and Cullin Curlee -C: Joshua Barton, Thomas
Berry, Henry Goodloe.
307. RB2,p305 - Add'l Inv: William Smith - R: 3 Nov 1314 - A: B. Gannaway B: William Knight, Thomas Woods,
William T. Henderson, Robert Clark, John Scott, John Burk, Satin Yancy, Mathew McClanahan, Joshua
Haskill, Alex Carmichael, Walker Gannaway.
308. RB2,?306 - Inv: Johnathan Cox - 4 Nov 1814 - A: Francis B, Cox.
309. RE2,p306 - Inv of Sale: Capt. Robert Bedford - R: 4 Nov 1814 - A: John Hoover - S: girl, Christa for
the widow, hired by John Spence; Lucinda hired to Soloaan Elam; Amey hired to John Caulfield; Clarissa
hired to John Spence; Nancy and 2 children hired to John Spence; Nicy and 3 children hired to John
Spence; Littleton hired to Robert Bedford - B: Abner Dement, John Carter, John Hoover, Hathew Haley,
William Robison, Hary C. Bedford, Gilliad Hubbell, Enoch Dickson, Elijah McClanahan, John Lenore,
William Easton, Cato Dement, Phillip Lenore, Daniel Trigg, David Keys, Kirby Cook, Anderson Johnston,
Thos, Boatwright, Reuben Woods, Francis Smith, Edward Hill, John Warren, William H. Wade, John Wade,
Samuel Warren, Janes Rucker, George Akin, James Daugherty, Robert Bedford, ? Littleton, Richard Walker,
John Ransom, Th. Cook, Isaac Shelby, Ota Cantrell, Dn. Cavanaugh, Mrs. Bedford, William Searcy, John
Johnson, Jno. Martin, Joseph B. Johns, Spencer Subtle, Samuel C. Rucker, William Robertson, John
Mathews, John Spence, John Johns, W. HcRich, W. W. Searcy, Beverly Nelson, Th. Rogers, Jno. Tarplay.
310. RB2,p311 - Inv: Joseph McLaughlin - R: 7 Nov 1814 - A: Archibald Hoore, Joseph McLaughlin - S: woian,
boy sold to Ruth McLaughlin; girl sold to Henry H. Hudson; boy sold to Samuel McLaughlin - B: Ruth
McLaughlin, Peggy HcLaughlin, Joseph McLaughlin, Absolon McLaughlin, Samuel McLaughlin, John Adcock,
Daniel Wadley, Azeriah Kimbro, John Bell, Archibald Hoore, William Caldwell, Larkin Johnson, Jaies
Higgins, Jonas Sikes, James Curry, Isaac Miller, Hoses Ashbrook, Johnathan Heflin, Francis C. Hash,
Elisha Smith, Williaa Hurphey, Williaa Lytle, John H. Tilford, John Henderson, Saiuel Pleuing, Willian
Pace, William Wallace, Robert Jetton, Fielder Bevins, John Allen, Ota Cantrell, Thoias P. Kearsey, John
Fleaaing, Thoaas Rucker, Lawson Davis, Daniel Harshall, B. Ganaway, John Hall, William Wade, G. P.
Wallace, William HcCall, Saauel Warren, Samuel Wilson, Henry Winrow, Jaaes Hontgoaery, Jaaes Roane,
Samuel F. Glass, George Seaton, Lewis Fleming, Alban Lowery, Benjamin Ransoa, Alex HcLaughlin, Th. A.
Sikes, John HcLaughlin, Henry Green, Allen Loury, Leon H. Wright, Alfred Hoore, Th. Keleough or
Killough, Richard Hight, Robert Hoore, Jobe Dean, Th. Palmer, Joshua Cates, Richard Rhodes.
311. RB2,p316 - Inv: Jaaes Brookshier - 8 Dec 1814 - E: Thomas ? .
END OF RECORD BOOK 2
RECORD BOOK 3
312. RB3,p3 - Return of Benjamin Bugg [probably deceased prior 7 Oct 1811] - R: 15 Dec 1814 - "...made by
Jeremiah Bumette in behalf of his wife, Tabitha Bumette formerly Tabitha Bugg, Admin." - EO: John
Watson, Jeremiah Burnett, Dr. David Moore, Brooking Bumette, Saauel Shannon, Reuben Burnette, Henry
Seat, John Bill, Benjamin Wate, John Walder, Junior, G. W. Banton, J. P., Theo. A. Cannon, J. P.
313. RB3,p6 - Inv: Jaaes Gilleland - R: 20 Feb 1815.
314. RB3,p7 - Monies received of estate of William Howell - R: Jan tera 1815 -A: Mary Howell, John Gamble.
315. RB3,p7 - Annual return of estate of minor heirs: John Andrews - R: 20 Feb 1815 - A &amp; G: Charles Ready -
Heirs: John Andrews, Peggy Andrews, Samuel Andrews, Paris [Persesj Andrews - "I have sold 4/9ths of
the 4 negroes" -S: Simon, Ben, Isaac, Seal.
316. RB3,p8 - Inv: John Hood - R: Jan 1815 - A: Kesiah Wood, widow; Janes Devore; Edward Johnson - W:
Nathaniel Perry.
317. RB3,p9 - Estate: Willian Arnold - 31 Oct 1814 - A: John Arnold - C: Williaa Nash, Thoaas Wallace,
Williaa Reece - S: 2 negroes to John Arnold, to Thomas Drennon, to Saa. Akins, to Nelly Arnold, widow.
318. RB3,p9 - Sale: Matthew Miller - 9 Jan 1815 - S: Hire of negro girl - A: Isaac Hiller.
319. RB3,pl0 - Inv: David Fleaaing - 24 Nov 1814 - A: Daniel Harshall -N: John Fleaaing - S: aan, Pleasant;
woaan, Lucy; woman, .Anne - 0: Joel Ferguson, Joan Sewell, Williaa Hayben, Turner Brashears, Henry D.
Thoapson, A. Lacky, Thoaas Ferguson, Michael Miller, Saauel Wallace, Alexander Cariichaei, Joseph
HcCrarie, Jaaes Saunders, Joseph Tweedy.
320. RB3,pll - Sale: John May - 12 Nov 1814 - A: Woodson Hay, Robert May - B: Robert Hay, Benjamin Ransoi,
John Tarpley, David Rutledge, Woodson May, Hance Hamilton.
321. RB3,pl2 - Add'l sales: Joseph HcLaughlin - R: 20 Feb 1815 - A: Archibald Hoore, Joseph HcLaughlin -
B: Alex Barnhill, Ruth McLaughlin, Henry H. Hudson, Loderick Hoore.
322. RB3,pl3 - Provision for widow/children: David Fleaaing - 24 Nov 1814 -A: Daniel Harshall - C: Hance
Hamilton, Prederick Barfield, George Doggett.
323. RB3,pl3 - Inv: John Winn - 6 Jan 1815 - E: Peter Winn, Penelope Winn.
27
324. RB3 ; pl4 - Sett: John Gasaway &amp; Robert Gasaway - R: 20 Feb 1815 - E: George Furr - C: William W. Searcy,
John Hoover - EO: Porter i Spence, John Spence, Henderson 4 Gatlin, Janes Henderson, James Gihbins'
William Lock, Jaaes C. Armstrong, J. P., William W. Searcy, J. P., Thomas Gasaway, William Gibson, Hoses
Bellah, J. P., Dr. James C. Armstrong, Will. H. Davis, J. P., Aaron Jones, John Smith, J. P., Dr. Clement
N. Reed, Alex. HcCullock, "C. Dement which Jinkin Whitten recovered of Daniel Boatright, Hordecai
Lillard, Lewis Anthony", B. Ganaway, Best Ward, Jas. Sharpe, J. P., Nicholas Gasaway, William Gasaway,
Benjamin Ward.
325. RB3,p22 - Inv: William Arnold - 22 Nov 1814 - A: John Arnold - B: Nelly .Arnold, John Arnold. Thos.
Drennon, Ota Cantrell, Burrel West, Braxton HaraMe, John Johnson, Henry Bell, John HcPeak, William
Nash, Jaaes Cunningham, Benjamin Horris, James Breechen, William Breechen, John Irvin, David Patton,
Henry HcPeak, Thomas Mitchell, John Nash, David Logan, Hicajah Peacock, John Hopkins.
326. RB3,p25 - Sale: Jaies Gilleland - 3 Feb 1815 - A: William Pope.
327. RB3,p28 - Inv: Jaaes Henderson - 11 Apr 1815 - A: John Henderson -S: 17 from age 7-45 years old - 0:
James Hurfey, Samuel A. Martin, Hoses Buckellow, Joshua Haskill, Thomas Woods, Peter Eateris, William
Henshaw.
328. RB3,p29 - WILL: Jaaes HcEwen of Rutherford Co., TN - DOW: 26 Jun 1814 - R: 4 May 1815 - Wife: Sarah
He Even - s: John Martin HcEwen, Alexander HcEwen, James HcEwen, William HcEwen, Josiah HcEwen - d:
Hargery Stewart, Sarah Henderson, Mary Miller HcEwen - gs: David HcEwen, son of William -E: friends,
Alexander HcEwen, Jaies HcEwen - W: John Alexander, John H. McKnight.
329. RB3,p30 - Inv: John Tweedy - R: 4 Hay 1815 - A: Daniel Harshall - S: girl, Philis; girl, Batte; boy,
Harry; girl, Barbery; girl, Charity; boy, Hoses; boy, Tom; boy, Bansse; girl, Vincy; boy, Anderson;
girl, Maria; boy. Charles.
330. RB3,p31 - WILL: Tarrance Burns - DOW: 18 Apr 1814 - R: 4/11 Hay 1815 - Wife: Ruth - E: Wife - 3 eldest
s: Asbury, Charles C, James - s: Jesse "when comes of age" - Legatees: Asbury Bums, Charles C. Burns,
Jaaes Bums, Jesse Burns, Sarah Burns, Lois Bums, Mary R. Burns, John H. Burns, Bethunia Burns, Ruth
D. Bums - W: Horatio Bums.
331. RB3,p32 - Inv: Robert Bedford - 15 Apr 1815 - R: 4 Hay 1815 - E: John Hoover, William W. Searcy - S:
man, Thank; woman, Rose; woman, Nancy; woman. Aaey; girl, Chacy; man, Irbey; girl, Nancy; boy, Gary?
boy, Helus; boy, John; boy, Anthony; woman, Kicey; girl, Cindy; girl, Christian; girl, Fanny; girl,
Jinney, deceased; girl, Tabby, now in hands of Phillip Stowe; girl, Haria; girl, Nanny; girl, Sally;
man, Littleton; man, George - 0: Thomas Tarpley, William Edwards, William Eastin, Beverly Nelson,
Jonathan Estill, Mary Coleman Bedford, Jaaes D. Caruthers, Robert Bedford, John R. Bedford, Uriah 3.
Cummins, Henry Trott, Anderson Johnson, Richard Waller, Thoaas Boatright, John Caulfield, George Akin,
Samuel Warren, Thoaas Rogers, John Edwards, John Johns, Walter Keeble, John Wade, William Robertson)
John H. Tilford, William Nor/ell, Joseph Arbuckle, William Jones, Benjamin Rucker, George Thompson,
John Carter, Hichael Lorrance or Lawrence, Waiter Kerrick, James Henderson.
332. RB3 ; p34 - WILL: George Goodman of Rutherford Co., 'TN - DOW: 5 Nov 1814 -R: 4 Hay 1815 - Wife: Jane
Goodman - "only" s: Jaaes Goodman - four d: Elizabeth Goodman [possibly married], Nancy C. Goodman,
Caty G. Goodman, Jane Goodman - S: boy, Jack "owned by Ant. Kinnard" - E: wife and Alexander McKeen
[HcEwen?] - S: Townzin Fuget, John Bullard.
333. RB3,p36 - Sett: James Thoapson - 4 Feb 1815 - Former A: Jaaes Thompson, Jonathan Hall - Present A: Mary
Thompson, Robert HcCoab - B: Anul Whitfield, Robert Kirk, Randolph Hall, J. Howell, Jonathan Wherry,
Andrew HcCabe, Thomas Berry, Joseph Youry, Jesse Brashear, William HcFerrin, James HcGill, Calvin
Curlee, John Gilleland, Joshua Haskill, Abraham Tennison, Jonathan Hall - C: John L. Jetton, Alexander
HcEwen, Jacob Wright - EO: Dr. Henderson, Abraa or Abraham Tennison, Am. Petty.
334. RB3,p38 - Sett: Mary B. Stephens [also known as Polly and Holly] -10 Jun 1814 - R: 4 Hay 1315 - A:
Benry Goodloe - "...in 1812 Hary B. Stephens, widow" - C: Robert HcCoab, Jordon Williford, John L.
Jetton - EO: Snappy A. Puckett, Charles Kavanaugh, Dewbart Barton, James D. Caruthers.
28
335. RB3 ; p40 - Sale: Humphrey Nelson - R: 18 Jun 1815 - A: Sarah Nelson, William Edwards - S bought: nan
by William Edwards; woman, boy by John Matthews; qirl by Phillip Sisom - B: Hatilda Nelson, Betsy
Allen, William Sisom, Daniel Nelson, Jacob Hall, Richard Cook, John Cluck, John Sanders, Allan Dimery,
John Matthews, Drury Hall, William Vaughan, Peterson Lenore, Samuel Purtle, Benjamin Drue, Jesse
Wilson, William Eastin, Arthur Harris, Hugh Endsley, Benjamin Rucker, Cader Dement, Beverly Nelson,
William Wade, Kirby Cook, William Drue, Samuel Hill, Phillip L. Lowe, William Edwards, Walter Keeble,
Zachariah Sisom, Gilbert Mason, Samuel Alsup, William Cummins, Joshua Ford, Mrs. Fergerson, John Baker,
Thomas Crenshaw, James McKnight, William Hill Wade, Edward Drue, Elias Baker.
336. RB3,p46 - Inv: James McEwen - 26 Jun 1315 - E: Alexander &amp; James McEwen.
337. RB3,p47 - WILL: David Barton of Rutherford Co., TN - DCW: 12 July 1315 -R: July tero 1815 - Wife:
Hannah Barton - d: Violet, Sarah - s: Swinfield, Robert, Joshua - S: woman, Luce with her son, Ben and
woman, Nancy to wife then divided between sons at wife's death? child, Charlott (daughter of Jenny)
to Violet; woman, Bett to Sarah; girl, Mary and Simon, her son - "...money due me from the estate of
Daniel Bird Saith" - E: sons, Joshua and Swinfield - W: Jonathan Price, Isaac Hill, John Dickson.
338. RB3,p49 - Inv: John P. H. Lenoir - R: 28 Sep 1315 - A: Peter Vaughan.
339. RB3,p50 - Sale: John Winn - 13 Jan 1915 - E: Peter Winn, Penelope Winn -B: Ahner Dement, James
Daugherty, Larkin Thacker, William Rawton, Walter Myrich, Thomas Tarpley, Thomas Ralph, Walter Keeble,
Kirby Cook, Uriah Cumins, John Hoover, Peggy Tucker, Benjamin Wilson.
340. RB3,p51 - Sale: John Mallard - R: Jul term 1815 - Ax: E. Mallard - A: Thornton Mallard - "...a
discharge signed by Major Genl. W. Carroll".
341. RB3,p53 - Inv: Samuel Hayes - R: 28 Sep 1815 - A: Elsa Hayes.
342. RB3,p54 - Inv: David Ramsey - R: 28 Sep 1815 - A: William Ramsey, Jr.
343. RB3,p54 - Inv: William Yearby - 10 Jul 1815 - A: Averett Yearby - 0: James Reed, Asha Dyer, Washington
Bankston, John Lorgent, John Grishaa, Green K. Hubbard, William Stokes, Josiah Bullard, Benjamin
Bullard, Demarous Moore, Robert Moore, Benjamin L. Athey, David Derault.
344. RB3,p55 - Inv: John Ncrris - R: Sep 1815 - A: Elizabeth Norris - S: nan, 30 years; girl, 9 years.
345. RB3,p56 - Inv: James Walker - R: 28 Sep 1815 - A: John Byler - "6 months &amp; 5 days tour of duty in
service of United States."
346. RB3,p57 - Inv: Edward Manning - 7 Oct 1815 - A: Annie Manning - 0: Lemuel Wilkinson.
347. RB3,p58 - Inv: Willie Jones - 5 Oct 1815 - A: Samuel Bowman - 0: Best Ward N: Ezekiel Ward - "...we
believe at the time Willie Jones descended the Riber as substitute of Best Ward in the campaign to New
Orleans he was possessed of the following property in the hands of wife and others..."
348. RB3,p59 - Inv: James Pais or Pace - Deceased: 4 May 1315 - A: Samuel Bowman - 0: John Thompson, _?
Gentry, William Russell.
349. RB3,p60 - Sale: James Pais or Pace - 12 Aug 1815 - 3: Caaauel [Campbell?] Tucker, Owen Fergason, John
Bradly, James W. Stewart, William Pace, Jr., George P. Wallace, J.S. Hale, Elizabeth Pace, Nancy Pace,
Alex Walker, Barry Stricklin, William Ccnnels, Sherwood Stroud, John Davidson, Samuel Wallace, John
Stroud, James Sanders, Harrison Weatherspoon , Samuel Kelton, William Russell, William Johnson, John
Bellait, William Simpson, Kutchen Freeman, Thomas Taylor, John Wallace.
350. RB3,p62 - Inv: William Rhodes - Oct ten 1815 - A: Richard Rhoads [or Rhodes] - "services in any to
New Orleans."
351. RB3,p62 - Inv: Thomas Corbele - 17 Aug 1815 - A: William Corbeie -S: 5 negroes.
29
352. RB3,p62 - Sales: Edward W. Smith - 5 Aug 1815 - E: Joseph Horton, James Morton.
353. RB3,p62 - Inv: Nidhaus Johnson - Oct ten 1815 - A: Jaies Johnson.
354. RB3,p63 - Inv: David Barton - Deceased 7 Oct 1815 - E: Joshua Barton - S: aoaan, Mary and son, Simon;
woman, Luce and her son, Ben willed to widow; girl, Nancy - L: J_ Webb.
355. RB3,p63 - Add'l Sales: James Henderson - 11 Jul 1815 - A: John Henderson - B: Peter Grayson, John Wade,
Enoch Harris, James D. Correthers 0: Robert Hay, Gillium Halloy, Thomas Washington.
356. RB3,p64 - Inv: Samuel Hays - 10 Oct 1815 - Widow: Ellis Hays &amp; family - B: James Hays - C: James
Kevins, Isaac Nance, John Fulton.
357. RB3,p65 - Inv: Bird Nance - Oct term 1815 - A: Allen Nance, James Sanford S: man, aged 30; woman, aged
30? girl, aged 10; boy, aged 6; boy, aged 4 -"...discharge from United States."
358. RB3,p67 - Sett: William Kelton - 23 Sep 1815 - A: Elizabeth Kelton, James Kelton - Legatees: Robert
Kelton, Alexander Lacky, Elizabeth Kelton, Junior, Samuel Kelton, Elizabeth Kelton, Jr., James Kelton -
A: Elizabeth and James Kelton - C: Daniel Bowman, Robert HcCoabs, _J_ Bellah - EG: George P. Wallace,
Rev'd W. Henderson, Dr. Sappington, Stephen White, Sherwood Harris, Blacksan Coleman, John Coffin
(Clerk of Circuit Court), Bennett Smith, John Dickson, John Davidson, John Ewing (Clerk, Court of
Appeals), N.T. Perkins, Thomas Yardley (funeral expense), Otto Harskell, Burwel Gannaway, A. B.
Sublett, James Vaughan, William Pace, James Devore, William Kelton, J. Howell, John Sloan, Archibald
Sloan, Henry Conway, John Jetton, John Newman, James Kelton, Robert Kelton, Alexander Lackey, Elizabeth
Kelton, Jr., Samuel Kelton.
359. RB3,p70 - Sales: John McCoy - Oct term 1815 - E: Mary McCoy - "...a discharge for services of deceased
in Capt. Bird Nance's Company for 4 months and 3 days" - B: James Blackaan, John Beesley, John Hampton,
Richard Heath, John Patterson, Thomas Land.
360. RB3,p70 - Sales: David Ramsey - 9 Oct 1815 - A: William Ramsey.
361. RB3,p71 - Sales: James Walker - Oct term 1815 - A: John Byler - B: William Lock, David Lance, Thomas
Lance, William Holbert, Rachael Walker, Answell Potts, William Potts, John Clark, John Byler, Samuel
Peters, Adaa Straton, Jonathan Heflin, William Leathers, Johnathan Lance, Nathaniel Walker, William
Hogan, David Fleming, William Wills, Matthew HcGaugh, Archibald Harris, John Hill, John Webb, James
Heflin, John HcKissick, Thomas Jackson, Thomas Potts, Andrew Adcock, Sally Brown, John Sutter.
362. RB3,p73 - Support of Widow: John Walker - Oct term 1815 - Widow: Rachael Walker - C: Merryman Landum,
Matthew McGaugh, Samuel Bullen.
363. RB3,p73 - Wid. Allow: Jaies Pais [Pace] - Widow: MaryAnne Pais family - C: John Davidson, Samuel
Killough, George P. Wallace -J. P.: Daniel Bowman.
364. RB3,p74 - Sett: Matthew Miller - 29 Jul 1815 - G of minor heirs: Mary Miller - C: Frederick Barefield,
Henry H. Hudson, George Dsleton.
365. RB3,p74 - Allowance for Widow: [no deceased name] - 31 Aug 1815 - Widow: Mary Tucker - C: William
Easten, John Warren, William Sublett.
366. RB3,p75 - Sett: Wilson Kerr - Oct term 1815 - A: Robert Jetton, Rachael Kerr - C: Frederick Barfield,
Hugh Robinson, Saiuel Campbell - EO: Thos. Hontagne, Trott and HcBrooi, John H. Tilford, John Stones,
John Smith, Blackaan Coleman, Elenor Williams, James Haberry, J_ Burleson, William Cotter, Robert
Jetton, Ben Haberry, Henry Trott, H. 4 J. Norville, James Henderson, William A. Sublett, J.D.
Correthers, N.T. Perkins, Ben Smith, Abran Thompson.
367. RB3,p76 - Sett: John Willson - Oct term 1815 - A: Robert Jetton, Samuel Willson - C: Frederick
Barfield, Hugh Robinson, Samuel Campbell -EO: Robert McMurry, Blackman Coleman, John Nugent, Joseph
E. Dobins, Joseph Williams (for tax), Ben Smith, M. 4 J. Norville, N.T. Perkins, J_ Sublette.
368. RB3,p77 - Sales: Gillian Halloy - 12 Hay 1814 - A: Burwill Ganaway, Fanny H. Halloy - S hired - B: John
Ransome, William John Henderson, E. Bullar, Daniel Parker, Williaa Pace, Albin Lowry, John H. Corthorn,
Alexander Carmicle, Thomas Woods, Nimrod Hanefee, Thomas Land.
369. RB3,p79 - Allowance for widow: James Gilleland - 3 Feb 1815 - Widow and family - C: Janes Hill, Hardy
Pope, William Adkinson.
370. RB3,p80 - POA: Joshua Davis of Garrad Co., KY appoint Elisha Davis of Davidson Co., TN ay attorney -
10 Jul 1797 - W: William Tracy, Seth Davis, A. Pearch - Power of Attorney produced in open court Jan
term 1816 - N: William Harris.
371. RB3,p82 - Inv: James Thompson - 5 Jan 1816 - E: Lewis Stevens.
372. RB3,p82 - Inv taken 22 Oct 1815, sold 18 Nov 1815: Daniel Parker - A: Patsey Parker.
373. RB3,p83 - Add'l Inv sold: John Willson - 4 Feb 1815 - A: Robert Jetton, Samuel Willson - B: W. Ganaway.
374. RB3,p83 - Add'l Inv: James Hoore - A: James Higgins - 0: Note on estate of John Norris, deceased -
"...a certificate for serving in the Creek nation as a private soldier in Capt. A. HcKeen Co. of
horsemen from 24th Sep 1813 until 3rd Nov 1813..."
375. RB3,p83 - Sale: Arthur Fuller - 23 Oct 1815 - A: Patsy Fuller.
376. RB3,p83 - Sale: Needhaus Johnson - A: James Johnson.
377. RB3,p84 - Inv: Lewis Whitly - Jan Ten 1816 - A: John Hobson, Rebecca Whitly.
378. RB3,p84 - Report: Dudley Hatnews - Jan Term 1816 - A: Joseph Newman.
379. RB3,p35 - Annual return of ainor heirs: John Andrews - Jan ten 1816 - Guardian: Charles Ready - Heirs:
John Andrews, Peggy Andrews, Samuel H. Andrews, Pursius Andrews - "4/9ths of estate of James Andrews,
deceased."
380. RB3,p85 - Add'l Inv: Robert Bedford - 8 Jan 1816 - E: Williaa W. Searcy, John Hoover - 0: George W.
Oliver, Hilliaa Edwards, John Wade, Abrahan Herrings. John H. Tilford, John Johns, Benjamin Rucker,
Joseph Pollard, J. Whiteside and Bell, David Abbott, Cleaent B. Bedford, Phillip L. Lowe, Isaac Hevin.
381. RB3,p86 - Sales: James Tucker - 4 Nov 1815(Sale) - A: Polly Tucker - B: Williaa Reynolds, Koonrad
[Conrad?] Baker, William Edwards, Thomas Cotter, Williaa Tucker, Williaa Cooper, James Hancock, George
Steel, John Steel, Richard Richards, Williaa Cotter.
382. RB3,p87 - Letters of Administration: Williaa Yearby - 8 Jan 1816 - A: Avert Yearby - 0: Green K.
Hubbard, John Grishaa.
383. RB3,p37 - Add'l Inv: William Knox - Jan ten 1816 - A: Joseph Bellew - 0: Williaa Ingram, Joseph
Thompson, John Gilleland, Enoch Thonpson.
384. RB3,p87 - Sales: Capt. Bird Nancy [Nance] - 2 Nov 1815 - A: Allen Nancy [Nance], Janes Staaford.
385. RB3,p88 - Add'l Inv and Sales: Wilson Kerr - 4 Feb 1815 (Sale -A: Robert Jetton, Williaa Powell in
place of wife - S: hire of negro by Rachael Kerr; hire of negro boy by John Willson - B: Nathaniel
Eobson, Robert Jetton, iebulin Jetton, Saauel Snith, Susanna Ward, Walker Ganaway, Williaa Hall,
Thoderick Haherry, Benjamin Ward - 0: John H. Tilford, Henry D. HcBrooa.
386. RB3,p89 - Sales: Jaaes Berry - 1 Nov 1815 (Saie) - E: Thoaas Berry, Elisabeth Berry - B: Young
Laughlin, Jaaes Gess, Williaa HcFerrin, L. H. Laughlin. Leonard Johns, Williaa Fait, John R. Finch,
Randolph Hall, Hoses HcConnile.
31
387. RB3,p90 - Final Sett: William Smith - 13 Jan 1816 - A: Burwill Gannaway -C: Frederick Barfield, James
F. Jetton, Daniel Bowman - EO: Samuel Wilson, Dr. Thomas Sappington, William A. Sublette, Henry Trott,
Isaac Johns, Joel Childress, John H. Tilford, Thomas Johns, Andrea Miller, Bennett Smith.
388. RB3,p91 - Sales: William Knox - 9 Jan 1816 - A: Joseph Billeu, Margret Knox - B: Thomas Hoore, James
Hanahan, Jaaes Gilleland, Henry Good, James Thompson, John Waddell, Ambrose Petty, Thomas Phillips,
Isaiah Renshaw, William Youree, George Gillespie, Jane Thompson, John Barkley, Betsey Thompson -0:
1_ Ingram, Joseph Thompson, John Gilleland, Enoch Thompson -EO: John Renshaw, Blackman Coleman, John
Gray, John Thompson, Thomas Moore, Henry Good, John Barbee, Jackson Wherry - C: John L. Jetton, Thomas
Berry.
389. RB3,p93 - Support of wife and 2 children: William Knox - 17 Jan 1814 - C: Isaiah Renshaw, Francis
Youree, John Renshaw - JP: Thos. Berry.
390. RB3,p93 - Sett: James Moore - 12 Jan 1816 - A: James Higgins - C: E.B. McCoy, Henry M. Hudson, John
Miller - "...served as private in Capt. HcKeen's Co. of cavalry from 24 Sep 1813 to 3 Nov 1813."
391. RB3,p95 - Sett: John Winn - 18 Nov 1815 - A: Peter Winn, Penelope Winn -EO: Thomas Tarpley, William
A. Sublette, Porter and Spence, N.T. Perkins, R.W. Curains, James Daugherty, Robert Smith, John
Matthews, William Hall, Edward Tucker, David Abbott, M. k J. Norvile, Blackman Coleman, Walter Keeble,
John Hoover - C: William W. Searcy, John Hoover, David Abbott.
392. Rb3,p96 - Sett: Humphrey Nelson - 18 Nov 1815 - A 4 Ax: (not named) -C: William W. Searcy, John Hoover,
David .Abbott - EO: Daniel Nelson, Cader Dement, Walter Keeble, Thomas Tarpley, Alexander McCullough,
Joseph B. Johns, Arthur Harris, Blackman Coleman, Porter &amp; Spence, John Cluck, James Roan, Aron
Stewart, David Abbott, Thomas Dunaway, John Donnelson, Drury Vaughan, Samuel Dunaway, William Edwards,
Bennett Smith, Henry Crabb, J. Whiteside.
393. RB3,p97 - WILL: William Dickinson of Raleigh, Wake Co., NC - DOW: 14 Aug 1813 - Wife: Nancy - E: Hark
Cooke.
394. RB3,p99 - Will of Walter Keeble, Senior [ SEE RB3,p20O - 14751 .
395. RB3,pl00 - ELL: Thomas Crossthwait of Rutherford Co., TN - DOW: 22 Nov 1815 - Wife: Elizabeth -
Brother and guardian of son: Shelton Crossthwait E: wife and Shelton Crossthwait - s: William (not 21)
"...my children" W: W. Keeble, Jr., George Simpson, N. Cassidy, Samuel Watkins.
396. RB3,pl03 - WILL: Joseph Thompson of Cripple of Rutherford Co., TN - DOW: 16 Oct 1815 - Wife: Elizabeth
gs 4 gd: James Harvey Thompson, Sally Thompson "children of my son Jaaes Thompson, deceased" - d:
Critty Thompson - E: Robert Kirk, Nathan Lyon - W: Joshua Haskill, James Caraack, Alexander Scott,
Thomas Berry, Jaaes McFerrin.
397. RB3,pl04 - Inv: John Pardell - taken 7 Oct 1815 - A: Mary Pardell -S: man, John; woman, Jude; boy,
Tony; woman, Luce; boy, Henry now in possession of James Alethart.
398. RB3,pl05 - Inv &amp; Sale: John Pace - 4 May 1815 - A: Sarah Pace - B: Kentchen Pace, Lewis Ship.
399. RB3,pl06 - Add'l Inv: Gillian Halloy - R: Oct tera 1815 - A: Burwell Gannasay, Francis H. Hailoy - 0:
Janes Henderson, deceased, John Henderson, James D. Correthers, Henry Trott.
400. RB3,pl07 - WILL: Jaaes Berry of Rutherford Co., TN - DOW: 13 Nov 1814 - Wife: Elizabeth Berry - "ay
children as they arrive of age" - s: John Campbell Berry, Jaaes Laughlin Berry - "wife now pregnant" -
E: wife &amp; Thoaas Berry - W: James McFerrin, Burton L. McFerrin, Young Laughlin.
401. RB3,pl08 - WILL: Miles Freeman - DOW: 2 Feb 1815 - R: Jul term 1815 - Wife: Margaret - "my children" -
W: Jacob Payne, Charles B. Collier, Willie Hutson.
402. RB3,pl09 - WILL: Gwin Howell of Rutherford Co., TN - DOW: 24 Jul 1812 - R: July tern 1815? - Wife:
Catharine W. Howell - Brother: William Howell -Sisters: Nancy Nelson, Harqaret Whitside - E: Catharine
W. Howell, Gwin Edwards, James Whitside - W: Hary Williamson, Hardy Pope, L. Davis.
403. RB3,pllO - WILL: Bird Nance or Nancy of Rutherford Co., TN - DOW: 18 Nov 1814 - s: John Nancy, William
Nance - d: Elizabeth Nance, Sally Nance - S: woman, Luce and all her increase be equally divided
between Lucy Gambill, John Nance, Elizabeth Nance, William Nance and Sally Nance; man, Peter to wife
but later to James H. Nance and Polly I. Nance and Thomas Nance and Hilly B. Nance - E: friend, Allin
Nance, James Stanford - W: Ryliegh D. Hurry, John Smith.
404. RB3,plll - WILL: Robert Bedford of Rutherford Co., TN - DOW: 5 Jul 1813 -5 sons: Stephen Bedford,
Robert Bedford, Clement Read Bedford, Edwin Walton Bedford, Thomas Jefferson Bedford - Wife: Hary
Colemaji Bedford - d: Hary Anne Eliza Bedford, Hary Nash Johns, Lucy Leqrand Rucker, Fanny Anne Bedford
"four younqest children": Fanny Anne, Edwin Walton, Thomas Jefferson, Hary Anne Eliza (all not of aqe]
S to Lucy: Hilly, Presly, Letty (dead) "Lucy owns"; qirl, Aqqy - S to wife: Frank, Rose, Nancy, Any
Clarisa, Juber, Nancy (daughter of Nancy) - S to Stephen: boy, Jerry - S to Robert: boy, Hilus - S to
Clement: boy, John - S to Edwin: boy, Anthony - S to Thomas: woman, Nisey "and increase after this" -
S to Fanny: qirl, Cinda; qirl, Christian; qirl, Fanny; qirl, Jinny - S to Hary A. Eliza: qirl, Tabby;
qirl, Haria; qirl, Nanny; qirl, Sally - S to be sold: men, Georqe and Littleton - E: John Spence, John
Hoover, Col. William W. Searcy - W: William Thweatt, Georqe Akin, Elizabeth Dauqhity, James Dauqhity,
Elizabeth Akin.
405. RB3,pll5 - Sett: David Flemiinq - 10 Jul 1815 - A: Daniel Harshall - First sale: 25 Nov 1814 - C: Fred.
Barfield, Daniel Bowman, Jno. Henderson.
406. RB3,pll6 - Sett: Samuel Smith - 4 Jun 1815 - A: William Smith - 0: John Spence, Robert Smith, Senior,
Cader Dement, John Dickson, Polly Dickson -C: William Edwards, John Hoover, Robert Warnack.
407. RB3,pll7 - Allowance for widow: James Henderson - July term 1815 - C: William Lytle, John Thompson,
William A. Sublette.
408. RB3,pll8 - WILL: Beaty HcCoy of Rutherford Co., TN - DOW: 16 Feb 1814 - R: 7 Hay 1816 - Wife: Peqqy
HcCoy - s: Henry HcCoy, Ezekiel Beaty HcCoy, Amos Alexander HcCoy, Francis Bradley McCoy, James HcCoy,
John HcCoy - d: Easther Boqqs - son-in-law: David Parks "that was married to Abigail HcCoy now dead" -
S: woaan, Rachel, to wife; man, Adam, to Henry; man, Isaac, to Exekiel; qirl, Hannah, to Amos; yellow
boy, Jacob, to Francis; woman, Darkis, to be sold - E: Ezekiel and Henry - W: Jaaes D. Wooten, Henry
Norman, Andrew Hall.
409. RB3,pl21 - WJJLL: Samuel Hoody of Rutherford Co., TN - DOW: 9 Sep 1815 - R: 7 Hay 1816 - "give to":
Samuel W. Henderson, Eliza E. Henderson - S: boy, Joe - A: Walter Reeble, Henry Trott - W: Henry W.
HcBroom, John Stockird, Richard Henderson.
410. RB3,pl22 - WILL: James Davidson of Rutherford Co., TN - DOW: 2 Har 1816 -R: 7 Hay 1816 - E and s: John
Davidson - d: Rebecca Younq, Hartha Davidson, Sarah. Lusk, Hary Johnson, Ruthy HcGee, Sinthy Hubbard -
I: Hartha Benson and her sister, Jane - qd: Polly Kirke, Sarah Davidson - W: Samuel Rillouqh, William
Wilson.
411. RB3,pl23 - Sett: John Thompson - R: 7 Hay 1816 - A: Hichael Rinnard - EO: Enos Everitt, Lewis Stephens,
Bennett Smith, William Stephens, Samuel Campbell, Doctor Webb, Alfred Blackian, Robert HcCoy, Currin
&amp; Hason, Abraham Herrinq, Georqe Seaton, William Bennett, James Blackian, John Dickson, John H. Head,
Adai TWaterf?], H.D. Thompson - O: John Averett, Cullin Blackian, William Bennett - S: sold negroes -
0: .Alex Bass, Lewis Stephens, J_ Williais, Nathaniel Rinnard - C: Jno. Smith, Soloion Beesley, James
Gillespie.
412. RB3,pl25 - VERBAL WILL : William Hill of Rutherford Co., TN - DOW: 26 Feb 1816 - R: 7 Hay 1816 - Wife
and children - W before Solomon Beesley, J. P., on 28 Feb 1816: Jaies Taylor, John Hill.
413. RB3,pl26 - Inv: William Johnson - taken 1 Har 1816 - A: Hariah Johnson -0: Robert Strother.
3 3
414. RB3,pl26 - Sett: Matthew Miller - 20 Mar 1816 - A: John Miller - C: William Mankin, George Oselton.
415. RB3,pl27 - Sett: James Andrews - 12 Apr 1316 - A: Charles Ready - C: Jacob Wriqht, Alexander McEwen,
Henry Goodloe -EO: Samuel Donnell - minor heirs.
416. RB3,pl28 - Sales: Lewis Whitley - R: 8 May 1816 - A: Rebecca Whitley, John Wasson - B: Rebecca Whitley,
Ezekiel Pope, John Hobson, Theoderick Haberry, Charles Pope, Wesley Hudson, Samuel HcFaddan, William
King, William Cooke, John Kelly, Francis Hancock, William Bowlin, Samuel Bowman, Elijah HcClanahan,
Joseph Bowlding, Nathaniel Hobson, Dennis Clay, William Lewis, William Rowland, Moreland Myrick, Thomas
Burley, Jeremiah Daniel, Isaac Harable, James Maberry, John Marlin, Ambrose House, Joseph Bowlin, John
D. Cooke, Peter Warren, Samuel Kelly, James Marlin, Morning Hobson.
417. RB3,pl30 - Amount of Estate: John Calvett - R: 8 May 1816 - A: Samuel and Joseph Bowman - EO: Benjamin
Ransom, Thomas Butler, John Christian, Robert Jarrott, Gidion Jarrott, William Caldwell, John Hill,
Ezekiel Moore, Anthony Kinnard, James Blackman, Enoch Head, William Snell, Robert Nichols, John Stone,
Mary Calvett, James Cooper.
418. RB3,pl31 - Inv: John Stovall - R: 8 May 1816 - A: Thomas Brothers -S: woman.
419. RB3,pl32 - WILL: Squire Knox of Rutherford Co., TN - DOW: 24 Feb 1816 - 8: 8 May 1816 - Wife: Susannah
now pregnant - s: Washington - daughters -E: Charles Ready; brother, Joseph Knox - W: Elijah Smith,
Thomas Knox, Angles McCloud.
420. RB3,pl34 - Inv: Joseph Thompson - F: Jan Court 1816 - R: 8 May 1316 ~ A: Robert Kird, Nathan Lyons -
0: Thomas Knox, Nid. Laughlin.
421. RB3,pl35 - Widow's allowance: [deceased not named, probably John Vardell] - 27 Jan 1816 - Widow: Mary
Vardell - C: Constant Hardeman, Matthew HcClanahan, John Fonville.
422. R33,pl36 - Sett: William Arnold - 30 Dec 1815 - A: John Arnold - EO: William Arnoid, Jr., Mcses Brown,
Baswell West, John R. Bedford, Jaaes Woods - "selling estate in S.C." - 4 of the heirs: Joseph Steward,
Jane Galliher, Samuel Steward, Rebecca Galliher - C: C.W. Santon, Theo. A. Cannon. William Nash.
423. RB3,pl37 - Inv: Josiah Smith - made 6 Apr 1816 - A: John Smith.
424. RB3,pl38 - Inv: John Vardell - R: 9 May 1816 - A: Constant Hardeman -0: James Bosswell, Turner Vardell,
John Finch - S hired out: John, about 25 yrs; woman, Judge, 50 yrs; woman, Luce, 20 yrs; boy, Adam,
3 yrs; young child, 6 sonths old.
425. RB3,pl39 - Sett: Dudley Matthews - R: 9 May 1816 - A: Joseph Newman - C: David Abbott, John Hoover -
EO: Porter &amp; Spence, David Endaly, Matthew Haley, John Coffer, Susan Matthews. Blackaan Coleman, Walter
Keeble, Mary Hunter, Thomas Beavers, David Abbott, John Sullins, Matthew McClanahan, Spencer Suttle,
Joseph Newman -"support of family".
426. RB3,pl40 - Widow's allowance: Lewis Whitley - 25 Jan 1816 - Widow: Rebecca Whitley - C: James B</dc:description>
<dc:description>Contains brief descriptions of entries in the Rutherford County court Record Books during the time period between 1803 and 1829</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.); Court records</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Periodical</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>190 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-01-26;mt2011-02-03</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication36ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/15</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>