<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Hallowed traditions marked Tennessee College</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Sloan, Eugene H.</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 13</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1979</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1900-1909; 1910-1919; 1920-1929; 1930-1939; 1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>HALLOWED TRADITIOt^S MARKED TENl^ESSEE COLLEGE
by
Eugene H. Sloan
The third school to be established by the Baptists of
Tennessee was Tennessee College, later known as Tennessee
College for Women in Murf reesboro. It was authorized by
the Southern Baptist Convention in 1905 and opened in 1907
as a response to what was felt to be a need for a school
for women, under Christian control, of high grade and with
honest standards. The ideal of its founders was to offer
the very best educational advantages under positive Christian
influences. The site selected was property of Union University
on East Main Street supplemented by large monetary donations
made by the citizens of Murfreesboro and Rutherford County.
The property on which Tennessee College was placed had
been purchased from M. B. Murfree by the Board of Trustees of
Union University in 1845. At the removal of Union University
the property had, after some uncertainty, remained m the hands
of the Union University trustees in Murfreesboro.
By-laws were adopted for twenty- seven directors to be
known as trustees. The officers of the board were C. R. Byrn,
president; C. S. Smith, Vice-president: Leland Jordan, secretary:
and R. W. Hale, treasurer. All trustees selected were to be
members of Missionary Baptist Churches. An executive committee
was to attend to immediate business during the year. Between
the time of the selection of this first board and the laying
of the corner stone on September 6. 1906, titles to property
were cleared and a charter was drawn.
In the fall of 1906, George J. Burnett and J. Henry Burnett
signed a contract as president and business manager, r e^ pec*- 1 vel y
2
of Tennessee College. These two men came from Liberty College
in Kentucky where they had been held in esteem. The incorpora-tors
filed for a charter on December 18, 1905. Listed as
incorporators were C. K. Byrn. R. Walter Hale, William, T. Hale.
Jr., Leland Jordan. Edward S. Reeves. E. T. Rion. Gentry S.
Smith, and John Williams. When the Board of Trustees was
organized December 19. 1905. Byrn was elected president, C. H.
Smith, vice-president; R. W. Hale, treasurer: and Leland
Jordan, secretary.
Byrn was a native of Milton, but had long been identified
with the hardware business in Murfreesboro and was a deacon in
First Baptist Church. He was described as an "indefatigable
worker" for Tennessee College until his death m 1929. A
tradition of Tennessee College was established by the Byrn
famiily. At the time of graduation each senior was presented a
Bible so "a graduate may leave the stage with a Bible m one
hand and a diploma in the other."
Gentry S. Smith was a Murfreesboro business man. for fif*:y
years a deacon m a Baptist Church, a trustee of the Bap+-ist
Orphanage and a Colonel on the staff of Republican Governor
Hooper.
Leland was a Murfreesboro lawyer who had handled r-^uch -^f
the laborious work of clearing the land title. He also pr^^cured
from the Federal government compensation for use of t:-.e Un:&gt;ir.
College property by Union troops in the Civil War.
R. W. Hale of Nashville was a ^-rustee and trea-urer C'i t'.'e
board from 1907 until 1927 and vice-president 1 rom 1929 ;r,* ; 1
1938. He was a member of the committee which, locafer Ten'-.e'^ .
- -
College in Murfreesboro. A native of Statesville ;:&#163; sr.d :
&#8226;.
3
brother, W. T. Hale, Jr., made the first donation to the college.
R. W. Hale was a graduate of Union University and W. T. Hale
of Vanderbilt. Both were prominent members of Immanuel Baptist
Church in Nashville and active in a variety of activities includ-ing
serving on the Board of the Tennessee Central Railway.
Other members of the first Board of Trustees were all
prominent religious leaders, many of whom had achieved distinc-tion
in the business and professional areas.
The Board membership in addition to the officers included:
R. R. Acree, Lansing Burrows, E. L. Davis, E. E. Polk, P.T.
Hale, W. T. Hale, Jr., A. J. Holt, R. E. Jarman, M. D. Jeffreys,
Howard L. Jones, F. N. Moore, I. N. Penick, T. S. Potts, Edward
S. Reaves, E. T. Rion, W. H. Ryalls, F. N. Smith, John W. Thomas,
A. L. Todd, I. J. VanNess, C. B. Waller, John Williams, and
J. S. Williams. Of these, seven were Rutherford County residents.
Two brothers, George Jackson Burnett and J. Henry Burnett were
members of the college staff.
George Jackson Burnett served the institution as president
from June 5, 1907 until June 30, 1923. A native of Auburn,
Kentucky, he had served as president of Liberty College in
Glasgow, Kentucky for many years and was president of the
Tennessee Baptist Convention and vice-president of the Southern
Baptist Convention.
J. Henry Burnett, general manager, was also a native of
Auburn, Kentucky. After fifteen years work with the Western
Recorder of Louisville, he served as business manager of Liberty
College, Richmond Virginia College, and four years as business
manager for Mercer University. After leaving the Tennessee
College Board in 1916. he was associated with the Calumet Tea
4
and Coffee Conpany, of which he became a vice-president in
1922. Long active as a Sunday School superintendent, clerk,
and deacon of Baptist churches he served 22 years as secretary
of the Tennessee Baptist Convention.
Among the trustees from Rutherford County represented a
wide range of interest. They included R. E. Jarman, the Rev.
Edward S. Reaves, E. T. Rion, John W. Thomas, Andrew L. Todd,
John Williams, and James C. Williams.
R. W. Jarman of Lascassas served as a member of the Board
of Trustees for the organization until his death in 1936. Mr.
Jarman was a successful farmer and business man, operating
automobile and hardware firms in Georgia.
Edward S. Reaves was pastor of First Baptist Church in
Murfreesboro and the spokesman before the Baptist Education
Commission for the establishment of the College in Murfreesboro.
He served as a Board member until he left Murfreesboro in 1906.
E. T. Rion, a Murfreesboro insurance man who served First
Baptist Church as Sunday School Superintendent and deacon, was
an incorporator of the College and served on its executive
committee for ten years.
John W. Thomas was a native of Murfreesboro and a graduate
of Vanderbilt University. He began working with the N. C. and
St. L. Railroad as an engineer in 1878 and ultimately advanced
to the presidency and general manager of the company in 1906.
Andrew L. Todd became a member of the Board when it was
organized and served as chairman from 1929 until 1937. Educated
at Union University, the University of the South, and Cumber-land
University, he served in the House of Representatives, the
State Senate and as a member of the State Board of Education
5
through four administrations. He was chairman of the Board
of Deacons of the Murfreesboro First Baptist Church. While
in the Tennessee General Assembly he served as Speaker of both
the Senate (1919) and the House (1921).
John Williams served as secretary of the Board from 1910
until 1924. He was a Murfreesboro lumber dealer and later
established a building materials business in Tampa, Florida
and Nashville, Tennessee.
The charter for Tennessee College was granted by the State
of Tennessee on December 18, 1905. The trustees were immedi-ately
faced with difficulties. They found the old Union
University buildings were in such deterioration they could
not be used. There was a lien of $3,000 on the property that
was discharged from funds subscribed by the citizens of Murfrees-boro.
There remained $23,159 of the subscription which was
increased by an issue of $40,000, 6 per cent interest bonds, to
be liquidated over a 10-year period. According to the Minutes
of the Tennessee Baptist Convention of 1906, the trustees re-quested
permission to raise $65,000 in funds for a new building
and furnishings.
On September 11, 1907, the new Tennessee College Building
was dedicated. E. Y. Mullins, president of the Southern
Baptist Seminary in Louisville, delivered the address. In his
remarks Dr. Mullins stated: "The newest and most approved and
noblest ideas of educational philosophy now accepted are nothing
less, and nothing more than what Baptists, as a denomination,
are pledged to endorse and to put into practice by the funda-mental
principles of their faith."
6
In 1908 an $8,500 addition to the original structure was
completed. This included a 32 by 50 gymnasium and six class-rooms
for elementary pupils.
The first faculty, as were subsequent additions, was chosen
with great emphasis on Christian character, culture, and educa-tion.
In the early years the faculty included graduates of
Radcliffe, Mount Holyoke, Wellesley, the University of Chicago,
Vassar, Columbia University, Oberlin College, the University of
Wisconsin, Vanderbilt, and the University of Texas.
In addition to the Burnett brothers, the first faculty and
administrative staff included Miss M. E. Lindsay as "lady
principal:" W. E. Everett, secretary: A. C. Davidson, Miss Rena
M. Hall, Miss Winfred T. Moore, Miss Willie Tabb Moore, Mrs.
Nellie B. Lowe, Harry Brown, Miss Lelia G. Russell, Mrs. Walter
Drake, Mrs. J. K. Marshall, Miss Annie Strader, Henry H. Nast,
Mrs. George J. Burnett, Mrs. Nettie Davidson Jones, Miss Corrine
Sedberry and Miss Anne S. Davis. The impressive curriculum in-cluded
philosophy, psychology, political science, natural science,
classical languages, music and art.
The first year 199 students were enrolled. Of these, 131
were boarding students. At that time, the school had an elemen-tary
department, a four-year "Preparatory School," the College and
the Conservatory.
Admittance to the college for the first year was on the
basis of completion of two years in a high school or academy.
Examination on entrance or a certificate from the principal of
the school was required.
7
The first five years saw, not only a maintenance of stand-ards,
but an increase in enrollment, facilities, and courses in
instruction.
In March 1909, the Board of Trustees passed a reolution
that "the object or ideal of Tennessee College is the estab-lishment
and development of a college for higher education of
women." A canpaign for $150,000 was launched to raise an
endowment
.
At the close of the year 1909-10, a definite change in
the work offered by the college was recommended to the Board of
Trustees. There was discussion of dropping the elementary
deaprtment. More irr^ortant, however, was the decision to offer
an additional year of college work and thereby complete the
A. B. course. President Burnett felt this step to be urgent
since high school principals preferred recommending a four year,
accredited college to their graduates. As a result of this
revised curriculum, the Bulletin of 1910-11 carried the announce-ment
that "Tennessee College will confer the degree of Bachelor
of Arts upon any student who satisfactorily completes the course
of study outlined below."
School Publications - Traditions
One of the earliest extant publications of the school is a
copy of the fourth edition of Volume II of the Tennessee College
Magazine dated June 1909. This 6x9 literary effort bound in
grey, contained 58 pages. It included: an original article on
the Barbizon Artists, by Willie Bumpas: "A Girl of the Middle
West," by Jural Couey, a post Victorian love vignette. Inter-spersed
throughout the magazine were quotations from numerous
Wordsworth's "Rustic Life in Wordsworth's Poetry."
8
In this issue of the magazine, an editorial reported that
there were 19 college students and 115 preparatory students the
first year the college operated. In the second year there were
48 college, 139 preparatory, 50 elementary, and 13 special students.
Students who received the Associate Arts degree during this
second year of operation were: Winnie Bumpass, Brownsville;
Grace Dean, Wartrace: Georgia Cunningham, Lewisburg; Mary Forgy,
Springfield. Anne Eades of Paducah, Ky., and Sarah Byrn, of
Murfreesboro, received the "Junior College diploma." Gladys
Young of Watertown and Evalie George Martin of Birmingham. Ky.,
received "diplomas in music." Lemma Drake of Lewisburg was
granted a "certificate in music."
Each of the Associate of Arts degree winners "read an essay
in regular morning exercises" as a partial fulfillment of the
degree requirements. Misses Young and Martin appeared in graduate
recital. After the recital, they "received their friends in
parlors and were the recipients of many gift bouquets."
It was this year of 1908-09 that May 7 was established for
the May Day fete. A description of this initial May Day indicated
that characters from Robin Hood dominated the pagentry that
named Gladys Young as Queen.
There were four major piiblications at Tennessee College &#8212;
THE TENNESSEANN, THE DRYAD, The TENNESSEE COLLEGE MAGAZINE and
the annual College Bulletin.
Perhaps the one of more important publications of literary
and lasting value was the quarterly college magazine. The major
division of each of these editions included an editorial, "News
Notes," and exchange critique of other college publications and
a collection of essays, short stories and poetry.
9
These quarterlies are the best source of information about
the routine activities of the College, the subtle modification
of life style, interests, and ambitions of students. The
TENNESSEANN carried factual stories. The Dryad recorded the
usual memorabilia that characterizes all such yearbook
publications.
In 1909 the reportial enphasis was on musical concerts,
soirees, a minstrel performance, a visit of the Fisk Jubilee
Singers, May Day and art exhibitions.
In the 1920' s there were more teas, buffet luncheons,
movie parties and a visit by the Mercer University Mandolin Club.
The report of simultaneous debates between Union University and
Tennessee College on the United States entry into the League
of Nations was reported. Tennessee College women (Ethel Childers
and Mildred Dodson-negative) ; (Elizabeth Leigh and Rose Goodman,
affirmative) were successful on both sides of the issue.
By the late 1920 's and early ' 30 ' s more emphasis was being
placed on sports. Thanksgiving Day attendance at Vanderbilt or
"local college" football games, more sophisticated musical con-certs
and variety of reports on meeting the exigencies of the
depression were featured.
There appeared stories of the routine observance of traditions
of the College. The annual Christmas pageant at First Baptist
Church, the rising at two o'clock in the morning by members of
the sophomore class to scavenge the fields for daisies; to make
a "daisy chain" to honor the seniors. The Valentine "key-to- the-heart
banquet," the song contests, mission activities, and
elaborate May Day festivities were among these treasured traditions.
10
The College seal was developed from a motto adopted in
1912 by the Board of Trustees. It was designed by Frances
Williams, instructor in art. On a conventional shield was a
background of a valley over which the sun was rising, sur-movmted
by a cross, a torch, and the words of the motto from
the 18th Psalms appears&#8212;"Where there is no vision the people
perish." This seal replaced a former design of a simple shield
on which a T appeared surrounded by the words, "Tennessee
College.
"
The period 1912-1917 was one of steady progress. The enroll-ment
increased to an average of around 240. In 1914 the elemen-tary
school was discontinued and the preparatory department was
established as a separate unit.
A typical year may have been 1912. The close of the school
year was described by a young lady in a letter as "a struggle
between a gaggle of geese and a charm of linnets bent on a mad
dash of lemmings, accompanied by an overindulgence in music
and tears."
This annual commencement period produced fetes of various
kinds&#8212;class days, lectures, addresses, recitals, receptions,
and the grand finale when proud graduates left the stage with
a Bible in one hand and a diploma in the other.
The 1912 commencement marked the first conferring of the
Bachelor of Arts degree. Julia Elizabeth Brown, Tullahoma:
Alice Eaton Burnett, Murfreesboro; Louise Hunter Hibbs, Mur-freesboro;
and Ophelia Aterbum Selph, LaGrange, Ky. , were the
recipients. Miss Burnett went on to Radcliffe for her graduate
11
study and returned in 1915 to join the Tennessee College
faculty. That same year, Nannie Reeves Patrick of Winchester
qualified for the Associate of Arts degree. Diplomas in piano
were won by Katherine Holladay and August Kause. The scope
of the breadth of music offering and geographic coverage of
the College is further illustrated in the recipients of certifi-cates
in piano awarded Janice Arnold, Wartrace; lone Jordan Butler,
McKenzie; Helen Maurine Hillsraan, Tresevant; Jessie Josephine
Prince, Sewanee; Louise B. Sasser, Middleton; and Sara Louise
Wilson, Niota.
That year the Preparatory Department graduated eight girls.
Included in these graduates were Mac Allen Batey, Sarah Ruth
Batey, Eula Josephine Maxwell, and Annie Vera Maxwell, of
Murfreesboro.
The frenzy of graduation that year began on May 20 with an
evening musical festival climaxed with a march played by four
girls on two pianos. There was a brief rallentando in this
period before building to the crescendo that began May 27 with
a post-graduate concert by Janie Hurt, assisted by Helen Winn,
soprano. On May 30, a recital by Katherine Holladay and Susie
Lickette was offered. In rapid succession came: an "Expression
Recital" on May 31; the annual address by the Lanier and Ruskin
Literary Societies on June 1; an Art Reception on June 2; a
Preparatory School Graduation; the Glee Club concert and the
June 4 commencement.
By 1918, the faculty numbered 31 (including docents, those
in the "Conservatory" headed by Henry H. Nast) . Nast held a
medical doctoral degree and seemed to have been an unofficial
12
school physician. Frances Bohannon, for whom the present
Murfreesboro music club was named, was an instructor. William
Blake Carlton was director of the chorus, assisted by Mary Belle
judson. Rubye Augusta Taylor (Mrs. Aultman Sanders) was instruct-or
of violin.
There was considerable institutional "inbreeding" of faculty.
In 1918 Violet Gross, A. B. 1916, music; Fay Poole, A. B. 1916,
expression; Lucile Inlow, A. B. 1917, English; Rhoda Smith A. B.
1914, elementary teacher; and Ina Smith, A. B. 1915, bursar; were
members of the staff. Such retention of graduates was one of the
reasons the traditions of Tennessee College have been so well
preserved.
In 1918 the sophomore class "adopted" a French orphan of
World War I - Guillanne Le Bihou. Armistice Day, November 11,
brought the school an unexpected holiday. A Red Cross auxiliary
on campus during the war numbered 66 members.
That year the student body was divided into two groups,
"Army" and "Navy", as the patriotic theme ran throughout the
Dryad. The year following, this Army-Navy motif, was used by
alumnae in launching a drive for $25,000 to "erect a memorial
library to honor Alice Burnett Stevens, A. B. , 1912, who died
of pneumonia October 21, 1918." The two student groups raised
$2,583.
Another drive, in 1915, was started by the girls to raise
$1,000 in a two month period beginning on December 14, 1914 - a
total of $1,606 was raised to aid in furnishing the school
library.
13
The student handbook of 1917-18 concluded with a statement
that seems to have been a part of the warp and woof of each
Tennessee College student-- "Have an unquenchable enthusiasm
for college life and let nothing daunt it."
This "unquenchable enthusiasm" was reflected in so many ways.
Pagentry played a prominent role in the traditions of the
school. Fortissimo, if it could be so applied, would be an apt
adjective for the function of music in the curriculum.
Drama and music became such an integral part of Tennessee
College that one year the students produced such versatile
presentations as "She Stoops to Conquer", "Little Town of
Bethlehem," "A Dream of the Past," "Tom Sawyer" "Alice in Wonder-land,"
and the annual May Day Festival. Much of the elaborate
sets, costuming, and musical interludes were products of student
effort.
The name of the College yearbook. The Dryad, and the Maypole
dances might have seemed a bit incongruous in an institution
devoted to the virtues of Baptist teaching. Yet the program
that marked the college decennial was typjcal of the blending of
fact and fantasy that was the catalyzer of the enduring and
unique spirit of Tennessee College.
The massive oaks that dotted the 15 acre campus - particularly
the stark, splintered trunk of a lighning blasted tree - was a
fit setting for the "Dryad Dream" in which fair denizens work
an adroit thaumaturgy on the conscious life, the intellect and
the emotions of these gentle and dedicated Thespians.
14
Occasionally, the pagentry reflected the modernity of a
period. In the February 1926 Tennessee College Magazine there
v/as an account of the Lanier Literary Society presentation in
which a French cabaret "The Black Cat" was featured. The guests
were permitted to enter through the mouth of a huge replica of
a cat's head. Attractive decorations suggested a French motif;
however, the liquid refreshments were limited to lemonadel
Following a "delightful hour in chapel," the midway was
opened. Amid the attractions was: The Wild Man, the Fortune
Tellers, the Moving Picture Show, the Animal Show, and the Merry-go-
round. Backers made enthusiastic spiels and refreshment
booths served sandwiches, ice cream cones, candy, punch, and
"other delicacies." Waitresses danced and sang and then took
orders for French wines (red, green, and yellow lemonade) . Other
features included a roulette wheel by means of which noisy favors
were distributed.
This all woman's college had scores of stirring and beautiful
songs, many of which are still sung at the annual alumnae meeting.
Among the first of these was "0 Tennessee, Fair Tennessee." The
lyrics were written by Frances Allen Hobgood with Elizabeth
Braswell Stephens composing the music.
"The Green and White" was composed by Mary Bell Judson with
the music by Henry Nast.
Ina Smith wrote the "College Hymn" and one of the more
popular of several May Day songs. The arrangements for each was
by Violet Gross. Other favorites was the Freshman song, "We were
Green as the Summer Grass" and "Tell Me Why."
15
Eva Lewis Smith poetized "CXir Alma Mater" that carried
the refrain:
T. C, T. C, prospered may she be;
T. C, T. C, the only one for me.
She's the queen, East or West,
She's the one I love best.
Health and physical education were important roles in TCW.
The TENNESSEE-ANN, the yearbook and promotional material of the
college, listed a variety of athletic activities from tennis to
field hockey.
A 1937 Field Day record of the Tennessee College Athletic
Association shows some remarkable track and field accomplish-ments.
A Miss Williams ran the 100-yard dash in 13 seconds.
Miss Noland took the 60-yard low hurdles in 9 4/5 seconds. Miss
Pugh and Miss Boyd tied at 47 inches in the high jump. Miss
Williams jumped 13 feet in the running broad jump and 7 feet
2 inches in the standing broad jump. Miss Muller won the base-ball
throw with 141 feet. Miss Judd tossed the basketball 17.8
feet. Miss Wade placed first in both the soccer kick (88 feet)
and the field hockey drive (156 feet) . Miss Haas was credited
with a winning toss of 29 feet, 3 inches in the nine pound shot
put, and she heaved the javelin 84 feet.
There were many hallowed traditions at Tennessee College.
The most famous of these was the May Day ceremonies which,
for many years, began with the Y.W.C.A. hanging a little cornu-copia
filled with spring flowers on the door of each room during
the night of April 30. The May Day celebration attracted a large
crowd each year. Two heralds led the parade with the May Queen
and her court arriving in a coach as a highlight of the pagentry.
16
The Athletic Association usually welcomed new students in
early September with a hike and in mid-October they were hostesses
to a "children's party." There were excursions to Lookout Mountain
or Mammoth Cave. On one occasion the entire faculty and student
body spent a day touring Vanderbilt, climaxed by singing at the
dedication of the Masonic Tertple.
watermelon cuttings the first week of school, the fall
outing at the Stones River Battlefield, memory books, the annual
song contest, the "fire squad," the Christmas Pageant at First
Baptist Church were among the continuing traditions established
at Tennessee College.
The period 1917 to 1923 was impeded by World War I. The
enrollment during this period was approximately 125, the primary
department having been discontinued. Enthusiasm ran high in 1919
because of the "75 million campaign." Tennessee College under
the plan of expenditure was to receive $400,000 and the Tennessee
College Magazine for December, 1919, spoke enthusiastically of
"No debts, a new heating plant, a new library, and a new
dormitory.
"
In 1920 property known as the "Thomas Property" was purchased.
In 1921 the Board took action to strengthen the college depart-ment
by stating that "it be the sense of this Board that our
President project the work of the college on a basis looking to
the making of Tennessee College a standard college."
In 1922 President Burnett offered his resignation. It was
accepted, effective June 1, 1923, and Dr. Harry Clark had this
to say in the Baptist and Reflector ;
17
"This is another case where the denomination loses the
services of one of its strong men because burdens grew
too heavy for him to bear . . For years there have
been positions for President Burnett to go into business
at twice the salary he is now receiving, but he has held
on out of loyalty to the Baptist cause. It is therefore
fitting that we should express our appreciation for his
heroic efforts."
Dr. E. L. Atwood, then vice-president of the school, was
made acting president and on March 4, 1924 he was named presi-dent
of the school.
Dr. Edward Leland Atwood was born in Clinton, Kentucky,
October 30, 187 2. He received the A. B. degree from Georgetown
in 1901. He attended the Groyer Theological seminary and received
the B. D. degree in 1909. In 1916 he was awarded the D. D. degree
from Union University. He came to Tennessee College as professor
of Bible and Religious Education in 1921.
Dr. Atwood laid great stress on standardization, but he met
the same economic problems which had been met previously. In
his annual report for 1927, he openly faced the issue with the
Board.
In 1928 Dr. W. M. Woods was selected as field representative
in an endeavor to raise $3 50,000 for endowment. In 1929 the
school was admitted to the Association of Colleges of Tennessee.
In 1930 the school was conferring the Bachelor of Arts and the
Bachelor of Science degrees and the work was approved by the
Southern Association of Colleges.
Dr. James A. Kirtley was dean of the college for many years
and was acting president for one year.
During the depression of the early thirties, the college under-went
severe financial difficulties. Members of the faculty and
18
administration received only a small per cent of their stipu-lated
salary. The Board of Trustees issued $100,000 in bonds
on February 8, 193 3.
Due to high-powered student solicitation, the enrollment
for 1935-37 was one hundred seventy, one of the largest in the
school's history. In 1938-39 the enrollment had dropped to only
seventy-eight and was low during the last years of operation
of the college.
In July, 1940, Dr. Atwood was retired by the Board of
Trustees and Reverend Merrill D. Moore, pastor of the Baptist
Church, Newport, Tennessee, named as his successor. Mr. Moore
resigned the presidency in March 1942, and relinquished his work
with the commencement exercises June 9, 1942. The enrollment
for the last year of administration was ninety-four. The bonded
debt was reduced by some eight or nine thousand dollars during
the two years tenure of Mr. Moore.
Dr. John B. Clark, former dean of Mercer University, became
president and head of the social science department on June 9, 1942.
He served in this capacity for four years, until the college
closed on July 1, 1945.
John Bunyan Clark was born in Hamilton, Alabama, and in
1907 received the B. S. Degree from Alabama Polytechnic Institute.
He was awarded the A. M. degree by Vanderbilt University in 1910.
He attended Harvard in 1911 and received the Ph.D. degree from
New York University in 1926. He was principal of high schools
in Alabama for a number of years. From 1917-1920, he was a
member of the S':ate Department of Education of Alabama. He was
19
Professor of history and enonomics at Alabama Polytechnic
Institute from 1920 - 1927, going from there to Judson College
where he served as Dean. In 1929, he went to Mercer as professor
of history and Dean of the College of Arts and Sciences.
There was an indebtedness of $24,000 on the college when
Dr. Clark took charge. Through the efforts of Dr. Clark, the
Women's Missionary Union, and the Baptist Cooperative Program,
by November 1945, the college was not only free from debt, but
had on hand a cash balance of approximately $135,000.
During the last years of Tennessee College, a great many
improvements were made in the physical plant; additions were
made to the library and equipment; the curriculum was revised;
plans were approved for new buildings. But the action of the
Baptist Executive Board and the Board of Trustees brought to
an end Tennessee College for Women in Murfreesboro after an
existence of over forty years.
A Bachelor of Science and Bachelor of Arts degree program
designed to be completed in three calendar years was developed.
One-year and two-year secretarial courses were offered, includ-ing
an oxymorous liberal arts- secretarial "church secretarial
certificate" for those who wished to combine somewhat contra-dictory
disciplines. A two-year course in music and a similar
offering in "Expression" leading to a Certificate was offered.
Provisions were made for the first two years work in pre-medical,
pre-nursing, and home economics.
Dr. Clark offered his resignation on October 19, 1945.
It was accepted by the Board of Trustees November 6, 1945.
20
On November 14, 1945, at the Baptist Convention in Nash-ville,
a committee was appointed to investigate and report back
to the 1946 convention on the advisability of making Tennessee
College co-educational. On December 11, 1945, the state
executive board voted to merge Tennessee College and all its
assets with Cumberland University at Lebanon. On January 10,
1946, this merger was approved by a majority of the Board of
Trustees,
Following this action, the minority group of trustees
filed suit to enjoin the Baptist Executive Board and the
majority of trustees from transferring the property. The
injunction was dissolved and the city of Murfreesboro and Ruther-ford
County purchased the property for a high school.
On June 20, 1946, by order of attorneys of both factions.
Dr. Clark turned over to representatives of Cumberland University
approximately $115,000 in cash and U. S. Bonds, and $8,000 of
student notes receivable.
At the Convention meeting in 1945, in the First Baptist
Church in Nashville, Lynn Claybrook, pastor of the First Baptist
Church in Lewisburg, brought the report on Christian Education.
According to a History of the Tennessee Baptist Convention ,
1974, by W. Fred Kendall, this report was a strong plea for a
college in Middle Tennessee for the training of ministers to be
established. The Rev. W. M. Wood of Murfreesboro introduced a
recommendation that Tennessee College be made a co- educational
institution.
The matter was tabled until after the college presidents
had spoken. Vferren F. Jones, Union University; James T. Warren,
21
Carson-Nev/man; John B. Clark, Tennessee College for Women; and
Roy Anderson, Harrison-Chilhowee Academy all spoke, discussing
the schools they served as presidents.
The matter of making Tennessee College for Women a co-educational
institution was considered and a committee appointed
to report to the Convention at its 1946 session.
The media accounts of the Convention action attracted the
attention of the trustees of Cumberland University, Lebanon,
Tennessee. They approached Tennessee Baptists with a proposition
to turn over the school and deed the property, located at
Lebanon, Tennessee, to Tennessee Baptists on the condition that:
(1) the school be maintained as a four-year co-educational
college with university rating; (2) the name, Cumberland
University, be retained; and (3) within a reasonable time the
endowment of the institution be increased to not less than
$5,000,000, to enable the institution to qualify for membership
in the Southern Association of Colleges. This proposition was
presented to the Executive Board in their annual session in
December 1945. The Board did not think it wise for Tennessee
Baptists to try to maintain two senior colleges in Middle
Tennessee. They recommended that Tennessee College for Women,
with an enrollment of only 7 5 students, be disbanded, its
property sold and used for endowment for Cumberland University,
and that 5 per cent which it received from Cumberland Program
receipts be transferred to Cumberland University.
Dr. Homer Pittard in his "Pillar and Ground", the history of
the Baptist Church in Murf reesboro, records the reaction of
this city to the consolidation with Cumberland.
22
"The year 1944 ended on a particularly dreary
note since it was learned that on December 11,
the Executive Board of the Tennessee Baptist
Convention had voted to merge the assets of
Tennessee College for Women with Cumberland
University of Lebanon, Tennessee; and WHEREAS,
Tennessee College for Women has operated
successfully for the past forty years and whose
graduates are now prominently identified in the
business world, in home making and in missions,
and WHEREAS, Murfreesboro and Rutherford County
have contributed both moral and financial support
to this institution over the years, BE IT RE-SOLVED
by the deacons of the First Baptist
Church, that we regret the committee's action in
setting forth this merger which will deprive
our church and community of a great asset.
Committee on Resolutions: H. F. Cantrell, Chair-man;
Lawrence Freeman, and W. W. McMasters.
This was followed in April by the announcement
that the church would become a party to the
pending suit in Chancery Court between the trustees
of Tennessee College and the trustees of Cumberland
University. The minority group, nine in number,
were all Rutherford County residents. There
were eighteen others divided equally between East
and West Tennessee. The participation of the
23
Baptist Church in the litigation proved to be a
futile gesture, however; it did serve to register
the indignation of the Murfreesboro community."
After a full discussion and the presentation of the legal
aspects of such a transfer by Andrew Tanner, attorney for the
Executive Board, the Executive Board voted to take over Cumber-land
University and set forth the conditions of the agreement.
It was agreed that a four-year co-educational school of
university rating be maintained, that the Cumberland Law School
be maintained as a part of the school, that within a reasonable
time the endowment be increased to permit membership in the
Southern Association of Accredited Colleges, and that Cumberland
University would be retained as the name of the institution.
Such charter changes were to be made as to give the institution
the same relationship to the Convention in the matter of owner-ship,
supervision, election of trustees and financial support
as that which existed between the Convention and Carson-Newman
College and Union University, with the specific understanding
that it was the purpose of the Convention to maintain for an
indefinite time a standard four-year senior co-educational
institution.
The Executive Board recommended that Tennessee College
for Women be merged with Cumberland University. Its records,
including alumnae records, were to be preserved as part of the
new institution. Traditional organizations and scholarship
funds as far as practicable, were to be preserved. A new
women's dormitory at Cumberland was to be named Tennessee College
Hall to indicate the relationship of Tennessee College to Cumber-
24
land. All of the equipment and other properties which could
be legally transferred to the new institution were to be
included in the merger.
In January 1946, the majority of the trustees of Tennessee
College for Women voted favorably upon the merger with Cumber-land
University. On the following day the Cumberland University
Board of Directors transferred both the property of the
university and their position as directors to a Baptist Board
of Directors, elected by the Executive Board. Edwin Preston,
from Arkansas, was elected president of the new college.
In the report on Christian Education to the Convention in
1945, an appraisal of this transaction was made:
By this provision Tennessee Baptists have acquired
without additional expense in cost or operating expenses
to the Convention, a senior college, for the training of
its ministry, a large body of law students, and both men
and women in the school of Arts and Sciences ... It will
also be noted that by this action the student body of the
Baptist school in Middle Tennessee has been increased from
approximately 75 students to 517 students, and its equip-ment
has been increased from approximately $10,000 to
$371,000.
Cumberland University had been operated under the auspices
of the U. S. A. Presbyterian Church which had ceased to give
support, and the school operated independently for a short time
before Baptists took it over.
The Law school, offering a one-year course, had graduated
many successful lawyers and had enjoyed an international reputa-tion
for many years.
In November 1948 every effort was made to help the consol-idation
with Cumberland to succeed.
25
The "Second Century" program was launched. There was a
campaign to raise $630,000 to be used for development. Endow-ment
was to be increased by $150,000 and $187,000 was to be
used to build additions to "Tennessee College Hall" the
residence center for women, and a president's home.
But after years of struggle, Cumberland lost its famous
Law School to Sanford University in Birmingham, Alabama, and
the senior college at Cumberland was consolidated with Belmont
College of Nashville in 1951.
The final years of each of these great Tennessee educational
institutions illustrates a thought of Thucydides. "Each presses
its own ends which generally results in actions where
The Common Cause decays." Fortunately the "common cause" that
decayed in Murfreesboro and Lebanon has found growth at Sanford
University and Belmont College. Both are Baptist institutions
that reflect the principles of the founders of each institution--
quality education.
Thus those who labored so valiantly for each school may
reflect that they were sustaining the old classical admonition
&#8212;
"Fortiter in re suavites in modes." Each was indeed very
gracious under pressure.
Tommy Lowe Curtis' history of Tennessee College closes
with a significant statement:
"So the history, the heritage, the high ideals
of Tennessee College for Women were given to a new
school and to new students to be perpetuated for-ever.
The four goals that are inscribed in the
Seal of Belmont College are not new: Truth, Courage,
Integrity and Service are ideals that have been
in existence since Tennessee College for Women came
into existence: we who carry these lamps with which
to light the darkness are deeply indebted to those
who lit and guarded them through the years."
26
A catalog published in 1940 gave the only comprehensive
record of the physical plant as it appeared in the last decade
of its operation.
Tennessee College was housed in a pressed brick, trimmed
with stone, situated in the center of an oak dotted 20 acre
campus on the north side of East Main Street, six blocks from
Court Square. The main building was 250 feet long, 125 feet
deep, rising three floors above the basement. There were three
entrances off East Main Street, each with a classic colonial
porch. The east wing contained the dining hall, kitchen, and
storage rooms. In the central portion of the main building,
the offices, four parlors, the faculty room, the student
recreation hall, the assembly hall, and the library were located.
On the second floor of this section, rooms used by the
Ruskin and Lanier Literary Societies, the Senior Hall, and
the piano studio were situated. Science laboratories were
contained in the basement. Four rooms on the third floor of
the east wing were equipped as an infirmary. A nurse was on
duty day and night.
The "North Building" was originally constructed as a
gymnasium in December, 1908.
Additions and modernization provided for home economics
laboratories, music, and lecture rooms. The 12,000 volume,
W. E. Everett Library with accomodations for 50 persons, was
also located in this area.
Immediately to the rear of the west wing of the building
was a 40 X 70 outdoor swimming pool. The area included a large
27
recreation space, tennis courts, a formal garden, and a
hockey field. The college building was centrally heated by
steam. There were 25 bathrooms on the second and third floors
where domiciliary units were located. These double rooms
were supplied with steel beds, equipped with steel springs,
felt mattresses and feather pillows, dressers, wardrobes,
study tables, straight chairs, and rocking chairs.
The final bulletin in 1945 issued by the College, listed
an accelerated program based on four quarters work provided
for completing the requirements for admission and the cost of
attending the college.
Expenses for the nine months term as listed in the 1945
catalog provided for tuition $270, Registration $2, Activity
fee $7.50, Infirmary $6, and Library $6. The activity fee
included subscriptions to the annual and the student newspaper.
There were various additional fees for music instruction, the
use of laundry room, electrical appliances, and "for all light
bulbs in excess of one 7 5 watt bulb for each room;" Textbooks
could be rented. Each freshman student was required to keep
a detailed record of expenditures and to submit the record to
the head of the commercial department for inspection and counsel.
The College also provided a bank for a depository of small amounts
of spending money.
Single meals were provided at 25 cents for breakfast, 35
cents for lunch, 40 cents for dinner, and 50 cents for the
Sunday special dinner.
Sionday, May 19, and Tuesday, May 21 marked the thirty-ninth
28
and final programs at Tennessee College for Women. At 11 A.M.
Siinday morning the members of this last class filed down to
the appointed area at First Baptist Church to hear the Rev.
T. B. Milligan offer the invocation and Dr. Andrew M. Smith
deliver the baccalaureate sermon. A classmate, Aletha Balcer,
sang "Some Sweet Day" and the Glee Club rendition was Thayer' s
"March On, Ye Soldiers True."
A play was presented by members of the senior class on
Monday evening following class day activities in the afternoon.
The change in curriculum in the later years is well illus-trated
in that only two musical diplomas&#8212;Aletha Waline Baker
in voice and Peggy Schneider Havens in music were awarded.
Yet in secretarial science, there were certificates to Dorothy
Perdue, Evelyn Perdue Sinclair, and Dorothy Mai Evans. Certi-ficates
in church secretarial science went to Alta Lee Grimes,
Mary Bedford Rogers, Vaughtie B. Rowland, Effie Lee Smith Miller,
and Lillie Dale Willard.
Bachelor of Science degrees were awarded Rita Marie Bentley,
Margaret Lanier Dunaway, Mary Elizabeth Smith, and Elizabeth
Wright. The more classical Bachelor of Arts were received by
Aletha Waline Baker, Lucy Carmine Boyd, Alta Lee Grimes, Peggy
Schneider Havens, Dorothy Clark Hendrix, Margaret Jackson,
Dorothy Perdue, Evelyn Perdue Sinclair, Mary Faye Pierce,
Carol Porter, Mary Bedford Rogers, Effie Lee Smith Miller and
Emma Anderson Towne.
Dr. W. C. Jones delivered the commencement sermon at ten
o'clock Tuesday morning. The Glee Club sang, Faye Pierce gave
an organ solo, President Clark conferred the degrees and certi-ficates,
the seniors sang The Alma Mater, O Tennessee Fair
Tennessee and all was over.
POISED FOR THE TRIP TO THE RAILWAY STATION
VIA UNION TAXI COMPANY
Posed but going nowhere: Martha Trevathan (Mrs. Dallas Ison) identified in this picture the
members (by their college names) of the Tennessee College Glee Club and made this
comment: "This print is a copy of the picture used for publicity purposes by the Tennessee
College Glee Club for its concert tours and the college annual. The Dryad, for 1935-36. It was
posed at the then rather new Sky Harbor, and the group's destination was as viewed. The
economic situation at the time made funds for even bus fares rather difficult for our group."
Those shown (left to right) are as follows: Director William Blake Carlton, Business Manager
Frances George, Unidentified, Rebekah Fisher, Katherine Bass, Pres., Martha Trevathan,
Lenora Edwards, Mary Elizabeth Duckworth, Ruth Shellenburger, Christine Johnson,
Jeanne Roberts, Katie Bell Smith, Marjorie Cambron, Maribeth Keeling, Florence Cox,
Lucinda Stone, Nelle Dodson, Virginia Anderson, Elizabeth Fowler, Rebecca Lax, Elizabeth
Curtis, Edna Lynn Wayne, Helen Cambron, Dorothy Noland, Freda Atwood, Marion Brasel,
Nona Boitnot, Vera Pearson, Edith Cron, Doris Caton Lovelace, Jean Kirtley, Jo Mitchell,
Mildred Robertson, VicePres. Individuals on steps from top: Virginia Stone, Marilyn
Neatherly, Sec.-Treas., Lurleen Bugg.
Heralds Leading The Procession
At Traditional May Day Pageant - 1 91
4
I i iil
Moon Over T.C. - Almost
^^ai
^^f^iiiagM
"Action" On The Courts To The
Rear Of The Building - 1 909</dc:description>
<dc:description>Tells the history of Tennessee College for Women, once located at the present site of Central Magnet Middle School on East Main Street, from its beginnings in 1906 until its closing in 1945</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rutherford County (Tenn.) -- History; Union University (Jackson, Tenn.); Universities and colleges -- Tennessee</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Tennessee College for Women</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>Murfreesboro</dc:coverage>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>59 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-01</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication13ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/126</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>