<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Petition of James Bole of Rutherford County for a Revolutionary War pension</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Bole, James; McFerrin, B.L.</dc:creator>
<dc:contributor>Fry, Edna</dc:contributor>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 13</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1832</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>1770-1779; 1780-1789; 1830-1839</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>72
PEnnON OF JAMES BOLE OF RDTHERFORD CODNTI
FOR i REVOLDTIONART WAR PENSION
Pumlshed by Mrs. Edna Fry
State of Tennessee
Circuit CoTirt, April Term, 1832
Rutherford County
On this 30th day of August, 1832, personally appeared before Burton L. McFerrin
an acting Justice of the Peace, for the County and State aforesaid. Janes Bole
at the residence of the said Janes Bole In the County and State aforesaid, aged
Eighty three years, three nonths and eleran days, who being first duly sworn
according to law, doth, on his oath, nake the following declaration in order to
obtain the benefit of the act of Congress passed June the 7th, 1832.
That he entered the service of the United States under the following naned
officers and served as herein stated. Having been drafted in the nilitia of
Pennsylvania he entered upon duty on the 26th day of July 1776 under Captain
Robert Elton, Janes Thonpson First Lieutenant and he thinks Jodeph Fleming
Second Lieutenant. On the day aforesaid the company to which he belonged,
assembled at the house of Captain Elton, then comnander, and marched directly
to Philadelphia, where they arrived he thinks the second day after they left
home. At Philadelphia his company joined the regiment of Pennsylvania Militia,
commanded by Colonel Moon, who had been commonly called Squire Moon before
entering the am^, having been a Justice of the Peace and his given name he does
not remember. At the time he entered the service as aforesaid, he resided in
Chester County, East Cain township in the State of Pennsylvania. His Captain
Elton, resided in the same county of township, and Colonel resided in the same
county, but he thinks not in the sane township. At the time he was drafted, he
thinks there was orders to raise ten thousand militia in the State of Pennsylvania,
to form what was called the flying camp . In about a week after he joined his
regiment at Philadelphia as well as he can recollect, he marched with his reglneat
to Amboy in the Jarsies, at which place the whole of the Pennsylvania Militia, met
together and quartered. He does not remember the names of the general officers
^o had the command of the whole of the troops; he knows he was in service under
General Patton the next year, and he may have had command of the troops at Amboy,
but he cannot remember so as to feel safe in stating it to have been so. He
remembers that the other field officers of his regiment, besides Colonel Moon,
was John Hammens First Major, John Culberson Second Major and Alexander Fleming
Standard bearer. The name of the adjutant of the regiment he has forgotten.
The term of service for which he was drafted was two months , which time he served
out, dviring the whole of which time he was quartered at Amboy as was the wnole
of the Pennsylvania Militia as well as he recollects. He was quartered immediately
on the soiind, above the mouth of the Raritan. During the whole of the time, to
the best of his recollection, that he was qiiartered at, or in Amboy, the British
was qioartered Immediately on the opposite side of the sound on Statan Island so
near to us that we could hear them beating the revilee every morning and sometimes
in the evening we could hear the beind of . While the militia were thus
situated there was a British vessel lay at about the distance of four miles down
73
the 80\md fi&gt;om us In fxill vision. He supposed his object In being there was to
watch our movements, amd give notice to the British troops on the Island, if we
should make any movements like crossing over to attack them. There was nothing
like an engagement between the British troops, and the forces to which he belonged,
during all the time he was at kmboj, that is to say there was nothing like a
general engagement. The British fired their cannon on the town of Amboy once or
twice, and he understood that they kill a man in the court house, who was in the
upper story. The troops to which he belonged, were once drawn up in line of battle,
the artillery planted and matches prepared to fire this cannon, but there was no
engagement and he does not remeniber to have seen any of the enemy; and he is not
able to state what was really the object of forming the troops in battle array.
During the time he was qxiartered as above stated he remembers an incident which
occurred that may not be amiss to mention. Several of our soldiers went into the
sound to bathe, and one of them kept swimming farther on towards the opposite '
side, returning and then swimming farther than before, \mtll at last, having
gotten a considerable distance from his comerades, it was perceived his intention
was to desert and cross over to the enemy. When this was discovered, our guard
commenced firing at him, but he had gotten so far from the shore, he was in but
little danger of being hit. Being am expert swimmer, he turned himself on his
back and in that way swam at his leisure, watching the fire of our guard, and
whenever he would see the flash of their guns, he would dive his head down in
the water, and then rest and swim on, lontil in that way he reached the opposite
side, where some of the British troops were assembled, by whom he was received with
demonstrations of great joy. Having served out his two months as above stated he
was verbally discharged by his 6aptain, or Lieutenant and he returned home.
On the Ist day of January, 1777, he agiin left home as a volunteer, and
proceeded to Philadelphia (his residence scill being in Chester County as afore-said)
where he entered the service in Captain William Wither 's company of volunteers,
he does not remember about the regiment to which he belongs, or that he belonged to
any regimsnt. He thinks his commander Colonel Moon, did not tvirn out on that
occasion, and he is under the iii^)resslon that there was no troops then at Phila-delphia,
but such volunteers as had thought proper to turn out in their countiry's
defense. He remembers, however, that Major Hannims was there, having volunteered,
eind that he belonged to his command, and he also remembers Major Spears who was
next in command to Bajor Hannims. The troops at Philadelphia were \mder the command
of General Putman. He does not think there was at that time, any regular troops
at Philadelphia, his best recollection is that they were all then at Morrlstown.
From Philadelphia, General Putman marched us to Trenton, and then to Princeton,
without making more than one night's halt at Trenton. We reached Princeton a few
days after the Battle had taken place there, between Gen. Washington's troops and
the British, and we were three days marching from Philadelphia there, encamping
the first night at Bristol the second at Trenton as already stated and the third
reaching Princeton. The troops which his regiment detached at Princeton
by Gen. Putman. After reaching Princeton he remained there during the
whole of the time of service, which was two months, except as hereafter stated.
While there General Putman made a call for a con^jany of volunteers to march to
Somerset for the pvirpose of attacking a party of the British which it was understood
was stationed there for the purpose of foraging. About fifty volunteered, declarant
being one of the number, and on the night of the 20th of Febrviary, we sat out and
proceeded about thirty miles, where we halted and remained until daylight. We then
proceeded on and reached Somerset about twelve o'clock. On that expedition we were
commanded by Captain Boon, who had volimteered to command us. A short distance
before we marched the town, we came upon the eneny's Sentinel, and fired at him, but
74
without effect. He immediately retreated to the main body of the enemy, and in
a very short time, we saw the eneniy, advancing and forming on an eminence in front
of the town. We soon perceived that they were too strong in numbers for us, and
therefore retreated without coming to an engagement. The enemy, infjtead of
piu*suing us, wheeled and marched in the other direction. For this movement, we
were unable to account, unless they was deceived as to our niimbers, a great many
coiontry people having joined us on horseback and went along with men from
curiosity as he supposes, than from any other notion, and moreover, we had formed
ourselves in a single file across an open field which made o\ir numoers appear greater
than it really was. Being thus deceived, or otherwise, if they discovered the
smallness of our forces, they supposed that we were only the advanced guard of
our army, that had been sent forward to bring on an engagement and then retreat,
and there by decoy them into the midst of superior numbers. Be this as it may
they wheeled in the other direction which perceiving we turned and pursued them.
On discovering which they hastened their retreat, and we were never able to over
take them, or get sight of them after they turned the hill, on which as already
stated, they at first fonned, although we pursued them through the town of Somerset,
and within three miles of Brunswic at which place, the main body of troops to
which they belonged, were stationed. When within that distsmce of Brunswic,
night overtook us, and we halted and took up quarters. The next morning we
proceeded on towards Brunswic and met with some American Light horse who had
been out or who was then out on a reconnoitering expedition. We still progressed
on in sight of Bmjnswic expecting that we should probably fall in with some of
the eneny In small parties; but we met with none of them, and so returned back
from there to Princeton. Declarant does not remember that there was any regular
troops at Princeton while he was quartered there. At the end of his tour, which
was two months, he received a verbal discharge from his Captain, and returned
home.
Early in the spring, after his return home, he was elected Second Lieutenant
in the Militia Company to which, he belonged, and then being a call upon the
militia shortly after his election, he was drafted. The company had been classed
in eight classes, to the second of which he belonged, and the first second
classes were both called out. He went out on the 25th day of June, 1777, and
commanded as Second Lieutenant in the company to which he belonged. The company
was under the command of Captain Scott, the najne of the First Lieutenant he
cannot remember, he having been a stranger to him before he went out; and he had
no acquaintances with him after his return home. He has also forgotten the name
of the ensign. His commission as Second Lieutenant, or at least a part of it .
under which he acted as such on this tour, is hereto annexed. A part of the
commission had been destroyed or lost by the wear and tear of time . It will be
perceived that his name in the part of his commission is spelled Boyle, which
spelling is sometimes adopted by those who are not familiar with his name, and
his mode of spelling it; and he supposed the Secretary in issuing his commission
fell into the mistake about the orthography of his name, which had sometimes
been made by others he states that under the commission, a part of which is here
exhibited, he acted knowing that it was intended for him, although the spelling
of his name is incorrect. The date of the commission is gone, and although it
is so much mutilitated he thought it best to append it to his declaration.
Declarant states that his company marched directly to Chester in Pennsylvania,
which is about thirty miles distant from where he resided, and thus he joined
the regiment commanded by Colonel Hannims, who had previously been a Major, and
is the same heretofore mention in this declaration. Major Morton commanded in
the regiment as First Major and Major Hartman acted as the Adjutant to troops
75
to which he belonged when on this toiir was under the commajid of General Potter.
He remained at Chester one month, during which time he had no action or dangerous
duties to perform. The troops during this time was regularly drilled everyday.
After remaining at Chester one month as above stated, he was marched across the
Delaware river to Billingsport on the Jersey side, where the troops to which he
belonged were engaged in building a fort and making puch fortifications as it was
thought the safety and proper defense of the country required. He was personally
fiuid actively engaged in this business. Having been one month at Billingsport,
and having served upon this tour two months in the whole, that being the period
for which he was called out, he was verbally discharged and had returned home.
About the 15th of June, 1778, as declarant thinks, he was again drafted and
went out a Second Lieutenant in a company commanded by Captain Ephraim Allen.
On this tour we were ordered out by the county Lieutenant, and was quartered at
one John Garner's in Chester County about one month; during which time we did
nothing but drill, vie were then ordered to Philadelphia by the county Lieutenant,
and upon our arrival there, thus being no farther use for us, we were verbally
discharged, and declarant returned home, which ended his military services;
except about five months, dviring which he was afterwards engaged as a waggoner
in the army; but for this service, he is advised he is not entitled to pay, under
the construction put upon the act of Congress by the War Department. Declarant
had no documentary evidence of his services except the part of his commission,
as hereto annexed, and he knows of no person, whose testimony he can procure;
who can testify to his services.
Declarant was born in Chester County, East Cain township Pennsylvania, near
little Brandywinc creek on the 19th of Kay, 174-9. He has no record of his age,
his information about his age he obtained from a record made in a bible,
belonging to his stepfather's in Pennsylvania, which he often saw, until he was
about 36 years of age. He left the bible at his stepfather's when he left there,
aJid he does not know what has become of it. When he entered service at each of
the periods as aforesaid, he resided in Chester County, Pennsylvania, as already
stated, and continued to reside there until 1780, at which time he moved to
Lancaster County, Pennsylvania, where he resided until 1785, at which time he
removed to Chester County, South Carolina, where he resided about eleven years,
thence he removed to Pendleton district where he resided until the 3rd day of
November, 1807, at which time he started to remove to Tennessee. On reaching
Tennessee, he settled in Rutherford County, where he has resided ever since. He
has already stated he was drafted, each term of service, except the second when
he volunteered. He never received a written discharge from the service. He
was well acquainted with General Sommers, Captain Brinkley, and Lieutenant Harris
of the North Carolina regular troops while they were stationed at Valley Forge,
but at the time he knew those officers, he was not himself in the army.
He is known to Francis Youree, Charles Ready Sen., Post I'^ster at Readyville,
Richard Standrige, Nathan I^on and many other persons in his neighborhood, who
he believes will testify as to his character for veracity and their belief of his
services as a soldier of the revolution.
He hereby relinquishes every claim to a pension whatever, or to an annuity.
except the present, and declares that his name is not on the pension roll of the
agency of any state.
76
Sworn to and subscribed the
day and year sd'oresaid before his
me. James x Bole
mark
We Francis Youree and Charles Ready Sen., Post Master at Readyville, Rutherford
County, Tennessee, both residing in said Rutherford County, hereby certify, that
we are well acquainted with James Bole who has subscribed and sworn to the above
declaration; that we believe him to be Eighty three years of age; that he is
reputed and believed in the neighborhood where he resided, to have been a soldier
of the revolution, and that we concvir in that opinion.
Sworn to and subscribed the s/Charles Ready Sen.
day and year kforesaid before
me. s/Francis louree
And I, the said Burton L. McFerrin Esq. do hereby declare iny opinion after
the investigation of the natter, and after putting the interrogations prescribed
by the *^ar Department, that the above named applicant was a revolutionary soldier,
and served as he states. And I, the said Burton L. McFerrin Esq. further certify
that I am well acquainted with Francis Youree and Charles Ready who have assigned
the foregoing certificate, and that they are residents of the county of Rutherford
and State of Tennessee, that they are credible persons, and that their statement is
entitled to credit. I also further certify that James Bole, the applicant who had
assigned and sworn to the foregoing declaration is infirm, and unable on account
of his infirmity to go to a court of record of the county, to subscribe to his
declaration.
B. L. McFerrin</dc:description>
<dc:description>A reprint of Revolutionary War soldier James Bole's 1832 petition to Rutherford County courts for a pension from his years of service</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Court records; Military pensions; United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1783</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>veterans</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>9 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-03-01</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication13ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/122</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>