<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Rutherford County Historical Society publication no. 11</dc:title>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1978</dc:date>
<dc:description>Digitized by the Internet Archive
in 2010 with funding from
Lyrasis IVIembers and Sloan Foundation
http://www.archive.org/details/publication11ruth
S3.50 The Copy
Rutherford County
Historical Society
PUBLICATION N0.11
Suiiimcr 1978
MURFREESBORO. TENNESSEE 37130
K"t3
TABLE OF CONTENTS
The State Capitol 1819-1826 1
by Alice N, Ray
From Jefferson to Elkhorn Tavern 7
The Story of Ben McCulloch
by Homer Pittard
Petition of Michael Lorance, Revolutionary 31
Soldier
furnished by Mrs. Peggy Herriage
A Country Store (1912-191^) 36
by Jack R. Mankin
^ Soule College e;8
by Eugene Sloan
Index IQil
LIBRARY 79-03209
MIDDLE TENNESSEE STATE UNIVERSITY
MURFREESBORO, TENNESSEE 37130
The Cover
This sketch is a version of the First Presbyterian Church
that stood in Murfreeshoro on East Church Street (now East Vine)
between 1820 and I863. Alice Ray, a member of the Rutherford
County Historical Society and a considerable authority on struc-tural
antiquities, developed a pencil sketch principally from des-criptive
materials found by Dr. Ernest Hooper in his research on
the church. Artist Jim Matheny, another Society member, converted
this rendering to the sharp ink sketch which appears on the cover.
The building was razed some time in I863 during the Federal
occupation of the town and was never rebuilt on this site by the
Presbyterians. The most intriguing aspect of the structure was its
service as the State Capitol in 1822, after the courthouse burned
during that year.
Recently, the Preservation classes at Middle Tennessee State
University, acting under tlie supervision of Dr. James Huhta, made
considerable archaeological explorations in the area of the Old
City Cemetery where the building supposedly stood. The "digs" re-sulted
in the exposing of a rather distinct line of foundation
stones and other data which have added considerably to the know-ledge
of the architectural design of the structure.
Our thanks to Judge Ben Hall McFarlin for his continuing in-terest
in and assistance to the Rutherford County Historical Soci-ety.
Through his efforts, Mrs. Donna Newlon was assigned as secre-tary
to the Society's office and in this capacity performed innu-merable
duties for the Society, including typing for this and
other publications.
RUTHERFORD COUNTY HISTORICAL SOCIETY
PUBLICATION NO. 11
Published by the
RUTHERFORD COUNTY HISTORICAL SOCIETY
OFFICERS
President Dr. Homer Pittard
Vice-President Mr. W. H. Westbrook
Recording Secretary Miss Louise Cav/thon
Corresponding Secretary and Treasurer htrs. Dorothy Hatheny
Publication Secretary Mr. Walter K. Hoover
Directors Kiss Mary Hall
Mr. Robert Rarjland
Mr. William Walkup
Publication No. 11 (Limited Edition~350 copies) is distributed to
members of the Society. The annual membership dues is $5.00 (Family&#8212;??. 00)
which includes the regular publications and the monthly NEV/SLETTER to all
members. Additional copies of Publication No. 11 may be obtained at $3-50
per copy.
All correspondence concerning additional copies, contributions to
futvu*e issues, and membership should be addressed to:
Rutherford County Historical Society
Box 906
Murfreesboro, Tennessee 3V130
RUTHERFORD COUNTY HISTORICAL SOCIETY
PUBLICATION NO. Vl.
FOREWORD
This volume represents the second publication for 1978 and,
follovdng past practice, each member or family membership, receives
a copy as a kind of "refund" for the Society membership duos. Thus,
membership in the Rutherford County Historical Society must be re-garded
as one of the most conpelling bargains found in any organization
in the community.
The Society has lived a life of happy solvency since its found-ing
a few years ago. This has been made possible through several low-key
projects which have generated revenue over and above that needed
for certain community programs and necessary expenses. Too, the wise
and efficient care of the Society funds is another inportant factor.
For this, the Society owes a great debt of gratitude to Dottie Matheny
Patty. Under her close scrutiny, there is never a question at any
time as to the status of the organization's finances.
Publication Ho. 11 is another effort to record some of the
community's heritage, hopefully, for posterity. In doing so, ^he
Society affirms one of the reasons for its foimding.
FOR SALE
THE FOLLOV/ING PUBLICATIONS ARE FOR SALE BY THE RUTIIi^FGRD COUII?! IHSTOnXGAL
SOCIETY, Box 906, Ihirfreesboro, Tennesjoee, 37130:
Publication # 1, 2, 3, U, 5, and 8: Out of print.
Publication # 6: Link Connnunity; History of I^Vergne; Fellov/ship Conanunity;
and the Sanders Family. 03.00 + 0-50 postage
Publication # 7: Hopewell Church, 1816-1883; Stones River Presbyterian
Church; Cripple Creek Presbyterian Church; Early MJJitia Ordor,
Petition by Cornelius Sanders for Rev. War Pencion.
$3.00 + C.50 postage
Publication # 9: History of Dilton $3.50 + 0.5O postage
Publication #10: 1864- Diary; Peter Jennings; Henderson Yoakum; Early
Methodist Church; and Overall Family 03=50 + 0.5O postage
18A0 Rutherford Census ; With index. 05.00 f 0-50 postage
Deed Abstracts of Rutherford Covinty . 1803-1810 . Names of land ovnero and
other genealogical infonnation from early deeds. $10.00 + 0.5O postage
Griffith; A beautifully illustrated bi-centennial publication.
$2.00 + 0.5O postage
The Story of Murfreesboro . A reprint of C. C. Henderson. History of the
town and county, hardbound with an index. $5.00 + $,50 postage
Rutherford County Medallion: Approximately the size of &amp; silver dollar
with Rutherford County coiirthouse pictured on one side and the center
of Tennessee marker on the back. 02. OC + 0.5O postage
Commemorative Plates:
Plate # 2: Pictures old Tennessee College in Murfreesboro
05.00 + 01. 00 postage
Plate 4 3; Pictures the Rutherford County Courthouse about 1900,
before it was remodeled. 06.00 + $1.00 postage
AVAILABLE FROM WILLIAM WALKUP, 202 Ridley St., Snyrna, Tennessee, 37167:
Map of Rutherford County showing roads, streams, and land owners, dated 1878.
03.50 + 0.5O postage
Cemetery Records published jointly with the Sons of tho American Revolution:
Vol. 1: Northwest portion of county including Percy Priest Lake area
and parts of Wilson and Davidson Counties, 256 cemeteries with
index and maps. 010-00 + $.$0 postage
Vol. 2: Eastern portion of Rutherford Co. and the weatern part of
Cannon Co., 2^,1 cematerieo v;ith index and nnps.
,$10.00 + $.50 postage
Vol. 3; Southwestern portion of Rutherford County, 193 cemeteries,
index and maps. $10.00 + $.50 postage
QUERIES
Prepared by Mrs. D. C. Daniel, Jr.
IMPORTANT: Publication of queries in this coluisn is free to all members
as space permits. Each query must appear on a full shcot of paper vhich
must bo dated and include membor'o name and address , Plenso typo if pos-sible.
Queries should give as much pertinent data ast pocsiblo, i.e.
approximate/actual dates of birth, marriage, death, etc. Queries must
refer to RUTHERFORD COUNTY, TENNESSEE FAJ4ILIES and icmediate connections.
Address all correspondence relating to queries to the Society, P, 0. Box
906, Murfreesboro, Tennessee 37130.
No. 1 WEBB, OWEN, DANIEL. SEAY, HAILEY: Seeking doscendanbe of Aaron
ViEBB (b. 1775, Pa.) and wife, h'^ry "Polly" OWEM, ved Rutherford
Co. Jan. 1, 1823. Children: Aeasa, Isaac Sholby (v;ed Mary Ann
SEAY 1853), Evander (wed Ifery E. DANIEL 1851), Nancy (wed VJilliara
B. HAILEY 1853), Robert, I^vid, and Lucy J. Plcnoe reply. Mro.
George F. Davis, ^752 Oak Cliff Drive._ElJ?aflo,_';H_79512,..
No. 2 FELKER, BAILEY: Susan Felker, 1830 census of Rutherford County,
with two sons ages 10-15, herself age 30-4-0, not in I84O census
of TN, in 1850 census of Oregon Co., MO in horns of covi John
Anderson FELKER who married Louisa BAILEY in Rutherford Co in
I84I (was she daughter ci' HoDjneo BAILEY?). Descendants of John
Anderson FELKER believe he married Louisa Meissncr. Rebecca
BAILEY Justice (married Justice 1840's) appears in 1850 census of
Oregon Co., MO in household of Nancy C. FELKEP. near household of
John Anderson FELKER (b. Sept. 4, 1819, Til, d. Sept. 11, 1894,
TX). Nancy (b. ca. 1817) supposedly divorced from ?
Melvin. Need any information re FELKERS and BAILEYS. Need name
of Susan FELKER 's husband, apparently deceased by 1830, or con-cerning
relatives of Susaii FELKER. Puszled as to why her daughter
(Nancy must have been Joiin Anderson's sister, cinco he held her
property in MO in his name until her second Earriaf:c in 18S5) did
not appear \/ith her in 1830 census. Need maiden nancs of Susan
FELKER or Nancy (if she was not a FELKER befora marriage) or
Ciiristian name of Nancy's first husband, Molvin being svu:'namo if
our family legends are true, MissJ^llldred J. Felker. 607_E._ Pitkin.
Pueblo. Co 81004
No. 3 TODD: TODD families descended from 5 original TODDs in Rutherford
Co. by I8O9 - compilation in progress to be published soon. Anyone
not previously contacted, please correspond. Particularly inter-ested
in parents and relation .:hip to other TODDs of William TODD
b. April 10, 1781 N. C? GA? married Madison Co., KY 1804, Jane
Douglas, and his brother Heubin TODD b, ca. 1792 GA married #1
Polly P. (Alexander?) and //2 Jcalca TODD, daughter of Aaron and
Sally TODD. Both brothers roared large facllles in Rutherford
County in the old Big Springs area. Sone say they were sons of
Mary Jane TODD, sister to oldest Benjamcn TODD to come to Ruther-ford.
ANY data greatly appreciated. Jean Douglas Van Meter,
2552 W. Stuart. Fresno. GAL 93711 .
No. 4 DOUGLASS: Desire any information abovit descendant s/parentB of
Rhodham DOUGLASS b. ca. 1775 VA, and in Rutherford Co, by 1810.
At least 2 of his sons, Bryant and Joseph were also listed in
Rutherford and Coffee Co census records. Dooire to knov; other
children and family background. Was Thomas DOUGLASS Rhodham'
s
brother? 1850 Bedford Co. census shows Rhodhnm. Jean Douglas
Van Meter. 2552 W. Stuart. Fresno. CAL 93711 .
A member of o\ir society is a genealogist: Mrs. Lalia Lester
1307 W. Morthfield Blvd.
Murfreesboro, Tenn. 37130
Tel.: (615) 896-9089
Index for Publication NOt 11
104
Adams 71
Allen 68
Allerton 78-103
Ambrose 100
Anna U
Avent 61-63-99
Baker 99
Baldwin 58-59-61-62
67
Banks 58
Barker 30
Barlow 64-66
Bamum 40
Bass 70-96-100-103
Bates 66
Batey 99
Beasley 78096-103
Becker 99
Bedford 10
Beer 29
Bell 86-96-98
Beesley 6
Benjamin 2
Benton 8
Blumenthal 99
Bock 66
Bostic 68
Bowles 58
Boyd 33
Brigance 30
Briney 91
Brown 28
Bryant 31
Buchanan 23
Burleson 28
Burton 58
Butler 98-99
Buttorff 100
^ym 99
Cannon 66-99
Callender 60-67-68
Campbell 60-61-99
Carney 61-70
Carter 31
Cason 98
Childress 6-66
Christy 98
Clark 103
Clay 63
Clayton 99
Coffee 8
Cohn 99
Coldwell 31
Collier 73-91
Cooper 64
Cornwallls 31
Covington 99
Cowen 31
Cox 68
Craig 71
Creech 96
Crlchlow 98-99
Crockett 7-11-12
Cross 66
Currell 99
Cxirtlss 26-27
Dann 86
Davidson 31
Davis 25-26-30-31
33
Deason 71
Dickson 31
Dixon 71
Draper 99
Dmmgoole 64
Earthman 98
Easten 71
Eaton 69
El kins 34
Earp 21
Eton 71
Falroloth 9&gt;94-95-96
103
Farrls 99
Flnley 58-60-61-62
63-64-67
Fleming 99-100
Flemmlng 100
Fletcher 66
Ford 34-35-66-99
Fowler 34
Freeman 90-96-103
Frost 91
Fry 74
Gallhralth 74
Gallor 92
105
Gamevell 56
GflniMuay 99
Gates 31
Gerhardt 99
Gill 6^
Qlltner 61
Glascock 74^84
Cobal 86
Goldstein 99
Good 98
Goodall 76
Goodrich 72
Govaa 78
Graves 73
Green 32
Gregg 28
Guan 30
Hackman 98
Hall 66
Hamen U
Easspton 32
Hancock 98
Han^ 90-103
Hnrdeman 30
Harlow 78
Harrell 93-96
Hartje 30
Hatcher 74
Hajnes 96-99
Ho^hill 28
Henderson 6-70-73-103
Hendrick 43-52
Henry 90
Hickock 28
Hoffman 64^86-93
Hollovray 66
Hooper 2-99
Hoover 68-91-96
Hopkins 60-61-8V86
87-92-93-94
Horton 66
Houston 12-13-14^18
24-100
Hudson 98-99
Haggins 61-98
Hughes 74
Hunt 98 ^e 60-84^86-87
93-94^96
Jackson 7
Johnson 30-100
Johnston 7
Jones 66-74-98
Keeble 8-69-70
Eelton 93-96
Kmdflll 17
Kerr 99
Klmbro 66
King 99
Knapp 64
Knox 99
Lea 70
Leatherman 98
Ledbetter 33-66
Lee 7-70
Leiper 103
Lenoir 8-11
Licker 90-103
Lindsey 99
Littler 99
Uvely 99
Locke 31
Logan 98-99
Longstreet 7
Lorance 31-33-34-35
Lowe 90
lyon 25-60-61
lytle 61-66-99
Madden 58
t^lone 30-64
Maney 99-100
Hanson 99
Mankin 36-42-50
Martin 73-76-77-78
79-80-81-82
84
Matthews 99
Maxwell 90-103
McArthtu: 103
McCulloch 7-8-10-11-12
13-14-15-16-17
18-19-21-22-23
24-25-26-27-28
29-30
McFadden 61-74
McParlin 90-92-103
MoFerrin 66-75
McGharen 91
McEinney 21
McLeod 28
McQuiddy 86
Headers 64
Mikell 93
Miles 99
Miller 99
Mitchell 8-31
106
Money 58
Moody- 62-63
Moore 32-60-61-66
69-70-71-98
Morgan 31_66-92
Morton 99
Muirhead 96
MulUns 96
Murfree 58-66
Naff 68
Naylor 99
Northcut 32
Nellson 66
Ordway BU
Otis 30
Overall 32-33-37-60
84^86-91-99
Parish 8
Parker 61
Parrish 100
Patience 96
Paty 73
Pea 66
Peabody 71
Pelican 27
Perkins 99
Phillips 28-100
Pierce 8-22-23
Pittard 7
Pltuner 69
Polk 6
Pollock 80
Powell 23
Prentice 94
Preston 50
Price 25-26
Quarles 86
Ragland 99
Ramsey 93-96
Handle 61-62
Ransom 52-69-71-99
Rather 99
Ray 1
Raymond 64
Read 31
Ready 66
Reid 30
Richardson 61-90-98
Ridley 98
Riggleman 94
Riggs 92-93-96-103
Rion 90
Robertson 60
Rolle 30
Rose 30
Ross 66
Rucker 58-99
Rutherford 32
Sawrie 66
Scott 24
SchiiTT-icher 86-93
Searcey 80
Shief 100
Simn 61-77-103
Sloan 58-103
Smith 66-74-9&gt;98
99
Sndther 30
Smotherman 103
Snead 60-73-74^-76
77-78-80-81
83-84
Soule 58-59
Spain 98-99
Sparks 98
Speer 30-74
Spence 60-61-63
Spiller 30
Spindle 81
Spindell 80
Stelnhagen 69
Stuart 7
Starr 30-100
Strnhn 74
Street 78-80
Stillivan 33
Surnmor 68
Suimerhill 63
Suii5)ter 32
Swan 72
Sweitzer 15
Tarlton 31
Tarrant 8
Tate 98
TatTim 98-99
Taylor 16-76
ThoETjEon 32-64-70-71
72-73-86-91
Todd 86-98
To! inn 75
Tonpkins 99
Totty 32
Tucker 32
107
Turner 99
Tvdggs 18-24
Van Dom 26-27
Vickers 9&gt;99
Wade 61
Walker 36
Ware 74
Wardlau 73-74-75-76
77-78_79_80
81-82-83-84
91
Warner 30
WatHns 61
Watts 99
Weathereby 91
Weakley 10
Webb 17-30
Wendal 61
West 60-71
Wharton
WhltnVer 86
Williams 99
Wllliford 32-33
White 32
Wolf 64
Woodfin 98
Woods 66-96
Wray 30
Young 23
Zlerold 78-103
DATE DUE
iJ.y^ 9^
'
OE 1 &#176; '^^
H t
Jfl 1 4 %t
Jiu^
\,l^2?'^
Alkl3JSL
&#8212;MAPv 8 qqq -M^
.
/ DEMCO 38-297 &#8226;
Call Number
T
976.857
R95lp
~ v.ll
79-05209
Rutherford County^ Higt. . Society
TT^
'
^' Vi
LIBRARY
MIDDLE TENNESSEE STATE UNIVERSITY
MURFREESBORO, TENNESSEE
M T S U LIBRARY
3 3082 00527 4971
SEP '-i 7 MO^CT 4 20(|6 M I n 71
&#187;03
^ffe- 4.^^
DATE DUE
- )4,
T^i^ R
DEC 1 1 porn
U-^</dc:description>
<dc:description>This volume contains several articles, each of which is treated separately in this collection and can be searched individually</dc:description>
<dc:description>The State Capitol 1819-1826 -- From Jefferson to Elkhorn Tavern: The Story of Ben McCulloch -- Petition of Michael Lorance, Revolutionary Soldier -- A Country Store (1912-1914) -- Soule College</dc:description>
<dc:subject>McCullock, Ben, 1811-1862; Rutherford County (Tenn.); Soule, Joshua, 1781-1867; United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1783; Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Family Histories; Building Histories; Girls' Schools; Soule College</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Periodical</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>242 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-24</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication11ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/93</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>