<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>My family</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Rion, Fount Henry</dc:creator>
<dc:relation>Rutherford County Historical Society Publication No. 18</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:publisher>Murfreesboro, TN</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1982</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>17th century; 18th century; 19th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:description>24
MY FAMILY
FOUNT HENRY RION
1958
25
-1-
Thomas Osborn, settled in Virginia 1616, was
Justice in 1631 and Member House of Burgess
in 1639.
-2-
-3-
Thomas Osborn
Martha
-U-John
Osborn
Ann
-5-
Thomas Osborn
Jane Patterson
-6-
Caleb Osborn
Susannah Jewell
1751
1762
-1799
- 1803
-7-
Johnathan Osborn
Hannah Spinning
1793
1793
- 1877
-1863
-8-
Harve7 Osborn
Ann C. Reed
1815
1817
-1886
-1863
-9-
Sallie E. Osborn
Fountain J. Henry
I82i0
I836
- 1916
- 1871
-10-
Nettie E. Henry
Winiam J. Rlrtn
i860
1857
-19U5
- 1887
-11-
Ellen Ann Rion
Robert Caldwell
1880
187U
-1961*
-1931
-12-
EUen Rion Caldwell
James Lawson Fleming
1906
Amanda Caldwell 1911
Sarah Caldwell
Walter Greene
1916
PREFACE
All of my life I have felt a desire to know more about ray family
connections but have done little to really satisfy that desire which
seems to have been rather deep rooted even when I was a child.
I have pleasant and satisfying memories which date back to that
period, for then a great many of the older generation were still living
and told me of interesting things that happened in that long ago. Most
vivid of these memories were the talks with my grandma Henry.
Then, a cousin, Howard E. Ronk was traveling around the country
visiting and interviewing members of the Osborn family, about whom he was
writing a history. These and many others with whom I had the privilege
of talking, gave me much interesting information.
My father having died when I was only three and one half years old,
and all of his family connections except Uncle Ed Rion, still living out
in the country, I had little or no opportunity to know them or to be
associated with them. This, of course, gave me a greater desire to know
more about them.
I visited in Murfreesboro every summer during my childhood and had
association with the Henrys, the Osborns, the Reeds and others, but the
Rions and Jones lived out at Lascassas and Hall's Hill and these were twelve
to fifteen miles away and in those days of only horse and buggy travel,
made it impossible for me.
Not until the summer of 1901* was I able to satisfy this desire, but
during that summer, mother and I made a visit to Aunt Fanny Rion Phillip's
and her family, who were then living out beyond Lascassas.
In addition to the most interesting conversations with Aunt Fanny who
had lived in that country all of her life, and other interesting facts
27
brought out by my mother, who wont out there to live after she married,
-
we took an all day long buggy ride through all that country,- over to the
old original Francis P. Rion home, built between 1825 and 1830 near fell's
HL11, and the old original Jones home across the road, built about 1796.
The trip in 190k was difficult as there were only crude roads including
these portions of road which ran through and along creek beds, all of which
emphasized in my mind how difficult travel was in those days of a hundred
years previous when our pioneer ancestors sought these new homes. No roads,
not even trails. Travel possible only following rivers or smaller streams
and often they found it necessary to axe out a new trail through the un-touched
wilderness.
Still living in the old Jones house at the time of our visit in 1901*
were some of the descendants of the Enoch Jones family who received us
graciously and treated us royally. They told me Interesting stories about
the old house, the barns, slave quarters and the country around about, tales
which had been handed down during the previous hundred years.
Nearby was the house in which my father was born and it was a thrill
to be there and to see and drink from the wonderful old spring at the foot
of the hill where, Aunt Fanny told us, papa used to go to get water for
the family.
We also visited the Will Jones place. Uncle Will Jones was a brother
of my father's mother,- and while I have no positive information on this,
I feel very sure that my father, William, was named for his Uncle Will Jones.
I enjoyed talking with these wonderful people. I am sure I am correct in
my impression that Uncle Will and Aunt Veenie Jones were the favorites of
both papa and mother, of all their family connections.
Then one of the most interesting events on that day's trip was a
23
visit to the old Enoch Jones cemetery. This was beautiful and the most
pretentious private, country cemetery I had ever seen. It was surrounded
by a substantial stone wall, capped with wide smooth stones and gates of
wrought iron. The masonry was as fine a job as I have ever seen anywhere.
The dominant feature was a tall white marble shaft to the memory of
Enoch Hunt Jones, my great-grandfather. My grandmother, Nancy Jones Rion,
was buried near her father and her grave marked with a simple slab. Many
other family graves were well marked and contained much family history.
Back in Murfreesboro on this same trip, I visited Uncle Wash Henry
and there talked Henry family with him.
During all this I made many notes, had received many pictures and
other keepsakes, - but in 1925 when the house at Brentwood burned, all
those things were lost.
Then for the thirty or more years intervening, I have been much, much
too busy to give more than fleeting thoughts to this matter of family
connections, however, the impelling thought that I should do something
about it, had recently been quickened by the realization that I had an
obligation to my children and grandchildren who have had little or no
opportunity to know anything about their ancestral family. I was deter-mined
to do something about it, so with the hope that some may have an
interest in such things, I have, using the information I already had as
a basis, made considerable research and investigation and have attempted
to compile, and in the pages which follow, to record some of these findings.
Realizing that exactly the same lineage applies to my sister's children,
I am taking the liberty of having sufficient copies prepared so that each
of her three daughters may have one.
Several years ago, I wrote a "Family History" to be included in my
29
book for my children "You Asked For It." I now find that some of the
latest data I have secured does not always coincide with that previously-written.
This is understandable when we consider some of the facts I
have been trying to uncover date back in some instances to more than two
hundred years.
I will not go back and make any changes in that previous story for
that is very different in character from this one as the previous one
contains copies of many personal letters.
In this story, I have tried, in so far as resources permit, to
identify as many as possible of our ancestors who served in the American
Continental Army during the Revolutionary War. These identified by records
are:
Will jam Rion Army of Maryland
Lt. Thomas Gayle Army of Virginia
Ezekiel Jones Army of Virginia
George Henry Army of Virginia
Ambrose Jeffries Army of Virginia
Col. Peter Dudley Army of Virginia
William Williams Army of Virginia
Caleb Osborn Army of New Jersey
Any historian, biographer or genealogist must, of necessity, rely
upon piecing together bits of information, often very &#171;nu&#187;n hits, in
creating the story, and especially in my case (such an amateur) there is
always a chance that some Inaccuracies may creep in.
It is ray sincere hope that those who read this may have a greater
esteem and appreciation for those who have gone on before us, and have
laid the foundations for an America which is great and as a result of
their pioneer labors and great sacrifice, we now live our lives more
abundantly.
I want to acknowledge with sincere appreciation, ray indebtedness to
all sources of help and inspiration that I have received in preparing this:
INDIVIDUALS
Ruth White Cook, Murfreesboro, Tennessee
(Daughter of Ora Rlon White)
Nannie Phillips Gray, Fountain City, Tennessee
(Daughter of Fanny Rion Phillips)
Hilda Jones Dunn, Washington, D. C.
(Daughter of Will Macklin Jones)
Lucie M. Browning, Culpepper, Virginia
(Researcher)
Howard E. Ronk - (Deceased)
(Historian of Osborn family)
ORGANIZATIONS
The Library of Congress
Washington, D. C.
National Archives and Research Service
Washington, D. C.
Tennessee State Library and Archives
Nashville, Tennessee
Virginia Historical Society
Richmond, Virginia
PUBLICATIONS
"The Culpeper Minute Men" Slaughter
"Historical Register of Virginians
in the Revolution" Qwathmey
"Genealogies" (Mostly Virginian) C. Marriott
31
RION
In colonial Virginia, there were many French people. They had left
their own land, some secretly In small ships and many driven out by
religious persecution. They were Protestants (called Huguenots).
During the 16th and 17th centuries the contest between the Catholic
party and the Protestant (Huguenot) party in France was bitter. The con-test
was as much political as religious.
After bloody struggles the Protestants fled to their fortified towns
and carried on the war with varying success.
In 1593, the Huguenots had secured their civil rights, and the right
to free exercise of their religion. They were also given equal claims
with the Catholics to all offices and dignities. They were also afforded
the means of forming a kind of Republic within the Kingdom, which Richelieu
regarded as a serious obstacle to the growth of the Royal power, hence, he
resolved to crush it.
The war raged from l62ii to 1629 when LaRochelle, the principal fort-ress
of the Huguenots, fell before the Royal troops.
Persecution continued under King Louis XIV.
In 1685, about 50,000 Protestants were driven out of France to other
countries. While many were driven out, many left by choice.
In the year 1700, seven hundred French settlers came to Virginia. The
shores of this region were not unknown to the Huguenots. The mild climate
attracted them and they gladly sought refuge there among the English.
It was with this background, and in the midst of this political and
religious intrigue that the first RION of which we have any record, came
to America.
32
And, in the midst of that bloody struggle in France, stood the
town of RION
.
While so many leaders on both sides, alike, were vising the bitter
spirit of religious controversy for their personal advantage, the RICH
family (or clan) was busy trying to keep peace and order so as to hold
their town intact.
The RION clan, prominent in France at that time, owned lands with
castles built on the estates. They served as Huguenots in these religious
wars until they were forced to leave France.
The RIONS were in America before 1725, as shown on the military
enlistment of WILLIAM RION, Sr. who was born in Maryland in 1750, later
moving to Charlotte County, Virginia where he died.
WILLIAM JAMES RION , my father, was born on May 23, 1857 near Halls
Hill in Rutherford County, Tennessee. He was the son of Thomas D. Rion
and Nancy Ann (Nannie) Jones.
He grew up on the farm where he was born and later the family moved
over near Lascassas where he worked with his father in the business of buying,
selling and trading livestock. They would buy up large numbers of horses,
mules, cows, sheep, hogs and when the Nashville market was right, they
would drive the herd or flock through the country from Murfreesboro to the
stock yards in Nashville, requiring two to three days to make the trip of
thirty-two miles. That was before the railroad began hauling livestock in
freight cars.
On December 17, 1879 he and ray mother, Nettie Ellen Henry, were
married in the Cumberland Presbyterian Church in Murfreesboro, with the Rev.
J. H. Warren officiating. It was a big wedding, with six attendants, all
33
cousins of the bride, with one exception. The groomsmen were Charles S.
Hendrix, William F. Henry, Charles W. Henry and the bridesmaids were
Lillie B. Elliott, Maggie E. Hendrix and Maggie Ralston. The two Henry
boys were sons of Uncle Wash Henry of Murfreesboro, while Charles E,
Hendrix and his sister Maggie E. Hendrix were the son and daughter of
Uncle "Billy" and Aunt Jane Reed Hendrix, then of McKenzie, Tennessee,
-
lillie B. Elliott, a first cousin, daughter of Aunt Nannie Henry Elliott,
and Maggie Ralston was a school chum at Soule College in Murfreesboro,
and no relation. These six attendants all signed the wedding certificate,
as official witnesses.
In a letter from Maggie Hendrix, some three weeks after the wedding,
she speaks of her "new cousin Willie" In most complimentary terms.
Evidently mother had sent her one of the wedding pictures of herself and
papa, for Maggie writes:
Your note containing the picture, was received
yesterday. Many thanks. All pronounce Cousin
Willie a handsome young man and highly compliment
the good taste you displayed in the selection of
such a man as his photo indicates and as I know
him to be. All extend to you their hearty con-gratulations
for a bright, a happy and useful
life in the future."
"It is needless for me to tell you that I fell
very much in love with Cousin Willie, for you
already know that. I was so very anxious to remain
longer and spend a few days with you in your new
home, out on the banks of that lovely little
Middle Tennessee stream."
Papa had first met my mother at a party, and it was "love at first
sight." That night she was wearing a dress trimmed in a ball fringe. After
the party, she missed one of the little balls and couldn't find it, but
after their wedding she discovered that papa had it in his wallet. He had
secretly cut it off at the party and had carried it ever since. (NOTE: I
now have the wallet and the ball).
34
Although "love at first sight" there was much to be considered in
this proposed marriage. Evidently young William was a very handsome and
highly worthy young man. He was six feet, one inch tall, in his sock feet
and weighed 175 pounds and was of a very lovable personality. But, his
only life had been that of a country boy and his young bride of nineteen
would have to share that kind of life, although she had never known any-thing
of that kind.
All investigations as to character, fitness, background, etc. seems
to have worked out very satisfactorily, for the wedding did take place and
they were settled in that - "new home, out on the banks of that lovely
little Middle Tennessee stream." (NOTE: I visited this place in 190U and
again recently - in 1958)
But life in this new home became anything but satisfactory to either
of them. In the meanwhile Uncle Tommy Henry had gone to Nashville and had
secured a very satisfactory job. Papa sought to follow him and also make
a try for a job in the city.
On November 2k&#187; 1880 the first baby was born, - my sister. Mother had
gone into town in Murfreesboro so she could be with her mother for this
occasion. She never returned to the country to live.
Under date of February 25, 1881, papa wrote mother from Nashville
on the stationery of "BAIRD &amp; JAMESON", "Staple and Fancy Groceries", 139
Church Street, stating he had secured a job there which was very satisfactory.
In the meanwhile, Grandma had moved to Nashville to make a home for
Uncle Tommy (her son) and papa went to live with them so mother and the baby
could follow soon.
I now have among my keepsakes, some stationery which indicates papa
was making a try at business for himself. The heading is as follows:
35
W. J. RION
CONFECTIONERY
FOREIGN AND DOMESTIC FRUITS
309 CHDRCH STREET
NASHVILLE, TENNESSEE
At another time he was employed by Mr. Charles Mitchell in the same
kind of business.
But his life was to be a short one. After a spell of pneumonia in
the winter of 1885-86, he contracted "consumption" (now known as tubercu-losis)
and on April 2, 1887, shortly before bis thirtieth birthday, he
passed on to his "great reward."
Although I do remember certain instances and circumstances which
occurred toward the end of his life, it has been a very great satisfaction
to me to have heard, all my life, from people who knew him well, only the
highest praise for his life and character,-his lovable disposition, his
thoughtfulness for the welfare and happiness of others and his devotion to
his wife and children and to Grandma Henry, who lived with us.
(NOTE: Nancy Ann Jones, his mother and her family will
be outlined in a separate section,- JONES . )
THOMAS D . RION . my grandfather, was born near Halls Hill, Rutherford
County, Tennessee, on April 8, 1831, the oldest son of FRANCIS P. RION
and wife NANCY GAYLE BLACKSTOCK.
Thomas D. RLon was married to Nancy Ann Jones on January 5, 185U.
They had three children, my father William James Rion, Edwin Thomas Rion
and Fanny Rion who married Ed Phillips.
Thomas D. Rion spent his entire life on the farm and in associated
activities such as buying, selling and trading in livestock.
36
During the War Between the States he served In the "conscript
Cavalry of Tennessee. Volunteering seemed to be failing to produce
sufficient recruits in the Confederate Army and grandpa Rion was assigned
to this duty of Conscription of recruits.
He died in Murfreesboro, Tennessee on September 26, I898. I re-member
him well. I would see him in Murfreesboro when I would be visiting
there and he happened to come into town. Grandma Rion, his wife had died
several years previously - on June 15* 1877. He had been a widower some
twenty-one years.
FRANCIS P. RION . usually called Frank, was my great-grandfather. He
was the son of William Rion, Sr. and wife Gilley (surname unknown).
Francis P. Rion was born in Virginia in 1805 and was married on January
17, 1825, in Charlotte C. H., Virginia to Nancy Ann Gayle, widow of David
Blackstock.
Francis had left home at an early age and evidently was employed on
the large plantation of the widow Blackstock which she had inherited on
the death of her husband David Blackstock. When Francis married Nancy
Ann,-he was "Bound Over" to her under Bond. I have not been able to find
the exact meaning of this term "Bound Over", but in this connection it was
an official, legal document requiring a bondsman who was his brother,
Joseph D. Rion. Being dated the same day as their marriage, indicates it
had to do with that as witnessed as follows:
"KNOW ALL MEN BY THESE PRESENTS:- that we,
Francis Rion and Joseph D. Rion are held and
firmly bound unto James Pleasants, Jr.
Governor of the Commonwealth of Virginia, in
the just and full sum of One Hundred and Fifty
Dollars, to the use of the Commonwealth, to the
37
payment whereof, well and truly to be made, we
bond ourselves, our heirs and jointly and
severally, firmly by these presents.
Sealed with our seals and dated this 17th day of
January 1825. M
THE CONDITION OF THE ABOVE OBLIGATION IS SUCH:-
"That, whereas, a marriage is to be solemnized
between the above bound Francis Rion and
Ann Blackstock, widow of David KLackstock, of
this County; now, if there be no lawful cause
to obstruct the same, then the above obligation
to be void, otherwise to remain in full force
and virtue."
FRANCIS RION (SEAL)
JOSEPH D. RION (SEAL)
H. B. CHERMSIDE, CLERK
CIRCUIT COURT, CHARLOTTE COUNTY
VIRGINIA
Nancy Ara^s father, Thomas Gayle had died just the year before,
(18210 and she turned to Francis, nineteen years her junior, for comfort
and solace.
In the Fall of 1825, the "Migration South" had started. The Virginia
holdings having been disposed of, they came South, through North Carolina
to Tennessee.
The emigration party was composed of Nancy Blackstock 1 s sisters and
their husbands, and other Rions.
Michael Rion stopped in North Carolina while some of his family moved
on to South Carolina where there is today a town by the name of RION.
William Rion, Jr., moved on to Kentucky.
This huge party of kinfolks brought their livestock and a few family
possessions with them to Rutherford County, Tennessee.
Just when they arrived is not known, but the first land purchase was
made by Francis P. Rion (our ancestor) in 1830. It was on the East fork of
Stones River near Halls Hill.
3*
Francis P. Rion, born in Virginia in 1805, died In Rutherford County,
Tennessee in 1878, buried in Floyd Cemetery north of Halls Hill, east of
and across the road from the Enoch Jones Cemetery. Here also lies his
wife, Nancy Gayle Blackstock, born 1787 In Gloucester County, Virginia and
died In Rutherford County, Tennessee in 1875
&#8226;
Francis P. Rion and Nancy Gayle Blackstock* s home was built of logs,
a two story structure among the beautiful cedars and the huge rocks on
the banks of Stones River. (NOTE: I visited this home in its original
condition, in 1&#176;0U,- and again in 1939 after it had been remodeled,- then
again in 1958 when I found a complete remodeling had taken place.)
Originally it was a commodious two story house, built of cedar lags
and sealed inside with wide poplar boards all hand made. The design and
workmanship of the original interior showed a finesse very unusual for
those pioneer times.
The doors, I thought so unusual, I copied them exactly for my present
home.
Also, I have in my rock garden, stones from the creek running through
the front lot of this place - and one from the original stone chimney which
was being torn down.
In one of the real estate transfers recorded, Francis P. Rion sold to
Thomas D. (my grandfather) and J. R. Rion (his brother) land bounded by
Stones River and by Stroops land near Halls Hill. Transaction made 1859
as recorded in Rutherford County Court records.
This tract of land sold to his two sons, adjoined the original place.
A large log house was on this land also. I visited this house in 190U
but when I returned in 1939 it had burned down. This house was the birth-place
of my father, so I secured rocks for my garden from the stone found-
39
atlon and a piece of the hearthstone.
From his sons, passed on down through their children, we have a
description of our ancestor, Francis P. Rion. This described him as a
typical "Virginia Gentleman Planter" and was a striking figure riding
over the plantation on his fine mares, carrying his gold headed walking
cane and wearing buckskin gloves. He was always well dressed. Bee-gum
hat, clothes of fine material and shining boots. On his hip hung his
revolver (a necessity in those pioneer days) but this was not in view,
as he was never seen coatless in public. His shirt was ruffled up the
front and he wore a "Shoo-fly tie" more commonly known as "Windsor."
Francis P. Rion had a large frame, weighing one hundred seventy-five
pounds. He was very active all his life, but became "despondent, quarrel-some
and contrary" after he lost all his property during the "War Between
the States."
He bought and sold cattle, driving them to market in Nashville and
sometimes along the Natchez Trace to Natchez or New Orleans. He used
his sons as helpers, perhaps beginning the tradition followed by my grand-father
who in turn had my father helping him.
THOMAS GAYLE ; - father of our great-grandmother, Nancy Ann Gayle
Blackstock, was born in England, April 17, 1750 - died May 2k, 182U. He
was married in 1770 to Mary Goode. They had seven children, the sixth
being Nancy Ann, born in 1700.
It is not known just when Thomas Gayle first came to America, but we
do have the record that he did serve as a Lieutenant in the American
Continental Army during the Revolutionary War.
40
Filed in the Court of Charlotte County, Virginia on the 5th day of
July I82I4, was a very elaborate and extensive will, indicating he was a
man of wealth and prestige.
WILLIAM RION, Sr., the first Rion of whom we have any direct record,
was born in Maryland in 1750. This fact has been established from the
record of his enlistment in the American Continental Array. This record is
as follows:
"A list of young men enrolled by
Captain James Young, Lt. James Bond,
Lt. John Smith and Ensign James Tool to
compose one company in the "Flying Camp"
August 1776."
William Rion enlisted in Baltimore, Mary-land
Company, July 5, 1776, age 26, -
5 ft. 7h inches tall, black hair, fair
complexion, weight 175 lbs. Born in
Maryland 1750."
His wife was GILLEY - - - - RION. Her surname is not mentioned in
any of the records. She is referred to in his will as "my wife Gilley
Rion. u
Sometime after the Revolutionary War was over, he moved to Charlotte
County, Virginia, where he died in 1813.
William Sr. and Gilley Rion had five children, the second of which was
our great-grandfather, Francis P. Rion.
William Rion, Sr. lived a long and useful life during those rough
pioneer days. While we do not have the exact records, he was, undoubtedly,
the son or grandson of one of the Huguenots who came to America during the
early 1700' s.
His body was laid to rest in a cemetery at Charlotte Court House,
Virginia, in I813.
41
Revolutionary Soldier, - plain citizen, - one of many pioneers,
suffering hardships, working toward a free AMERICA which they could pass
on down to their children, - US - that we may enjoy the benefit of their
labor.
It is interesting to note in "Historical Register of Virginians in
the Revolution" by Gvathmey, that four (U) RION men are listed as serving
from Virginia. These are: JOHN RION who served in the 8th Virginia
Regiment, Continental Line; EDWARD RION (sometimes spelled Ryon) served
with the 3rd and Uth Virginia Regiments, Continental Line} ANDREW RION
and LASURIS RION are listed but for thier service records, only the War
Department is given for reference.
I cannot place just where, if anywhere, these four men fit into our
family connection, but I feel it is safe to assume there was a family
connection and that these or their immediate forebears were among those
migrating from France with the Huguenots. In France they were one family -
one "clan." Most of them migrated to Virginia.
The military enlistment record of our direct ancestor William Rion,
shows he was born in Maryland and later moved to Virginia. No records
have been found to give the names of William Rion's forebears.
42
HERALDIC DESCRIPTION OF RION
ARMS - Gules, three lions' heads or.
CREST - A griffln&#187;s head or.
Heraldry is defined as the art or science of blazoning or
describing in appropriate technical terms coats of arms and other
heraldic and armorial insignia. The system is of very ancient origin.
In its modern sense, however, the heraldic art dates from the time
of the Crusades, and was reduced to its present perfect system by the
French; and it was not until that period that the crest or cognizance was
generally adopted. The crest is a device worn on top of the shield,
usually placed on a wreath, and was borne by knights and other personages
of rank, when clad in armor, to distinguish them in battle, and as a mark
for their followers and supporters. At first these badges were worn on
the helmet, to render them more plainly visible, or on the arm, but in
later times were transferred to the shield or armor. Many families have
preserved their mottoes, or watch-words, which usually represent some
characteristic of the family, or sometimes the war cry of the clan. Others
never adopted a motto, just as many never adopted a crest.
An erroneous idea is entertained by some that heraldic symbols denote
an aristocratic or exclusive class and is undemocratic in its origin and
permanency. On the contray, these badges of distinction were the reward
of personal merit, and could be secured by the humblest as well as the
highest. They are today the testimonials and warrants of bravery, heroism,
and meritorious deeds of our ancestors; and they appeal to the pride of the
intelligent and enlightened descendants of these distinguished families today,
as the valiant deeds and self-sacrificing acts of contemporary persons
would to their posterity.
43
JONES
When, on January 5, l8$U&gt; my grandfather Thomas D. Rion was married
to Nancy Ann Jones, this family of her father, Enoch Hunt Jones, became
a very vital connection which has, all along, been much appreciated and
respected by me.
For some reason I cannot fully explain, this branch of our family
has always held a particular interest and fascination for my imagination.
Perhaps it is on account of the memorable visit I made in 190li to the old
original Jones homestead in Rutherford County, Tennessee. Although 108
years had elapsed at that time, since the house had been built, there were
still living in the old home place, certain of the descendants of the Jones
family, whose names I cannot remember, who seemed quite familiar with old
family history as well as the material history of the old homestead.
I recall that they told me that the house was built about 1796, and
this ties in very well with the date of the marriage of Ezra Jones and
Margaret Runt, March 15, 1796.
This was a wonderful old two story house, built of sturdy cedar logs,
especially good workmanship for those pioneer days, when usually the tools
were crude and cumbersome, consisting mostly of a chopping axe, a foot-adz,
a saw, an auger and a frow for splitting boards. These, with a hoe, a plow
point, some seeds of grain and vegetables for their first crop were the
prime necessities for a pioneering venture.
I was shown how the original house looked before the logs were
weather-boarded on the outside with wide poplar boards and painted white.
The house was "L" shaped with a wide, spacious veranda across the
front and another wide porch inside the "L". Just a short distance from
44
this side porch, stood a most magnificent old white oak tree. It's
branches extended over a diameter of more than a hundred feet. It was
quits evident that this particular site was selected for building the
house, due to the presence of that grand tree. There were a number of
fine trees of oak, poplar, cedar and beech in the grove, but this massive
oak was outstanding.
I was shown the old kitchen, much in its original form,- little
changed from the days when all the cooking was done in the old fire place
with its smoldering embers,- the large pot, swung from the crane, the
dutchoven for baking, -these with a skillet, a frying pan and a wooden
tray in which to mix meal for bread,- a pair of pot hooks and if they
could afford it, a hand mill with which to grind corn.
I was shown the old log barns and other service houses (much in the
old Virginia tradition) still in use at that time but showing their 108
years of hard use. Some of the old "slave quarters" were still standing.
As I walked about these surroundings I could not escape wondering
with my imagination, back into those rough pioneer days with these
ancestors, trying to picture in my own mind what it was like back there,
settling in this new country the very year that the State of Tennessee was
admitted to the Union, &#171;-no roads, hardly a trail, Indians continuing hostile,
few if any neighbors, no stores from which to buy necessities. Everyone
must be self-sustaining, self-reliant.
Hunting and fishing, with wild greens, berries and fruits helped in
Summer and Fall, while hogs, if they were fortunate to have brought along
a few, were feasting upon the abundance of acorns, beech and hickory nuts
getting fat for that long looked-for day when it would be cold enough for
"hog killing."
45
Within a few years when the country was a little more populated
the homesteaders were served by pack-peddlers, walking through the
country, from house to house with dress goods, linens, etc., then the
traveling shoemaker, who would stay in the home until he had made shoes
for every member of the family, and then go from house to house serving
all alike.
Skins from cattle, deer and groundhogs were all tanned in the same
trough, for leather for the shoes, harness etc.
On the wide planked floors of the house were beautiful, homespun
hooked rugs, hand made from cloth scraps. The beds were immaculate in
home woven coverlets, all seeming to me to be much as it was in those
early days.
I was shown picture albums as well as other pictures and treasures
and on the table, the family Bible. Almost everyone of the old pioneers
carried with them as the one indispensible treasure, a Bible, as they
were mostly religious folk, and in this they kept their family records. If
the Biblical names of our three Jones ancestors, Ezekiel, Ezra, and Enoch
have any significance, this must have been true with them,
Another most interesting feature they pointed out to me, was a stile
or "horse block" built of rock, which they said Grandpa Ezra Jones had
built for his bride, so she could easily mount her favorite saddle horse
which he had given her for a wedding present. Later, (on my 1939 visit)
the people then living on the place, gave me one of the stones from this
stile and it is now a part of my rock garden at my Florida home.
NOTE: For the benefit of the younger generations who have
never seen one, perhaps we should explain that a
STILE is a short series of steps intended to be used
in crossing over a fence without opening gates, and
46
in cases such as this one, where a lady could mount
her saddle horse easily without having to pull up.
The ladles of that day always wore long skirts, even
in horse-back riding, and they always rode "side-saddle."
It would have been disgraceful to have
permitted her ankles to show, to say nothing of
riding straddle a horse. This particular stile
(or horse block) was built of field stones, with
five or six small steps leading up to the large
cap-stone about three feet off the ground.
The earliest of our Jones ancestors of which we have any record, was
Ezekiel Jones, who lived in Virginia, and is recorded in the "Historical
Register of Virginians in the Revolution ", as having served in the 13th
Virginia Regiment,-Continental Line. No further information is available,
His son Ezra Jones was born on February 3&gt; 1772 and on March 15, 1796
was married to Margaret Hunt, daughter of Enoch Hunt.
The records show that Ezra Jones moved to "North Carolina" with no
record of his moving to "Tennessee']. It is interesting here that this
seeming discrepancy can perhaps be easily explained by the fact that there
was no State of Tennessee prior to 1796, as it was not until that year that
Tennessee was admitted to the Union, hence, it can be assumed that he could
have moved directly to that spot in Rutherford County, for then "North
Carolina" included all territory from the Atlantic Ocean to the Mississippi
River, the same territory as now embraced by both States of Tennesse and
North Carolina.
On May 11, 1798, Ezra and Margaret Jones were presented with their
first-born, a son whom they named Enoch Hunt Jones, who was to carry on the
tradition of the pioneer spirit and to later serve his country in War and
Peace.
47
Ezra Jones laid a wonderful foundation for those who were to follow
him, and his son, Enoch Hunt Jones, (my great-grandfather) not only carries
on, but added Stature and Dignity to life around him.
Excellent testimony to this fact is the existence of the Jones family
Cemetery, which, when I first saw it in 190h and later in 1939, was in
excellent condition. It covered a piece of land, maybe a quarter of an
acre. It is surrounded by a beautifully constructed stone wall about
two feet thick and three to three and one-half feet tall, built of care-fully
selected field stones and capped with wide smoothly hewn stones.
The masonry had every evidence of skilled craftsmanship of a later period,
indicating that it was created in Enoch Jones time, rather than an earlier
period. The entrance was guarded by carefully locked, wrought iron gates
of artistic design, all a fitting tribute to the memory of loved ones.
The grave-stones inside were mute evidence that "someone cared."
The stones ranged in size and pretense from modest small to medium sized
slab markers to the larger and more pretentious, the whole, dominated by a
tall gleaming white shaft, in the center, to the memory of Enoch Hunt Jones.
All the stones are plainly marked and most of them bear considerable inform-ative
family history, making the task of a would-be genealogist (such as me)
much easier.
Such strong evidence of family solidarity and stability is rarely
found in Rural America.
NANCY ANN JONES: Daughter of Enoch Hunt Jones and Eunice Macklin
(McLinn) Jones, was born September 6, I83U and was married to Thomas D. Rion
(my grandfather) on January $, 18&amp;. She was the mother of three children,
William James Rion (my father) the oldest,-Edwin Thomas Rion and Fanny Rion.
43
Grandma Rion died June 15, 1877 at the age of forty-three years.
I have been told she was a frail little person, but bravely, and too
much so, tried to carry on her household duties raising a family and
administering to their needs. When she died, Papa was only twenty years
old, - Uncle Ed was fifteen and Aunt Fanny about eleven or twelve.
I have heard mother and others tell of occasions when Papa would
find his mother exhausted over some household chore such as cooking or
washing, and would pick her up in his arms and carry her to her bed and
return to finish the chore himself. In hearing others speak of my grand-ma
Rion, it was always in the most endearing terms.
ENOCH HUNT JONES ; father of my Grandma Rion, was born May 11, 1798
near Hall's Hill, Rutherford County, Tennessee, son of Ezra Jones and
Margaret Hunt Jones. He grew up on the plantation where he was born,
but soon was to leave those familiar surroundings for service in the
Armed Forces of the United States,- under General Andrew Jackson, against
the British, at or near New Orleans - the War of 1812.
At the age of sixteen, he enlisted on September 28, l8lli, ENOCH H.
JONES, Private, in Captain Richard Tate's Company VOLUNTEER MOUNTED
GUNMEN.
"Col. Thomas Williamson, -Muster Roll of the
Field and Staff Officers of Col. Thomas William-son's
Regiment of Tennessee Volunteer Mounted
Gunmen in General John Coffee's Brigade, in the
United States service, under the command of
Major General Andrew Jackson. Mustered on the
28th September l8lU."
The above from records in Tennessee State Library and Archives,
and continues,-
49
"Capt. Richard Tate, -28th September l8lU to
27th April l8l5,-I certify on honor, that each
non-commissioned officers, musicians, artificer
and private of the Company under my command
traveled eighty miles in marching from Nashville
in Davidson County their place of residence to
Fayetteville in Lincoln County where they were
mustered into service."
The history which ties in with this service record is,-
"August 15th, 181U - after signing a treaty with
the Creek Indians, General Jackson went to Mobile
and found the English menacing the Gulf Coast
settlements .
"
It was shortly after this that the enlistment of Volunteers from
Tennessee, including Enoch H. Jones, was called for, and joined the
forces to the South.
"After capturing Pensacola from the Spanish,
-
Jackson moved on December 2, l8lli, to New Orleans.
December 10th, British troops landed below
New Orleans and advanced on that point.
December 23rd, Jackson attacked from two different
positions.
January 1, 1815, British opened an offensive, and
were reinforced January 6th."
By this time Jackson's forces had been gathered together,- "A
motley array of sailors, regulars, Creoles, pirates, negroes, Frenchmen,
Kentuckians and Tennesseeans . " These held Jackson's left, in the battle
which began early on the morning of January 8th and lasted until January
18th.
Even after several crushing defeats the British seemed loath to de-part,
and did not until February 11th. Thus ended the land fighting.
The job finished, our Soldier Enoch Jones returned to his home and
was mustered out on April 27, l8l&#163;.
Later, Enoch Jones was to be honored as we shall relate later.
50
Pension records in the National Archives in Washington show that
Enoch H. Jones received a war pension of $8.00 per month.
About 1825, Enoch Hunt Jones was married to Eunice Macklin (or
Mcldnn). They had five children, one of whom was my grandmother, Nancy
Ann Jones Rion. Eunice Macklin died May 1, 1839.
Enoch Jones was married three additional times and while none of
these wives relate to my family, I will mention them for the record.
His second wife was Rebecca F. Hunt (a cousin) whom he married
about I81i0. She died May 19, 1856.
The third wife was Caroline Hunt Ready, married about i860. She
died May 9, 1873.
The fourth wife was Oma McKnight and no dates are available.
Our research has disclosed an interesting document copied from
Page 511 - Record of the United States Census of 1850, secured by Hilda
Jones Dunn of Washington from the National Archives.
NOTE: This document contains the names of those of the family living
in that house at that time, listed by name and age which apparently was
guessed at as we find discrepancies. For example, Nancy is listed as
eighteen. She was born in I83U, hence was actually sixteen. Enoch,
himself, listed as sixty, while born in 1798, was fifty-two. Another
error is in place of birth. They were all born in Tennessee,- only tho
ancestors were from Virginia. But the record is interesting. Also note,
no slaves are listed.
* There is a seperarte census record of slaves for the year
1350.
49a
The Jones House no&#171; owned by-
Bill lynch
51
McCracklns District County of Rutherford State of Tennessee
Enumerated at Census of l8$0 Date of August 26
Name Age Born in
Jones, Enoch 60 Virginia
Jones, Rebecca U0 Virginia
Jones, Sarah 21 Virginia
Jones, Nancy A. 18 Virinia
Jones, William 13 Virginia
Jones, Martha 12 Virginia
Jones, Gusham 10 Virginia
Jones, Fanny 8 Virginia
From the 1850 Census Records of Rutherford County
&#171;
Tennessee *
In the National Archives, Washington, D. C .
In addition to the above copy of Census of 18$0,- below we see the
report of 1830, which is of an entirely different form, giving no names,
only males or females according to age groups, and slaves only male or
female.
County of Rutherford State of Tennessee
Enumerated at Census of I83O
Name Age
Jones, Enoch H. Males 1 under 5 Females 3 under $
1 - 30 to U0 1 - 30 to 1*0
3 Slaves 1 Slave
The special honor, mentioned earlier, came to Grandpa Enoch on May
20, 1880, when he was eighty-two years old, at which time he was selected
to pull the cord unveiling the handsome bronze statue of General Andrew
Jackson which had been erected on the State Capitol grounds at Nashville.
52
The Nashville Banner, afternoon newspaper of Nashville, often
features stories of important historical events of the past and where
possible, shows old photographs of the event.
Such a story was featured in the magazine section on May 19, 1939*
headed "UNVEILING OLD HICKORY'S STATUE". and reprinting a photograph made
on that occasion. Under the picture was the following story:
"The unveiling of the Clark Mills ' equestrian
statue of Gen. Andrew Jackson was a feature of
the Nashville Centennial Exposition, April 23 -
May 29, 1880. The unveiling was held on May 20.
A crowd of 30,000 thronged Capitol Hill that
day to witness the ceremonies. Among the mili-tary
celebrities present were Gens. Joseph. E. John-ston
and Edmund Kirby Smith (CSA) and Gen. D. C. Buell,
former commander of the Union Army of the Ohio.
Dr. T. A. Atchison, exposition president, delivered
a welcome address; John F. House delivered the
oration of the day, and Enoch Jones , a veteran of
Jackson's wars, pulled the cord unveiling the
handsome bronze statue."
Just how or why Enoch Jones was selected for this honor is not
revealed in any of the records. The Tennessee State Archives does contain
a clipping from the "Nashville Republican Banner" of May 20, 1880 (the
date of the unveiling) "UNCLE ENOCH JONES, an old Jackson soldier of
Rutherford County, is in the city, as a guest of W. L. McKay, 387 S.
Summer St&#187;"
It is known that he was often affectionately referred to as "uncle"
Enoch Jones.
At the time of the erection of Clark Mills' magnificent bronze
equestrian statue of General Jackson at Nashville, a total of three of
these were cast, one to be erected at New Orleans, one at Washington, D. C.
and this one at Nashville and it is with a lot of pride that we recall
this honor to our ancestor.
53
A little less than five years later, Enoch Hunt Jones was laid to
rest in the beautiful little cemetery on the hill, having "departed this
life on February 2, 1885."
SUPPLEMENT
JONES
Since transcribing the foregoing, relating to Enoch Hunt Jones, we
have discovered that the original Family Bible of Enoch Jones is now in
the possession of his grandson Ed Jone, son of Gursham Jones.
While the information about our part of the family, as contained in
this Bible, differs very little from what we already have, it is more
complete and is especially interesting and valuable because most of it is
in Enoch Jones own handwriting.
I have never seen family birth records in such complete detail as to
mention the time of day as well as the date. My grandmother, for instance,-"
Nancy Ann Jones, born Saturday night, 6th of September, 183b at the hour
11 o&#187;clock."
Also note, -his entry on the death of his wife Eunice McLinn Jones,
-
"It is her gain tho a great loss to me," he wrote, tenderly, then
initialed the entry "E. H. J".
Eunice McLinn Jones was the mother of nine children. She died at
the early age of 35
&#8226;
Any controversy regarding the correct spelling of her name McLinn,
seems now to be resolved, as Enoch, in his own handwriting, wrote it,-
"McLINN."
Entered here is the complete record as copied from the original
Bible of Enoch Hunt Janes.
54
BIBLE
Daniel D. Smith's Stereotype Edition
Stereotyped by E. White, New York
Published and Sold by Daniel D. Smith, New York
at
The Franklin Juvenile Book and Stationary Store, No. 190
Greenwich Street
also by
The Principal Booksellers in the United States
1825
Bible of Enoch Hunt Jones ( 1798 - 1885) of
Rutherford County, Tennessee
Bible now in the possession of E. L. Jones,
Jefferson Pike, Route 3&gt; Murfreesboro, Tennessee
FAMILY RECORD
MARRIAGES
Enoch Hunt Jones was born on the 11th day, May 1798.
Eunice McLin was born on the 15th day, December, I8OI4.
The above couple was joined in wedlock on Thursday evening, the 2hth
day, March, 1825.
E. H. Jones
Eunice Jones
Eunice Jones, first wife of E. H. Jones, deceased this life on the
1st day, May, 1839, in the morning. It is her gain tho a great loss
to me.
E. H. J.
Married - E. H. Jones and Rebecca F. Hunt on the - - October 1839.
E. H. Jones and the yd. Caroline Hancock married the 22nd of November,
i860.
E. H. Jones and Naomi (this word not clear) S. (or G.) McKnight the
Yd of McKnight was married on the 8th day, October, 1873 &#8226;
55
BIRTHS
Margaret Catherine Jones was born on 22nd of March, 1826 it
being on Tuesday.
Sary Elizabeth Jones was born on the 18th Aprile, 1827 - it
being on Wednesday.
James E. Jones was born on Monday the 22nd day of December,
1828. Four o'clock in the evening.
Christiana Jane Jones born on Friday the 9th day of January,
1829.
Enoch Hunt Jones born on Monday the 12th day of September,
1851. Eight o'clock in the morning.
Josephas Alexander Jones was born Aprile 1st, 1833
&#8226;
Nancy-ann Jones born Saturday night, 6th of Septentoer, I83U at
the hour 11 o'clock.
William Anderson Jones born Friday morning, 10 o'clock -
August 12th, I836.
Marthey B. Jones born Sunday Evening, 2 o'clock Uth or 8th
(not clear) Aprile, 1838.
Ourshorn Hunt Jones born January 15th, I8I4I.
Fanny Green Jones born 12th October, 18U3*
Fanny Green Jones, wife of WiU T. McKnight, died on the 25th
October, 1868.
DEATHS
Rebecca F. Jones, the 2nd wife of E. H. Jones, died the 19th
of May 1856.
Caroline Jones, 3rd wife of E. H. Jones, died the 9th of May,
1873. Age 73 years.
56
Naomi G. Jones, Uth wife, died Saturday morning 6-2g o'clock
June the 17th, 1876.
Enoch Hunt Jones died February 3rd, 1885. Age 86 years, 8
months and 22 days.
* Enoch Hunt Jones deceased this life on Friday the 2nd day
of August, 1833, two o'clock in the evening, aged 22 months, 20 days,
and 6 hours.
Margaret Catherine Hartwell departed this life on the 10th day of
May, l8Ui.
James Ezra Jones departed this life on the 7th day of July, 1857
at 2 o'clock P. M. in the 29th year of his age.
Nancy Ann Rion, wife of T. D. Rion - daughter of E. H. Jones died
Friday, the 15th, June, 1877-6 o'clock in the evening.
Christana Jane Jarmon, daughter of E. H. Jones. Died the 25th
of May, 1882, 3 o'clock in the evening.
* This must be "Junior."
NOTE: The abbreviation "yd" as used in the foregoing, seems to have
been intended for "wd" abbreviation for widow.
EUNICE McLINN (MACKLIN): First wife of Enoch Hunt Jones, was born
on December 15* l80li, probably in the edge of Wilson County, Tennessee,
adjoining Rutherford County.
NOTE: Records show that James B. McLinn, "sold his property in 1817
to James Black, "-Property on Bradley Creek.
Eunice McLinn, or Macklin as the name is spelled both ways in
different places, was the daughter of James B. McLinn. She is listed as
57
one of seven children mentioned In his Last Will and Testament, probated
in Rutherford County, April 1820.
Eunice McLinn was married to Enoch Hunt Jones about 1825 (exact date
not given.) She died on May 1, I839. Among her several children were
Nancy Ann, my grandmother Rion, and her favorite brother Will Jones as
shown in the 1850 Census report.
JAMES B. McIJNN, or MACKLDJ; The father of my great-grandmother
Jones lived in Wilson County and later in Rutherford County as shown in
early real estate transfers. We could not find any record of dates of
birth, marriage or his death. The only clues to the period covered by
his life are in his Last Will, probated in April 1820 listing his daughter
Eunice seventh among his children, and she was born December 15, I8OI4..
No records could be found of his wife's name or family history. She must
have died prior to the writing of the Will of 1820 as she is not
mentioned therein.
EZRA JONES : Father of Enoch Hunt Jones, was born in North Carolina
on February 3, 1772. He was married to Margaret Hunt on March 15, 1796.
The records of the United States Census of I830 should be of interest
here -
County of Rutherford State of Tennessee
Enumerated at Census of 1830
Name Age
Jones, Ezra Males 2 - 20 to 30 Females 1 - 15 to 20
1 - 50 to 60 1 - 20 to 30
1 - 50 to 60
h slaves k slaves
53
MARGARET HUNT: Was born on October 18, 1773 and died May 22,
1877, a very long life, - 10U years. Margaret was the daughter of
Enoch Hunt who married a - - - - Lorrance.
ENOCH HUNT ; It Is not difficult to now see where great-grand-father
Enoch Hunt Jones got his name. Enoch Hunt was married to - - - -
lorrance. (given name unknown.) They had ten children, seven sons
and three daughters. No dates of birth, marriage or death are avail-able
on Enoch Hunt or his wife.
EZEKIEL JONES: With no other records, we will be content with
this ancestor's Revolutionary War record found in "Historical Register
of Virginians in the Revolution" as having served in the 13th Virginia
Regiment of the Continental line.
59
HENRI
The name Henry has a Teutonic derivation meaning "Ruler of the home,-
rioh or mighty lord." This personal name Imported by the Normans, was
widely used by the English rulers. It was adopted as a surname in England
and Scotland where most of the American emigrants originated, however,
the name was not unknown in Ireland, Brittany and France.
The ancestry of the Henry family traces back to the 12th Century.
Thus, the name is mentioned in the "Roll of Battle Abbey," the "Doomesday
Book" and In the "Great Rolls of the Pipes" in 1153.
The Henrys of Ireland are descendants of the Scots who were re-settled
in Ulster by James I. Religious persecutions of the Covenanters
at a later period, followed by dispossession and eviction from their
homes and in many instances resulting in large numbers leaving Ireland
for Jtaerica. The Henry family was well represented In this tide of
emigration of these Scotch-Irish to America.
Early records indicate that several members of this family, after
emigrating to America, settled in various parts of the country and established
their own branch of the family.
Virginia was the new land chosen by the ancestors of our branch of the
Henry family, for their new homes.
In the early 1730&#187;s, large grants of land in some of the Virginia
cotttties made possible great estates being carved out of the wilderness.
Smoke from an occasional settlers cabin also curled through the valleys
and from mountain sides in portions hitherto little known.
Among these early 1730 settlers were two brothers, John Henry and his
60
brother, the Reverend Patrick Henry. They were from Aberdeen, Scotland.
Their father was Alexander Henry who married Jean Robertson.
John Henry received hie education at Kings College, Aberdeen,
Scotland where he was an honor student.
After arriving in America, John Henry was married to Sarah Winston,
and to this union, nine children were born, two sons and seven daughters.
The youngest was a son born May 29, 1736, whom they named Patrick, doubt-less
for his Uncle, the Reverend Patrick Henry&gt; Parson of Hanover.
Intellectually, and in all qualities that make for character, John
Henry, the scholarly gentleman, undoubtedly brought to his son Patrick
and to his other children, a superior heritage. This was augmented for
Patrick by the influence of John's brother, the learned Rector of St.
Pauls in Hanover County.
Although I am unable to establish the direct connection, it has always
been my understanding, that our branch of the Henry family descended from
this connection, in fact, directly so. Even though I have not been able
to determine the exact status, nevertheless the very interesting studies
I have made of the entire Virginia branch of the Henry family, Increases
my pride in being one of them.
As all genealogists must piece together their story from numerous bits
of information, and sometimes very small hits, it has certainly been true
in this instance.
A well known Eighteenth Century London editor, printer and writer,
David Henry, a kinsman of the Henry's who settled in Virginia, had this
said of him - "He had a well stored mind and in all his writings he never
forgot the instructive moral." David Henry never left England, but in
writing of his Henry kin who had emigrated to Virginia, he said, -"They were
6l
ore respected for their good sense sad superior education than for their
riches, n and again, "At every neighboring gathering of the Gentlemen,
they were described as among the foremost, of genteel style and at great
pains to instruct their children."
In another instance, editor David Henry mentions that several of his
relatives "sought their fortunes in Virginia where their name is held in
high esteem."
In 1901*, I talked with Uncle Wash Henry on this family connection,
and made some notes, but unfortunately these were lost in the fire and
my memory does not serve me sufficiently to recall many of the facts, but
although in my recent studies and research, I am unable to trace the exact
connection to Patrick Henry. I have found it most Interesting and am still
very proud to be a part of the family of "The Henrys of Virginia" and
especially the Fount Henrys.
My interest was re-kindled a few years ago when I discovered a letter
which had been written to my sister, January 2k* 1927 by Col. William L.
Crittenden, seeking family information for the completion of the Henry
family history, which was however, never completed. Col. Crittenden's
grandmother was Mary Catherine Henry, a sister of my grandfather Fountain
Jeffries Henry and Uncle Wash Henry.
In his letter, Col, Crittenden states: "I imagine that you already
know that your great-grandfather was Fountain Fisher Henry, Captain of
Culpeper Minute Men (wife Sara Dudley Jeffries) your great-great-grand-father
was Joel Henry (wife Sussana Allen) and your great-great-great-grandfather
was George Henry."
"I have often visited the old Henry plantation 'Clover Creek' in Cul-peper
County and the town house at Culpeper Ct. H., which is an old brick
62
Mansion and which was used as a hospital for Confederate wounded of the
second Battle of Manassas."
With this bit of information , I have been successful in contacting
a researcher in Culpeper and have developed sons additional information,
but far too little.
On the subject of the old Henry homes, Miss Browning, the reasearcher
writes,- "I could not find anything about 'Clover Creek' the Henry plantat-ion.
The Fountain Fisher Henry hone (town house) is on Main Street in the
town of Culpeper,- Lafayette was entertained in this home."
Culpeper County, Virginia, the birthplace of my grandfather, Fountain
Jeffries Henry and his father Fountain Fisher Henry,-has taken it's right-ful
place as one of Virginia's most historical spots.
It derives its name from Thomas, Lord Culpeper, who was Royal Governor
of the Colony of Virginia from 1680 to 1683, in which position he was held
in high esteem.
Lord Culpeper was one of the grantees of the territory of Virginia and
at one time controlled all the land between the Rappahannock and the Patomac
Rivers. Culpeper County, named in his honor, is only a small part of his
extensive holdings.
Culpeper County Court House, as the little city of Culpeper was called
in olden days, has been the scene of many notable historic events. Oeorge
Washington took his oath of office at Culpeper as county surveyor in 171*9.
What is now a peaceful and industrious country side has, In the past
been the scene of bloodshed during both the Revolution and the War Between
the States. Records show that thirty-seven battles and engagements took
place upon Culpeper soil.
The Culpeper Minute Men were famed for their valor during the
Revolutionary struggle.
63
The people met in Contention la Richmond July 17* 1775 at which tine
Patrick Henry made his Immortal speech. "Give Me Liberty, or aire Me
Death." This Convention appointed a general committee of safety for the
Colony and directed committees of safety to be chosen by the freeholders
in each county.
The Convention also divided the Colony into districts in each of
which a battalion of 500 men was to be raised and disciplined to march
at a "minutes warning."
These were the Minute Men, of whom John Randolph said, "They were
raised in a minute, marched in a minute and conquered in a minute."
During the Revolution, the Culpeper Minute Men were hunting shirts
of strong brown linen and on the breast of each shirt was worked in large
white letters the words - "Liberty or Death. "
Their flag had in the center a rattlesnake coiled in the act to strike.
Below it were the words "Don*t tread on me!" At the sides "Liberty or Death"
and at the top "The Culpeper Minute Men."
The illustrious organisation, though not continually active after the
close of the Revolution, was re-activated at the outbreak of the War Between
the States, and at sometime during this period, Fountain Fisher Henry
served as Captain. In various records I have studied, including
"Geneologies, Mostly Virginian" by Crittenden Narriott, a manuscript in the
Rare Books Division of the Library of Congress, when the name of my great-grandfather
is mentioned it usually carries the title, -ie - "Fountain
Fisher Henry, Captain. Culpeper Minute Men." This organization will live
in history and in the hearts of the people as long as the love of American
Liberty survives.
64
In our Immediate family history the Henry family connection Is
through my mother, NBTTIB BLLBN HBNRT.
NBTTIB BLIIBN HBNRY.-ay aether, was born In Murfreeaboro, Rutherford
County, Tennessee, on September 6, i860. She was the only daughter of
Fountain Jeffries Henry and Sallie Ellen Osborn. Mother grew up In Murfreea-boro,
receiving nost of her education at Soule College and later finishing
her education at a college in McKenzle, Tennessee. The head master of this
school was Uncle "Billy" Hendrix, and while there, mother lived with Aunt
Jane and Uncle Billy, and roomed with their daughter Maggie Hendrix, her
cousin, becoming very close companions.
At a party near Lascassas, she met William James Rion and on December
17, 1879, they were married in the First Cumberland Presbyterian Church
in Murfreesboro, Rev. J. H. Warren officiating.
(More on this wedding on Page 7 , in sketch on my father)
After marriage, mother and papa lived in the country near Lascassas
but were back in Murfreesboro by the following Fall, and on November 2U,
1880 my sister was born.
About two years after that, they moved to Nashville, where, on October
13, 1883, I was born.
Our father died on April 2, 1887, shortly before his thirtieth birth-day,
while mother was only twenty-six.
Before papa's death, during the latter part of his long illness, it
became necessary for mother to go to work to help carry on the heavy bur-den,
financial and otherwise.
Her first position was with the oldest and most historic store for
ladies,-THOMPSON &amp; KELLT. They handled principally, dress goods by the
65
bolt as this was before the day of "Ready to Wear" goods as we now
know than.
Mother's health was not good. She was thin and frail and soon lost
the battle of trying to lift the heavy bolts of woolens from shelf to
counter and back, and had to give up this work with which she was physio-ally
unable to cope.
After papa's death, Mr. P. M. Hill offered her a place in his
Millinery Store, in the "work room" making hats, -here she could be seated
while at work. She loved this work for it was pleasant and easy and she
soon became so adept at design and execution, she was transferred to the
sales floor. It should be recalled at this point that with Millinery
this also was before the days of "Ready to Wear." With the exception of
a few Imported Paris Models, no ready made hats were on sale. Every hat
was made especially for the lady customer, hence, her skill of delineation
and design were highly valuable assets. She did well in the Millinery
business, so much so that she remained in it until 192U, or a total of 37
years, during which she served many of the great ladies, of Nashville, as
well as the near great.
Her life was one of real service.
On October 8, 19U5 while taking an afternoon nap, her spirit quietly
slipped away. She had only a few days before, passed her 85th birthday.
FOUNTAIN JEFFRIES HENRY .- was born October 7, I836 In Culpeper Ct. H.,
Virginia. He was the son of Fountain Fisher Henry and Sarah Dudley Jeffries
of ^ulpeper, Virginia. He moved to Murfreesboro, Tennessee, along with his
brother Washington C. Henry and a sister, Nannie Henry (married J. H. Elliott).
66
There he net and married Sallie Ellen Osborn on May 19, 1859.
Grandfather Fountain Jeffries Henry, though christened "Fountain,"
was known as, and generally called "FOUNT", hence when I was named for
him I was given the shortened name "FOUNT" and was never known by any
other.
Grandfather Henry was a brick contractor, by trade, as was his
brother Wash Henry. Many houses now stand in Murfreesboro and in Pulaski,
Tennessee that were built just prior to, or immediately after the War
Between the States, which interrupted his career, for as hostilities grew
in magnitude, Fountain Jeffries Henry was among many prominent Murfrees-boro
men who in October 1862 were mustered into "COMFANT D, ELEVENTH
TENNESSEE CAVALRY" of the Confederate Army, and served throughout the
duration of the War, and at one time, received a gunshot wound in his hip,
and later died from the effects of this wound.
From a newspaper clipping from the "Murfreesboro Free Press", I
find the following:
COMPANY D , ELEVENTH
TENNESSEE CAVALRY
"Following is a list of officer and men as they
were mustered into the Confederate Army in Octo-ber
1862."
Then a long list of approximately 125 names from
well known Murfreesboro families, are listed
among which appear the following,-two brothers
and a brother-dn-law,
FOUNT HENRY
W. C. HENRY
J. H. ELLIOTT
Then in a letter from the Tennessee Board of Pension Examiners
t
"This is to certify that Sallie E. Henry, the
67
widow of F. J. Henry, who belonged to Co* D.
Uth Tenn. Cav. was a pensioner of Tennessee."
"P. J. Henry1 s record as a Confederate Soldier
was "A No. 1" and his daughter Mrs. Nettle B. Rial
Is clearly- entitled to join the United Daughters
of the Confederacy."
This letter was signed by General John P. Hickman whom I knew in my
younger years. He was a Veteran of the Confederate Army.
Many are the memories I cherish, of stories, told me by Grandma
Henry, of those terrible times during that War as she was left alone with
her two little babies, my mother then two years old and her little brother
an Infant in arms, and grandpa away and the uncertainty which hourly grew
more unbearable as this terrible conflict raged around their very doors.
Fount Henry died in 1871 from the effects of the gunshot wound
received a few years earlier, during the Civil War.
Grandma Henry (SaUie Ellen Osborn) will be further mentioned In the
Osborn line.
FOUNTAIN FISHBR HENRI, was born in Culpeper County, Virginia, the son
of Joel Henry and Susannah Allen. I have not been able to find any dates
of birth, marriage or death, but from records and other evidence, Fountain
Fisher Henry was a Virginia Gentleman of Importance, especially in and
around Culpeper Ct. H.
He was married to SARAH DUPLET JEFFRIES , and they had seven children,
as evidence by his Last Will and Testament, made on the 9th day of September
i860. At that time no mention was made of his wife Sarah so it can be
assumed that she had died before that time. Further evidence of this lies
in a letter from Grandpa Henry to my grandma, written from Culpeper in
63
January of i860. He had gone there for a visit with his father, who was
ill. No mention is made of his mother. He described his train trip,
which was very rough but only natural In those very early days of rail-road
pioneering.
It may be interesting to include here a copy of that letter, keeping
in mind he had been married only eight months and he was only 23 years and
3 months old. Grandma was only 19 years, 5 months . old.
Culpeper Ct. Hs.
Jany. 2lith, i860
}ty dear Sallie:
I know you think it has been a long time since I left
and I think so too, but it will not be very long before I will
be back for I am very tired of staying here I can assure you.
My Father is much better than he was when I got here. It seems
to do the old man so much good for me to be here. About the
first question he asked me was why I did not bring my wife, and I
had to promise to come again and bring you before he would let me
alone, but I showed him your picture and he was very much pleased
with it and all of them think it is pretty. You know they are
judges of beauty. Everything is so changed here that I hardly
think it is home but I know just as many as I did when I left.
Everybody that knows me says I have not changed a single bit since
I left here but I think very different. I am going out in the country
today to see my old Aunt and I reckon she will give me those pants,
I was talking about. If she does not, I will always think she
ought, don't you think so. When she heard I had come she came to
town immediately to see me.
I did not tell you in my other letter (or note) how we got along
with Florence, much better than I expected but I don't wish to
have another trip of the same kind. We got here Saturday Evening
at 6 o'clock, not as soon as I expected but had to stay all night
in Chattanooga, which threw us back about 13 hours, but I can go
back much faster than I came.
I am not going to tell you exactly when I will get there, for I
might not get there exactly at that time and then you would be
uneasy about me, but I will be there sooner than you think I will.
I want to take you on surprise when I come.
Well Sallie you know I am not much of a hand to write letters so
you must make out the best you can with this until I come, and
then I will tell you all I know and a little more. I have declined
going to Washington City as I would have to stay two days longer
69
than I intend to stay and I want to see ay old sweeting* too
bad for that. If you hare not written to me yon need not write
for I would not be here to get it. It takes a letter longer
to cone than it did me. I reckon I had better close my letter
for you can hardly read this. It is so badly written. Qire
my best respects to all the family and believe me as ever,
Tour affectionate Husband,
Fount
P. 3. Take good care of the dog.
In the Will, - no mention is made of any specific properties to be
divided among the seven children, nor any estimated values, but for the
record we will copy the text of the Will here:
FOUNTAIN FISHER HENRY'S WILL
"I, Fountain F. Henry, of the County of Culpeper
do make this my last Will and Testament hereby
revoking all others heretofore made by me.
FIRST: I direct my executor, hereinafter named,
to sell all my estate, real and personal, and
out of the proceeds first to pay ny debts and
then to divide the residue into seven equal
parts, one part I give to each of my following
named children, - Susan C Bell, Martha L. Cooper,
Washington C. Henry, Ann 0. Elliott and
Fountain J. Henry; one seventh part I give to my
son Washington C. Henry in trust for the sole and
separate use of my daughter Mary C amiss, and the
remaining seventh part, I give to Washington C. Henry
in trust for my Grandson, Robert A* Collins, the
interest, if necessary, to be expended in his edu-cation
and support and the principal to be paid to
him when he arrives at the age of twenty-one years.
SECOND: I appoint my friend, James W. Green, my executor.
In testimony whereof I have hereunto set my hand and
seal this 9th day of September i860.
Fountain F. Henry (SEAL)
Signed, sealed, published and
declared as the last Will and Testament
of the testator in our presence at the
same time, at the request of the
testator in his presence and in the
70
presence of each other subscribed our
names as witnesses thereto, the 9th day
of September i860.
JAMES W. GREEN
JAMES 0. FIELD
THO. 0. FLINT
Fountain Fisher Henry served as Captain of the "Culpeper Minute
Men" - but no dates are available as to duration of this service, or the
period of time engaged.
SARAH DUDLEY JEFFRIES: Wife of Fountain Fisher Henry, was of a dis-tinguished
Virginia family. She was the daughter of Richard Jeffries
and Ann Cannon Pollard . No dates are available except that Richard and
Ann were married in 1796. Richard Jeffries was the son of Ambrose Jeffries
and Rachel Dudley. Rachel being the daughter of Col . Peter Dudley,
Revolutionary Soldier from King and Queen County, Virginia. This Jeffries
information was secured from Miss Georgie Jeffries, age 93* of Culpeper,
and is all that she could remember. She had no records.
Both the Jeffries and Dudley families were represented in the
Revolutionary struggle and from the information we have secured, it is
safe to assume they were held in high esteem, and especially so within the
family as there are several namesakes including my grandfather Fountain
JEFFRIES Henry and his mother Sarah DPDLET Jeffries. Col. Crittenden's
slater was named "Sarah Dudley Crittenden", and many others of the descend-ants
bear their names.
JOEL HENRY: Father of Fountain Fisher Henry was married to SUSANNAH
ALLEN . While no dates are available it is probable they were married about
1790. It has been impossible to secure accurate information on either of
71
these great-great-grand parente bat we can safely assume that Joel Henry
was born in Culpeper County, Virginia, as we hare ascertained that his
father George Henry is listed as a soldier in the Revolutionary War from
Culpeper County.
QBORQE HENRY: No dates or other information has been developed on
the personal or family side of George Henry, except that of his military
record as listed in "Historical Register of Virginians in The Revolution."
Also no mention is made anywhere of his wife's name or her family.
I have understood all my life that we were descended from or very close
to Patrick Henry, but I am unable at this time to establish this. There are
several by the name of George Henry connected with the Patrick Henry family,
but just which one, if any, is the correct connection seems destined to re-main
a secret from me, - after all, Patrick had seventeen children and sixty
grand-children, and 200 years of genealogy is too large a task for me*
72
OSBORN
It has been interesting to note what a prominent part Virginia has
had in the background of the three previously mentioned branches of our
family - Rion - Jones - Henry. While our first record of the Rions in
America show that William Rion was born in Maryland and Thomas Gayle in
England, the fulfilment of their lives was inseparably linked with Virginia.
With the Jones, we know nothing prior to their living in Virginia,
and so, with the Henrys, except the John Henry family from Aberdeen,
Scotland.
This is also, not only true with the Osborn branch, but we are
happy to have this history in more detail, and dating back further than
any of the others.
For this more accurate information, we are indebted to Howard E.
Rank of New York City, now deceased, whose mother was an Osborn and first
cousin to my great-grandfather Harvey Osborn.
I recall distinctly, when I was a child - perhaps ten years old -
this man and his wife visited at our home for a week or two, on a very
extended trip, all over the United States gathering facts, - names - dates -
etc. on all branches of the Osborn family, making a close study and compiling
those facts with a view that someday a volume might be published so that
all of the numerous members of that family might have one - but unfortunately,
that proved too costly a venture and the idea discarded, but the manuscripts
have proved invaluable many times.
To further identify this man with the family I would like to relate
here, a story that intrigued me in my early years. I had &#8226; heard that my
great-great-great-grandfather, Caleb Osborn, had two sons, and that one of
73
these sons had nine daughters and no sons and the other had nine sons
and no daughters.
One day while I was visiting in New Tork and discussing Osborn
family with Cousin Howard, I asked him if that could be true. He answered
promptly that it was perfectly true - but it was not all the story, - and
he proceeded to tell me there were THREE sons, Instead of just two, and one
had nine sons, one had nine daughters, and the other one had nine children -
boys and girls.
Then he explained our mutual kinship by telling me,- his mother was
one of the nine daughters and my great-grandfather was one of the nine sons.
It was a real satisfaction to me to have been able to visit with him
several times before he died, and to listen to him tell of the historic
facts connected with the family.
I wish I knew now, where that manuscript could be found. I would
like so much to see it.
I recall that he told me of the first Osborn in America, one Thomas
Osborn, born in England and came to America about 1609, landing at James-town
with some of the early English settlers. This was just two years after
the first settlers landed there. We have no further record of his movements
for the next seven years, - or until 1616 - when the records show he settled
in Chesterfield "Colony", Virginia, in November of that year. (This is
probably the Chesterfield County of modern day Virginia and I assume it was
near this section where he settled.)
We have no record of his marriage, nor his wife's name, only my hazy
recollection that Howard told me she was a Roseberry from England.
In 1631, Thomas Osborn was made a JUSTICE,- and in 1639 he became a
member of the HOUSE OF BURGESSES - of the Colony of Virginia.
74
The record seems to be blank from this time until his QRAND30N.
THCMAS, appears in the record. No mention is made of his son, however
his grandson Thomas and his great-grandson John, with their families,
remained in Virginia, - but the great-great-grandson of the original
Thomas, left Virginia and moved north to New Jersey. His name was also
Thomas and wife Jane Patterson.
Their son CAIZB OSBORN, born at lyon's Farm, New Jersey on February
2h, 1751, was to have a distinguished career in the Revolutionary War and
to meet his death on December 20, 1799 in a most unusually tragic manner.
Caleb Osborn was a close friend of George Washington and served with
him throughout the Revolutionary War, was with him through that terrible
winter at Valley Forge, therefore, it was not unlikely that when General
Washington died, Caleb Osborn would be asked to serve as one of a guard of
honor. This group were riding horseback in the funeral procession and
necessarily on strange horses. Returning from the interment, Caleb's
horse became frightened and threw him onto a picket flnce, fatally wounding
him, and causing his death on December 20, 1799*
The records do not show when, before the Revolutionary War or after-ward,
but this Osborn Ancestor moved to New York City and had a home on the
lower tip of Manhattan, facing the "Battery. About 1920 this house was
pointed out to me by Howard Rank, and at that time was the only residential
building left on that busy street. All others had been crowded out by large
business structures.
Johnathan Osborn, second oldest son of Caleb Osborn, was born at New-ark
on July 31, 1793, - was married to Hannah Spinning of Elizabethtown,
75
October 23, l8ll*. They moved to Oxford, North Carolina where ho died
February 26, 1877.
This Johnathan Osborn was the one of three brothers who had nine sons,
the oldest of which was Harvey Osborn, my great-grandfather who was born
August 31, 1815* He moved to Murfreesboro, Tennessee where he married inn
Campbell Reed on October 8, 1839. Their oldest child was Sallie Ellen Osborn,
my grandmother, who was born August 8, I8I4O.
Just as I owe much to Howard Ronk for this earlier history of the
Osborn family, I am equally indebted to my grandmother for my knowledge
of the Osborns, - from her father and mother on down. Also I am indebted
to her for stimulating in me, a greater respect for and desire to know more
about all my family connections.
More members of the Osborn side of my family remained In Murfreesboro
longer than any others and as I visited there regularly each Sumner it was
only natural that I knew more of the older folk and enjoyed the many stories
of the old pioneer days.
There has been handed down through several generations of Ellen's, a
priceless bedspread. Exquisite In design and workmanship, completely hand
woven and hand embroidered. I have been in the Garden where it was that
Grandma Reed with her own hands, planted the seed, hoed and cultivated the
plants, picked the cotton, spun it on her own spinning-wheel, wove the
fabric on her own loom, embroidered and tufted it, heavily, in a most
artistic design, and deeply fringed the edges. It is a genuine work of art,
a priceless tribute to the versatility and ingenuity of this pioneer woman.
This was my great-great-grandmother Eleanor Rankin Reed, born July 11,
1800 and died August 2k, 1881*. Grandma Reed was definitely the favorite of
my mother and my grandmother. She was a very wise woman and her counsel and
advice were sought by many in the family.
76
The several generations of Ellens to which I referred, began with,
so far as I know, the maker of the bedspread:
ELENOR (ELLEN; RANKIN REED 1800 - 1881*
on down through:
ANN CAMPBELL REED OSBORN 1817 - 186U
SALLIE ELLEN OSBORN HENRI I8I4O - 1916
NETTIE ELLEN HBNRI RION i860 - 1?U5
ELLEN ANN RION CALDWELL i860 - 1961*
ELLEN RION CALDWELL FLEMING 1906 -
It was Ann Campbell Reed who married my great-grandfather Harvey
Osborn, and these were the parents of my grandma, Sallie Ellen Osborn
who married, Fountain Jeffries Henry.
During the Civil War, the suffering and distress of the Southern
people was not brought about by the shooting alone, but by the many con-tributing
factors such as privation, even starvation,- disease and pesti-lence.
Around Murfreesboro, the dread scourge of small pox took its toll.
One day during this siege, a man knocked on the door of Grandpa
Harvey Osborn *s home. He had with him, three of the younger sons (Grandma
Henry's brothers.) Their father and mother were told that the boys had
been discovered "catching a ride" on the rear of a large farm wagon going
cross town, and what they did not know was that the wagon was carrying
corpse
.
several of them died from small pox. All of the boys clothes were
to be burned outside and they washed with alcohol on entering the house.
This precaution however, did not prevent the boys from contracting the
disease, but the precautions did help prevent serious cases and the boys
recovered
&#8226;
77
Bat while they were sick, their father became ill with the sane
disease and due to the good nursing care of the mother, he too, recovered,
but through all this nursing, Grandma Osborn was stricken in a most serious
manner, and from this terrible disease, died on December 3, 1863.
Grandma Henry was living In her own home when she heard that the three
brothers had gotten caught in this trouble, so In an effort to rescue her
baby brother, Uncle Joe Osborn, who was then only three years old, she went
to her father's home, remaining on the outside, taking every possible pre-caution
(for she had two little ones of her own at home, my mother three
and Uncle Tonmy one.)
The baby brother was up stairs, had had no contact with the sick
brothers, so they stripped him of all clothes, bathed him thoroughly with
whiskey (it was serving as sterile alcohol) and lowered him in a sheet to
Grandma, who took him with her and cared for him for several years.
A few years after that, grandfather Harvey Osborn married again and
his second wife then assumed the job of raising Uncle Joe* The family of
older children were not too happy about this second marriage as they did
not consider her socially equal to their father.
Many, many times during my simmer vacations in Murfreesboro, I rode out
to the little farm, about a mile outside the city limits to visit this, -the
only "Grandma Osborn" I had really known, and to me, a little boy, she was
just a dear, sweet little old "grandma n who seemed to love me very much and
appreciate my visits.
She, too, knew many interesting stories about the family.
Her husband, Grandpa Harvey Osborn, had died there in Murfreesboro an
February 2k, 1886. I was hardly three years old and, of course, never knew
him.
rt
One of my mother's most cherished memories of Grandpa Harvey Osborn
was an occasion soon after papa and mother were married. They went to see
Grandpa, and he was expressing his congratulations and good wishes. Mother
described the scene with Grandpa sitting in front of a wood fire, in the
large open fire place - rocking llesurely in his favorite chair, a large
wooden rocker with cane seat and back and wide flat armrests, all well
cushioned for increased comfort.
Never changing his gase from the blue and yellow flames, flickering
among the glowing embers, he said, - "Nettie, I want to give you some
advice if you will heed, your marriage will be a success,- always keep
two bears in your house,- "bear, and forbear."
Nov to list the direct line of the Osborn family
in reverse of their chronological order:
SALLIB ELLBN OSBORN: my grandma Henry, was born in Murfreesboro,
Tennessee on August 8., l8U0. Her entire childhood, in fact the first U2
years of her life were spent in Murfreesboro*
She recleved her entire education at Murfreesboro Female Institute, and
at Soule College. I have some of her "report cards" which indicate she was
an excellent student.
Her younger days were spent in comparative ease as her father, though
not considered a rich man, was within the catagory of "well-to-do."
During her early years She was interested in the many Inventions and
developments of world importance which were taking place. The sewing
machine, the cotton gin, the electric light, the telephone, the steamboat
and the steam railroad. She had told me of the thrill she had on seeing the
first steam railroad train go through Murfreesboro. She was a child of about
79
eight years. News had spread about town that at an announced time, this
marvelous new invention would pass through town. Just about the entire
population turned out to share in this great event. Many prominent citisane
of Murfreesboro had become stockholders in the new Nashville &amp; Chattanooga
Railway, hence the interest at this point on the line was very great.
On Hay 19, 1659* just three months before her 19th birthday, she was
married to Fountain Jeffries Henry.
To this union were born two children, my mother and her brother, two
years younger.
As related in the sketch on Grandpa Henry, the War Between the States
which began in 1861, grew in intensity and in 1662 Grandpa enlisted on the
Confederate side.
Some of the fiercest battles of the War were fought in and around
Murfreesboro, notably the Battle of Stone's River, just one mile north of
the town, near the railroad.
It was on December 26, 1862, - Grandpa had been In the army about
two months, when Confederate commander, General Bragg began the concentration
of his forces on Stone 1 s River. On December 29 the engagement began. A
see-sawing of advantages between the two opposing forces ensued during the
following few days, until on January 3, 1863, General Bragg retreated toward
Tullahoma, and on January $, the ttiion Army moved in to occupy Murfreesboro.
This brought on much hardship and suffering to the women and children,
left defenseless, and many times I have heard Grandma try to describe the
terrible feeling of "emptiness" in the whole town. All the younger and
able-bodied men in the army, and no way to get any word of their plight.
Rifle fire and the booming of cannon which had gone on for days, had hushed,
but in its place now the beat of soldier's feet - YANKEE - soldiers.
so
Grandma's hone at that time, was a comfortable little brick cottage
located diagonally across the street from Soule College. They had a large
brick underground cistern filled with rainwater, their only source of water
other than the "Town-pump" as no public waterworks existed at that time.
When the Yankees moved into town, the first thing they did was to take
over Soule College for a hospital for their wounded, then immediately
plundered the neighborhood, stripping all homes of their food supplies, all
clothing and linens for beds and bandages, even the baby clothes, and
carried water from the cistern until it was empty.
At this time, mother was nearly two and a half years old, and her
brother Toramie only a few months.
Grandma told pathetically of her desolation as she stood on the porch,
helpless, holding the baby in her arms, and mother, by the hand as she
watched everything in the world she owned being carried away. But the even
greater burden on her heart was the fate of her husband. What had happened
to him? The fighting had been fierce, the Yankee losses had been heavy
both in killed and wounded. It was only to be assumed, as they had heard
that the Confederate losses had been even greater. The uncertainty was
terrible
.
Wearily and desolately, she turned away and with the two babies, walked
the few blocks to Main Street and to her father's home where she remained
for a good while.
The War was over in 1865, and with Grandpa home, it was hoped that
peace would soon be a reality, but - not so. Troubles of a different kind,
and in some respects, worse than War, if that were possible.
Riff-raff moved in, from the north, and with corrupt men in high places,
these, so called, "Carpet Baggers" continued to harass and persecute the
Si
southerners. Some of the negroes became arrogant and offensive, and to
help curb this condition, the original secret organisation, the KU-KLUX
CLAN was organized.
Not to have been able to bring under control the arrogance and
vindictiveness of those half-savage negroes of those post-slave days
would have been unthinkable. What laws that existed for such protection
were not being enforced by the Northern politicians who were placed over
the conquered Southerners.
The negro of that time was inherently and mortally afraid of ngho8tsw
or "hants" as they called then, -so it was to take full advantage of this
emotion that the best of the southern men banded themselves together in
this secret society and dressed in white robes and white head-dress, and
the negroes, seeing large bands of these white robed figures (HANTS)
riding in on horseback, were more rigidly held in check.
Only occasionally did the Clansmen find it necessary to catch a
particularly arrogant one and give him a good flogging. News of such
occasions spread rapidly among the negroes and struck terror to their souls.
This unbearable condition was eventually brought under control.
Grandma told me of many instances during this hectic period. The women,
at home, made the white robes and masks, yet did not know who would be
wearing thera. It was so secret that wives and mothers did not know that
their own husbands and sons were Involved. Of course, they suspicioned such,
but accurate knowledge was kept secret from them.
That magnificent motion picture - "The Birth of a Nation" truly depicted
life during this period of reconstruction, and although Grandma was not
interested in many moving pictures, she, evidently was awaiting the showing
of this one,- for after she died, we found in her purse newspaper notices of
the approaching dates, but she died before that time.
S2
On July 1, 1871, her beloved husband, - "MI FOUNT" (as she always
called him) passed on to the "Great Beyond," Ids death attributed to the
effects of a gunshot wound In his hip, received during the War.
The family was living in a small one story, frame cottage on Main
Street, and after grandpa's death, she remained there until Uncle Tommie
went to Nashville to work and mother was married.
Alone, grandma worked at dress-oaking to make a living for her two
children, It was a brave struggle, but struggle it was, until Uncle
To&#8212;ii got to the place where he could help.
By 1882, Grandma, Uncle Tommie, papa, mother and sister were all
settled in Nashville, then in 1883, I was born. Then in 1885, tragedy
struck again, her beloved Tommie was stricken and died suddenly. From
that time on to her death, her life was lived solely for my mother, my
sister and for me.
On March 10, 1916, her beautiful Spirit passed from her frail body.
Hsr 76 years had truly been years of self-sacrifice, and during her
last ten years, she had done much to make her great-granddaughters happy.
The little children, as they naturally would, began asking questions
about Grandma,-"Where is my Grandma?" "When will Grandma come back?"
We tried to explain that God had taken Grandma to His home in Heaven
where she would be with the Angels.
Evelyn, then just two and one-half, expressed the true feelings of all
of us, as she looked up and exclaimed, "Oh! won&#187;t the Angels enjoy my Grandma!"
HARVEY 0SB0RN: my great-grandfather was the oldest of nine sons born to
Jonathan Osborn and Hannah Spinning at Elizabethtown, New Jersey on August
31, 1815. The family moved to Oxford, North Carolina where Harvey grew up,
but when a young man, he moved to Murfreesboro, Tennessee where he met and
S3
married Aim Campbell Reed. This marriage took placo in Murfreesboro on
October 8, 1839. They had seven (7) children,- two girls and ttm boys.
My Qrandma Henry was the oldest of these. Her sister, Mary, was the mother
of Cousin Annie May Cook Spain, who* we all called "MaMie", so nick-&#171;amed
by our little girls. The brothers were Will, James, Robert, Harvey and Joe.
A great deal of the history of Harvey Osbom, Sr. has already been
covered in the sketch on Qrandma Henry, hence it is not necessary to
repeat it here.
Harvey Osborn died at Murfreesboro on February 2U, 1886, and is buried
in Evergreen Cemetery.
AHN CAMPBBLL REED : my great-grandmother Osborn was the daughter of
James Reed and ELenor Rankin. She was born in Murfreesboro (a Christmas
gift) on December 25, 1817.
This one, in the Century long list of births in the direct line, is
the only one which is not on exactly the 20th year. This has always been
an interesting coincidence, for as far back as we have record,
-
Qrandma Rankin was born in 1780
Qrandma Reed was born in 1800
Grandma Osborn was born in 1817
Qrandma Henry was born in 181*0
My mother was born in i860
My sister was born in 1880
As related previously, grandma Osborn died on December 3, 1863, during
the Civil War, after nursing three of her young sons and then her husband
through a horrible siege of small pox.
JAMES RBBD t my great-great-grandfather, was born June 27, 1793. He
was married to Elenor Rankin about 1816 or early 1817. We do not have any
detailed information about this ancestor, however, I do remember that in
my childhood days, I was impressed, from hearing the older folks talk, that
34
"Grandpa and Grandma Reed" war* held in the very highest esteem by family
and friends alike. He died on ipril 29, 1865 and is buried in the Reed-
Osborn plot in Brergreen Cemetery in Murfreesboro.
BUBNOR RANKIN: was born on July 11, 1800. Was married to James Reed
about 1816-1817. She lived a long and useful life and died August 2U, 1881*.
Among our large family connection, Grandma Reed was always and in all
ways, my mother's favorite. I have heard mother tell of many instances
where she would go to "Grandma Reed" for counsel and advice.
Blenor Rankin Reed was, of course, the daughter of Grandpa and Grandma
Rankin, but I regret I do not have any information on either of them except
that Grandma Rankin was born in 1780. This I recall in connection with the
direct line of mostly Bllons, born at twenty year intervals beginning with
"Grandma Rankin In 1780."
JONATHAN OSBORNt was born at Newark, New Jersey on July 31, 1793.
Jonathan's grandfather, Thomas Osborn, was born in Virginia, but in his
early yotng manhood, left home and went north, settling in New Jersey.
Jobnathan was married to HANNAH SPINNING of Elisabethtown, New Jersey,
on October 23, 181U. She was born March 25, 1793,- and died January 12,
1863 in Oxford, North Carolina, where the family had moved during previous
years.
CAI&#163;B OSBORN .- father of Johnathan Osborn, was born February 2k, 1751,
at Lyons Farm, New Jersey. He was married on June 3, 1781, to SUSANNAH
JBWELL. These were my great-great-great-grandparents.
It was this Calbe Osborn who served with George Washington during the
Revolutionary War, -was with him through that terrible Winter at Valley
35
Forge,- and who died on December 20, 1799, from effects of being thrown
from a horse returning 'from Washington's burial.
His wife, Susannah Jewell, was born in June 1762, and died April
29, 1803.
THOMAS OSBORN ; was the father of Caleb Oaborn, and it was he who left
the home in Virginia to live in New Jersey. He was married to JANE
PATTERSON. We do not hare any dates on either of these.
JOHN OSBGRNi the father of the Thomas Osborn just mentioned, is also
the son of a Thomas Osborn. John Osborn was born about 1680. There are
three Thomas Osborns within fire generations, and we know little about any
of them, except the first. The wife of John Osborn was Ann. All other
information is lacking.
THOMAS OSBORN
&#187;
whose wife was Martha, was the grandson and namesake
of the first Thomas Osborn and we have no further information about them,
however, we assume this Thomas Osborn was born about 1650, in Virginia.
UNKNOWN , the records as furnished show a generation here, but with
all names and dates unknown, however, we can assume that this Osborn, the
first in our line to be born in America, was born about 1620 to 1625* At
this very early date, there were probably few, if any, private family
records kept.
There are no public service data recorded, as is in the case of his
father, the original Thomas Osborn.
86
THOMAS OSBCRNt This, our original ancestor in America, was born In
England in the late 1500*8, and emigrated to America among the rery early
settlers at Jamestown. His name is not listed amongh the "First Settlers"
who landed in 1607, but the Ronk records indicated he arrived about two
years later, or 1609.
In 1616, he set out from the Jamestown settlement and went up the
James River a few miles and settled in Chesterfield "Colony." We can
assume that this "Colony" was what is now, in whole or in part, Chester-field
County. This section lies South and West of Richmond.
Thomas shorn was not long in taking a prominent part in the life of
his community. This was not an easy thing to do in the face of the dangers
of those pioneer times, to say nothing of those hostile Indians in that
vicinity, which was near the home grounds of the once famous and powerful
Indian Chief, Powhatan, father of Pocohontas.
However, in 1631, Thomas Osborn was made a Justice.
Then in 1639 he was made a member of the House of Burgess, the govern-ing
body of the Colony of Virginia.
We have no records concerning his wife, only my memory that Howard Ronk
told me he married a Roseberry from England.
OSBORN
CHRONOLOGICAL SUMMARY
1. Thomas Osborn
Unknown
2. Not Recorded
Unknown
3. Thomas Osborn
Martha
U. John Osborn
Ann
B7
5. Thomas Osborn
Jane Patterson
6. Caleb Osborn
Susannah Jewell
7. Johnathan Osborn
Hannah Spinning
8. Harvey Osborn
Ann Campbell Reed
9. Sallie Ellen Osborn
Fountain Jeffries Henry
10. Nettle Ellen Henry
William Janes Rion
11.
EUen Ann Rion - Fount Henry Rion
S3
ADDENDA
In pursuing my desire to learn more about those who have, in the
recent centuries, done so much ,-braved such insurmountable difficulties,-
suffered so many defeats and achieved so many triumphs, that I - and so
many others might have more of life, liberty and happiness, - I have found
a deeper sense of appreciation and a greater desire to honor those who
have left to us this heritage, for to do so is a part of the greatness of
living.
I sincerely hope that my feeble efforts in securing and compiling these
few facts about those of our blood who lived through the perils of pioneer-ing
days, of Wars and pestilence, yet, have enjoyed much of peace and
contentment, -will engender in the hearts of those who read this, a deeper
sense of reverence and appreciation for them.
They have written in the book of life. Some of the pages are beauti-fully
soiled with the sweat of toil, some are pure white and many are
written in the blood of the Revolution, but all are honorable and plain
to see.
Today, each of us is a writer, each day we turn a new page in the
book titled "This is My life." All preceding pages are closed with the
fall of yesterday,-tomorrow is not yet ready for recording.
Each morning there lies before us a clean page on which to record
our deed3 of today.
May we now be builders for tomorrow, even as our forbears, that those
who follow us may have a richness of life not now foreseen, filled with
Spiritual strength in service to those who follow us, for,-"To live in
the hearts we leave behind is not to die."</dc:description>
<dc:description>A history of the author's family, most prominently the Osborns, Caldwells and Rions, the last of whom were Rutherford County residents</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Family history; Genealogy; Rutherford County (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Article</dc:format>
<dc:format>Paper</dc:format>
<dc:format>67 p.</dc:format>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Copyright protected</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>Publications of the Rutherford County Historical Society may be freely referenced and reproduced with proper attribution</dc:rights>
<dc:contributor>Rutherford County Historical Society</dc:contributor>
<dc:contributor>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University; Internet Archive</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ap2011-02-15</dc:date>
<dc:source>publication18ruth.pdf</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/rchs/id/135</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>