<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Dr. W. D. Dorris’ narrative of family history, Nashville, Tennessee, 1879 December 12</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <identifier>Dorris Narrative 001 - 075</identifier>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated encoding="edtf" keyDate="yes">uuuu</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <physicalDescription>
    <internetMediaType>image/jpeg</internetMediaType>
    <form>still image</form>
    <form>photocopy</form>
    <form>text</form>
  </physicalDescription>
  <location>
    <physicalLocation>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</physicalLocation>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/7374</url>
    <url access="preview">http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/nr/id/7374</url>
  </location>
  <abstract>A photocopy of a family history narrative written by Dr. William D. Dorris. The narrative chronicles early Nashville history, with biographical information about several families including Dorris, Menees, Naive, Whitsett, Nance, Frost families and others. He states: “My father, John Irwin Dorris, was born on the eastern shore of Maryland, October the 22nd, 1773. The Dorrises were Greeks. My father’s mother was a Scotch lady, Mary Griffin. My father was her first son. He came to Cumberland in 1790. He came to Nashville when but a few cabins and a blockhouse were there. It was called French Lick Station then.” The author states: “I, William Dawson Dorris, was born, according to the record in my father and mother’s Bible, Aug. 23rd, 1802, in Robertson County ....” Dr. Dorris studied medicine at Transylvania University in Lexington, Kentucky and graduated in 1834. He was in professional service until 1836 when he enlisted as a private in Capt. Grundy’s Company of State Guards which was put under Col. William Trousdale. Tenn. Infantry, 2nd Regiment, Tennessee. In addition to the Seminole War, Dr. Dorris also served in the Mexican War. He would continue his career as a physician in Nashville. Dr. Dorris was married to “Rebecca Shivers, February 1st, 1827, who was born on White’s Creek, Davidson County, Tenn., Jan. 9, 1810. She was the daughter of Jonas Shivers who was a Primitive Baptist Preacher. His wife’s maiden name was Elizabeth Fleming; their nationalities, Scotch-Irish and Welsh.” As a veteran of three wars, Dr. Dorris was featured in the April 23rd, 1888 Daily American newspaper, Nashville, with a survey of his distinguished career when a pension was granted to him for military service, stating that he was then in his 86th year and “is a veteran of three wars, having been surgeon of Campbell’s regiment in the Seminole war of 1836, in the Mexican war and in the late conflict between the States.” Dr. Dorris survived his wife’s death in 1881 by eleven years. The names of their ten children: Eliza Ann Dorris Wilson (1828-1904); John Irwin Dorris (1830-1848); Christiana Dorris Stewart (1832-1909); William Noah Dorris (1833-1847); Rebecca Dorris (1835-1849); Joseph Dorris (1837-1838); Alexander Osceola Dorris (1838-1891); Henry Harrison Dorris (1841-1913); Duncan Robertson Dorris (1843-1890); and Emeline Dorris Cooper (1846-1914). Dr. and Mrs. William D. Dorris are interred at Nashville City Cemetery. Forms part of Vertical Files, Family: W. D. Dorris narrative photocopies donated to Metro Nashville Archives by Betty Dorris Davis.</abstract>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Collection">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Vertical Files, Family: W. D. Dorris narrative photocopies</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <accessCondition type="local rights statement">U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</accessCondition>
  <subject>
    <topic>Dorris family</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Menees family</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Naive family</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Whitsett family</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Nance family</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Frost family</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Dawson family</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Veterans--Tennessee--History--Sources</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85112549">
    <topic>Religion</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Indians of North America</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Rutherford County--Tennessee--Genealogy</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Davidson County (Tenn.)--Genealogy</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Sumner County (Tenn.)--Genealogy</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>United States. Army--Surgeons</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Cumberland River (Ky. and Tenn.)--History--Sources</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Nashville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <temporal encoding="edtf">18uu</temporal>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <temporal encoding="edtf">19uu</temporal>
  </subject>
  <genre authority="aat" valueURI="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300264387">images (object genre)</genre>
  <genre authority="aat" valueURI="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300257688">copies (document genres)</genre>
  <genre authority="aat" valueURI="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300263751">texts (document genres)</genre>
  <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
  <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Project">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Nashville Public Library Digital Collection</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <location>
      <url>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/landingpage/collection/nr</url>
    </location>
  </relatedItem>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Nashville Public Library</recordContentSource>
    <recordChangeDate>2023-05-09-04:00</recordChangeDate>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
    <recordOrigin>Record has been transformed into MODS 3.5 from a qualified Dublin Core record by the Digital Library of Tennessee, a service hub of the Digital Public Library of America, using a stylesheet available at https://github.com/utkdigitalinitiatives/DLTN. Metadata originally created in a locally modified version of qualified Dublin Core using ContentDM (data dictionary available: https://wiki.lib.utk.edu/display/DPLA.)</recordOrigin>
  </recordInfo>
</mods>
