<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Photograph of the tombstone of Captain William M. Driver</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <identifier>P-4410</identifier>
  <name>
    <namePart>Hall, Kay (Photographer)</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/pht">Photographer</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated encoding="edtf" keyDate="yes">2000</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <physicalDescription>
    <internetMediaType>image/tiff</internetMediaType>
    <form>still image</form>
    <form>photographs</form>
  </physicalDescription>
  <location>
    <physicalLocation>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</physicalLocation>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/323</url>
    <url access="preview">http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/nr/id/323</url>
  </location>
  <abstract>A photograph of the tombstone of William Driver in Nashville City Cemetery, 2000. Driver is credited with nicknaming the American flag "Old Glory." A master mariner, on an 1831 voyage to the South Pacific aboard the 110-ton whaler Charles Doggett, he escorted sixty-five descendants of the Bounty survivors from Tahiti back to their home on Pitcairn Island. After leaving the sea in 1837, he moved to Nashville. Employed as a salesman for various Nashville businesses, he served as vestryman of Christ Episcopal Church. Every holiday, he displayed "Old Glory" outside his house by a rope extending from an upstairs room to a tree across the street. During the Civil War Driver remained loyal to the Union and sewed "Old Glory" into a quilt for safekeeping. When the Union army occupied Nashville, Driver gave the flag to the troops to be flown for a short time over the State Capitol. His tombstone consists of a ship's anchor leaning against a vine-covered tree. At his request, his rescue of the Pitcairn people was inscribed on his grave marker. One engraving on the tombstone reads: "A master mariner. Sailed twice around the world. Once around Australia. Removed the Pitcairn people from sickness and death in Tahieta to their own island home Sept. 3, 1831. Then 69 in number now 1200 souls." The second inscription reads: "William Driver Born in Salem Massachusetts March 17, 1803. Died in Nashville Tennessee March 3, 1886." The third inscription reads: "His Ship His Country and His Flag Old Glory." "Old Glory" has been exhibited at the Smithsonian Museum of American History in Washington, D.C. since 1922. Forms part of the Nashville Room Historic Photographs Collection. 1 photograph in matte frame : b &amp; w ; 8 x 10 in.</abstract>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Collection">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Nashville Room Historic Photographs Collection</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <accessCondition type="local rights statement">U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</accessCondition>
  <subject>
    <topic>Driver, William, 1803-1886--Monuments--Tennesse--Nashville</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Nashville City Cemetery</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Capital City</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Tombs and sepulchral monuments--Tennessee--Nashville</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Sepulchral monuments--Tennessee--Nashville</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <temporal encoding="edtf">2000/2009</temporal>
  </subject>
  <genre authority="aat" valueURI="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300264387">images (object genre)</genre>
  <genre authority="aat" valueURI="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300046300">photographs</genre>
  <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Project">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Nashville Public Library Digital Collection</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <location>
      <url>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/landingpage/collection/nr</url>
    </location>
  </relatedItem>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Nashville Public Library</recordContentSource>
    <recordChangeDate>2023-05-09-04:00</recordChangeDate>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
    <recordOrigin>Record has been transformed into MODS 3.5 from a qualified Dublin Core record by the Digital Library of Tennessee, a service hub of the Digital Public Library of America, using a stylesheet available at https://github.com/utkdigitalinitiatives/DLTN. Metadata originally created in a locally modified version of qualified Dublin Core using ContentDM (data dictionary available: https://wiki.lib.utk.edu/display/DPLA.)</recordOrigin>
  </recordInfo>
</mods>
