<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Program, Lily Pons with Frank La Forge, Ryman Auditorium, 1941 April 22</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <identifier>Wilhelmina Webb Ryman Aud Programs Lily Pons 001 - 015</identifier>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated encoding="edtf" keyDate="yes">1941-04-22</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <physicalDescription>
    <internetMediaType>image/jpeg</internetMediaType>
    <form>still image</form>
    <form>text</form>
  </physicalDescription>
  <location>
    <physicalLocation>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</physicalLocation>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/9003</url>
    <url access="preview">http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/nr/id/9003</url>
  </location>
  <language>
    <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
  </language>
  <abstract>A Ryman Auditorium concert program to a performance by the famous operatic soprano Lily Pons with pianist Frank La Forge. This concert was presented by the Nashville Metropolitan Opera Guild at the Ryman Auditorium, in Nashville, Tennessee on April 22nd, 1941. Lily Pons was a famous Metropolitan Opera star and at this concert performance, she was accompanied by Frank La Forge, renowned composer-pianist. Frank Versaci, Flutist, also performed in some of the pieces with flute obbligato. Three of the concert program songs were composed by Frank LaForge and dedicated to Miss Pons. Among the advertisers listed in the program are Ward-Belmont Conservatory; Strobels Music Shop; Nashville Metropolitan Opera Guild; Harris-Smith Chicken Farm, Morris Zager Importers, The Music Box, Town &amp; Country Shop, Eleanor Dubuisson Fossick, Uthmanor Shops, Pauline School of the Dance and Allied Arts, Rock City Mill &amp; Lumber Co., John W. McDougall Co., Camerata College of Music, McClure’s Dept. Store, Williams Market, M.P. Brothers Co., Phillips &amp; Buttorff Mfg. Co., Martin Hayes, 216 Dinner Club, Coca-Cola, Green Hills Market, Phil Harrison, Emma’s Flower Shop, Candyland, Grace’s, Union Ice Cream, Piggly Wiggly, Russell Motor Co., Acklen Park Pharmacy and College Pharmacy, Frank Coal Co. and Keith-Vaughn Coal Co., Model Hardware &amp; Plumbing, Harley-Holt Co., Nashville Community Playhouse, Nashville Surgical Supply Co, Wilson-Quick Pharmacy, Hermitage Laundry, Capitol Dry Goods, Young Roofing Co., Y. Albert Oriental Rug &amp; Carpet Co., Zager Tire Co., Calvert’s Photographs, and Spring Hill Cemetery &amp; Mausoleum. Also, the Committee members of the Metropolitan Opera Guild are listed in the program. The Executive Committee: Miss Anne Mae Kennedy, Miss Marjorie Cooney, Mrs. Henry Richardson, Mrs. Weaver Harris, Mrs. Cobb Pilcher, Mrs. Marguerite Shannon, Mrs. Francis Washington, Miss Sarah Armistead, Robert Strobel, Miss Mary Dorothy Cain. The Board of Directors: Mrs. T. Graham Hall, Mrs. O. C. Carmichael, Mrs. Rogers N. Herbert, Mrs. R. B. Bennett. The Concert Committees: Miss Anne Mae Kennedy, Mrs. Francis Washington, Mrs. T. Graham Hall, Mrs. W.P. Cooper, Mrs. O.C. Carmichael, Mrs. Jos. H. Thompson, Miss Sarah Armistead, Mrs. Vester Walker, Miss Margaret Lindsley Warden, Mrs. Henry Richardson, Mrs. Weaver Harris, Mrs. Cobb Pilcher, Mrs. Ed Hicks, Mrs. Jack DeWitt, Mrs. Ruby Turney Russell, Mrs. Tom Davidson, Mrs. John W. McDougall, Mrs. Eugene Stritch, Miss Anita Williams, Miss Florence Ryan, Miss Margaret Welsh, Miss Hulda Cheek, Miss Matilda Gibson, Mrs. R.B. Bennett, Miss Frances Sullivan, Miss Marjorie Cooney, Miss Mary Dorothy Cain, Mrs. Paul Sloan, Jr., Mrs. John W. McDougall, Mrs. Milton Smith Lewis, Mrs. Fowler Hollabaugh, Mrs. Lewis Meadors, Mrs. Marguerite Shannon, Miss Mildred Joy, Mrs. Ed Harris, Mrs. Rogers Smith, Mrs. T.G. Pollard, Mrs. Frank Fessey, Mrs. James D. Rhea, and Mrs. Ed Harris. The concert sponsors listed are: Metropolitan Opera Guild, Mr. Sam W. Berger, Jr., Mr. Howard Baughman, Dr. Joseph E. Burk, Mr. Edwin W. Craig, Mr. N.A. Crockett, Mrs. M.J. Cain, Miss Huldah Cheek, Mrs. O.C. Carmichael, Mr. C. Runcie Clements, Dr. Carl R. Crutchfield, Mr. Paul M. Davis, Mr. Silliman Evans, Mr. Frank M. Farris, Mr. Bernard Fensterwald, Miss Matilda Gibson, Mr. A.L. Hanover, Mr. Edward Potter, Jr., Mr. Domenick Petrucelli, Mr. Frank C. Stahlman, Mr. Alfred Starr, Mr. Milton Starr, Mr. Tony Sudekum, Dr. Robert E. Sullivan, Mr. Claude P. Street, Mr. Leonard Sisk, Mr. Robert Strobel, Mr. Joseph H. Thompson, Mr. Edwin Warner, Mr. William H. Wemyss, Mr. Albert Werthan, Miss Margaret Lindsley Warden, and Mr. J. Zanini. Forms part of the Wilhelmina Webb Collection. 1 illustrated program.</abstract>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Collection">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Wilhelmina Webb Collection</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <accessCondition type="local rights statement">U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</accessCondition>
  <subject>
    <topic>Pons, Lily, 1898-1976</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>La Forge, Frank, 1879-1953</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Versaci, Frank</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Ryman Auditorium (Nashville, Tenn.)</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Musicians</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Singers</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Performances--Tennessee--Nashville</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Performing arts--Tennessee--Nashville</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Entertainment--Tennessee--Nashville</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <temporal encoding="edtf">1940/1949</temporal>
  </subject>
  <genre authority="aat" valueURI="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300264387">images (object genre)</genre>
  <genre authority="aat" valueURI="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300263751">texts (document genres)</genre>
  <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
  <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Project">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Nashville Public Library Digital Collection</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <location>
      <url>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/landingpage/collection/nr</url>
    </location>
  </relatedItem>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Nashville Public Library</recordContentSource>
    <recordChangeDate>2023-05-09-04:00</recordChangeDate>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
    <recordOrigin>Record has been transformed into MODS 3.5 from a qualified Dublin Core record by the Digital Library of Tennessee, a service hub of the Digital Public Library of America, using a stylesheet available at https://github.com/utkdigitalinitiatives/DLTN. Metadata originally created in a locally modified version of qualified Dublin Core using ContentDM (data dictionary available: https://wiki.lib.utk.edu/display/DPLA.)</recordOrigin>
  </recordInfo>
</mods>
