<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Nashville City Market House 1935 - 1957</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <identifier>CDM 021</identifier>
  <name>
    <namePart>Wilbur F. Creighton</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/ctb">Contributor</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated encoding="edtf" keyDate="yes">1935/1957</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <physicalDescription>
    <internetMediaType>image/jpeg</internetMediaType>
    <form>photographs</form>
  </physicalDescription>
  <location>
    <physicalLocation>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</physicalLocation>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/93</url>
    <url access="preview">http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/nr/id/93</url>
  </location>
  <abstract>Property was acquired by the City of Nashville on the north side of the Public Square as a building site for a new City Market House in September of 1935. Plans for the new building were submitted by architect Henry C. Hibbs. Upon approval of Hibbs's design, the engineering firm Foster and Creighton was awarded the construction contract in the fall of 1935. (1) Demolition of existing buildings began the process of preparing the site for a new building. (2) The framework of the market house dome appears to be nearly complete in this October 1936 photograph. To the right of the dome, the construction of the new Davidson County Courthouse can be seen in this view. (3) With the building nearing completion, workers concentrate on the dome that sits atop the center of the structure. (4) An interior view looking north into the building, dated December of 1936, shows the concrete framework and exposed brick outer walls. (5) Just 3 months later, a northerly view shows the newly completed interior. (6) A similar view of the south end of the building shows the front, center entrance. (7) Market trucks and delivery vans are doubled-parked in the street in front of the market house, while several gentlemen linger near the entrance to the Market House Café located at the west end of the building. (8) An apron-wearing, market house employee stands near the front entrance in this ca. 1954 photograph. 8 x 10 in.</abstract>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Collection">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Wilbur F. Creighton Collection</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <accessCondition type="local rights statement">U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</accessCondition>
  <subject>
    <topic>Nashville City Market House</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>City government</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Capital City</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Nashville (Tenn.)</topic>
  </subject>
  <genre authority="aat" valueURI="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300046300">photographs</genre>
  <note>Donation</note>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Project">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Nashville Public Library Digital Collection</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <location>
      <url>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/landingpage/collection/nr</url>
    </location>
  </relatedItem>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Nashville Public Library</recordContentSource>
    <recordChangeDate>2023-05-09-04:00</recordChangeDate>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
    <recordOrigin>Record has been transformed into MODS 3.5 from a qualified Dublin Core record by the Digital Library of Tennessee, a service hub of the Digital Public Library of America, using a stylesheet available at https://github.com/utkdigitalinitiatives/DLTN. Metadata originally created in a locally modified version of qualified Dublin Core using ContentDM (data dictionary available: https://wiki.lib.utk.edu/display/DPLA.)</recordOrigin>
  </recordInfo>
</mods>
