<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Photograph of Rebecca Landers in Women's Army Auxiliary Corps uniform, 1943 May 26</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <identifier>VHP-WWII-Jennings</identifier>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated encoding="edtf" keyDate="yes">1943-05-26</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <physicalDescription>
    <internetMediaType>image/tiff</internetMediaType>
    <form>still image</form>
    <form>digital prints</form>
  </physicalDescription>
  <location>
    <physicalLocation>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</physicalLocation>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/352</url>
    <url access="preview">http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/nr/id/352</url>
  </location>
  <abstract>A studio portrait of Rebecca Landers in Women's Army Auxiliary Corps (WAAC) uniform, 26 May 1943. An inscription on the front of the photograph to her husband, Corris, reads: "Everlastingly your wife, Rebecca." A few months after this photograph was taken, the Women's Army Auxiliary Corps would become the Women's Army Corps (WAC), reflecting their change in status from a civilian auxiliary to members of the military. Rebecca (Bonham) Landers Jennings was born in Alabama, attended Tuskegee University, met and married her first husband, Corris, and joined the Women's Army Auxiliary Corps (later the Women's Army Corps) after her husband joined the army and was sent to Europe during World War II. After the war and their discharge from the armed forces, she and her husband used the GI Bill to attend Tennessee State University and Fisk University, where she obtained her bachelor's and master's degrees. She was widowed and remarried, and went on to pursue a career in education with the Nashville Public Schools where she taught for over 30 years. Forms part of the Veterans History Project. 1 digital print.</abstract>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Collection">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Veterans History Project collection, World War II series</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <accessCondition type="local rights statement">U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</accessCondition>
  <subject>
    <topic>Jennings, Rebecca Bonham Landers</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Landers, Corris</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>United States. Army. Women's Army Auxiliary Corps.</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>United States. Army. Women's Army Corps.</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85085207">
    <topic>Military history</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>World War II</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>War</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Veterans--Tennessee--History--Sources</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>World War, 1939-1945--Participation, female</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>World War, 1939-1945--Participation, African American</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Military personnel--Tennessee--Nashville</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Soldiers--Tennessee--Nashville</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <temporal encoding="edtf">1940/1949</temporal>
  </subject>
  <genre authority="aat" valueURI="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300264387">images (object genre)</genre>
  <genre authority="aat" valueURI="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300312222">digital prints</genre>
  <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Project">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Nashville Public Library Digital Collection</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <location>
      <url>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/landingpage/collection/nr</url>
    </location>
  </relatedItem>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Nashville Public Library</recordContentSource>
    <recordChangeDate>2023-05-09-04:00</recordChangeDate>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
    <recordOrigin>Record has been transformed into MODS 3.5 from a qualified Dublin Core record by the Digital Library of Tennessee, a service hub of the Digital Public Library of America, using a stylesheet available at https://github.com/utkdigitalinitiatives/DLTN. Metadata originally created in a locally modified version of qualified Dublin Core using ContentDM (data dictionary available: https://wiki.lib.utk.edu/display/DPLA.)</recordOrigin>
  </recordInfo>
</mods>
