<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Graduates of Columbia NYA Beauty Culture School, from the Nashville Times, 1940 March 01</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <identifier>ColumbiaBeautySchool--NT-1940</identifier>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated encoding="edtf" keyDate="yes">1940</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <physicalDescription>
    <internetMediaType>image/jpeg</internetMediaType>
    <form>still image</form>
    <form>text</form>
  </physicalDescription>
  <location>
    <physicalLocation>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</physicalLocation>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4259</url>
    <url access="preview">http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/nr/id/4259</url>
  </location>
  <language>
    <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
  </language>
  <abstract>A captioned photo from the Nashville Times (1940), about graduates in the beauty culture school in Columbia, Tennessee. The caption reads: “Columbia, Tenn., March 1 (Spl.) Students of the NYA girls school here, which reopened at the historic Columbia Institute buildings in January of 1939, are looking forward with interest to Saturday. It is on that day the first class of this school to graduate in beauty culture, which is a major subject, will got to Nashville to take the state examinations before the State Board of Cosmotology Saturday. In the NYA school there are 102 girls, from all parts of the state. Back row, left to right, Kathryn Hulin, Coley Wright, Thelma Kirk, Mable Wilson, Dora Alsup, Hettie Noles, Irene Esson, Viola Williams, Hazle Crabtree, Jewell Robison, Fairisee Weatherington. Front row, left to right, Mary Ellen Raulston, Era Scott, Elizabeth Puckett, Marjorie Burkheart, Miss Dezzie Eason (teacher) Pauline McDonald, Lorene Bradford, Nina Lou Gray and Mable Knight.” National Youth Administration (NYA) was established by executive order on 26 June 1935 as a division of the Works Progress Administration. The student work program eventually helped more than 2 million students find jobs. The agency was almost completely decentralized, with many of the projects being administered by states and communities. Forms part of the Nashville Times newspaper collection. 1 digital photo.</abstract>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Collection">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Nashville Times Newspaper Collection</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <accessCondition type="local rights statement">U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</accessCondition>
  <subject>
    <topic>United States. National Youth Administration of Tennessee--History--Sources</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>United States. National Youth Administration--History--Sources</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Beauty operators--Tennessee--Columbia</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Occupations--Tennessee--Columbia</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Political science--History--Sources</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Education--Tennessee, Middle--History--Sources</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Columbia (Tenn.)--History--Sources</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Columbia (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Maury County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <temporal encoding="edtf">1940/1949</temporal>
  </subject>
  <genre authority="aat" valueURI="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300264387">images (object genre)</genre>
  <genre authority="aat" valueURI="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300263751">texts (document genres)</genre>
  <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
  <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Project">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Nashville Public Library Digital Collection</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <location>
      <url>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/landingpage/collection/nr</url>
    </location>
  </relatedItem>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Nashville Public Library</recordContentSource>
    <recordChangeDate>2023-05-09-04:00</recordChangeDate>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
    <recordOrigin>Record has been transformed into MODS 3.5 from a qualified Dublin Core record by the Digital Library of Tennessee, a service hub of the Digital Public Library of America, using a stylesheet available at https://github.com/utkdigitalinitiatives/DLTN. Metadata originally created in a locally modified version of qualified Dublin Core using ContentDM (data dictionary available: https://wiki.lib.utk.edu/display/DPLA.)</recordOrigin>
  </recordInfo>
</mods>
