<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Faculty of Main Street School, Nashville, Tennessee, 1892</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <identifier>ClementsColl GeoDetriusClements f2 school012</identifier>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated encoding="edtf" keyDate="yes">1892</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <physicalDescription>
    <internetMediaType>image/jpeg</internetMediaType>
    <form>still image</form>
    <form>negatives</form>
  </physicalDescription>
  <location>
    <physicalLocation>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</physicalLocation>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/6371</url>
    <url access="preview">http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/nr/id/6371</url>
  </location>
  <abstract>A group photo of the faculty of Main Street School located in Nashville, Tennessee. The Annual Report of the Superintendent lists the names and positions of teachers at Main Street School for session 1891-92: Mr. M. M. Ross, Principal; Mr. George D. Clements, Eighth Grade; Miss Jennie H. Frensley, Seventh Grade; Miss Ada Butler, Sixth and seventh grades; Miss Josie Schott, Sixth Grade; Miss Naomi Shea; Fifth grade; Miss Ella R. Walsh, Fifth Grade; Miss Maggie Handly, Fourth and fifth grades; Miss Zadie I. Geiger, Fourth Grade; Miss Hattie R. Cotton, Principal second floor; Miss Mary E. Pope, Fourth Grade; Miss Maggie Gallagher, Third Grade; Miss Emma E. Moulton, Third Grade; Miss Bessie Sutherland, First and third grades (organist); Miss Mary Matthews, First and second grades; and Miss Lena Wilson, First and second grades. Educators specifically identified by name in this photo are: Principal M. M. Ross (seated center) and George Demetrius Clements (standing on the extreme right). Main Street School was erected by the corporation of Edgefield at Seventh and Main circa 1870, and it became a city school when Edgefield was annexed to Nashville. It was used until 1894, when the original Warner school was erected and the Main Street School building was razed. Forms part of George Paul Clements, Jr. Collection. 1 photographic copy print.</abstract>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Collection">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>George Paul Clements, Jr. Collection</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <accessCondition type="local rights statement">U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</accessCondition>
  <subject>
    <topic>Clements family</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Clements, George D., 1843-1930</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Ross, M. M.</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Education--Tennessee--Nashville</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Educators--Tennessee--Nashville</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Teachers--Tennessee--Nashville</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Elementary school principals--Tennessee--Nashville</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Elementary schools--Tennessee--Nashville</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <temporal encoding="edtf">1890/1899</temporal>
  </subject>
  <genre authority="aat" valueURI="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300264387">images (object genre)</genre>
  <genre authority="aat" valueURI="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300127173">negatives (photographic)</genre>
  <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Project">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Nashville Public Library Digital Collection</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <location>
      <url>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/landingpage/collection/nr</url>
    </location>
  </relatedItem>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Nashville Public Library</recordContentSource>
    <recordChangeDate>2023-05-09-04:00</recordChangeDate>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
    <recordOrigin>Record has been transformed into MODS 3.5 from a qualified Dublin Core record by the Digital Library of Tennessee, a service hub of the Digital Public Library of America, using a stylesheet available at https://github.com/utkdigitalinitiatives/DLTN. Metadata originally created in a locally modified version of qualified Dublin Core using ContentDM (data dictionary available: https://wiki.lib.utk.edu/display/DPLA.)</recordOrigin>
  </recordInfo>
</mods>
