<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Alex Green Elementary School, Nashville, Tennessee, 1981 March</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <identifier>Harris Slides 564 Alex Green School Mar81</identifier>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated encoding="edtf" keyDate="yes">1981-03</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <physicalDescription>
    <internetMediaType>image/jpeg</internetMediaType>
    <form>still image</form>
    <form>negatives</form>
  </physicalDescription>
  <location>
    <physicalLocation>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</physicalLocation>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/7190</url>
    <url access="preview">http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/nr/id/7190</url>
  </location>
  <abstract>An exterior view of Alex Green Elementary School, located at 4020 Whites Creek Pike, Nashville, Tennessee, circa March 1981. The first school in the Whites Creek community was held in a building called Temperance Hall, on the ground now occupied by the Alex Green Church parsonage. The first school house was built in the late 1800s on property owned by Mr. Tim Manlove. In 1887 the county bought the property and changed the name to Alex Green Academy in honor of Miss Julia Green’s grandfather, the late Rev. Alexander Little Page Green, an eminent Methodist minister and a prominent landowner in the community. About 1913 the two-room building was remodeled and two more rooms were added to the front. In 1922 the school became a high school and remained so for three years. In 1936 the old frame building was replaced by a modern brick building with four classrooms. The enrollment was enlarged by absorbing two one-teacher schools, Weaver School on Whites Creek Pike and Buena Vista School on Buena Vista Pike. In 1952 the cafeteria, kitchen and two-classrooms were added, then subsequently eight portable classroom structures. Forms part of the Claynita Harris Slide Collection. The original is a 35 mm color transparency (2 x 2 in. slide mount)</abstract>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Collection">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Claynita Harris Slide Collection</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <accessCondition type="local rights statement">U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</accessCondition>
  <subject>
    <topic>Alex Green Elementary School (Nashville, Tenn.)</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Architecture--Tennessee--Goodlettsville</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Buildings--Tennessee-- Nashville</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Elementary schools--Tennessee--Nashville</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Whites Creek Pike (Nashville, Tenn.)</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <temporal encoding="edtf">1980/1989</temporal>
  </subject>
  <genre authority="aat" valueURI="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300264387">images (object genre)</genre>
  <genre authority="aat" valueURI="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300127173">negatives (photographic)</genre>
  <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Project">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Nashville Public Library Digital Collection</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <location>
      <url>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/landingpage/collection/nr</url>
    </location>
  </relatedItem>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Nashville Public Library</recordContentSource>
    <recordChangeDate>2023-05-09-04:00</recordChangeDate>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
    <recordOrigin>Record has been transformed into MODS 3.5 from a qualified Dublin Core record by the Digital Library of Tennessee, a service hub of the Digital Public Library of America, using a stylesheet available at https://github.com/utkdigitalinitiatives/DLTN. Metadata originally created in a locally modified version of qualified Dublin Core using ContentDM (data dictionary available: https://wiki.lib.utk.edu/display/DPLA.)</recordOrigin>
  </recordInfo>
</mods>
