<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Code, Property of Davidson County Highway Commission, Effective October 1, 1960</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <identifier>Highway Commision Code Property of 1960</identifier>
  <name>
    <namePart>George W. Himes (Donor)</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/dnr">Donor</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated encoding="edtf" keyDate="yes">1960-10</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <physicalDescription>
    <internetMediaType>image/jpeg</internetMediaType>
    <form>still image</form>
    <form>text</form>
  </physicalDescription>
  <location>
    <physicalLocation>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</physicalLocation>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/10335</url>
    <url access="preview">http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/nr/id/10335</url>
  </location>
  <language>
    <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
  </language>
  <abstract>A book of property code related to the Davidson County Highway Commission, with the effective date of October 1, 1960. The listed officials are Wm. C. (Al) Greer, Chairman; Herbert Jones, Commissioner; W. E. Pilkerton, Commissioner; Hue T. Ammerman, Secretary; W.D. Lamb, Engineer; and Wm. W. Turner, Superintendent. The preface reads: “By authority of Chapter 519 of the Private Acts of the General Assembly of State of Tennessee, 1927, the Davidson County Road Commission of three members who have charge of the building, reconstruction, repairs, maintenance and supervision of the highways, bridges, and ferries of said County, and the management and control of the workhouse and working of county prisoners, and among other things are charged with the responsibility of keeping a full and accurate detail report of all moneys received by the Board and a detailed cost system for all new construction, reconstruction, repairs, maintenance and operations. By said act this detail is placed upon the Secretary of said Commission and in order to perform this duty this code is promulgated for the use of all employees of said Commission whose duty it is to certify to the pay rolls, use of materials, equipment, etc., of said Commission. This code has been made as simple as it is possible to do with the view that any employee may understand and be able to use it accurately to give the information and results desired. Cost keeping should start with the first survey on Highway work and be a comprehensive continuous record, by distinct features to completion of construction, maintenance cost records are then started and continue from year to year. Proper cost records are nothing more or less than historical facts, which if intelligently compiled form a base on which the history of the project is built. When entered into with the proper spirit and a system of accounting which makes possible definite and effective results, construction cost keeping becomes a most fascinating study. The object of the above comments is to encourage the study of this book, instead of simply reading it. The arrangement of the book and much labor in its compilation has been with the hope that the employee whose duty it is to use this information will study it so an accurate record of every transaction or expenditure may be made. Check your projects, do not trust your memory.” Forms part of the published collection: Code, Property of Davidson County Highway Commission. 1 book.</abstract>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Collection">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Davidson County Highway Commission Code Property</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <accessCondition type="local rights statement">U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</accessCondition>
  <subject>
    <topic>Greer, William C.</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Jones, Herbert</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Pilkerton, W.E.</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Ammerman, Hue T.</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Lamb, W.D.</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Turner, William W.</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Roads--Tennessee--Nashville and Davidson County</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Urban transportation--Tennessee--Nashville and Davidson County</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <temporal encoding="edtf">1960/1969</temporal>
  </subject>
  <genre authority="aat" valueURI="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300264387">images (object genre)</genre>
  <genre authority="aat" valueURI="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300263751">texts (document genres)</genre>
  <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
  <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Project">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Nashville Public Library Digital Collection</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <location>
      <url>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/landingpage/collection/nr</url>
    </location>
  </relatedItem>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Nashville Public Library</recordContentSource>
    <recordChangeDate>2023-05-09-04:00</recordChangeDate>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
    <recordOrigin>Record has been transformed into MODS 3.5 from a qualified Dublin Core record by the Digital Library of Tennessee, a service hub of the Digital Public Library of America, using a stylesheet available at https://github.com/utkdigitalinitiatives/DLTN. Metadata originally created in a locally modified version of qualified Dublin Core using ContentDM (data dictionary available: https://wiki.lib.utk.edu/display/DPLA.)</recordOrigin>
  </recordInfo>
</mods>
