<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>To a swell fellow in the service!, circa 1943</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <identifier>VHP-WWII-O'connor-f14,swell fellow card</identifier>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated encoding="edtf" keyDate="yes">1943~</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <physicalDescription>
    <internetMediaType>image/tiff</internetMediaType>
    <form>text</form>
    <form>documents</form>
    <form>cards</form>
  </physicalDescription>
  <location>
    <physicalLocation>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.</physicalLocation>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/483</url>
    <url access="preview">http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/nr/id/483</url>
  </location>
  <abstract>Greeting card from Susie Agee, Edward O'Connor's sister, sent to him sometime during World War II. She writes a personal note to "Bud" on the back of the card, telling Edward that her husband, Malcolm, "really did enjoy reading about all those awful sounding guns," but she continues: "I guess you got a kick out of it, didn't you." Edward received many of these types of greeting cards from his family during his time in the service. Edward E. O'Connor Jr. was born on Jan. 14, 1915 in Nashville to Edward Earl O'Connor and his wife, Kate. He attended Jere Baxter and Isaac Litton schools in Nashville, and married Loraine Erwin, daughter of Mr. and Mrs. Martin P. Erwin of Santa Fe, Tenn. on June 9, 1940 at City Road Chapel Methodist Church in Madison, Tenn. Edward E. O'Connor, Jr., a native Nashvillian, went into the Army Air Corps early in 1943 and was sent overseas early in 1944. He served as a ball turret gunner aboard the B-24 "Hubba Hubba" with the 415th Bombardment Squadron of the 98th Bombardment Group (Heavy), stationed in North Africa and Italy. According to a government telegram, he was shot down over Austria on Palm Sunday, April 2, 1944; however, Ed always told his family he was shot down over Yugoslavia. He returned to American lines with the help of Tito's partisans. He had been missing in action for 30 days. He soon returned to the U.S. where he continued his military service as a gunnery school instructor. He was discharged in Oct. 1945. Forms part of the Veterans History Project. 1 greeting card.</abstract>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Collection">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Veterans History Project collection, World War II series, Edward E. O'Connor Jr. papers</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <accessCondition type="local rights statement">U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</accessCondition>
  <subject>
    <topic>O'Connor, Edward E., 1915-1992</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Agee, Susie (Mrs. Malcolm)</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85085207">
    <topic>Military history</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>World War II</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>War</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Veterans--Tennessee--History--Sources</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Greeting cards--United States</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>World War, 1939-1945--Caricatures and cartoons</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>World War, 1939-1945--Social aspects</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Soldiers--Correspondence</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Soldiers--Tennessee--Nashville</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Military personnel--American--Tennessee--Nashville</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Military service--United States</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Soldiers--American--Tennessee--Nashville</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <temporal encoding="edtf">1940/1949</temporal>
  </subject>
  <genre authority="aat" valueURI="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300263751">texts (document genres)</genre>
  <genre authority="aat" valueURI="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300026030">documents</genre>
  <genre authority="aat" valueURI="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300026756">cards (information artifacts)</genre>
  <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Project">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Nashville Public Library Digital Collection</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <location>
      <url>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/landingpage/collection/nr</url>
    </location>
  </relatedItem>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Nashville Public Library</recordContentSource>
    <recordChangeDate>2023-05-09-04:00</recordChangeDate>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
    <recordOrigin>Record has been transformed into MODS 3.5 from a qualified Dublin Core record by the Digital Library of Tennessee, a service hub of the Digital Public Library of America, using a stylesheet available at https://github.com/utkdigitalinitiatives/DLTN. Metadata originally created in a locally modified version of qualified Dublin Core using ContentDM (data dictionary available: https://wiki.lib.utk.edu/display/DPLA.)</recordOrigin>
  </recordInfo>
</mods>
