<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>The Fifth Stanza of The Song of the Night Writers, Watkins Institute, 1969</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <identifier>Betty Hadley Coll Song of the Night Writers Watkins</identifier>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated encoding="edtf" keyDate="yes">1969</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <physicalDescription>
    <internetMediaType>image/jpeg</internetMediaType>
    <form>still image</form>
    <form>text</form>
  </physicalDescription>
  <location>
    <physicalLocation>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</physicalLocation>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/11422</url>
    <url access="preview">http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/nr/id/11422</url>
  </location>
  <language>
    <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
  </language>
  <abstract>“The Fifth Stanza of The Song of the Night Writers” is a publication by “The Night Writers” of Watkins Institute in 1969. According to the preface by Professor Alfred L. Crabb, “we herewith offer to our public the 1969 issue of our various and varied ‘songs.’ We are not professional writers ….But all of us have a deep and demanding interest in Nashville or hereabouts. That interest we have put on these pages with such skill and art as we could summon in the hope of adding to your understanding of several parts and phases of our city. These pages are our low bow to one of the earth’s choice places.” Dr. Alfred L. Crabb was an esteemed Professor of Education at Peabody College in Nashville and was the author of many novels about Tennessee, especially about the Civil War. The booklet includes these essays: A Summer Scene, A Winter Home (A History of Ridgetop) by Mary Louise Derseweh -- A Biographical Sketch of Mrs. James K. Polk by Mrs. Felix Treadway -- Chicago and Nashville: Personalities of Two Cities by Mrs. Jo Ann Swanson -- Progress in Education by Mrs. Lois Meguiar Hadley -- This is Du Pont, Better Things Because of Textiles by Mrs. Marie Nunley -- Nashville’s Most Spectacular Disaster by Reda Goff -- Ashland City, Yesterday and Today by Mrs. Martha Morris -- Charlotte Reeves Robertson by Mrs. Margaret Ikenberry -- The Staff of Life, Tennessee Style by Ruth Truett -- John Wesley Work III (1901-1967) by Charlotte Coffey -- Nashville’s Children Museum, Sketched in Rhyme by Josephine Bambach -- Dr. John Todd Edgar, A Great Preacher by Mrs. Ruth Douglass Darby -- George Dury, Portrait Painter, 34 Union by Mrs. Carolyn Carver -- May There Aways be a Cumberland by Mrs. Ruth M. Witt -- A Certain Stubborness by Ann Magruder -- Lucy Gage, A Dynamic Teacher by Nona Sparks -- Reverend James Whitsitt, Pioneer Preacher by Amelia Whitsitt Edwards -- The Fountain of Health by Robert L. Martin -- Nashville, My Adopted Home by Edna Lewis -- “A History Written in Tears, but Radiant with Glory” by Lucile K. McDonald -- A Walk Down Unknown Trails by John Stroud -- The Various Beginnings of the Carnegie Library -- Recipe for a City Called Nashville by Ella Mae Harris. Forms part of the Betty Hadley Collection.</abstract>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Collection">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Betty Hadley Collection</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <accessCondition type="local rights statement">U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</accessCondition>
  <subject>
    <topic>Crabb, Alfred Leland, 1884-1979</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Watkins Institute (Nashville, Tenn.)</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Education--Tennessee--Nashville</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Urban life--Tennessee--Nashville</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Manners and customs--Tennessee--Nashville</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Nashville (Tenn.)--Intellectual life</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <temporal encoding="edtf">1960/1969</temporal>
  </subject>
  <genre authority="aat" valueURI="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300264387">images (object genre)</genre>
  <genre authority="aat" valueURI="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300263751">texts (document genres)</genre>
  <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
  <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Project">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Nashville Public Library Digital Collection</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <location>
      <url>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/landingpage/collection/nr</url>
    </location>
  </relatedItem>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Nashville Public Library</recordContentSource>
    <recordChangeDate>2023-05-09-04:00</recordChangeDate>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
    <recordOrigin>Record has been transformed into MODS 3.5 from a qualified Dublin Core record by the Digital Library of Tennessee, a service hub of the Digital Public Library of America, using a stylesheet available at https://github.com/utkdigitalinitiatives/DLTN. Metadata originally created in a locally modified version of qualified Dublin Core using ContentDM (data dictionary available: https://wiki.lib.utk.edu/display/DPLA.)</recordOrigin>
  </recordInfo>
</mods>
