<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Maps (2) of Rhea County, Tennessee, showing civil districts (1836)</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/">No Copyright - United States</accessCondition>
   <location>
      <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://teva.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll23/id/8862</url>
      <url access="preview">http://teva.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p15138coll23/id/8862</url>
   </location>
   <abstract>Hand-drawn maps (one linen) of Rhea County, Tennessee show the civil districts laid out in 1836. It names rivers, creeks, certain roads, and county lines. Civil districts were also election precincts, and the map(s) show polling places--usually residences, but in one district a schoolhouse--where voting would take place within the district. Polling places include, in addition to the schoolhouse, Jones's, Whaley's, Hill's, Dyer's, Thompson's, and Paul's residences, and the city of Washington. Other important early locations in Rhea County are denoted, such as: Hornsby's Ferry, McKiddy's, Hoodenpyle's, Kelley's Ferry, West's Mill, Garwood's, and Mitchel's Spring.</abstract>
   <abstract>These 1836 county maps showing the new civil districts, required by the new state constitution, written in 1834 and ratified the following year, which mandated such civil divisions for taxation purposes, were done for many counties. Rhea County was formed in 1807 from Roane County, and was split to form Meigs County in 1836. It is named for Revolutionary War veteran and Tennessee statesman, John Rhea. The county seat and largest city is Dayton, originally called Smith's Crossroads. It was renamed in 1877 after the city of Dayton, Ohio. Dayton was the stage for the famous Scopes Trial in 1925. Washington, shown on the map, was the most important city in Rhea County until the Cincinnati Southern Railway was laid out four miles west of it in 1880.</abstract>
   <originInfo>
      <dateCreated>1836</dateCreated>
   </originInfo>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordContentSource>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</recordContentSource>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <subject>
      <topic>Rhea County (Tenn.)--Maps</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic/>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Maps</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Rivers</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Streams</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Roads</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Boundaries</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Schools</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <geographic>Rhea County (Tenn.)</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <geographic>Map 1196</geographic>
   </subject>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>TSLA Map Collection</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Tennessee State Library and Archives</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>950740468</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Map 1196</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form>Maps</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
</mods>
