<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Map showing the Mexico City Campaign during the Mexican War (1847)</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/">No Copyright - United States</accessCondition>
   <location>
      <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://teva.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll23/id/422</url>
      <url access="preview">http://teva.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p15138coll23/id/422</url>
   </location>
   <name>
      <namePart>McClellan, John</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cre">Creator</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <abstract>Extremely detailed map showing Gen. Winfield Scott's Mexico City campaign during the Mexican War, Aug.-Sept. 1847. It outlines Mexican and American troop dispositions and movements during the three major battles around Mexico City: Contreras, Churubusco, and Molino del Rey (the fortress at Chapultepec). It details the topography and nineteenth century road system around the Mexican capital, city grids, forts, roads, canals, and geographic features such as rivers, lakes, and the "Pedregal or field of lava" near Contreras over which attacking American troops moved. The upper right and left hand corners show the number of casualties in each of the battles at the end of this campaign.</abstract>
   <abstract>On March 9, 1847, American troops performed their first major amphibious operation, landing 12,000 men, supplies, weapons, and horses at Veracruz, Mexico. After the 12-day siege of the city, the Mexicans surrendered. Scott's troops continued their campaign toward Mexico City and met Mexican troops under General Santa Anna entrenched near Cerro Gordo. After a decisive victory, the Americans marched on to Puebla, who surrendered without resistance. After the Battles of Contreras, Churubusco, Molino del Rey, and Chapultepec, Santa Anna withdrew to Guadalupe Hidalgo. After a 5 month guerilla campaign, the war ended there with the signing of the Treaty of Guadalupe Hidalgo on February 2, 1848. The treaty ceded California, Nevada, Utah, and parts of New Mexico, Arizona, Texas, Oklahoma, Kansas, Wyoming, and Colorado to the United States for $15 million. Many generals in the Civil War participated in the Mexican War, specifically the Mexico City campaign including: Robert E. Lee, George Meade, Ulysses S. Grant, James Longstreet, Thomas "Stonewall" Jackson, Gideon J. Pillow, Joseph E. Johnston, Sterling Price, George B. McClellan, Daniel H. Hill, and George Pickett. Future Tennessee governor William Trousdale served as a Colonel in this campaign.</abstract>
   <originInfo>
      <dateCreated>1847</dateCreated>
   </originInfo>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordContentSource>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</recordContentSource>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <subject>
      <topic>Mexican War, 1846-1848</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Mexico</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>United States. Army</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Maps</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Campaigns</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <geographic>Mexico</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <geographic>Washington (D.C.)</geographic>
   </subject>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>TSLA Map Collection</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Tennessee State Library and Archives</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>40400448</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Map 690</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form>Maps</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
</mods>
