<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Highway map of Tennessee showing the construction progress during 8 year period 1918-1926, on federal and state aid roads</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/">Copyright Not Evaluated</accessCondition>
   <location>
      <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://teva.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll23/id/9968</url>
      <url access="preview">http://teva.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p15138coll23/id/9968</url>
   </location>
   <abstract>Distributed by Austin Peay Campaign Committee, this highway map of Tennessee shows the progress made in highway construction during the administration of Gov. Austin Peay. The red lines show the work contracted by the Peay administration while the green lines show the work contracted by all former administrations. The text indicates that this map was used by the Austin Peay Campaign Committee during the 1926 governor's race. Peay won the race but died shortly after beginning his third term in 1927.</abstract>
   <abstract>Gov. Peay was instrumental in expanding Tennessee's highway system. During his administration, state highways expanded from 244 miles to over 4,000 miles. The Tennessee State Highway Department was created in 1915 to oversee both publicly and privately funded highways. The earliest highway maps were created by physically driving roads and using specialized instruments to measure distance, gradient, altitude, and mapping each particular road. They often consulted the United States Geological Survey maps and worked in tandem with them to keep one another's maps current, often using transparent sheets to make corrections or additions. The State Highway Department was renamed the Tennessee Department of Transportation in 1972.</abstract>
   <originInfo>
      <dateCreated>1926</dateCreated>
   </originInfo>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordContentSource>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</recordContentSource>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <subject>
      <topic>Tennessee--Roads--Maps</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Peay, Austin, 1876-1927</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Maps</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Roads</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Travel</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Political campaigns</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <geographic>Tennessee</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <geographic>Nashville (Tenn.)</geographic>
   </subject>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>TSLA Map Collection</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Tennessee State Library and Archives</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Map 2221</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form>Maps</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
</mods>
