<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Surveys of John Walker Jr. and Elizabeth Lowry land in Marion County, Tennessee and Cherokee territory (1820)</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/">No Copyright - United States</accessCondition>
   <location>
      <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://teva.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll23/id/851</url>
      <url access="preview">http://teva.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p15138coll23/id/851</url>
   </location>
   <abstract>Two surveys of 640 acre 'reservations' are included in this document. Such tracts were granted to tribal heads of families "residing within the ceded territory" of land in southeastern Tennessee, conveyed by the Cherokee to the United States by the 1819 treaty. The first is of Elizabeth Lowry's (Lowery) land (640 acres) on the north side of the Tennessee River in Marion County, incl. her dwelling house. The second is of John Walker Jr.'s land (640 acres) on the north side of the Tennessee River in Cherokee territory, incl. his dwelling house and ferry. This plat is accompanied by a letter to Col. Return J. Meigs, the Cherokee agent, stating his residency. A third, text-only survey for Elizabeth "Betsey" Pack is included.</abstract>
   <abstract>John Walker Jr.'s father, John Walker Sr., was half Cherokee, a friend of Andrew Jackson by virtue of fighting under him during the Creek Wars, including Horseshoe Bend, and grandson of Nancy Ward. John Walker Jr. was the son of John Walker Sr. and Elizabeth Lowery. He married Emily Stanfield Meigs, Col. Return J. Meigs grand-daughter, and Nannie Bushyhead, sister of Reverend Jesse Bushyhead. Walker was eventually shot and killed by men who opposed letting the Cherokee remain in Tennessee and parts of Georgia.</abstract>
   <originInfo>
      <dateCreated>1820</dateCreated>
   </originInfo>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordContentSource>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</recordContentSource>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <subject>
      <topic>United States. Office of Indian Affairs. Cherokee Agency, East</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Cherokee Indians--Land tenure</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Maps</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Surveying</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Rivers</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic/>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <geographic>Marion County (Tenn.) McMinn County (Tenn.)</geographic>
   </subject>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Coile, Grace Armstrong Collection of Robert Armstrong Papers 1790-1930</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>THS 889</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Tennessee Historical Society</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>THS-II-J-4, B.19, F.3</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form>Maps</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
</mods>
