<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Proposed Tennessee location for superconducting supercollider (SSC)</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/">Copyright Not Evaluated</accessCondition>
   <location>
      <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://teva.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll23/id/10388</url>
      <url access="preview">http://teva.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p15138coll23/id/10388</url>
   </location>
   <abstract>Map of the proposed Tennessee location for the Superconducting Supercollider, a massive particle accelerator. Geologists suggested parts of Rutherford, Williamson, Bedford, and Marshall counties to contain the collider, that would have been 53 miles in circumference. Rivers, creeks, roads, towns and county boundaries are all denoted.</abstract>
   <abstract>In 1987, President Ronald Reagan directed the Department of Energy to request proposals from states to construct a Superconducting Super Collider. The Super Collider was a particle collider designed to smash together subatomic particles to simulate the conditions during the Big Bang. The collider was planned to be a massive oval-shaped tube with a 10 foot wide tunnel, 53 miles in circumference and 14 miles in diameter. Of the 25 states that submitted site proposals, 8 finalists were selected, including Tennessee. The project was estimated to run between $4.4 and $11.8 billion dollars, which included the collider itself, above ground offices, laboratories, and supporting buildings. Ultimately Texas's proposal won out, and construction began in 1993. Cost overruns and political positioning doomed the project and by 1994 the project ended after over $2 billion was already spent. (National Museum of American History Archives, Administrative Note on Superconducting Super Collider Collection) From Department of Economic and Community Development publication.</abstract>
   <originInfo>
      <dateCreated>1988</dateCreated>
   </originInfo>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordContentSource>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</recordContentSource>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <subject>
      <topic>Superconducting Super Collider</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Particle accelerators</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Bosons</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Nuclear counters</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Maps</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Geology</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Roads</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Streams</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Rivers</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Boundaries</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Science</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Physics</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <geographic>Tennessee</geographic>
   </subject>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>TSLA Map Collection</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Tennessee State Library and Archives</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Map 2034</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form>Maps</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
</mods>
