<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Tennessee and portions of bordering states (showing Cherokee and Chickasaw treaty cessions)</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/">No Copyright - United States</accessCondition>
   <location>
      <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://teva.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll23/id/9055</url>
      <url access="preview">http://teva.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p15138coll23/id/9055</url>
   </location>
   <abstract>Map of Cherokee and Chickasaw land cessions in Tennessee, Kentucky, North Carolina, Georgia, and Alabama, overlaid on a contemporary map of the region, published in the 18th Annual Report of the Bureau of American Ethnology to the Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution. In addition to the 1890s towns, historical sites such as forts, military encampments, public houses, white settlements, Native American villages, and historical roads are shown.</abstract>
   <abstract>The are shaded gray in Middle Tennessee and numbered 3 was ceded by the Cherokee on November 28, 1785, known as the Treaty of Hopewell. This land was set off by North Carolina for military reservations. The area shaded blue in East Tennessee and into North Carolina designated number 8 was ceded by the Cherokee on July 2, 1791, known as the Treaty of Holston and negotiated by William Blount. The area shaded yellow and numbered 57 was ceded by the Cherokee on October 25, 1805, known as one of the Treaties of Tellico. The area shaded red and designated 64 was ceded by the Cherokee on January 7, 1806, known as the Treaty of Washington.The large orange parcel numbered 100 was ceded by the Chickasaw on October 19, 1818 and is known as both the Chickasaw Purchase and the Jackson Purchase.</abstract>
   <originInfo>
      <dateCreated>1897</dateCreated>
   </originInfo>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordContentSource>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</recordContentSource>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <subject>
      <topic>Maps</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <geographic>Tennessee</geographic>
   </subject>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>TSLA Map Collection</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Tennessee State Library and Archives</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Map 509</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form>Maps</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
</mods>
