<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Parts of Tennessee and Alabama (showing Chickasaw treaty cessions)</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/">No Copyright - United States</accessCondition>
   <location>
      <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://teva.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll23/id/9053</url>
      <url access="preview">http://teva.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p15138coll23/id/9053</url>
   </location>
   <abstract>Map of Chickasaw land cessions in Tennessee and Alabama, overlaid on a contemporary map of the area, published in the 18th Annual Report of the Bureau of American Ethnology to the Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution. In addition to the contemporary 1890s towns, historical features such as forted stations (e.g. Ziegler's Station and Bledsoe's Lick), public houses, white settlements, and Native American villages (e.g. Crow Town, Chickasaw Old Fields), and historical roads (e.g. General Jackson's Military Road, Georgia or Federal Road) are shown.</abstract>
   <abstract>The area shaded in blue designated with the number 55 represents the land ceded by the Chickasaw on July 23, 1805. The land shaded in orange and numbered 80 was ceded by the Chickasaw on September 20, 1816. The area in green and numbered 81 was apart of the September 20, 1816 treaty but was a reservation for Col. George Colbert and his heirs. The large red parcel numbered 100 was ceded by the Chickasaw on October 19, 1818 and is known as both the Chickasaw Purchase and the Jackson Purchase. The small sliver of land shaded yellow was ceded by the Chickasaw on October 20, 1832, and was the last cession east of the Mississippi for the tribe. It was made later than the earlier cession due to the mistake made by James Winchester when surveying the southern boundary line.</abstract>
   <originInfo>
      <dateCreated>1897</dateCreated>
   </originInfo>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordContentSource>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</recordContentSource>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <subject>
      <topic>Maps</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <geographic>Tennessee; Alabama; Mississippi; Kentucky</geographic>
   </subject>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Serials</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Tennessee State Library and Archives</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>E51 .U55 18th pt.2 c.1 1896/97 (Books)</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form>Maps</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
</mods>
