<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Plot of rebel fortifications made 1861 at Mill Springs Ky. encamped by Felix K. Zollicoffer Brig. Gen. Comdg. C.S. Vol.</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/">No Copyright - United States</accessCondition>
   <location>
      <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://teva.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll23/id/8928</url>
      <url access="preview">http://teva.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p15138coll23/id/8928</url>
   </location>
   <abstract>Hand-drawn map of Mill Springs, Kentucky made during the Civil War and showing the disposition of Confederate units. The map shows the Cumberland River, Monticello Road, S[o]merset Road, and Confederate fortifications. The town of Mill Springs and Robertsport are stylized and details of Robertsport include the grocery and a clothing store. The title ""Plat of Rebel Fortifications"" suggests the map was drawn by a Union witness.</abstract>
   <abstract>The Battle of Mill Springs (or Fishing Creek, as it was sometimes known) took place on January 19, 1862 and was a complete Union victory. Brigadier General Felix K. Zollicoffer led Major General Crittendon's first brigade to fortify the Cumberland Gap in September 1861. By November, Zollicoffer had moved his troops into Kentucky and established a fortified position on the Cumberland River. On the morning of January 19, Zollicoffer and his men--many of whom were armed with old flintlock muskets, which would not fire in the rain--launched an attack on the Union troops, commanded by Brigadier General George H. Thomas. With poor visibility due to darkness, smoke, and his own myopia, Zollicoffer, in his white raincoat, led the vanguard and mistakenly approached enemy troops. He was mortally wounded, becoming the first Confederate general to die in the West. After his death, his soldiers panicked and fled the battle.</abstract>
   <originInfo>
      <dateCreated>1861</dateCreated>
   </originInfo>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordContentSource>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</recordContentSource>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <subject>
      <topic>United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Mill Springs, Battle of, Ky., 1862</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Zollicoffer, Felix Kirk, 1812-1862</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Maps</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Forts &amp; fortifications</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Roads</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Campaigns &amp; battles</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <geographic>Mill Springs (Ky.)</geographic>
   </subject>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>TSLA Map Collection</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Tennessee State Library and Archives</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>953413579</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Map 2542</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form>Maps</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
</mods>
