<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Plat Map of Santa Fe, Tennessee showing the Erwin-Fitzgerald dispute (1873)</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/">No Copyright - United States</accessCondition>
   <location>
      <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://teva.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll23/id/417</url>
      <url access="preview">http://teva.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p15138coll23/id/417</url>
   </location>
   <abstract>Plat map of downtown Santa Fe, Tennessee showing the locations of each party in the homicide of Ped Fitzgerald by William T. Erwin. The map, possibly an exhibit in the trial, indicates details of the murder scene and locations and names of other buildings surrounding the public square.</abstract>
   <abstract>"Our village was the scene of a very sad and exciting affair last Saturday evening, the particulars of which, as near as we can learn them, being as follows: Mr. Will T. Erwin and Lew Adkinson had a trial before Esq. Sparkman during which, Roan Erwin and Lew Adkinson got into a fight, Adkinson being very much bruised in the face with a piece of iron in the hands of Erwin. A short time after, a dispute arose in the street between Ped Fitzgerald and Roan Erwin, when Will T. Erwin stepped up and told Fitzgerald to dry up, who immediately took up a large rock and threw at Erwin, who dodged, and drawing his pistol, fired, the ball striking Fitzgerald in the left breast, near the heart, and passed through and out at the right side of the back. Fitzgerald spoke but once and fell dead. Erwin was arrested after a short struggle, by P. C. Gray who was near at the time. Had Erwin's pistol fired for him the second time, Gray would also have been a corpse, but an overruling Providence prevented the double tragedy. Erwin was tried before Esq. John T. Sparkman and admitted to bail in the sum of $3,500, J. L. Williams, F. B. Craige, and C. S. Erwin as bondsmen. Fitzgerald leaves a wife and six small children, and a widowed mother. Too much whisky was the cause of this sad affair. 'Tis very strange that our country cannot afford temperance men enough to give us some kind of law to prevent such foul deeds. Cursed alcohol! Will its ravages never grow less? It makes so many poor widows and orphans, and all classes feel its plagues." -The Columbia Herald (Columbia, Tenn.) May 30, 1873</abstract>
   <originInfo>
      <dateCreated>1873</dateCreated>
   </originInfo>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordContentSource>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</recordContentSource>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <subject>
      <topic>Plats</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Homicide</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Tennessee. Supreme Court</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Maps</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Newspaper headlines</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Journalism</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Homicides</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <geographic>Maury County (Tenn.)</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <geographic>35.73507</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <geographic>-87.12806</geographic>
   </subject>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Fussell, Joseph H. (1836-1915) Papers, 1809-1921</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>232</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Tennessee State Library and Archives</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>XII-G-4, B.1 , F.3</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form>Drawings</form>
      <form>Maps</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
</mods>
