<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Map of Jackson County, Tennessee showing civil districts (1836)</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/">No Copyright - United States</accessCondition>
   <location>
      <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://teva.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll23/id/8828</url>
      <url access="preview">http://teva.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p15138coll23/id/8828</url>
   </location>
   <abstract>Map of Jackson County from 1836 showing the first civil districts of the county. It shows a very detailed view of the waterways in the county, naming each river, creek, branch, and fork of the Cumberland River. Civil districts are drawn in faded red ink along with each district number. Each dotted line represents a road that serves as a district line, each are named as well, including the famous and important Walton Road. The center for holding elections in each district are represented as squares and denoted as "center." A legend is available in the bottom right and the scale is explained at the top. Written descriptions of the civil district boundaries are appended to the map.</abstract>
   <abstract>These 1836 county maps showing the new civil districts, required by the new state constitution, written in 1834 and ratified the following year, which mandated such civil divisions for taxation purposes, were done for many counties. Jackson County was established by the Tennessee General Assembly in 1801 from part of Smith County and Native American lands. It is named for Andrew Jackson, at the time a Tennessee Supreme Court Justice and former U.S. Senator and Representative. Its county seat and largest city is Gainesboro, named for General Edmund Pendleton Gaines, a hero of the War of 1812.</abstract>
   <originInfo>
      <dateCreated>1836</dateCreated>
   </originInfo>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordContentSource>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</recordContentSource>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <subject>
      <topic>Jackson County (Tenn.)--Maps</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic/>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Maps</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Boundaries</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <geographic>Jackson County (Tenn.)</geographic>
   </subject>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>TSLA Map Collection</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Tennessee State Library and Archives</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>945694622</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Map 1100</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form>Maps</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
</mods>
