<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Battle of Brandywine in which the rebels were defeated, September the 11th. 1777, by the army under the command of General Sr. Willm. Howe</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/">No Copyright - United States</accessCondition>
   <location>
      <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://teva.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll23/id/9009</url>
      <url access="preview">http://teva.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p15138coll23/id/9009</url>
   </location>
   <name>
      <namePart>Werner, S. W.</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cre">Creator</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <abstract>A 1778 London-published map showing the Revolutionary War Battle of Brandywine, a debacle for Gen. Washington and the American cause which led directly to the loss of Philadelphia and the hard winter quarters at Valley Forge. Indicates troop postion and movement throughout the day-long battle. Hand-colored troop designations are as follows: Americans (Rebels) in gold, British in red, and Hessians and Anspachers in blue. Roads, rivers, headquarters,the Birmingham Meeting house, and the town of Dilworth are all denoted. Relief shown by hachures. Ferguson's riflemen are specifically designated.</abstract>
   <abstract>The Battle of Brandywine took place on September 11, 1777, and was the largest battle of the Revolutionary War. General George Washington and approximately 14,600 troops stood in the way of General William Howe and Philadelphia. Under cover of fog, Lieut. Gen. Knyphausen led a feinting maneuver at Chadds Ford while the bulk of Howe's forces, led by Gen. Cornwallis, attacked Washington's right flank. Washington was severely outmaneuvered by this advance on his right as most of his troops were defending the ford. Maj. Gen. John Sullivan was sent to meet Cornwallis, while Brig. Gen Anthony Wayne covered Knyphausen's advance. Washington and Nathanael Greene arrived later in the day to reinforce Sullivan but the damage was done. The Americans suffered 1300 casualties, while the British sustained just under 600. Washington retreated to Philadelphia and the Continental Congress was forced to flee the city. This battle put Washington under severe scrutiny for his failures, and shortly after the fall of Philadelphia on September 26, 1777, the Conway Cabal attempted to relieve him of command. The Continental Army spent the winter of 1777-1778 at Valley Forge.</abstract>
   <originInfo>
      <dateCreated>1778</dateCreated>
   </originInfo>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordContentSource>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</recordContentSource>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <subject>
      <topic>Brandywine, Battle of, Pa., 1777</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Brandywine Creek (Pa. and Del." Brandywine Battlefield Park (Pa." Brandywine, Battle of, Pa., 1777--Maps--Early works to 1800</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Maps</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Campaigns &amp; battles</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Forts &amp; fortifications</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <geographic>Brandywine Creek (Pa. and Del.)</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <geographic>London (England)</geographic>
   </subject>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>THS Map Collection</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>784</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Tennessee Historical Society</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>5565193</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>THS 53</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form>Maps</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
</mods>
