<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Route of the Memphis-Nashville-Bristol highway (1911)</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/">No Copyright - United States</accessCondition>
   <location>
      <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://teva.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll23/id/53</url>
      <url access="preview">http://teva.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p15138coll23/id/53</url>
   </location>
   <abstract>Map showing the proposed route of the Memphis-Nashville-Bristol Highway to be constructed 1911-1913. The map shows all the counties of Tennessee with their county seats, as well as the major railroads through Tennessee. There are advertisements bordering the map that show photographs of various road-building equipment. On the reverse is an open letter from the Wilson, Ingram and Company addressed to Mr. Good Road Builder, State of Tennessee, suggesting that Austin-Western Road Machinery be used.</abstract>
   <abstract>The construction of the Memphis to Bristol Highway offered citizens, businesses, and tourists a means to effectively cross the state and offered the opportunity to unify more closely the three grand divisions. The good roads improvement movement had arisen in the 1890s with the support of the railroads, the farm alliances, and the bicyclists, and it had widespread public approval across the state. When motorized vehicles came onto the scene at the turn of the 19th century, they provided travel competition to railroads and steamboats and spawned the creation of local auto clubs and the Tennessee Good Roads Association. The Association threw its support behind the construction of an all-weather Memphis to Bristol highway. The building of the Memphis to Bristol Highway encouraged the undertaking of additional state road-building projects and encouraged Virginia and Mississippi to extend the highway. Local businessmen had formed the Memphis to Bristol Highway Association in 1911 to promote this 500-mile long highway. In 1926, two-thirds of the route was designated as U. S. 70, the major east-west corridor in the region. In the late 1920s the entire route became part of the Broadway of America Highway from California to New York.</abstract>
   <originInfo>
      <dateCreated>1911</dateCreated>
   </originInfo>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordContentSource>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</recordContentSource>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <subject>
      <topic>Roads--Tennessee--Maps</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Road machinery industry</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Metal culverts</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Maps</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Roads</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Road construction</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Machinery</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Construction equipment</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Machinery industry</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Graders (Earthmoving machinery)</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Road rollers</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Plows</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Carts &amp; wagons</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <geographic>Tennessee</geographic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <geographic>Nashville (Tenn.)</geographic>
   </subject>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>TSLA Map Collection</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Tennessee State Library and Archives</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>957558404</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Map 2217</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form>Maps</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
</mods>
