<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Siege of Vera Cruz by the U. S. troops under Major General Scott, in March 1847</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <accessCondition type="use and reproduction" xlink:href="http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/">No Copyright - United States</accessCondition>
   <location>
      <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://teva.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll23/id/9078</url>
      <url access="preview">http://teva.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p15138coll23/id/9078</url>
   </location>
   <abstract>Map of the siege of Vera Cruz during the Mexican-American War. Vera Cruz, and its surrounding forts, is shown with roads leading to and from the town. The amphibious landing location is noted, as is the troop positions of the various divisions led by Worth, Twigg, and Patterson. The headquarters of each general are noted as are the depots, batteries, and entrenchments. Naval guns were taken off the American ships and used to reduce Mexican positions. The 1st and 2nd regiments of Tennessee Volunteers were engaged on the center-right of the American's ""line of investment."" A small table containing casualty numbers is located in the bottom right. Presented by Major Adolphus Heiman [presumably to the Tennessee Historical Society], May 4, 1858.</abstract>
   <abstract>On March 9, 1847, American troops performed their first major amphibious operation, landing 12,000 men, supplies, weapons, and horses at Vera Cruz, Mexico. After the 12-day siege of the city, the Mexicans surrendered. Scott's troops continued their campaign toward Mexico City and met Mexican troops under General Santa Anna entrenched near Cerro Gordo. After a decisive victory, the Americans marched on to Puebla, who surrendered without resistance. After the Battles of Contreras, Churubusco, Molino del Rey, and Chapultepec, Santa Anna withdrew to Guadalupe Hidalgo. After a 5 month guerilla campaign, the war ended there with the signing of the Treaty of Guadalupe Hidalgo on February 2, 1848. The treaty ceded California, Nevada, Utah, and parts of New Mexico, Arizona, Texas, Oklahoma, Kansas, Wyoming, and Colorado to the United States for $15 million. Many generals in the Civil War participated in the Mexican War, specifically the Mexico City campaign including: Robert E. Lee, George Meade, Ulysses S. Grant, James Longstreet, Thomas ""Stonewall"" Jackson, Gideon J. Pillow, Joseph E. Johnston, Sterling Price, George B. McClellan, Daniel H. Hill, and George Pickett. Future Tennessee governor William Trousdale served as a Colonel in this campaign.</abstract>
   <originInfo>
      <dateCreated>1847</dateCreated>
   </originInfo>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordContentSource>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</recordContentSource>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
   </recordInfo>
   <subject>
      <topic>Mexican War, 1846-1848--Campaigns--Maps</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Veracruz (Veracruz-Llave, Mexico)--Maps</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Maps</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Campaigns</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Forts &amp; fortifications</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Roads</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Troop movements</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Trench warfare</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <topic>Military headquarters</topic>
   </subject>
   <subject>
      <geographic>Veracruz (Veracruz-Llave, Mexico)</geographic>
   </subject>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>THS Map Collection</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>15</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Tennessee Historical Society</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>44145740</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>THS 55</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <physicalDescription>
      <form>Maps</form>
   </physicalDescription>
   <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
</mods>
