<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Correspondence from Mary Guthrie Latta to Samuel R. Ratta, December 18, 1861</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <identifier>34133</identifier>
  <name>
    <namePart>Latta, Mary Guthrie (1833-1920)</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cre">Creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated encoding="edtf" keyDate="yes">1861-12-18</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <physicalDescription>
    <internetMediaType>image/tiff</internetMediaType>
  </physicalDescription>
  <location>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll1/id/204</url>
    <url access="preview">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p15138coll1/id/204</url>
    <url note="iiif-manifest">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/iiif/info/p15138coll1/204/manifest.json</url>
    <physicalLocation>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</physicalLocation>
  </location>
  <subject>
    <topic>Civil War in the West</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Civil War society</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>United States - History - 1783-1865</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>United States - History - 1849-1877</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>United States History - Civil War, 1861-1865</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85026421">
    <topic>Civil war</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>War</topic>
  </subject>
  <abstract>Four-page letter from Mary Guthrie Latta to her husband, Samuel, conveys her anxiety at not hearing from him and her disappointment both in his defeat for promotion to Lt. Colonel and in his inability to come home for Christmas. She also relates news of the family and household affairs. It seems Samuel plans to coach Mary to write a letter of appeal to Brigadier General Gideon J. Pillow that might get Samuel sent home--possibly through a plea of hardship.</abstract>
  <accessCondition type="local rights statement">While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use.</accessCondition>
  <subject>
    <geographic>Dyersburg (Tenn.)</geographic>
  </subject>
  <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
  <abstract>[Page 1] “some good. I [missing] written by return mail. &amp; though not so long or so interesting as yours, I have written about all I know at present. &amp; I know it possessed one charm for me. It will bring an answer &amp; I hope a speedy one. M. G. Latta Dyersburg Tenn Dec. 18 61 My dear husband – I had began to be dreadfully anxious to hear from. &amp; had almost concluded to write you a second letter, when I received yours of the 18th by last Monday’s mail. You have never been so long writing before, &amp; did not know what to think of it. Never dreaming you were indulging in a feeling of pique [?] because I had not written sooner when you know you can’t possibly be as anxious to hear from me as I am from you. Don’t do so any more or I shall have to scold you &amp; you know I am a second Han [?] tippe for scolding. Be thankful I am that I have those dear little children for you to think about so much as only to find consolation in writing. As well indeed as they are my only consolation in separation from you. Kate” [Page 2] “was very sick all last week. But is now entirely well &amp; as mischievous as ever. But more of a baby, as I am always obliged to spoil them when they are sick. Johnny is quite well. Mary dabs him with salt water every morning. &amp; so strong is his faith in virtue he thinks it is making him a man as fast as any thing could do. He has got as far as “baker”: &amp; is so proud of it that he told me I must tell you when I wrote. &amp; I expect Pa will be equally proud to hear it. I am glad to hear you have your winter quarters up &amp; I know I shall enjoy your nice log cabin as much as you will. For instead of picturing you, sitting by an open fire exposed to all the inclemency’s of weather I can now have the satisfaction of knowing you are secure from the cold, the wind &amp; rain. &amp; if I could be equally sure that you were safe from the Lincolnites, I would be satisfied. I suppose it is hardly worth while for me to condole with you about your” [Page 3] “defeat for Lt. Col for if you do not care for it I am sure I don’t. I think your position is a very good one, &amp; I have no higher ambition for you than that you discharge your duties in that position to the satisfaction of all. - &amp; to have you at home again, that is worth all the honors in the world. Though I cannot but feel surprised, that men of any judgment or sense at all, would prefer any one else to you. For I do not know that when you have it in your power, you are arbitrary &amp; tyrannical, but just the best &amp; dearest man in the world. Though it is your wife that says it. I almost felt like crying when you gave me so little encouragement to look for you Christmas. Like yourself I do not want you to come home without a furlough. For I think is a bad example for a Capt. to set. &amp; the men are practicing it to much already for the good of the army. About the letters you are to dictate &amp; I to copy, send it &amp; whenever you like. I am willing to do anything to get you home.” [Page 4] “though I do feel a little delicacy in going to Gen. Pillow about my private affairs. I suppose you will not thank me for my letter if you again neglect to give you particulars of home. John has moved to the country. &amp; is beginning to realize how hard the farmers have to work. LC. &amp; Berry have been hauling in his corn this week. I expect he will begin to think that being a man of family is not as easy a life as single blessedness. For it is work all day &amp; nurse the baby at night. We killed our hogs &amp; beef on Monday last. &amp; received the pork from Mrs. Foulkes two weeks ago. The weather has been so warm that I am in constant dread of losing it. We have bought no more corn since you left. I think if you could get a good price for Brownlow you had better sell him. We have to keep him in the stable all the time. He has got so foolish father is afraid either to drive or ride him, &amp; I shall not have any use for him in some time. &amp; until you return he is likely to be of very little service. &amp; you had better get mad again, you see it does”</abstract>
  <abstract>1990-198</abstract>
  <abstract>84</abstract>
  <abstract>http://state.tn.us/tsla/history/manuscripts/findingaids/90-198.pdf</abstract>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Collection">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Samuel Rankin Latta Papers, 1848-1862</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Project">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Civilian Life in the Civil War</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <abstract>The items in this collection offer new perspectives into the lives of numerous non-combatants during the Civil War in Tennessee and throughout the southeast.  The correspondence and primary writings touch on several themes relating to the home front, including the diverse roles of women, the relationship between occupying/invading forces and civilians, personal beliefs regarding secession and the war, and the effect of the war on African American Tennesseans.  These sources can offer the public a lens into the lives of many Civil War non-combatant men and women, a subject of increasing importance in Civil War scholarship...</abstract>
    <location>
      <url>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/landingpage/collection/p15138coll1</url>
    </location>
  </relatedItem>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Tennessee State Library and Archives</recordContentSource>
    <recordChangeDate>2023-05-12-04:00</recordChangeDate>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
    <recordOrigin>Record has been transformed into MODS 3.5 from a qualified Dublin Core record by the Digital Library of Tennessee, a service hub of the Digital Public Library of America, using a stylesheet available at https://github.com/utkdigitalinitiatives/DLTN. Metadata originally created in a locally modified version of qualified Dublin Core using ContentDM (data dictionary available: https://wiki.lib.utk.edu/display/DPLA.)</recordOrigin>
  </recordInfo>
</mods>
