<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Correspondence from Joseph Gerald Branch to Mary Jones (Polk) Branch, March 16, 1864</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <identifier>34132</identifier>
  <name>
    <namePart>Branch, Joseph Gerald, 1817-1867</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cre">Creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated encoding="edtf" keyDate="yes">1864-03-16</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <physicalDescription>
    <internetMediaType>image/tiff</internetMediaType>
  </physicalDescription>
  <location>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll1/id/169</url>
    <url access="preview">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p15138coll1/id/169</url>
    <url note="iiif-manifest">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/iiif/info/p15138coll1/169/manifest.json</url>
    <physicalLocation>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</physicalLocation>
  </location>
  <subject>
    <topic>Civil War in the West</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Civil War society</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>United States - History - 1783-1865</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>United States - History - 1849-1877</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>United States History - Civil War, 1861-1865</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85026421">
    <topic>Civil war</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>War</topic>
  </subject>
  <abstract>Letter from Joseph Gerald Branch in Davis Lake Plantation, Arkansas, to his wife, Mary, in Maury County, Tennessee. He is concerned that his letters are not reaching her, and he observes, "What is property or anything else compared to one's family?" He has not heard "one word" from her and would be relieved to hear some news. Branch complains that life has been hard and disagreeable for him. In all, the letter conveys his loneliness and anxiety during the time of war.</abstract>
  <accessCondition type="local rights statement">While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use.</accessCondition>
  <subject>
    <geographic>Desha County (Ark.)</geographic>
  </subject>
  <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
  <abstract>[Page 1] “Davis Lake – March 16th 1864 My Dear Sweet Wife: - I have written you several letters and sent them to Memphis to be mailed to you at Columbia, care of Mr. Houston Nashville – but I do not know that any of them have ever reached you – I do not know whether this will ever reach you, but I will write a few lines hoping perchance it may- I have not heard one word from you or Columbia since I left there – A heavy cloud of the thickest blackness seem to hang between us, impervious to every ray of communication – It almost drives me mad – I cannot and will not stand it much longer - What is property on anything else compared to one’s family? If I could only get one word that you were well &amp; happy &amp; that my children were also well, it would be the greatest relief to me – This long &amp; awful silence overpowers me with doubt, uncertainty and the deepest anxiety – Have you received my letters? If you have could you not send a letter to Memphis for me to – care of Pickett or Mr. C. DeLoach – Either would send it to me as there is frequent passing between here &amp; Memphis – If in no other way could you not send some one specially to bring it? – If I do not hear from you in a short time, you” [Page 2] “will see me regardless of consequences – I have succeeded in employing Mr. Arnold to take charge of this place and the negroes, I think, will remain here – not one has left as yet and they work some, or perhaps tolerably well under the circumstances – I am preparing to plant a crop both of corn and cotton on both pieces and if let alone by the Confederates expect to make 350 or 400 Bales of cotton – Early last November I made arrangements with a man named Shepard to send you and Mr. Martin ample funds and to write you – He has however failed to send you the money and I am now trying to make another arrangement with Mr. Hudson to let him have the cotton if he will send you &amp; Mr. Martin the money – I have directed him to deposit it with Mr. W. S. Pickett of Memphis – If he complies &amp; he sends you the money invest it in a residence or home for yourself – If your mother will sell her place buy it – I prefer it to any other – If she will sell tell her she can keep it so long as she lives or desires – have the Will made out to you &amp; your children – Since I left you my life has been exceedingly hard &amp; disagreeable – full of troubles &amp; anxieties – “ [Page 3] “The negroes have behaved so well that I feel that I ought to be happier and more thankful – But to be isolated, cutoff from every so social enjoyment, and not know which moment every thing around me may be destroyed by Jay hawkers on one side or the other – To be in constant dread of every thing, has nearly harrassed my life out of me – I am here between the two armies with only the bad &amp; ricious, left in the neighborhood – Who generally are ready to aid &amp; assist the soldiers in any wicked or mean thieving or robbing [expeditions?] – I have not yet been molested personally, but i have been jay hawked in way of stock until I am used to it – My purse nor my watch have been yet demanded but I do not know at what moment day or night they may be – Why has not Mrs. Martin written me? – I do not know whether her papers have ever been sent to Genl Sheets at Little Rock – My thoughts constantly run on you and your situation and you approaching troubles – Oh darhling! My heart longs to be with you when that time comes be firm, patient &amp; courageous – Recollect to be “a hen in the strife” – If the lord spares you, we will” [Page 4] “be together in a short time thereafter at any rate – for either I will go to you or you shall come to me – As soon as I can fix up the business here on a safe basis I will leave and then you will hear from me wherever I may go and you can join me in visiting sister or Lainy’s family – If I can do so (and you can judge) I will visit Columbia – How would that suit you? Write me your views that I may act understandingly. – I do hope my boys are going to school and improving their opportunities – Tell them nothing will please me more than to find they study and improve themselves – Give my love to them &amp; Mrs Martin’s family – Has my daughter &amp; my little Lawrence forgotten they have a father – kiss them for me – Give my love and best love to your Mother &amp; Pet – Tell the old lady I often wish I could be with her – I have not seen or heard from Cad – In conclusion do try to get a letter to me – Send it to Memphis to care of some friend to be sent to Mr. Hudson or George Sexton [?] on Arkansas River for me – They go to the Gun boat at mouth of White River every day – James &amp; family are here &amp; well. Your truly Devoted &amp; sincere: Husband: - Joseph Branch: -”</abstract>
  <abstract>91-169</abstract>
  <abstract>1336</abstract>
  <abstract>http://state.tn.us/tsla/history/manuscripts/findingaids/91-169.pdf</abstract>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Collection">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Gerald Branch Howard Papers, 1770-1973</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Project">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Civilian Life in the Civil War</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <abstract>The items in this collection offer new perspectives into the lives of numerous non-combatants during the Civil War in Tennessee and throughout the southeast.  The correspondence and primary writings touch on several themes relating to the home front, including the diverse roles of women, the relationship between occupying/invading forces and civilians, personal beliefs regarding secession and the war, and the effect of the war on African American Tennesseans.  These sources can offer the public a lens into the lives of many Civil War non-combatant men and women, a subject of increasing importance in Civil War scholarship...</abstract>
    <location>
      <url>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/landingpage/collection/p15138coll1</url>
    </location>
  </relatedItem>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Tennessee State Library and Archives</recordContentSource>
    <recordChangeDate>2023-05-12-04:00</recordChangeDate>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
    <recordOrigin>Record has been transformed into MODS 3.5 from a qualified Dublin Core record by the Digital Library of Tennessee, a service hub of the Digital Public Library of America, using a stylesheet available at https://github.com/utkdigitalinitiatives/DLTN. Metadata originally created in a locally modified version of qualified Dublin Core using ContentDM (data dictionary available: https://wiki.lib.utk.edu/display/DPLA.)</recordOrigin>
  </recordInfo>
</mods>
