<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Correspondence from Mary Dedman to Tommie Williams, March 13, 1865</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <identifier>34079</identifier>
  <name>
    <namePart>Dedman, Mary</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cre">Creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated encoding="edtf" keyDate="yes">1865-03-13</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <physicalDescription>
    <internetMediaType>image/tiff</internetMediaType>
  </physicalDescription>
  <location>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll1/id/84</url>
    <url access="preview">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p15138coll1/id/84</url>
    <url note="iiif-manifest">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/iiif/info/p15138coll1/84/manifest.json</url>
    <physicalLocation>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</physicalLocation>
  </location>
  <subject>
    <topic>Civil War in the West</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Civil War society</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>United States - History - 1783-1865</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>United States - History - 1849-1877</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>United States History - Civil War, 1861-1865</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Social values</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Domestic life</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Soldiers</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Military life</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Military personnel</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Military organizations</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Armies</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>War</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Cities &amp; towns</topic>
  </subject>
  <abstract>Letter from Mary Dedman of Selma, Alabama, to Tommie Williams. She gives details of the day of fasting and prayer, and prays for peace with liberty.</abstract>
  <accessCondition type="local rights statement">While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use.</accessCondition>
  <subject>
    <geographic>Selma (Ala.)</geographic>
  </subject>
  <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
  <abstract>“Selma March 13th, 1865 Dear Tommie I received your letter several days ago. While out at Jane’s, and would have answered it immediately, but had no writing material out there with me. Consequently had to defer writing until I came home. I received three other letters the same day I received yours, but was very much disappointed that among them was not one from my dear husband. I fear if you had witnessed the disappointment expressed by my countenance, you would have thought that your letter was not receiving a very cordial reception; but not so. I was as happy to receive it and it afforded me as much pleasure as a letter from any other person, save my husband, could have done. When I tell you that it is now more than a month since I heard from him I know you will not blame me for feeling disappointed that I did not receive a letter from his also. I was sorry to hear that you had been sick, hope you will not have the misfortune to be sick again. At least in the State of Georgia, as the people there are so little disposed to accommodate soldiers. I am glad that you and Billie succeeded in overtaking the wagons, but I think it will be some time before you reach the other portion of your command. If it is, as I suppose in front of Sherman. It is rumored that we now have Sherman in a close place and will probably capture him. But we have so many rumors that we do not know when to consider them reliable. An attack on Mobile is now threatened. There are twenty four vessels inside the bay and in sight of the city. Our authorities seem to be confidant of their ability to hold the city. God grant that they may be. For if they capture Mobile they can very easily come to Selma in their Gunboats while the river is so high. There are many inducements for them to come to this place. Among others, the release of the Yankee prisoners who are now here. We have a large number of them here. They were brought from Cahaba, in consequence of their prison being submerged with the water from the Ala. River. Before our authorities could succeed in getting boats to bring them off, the water rose several feet in the prison and they were necessarily compelled to stand in it until the Boats could come to their relief. There were several boats lying at the wharf, but they could get no wood as the freshet had washed away all the wood on the river. When this news reaches the North, I fear they will use it as a pretext for inflicting some additional cruelties on our prisoners. Many families in Selma fared as badly as they did. A great portion of East Selma was submerged and the families had to evacuate their houses. Last Friday was observed here by a majority of the people as a day of fasting and prayer, and I hope was so observed throughout the Confederacy. I have great faith in the efficacy of prayer and I believe God will hear and answer the prayers of His people and grant us peace with liberty and independence. It is rumored that two other Commissioners, Singleton and Hughes, have been sent from Washington to Richmond. I do not know the object of their mission. If it is to negotiate a peace, God grant that they may be successful. Has Willie recovered from the spell of enchantment which the Georgia young lady threw over him? She must have been very attractive or Willie very susceptible, to have been made such an easy conquest of. Did matters progress as far with them as they did with you and the sentimental young lady from whom you received that famous letter? Tommie I am “taking it for granted” that you are sincere when you say you do not object to long letters and am stretching this to a pretty good length. You flatter me, though, when you say you trust to gather some ideas from a correspondence with me. I am but a plain, matter of fact letter writer and do not profess to be capable of interesting those in whom I am not myself interested. Having for you the affection of a relative, I expect to write to you as such and wish I were capable of writing such letters as would be both beneficial and instructive to you. Lori says she will answer your letter in a few days. I hope to hear from both you and Willie again soon. All join me in love to you, and Bettie sends you a kiss. Write soon. Yours affectionately Mary A. Dedman”</abstract>
  <abstract>60-342</abstract>
  <abstract>1303</abstract>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Collection">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Hamilton-Williams Family Papers, 1850-1971</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Project">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Civilian Life in the Civil War</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <abstract>The items in this collection offer new perspectives into the lives of numerous non-combatants during the Civil War in Tennessee and throughout the southeast.  The correspondence and primary writings touch on several themes relating to the home front, including the diverse roles of women, the relationship between occupying/invading forces and civilians, personal beliefs regarding secession and the war, and the effect of the war on African American Tennesseans.  These sources can offer the public a lens into the lives of many Civil War non-combatant men and women, a subject of increasing importance in Civil War scholarship...</abstract>
    <location>
      <url>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/landingpage/collection/p15138coll1</url>
    </location>
  </relatedItem>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Tennessee State Library and Archives</recordContentSource>
    <recordChangeDate>2023-05-12-04:00</recordChangeDate>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
    <recordOrigin>Record has been transformed into MODS 3.5 from a qualified Dublin Core record by the Digital Library of Tennessee, a service hub of the Digital Public Library of America, using a stylesheet available at https://github.com/utkdigitalinitiatives/DLTN. Metadata originally created in a locally modified version of qualified Dublin Core using ContentDM (data dictionary available: https://wiki.lib.utk.edu/display/DPLA.)</recordOrigin>
  </recordInfo>
</mods>
