<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Correspondence from G. R. Rutledge to Robert Rutledge, November 2, 1863</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <identifier>34179</identifier>
  <name>
    <namePart>Rutledge, G. R.</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cre">Creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated encoding="edtf" keyDate="yes">1863-11-02</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <physicalDescription>
    <internetMediaType>image/tiff</internetMediaType>
  </physicalDescription>
  <location>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll1/id/316</url>
    <url access="preview">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p15138coll1/id/316</url>
    <url note="iiif-manifest">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/iiif/info/p15138coll1/316/manifest.json</url>
    <physicalLocation>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</physicalLocation>
  </location>
  <subject>
    <topic>Civil War in the West</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Civil War society</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>United States - History - 1783-1865</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>United States - History - 1849-1877</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>United States History - Civil War, 1861-1865</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85026421">
    <topic>Civil war</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>War</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Correspondence</topic>
  </subject>
  <abstract>Letter from G. R. Rutledge to Robert Rutledge commenting on the prices of provisions in the region, the lack of certain goods, and his need to purchase a horse. He expresses concern for Robert's health and provisions and is worried about Gam (Gamble), who was captured by and remains in the custody of Union troops. He also expresses his fears about the bleak Confederate military situation.</abstract>
  <accessCondition type="local rights statement">While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use.</accessCondition>
  <subject>
    <geographic>Zebulon (Ga.)</geographic>
  </subject>
  <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
  <abstract>[Page 1] “Zebulon Ga. Nov. 2nd 1863 Dear Robert I have just received your letter of the 29th ult. sorry indeed to hear of your condition I would not feel so bad about you if I could do anything for you I would certainly go to your relief if I could pass the road above Atlanta no one but souldiers can travel on the cars above Atlanta several have tried it from here and been turned back at Atlanta I wrote to L. H. Reeder a few days ago about your condition &amp; to supply your wants if possible without regard to cost I stated to him that we had sent you clothes &amp; they had been lost I wrote him to get you a pair of shoes a quilt &amp; under shirts &amp; convey to them too you If you could only come home we could supply your wants for the winter” [Page 2] “I recd. a letter from Reader a few days since dated the 25th Oct. stating that he would be here in the course of a month or six weeks to buy land I will go with him to look at land &amp; will buy If I find any suitable Thare are plenty of provisions in this country but very little for sale farmers holding back for better prices I can just pick up a little here and a little thare &amp; make out to get enough to live upon not been able to buy the first bushel of wheat since I have been here plenty of wheat but none for sale I get some flour at 20 cts I believe it will bring $10.00 &amp; corn $3.00 a bushel again Jan. I will buy my supply of corn before long at some price I have a supply of molasses at $3.00 pr Gal. we have plenty of milk No chance to get Bacon here and unless we can get it from Reeder we will have to do without next year I have bought no horse yet cannot do without one to go to mill &amp; haul wood. –” [Page 3] “have one in view that I suppose I will buy price $850. and that is the best that I can do here I have tried it &amp; it suits me well It is a fine mare with colt I intend trying to make some money out of her even at that price Robert you will be surprised when I tell you I have not seen the first particle of frost here yet the grass is still green &amp; sweet potatoes still growing we get plenty of sweet potatoes at $2. pr Bushel Robert I feel very low spirited to night feel Bad for you and Gam. Willie has just taken a long cry about Gam. I am all ways thinking about him I fear he will not be able to stand the treatment that he will receive at the hands of the wicked Foe Robert I see nothing cheering before us our country is ruined our men demoralized no prospect for happiness in this world Let us look to God to sustain &amp; carry is through” [Page 4] “our troubles and may we rely upon him alone for safety &amp; happiness &amp; may we all ways be mindful of our depending upon him and all ways be prepared to meet him if we should be suddenly taken from the world Tuesday morning Nov. 3rd All well this morning Willie has just started to mill for meal 7 miles I gave Lanson Beckham a letter to you with the Key of your satchel sealed up in the letter Could you not get his Col. to stop his pay for you Beckham is a man of common sise fair complexion with his upper front Teeth out This is my best recollection of him Write to Reeder your condition about clothes and I think you will get supplied Write soon Truely your Father G. R. R. P.S. I paid Beckham Five dollars to take your cloths to you”</abstract>
  <abstract>1990-340</abstract>
  <abstract>1263</abstract>
  <abstract>http://www.tennessee.gov/tsla/history/manuscripts/findingaids/90-340.pdf</abstract>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Collection">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Rutledge Family Letters, 1858-1865</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Project">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Civilian Life in the Civil War</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <abstract>The items in this collection offer new perspectives into the lives of numerous non-combatants during the Civil War in Tennessee and throughout the southeast.  The correspondence and primary writings touch on several themes relating to the home front, including the diverse roles of women, the relationship between occupying/invading forces and civilians, personal beliefs regarding secession and the war, and the effect of the war on African American Tennesseans.  These sources can offer the public a lens into the lives of many Civil War non-combatant men and women, a subject of increasing importance in Civil War scholarship...</abstract>
    <location>
      <url>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/landingpage/collection/p15138coll1</url>
    </location>
  </relatedItem>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Tennessee State Library and Archives</recordContentSource>
    <recordChangeDate>2023-05-12-04:00</recordChangeDate>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
    <recordOrigin>Record has been transformed into MODS 3.5 from a qualified Dublin Core record by the Digital Library of Tennessee, a service hub of the Digital Public Library of America, using a stylesheet available at https://github.com/utkdigitalinitiatives/DLTN. Metadata originally created in a locally modified version of qualified Dublin Core using ContentDM (data dictionary available: https://wiki.lib.utk.edu/display/DPLA.)</recordOrigin>
  </recordInfo>
</mods>
