<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>William Luther Bigelow Lawrence Diary Excerpts</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <identifier>34085</identifier>
  <name>
    <namePart>Lawrence, William Luther Bigelow, 1828-1902</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cre">Creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated encoding="edtf" keyDate="yes">1859/1865</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <physicalDescription>
    <internetMediaType>image/tiff</internetMediaType>
  </physicalDescription>
  <location>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll1/id/63</url>
    <url access="preview">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p15138coll1/id/63</url>
    <physicalLocation>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</physicalLocation>
  </location>
  <subject>
    <topic>Civil War in the West</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Civil War society</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>United States - History - 1783-1865</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>United States - History - 1849-1877</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>United States History - Civil War, 1861-1865</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Nashville (Tenn.)</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85026421">
    <topic>Civil war</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>War</topic>
  </subject>
  <abstract>Excerpts from the diary of William Luther Bigelow Lawrence. He details joining the Nashville Guards, the scarcity of provisions, and the surrender of Nashville. He proclaims the trampling of private rights by Federal soldiers, the fleeing of his slaves, the demise of his grocery business, and the destruction of his farm and property with the Battle of Nashville.</abstract>
  <accessCondition type="local rights statement">While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use.</accessCondition>
  <subject>
    <geographic>Davidson County (Tenn.)</geographic>
  </subject>
  <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
  <abstract>[Page 52] “1859 Nov. 30th. Killed twenty-two hogs yesterday &amp; busy cutting up &amp; salting today - December 1st Settled with Shaffer in full for brick work done for me on Servant’s house &amp; Coal bin “ 3rd Cold rain all day &amp; yesterday mixed with fine hail, trees glazed with a thick coat of ice, limbs occasionally falling with the heavy weight upon them. Thermometer 32°. Willie &amp; I in doors nearly all day. Yesterday was the day appointed for the execution of the notorious John Brown of Harpers Ferry &amp; Kansas memory. I see from reports by the telegraph that he has paid the extreme penalty of the law for his crimes at Harpers Ferry, where he headed an insurrection the object of which was to free the slaves of Virginia, some four or five others were condemned to die with him. This is the first scheme of the kind which has ever been openly attempted in this country &amp; it has promptly met with its just retribution, but yet I fear, speedily as it has been quelled it is but the beginning of a chain of events which will ultimately end in the dissolution of our glorious Union. Allen A. Hall has been commited to appear at the next term of the Criminal Court. Dec. 7th Thermometer at 6 A.M. was 26° below freezing point. Earth covered with snow &amp; sleet. Fires quite comfortable (?) Dec r 23rd Completed my fourth sitting with Dr Camlin Dentist, paid $43.75 for work done on my teeth consisting of seperating, filling &amp; cleaning. My dear wife has been gone more than three weeks, Oh! How could I live without her cheerful smiles &amp; love-beaming face to greet me when I come in from the toils of busy life. My love grows with my growth &amp; strengthens with my strength.” [Page 69] “1860 Nov 15. Attended the funeral service &amp; burial of Dr. John T. Edgar who died on Monday [missing]ing last of Apoplexy. He performed the marriage ceremony for five of my father’s children, preached the funeral sermon of both my parents &amp; of six of their children. Dr. Bardwell, Dr. Edgar’s assistant pastor, preached his funeral sermon, many other ministers assisted him in the service – Nov 23rd Yesterday rain &amp; fine hail, today rain, snow &amp; high cold wind from the North-west. Wife busy putting up Turkeys &amp; chickens – Dec 25th Christmas. Took dinner at Belmont Addison Hayes &amp; two daughters, Oliver &amp; wife &amp; two boys Hal Hayes, Mrs Pointer, self &amp; wife &amp; three children &amp; Mrs O. B. Hayes In present, had a merry time eating, drinking, chatting &amp;c. At night attended the girls Sallie A &amp; Adie H. to a small party at Mrs Louis’s. Last month engaged Julius Ricon to lay off &amp; make with my force a road &amp; circle from front gate to front door. He is going ahead with it as fast as the weather will permit. This has been an expensive year to me as well as to many others. My meat gave out early, in August I think, my corn did not last until the new crop came on. I had therefore to buy both bread &amp; meat. My crop of corn was exceedingly small when it did come in consequence of the serious drouth. I am of the opinion that our beloved Union is drawing to an ignonimious end. Lincoln has been elected President &amp; the whole South is shaken from center to circumference – God grant that we may be preserved from civil war &amp; a servile insurrection!” [Page 70] “Anno Domini 1861 Jan 1st Finds the American Eagle in deep distress, while want &amp; misery &amp; fear and trembling walk unrestrained over the land, which was once the home of plenty &amp; happiness. The politicians cannot save the Union, the people are divided, business stagnant &amp; nothing but the power of Almighty God can save us from that distruction to which we are so rapidly hastening. Jan 8th Finds me at home determined never to despair however hard times may be or however threatening the future may look. I have made preperations to commence with an early plowing of my ground in order that I may take time &amp; do everything well. Ricon is working on road with three or four hands to assist him. Wagner constantly hauling manure from town. Jan 20th Commenced breaking up old sedge-grass lot containing about 16 acres it having lain idle for fifteen years or more. Think it will produce well. Running two double horse plows. Feb. 4th Friday. Received from Cincinati 890 lbs of bacon, 500 lbs sides, balance hams, on 1st Inst. Julius Ricon , stole, boxed up &amp; endeavored to send to his brother in Clarksville 3 of my hams which were intercepted. I had him arrested &amp; incarcerated today. He has also raised considerable money under false pretences – Bacon cost me 10 5/8 cents here. Feb 9th Election held today in Tennessee. Question, Union or Disunion. I voted for Union &amp; Convention. South Carolina, Ala. Miss. Gea. Florida &amp; La have already seceded from the Union – Ten States” [Page 71] “1861 May 1st The Legislature in Extra Session has made a call upon the state for 55,000 troops, 25,000 for immediate service &amp; 30,000 as a reserve to be mustered in as soon as needed, also $5,000,000 have been appropriated for defence. Secession Ordinance &amp; Confederate Alliance past. June 1st Companies are being rapidly mustered into service from all parts of the State – June 8th Vote was taken upon Seperation &amp; Representation &amp; carried by a large majority in affirmation. (May 25) Was mustered into the State Service. Alex. Porter, Captain of Company. Am holding the exalted position of 2nd Corporal &amp; c. &amp; e. This section of Country has been visited this Spring by Measuring Worms, Cut-worms, Army-worms &amp; Potatoe-bugs notwithstanding all of which, the crops are looking quite promising – June 9th Our Company are in active service – at present engaged in guarding Government property to the amount of several millions of Dollars worth – June 15th The weather is very dry &amp; hot, a drought is imminent – The Enemy has invaded us &amp; hard fighting is looked for now – Fighting has commended at Alexandria, Acqueci Creek, Bethel, &amp; other points in Virginia – June 17th The Secession Flag now waves in triumph from our State Capitol, it was hoisted today amid much enthusiasm – Farmers are cutting wheat &amp; rye –“ [Page 72] “1861 March – Having determined to manage my place in a more systematic &amp; judicious manner than ever before. I have added to my farming implements a harrow for three horses costing 20 dollars, a roller worth $16 &amp; other tools. Am plowing deep &amp; thoroughly am sowing &amp; planting in a manner to prevent washing, well-pulverising the soil &amp; c &amp; c. Have also taken from the fields many cartloads of rocks &amp; stumps – My heavy expenses last year have stimulated me to renewed industry &amp; economy – April 4th Attended funeral of Henry Douglas, died of Consumption. Oats up several inches high, planting corn sticking peas &amp; c. April 13th The great &amp; political crisis is upon us. Which has been anticipated for a long time. Fort Sumpter was attacked yesterday by the South Carolinians &amp; surrendered today. Military movements are going on. North &amp; South, excitement rules &amp; is galloping rampant over the Country. Bedding out sweet potatoes &amp; c. April 20th Lincoln has made a call upon all the border &amp; Northern States for troops to put down “rebellion” in our Sister Southern States. Our Gov Harris has indignantly refused to furnish a single man for any such accussed purpose, but 50,000 if necessary for the defence of our &amp; their rights April 25th A called session of the Legislature commences today for the purpose of devising measures to meet the extraordinary times that are upon us. Nashville &amp; the State generally are busy in warlike preperations, companies are forming at this time in almost every district in the State. I have joined the Nashville Guards commanded by Mayor Heiman a gallant Officer who has seen service in the wilds of Mexico – “ [Page 73] “1861 July 4th our company discharged from service in consequence of the heavy expense it brought upon the State. July 21st The Great Battle of Manassas was fought today, with great slaughter on both sides &amp; victory perched upon the Confederate Standard – The prospect for an abundant crop of everything is unusually fine – Aug 1st made a race for Lt. Col. of Militia and was defeated by a small vote, owing doubtless to my having come out as a candidate too late – and not getting votes enough to elect me Aug 6th Was appointed Quarter-master to the 85th Regiment of Militia by Col Fulghum – Aug 17th John Thompson thrashed out 50 bushels of Wheat &amp; 20 bushels of Rye for me. Sept 19th Commenced cutting crab-grass which is more abundant this fall than I ever saw it before – Hired Bowstead at $1 per diem – Oct 1st Have about 27 acres of wheat sowed Dec 25th have had more sickness the past fall than ever before among the negroes, colds, Pleurisy &amp; c have prevailed extensively, some bad cases of Pleurisy but no deaths – Dr Woodward in attendance. Spent this day at home. Bought on the 23rd Instant Fitzhugh 22 head of hogs, 1 bull, 1 heifer &amp; 1 colt. My crop of corn this year was fine for which I feel thankful to an Overruling Providence – Weather so far has been exceedingly mild &amp; pleasant for winter, no ice or snow of any consequence which is very propitious to our brave army now in camp &amp; field –“ [Page 74] “Anno Domini 1862 January 1st. The internecine war of Lincoln waged against the unoffending South still progresses, every preparation is being made to fasten the yoke of bondage upon the beautiful &amp; chivalrous Southern country. But our people are determined to be forever free &amp; independent of the Northern fanatics &amp; tho the war may be long &amp; bloody we will never submit. Many battles have already been fought with great odds against us yet in almost every single engagement the Great God of battles has favored our side. Mason &amp; Slidell have been captured, thrown into prison &amp; subsequently ignominiously surrendered to the British Lion. The Stone Blockade has commenced &amp; England &amp; France are indignant. A fair product now exists of the breaking up of the blockade. Provisions are exceedingly scarce in the Cotton States. Pork is selling at $40 per barrel &amp; not enough to supply the demand. Beef has been packed extensively in this place and sells at $30 per barrel. The Government has bought many thousand hogs for the use of the Army at 10 cents gross. Clothing &amp; shoes bear enormous prices. We trust in Providence &amp; hope for the “better day a-coming” Sunday Jan 19th The Revolution moves on, and attack upon Bowling-Green has been expected for some time but as the invader still stands aloof – Nashville seems to be the great aim of our enemy at present, he has already advanced upon Forts Henry &amp; Donelson &amp; causes considerable excitement here Sunday Feb 16th A few days since Fort Henry fell into Federal hands. Today Nashville is all excitement in consequence of the surrender of Fort Donelson with Gen. Buckner &amp; some ten thousand men. Federals looked for him in a few days –“ [Page 75] “1862 Feb 23rd Sunday. The Federal Picket made their appearance opposite the City today. The wire and R.R. bridges have been destroyed by our forces. Gen Johnson has declared that he cannot defend the City. The Mayor will consequently make a formal surrender tomorrow or next day. Yesterday Jeff Davis was Inaugurated first President of the Confederate States under the permanent Constitution. Feb 25th Federals under Buell have reached the City &amp; are landing in force. They say that private rights &amp; private property shall be protected. March 1st More rain has fallen here than in any previous winter according to my recollection – Farming is consequently quite retarded – → March 3rd Monday Morning at 5 O’Clock ← Risley P Lawrence, 2nd, opened his peepers to the Terrestrial surroundings of Hillside, to the Colic &amp; to the world generally, like Eva’s his advent was marked by a Rainbow. May their blessings &amp; joys thro life be as numerous &amp; bright as the tints of that Rain-bow. Dr. Thomas Atchison called, but arrived after the frolic was over – 4th July. This day was celebrated here by a Military Procession &amp; Speaking at the Capitol. The display of Union flags about the City was meager in the extreme, scarce a dozen private houses showed their colors. The citizens took no part whatever in the Procession. The great battle of Shilo was fought in April, the two days fight of Seven Pines before Richmond &amp; the great battle of six days at the same place in which McClellan’s grand army was overwhelmed &amp; driven back fifteen miles was ended. July 2nd. Rebels are Jubilant and are confident” [Page 76] “1862 of final success. God grant that this bloody war may end but not until our Independence is achieved &amp; our rights fully recognized. Our corn crop is splendid, or wheat indifferent our oat a failure. The Federal Soldiers have materially injured the Poultry crop in this region of country. January Anno Domini 1863 Many incidents of importance to the People &amp; to the Nation have transpired since my last writing in this book, which are now matters of history. The first Summer in this portion of Tennessee witnessed a “Reign of Terror” which I hope never to see enacted again. Communication between this place &amp; Louisville being cut off gave license to the Federal Soldiers to commit acts of barbarism unbecoming a civilized people even toward a savage foe. Private rights of every character were trampled under foot in the most outrageous manner. But thank Heaven we have yet a little life to live upon &amp; things look a little better now. Gen. Negley was Commandant of this Post last Summer but his command is now at Murfreesboro. The great &amp; bloody Battle of Stone’s River has just been fought &amp; is now a matter of history. May 1st My fencing being all destroyed or removed about my tillable land, have rented some land from Mrs Montgomery at $3 per acre, &amp; have made a garden in my Poultry yard. Daniel Bryson of the 78th Penn has been military guard for our Premises for six months. June 1st The war still goes on with little or no prospect of a speedy termination. The Federal arms seem to be in the ascendent. Vicksburg &amp; Port Hudson are closely invest[missing]” [Page 77] “1863 while Lee invades Pennsylvania. July 4th Vicksburg surrenders to Grant &amp; Meade drives Lee from Pennsylvania. John Morgan is making his way into Ohio with what designs remains to be seen. Unusual amount of rain. Aug 1st Port Hudson fell last Month John Morgan was captured, is now a prisoner within the walls of the Ohio State Prison. Bragg has fallen back to Look-out Mountain, Gilmore &amp; the Fleet have attacked Fort Wagner, meeting a repulse &amp; heavy loss. The prospect of the Confederacy at this time look decidedly “blue”. The draft is being carried out in the North generally including men of all colors &amp; the blacker the better. In New York however in consequence of mob violence &amp; resistance draft has been temporarily suspended. Gen R. L. Granger commander of this Post at this time &amp; the Military are kept in wholesome restraint &amp; discipline. January Anno Domini 1864 Notwithstanding the severity of the Weather, so far we have managed to keep up our fires up &amp; thanks to a kind Providence have a shelter yet to protect us from the storms &amp; a little in the “Larder” to feed upon. Made a little corn &amp; hay for the which are very thankful. Friday March 11th Determined to make something to live upon if possible during these troublous times, I have this day formed a Partnership with D. Cook Jr of Lebanon for the purpose of carrying on a Grocery Business in the house of W. H. Lucus &amp; Co” [Page 78] “1864 We have agreed to put in an equal amount of Capital &amp; divide equally the Profits &amp; Losses. Mortgaged Land for the purpose of raising means to begin on. Cultivating no crop this year except a vegetable garden. Available hands all left except Bill &amp; some women and children. 4th July. Am pleased with the new avocation in which I have embarked. Find my colleugue a prompt &amp; efficient business man, think we should make money if not too much restricted by the Military regulations. Friday July 28th 1864 → Miss Sarah H. Lawrence commenced her mortal career 3 O clock A. M. of this day &amp; date, may she live &amp; prosper &amp; become a treasure to her Parents &amp; a useful member of Society. Dr Atchison as in the case of Risley was too late to officiate.← Aug 1st In consequence of the desertion of my own negroes, have been compelled to hire “Contrabands” as servants &amp; am getting along first rate. Aug 14th Grocery trade rather dull in consequence of shipments to county towns being suspended until the new order takes effect. Coffee firm at 70cents, Choice N.O. Sugar 40c, Crushed &amp; granulated 45, meal retails at $3.00 per bushel. Small Pox still prevails to some extent in the city. Geo. Shields &amp; family spending the Summer with us. Sherman is investing Atlanta &amp; Grant hammers army at Richmond with no immediate prospect of capturing either strong hold. Federals also attacking Mobile” [Page 79] “1864 Sept 1st Carrying on the Grocery business, but under many disadvantages owing to the military restrictin around trade &amp; fear we can make no money. Expenses are very heavy &amp; profits short. Dec 15th The great Battle of Nashville was fought today in which the Confederates under Gen Hood was completely overthrown by Gen Thomas. From my hill I witnessed the engagement &amp; listened to the incessant roar of the artillery the rattle of small arms &amp; the shouts of the advancing columns. The Federal lines of ranks ran transversely across my place &amp; just by my front door. Gen Beaty made his Headquarters at my house with his Staff &amp; servants occupied every room in it. A portion of the time the weather was very cold &amp; all my fencing, the work of many months of toil to me was swept away in a very few days. All my Quarter Buildings &amp; oat houses were entirely consumed &amp; all furniture that I had not moved to town was completely destroyed. I also lost all my stock, consisting of cows, horses, hogs, pigs, &amp; c. We are at present staying at Charley Thompson’s who has kindly taken us in until the excitement is over. Dec 24th The military have left my premises &amp; Oh what an uninviting prospect is before me! All my lovely forest &amp; shade trees destroyed, my beautiful yard a mudhole &amp; ruin &amp; debris scattered all around me, nothing but the naked dwelling left &amp; yet how thankful I feel for even that little. It might have been worse” [Page 80] “1865. Anno Domini 1865. Back home again, not the beautiful, quiet place I left a short time since, but a rugged, churless, barren, forlorn, “Black-House”. We have gone to work to make ourselves comfortable for the balance of the winter. We can keep warm at all events, as the amount of “rubbish combustible,” lying about us is considerable. March 30th Have moved our Grocery stock to Wm. Lyons &amp; Co on Market Street. Have concluded to close out &amp; dissolve partnership. We have not been as fortunate in business as we had hoped we should be &amp; Groceries have tumbled upon the first prospect of Peace. July 4th 1865 Peace, Glorious Peace once more smiles upon our distructed Country. Swords will be sheathed &amp; the artillery cease to belch forth its distructive contents, but yet it is dreadful to reflect upon the number of Gallant Spirits that have been sacrificed in the bloody contest that I hope never to see renewed again Dec 1865 Have spent the Summer &amp; Fall mainly in making repairs &amp; fences around my land East of the Granny-white Pike into about 10 acre lots, which I propose to rent or lease, as under the present state of labor I cannot cultivate to my satisfaction. Much land is offered for sale &amp; lease in this county &amp; many transactions in that way take place daily. We have laid off Rokeby Place also for the purpose of renting &amp; leasing out.”</abstract>
  <abstract>1968-006</abstract>
  <abstract>811</abstract>
  <abstract>http://state.tn.us/tsla/history/manuscripts/findingaids/68-006.pdf</abstract>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Collection">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Lawrence Family Papers, 1780-1944</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Project">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Civilian Life in the Civil War</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <abstract>The items in this collection offer new perspectives into the lives of numerous non-combatants during the Civil War in Tennessee and throughout the southeast.  The correspondence and primary writings touch on several themes relating to the home front, including the diverse roles of women, the relationship between occupying/invading forces and civilians, personal beliefs regarding secession and the war, and the effect of the war on African American Tennesseans.  These sources can offer the public a lens into the lives of many Civil War non-combatant men and women, a subject of increasing importance in Civil War scholarship...</abstract>
    <location>
      <url>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/landingpage/collection/p15138coll1</url>
    </location>
  </relatedItem>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Tennessee State Library and Archives</recordContentSource>
    <recordChangeDate>2023-05-12-04:00</recordChangeDate>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
    <recordOrigin>Record has been transformed into MODS 3.5 from a qualified Dublin Core record by the Digital Library of Tennessee, a service hub of the Digital Public Library of America, using a stylesheet available at https://github.com/utkdigitalinitiatives/DLTN. Metadata originally created in a locally modified version of qualified Dublin Core using ContentDM (data dictionary available: https://wiki.lib.utk.edu/display/DPLA.)</recordOrigin>
  </recordInfo>
</mods>
