<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Call to the District Court of the Confederate States of America for the Middle Division of the District of Tennessee for N. E. Alloway</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <identifier>34157</identifier>
  <name>
    <namePart>District Court of the Confederate States of America</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cre">Creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated encoding="edtf" keyDate="yes">1862-01-06</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <physicalDescription>
    <internetMediaType>image/tiff</internetMediaType>
  </physicalDescription>
  <location>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll1/id/67</url>
    <url access="preview">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p15138coll1/id/67</url>
    <url note="iiif-manifest">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/iiif/info/p15138coll1/67/manifest.json</url>
    <physicalLocation>Tennessee Historical Society Civil War Collection, 1860-1982</physicalLocation>
    <physicalLocation>Tennessee Historical Society</physicalLocation>
  </location>
  <subject>
    <topic>Civil War in the West</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Civil War society</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>United States - History - 1783-1865</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>United States - History - 1849-1877</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>United States History - Civil War, 1861-1865</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85026421">
    <topic>Civil war</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>War</topic>
  </subject>
  <abstract>Call to the District Court of the Confederate States of America in Nashville by Clerk Jacob McGavock for N. E. Alloway. Alloway is the garnishee, answering the interrogatories of the Court dealing with property and allegiances. Authorization comes from the Confederate Sequestration Act of 1861. Handwritten question indicates the garnishee is suspected of holding property for Unionist Judge John Catron.</abstract>
  <accessCondition type="local rights statement">While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use.</accessCondition>
  <subject>
    <geographic>Nashville (Tenn.)</geographic>
  </subject>
  <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
  <abstract>[Page 1] “District Court of the Confederate States of America, For the Middle Division of the District of Tenn. To M. E. Alloway Nashville greeting: You are hereby commanded to appear at the said District Court, at the Court-Room at Nashville, on the 3rd Monday of January 1862, then and there to answer, under oath, what property or effects of any alien enemy you had at the time of the service of this garnishment process, or since have had under your possession or control belonging to or held for an alien enemy; or, in what sum, if any, you are and were at the time of service of garnishment, or since have been indebted hereto annexed, and such other questions as may be put to you touching the property and effects of alien enemies; and further to abide by and perform such orders and decrees as may be made in the premises. Herein fail not, under the penalties prescribed by law. In Testimony Whereof, I, Jacob McGavock, Clerk of said Court, have hereunto set my hand, and affix the Seal of said Court, at office, this 6th day of January, 1862. Jacob McGavock” [Page 2] “Have you any property or effects in your possession or under control belonging to or held for the use of Judge Catron? If so, state what it is.” [Page 3] “INTERROGATORIES To be Propounded to, and Answered by Garnishees. 1. Have you now, or have you had in your possession, or under your control, since the 2d day of July last, (1861,) and if yea, at what time, any land or lands, tenement or tenements, hereditament or hereditaments, chattel or chattels, right or rights, credit or credits, within the Confederate States of America, held, owned, possessed or enjoyed for or by an alien enemy; or in, or to which any alien enemy had, and when, since that time, any right, title, of interest, either directly or indirectly? 2. If you answer any part of the foregoing interrogatory in the affirmative, then set forth specifically and particularly a description of such property, right, title, credit or interest; and if you have disposed of it in whole or in part, or of the profit, or rent, or interest accruing therefrom, then state when you made such disposition, and to whom, and where such property now is, and by whom held. 3. Were you, since the 2d day of July, 1861, and if yea, at what time, indebted either directly or indirectly, to any alien enemy, or alien enemies? If yea, state the amount of such indebtedness, if one, and of each indebtedness, if more than one: give the name or names of creditors, and the place or places of residence; and state whether, and to what extent, and also the time and manner of the discharge. 4. Do you know of any land or lands, tenement or tenements, hereditament or hereditaments, chattel or chattels, right or rights, creditor or creditors, within the Confederate States of America; or any right or interest held, owned, possessed or enjoyed, directly or indirectly, by or for one or more alien enemies since the 2d day of July, 1861, or in or by which any one or more alien enemies had since that time any claim, title or interest, direct or indirect? If yea, set forth, specifically and particularly what and where the property is, and the name and residence of the holder, debtor, trustee or agent. 5. State all else that you know which may aid in carrying into full effect the Sequestration Act of the 30th of August, 1861, and state the same as fully and particularly as if thereunto specially interrogated. S. R. Cockrill Receiver C. S. A. Note—The garnishee in the foregoing Interrogatories is specially warned that the Sequestration Act makes it the duty of each and every citizen to give the information asked in said interrogatories. {Act of 30th of August, Section 2.} And if attorney, agent, former partner, trustee, or other person holding or controlling any property or interest therein of or for any alien enemy, shall fail speedily to inform the Receiver of the same, and to render him an account of such property or interest, he shall be guilty of a high misdemeanor, and upon conviction, shall be fined in a sum not exceeding five thousand dollars, and imprisoned not longer than six months, and be liable to pay besides, to the Confederate States, double the value of the property or interest of the alien enemies so held subject to his control. {Sec. 3.} The Attorney General has also prescribed the following rule of practice for the Courts, by virtue of the authority vested in him, under the 16th section of the law: RULE—Garnishees, to whom written or printed interrogatories are addressed, may make appearance by filing written answers, sworn to before a Justice of the Peace, or other competent officer, unless specially ordained by the Court to appear in person.”</abstract>
  <abstract>THS 481</abstract>
  <abstract>1091</abstract>
  <abstract>http://state.tn.us/tsla/history/manuscripts/findingaids/ths481.pdf</abstract>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Project">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Civilian Life in the Civil War</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <abstract>The items in this collection offer new perspectives into the lives of numerous non-combatants during the Civil War in Tennessee and throughout the southeast.  The correspondence and primary writings touch on several themes relating to the home front, including the diverse roles of women, the relationship between occupying/invading forces and civilians, personal beliefs regarding secession and the war, and the effect of the war on African American Tennesseans.  These sources can offer the public a lens into the lives of many Civil War non-combatant men and women, a subject of increasing importance in Civil War scholarship...</abstract>
    <location>
      <url>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/landingpage/collection/p15138coll1</url>
    </location>
  </relatedItem>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Tennessee State Library and Archives</recordContentSource>
    <recordChangeDate>2023-05-12-04:00</recordChangeDate>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
    <recordOrigin>Record has been transformed into MODS 3.5 from a qualified Dublin Core record by the Digital Library of Tennessee, a service hub of the Digital Public Library of America, using a stylesheet available at https://github.com/utkdigitalinitiatives/DLTN. Metadata originally created in a locally modified version of qualified Dublin Core using ContentDM (data dictionary available: https://wiki.lib.utk.edu/display/DPLA.)</recordOrigin>
  </recordInfo>
</mods>
