<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:oai="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Correspondence from Mary Minerva Rutledge to her sister, October 9, 1862</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <identifier>34172</identifier>
  <name>
    <namePart>Rutledge, Mary Minerva Montgomery</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm type="text" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cre">Creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated encoding="edtf" keyDate="yes">1862-10-09</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <physicalDescription>
    <internetMediaType>image/tiff</internetMediaType>
  </physicalDescription>
  <location>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll1/id/269</url>
    <url access="preview">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p15138coll1/id/269</url>
    <url note="iiif-manifest">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/iiif/info/p15138coll1/269/manifest.json</url>
    <physicalLocation>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</physicalLocation>
  </location>
  <subject>
    <topic>Civil War in the West</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Civil War society</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>United States - History - 1783-1865</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>United States - History - 1849-1877</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>United States History - Civil War, 1861-1865</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject authority="lcsh" valueURI="http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85026421">
    <topic>Civil war</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>War</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Correspondence</topic>
  </subject>
  <abstract>Letter from Mary Minerva Rutledge to her sister concerning the health of an individual named "Green," the mischievous activities of "Lincolnites," and her husband Robert Rutledge.</abstract>
  <accessCondition type="local rights statement">While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use.</accessCondition>
  <subject>
    <geographic>Holston River (Tenn.)</geographic>
  </subject>
  <typeOfResource>text</typeOfResource>
  <abstract>[Page 1] “Holston River Oct 9th 1862 Dear Sister I arrived here safe but was very tired George did not like riding on the cars very much he was afraid he was very glad to get to change from the cars to a Buggy I found the folks all well I have not heard much about Green yet. Sarah sayes that he was at the Hospital when Nelson found him he came very near not geting him when the Courier first looked over his books he toled Nelson that he was dead but that would not satisfy Nelson and he made him look again and he found the names of two Montgomerys that had died and was about to turn Nelson off but he begged him to look again and directly he came to Greens name and” [Page 2] “sayed that he was alive The Courier then went and asked Green if he knew a man that lived near his home by the name of Nelson Green studied some time and then sayed that he did Nelson was then brought into the room he did not know Green but Green knew him he has not improved but very little since he came home Sarah sayes that she would never off know him he sayes that he went out in the Country to an old Ladys hous to stay a while and was taken down again and lay their Six weeks and had to be moved back to the Hospital he sayed that the Old Lady and her Daughters wer very kind to him They made some new clothes and wanted to give him some but he would not take them because he had no Money to pay for them, he says the first Dr that waited on him was no account he never broke the diseas at all Sarah sayes that he had no Dr attending on him when” [Page 3] “she was their Green toled Sarah that he borrowed $20 from Jim Alexander and put it in his pocket to have in their when he died so that they could have it to buy his Coffin with he sayed that he had seen so many just rolled up in their Blankets and burried and did not want to be put away that way. he saved the Money and when he got to Knoxville he met with Jim Alex and payed him back the same Money. I expect to go up home the last of this week or the first of the next I fear that I will not find Jule or Green either their as they wer talking of going to Sams the last of this week you asked me to write you a long letter I can not do it this time for I have heard nothing that would be interesting to you. The Lincolnites have been doing some mischief over on Clinch the night that I came up they set fire to John Lacheys barn and burned up some fine horses and about three” [Page 4] “thousand dollars worth of other things he had moved his Family over to Mr Russell in the and just taken some darkies and went back to sow wheat I guess they was afraid that he was going to move back their is very few southern men over their and they have had to all leave their homes. You had better direct your letters to Marysville you must write soon and give me all off the news I hope Ma is better by this time I suppos Pa toled you about Rob coming so near getting his neck broke and tearing his pants off ove him I fear he will get his neck broke yet I cannot think of any thing more to write you must write soon M M Rutledge”</abstract>
  <abstract>1990-340</abstract>
  <abstract>1263</abstract>
  <abstract>http://www.tennessee.gov/tsla/history/manuscripts/findingaids/90-340.pdf</abstract>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Collection">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Rutledge Family Letters, 1858-1865</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <relatedItem type="host" displayLabel="Project">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Civilian Life in the Civil War</title>
    </titleInfo>
    <abstract>The items in this collection offer new perspectives into the lives of numerous non-combatants during the Civil War in Tennessee and throughout the southeast.  The correspondence and primary writings touch on several themes relating to the home front, including the diverse roles of women, the relationship between occupying/invading forces and civilians, personal beliefs regarding secession and the war, and the effect of the war on African American Tennesseans.  These sources can offer the public a lens into the lives of many Civil War non-combatant men and women, a subject of increasing importance in Civil War scholarship...</abstract>
    <location>
      <url>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/landingpage/collection/p15138coll1</url>
    </location>
  </relatedItem>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Tennessee State Library and Archives</recordContentSource>
    <recordChangeDate>2023-05-12-04:00</recordChangeDate>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
    <recordOrigin>Record has been transformed into MODS 3.5 from a qualified Dublin Core record by the Digital Library of Tennessee, a service hub of the Digital Public Library of America, using a stylesheet available at https://github.com/utkdigitalinitiatives/DLTN. Metadata originally created in a locally modified version of qualified Dublin Core using ContentDM (data dictionary available: https://wiki.lib.utk.edu/display/DPLA.)</recordOrigin>
  </recordInfo>
</mods>
