<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Bill of sale for Mary, an enslaved girl, in Williamson County, Tennessee, from Joshua Reams to William Harrison, Jr., 1841 February 02</dc:title>
<dc:description>A bill of sale from Williamson County, Tennessee, documenting the transfer of an enslaved girl slave named Mary from Joshua Reams to William Harrison, Jr. for the sum of three hundred and fifty dollars, dated Feb. 2, 1841.  The verso of this document lists the subscribing witnesses, Daniel Baugh and Guilford Dudley, who appeared before Lemuel B. McConnico, clerk of the Williamson County Court and the Register's office on Feb. 6, 1841.  Forms part of the Harrison House Collection.  1 document : b &amp; w ; 11 x 19.5 cm.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Harrison, William, 1825-1889; Reams, Joshua; Baugh, Daniel; Dudley, Guilford, 1756-1833; Harrison family; Reams familiy; McConnico, Lemuel B.</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Harrison House (Franklin, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African Americans; Business; African Americans--Tennessee--Williamson County--Genealogy; African Americans--Tennessee--Franklin--Genealogy; Slave bills of sale--Tennessee--Williamson County; African Americans--Social conditions--19th century; African Americans--Tennessee, Middle--History--Sources; Slavery--Tennessee--Williamson County; Plantation owners--Tennessee--Franklin; Plantation owners--Tennessee--Williamson County; Economic &amp; political systems; Slavery--Tennessee--Franklin; Slaves--Tennessee--Franklin</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Williamson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Williamson County (Tenn.)--Social conditions--19th century</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1841-02-02</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>HHC - f1, front - slave bill 1841; HHC - f1, verso - slave bill 1841</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Harrison House Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1840-1849</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1119</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>