<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>As Professor U.B. Sharp and the Spanish Fox, Brian Hull interviews fellow Wishing Chair Productions staff Mary Bailey (Mary Mary, J.J.) and Pete Carden (Tommy Dog, Library Pete), 2007 November 14</dc:title>
<dc:description>An edited excerpt with transcript and photograph from an interview with the Nashville Public Library's Wishing Chair Productions staff Mary Bailey (as Mary Mary and J.J.) and Pete Carden (as Tommy Dog and Library Pete), conducted on 14 November 2007 by Brian Hull (as Professor U.B. Sharp and the Spanish Fox) at the Nashville StoryCorps StoryBooth, located in the Nashville Room of the Nashville Public Library.  The puppets talk about their library cards and learn a new Spanish word.  The complete, un-edited interview, as well as an index, is available in the Special Collections Division. These interviews were recorded by StoryCorps at the Nashville Public Library with the support of the Nashville Public Library Foundation and are provided courtesy of StoryCorps, a national initiative of Sound Portraits Productions to record and collect oral history interviews. www.storycorps.net</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Bailey, Mary T., 1963- --Interviews; Carden, Pete, 1969- --Interviews</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Wishing Chair Productions</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Popular Culture; Children's History; Entertainment; Performing Arts; Theatre; Capital City; Libraries; Storytelling--Tennessee--Nashville; Puppeteers--Tennessee--Nashville; Hand puppets--Tennessee--Nashville; Puppets--Tennessee--Nashville; Entertainers--Tennessee--Nashville; Entertainment--Tennessee--Nashville; Puppet shows--Tennessee--Nashville; Libraries and puppets--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Bailey, Mary T., 1963- (Interviewee); Carden, Pete, 1969- (Interviewee); Hull, Brian, 1962- (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>StoryCorps (Project)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>2007-11-14</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3 (3 min., 26 sec.)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>NPL000079_excerpt.mp3; NPL000079_transcript.pdf; NPL000079_g1.jpg</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from:  NPL000079 original StoryCorps interview edited by Clint Tatum in June 2008.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English; Spanish</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville StoryCorps StoryBooth Interviews 2007-2008</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/2013</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>