<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Broadway Presbyterian Church, 1911</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard of Broadway Presbyterian Church, located at 1616 West End Avenue in Nashville, Tennessee.  This church was dedicated on January 11, 1911.  The foundation was made of rough cut stone blocks.  The exterior walls were tan brick.  The roof was gabled with tar shingles.  The windows were stained glass.  The doors were constructed of wood.  In 1921 the congregation left this building, and it became home for the Corinthian chapter of the Order of De Molay serving as the Corinthian Lodge no. 414 (F &amp; Am) until 2005.  In 2006 the building was razed to make way for new development.  Forms part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project. 1 postcard : b &amp; w ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Broadway Presbyterian Church (Nashville, Tenn.); Corinthian Lodge no. 414 (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Popular Culture; Religion; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Organizations; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Religious facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Church architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Presbyterian church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Details; Protestant church buildings; Brick churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Gables--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Fraternal organizations--Tennessee--Nashville; Masonic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Columns--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville; Business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Protestant churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Presbyterian churches--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs; Hillsboro-West End (Nashville, Tenn.); West End Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1911</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>SSSP - Broadway Presbyterian</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1910-1919</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1035</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>