<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Sister Cities board members Doug Berry and Burkley Allen present a flood relief check, from donations gathered at a concert in Nashville&#8217;s sister city Magdeburg, Germany, to Mayor Karl Dean and Executive Director of Hands on Nashville Brian Williams</dc:title>
<dc:description>Sister Cities board members Doug Berry and Burkley Allen present a flood relief check, from donations gathered at a concert in Nashville&#8217;s sister city Magdeburg, Germany, to Mayor Karl Dean and Executive Director of Hands on Nashville Brian Williams. The jazz group Sax&#8217;n Anhalt played at the Johanniskirche and the relief concert for flood recovery efforts raised over $6,000.

Forms part of the Nashville Room Flood 2010 Digital History Project. </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Dean, Karl;Williams, Brian;Berry, Doug;Allen, Burkley</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Sister Cities International</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Floods--Nashville (Tenn.);Natural disasters--Nashville (Tenn.); Disaster relief;Government response</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--Floods;Nashville (Tenn.)--History--21st century;Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources;Magdeburg (Germany)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Layda, Gary (Photographer);</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2010-05</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/JPEG</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>FDH-0072</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Flood 2010 Digital History Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2010-2019</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4034</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>