<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of Mrs. Coretta Scott King , Reverend Kelly Miller Smith, and Mrs. D. Conrad Gandy, First Baptist Church, Nashville, Tennessee, 1958 October 20</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of Coretta Scott King, Reverend Kelly Miller Smith and Mrs. D. Conrad Gandy at First Baptist Church, Nashville, Tennessee, October 20, 1958. Mrs. King addressed the group at a Women's Day program at First Baptist Church, 8th Avenue North, Nashville, Tennessee. During her speech, Mrs. King said: "We must not stop until freedom becomes a reality."  Her appearance in Nashville was just weeks after her husband, Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. was stabbed in New York City. Forms part of the Nashville Banner Archives. 1 photograph : b &amp; w ; 8 x 10 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>King, Coretta Scott, 1927-2006; Smith, Kelly Miller, 1920- ; Gandy, D. Conrad, Mrs.</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>First Baptist Church (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Civil Rights; African Americans; Race Relations; Religion; African Americans--Civil rights--Tennessee--Nashville; 
Civil rights movements--Tennessee--Nashville--History--Sources; Civil rights workers--Tennessee--Nashville; African Americans--Civil rights--Tennessee--Nashville; African Americans--Tennessee--Nashville--History--Sources; Baptist churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Civil rights leaders--United States </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social conditions; Nashville (Tenn.)--Race relations; Southern States--Race relations--History--20th century-Sources; Eighth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Ray, Bob (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1958-10-20</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/tiff</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BP-King, Mrs. Martin Luther-Coretta Scott King</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/564</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>