<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of defense attorneys for student demonstrators, Nashville, Tennessee, 1960 March 02</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of lead defense attorneys for student demonstrators, Davidson County Courthouse, Nashville, Tennessee, March 2, 1960. Attorney Robert E. Lillard gestures in his defense of the students on trial for their part in the sit-in demonstrations in downtown stores and lunch counters. Pictured left to right (front row): Adolpho A. Birch, Robert E. Lillard, Coyness L. Ennix, Sr., and Avon Williams, Jr.  Along with attorney Z. Alexander Looby, these attorneys were the spearheads of the defense for the student demonstrators. Forms part of the Nashville Banner Archives. 1 photograph : b &amp; w; 8 x 10 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Birch, Adolpho A., 1932- ; Lillard, Robert Emmitt, 1907-1991; Williams, Avon N., 1921-1994; Ennix, Coyness L., 1898-1984</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Davidson County Courthouse (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Civil Rights; African Americans; Race Relations; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; African Americans--Civil rights--Tennessee--Nashville; African Americans--Social conditions; Civil rights--Tennessee--Nashville; African Americans--Segregation--Tennessee--Nashville; Civil rights movements--Tennessee--Nashville; Lawyers--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Demonstrations-- Tennessee--Nashville; Civil rights workers--Tennessee--Nashville;  Protest movements--Tennessee--Nashville; Social justice--Tennessee--Nashville; Actions &amp; defenses--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social conditions; Nashville (Tenn.)--Race relations; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Commerce</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Cooley, Vic (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1960-03-02</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/tiff</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BP-Segregation-Nash-TN-March 1960-lawyers</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/566</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>