<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Oral history interview with Annie Woodfolk Carter, 1980 July 28</dc:title>
<dc:description>Excerpts from an oral history interview with Nashvillian Annie Woodfolk Carter, conducted on 28 July 1980 by Nathaniel A. Crippens as part of the Century III Nashville: Nashville Heritage Project.  In these excerpts, Carter discusses moving to Cleveland, Ohio, during World War I because of new job opportunities for African Americans; African American and Irish neighborhoods in East Nashville when she was a child; the fire department in East Nashville; how she and her husband became affiliated with a predominantly-white Lutheran church after moving back to Nashville during the 1960s; going to Union Station on Sunday afternoons; and the segregated facilities at Union Station and on the trains.   The complete interview, as well as an index, is available in the Special Collections Division.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Carter, Annie Woodfolk, 1896-1986--Interviews</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Union Station (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville (Tenn.). Fire department</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Military History; World War I; Civil Rights; African Americans; Popular Culture; Religion; Entertainment; Capital City; Transportation; Housing; Architecture; Buildings; World War, 1914-1918; African Americans--Economic conditions; African Americans--Employment; African Americans--Tennessee--Nashville; African Americans--Housing--Tennessee--Nashville; African Americans--Social conditions--Tennessee--Nashville; Ethnic neighborhoods--Tennessee--Nashville; Segregation--Tennessee--Nashville; African Americans--Segregation--Tennessee--Nashville; Segregation in transportation--Tennessee--Nashville; Irish Americans--Tennessee--Nashville; Irish Americans--Social conditions--Tennessee--Nashville; Irish Americans--Housing--Tennessee--Nashville; Lutheran churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Religion--Tennessee--Nashville; Church attendance--Tennessee--Nashville; Church membership--Tennessee--Nashville; Fire departments--Tennessee--Nashville; Transportation--Tennessee--Nashville; Street-railroads--Tennessee--Nashville; Transportation buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Immigrants--Tennessee--Nashville--Social conditions</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Race relations; Nashville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social conditions; East Nashville (Nashville, Tenn.)--History--Sources; East Nashville (Nashville, Tenn.)--Race relations; East Nashville (Nashville, Tenn.)--Social life and customs; East Nashville (Nashville, Tenn.)--Social conditions; Cleveland (Ohio)--Economic conditions</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Carter, Annie Woodfolk, 1896-1986 (Interviewee); Crippens, Nathaniel A., 1913-2004 (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1980-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CENTIIICarterAWaclip1.mp3; CENTIIICarterAWaclip2.mp3; CENTIIICarterAWaclip3.mp3; CENTIIICarterAWaclip4.mp3; CENTIIICarterAWbclip1.mp3; CENTIIICarterAW_transcript.pdf</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from:  CENTIIICarterAW audio cassette recording converted to digital format in 2006.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Century III Nashville: Nashville Heritage Project : oral history</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1980-1989</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1801</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>