<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Oral history interview with Margaret Wright, 1976 August 30, excerpt 01</dc:title>
<dc:description>An excerpt from an oral history interview with Margaret Wright, conducted on 30 August 1976 by Ann Wells as part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. Tennessee Centennial Project.  Wright describes the different areas and exhibits at the Centennial, including the Chinese and Mexican villages, a replica of Anne Hathaway's cottage, and a replica of a pyramid.  The complete interview is available in the Special Collections Division.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Wright, Margaret Fall, 1887-1985--Interviews; Hathaway, Anne, 1556?-1623</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Tennessee Centennial and International Exposition (1897 : Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Popular Culture; Exhibitions--Tennessee--Nashville; Chinese--Tennessee--Nashville; Mexicans--Tennessee--Nashville; Pyramids--Tennessee--Nashville; Amusements--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Tennessee--Centennial celebrations, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Tennessee--Exhibitions</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.; Wright, Margaret Fall, 1887-1985 (Interviewee); Wells, Ann (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1976-08-30</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3 (56 sec.)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>HNITCPWrightclip1</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from:  HNITCPWright audio cassette recording converted to mp3 format in 2006.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Tennessee Centennial project: oral history</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1970-1979</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/968</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>