<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>They will go caroling for Fannie Battle Day Home Christmas Eve, circa 1951 December 12</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of a group of junior choir members at Shelby Avenue Baptist Church, circa 12 December 1951, seen practicing for singing carols on Christmas Eve for benefit of the Fannie Battle Day Home.  Their designated area was the East Nashville area with Mrs. J.T. Dugger. They are front row, left to right, Miss Barbara Oliver, Miss Barbara West, Miss Connie Ray, Miss Jewell Marie Spencer and Miss Shirley Ann Willis; back row, Miss Dixie West, Miss Ann Ray, Miss Loretta Stewart, Miss Barbara Herod and Miss Christine Pomeroy.  This photograph illustrated the newspaper article "They will go caroling for Fannie Battle Day Home Christmas Eve," published in the 12 December 1951 issue of the Nashville Banner.  Forms part of the Fannie Battle Day Home Records.  1 photograph :  b &amp; w ; 10 x 8.25 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Oliver, Barbara; West, Barbara; Ray, Connie; Spencer, Jewell Marie; Willis, Shirley Ann; West, Dixie; Ray, Ann; Stewart, Loretta; Herod, Barbara; Pomeroy, Christine; Dugger, J.T., Mrs.</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Fannie Battle Day Home; Fannie Battle Social Workers; Shelby Avenue Baptist Church (Nashville, Tenn.)--Choral organizations</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Capital City; Organizations; Popular Culture; Children's History; Performing Arts; Music; Religion; Women social reformers--Tennessee--Nashville; Charity--Tennessee--Nashville; Charities--Tennessee--Nashville; Day care centers--Tennessee--Nashville; Child care workers--Tennessee--Nashville; Social workers--Tennessee--Nashville; Child care--Tennessee--Nashville; Women in charitable work--Tennessee--Nashville; Altruism--Tennessee--Nashville; Benevolence--Tennessee--Nashville; Social work with children--Tennessee--Nashville; Children--Social conditions; Children--Charities; Child welfare; Christmas carols; Caroling--Tennessee--Nashville; Holidays--Tennessee--Nashville; Nonprofit organizations--Tennessee--Nashville; Women in nonprofit organizations--Tennessee--Nashville; Choirs (Music)--Tennessee--Nashville; Charitable organizations--Tennessee--Nashville; Community service--Tennessee--Nashville; Economic &amp; social conditions--Tennessee--Nashville; Singing--Tennessee--Nashville; Music--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social conditions; Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Davidson County (Tenn.)--Social conditions</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Underwood, Doug (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1951-12-12</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>FBDHR-SB-Carol Publicity-1951-B11, f43-p2</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Fannie Battle Day Home Records</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1849</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>