<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Dormitory, Cumberland University, Lebanon, Tenn., circa 1913</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard of a dormitory building at Cumberland University located in Lebanon, Tennessee.  Founded in 1842, the school is one of the six oldest academic institutions in the state of Tennessee.  The campus occupies forty-three acres of land.  The school used to require students to live on campus in dormitories such as the one pictured, but now students have the choice to live off-campus as well.  Forms part of the Nashville Room Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Cumberland University (Lebanon, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Education; Colleges and Universities; Buildings; Architecture; Schools; Private Schools; Postcards--Tennessee--Lebanon; Buildings--Tennessee--Lebanon; Architecture--Tennessee--Lebanon; Education--Tennessee--Lebanon; Universities and colleges--Tennessee--Lebanon; School facilities--Tennessee--Lebanon; Educational facilities--Tennessee--Lebanon; Universities &amp; Colleges--Tennessee--Lebanon</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Cumberland Square (Lebanon, Tenn.); Lebanon (Tenn.)--Intellectual life; Lebanon (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Lebanon (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1913</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Nash - 72a - Dormitory, Cumberland University, Lebanon, Tenn.</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1910-1919</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/814</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>