<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Miss Nashville Pageant contestants with Mayor Ben West and Pat Boone, 1954</dc:title>
<dc:description>Pictured: Four 1954 Miss Nashville Pageant contestants posing with Mayor Ben West and entertainer Pat Boone.  Charles Eugene &#8220;Pat&#8221; Boone (born June 1, 1934) was born in Jacksonville, Florida and his family moved to Nashville when he was two years old.  He attended and graduated from David Lipscomb High School in 1952, then next enrolled in David Lipscomb College. Pat Boone began recording for Nashville&#8217;s Republic Records in 1954. One of the convertible cars in this photo displays a sign that reads: &#8220;Pat Boone, Republic Records, Three Times Winner of the Ted Mack Program.&#8221;  Another sign reads: &#8220;Mary Ann Lawrence, sponsored by Popcorn Village.&#8221;  Forms part of Record Group 3, Metro Davidson County Photographer. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>West, Ben, 1911-1974;  Boone, Pat; Lawrence, Mary Ann</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Beauty contests--Tennessee--Nashville; Beauty contestants--Tennessee--Nashville; Celebrities--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1954</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 3 8380 Miss Nashville 1954 contestants w Pat Boone &amp; West 002</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3 Metro Davidson County Photographer</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/5816</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>