<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Tony Sudekum Memorial Planetarium at Nashville Children&#8217;s Museum, circa 1950s</dc:title>
<dc:description>A scene from a special event at the Tony Sudekum Memorial Planetarium in the Nashville Children&#8217;s Museum, circa 1950s.  A planetarium is a theatre built primarily for presenting educational and entertaining shows about astronomy and the night sky.  Beginning in 1951, Mrs. Sudekum generously donated funds for the construction of a planetarium as a gift to the children of Nashville in her husband&#8217;s memory.  The Sudekum Planetarium was dedicated on March 3rd, 1952, with Dr. Armand Spitz, the designer of the planetarium instrument, as the guest of honor.  The facility featured a Spitz 512 star projector, one CRT video projector, and 36 slide projectors under a 40 foot diameter dome ceiling, with circular rows of upholstered, reclining seats that seated and audience capacity of 116.  The Sudekum Planetarium was located on the second floor of the Nashville Children&#8217;s Museum at 724 Second Avenue S in downtown Nashville, Tennessee.  In 1974, the entity changed its name to the Cumberland Museum and Science Center, and moved to new facilities at 800 Ridley Boulevard, the predecessor of the Adventure Science Center.  Forms part of Record Group 3, Metro Davidson County Photographer. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in. </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Sudekum family; Spitz, Armand</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Children&#8217;s Museum, Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Planetariums--Tennessee--Nashville; Astronomy--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Entertainment--Tennessee--Nashville  </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc. ; Second Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1950s</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG3 1228 Children's Museum, Tony Sudekum Memorial Planetarium March 1958 012</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3 Metro Davidson County Photographer   </dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/6913</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>