<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>St. Thomas Hospital, Nashville, Tenn., between 1930 and 1945</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard of St. Thomas Hospital located on Hayes Street at the corner of Twentieth Avenue.  This hospital was established by Bishop Thomas S. Byrne, and run by the Sisters of Charity under the Roman Catholic Church.  In 1974, St. Thomas opened a new building on Harding Road.  The newest wing of the facility is now used by Baptist Hospital, while the rest of the structure was torn down for a parking lot.  Forms part of the Norton Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Saint Thomas Hospital (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Capital City; Medicine; Downtown Nashville; Public Health; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Hospitals--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Urban hospitals--Tennessee--Nashville; Health facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Hospital buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Catholic hospitals--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social conditions; Hayes Street (Nashville, Tenn.); Twentieth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>between 1930 and 1945</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Norton - 0301</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Norton Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939; 1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1954</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>