<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Portrait of Eliza Dewees Tannehill, ca. 1914</dc:title>
<dc:description>Eliza Tannehill in late middle age, wearing a bonnet tied in a bow at the neck and a dark dress with a large collar.  She is seated on a red chair.  Eliza Dewees Tannehill was born in 1789 in Kentucky and died in 1843 in Nashville.  She married Wilkins Tannehill in 1810.  Wilkins Tannehill was born in 1787 in Pennsylvania and died in 1858 in Nashville.  He was a merchant, banker, writer, editor, and Masonic leader, and he served as Nashville's Mayor from 1825-1827.  Oil on canvas.  Presented to the library in January 1966 by Tannehill's great-grandson, Wilkins Tannehill Bayless.  The portrait is currently on display in the Nashville Room on the Nashville Public Library's second floor.  The portrait was painted by a family member, Frances Elizabeth Bayless Willett, around 1914 and modeled after the original done by Washington B. Cooper around 1840.  The original is held by the Tennessee State Museum, 505 Deaderick Street, Nashville, TN 37243.

The library's portraits were photographed as part of the National Society of The Colonial Dames of America in Tennessee's Tennessee Portrait Project (http://www.tnportraits.org/index.htm).  </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Tannehill, Eliza Dewees, 1789-1843--Portraits</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Popular Culture; Portraits, American--20th century; Portraits--Tennessee--Nashville; Authors' spouses--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Willett, Frances Elizabeth Bayless, 1840-1924 (Artist)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>National Society of The Colonial Dames of America in Tennessee</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1914</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Portraits; Paintings</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>tannehill-eliza-lg</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Portrait Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1910-1919</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1867</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>