<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Eastland Baptist Church, 2001 January</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of the Eastland Baptist Church located at 1215 Gallatin Road in Nashville, Tennessee.  This church's congregation formed in 1911 and originally met in the home of one of the members.  Their first church building was built on the Southwest corner of Greenwood and Chapel Avenues.  The current building on Gallatin Road was erected almost ten years later and the first service was held in December of 1920.  In 1922 the church voted to erect a new auditorium.  In 1923 the church voted to erect a two-story addition to the church building on the North side for Sunday school classes.  As the years continued other renovations and additions were added as needed.  The architecture style is Classical Revival.  The foundation is made of stone.  The exterior walls are red brick and stretcher.  There is an asphalt shingle roof.  The front and side windows are marbleized glass.  The doors are wooden.  Special features include a historic pipe organ and marble pillars on the interior of the sanctuary.  Forms part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project. 1 photograph : col. ; 4  x 6  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Eastland Baptist Church (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Popular Culture; Religion; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Religious facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Church architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Baptist church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Brick churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Columns--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Details; Churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville; Baptist churches--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs; Gallatin Road (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2001-01</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>SSSP - Eastland Baptist</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/776</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>