<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of the United States Post Office, Nashville, Tennessee, between 1979-1998</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of the United States Post Office on Broadway, between Ninth Avenue South and Tenth Avenue South. It was designed by the Nashville architectural firm of Marr and Holman (Thomas Scott Marr and Joseph W. Holman) and constructed in 1933-34 with funds allocated by Congress during the Hoover administration. Marr and Holman adhered to project guidelines stating that the front of the building should be in a classical style, while the interior is Art Deco. The building was listed on the National Register of Historic Sites in 1984. It served as the main U.S. Post Office for Nashville until 1986, when a new central processing facility opened in Donelson. It continued to serve as a downtown branch of the post office after that time. The building was transferred to the city of Nashville in 1998 in preparation for its use as the home to the Frist Center for the Visual Arts. The Downtown Branch USPO moved into new quarters on the lower level, Tenth Avenue side, of the building in 1999. The Frist Center opened in 2001. The lobby of the Frist has been restored to the 1934 design; with the exception of glass doors leading to exhibit galleries and Art Deco style benches that are not original. The exact date of the image is unknown, but the type of film and information on the slide mount suggests it was taken sometime between the late 1970s and the photographer's death in 1998. Photographed by the Nashville architect Charles Wesley Warterfield, Jr. (1926-1998); the architectural photograph forms part of the Charles Warterfield Architectural Collection. Gift of: The Estate of Charles W. Warterfield, Jr., F. A. I. A. The original is a 35 mm color transparency (2 x 2 in. slide mount)</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Frist Center for the Visual Arts (Nashville, Tenn.); United States Post Office (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Popular Culture; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Post offices--Tennessee--Nashville; Government facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Broadway Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Warterfield, Charles W. (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Estate of Charles W. Warterfield, Jr., F. A. I. A. (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>between 1979-1998</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still image; Slides; Architectural photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/tiff</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>WSC 0773</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Charles Warterfield Architectural Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1970-1979; 1980-1989; 1990-1999</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/44</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>