<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Printer&#8217;s Alley, Nashville, Tennessee, 1958 February</dc:title>
<dc:description>A view of Printer&#8217;s Alley, Nashville, Tennessee, February 1958.  The businesses pictured in this photo are: Irvin&#8217;s Restaurant, Rainbow Room, Carousel, Wherry Furniture Company, and the VooDoo Room.  Printer&#8217;s Alley is named for Nashville&#8217;s publishing and printing industry that started in this immediate area before the turn of the twentieth century.  During the 1920s&#8217; Prohibition, there were several speakeasies in the alley.  During the 1940s, nightclubs opened in the alley when the entertainment district was a showcase for the talents of performers such as Boots Randolph, Chet Atkins, Waylon Jennings, Dottie West, Hank Williams, Barbara Mandrell, and Jimi Hendrix.  Printer&#8217;s Alley continues to be a popular entertainment destination for both locals and tourists.  Printer&#8217;s Alley is a National Register Historic District.  Forms part of Record Group 3, Metro Davidson County Photographer. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Printer&#8217;s Alley (Nashville, Tenn.); Irwin&#8217;s Restaurant (Nashville, Tenn.); Rainbow Room (Nashville, Tenn.); Carousel (Nashville, Tenn.); Wherry Furniture Company (Nashville, Tenn.); Voodoo Room (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Businesses--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Commercial buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Nightclubs--Tennessee--Nashville; Alleys--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Printers Alley (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1958-02</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG3 7684 Printers Alley Feb 1958 001</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3 Metro Davidson County Photographer</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/6815</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>