<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Yearbook &#8220;Salmagundi,&#8221; of Boscobel College for Young Ladies, Nashville, Tennessee, 1911</dc:title>
<dc:description>The 1911 yearbook, known as &#8220;Salmagundi,&#8221; published by Boscobel College for Young Ladies, featuring students, faculty, trustees, clubs, athletics, societies, and more.  Boscobel College for Young Ladies was a college in East Nashville, founded in 1889 as the Nashville Baptist Female College by the Tennessee Baptist Convention.  The college operated for twenty-five years--until 1914.  The campus was built around an East Nashville mansion, formerly owned by Anna Shelby Williams.  The mansion stood atop a tree-covered hill overlooking the Cumberland River.  The campus covered ten wooded acres on Sevier Street near South Seventh Street (then called Foster Street), south of Sylvan Street.  In 1918, the property became home to the National Baptist Seminary and Missionary Training School, which functioned until 1931. The buildings were razed in 1940.  Several Nashville businesses are advertised, including: Boscobel College (Nashville, Tenn.); Parrish Shoe Company (Nashville, Tenn.); Gray-Fox Tailoring Co. (Nashville, Tenn.); Calvert Brothers (Nashville, Tenn.);  Starr Piano Company (Nashville, Tenn.); Skalowski&#8217;s Candy (Nashville, Tenn.); Geny Brothers (Nashville, Tenn.); Maxwell House Hotel (Nashville, Tenn.); George R. Calhoun &amp; Company (Nashville, Tenn.).; Phillips and Buttorff Manufacturing Company (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville Railway and Light Company; Hermitage Hotel (Nashville, Tenn.); DeMoville Drug Company (Nashville, Tenn.); H.A. French Music Publisher (Nashville, Tenn.); Harris, Davis &amp; Company (Nashville, Tenn.); Foster &amp; Parkes (Nashville, Tenn.); Howe&#8217;s Distilled Water (Nashville, Tenn.); Overton &amp; Bush (Nashville, Tenn.); M. Cook &amp; Company (Nashville, Tenn.); Joy Floral Company (Nashville, Tenn.); Cumberland Telephone &amp; Telegraph Company (Nashville, Tenn.); W.J. Cude Land &amp; Lumber Company (Nashville, Tenn.); Loventhal, Frank &amp; Company (Nashville, Tenn.); B.H. Stief Jewelry Co. (Nashville, Tenn.); Standard Furniture Company (Nashville, Tenn.); Corbitt Photographers (Nashville, Tenn.); Duncan Hotel (Nashville, Tenn.); W.C. Tucker (Nashville, Tenn.); Herbrick &amp; Lawrence (Nashville, Tenn.); Thuss Photographers (Nashville, Tenn.); Jack Walters (Nashville, Tenn.); Crone &amp; Jackson (Nashville, Tenn.; H. G. Hill (Nashville, Tenn.); Dury&#8217;s Photo Stock House (Nashville, Tenn.); W.C. Williams &amp; Company (Nashville, Tenn.); M.E. Derryberry &amp; Company (Nashville, Tenn.); White Trunk &amp; Bag Company (Nashville, Tenn.); Royal Shoe Company (Nashville, Tenn.); Fatherland Pharmacy (Nashville, Tenn.); Wharton - Yarbrough Paint and Glass Co. (Nashville, Tenn.); Greenfield-Talbot Furniture Co. (Nashville, Tenn.); Walk-Over Shoe Co. (Nashville, Tenn.); Davis, Hicks &amp; Green Co. (Nashville, Tenn.); McEwen Laundry (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville Laundry Co. (Nashville, Tenn.); Belle Camp Chocolates (Nashville, Tenn.); and the Standard Printing Company (Nashville, Tenn.)
Forms part of the yearbook collection: Boscobel College, &#8220;Salmagundi,&#8221; 1911.  1 volume 
</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Boscobel College (Nashville, Tenn.); Parrish Shoe Company (Nashville, Tenn.); Gray-Fox Tailoring Co. (Nashville, Tenn.); Calvert Brothers (Nashville, Tenn.);  Starr Piano Company (Nashville, Tenn.); Skalowski&#8217;s Candy (Nashville, Tenn.); Geny Brothers (Nashville, Tenn.); Maxwell House Hotel (Nashville, Tenn.); George R. Calhoun &amp; Company (Nashville, Tenn.).; Phillips and Buttorff Manufacturing Company (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville Railway and Light Company; Hermitage Hotel (Nashville, Tenn.); DeMoville Drug Company (Nashville, Tenn.); H.A. French Music Publisher (Nashville, Tenn.); Harris, Davis &amp; Company (Nashville, Tenn.); Foster &amp; Parkes (Nashville, Tenn.); Howe&#8217;s Distilled Water (Nashville, Tenn.); Overton &amp; Bush (Nashville, Tenn.); M. Cook &amp; Company (Nashville, Tenn.); Joy Floral Company (Nashville, Tenn.); Cumberland Telephone &amp; Telegraph Company (Nashville, Tenn.); W.J. Cude Land &amp; Lumber Company (Nashville, Tenn.); Loventhal, Frank &amp; Company (Nashville, Tenn.); B.H. Stief Jewelry Co. (Nashville, Tenn.); Standard Furniture Company (Nashville, Tenn.); Corbitt Photographers (Nashville, Tenn.); Duncan Hotel (Nashville, Tenn.); W.C. Tucker (Nashville, Tenn.); Herbrick &amp; Lawrence (Nashville, Tenn.); Thuss Photographers (Nashville, Tenn.); Jack Walters (Nashville, Tenn.); Crone &amp; Jackson (Nashville, Tenn.; H. G. Hill (Nashville, Tenn.); Dury&#8217;s Photo Stock House (Nashville, Tenn.); W.C. Williams &amp; Company (Nashville, Tenn.); M.E. Derryberry &amp; Company (Nashville, Tenn.); White Trunk &amp; Bag Company (Nashville, Tenn.); Royal Shoe Company (Nashville, Tenn.); Fatherland Pharmacy (Nashville, Tenn.); Wharton - Yarbrough Paint and Glass Co. (Nashville, Tenn.); Greenfield-Talbot Furniture Co. (Nashville, Tenn.); Walk-Over Shoe Co. (Nashville, Tenn.); Davis, Hicks &amp; Green Co. (Nashville, Tenn.); McEwen Laundry (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville Laundry Co. (Nashville, Tenn.); Belle Camp Chocolates (Nashville, Tenn.); Standard Printing Company (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Advertising--History--Sources; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Business enterprises--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Education--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Universities and colleges--Tennessee--Nashville; Women--Tennessee--Nashville; School facilities--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Intellectual life</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Davis, Betty Dorris (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1911</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Boscobel College Yearbook 1911</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Boscobel College Yearbook 1911</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1910-1919</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/8766</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>