<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Rice School Rhythm Band, from the Nashville Times, 1940</dc:title>
<dc:description>A captioned photo from the Nashville Times (1940), about &#8220;The Rhythm Band of the Rice Kindergarten and Primary School gave a program recently at the Hobson Methodist Church for the William B. Bate Chapter, U. D. C. and for the beginners&#8217; department of the Hobson church. Members of the band seen from left to right above, are as follows: Phillip Hummel, Joanne Scott, Neel Beard, Nancy Ann Simmons, Bobby Robinson, Betty Jean Earhart, Betty Banker, Jack Payne, R. V. Hickey, and Joe Payne.&#8221; One of the first kindergartens in Nashville was opened in the 1920s by Zula Smith Rice on Scott Avenue. Forms part of the Nashville Times newspaper collection. 1 digital photo.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rice Kindergarten and Primary School (Nashville, Tenn.); United Daughters of the Confederacy. William B. Bate Chapter (Nashville, Tenn.); Hobson Methodist Church (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Entertainment events--Tennessee--Nashville; Students--Tennessee--Nashville; Children--Tennessee--Nashville; Bands (Music)--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1940</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RiceSchoolRhythmBand--NT-1940</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Times Newspaper Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4234</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>