<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of the vaulted ceiling interior of the Union Station Hotel, Nashville, Tennessee, between 1986 and 1989</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of the vaulted ceiling interior of the Union Station Hotel, 1001 Broadway, Nashville, Tennessee. The Romanesque-style building was constructed 1898-1900 as the depot for the Louisville and Nashville Railroad. It was designed by Richard Montfort, architect for the railway. This view is of the hotel lobby and dining area in what would have been the central lobby of the train station. The station and adjoining train shed, an unusually large single-span, gable roof structure, were jointly added to the National Register of Historic Places in 1969 and designated as a National Landmark in 1976. The station deteriorated until it was closed in 1975, but the shed was still used until 1979. The station was restored and reopened as a hotel in 1986. The shed was damaged by fire and demolished in 2000. Because the engineering significance of the train shed was part of the reason for National Landmark status, Union Station lost that designation in 2003.  Photographed by the Nashville architect Charles Wesley Warterfield, Jr. (1926-1998); the architectural photograph forms part of the Charles Warterfield Architectural Collection. Gift of: The Estate of Charles W. Warterfield, Jr., F. A. I. A.  The original is a 35 mm color transparency (2 x 2 in. slide mount)</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Montfort, Richard</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Union Station (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Transportation; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville;  Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architects--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Details; Transportation--Tennessee--Nashville; Railroads--Buildings and structures--Tennessee--Nashville; Transportation buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Railroad stations--Tennessee--Nashville; Hotels--Tennessee--Nashville; Ceilings--Tennessee--Nashville; Vaults (Architecture); Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Warterfield, Charles W. (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Estate of Charles W. Warterfield, Jr., F.A.I.A. (Donor); Montfort, Richard (Architect)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>between 1986 and 1989</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Slides; Photographs; Architectural photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/tiff</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>WSC 4395</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Charles Warterfield Architectural Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1980-1989</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/488</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>