<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Skyline at night, Nashville, Tennessee, between 1930 and 1945</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard of the Nashville city skyline at night circa 1930.  The scene is possibly a view from the Woodland Street Bridge or Jefferson Street Bridge looking toward the Shelby Street Bridge.  The state capitol is discernable in the distance.  The Cumberland River is pictured in the foreground.   Forms part of the Norton Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Tennessee State Capitol (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Architecture; Buildings; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Rivers--Tennessee--Nashville; Bridges--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Cityscapes</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Cumberland River (Ky. and Tenn.)--Navigation; Shelby Street Bridge (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Capitol News Co. (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>between 1930 and 1945</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Norton - 0389</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Norton Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939; 1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1814</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>