<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Mayor Ben West with Japanese representatives at Genesco, 1961 March 09</dc:title>
<dc:description>Pictured left to right: Yanosuke Yoshioka, representative director of Chiyoda Shoe Co., Tokyo; Yasuma Oda, director of Chiyoda and of Genesco Japan; Mayor Ben West; Stephen Klausner, president of Genesco&#8217;s Intercontinental Shoe Co.; Toshinoshin Sakurai, president of Tokyo Plat Shoe Manufacturing Co.; and Kyo Kaneko, Chiyoda engineer.  During their 10-day tour of the Nashville business, the Tokyo shoe manufacturing officials were also awarded gold keys and honorary citizenship of Nashville by Mayor Ben West.  Genesco was originally founded as the Jarman Shoe Company in 1924 as a footwear manufacturer, they were later renamed the General Shoe Company in the 1930s.  The company took its current name, Genesco, in 1959.  Under the leadership of W. Maxey Jarman, the son of co-founder J.F. Jarman, the company began the process of diversifying and expanding the business into an international apparel conglomerate.  Forms part of Record Group 3, Metro Davidson County Photographer. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>West, Ben, 1911-1974; Klausner, Stephen</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Genesco, Inc.--History</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Business enterprises--Tennessee--Nashville; Commerce--Tennessee--Nashville; Businesspeople--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Mayors--Tennessee--Nashville; Businessmen--Tennessee--Nashville; Businessmen--Japan--Tokyo</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1961-03-09</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 3 819 Genesco Japanese Reps w MayorWest mar9 1961 010</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/5963</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>