<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Oral history interview with Angelo Anderson and Angela Anderson Jones, 1986 October 21</dc:title>
<dc:description>Excerpts from an oral history interview with Angelo Anderson and his daughter Angela Anderson Jones, conducted on 21 Oct. 1986 by John Egerton as part of the Homecoming '86 Oral History Project. Anderson and Jones discuss Anderson's immigration to the United States from Greece in 1901 and his experiences upon arrival in the U.S.; Anderson's conscription into the Greek army while on a visit back home in 1912; Anderson's buying his uncle's shoeshine business in 1905; other Greek families in Nashville; Anderson's witnessing the Cooper-Carmack shooting in 1908; Anderson's business experiences in Nashville, including operating Candyland; Greek traditions that continued in the United States, including "fixed" marriages and membership in the Greek Orthodox Church; and Anderson's wine making during Prohibition.  The complete interview, as well as an index, is available in the Special Collections Division.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Anderson, Angelo, 1886-1991--Interviews; Jones, Angela Anderson, 1914-1990--Interviews; Carmack, Edward Ward, 1858-1908; Cooper, Duncan Brown; Cooper, Robin, d. 1919</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Greece. Stratos--Recruiting, enlistment, etc.; Orthodoxos Ekklesia tes Hellados; Candyland (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Business; Enterprise; Capital City; Crime; Popular Culture; Greeks--Tennessee--Nashville; Emigration and immigration--20th century; Immigrants--United States--20th century; Immigrants--Tennessee--Nashville--Interviews; Children of immigrants--Tennessee--Nashville; Draft--Greece; Business enterprises--Tennessee--Nashville; Greeks--United States--Social life and customs; Greeks--United States--Religious life and customs; Marriage customs and rites-Greece; Wine and wine making--Tennessee--Nashville; Prohibition--Tennessee--Nashville; Candy industry--Tennessee--Nashville; Murder--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Commerce; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Economic conditions</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Anderson, Angelo, 1886-1991 (Interviewee); Jones, Angela Anderson, 1914-1990 (Interviewee); Egerton, John (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1986-10-21</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>OHP86Anderson1aclip1.mp3; OHP86Anderson1aclip2.mp3; OHP86Anderson1aclip3.mp3; OHP86Anderson1aclip4.mp3; OHP86Anderson1bclip1.mp3; OHP86Anderson1bclip2.mp3; OHP86Anderson2clip1.mp3; OHP86Anderson2clip2.mp3; OHP86Anderson_transcript.pdf</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from:  OHP86Anderson audio cassette recording converted to digital format in 2006.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Homecoming '86 Oral History Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1980-1989</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1939</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>