<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Maxwell House Hotel, circa 1950-1961</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of the Maxwell House Hotel in downtown Nashville, Tennessee. This five-story hotel was begun by John Overton in 1859, but the Civil War delayed its completion. It was used for barracks for both Union soldiers and Confederate prisoners during the war. It eventually opened for business as a hotel in 1869. The Maxwell House was known for the lavish Christmas dinners it provided and played host to a variety of dignitaries, including U. S. presidents, over the years. Joel Cheek named his blended coffee that was served in its restaurant for the hotel, creating Maxwell House Coffee. The building was located on the corner of 4th Avenue N. (formerly Cherry Street) and Church Street (formerly Spring Street) with the entrance opening onto 4th Avenue. It burned on Christmas Night, 1961 and the gutted remains were razed in 1962 for safety reasons. A bank was eventually built at the location. Photographed by the Nashville architect Charles Wesley Warterfield, Jr. (1926-1998); the architectural photograph forms part of the Charles Warterfield Architectural Collection. Gift of: The Estate of Charles W. Warterfield, Jr., F. A. I. A. The original is a 35 mm color transparency (2 x 2 in. slide mount).</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Maxwell House Hotel (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Popular Culture; Architects--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Fourth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Church Street (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Warterfield, Charles W. (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Estate of Charles W. Warterfield, Jr., F.A.I.A. (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>between 1950 and 1961</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Slides; Photographs; Architectural photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>WSC 534</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Charles Warterfield Architectural Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959; 1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/8</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>