<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Program, The Nashville Community Playhouse, presentation of &#8220;The Tempest,&#8221; 1947 December </dc:title>
<dc:description>A Nashville Community Playhouse program for a theatrical production of William Shakespeare&#8217;s &#8220;The Tempest,&#8221; presented December 10th-20th, 1947.  This production, in conjunction with the Nashville Children&#8217;s Theatre, was directed by Raymond Johnson and Carolyn Binkley.  The production scheme was by Wyman Kane; Detailed set painting by Christine Tibbott; Lighting by Bill Alder; Choreography by Albertine; Music directed by Walter Ihrke and Martha Eatherly; Special Music Composed by Dennis Arundell; Walter Ihrke, Pianist; and Elizabeth Wilfley, Harpist.  The actors in the play were Madge Joseph, Daniel Burton, Robert Garber, Raymond Johnson, Tom Hays, Jim Denham, Milton Carney, Arthur Wills, Wyman Kane, James Maddux, Robert Goldman, Sylvia Stahlman, Whit Stokes, Brock Stokes, Dorothy Parkes, Bonnie Sandefur, Mildred Joy, Josephine Gibson, Lois Feldkircher, Teena Sullivan Cumfer, Connie Ewin, Bitsy Higgins, Nancy White, Ruth Woodard, William Hickman, Bobby Gene Mayo, Jack Sandefur, Frederick Stansberry, Bob Strobel, Barbara Ann Pratt, Betsy Riddle, Gloria Stratton, Anne Riley Whitmer, and Rita Zeitlin.  Forms part of the Wilhelmina Webb Collection. 1 program. </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Johnson, Raymond; Binkley, Carolyn</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Community Playhouse (Nashville, Tenn.)--History--Sources; Belcourt Theatre (Nashville, Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Performances--Tennessee--Nashville; Performing arts--Tennessee--Nashville; Entertainment--Tennessee--Nashville; Advertising--Tennessee--Nashville; Community theater--Tennessee--Nashville; Theater--Tennessee--Nashville; Theatrical companies--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Belcourt Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1947-12</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Programs; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Wilhelmina Webb Collection Nash Community Playhouse progs 1940-47 The Tempest 001 - 020</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Wilhelmina Webb Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/9274</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>