<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Nashville Banner Business Manager advertising correspondence, circa 1892</dc:title>
<dc:description>A piece of commercial advertising correspondence created by Edgar M. Foster, business manager of the Nashville Banner from 1891 to at least 1915.  In this letter, Foster urges advertisers to consider placing ads with the Nashville Banner because of its wide distribution.  In this letter, Foster claims that the Banner's circulation exceeds that of any other Nashville paper.  He also mentions that an enclosed editorial clipping further attests to that claim.  Forms part of the Nashville Banner. Business Manager. Advertising correspondence, 1891-1915. (bulk 1900-1901). 1 letter : b &amp; w ; 8.5 x 11 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Foster, Edgar M.--Correspondence</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Banner</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Business; Capital City; Advertisements; Printing/Publishing; Downtown Nashville; Industries; Enterprise; Newspapers--Tennessee--Nashville; Business--Tennessee--Nashville; Business enterprises--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Businesspeople--Tennessee--Nashville; Communication--Tennessee--Nashville; Mass media--Tennessee--Nashville; Journalism--Tennessee--Nashville; Newspaper publishing--Tennessee--Nashville; Correspondence--Tennessee--Nashville; Advertising--Newspapers--Tennessee--Nashville; Newspaper industry--Tennessee--Nashville; Business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Advertising--Tennessee--Nashville; Commercial organizations--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Commerce</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Foster, Edgar M. (Correspondent)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1892</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text; Letters (correspondence); Commercial correspondence; Print advertising</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>ESF - Bus - Banner Bus. Manager</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner. Business Manager. Advertising correspondence, 1891-1915. (bulk 1900-1901)</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1890-1899</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/821</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>