<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>The Draughon Building, between 1907 and 1917</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard of the Draughon Building in downtown Nashville, Tennessee. The 1930 Nashville City Directory lists their address at 124-126 8th Avenue North. The early 20th century postcard description reads: "Nashville, Tenn., home office of Draughon's Practical Business Colleges; established 1888; $300,000.00 capital; 31 Colleges in 17 States: Nashville, Washington, Atlanta, Austin, Columbia (S.C.), Dallas, Denison, El Paso, Evansville, Ft. Worth, Ft. Scott, Ft. Smith, Galveston, Houston, Jackson (Miss.), Jacksonville, Kansas City, Knoxville, Little Rock, Memphis, Montgomery, Muskogee, Oklahoma City, Paducah, Raleigh, St. Louis, San Antonio, Shreveport, Springfield (Mo.), Tyler, and Waco. Jno. F. Draughon, President." Forms part of the Nashville Room Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Draughon Practical Business College (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Education; Colleges and Universities; Business; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Business schools--Tennessee--Nashville; Education--Tennessee--Nashville; Universities and colleges--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Eighth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>between 1907 and 1917</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Nash - 72b</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1900-1909; 1910-1919</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/2290</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>