<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>First Baptist Church - Capitol Hill, 2001 November</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of First Baptist Church Capitol Hill.  Originally called First Colored Baptist Church, this African American church was founded by Reverend Nelson Merry in 1865.  The church sprang from the First Colored Baptist Mission, a group of African American Baptists that requested independence from the parent white Baptist church.  In 1865, First Baptist on Broadway granted the group independence and eventually the new church built a building on the northwest corner of Eighth Avenue North (Spruce) and Cedar (Charlotte) Street.  This church served as the headquarters of the Nashville sit-in movement.  It was there that strategy sessions, nonviolence workshops and mass rallies took place.  The church changed its name to the First Baptist Church Capitol Hill in 1969.  Nashville architect, L. Quincy Jackson, designed the present building in 1972 at 900 James Robertson Parkway and Nelson G. Merry Street.  The architecture style is modern.  The foundation is made of stone.  The exterior walls are comprised of concrete and bricks.  Forms part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project. 1 photograph : col. ; 4  x 6  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>First Colored Baptist Church (Nashville, Tenn.); First Baptist Church Capitol Hill (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Popular Culture; Religion; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Religious facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Church architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Baptist church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Brick churches--Tennessee--Nashville; African American churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture, Modern--Tennessee--Nashville; Protestant church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Baptist churches--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs; James Robertson Parkway (Nashville, Tenn.); Nelson G. Merry Street (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2001-11</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>SSSP - 1st Baptist Capitol Hill</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/887</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>