<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Nativity Scene at Centennial Park, Nashville, Tennessee, between 1953 and 1967</dc:title>
<dc:description>Pictured: A view of the Nativity exhibition at Centennial Park, between 1953 and 1967.  The origins of this special exhibit began in 1953 when Nashville businessman Fred Harvey and Harvey&#8217;s Department Store began sponsoring this exhibition at Centennial Park.  It was on view yearly during the Christmas season. Thousands of Nashvillians were drawn to Centennial Park by the beauty of this life-size cre&#768;che. The sculpted design was created by Guido Rabacini and made by the Silvestri Art Manufacturing Company of Chicago at a cost of approximately $20,000. The last year the nativity scene was on display was 1967. Forms part of the Bill Goodman Photographic Slides Collection.  1 35 mm negative.  </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Parthenon (Art museum : Nashville, Tenn.) </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Urban parks--Tennessee--Nashville; Parks--Tennessee--Nashville; Cultural parks--Tennessee--Nashville; Christmas--Tennessee--Nashville; Cre&#768;ches (Nativity scenes)--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc. </dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Goodman, Bill (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>between 1953 and 1967</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Goodman Slides Nashville 294</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Bill Goodman 35 mm Slides Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959; 1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/10414</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>