<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Christ Church Cathedral, 2001 May</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of Christ Church Cathedral located at 900 Broadway Avenue, Nashville, Tennessee.  Christ Church Cathedral serves as the Cathedral for the Episcopal Diocese of Tennessee.  Originally built in 1830 on the corner of Sixth Avenue and Church Street, Christ Church underwent a move of location after sixty years.  In 1890 the church was sold and a new lot was purchased for a new church on Broad and McLemore (Ninth Avenue).  The present structure was completed in 1894 and still stands today as Christ Church Cathedral.  The Victorian Gothic structure was designed by Francis Hatch Kimball of New York.  Christ Church was constructed of Sewanee sandstone, a gift from the University of the South.  Bowling Green grey stone was used in the trim, the gargoyles and later in the tower.  The gabled and hipped roof is comprised of slate shingles and has a very complex structure.  A mix of Gothic arched and circular shaped, stained glass windows with finished stone blocks surrounding the glass are frequently placed amongst the walls.  Having undergone recent renovations and restorations, Christ Church now offers free weekly guided tours.  Forms part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project. 1 photograph : col. ; 4  x 6  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Christ Church Cathedral (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Popular Culture; Religion; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Religious facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Church architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Episcopal church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Protestant church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church architecture--Details; Cathedrals--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture, Gothic--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture, Victorian--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Episcopal churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Protestant churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville; Religious architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs; Broadway Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Ninth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2001-05</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>SSSP - Christ Church Cathedral</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/741</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>