<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Excerpt 1 from oral history interview with Joseph R. O'Donnell, 2003 July 07</dc:title>
<dc:description>An excerpt from an oral history interview with Joseph R. O'Donnell, conducted on 7 July 2003 by Robert P. Richardson as part of the Nashville Public Library's Veterans History Project.  As a Marine photographer, O'Donnell was assigned to overseas duty in the Pacific theater, where he took pictures of the  two cities of Hiroshima and Nagasaki, just after the atomic bomb blasts.  In this excerpt, O'Donnell discusses the view from a hilltop overlooking Nagasaki.  The complete interview, as well as a transcript, is available in the repository.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>O'Donnell, Joe (Joseph Roger), 1922- --Interviews</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Veterans History Project (U.S.); United States. Marine Corps--Interviews</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Military History; World War II; World War, 1939-1945--Veterans--Tennessee--Nashville; Veterans--Tennessee--Interviews; World War, 1939-1945--Photography; World War, 1939-1945--Destruction and pillage--Japan; Atomic bomb--Japan--Blast effect; Photographers--Interviews</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nagasaki-shi (Japan)--Description and travel; Nagasaki-shi (Japan)--History--Bombardment, 1945</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>O'Donnell, Joe (Joseph Roger), 1922- (Interviewee); Richardson, Robert Price, 1926- (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>James, Carolyn (Transcriber)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>2003-07-07</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3 (344 KB; 22 sec.)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>VHPODonnelJ1aclip1</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from:  VHPODonnellJ (VHP tapes 169 &amp; 170) audio cassette recording converted to mp3 format in 2006.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Veterans History Project collection, World War II series</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/234</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>