<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Navy Submarine Chaser launched by Mrs. Francis Craig in Nashville, Tennessee, 1942 September</dc:title>
<dc:description>A scene from the launch of a World War II Navy submarine chaser, built in Nashville, and dedicated by Mrs. Francis Craig, circa September 1942. The Nashville Bridge Company built this vessel at a facility along the Cumberland River near downtown Nashville.  Forms part of Record Group 412, Photographs Collection. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Craig family</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Bridge Company</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Shipbuilding industry--Tennessee--Nashville; Business enterprises--Tennessee--Nashville; Rivers--Tennessee--Nashville; Industries--Tennessee--Nashville; Steel industry and trade--Tennessee--Nashville; Transportation--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Cumberland River (Ky. and Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1942-09</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 412 712 Navy Sub chaser launch by MrsFrancisCraig Sept1942 007</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 412</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/5610</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>