<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Handwritten letter to &#8220;the Honorable County Commissioners,&#8221; from Mrs. A.C. Parrish, Nashville, Tennessee, 1886 January 21 </dc:title>
<dc:description>A handwritten letter to &#8220;the Honorable County Commissioners, from Mrs. A.C. Parrish, dated Jan. 21st, 1886.  She states her ownership of &#8220;80 ft. of ground on the west side of Sth College St. and known as Parrish&#8217;s Stable.&#8221;  The First Ward of Nashville in the year 1880 began &#8220;at the Suspension Bridge, running west along the south side of the Public Square to College Street, along the Square to Deaderick Street, west on Deaderick Street to Cherry Street, south on Cherry Street to Demonbreun Street, east on Demonbreun Street in a direct line to the Cumberland River, thence along said river to the beginning.&#8221;  Forms part of the Davidson County Court, Loose Records-Additions-Wards. 1letter. </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Parrish family</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Parrish Stable (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Business enterprises--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Correspondence--Tennessee--Nashville; Business--Tennessee--Nashville; Businesspeople--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; College Street (Nashville, Tenn.); Third Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1886-01-21</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CountyCourtLooseRecords-Add Ward 1 003</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Davidson County Court, Loose Records-Additions-Wards</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1880-1889</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/9819</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>