<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of fire hall and staff of Engine Company 11, Nashville Fire Department, Nashville, Tennessee, 1956 March 01</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of the men of Engine Company 11 (located at 1204 Jefferson Street) standing in front of their fire hall honoring their leader, Captain Robert Campbell (holding award), who was retiring after being on the company roster 31 years as pipeman, lieutenant, and captain. They had a luncheon and presented him with an award stating "Outstanding service Nashville Fire Department, March 1, 1925 - March 1, 1956." The group included speakers E. T. Keeble and Robert E. Lillard, once a fireman himself. Forms part of the Nashville Banner Archives. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 3.25 x 4.25 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Campbell, Robert; Keeble, E.T.; Lillard, Robert Emmitt, 1907-1991</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.). Fire Department. Engine company 11</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Capital City; City Government; Architecture; Buildings; Fire Halls; Fire departments--Tennessee--Nashville; Fire stations--Tennessee--Nashville; Engine companies--Tennessee--Nashville; Fire fighters--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Jefferson Street (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Gunter, Jack (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1956-03-01</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/tiff (14.1 MB)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BN 1956-550</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/458</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>