<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>William E. Beard, Associate Editor of The Banner, circa 1940s</dc:title>
<dc:description>William E. Beard was born in 1873 at Estill Springs, Tennessee, son of Captain Richard and Maria L. Dromgoole Beard of Murfreesboro, Tennessee. During his career he was a soldier, journalist, war correspondent, naval historian, and long-time officer of the Tennessee Historical Commission and member of the Tennessee Historical Society.  After service in the Spanish-American War, he was a reporter with several newspapers and by 1910 was State news editor of the Nashville Banner.  In 1933, Beard was promoted to Associate Editor and during WWII he became an accredited navy War Correspondent.  He died in 1950 in Nashville, burial in Mt. Olivet Cemetery.  Forms part of Record Group 412, Photographs Collection. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Beard, W. E. (William Ewing), 1873-1950</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Banner</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Businesspeople--Tennessee--Nashville; Journalism--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1940s</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 412 103 Wm E Beard Assoc Editor of Banner 006</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 412</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/5182</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>