<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of Al Menah Temple Shriners leaving Union Station Nashville, Tennessee, for Southeastern Convention, 1959 November 03</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of the Al Menah Temple Shriners waving goodbye from the back of a train leaving Union Station in Nashville, Tennessee to attend the annual Southeastern Shrine Convention in Memphis, Tennessee where they stayed at the Peabody Hotel. The group includes Al Menah Potentate Judge Raymond Leathers, Floyd Pendelton, Potentate's Guard, and Governor and Mrs. Buford Ellington. More than 300 Shriners representing Nashville and Middle Tennessee were aboard the special 16-car train.  Forms part of the Nashville Banner Archives. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 3.25 x 4.25 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Leathers, Raymond; Pendelton, Floyd; Ellington, Buford, 1907-1972; Ellington, Catherine Ann Cheek</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Ancient Arabic Order of the Nobles of the Mystic Shrine for North America. Al Menah Temple (Nashville, Tenn.); Union Station (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Capital City; Organizations; Transportation; Popular Culture; Transportation--Tennessee--Nashville; Railroads--Buildings and structures--Tennessee--Nashville; Railroads--Tennessee--Nashville; Railroad trains--Tennessee--Nashville; Railroad travel--Tennessee--Nashville; Railroad stations--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Schleicher, Paul (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1959-11-03</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/tiff</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BN 1959-2129</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/461</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>