<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Letter from William Williamson to his brother, P.J. Williamson, during the Civil War, 1863 September 14</dc:title>
<dc:description>A letter from Dutch immigrant, William Williamson, to his brother, Peter J. Williamson, during the Civil War.  In 1862 Peter J. Williamson enlisted as a Private in the 1st Wisconsin Cavalry, Company F and was ultimately promoted to Full 1st Lieutenant.  During the war, Williamson's regiment was involved in scouting and raids in Missouri and Arkansas and saw battle in the Middle Tennessee, Chickamauga, and Atlanta campaigns. In this letter from Green Bay, Wisconsin, William Williamson is answering a communication from Peter who has asked him to look in on his wife, Eunice, and their children.  He describes the health problems his boss has been having and therefore his reasons for not having been able to do as requested.  He states that he has been in contact with Eunice, though, and speaks of her plans and his opinions of those plans.  He then speaks briefly on Green Bay and its development and of the Copperhead movement and its impact on politics in Wisconsin and the war in general. He cites New York Governor Horatio Seymour and the "late riot," referring to the draft riots that had recently occurred in New York City. Williamson closes by speaking of family issues and tells his brother he will try to write longer when he has time.  Forms part of the Peter J. Williamson Letters. 1 letter : col. ; 8  x 10  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Williamson, Peter J., 1823-1907; Williamson, Eunice Leihy, 1840-1928; Williamson, William, b. 1841; Seymour, Horatio, 1810-1886</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>United States. Army. Wisconsin Cavalry Regiment, 1st (1861-1865); United States. Army--Military life; New York (State). Governor (1863-1865 : Seymour); Chicago and North Western Railway Company</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Military History; Civil War; Popular Culture; Capital City; War; Soldiers--United States--Correspondence; Soldiers--United States--Personal narratives; Immigrants--Wisconsin; Immigrants' writings, Dutch; Family; Copperhead movement</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--19th century--Sources; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Personal narratives; Tennessee--History--Civil War, 1861-1865; Green Bay (Wis.)--History--19th century; Wisconsin--History--Civil War, 1861-1865; New York--History--Civil War, 1861-1865</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Williamson, William, b. 1841</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Currey, Martha T. (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1863-09-14</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text; Letters (correspondence)</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>PJW -  f, 42</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Peter J. Williamson Letters</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/2102</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>