<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Saint Cecilia Academy historical marker, Nashville, Tennessee, 1980 August </dc:title>
<dc:description>A historical marker for Saint Cecilia Academy in Nashville, Tennessee, photographed circa August 1980 that reads: &#8220;The name Saint Cecilia, patroness of music was chosen for a grammar and high school for girls, opened in October 1860 by four Sisters who had moved to this site from Saint Mary&#8217;s Convent, Third Order of Saint Dominic, Somerset, Ohio on August 17, 1860.  The central building was completed in 1862, the west wing in 1880, and the east wing in 1913.&#8221;  The marker was erected in 1971 by the Historical Commission of Metropolitan Nashville and Davidson County.  The marker is located at the intersection of Dominican Drive and Athens Way.  The original building in North Nashville is still used as a convent, the official Motherhouse of the Dominican Sisters (801 Domincan Drive).  St. Cecilia&#8217;s Academy is Nashville&#8217;s oldest private high school.  Forms part of the Claynita Harris Slide Collection.  The original is a 35 mm color transparency (2 x 2 in. slide mount) </dc:description>
<dc:subject>St. Cecilia's Academy (Nashville, Tenn.); Dominican Sisters of the Congregation of Saint Cecilia; Catholic Church--Education--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Catholic high schools--Tennessee--Nashville; Private schools--Tennessee--Nashville; Church schools--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1980-08</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives </dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Harris Slides   558 Saint Cecilia Academy Plaque</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Claynita Harris Slide Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1980-1989</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/7052</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>