<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>One branch needs some trimming and training, between 1955 and 1974</dc:title>
<dc:description>An original political cartoon drawing created by Jack Knox, the Nashville Banner editorial cartoonist from the mid-1940s to early 1970s.  This cartoon pertains to the growth of the Federal bureaucracy.  The cartoon shows a man with tree pruners in hand looks at a tree ("U.S. Gov't").  Two branches ("States," and "Legislative") are fine growing upright from the trunk, but one branch ("Fed. Judiciary") has wound itself around the others with multiple gavels that have sprouted at the branches.  Forms part of the Jack Knox Political Cartoon Collection. 1 original cartoon drawing : b &amp; w ; 11.5 x 15 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Nashville Banner</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Capital City; Politics; Political cartoons--United States--20th century; Political cartoons--Tennessee--Nashville; Caricatures and cartoons--Tennessee--Nashville; Cartoonists--Tennessee--Nashville; Editorial cartoonists--Tennessee--Nashville; Government spending policy--United States--Caricatures and cartoons; Jurisdiction--United States--Caricatures and cartoons; Cartoonists; Politics &amp; government--United States--Washington, D.C.; Economic &amp; political systems</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>United States--Politics and government--20th century--Caricatures and cartoons</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Knox, Jack, 1910- (Cartoonist)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Knox, Joseph T. (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>between 1955 and 1974</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Caricatures; Cartoons (Commentary); Editorial cartoons</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Knox NPL-324</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Jack Knox Political Cartoon Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1397</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>