<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Close up of an original ionic capital column from the Tennessee State Capitol, n.d.</dc:title>
<dc:description>An undated photograph of an ionic capital column from the restoration of the Tennessee State Capitol Building in Nashville, Tennessee. This remnant is derived from the original columns of the Capitol Building, which was renovated during a massive restoration project (1953-55) and subsequently moved to the grounds of the Tennessee State Prison and stored there for years until the 1990s, when Nashville architect Charles W. Warterfield, Jr. located the old columns and capitals in a field near the state penitentiary and placed them once again on the grounds of Capitol Hill and also the Bicentennial Mall as a tribute to the grandeur of the past. This artfully arranged grouping of fragments of the original columns would be named the Charles Warterfield Reliquary in his honor. Architect Charles Warterfield, Jr. (1926-1998) began his career as a draftsman for the major restoration of the Capitol from 1953-55 and later oversaw the interior restoration of the Capitol in 1987-88; he was a member of the master planning team for the Bicentennial Mall project, and was chairman of the Metro Historical Commission 1977-1981. He is credited with advocating the ordinance that made historic zoning possible in Nashville. With his knowledge of architecture and through his photography he gave many lectures on Nashville architecture to overflow crowds. Photographed by the Nashville architect Charles Wesley Warterfield, Jr. (1926-1998); the architectural photograph forms part of the Charles Warterfield Architectural Collection. Gift of: The Estate of Charles W. Warterfield, Jr., F. A. I. A. The original is a 35 mm color transparency (2 x 2 in. slide mount).</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Tennessee State Capitol (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Architects--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Public buildings; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Warterfield, Charles W. (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Estate of Charles W. Warterfield, Jr., F.A.I.A. (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>19--</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Slides; Photographs; Architectural photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>WSC 6082</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Charles Warterfield Architectural Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/18</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>