<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Tennessee National Guard, 1950</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of the Tennessee National Guard building and truck at Nashville Municipal Airport with signage saying &#8220;Join the new Tennessee National Guard, Earn, Learn, Serve.&#8221; The National Guard continued to be based at the Nashville Airport after World War II, the Tennessee National Guard&#8217;s 105th Observation Squadron, which flew missions including reconnaissance and fighter-interceptor operations during the 1930s and 1940s, continued these operations during the 1950s. In 1961, the 105th became the flying squadron of the 118th Air Transport Wing. Nashville's airport officially opened in 1937 as Berry Field, in honor of Colonel Harry S. Berry, the state administrator of the Works Progress Administrator, or WPA. Berry Field became the military base for the 4th Ferrying Command during World War II and was returned to the city when the war ended. The airport&#8217;s name was officially changed to Nashville International Airport in 1988, but the original three-letters BNA, which stands for Berry Field Nashville, remains. Forms part of Record Group 3, Metro Davidson County Photographer. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 3 x 4 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Metropolitan Nashville Airport Authority--History--Sources; 
Tennessee. National Guard </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Airports--Tennessee--Nashville--History; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1950</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 3 40 Airport001</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3 Metro Davidson County Photographer</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4123</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>