<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Hillery, third baseman, from the Nashville Daily American, 1886 March 04</dc:title>
<dc:description>A newspaper image of James John Hillery, third baseman of the professional baseball team the Nashville Americans. In 1885, the Southern League was formed, and Nashville&#8217;s entry into the new league for two seasons was the Nashville Americans. Forms part of the Nashville Daily American Newspaper Collection. 1 digital photograph</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Hillery, James J.</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Americans (Baseball team)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Baseball--Tennessee--Nashville--History; Baseball players--Tennessee--Nashville; Baseball teams--Tennessee--Nashville; Sports--Tennessee--Nashville; Sports teams--Tennessee--Nashville; Athletes--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Newspapers</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1886-03-04</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Hillery--Third Baseman--Baseball--Daily American--3-14-1886</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Daily American Newspaper Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1880-1889</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4360</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>