<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Second Presbyterian Church, 2001 May</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of the former Second Presbyterian Church located at 3511 Belmont Boulevard in Nashville, Tennessee.  The founding of the Second Presbyterian congregation dates back to 1843, but this structure was not erected in this Green Hills neighborhood until 1941.  The foundation is brick.  The exterior walls are brick.  The gabled roof is made of tar shingles.  The windows are purple colored glass with shutters.  An oculus adorns the front facade.  The doors are wood.  Special features include architectural arches and a steeple.  In 1951 a fund-raising drive collected enough money to construct an addition to the building.  In 1982 a pipe organ was installed into the sanctuary.  In 1990 a 9,600 square foot addition consisting of a larger fellowship hall and additional classrooms was completed, but in 2003 a major fire caused the congregation to lose their sanctuary and rebuild in 2005.  Work on the new sanctuary was complete in 2006.  Forms part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project. 1 photograph : col. ; 4  x 6  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Second Presbyterian Church (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Popular Culture; Religion; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Religious facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Church architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Presbyterian church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Protestant church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Brick churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Details; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Presbyterian churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Steeples; Architectural details--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs; Belmont Boulevard (Nashville, Tenn.); Green Hills (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2001-05</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>SSSP - 2nd Pres-current</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1520</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>