<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Letter from Isaac Morgan Leihy and his wife Ruth Leihy to P.J. Williamson, 1869 December 01</dc:title>
<dc:description>A letter from Isaac Morgan Leihy and his wife Ruth Leihy to their son-in-law and Dutch immigrant, Peter J. Williamson.  In 1862 Williamson enlisted as a Private in the 1st Wisconsin Cavalry, Company F and was ultimately promoted to Full 1st Lieutenant.  During the war, Williamson's regiment was involved in scouting and raids in Missouri and Arkansas and saw battle in the Middle Tennessee, Chickamauga, and Atlanta campaigns. After the war, he and his family settled in Nashville, where he became an architect.  Williamson's wife, Eunice, spent time in California nursing her health.  In this letter from San Bernardino, California, the Leihy's write of Eunice's time spent in their care.  They received his letter to her dated November 11th, 1869, and had not forwarded it because they think Eunice to be on her way home to Nashville.  They mention that they know nothing about William not answering his letters and hope no unpleasant feelings have been created due to her stay there.  They express their sympathy toward Williamson and the children for their loneliness during Eunice's absence.  Isaac and Ruth report their health as "tolerable" and mention returning from a trip to San Diego.  They discuss the possibility of moving to Los Angeles County in the future and speak of their religious beliefs.  They report an encounter in San Diego in relation to the keeper of the Bay View Hotel and how poor he seemed.  In closing they send Waldo and Irwin's love to Johnny and Willy and ask Williamson to write back concerning Eunice's arrival home.  Forms part of the Peter J. Williamson Letters. 1 letter : col. ; 5 x 8 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Williamson, Peter J., 1823-1907; Williamson, Eunice Leihy, 1840-1928; Leihy, Isaac Morgan; Leihy, Ruth Calkins; Williamson, William, b. 1841; Williamson, Peter, b. 1862; Williamson, Willy (William), b. 1859; Leihy, Waldo L., b. 1853?; Leihy, Irwin M., b. 1859?</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Bay View Hotel (San Diego, Calif.)--History--19th century</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Military History; Civil War; Popular Culture; Religion; War; Soldiers--United States--Correspondence; Soldiers--United States--Personal narratives; Immigrants--Wisconsin; Immigrants' writings, Dutch; Health; Sympathy; Loneliness; Poor; Religion; Travel </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--19th century--Sources; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Personal narratives; Tennessee--History--19th century; San Jose (Calif.)--History--19th century; San Diego (Calif.)--History--19th century; Los Angeles County (Calif.)--History--19th century</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Leihy, Isaac Morgan; Leihy, Ruth Calkins</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Currey, Martha T. (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1869-12-01</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text; Letters (correspondence)</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>PJW - f, 87</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Peter J. Williamson Letters</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/2225</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>