<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Camel rides at reasonable prices, circa 1943</dc:title>
<dc:description>Photograph of soldiers in uniform, most with their backs towards the camera, gathered around a kneeling camel. One soldier appears to be mounting or dismounting the camel, assisted by a man in a turban.  Morris Levine is at far right. Morris Levine was born on Dec. 8, 1917 in Nashville, Tenn., the son of Hyman and Mary Levine, who were Jewish immigrants from Russia. He graduated from Hume-Fogg High School in 1934. He attended the YMCA Night Law School, took the bar exam in 1938, and was still under 21 years old when he received his license to practice law. He was engaged to Virginia Hiken before World War II, but they postponed their marriage due to the war. He served in the Army Air Corps and as a Judge Advocate in Karachi, India, part of the China-Burma-India (CBI) Theater of operations during World War II. He served in the 54th Material Squadron as part of the 51st Air Base Group. Forms part of the Veterans History Project. 1 black and white photographic print (snapshot).</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Levine, Morris, 1917-2001</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>United States. Army Air Forces. Material Squadron, 54th; United States. Army Air Forces. Air Base Group, 51st</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Military History; World War II; War; Veterans--Tennessee--History--Sources; World War, 1939-1945--Participation, Jewish; World War, 1939-1945--Photography; World War, 1939-1945--India--Karachi; Soldiers--Recreation; Deserts--India--Karachi; Camels--India--Karachi</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>India; Karachi (Pakistan)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca.1943</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs; Snapshots</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/tiff</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>VHP-WWII-Levine p250</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Veterans History Project collection, World War II series, Morris Levine papers</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/480</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>