<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Chapel Avenue Church of Christ, 2001 May</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of the former Chapel Avenue Church of Christ located at 108 Chapel Avenue, now East Academy, a private elementary school in East Nashville.  The Chapel Avenue Church of Christ building was sold in 2001 to help fund the retirement of one of their German missionaries who founded a Church of Christ in Europe.    The foundation is made of grey rough cut stone blocks.  The exterior walls are comprised of tan rough cut stone blocks.  The roof is flat.  The windows are colored glass.  The doors are made of wood with glass windows.  Forms part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project. 1 photograph : col. ; 4  x 6  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Chapel Avenue Church of Christ, (Nashville, Tenn.); East Academy (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Popular Culture; Religion; Schools; Capital City; Education; Elementary Schools; Private Schools; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Religious facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Church architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Churches of Christ--Tennessee--Nashville; Elementary school facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; School buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Schools--Tennessee--Nashville; Churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Private schools--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs; Chapel Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); East Nashville (Nashville Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2001-05</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>SSSP - Chapel Ave CoC</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/739</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>