<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>George Peabody College for Teachers, Nashville, Tenn., between 1920 and 1939</dc:title>
<dc:description>A color postcard of buildings on the campus of the George Peabody College for Teachers, circa the 1930s. The six buildings depicted on the postcard include the Library, West Dormitory, Social-Religious Building, Jesup Psychological Laboratory, Demonstration School, and Industrial Arts Building. Forms part of the Nashville Room Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>George Peabody College for Teachers</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Education; Colleges and Universities; Capital City; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Education--Tennessee--Nashville; Teachers--Training of--Tennessee--Nashville; Universities and colleges--Tennessee--Nashville; Teachers' colleges--Tennessee--Nashville; Educational facilities--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>E. C. Kropp Co. (Publisher)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>between 1920 and 1939</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Nash-75-Geo. Peabody</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1920-1929; 1930-1939</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/601</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>