<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of Stokely Carmichael, Vanderbilt University, Nashville, Tennessee, 1967 April 08</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of Stokely Carmichael at the 1967 IMPACT Symposium, Vanderbilt University, Nashville, Tennessee, April 8, 1967. Carmichael's 1967 appearance at Vanderbilt University would be cited as "the cause of significant controversy throughout the city and state." Stokely Carmichael later described the audience at Vanderbilt as "attentive and respectful." The theme for the Symposium was "The Individual in American Society." The IMPACT lecture series was completely organized, funded, and planned by students. While serving as the chairman of the Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (SNCC), Carmichael promoted college campus outreach programs. It was under the leadership of Carmichael that the philosophy of SNCC evolved. Forms part of the Nashville Banner Archives. 1 photograph : b &amp; w ; 8 x 10 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Carmichael, Stokely</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (U.S.); IMPACT Symposium (Vanderbilt University)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Civil Rights; African Americans; Race Relations; Education; Colleges and Universities; African Americans--Civil rights--Tennessee--Nashville; Black Nationalism--United States; African Americans--Race identity; African American political activists--Tennessee--Nashville--History--Sources; Civil rights workers--Tennessee--Nashville; Activists--American--Tennessee--Nashville; Civil rights leaders--United States; Protest movements--Tennessee--Nashville; Meetings--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social conditions; Nashville (Tenn.)-Race relations; Southern States--Race relations--History--20th century--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Cooley, Vic (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1967-04-08</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/tiff</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BP-Carmichael, Stokely</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/563</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>