<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Franklin and Columbia Turnpike Company capital stock document no. 149, issued to William Harrison, Sr., witnessed 1850 December 02</dc:title>
<dc:description>A stock certificate of the antebellum period issued to William Harrison, Sr. certifying capital stock in the Franklin and Columbia Turnpike Company, as witnessed on Dec. 2, 1850.  Historically, the turnpikes started with local ownership in the form of small corporations, along with the issuance of a state charter.  As the system became more established, roads were "bought up" by groups or individuals interested in profitable venture.  The turnpike phase was the most important aspect of Tennessee's internal improvement system of the 1830s.  The economic aspects related to the turnpikes provided a basis of material wealth that contributed to the building of the railroad system in the 1850's.  Forms part of the Harrison House Collection. 1 document : b &amp; w ; 17 x 17 cm.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Harrison, William, 1799-1865; Critz, Jacob; Cheairs, John Wesley, 1806-1873</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Harrison House (Franklin, Tenn.); Franklin and Columbia Turnpike Co. (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Business; Transportation; Roads--Tennessee--Williamson County; Roads--Tennessee--Maury County; Toll roads--Tennessee, Middle; Stock certificates--Tennessee, Middle; Toll roads--Tennessee; Business enterprises--Tennessee--Franklin; Business enterprises--Tennessee--Columbia</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Tennessee, Middle--Economic aspects--19th century</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1850-12-02</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text; Stock certificates</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>HHC - f5 - Franklin &amp; Columbia Turnpike stock 1850</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Harrison House Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1850-1859</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1115</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>