<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of Scarritt College, circa 1929</dc:title>
<dc:description>Dedicated in March 1928, Scarritt College remains one of architect Henry C. Hibbs' signature designs in the collegiate gothic style. Hibbs was awarded a gold medal for his work on Scarritt and was recognized in the December 1929 issue of Southern Architect and Building News, for which this photo was likely taken. Forms part of the Henry C. Hibbs Papers. 1 photograph : b&amp;w ; 8 x 10 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Hibbs, Henry C. (Clossen), 1883-1949</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Scarritt College for Christian Workers--History; Scarritt-Bennett Center--History</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Architects; Buildings; Schools; Education; Colleges and Universities; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architects--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture, Gothic--Tennessee--Nashville; Religious facilities--Tennessee--Nashville;  Church colleges--Tennessee--Nashville; Methodist universities and colleges--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Tebbs &amp; Knell, Inc. (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1929</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/tiff (31.8 MB)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>HCHP-Bldg-Scarritt College-p19</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Henry C. Hibbs Papers</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1920-1929</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/347</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>