<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Eastwood Christian Church, 2001 January</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of the Eastwood Christian Church (Disciples of Christ) located at 1601 Eastland Avenue, Nashville, Tennessee in the East Nashville neighborhood.  The church's congregation originated as the Woodland Street Christian Church in 1871.  After being destroyed by the great fire in 1916 and again by the tornado of 1930, the present Eastland Christian Church buildings were built in 1933 (Religious Education Building) and 1951 (sanctuary).  The name changed when Woodland Street Christian Church congregation merged with the East Nashville Christian church congregation.  They combined the two names to form Eastwood and moved into the new buildings together.  The church structure incorporates a Gothic architecture style.  The foundation is made of brick.  The exterior walls are brick.  The roof is made of asphalt shingles.  The windows are frosted glass.  The doors are wooden.  Forms part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project. 1 photograph : col. ; 4  x 6  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Eastwood Christian Church (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Popular Culture; Religion; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Religious facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Church architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture, Gothic--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Details; Protestant church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs; Eastland Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); East Nashville (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2001-01</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>SSSP - Eastwood Christian Church</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/777</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>