<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Second Decade of the Nashville Community Playhouse, 1945 October 08</dc:title>
<dc:description>A brochure commemorating the beginning of the second decade of the Nashville Community Playhouse.   It contains a brief history of theatre in Nashville, starting with mentions of the Stagecrafters group and the Little Theatre of Nashville, moving to the history of the Nashville Children's Theater, and finally the history of the Community Playhouse.  Also included is a list of Community Playhouse productions up until that point, a photograph montage, a finance report, board, artist membership and information.  The Nashville Community Playhouse was located at 2102 Belcourt Avenue.  Published by the Nashville Community Playhouse, October 8, 1945.  Forms part of the Hume-Fogg High School Collection. 1 brochure ; 7.5 x 10.75 in. (cover and 10 pages).</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Nashville Community Playhouse</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Performing Arts; Theatre; Popular Culture; Entertainment; Performing Arts--Tennessee--Nashville; Actors--Tennessee--Nashville; Community theater--Tennessee--Nashville; Theater--Tennessee--Nashville;  Actresses--Tennessee--Nashville; Theatrical companies--Tennessee--Nashville; Theatrical productions--Tennessee--Nashville; Entertainment--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Belcourt Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1945-10-08</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Ephemera; Brochures</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Hume-Fogg, Community Playhouse</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Hume-Fogg High School Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/876</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>