<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>General Robert Macomb&#8217;s home on Spuyten Duyvil Creek, New York, n.d.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Exterior view of General Robert Macomb&#8217;s Home on Spuyten Duyvil Creek, New York.  The property was &#8220;purchased by Alexander Macomb about 1789. Inherited by his grandson, Robert Macomb in 1810. [On] June 10, 1847 Wm. Foster, Jr.&amp; Caroline Matilda Macomb married here. Sold in 1848 (Godwin, a Tavern), vacated 1917, razed 1920.&#8221;  The notation on the verso of the photo cites the children of Wm. Foster Jr. and Caroline Matilda Macomb: Macomb George, Pell William, and Chauncey Charles Foster.  These digital reproductions were scanned from the scrapbook of Mrs. Frank A. Wilk (Alva Herbert Wilk). 1 digital photograph.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Foster family; Macomb family</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture, Domestic--New York; Dwellings--New York; Historic buildings--New York; Buildings--New York</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Spuyten Duyvil (New York, N.Y.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>n.d.</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Wilk scrapbook pg 004 Gen. Macomb home NY; Wilk scrapbook pg 004a Gen. Macomb NY home info</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Mrs. Frank A. Wilk Digital Photographs Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>19th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4945</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>