<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of the Elliston-Buford house in Nashville, Tennessee, between 1960 and 1975</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of the Elliston-Buford house, at 2300 Elliston Place, Nashville, Tennessee. The residence, originally built circa 1881, was the home of Lizinka Elliston Buford and husband Edward L. Buford, a Nashville businessman and Confederate War veteran. Lizinka's father was William Robert Elliston, the son of Nashville Mayor Joseph Thorpe Elliston (1814-1817). Circa 1928, the five-acre Elliston Place site, with its two mansions, was purchased in the building of the Father Ryan High School campus. The Roman Catholic school was named for Father Abram Joseph Ryan (1839-1886), often referred to as the "poet-priest of the South." Photographed by the Nashville architect Charles Wesley Warterfield, Jr. (1926-1998); the architectural photograph forms part of the Charles Warterfield Architectural Collection. Gift of: The Estate of Charles W. Warterfield, Jr., F. A. I. A. The original is 35 mm color transparency (2 x 2 in. slide mount)</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Ryan, Abram Joseph, 1839-1886; Buford, Lizinka Elliston--Homes and haunts--Tennessee--Nashville; Buford, Edward L.--Homes and haunts--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Father Ryan High School (Nashville, Tenn.); Elliston-Buford House (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architects--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Neighborhood--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture, Domestic--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Houses--Tennessee--Nashville; Neighborhoods--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Warterfield, Charles W. (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Estate of Charles W. Warterfield, Jr., F. A. I. A. (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>between 1960 and 1975</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still image; Slides; Architectural photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>WSC 3899</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Charles Warterfield Architectural Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969; 1970-1979</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/57</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>