<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>A. Laidye Askew reflects on her philosophy of education, 2007 September 26</dc:title>
<dc:description>An edited excerpt with transcript and photograph from an interview with retired educator A. Laidye Askew, conducted on 26 September 2007 by StoryCorps Facilitator Martha O'Brien at the Nashville StoryCorps StoryBooth, located in the Nashville Room of the Nashville Public Library.  Askew shares her philosophy of education, including her use of the Socratic Method; having an open, relaxed atmosphere in the classroom where children have the freedom to do their work when they are ready; and developing visual vocabulary books to help children learn definitions.  The complete, un-edited interview, as well as an index, is available in the Special Collections Division. These interviews were recorded by StoryCorps at the Nashville Public Library with the support of the Nashville Public Library Foundation and are provided courtesy of StoryCorps, a national initiative of Sound Portraits Productions to record and collect oral history interviews. www.storycorps.net</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Askew, A. Laidye, 1940- --Interviews</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Popular Culture; Education; Storytelling--Tennessee--Nashville; Educators--Tennessee--Nashville; Teachers--Tennessee--Nashville; Women educators--Tennessee--Nashville; Questioning; Learning; School children--Tennessee--Nashville; Students--Tennessee--Nashville; Classroom management--Tennessee--Nashville; Classroom environment--Tennessee--Nashville; Vocabulary--Study and teaching--Aids and devices</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Intellectual life</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Askew, A. Laidye, 1940- (Interviewee); O'Brien, Martha, 1945-  (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>StoryCorps (Project)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>2007-09-26</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3 (3 min., 44 sec.)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>NPL000014_excerpt.mp3; NPL000014_transcript.pdf; NPL000014_g1.jpg</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from:  NPL000014 original StoryCorps interview edited by Aimee James in June 2008.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville StoryCorps StoryBooth Interviews 2007-2008</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1828</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>