<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Program, The Nashville Community Playhouse, presentation of &#8220;Little Foxes,&#8221; 1943</dc:title>
<dc:description>A Nashville Community Playhouse program for a theatrical production of Lillian Hellman&#8217;s &#8220;The Little Foxes,&#8221; presented December 7th-11th, 1943.  The production was directed by Mrs. Inez B. Adler.  The actors in the cast are Lilian R. Ward; Al Margolin; Margie Knight; Alfred D. Moore; Cpt. Irvine Stirton; Noncie Reed Bradley; Sgt. Hugh O&#8217;Connell; Frank Drury; Virginia Mansell; and Pvt. John Newland.  Includes a list of the sustaining membership for the 1943-44 year.  Forms part of the Wilhelmina Webb Collection. 1 program. </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Adler, Mrs. Inez B.; Ward, Lilian R.; Margolin, Al; Knight, Margie; Moore, Alfred D.; Stirton, Irvine; Bradley, Noncie Reed; O&#8217;Connell, Hugh; Drury, Frank; Mansell, Virginia; Newland, John </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Community Playhouse (Nashville, Tenn.)--History--Sources; Belcourt Theatre (Nashville, Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Performances--Tennessee--Nashville; Performing arts--Tennessee--Nashville; Entertainment--Tennessee--Nashville; Advertising--Tennessee--Nashville; Community theater--Tennessee--Nashville; Theater--Tennessee--Nashville; Theatrical companies--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Belcourt Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1943</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Programs; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Wilhelmina Webb Collection Nash Community Playhouse progs 1940-47 Little Foxes Hellman 001 - 005</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Wilhelmina Webb Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/9332</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>