<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Interior of West End Synagogue, Nashville, Tennessee, 1951   </dc:title>
<dc:description>Interior views of the West End Synagogue, 3810 West End Avenue, Nashville, Tennessee, in 1951.  Originally founded as Khal Kodesh Adath Israel in 1874 in downtown Nashville.  This modern structure was designed by architect Percival Goodman of New York City.  Upon completion of the new building, it was dedicated in 1951. West End Synagogue is affiliated with the United Synagogue for Conservative Judaism. The Foster &amp; Creighton construction contracting firm was founded in 1885 by Wilbur F. Foster and Robert T. Creighton, who had both served as City Engineer of Nashville.  Forms part of the Foster &amp; Creighton General Contractors Collection. 5 b &amp; w photographs.   </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Construction industry--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Synagogues--Tennessee--Nashville; Jews--Tennessee--Nashville--History--Sources; Synagogue architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Religious architecture--Tennessee--Nashville  </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; West End Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Don Cravens (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Creighton III, Wilbur (donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1951</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Foster Creighton Coll Nashville Projects West End Synagogue 1951 001 - 005</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Foster &amp; Creighton General Contractors Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/8945</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>