<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Castle Hall, Joel A. Battle Lodge, K.P. Nashville, Tenn., circa 1908</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard of Castle Hall, the meeting place for the Joel A. Battle Lodge.  Col. Joel A. Battle was a Knight of Pythias, and to show the high esteem in which his brethren of this order held him, several years following his death in 1872, a lodge was organized in Nashville, named Joel A. Battle Lodge in his honor.  The hall for the lodge was built near the Peabody Normal College on Second Avenue at a cost of $15,000.  The architects chosen to design Castle Hall were Thompson &amp; Zwicker.  The contractor was John Oman. Forms part of the Nashville Room Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Battle, Joel A.</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Knights of Pythias. Joel A. Battle Lodge (Nashville, Tenn.); Castle Hall (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Organizations; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Fraternal organizations--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Second Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>International Post Card Co. (Publisher)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1908</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Nash-25a-Castle Hall, Joel A. Battle Lodge, K.P. Nashville Tenn.</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1900-1909</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/660</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>