<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Protection order granted to William Harrison, Jr., Williamson County, Tennessee, by Head-Quarters District of Nashville, Provost Marshal's Office, 1864 April 25</dc:title>
<dc:description>A protection order granted to William Harrison, Jr., of Williamson County, Tennessee, by Head-Quarters District of Nashville, Provost Marshal's Office on April 25, 1864.  The document cites protection granted for "farm, timber, forage, stock, buildings, provisions, and all personal property not above mentioned.  All officers and soldiers in the United States Service are directed to respect and, if nece[s]sary, enforce the requirements of this order." This document was issued "by command of Maj. Gen. Rousseau" and signed by Horace Tompkins, 1st Lt. of the 19th Michigan Infantry and Asst. Provost Marshall.  Forms part of the Harrison House Collection. 1 document : b &amp; w ; 20  x 25 cm.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Harrison, William, 1825-1889; Tompkins, Horace</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Harrison House (Franklin, Tenn.); Confederate States of America--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Military History; Civil War; Plantation life--Southern States--History--19th century--Sources; Plantation owners--Tennessee--Franklin; Plantation owners--Tennessee--Williamson County; Economic &amp; political systems; Farmers--Tennessee--Franklin; Farm life--Tennessee--Franklin</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Sources; Williamson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Franklin (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Tennessee--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Sources; Franklin (Tenn.)--Social conditions--19th century; Tennessee, Middle--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1864-04-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>HHC - f6 Provost protection order 1864</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Harrison House Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1116</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>