<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Old Center Elementary School, Goodlettsville, Tennessee, 1981 June</dc:title>
<dc:description>An exterior view of Old Center Elementary School, located at 1245 Dickerson Road, Goodlettsville, Tennessee, circa June 1981. The original school was a one-room log housed, facing Old Campbell Road off Dickerson Road.  Old Center got its name from the fact that at one time four big farms cornered at the site of the school&#8217;s location, and each farm owner gave a quarter of an acre, and from that the name &#8220;Old Center&#8221; was derived.  One account places the date for this original &#8220;Old Center&#8221; at 1876.  This building at some time prior to 1900 was replaced with a white frame school, with subsequent expansion.  In 1936 a brick school building was completed at the site on Dickerson Road and given the name &#8220;Old Center.&#8221;  Forms part of the Claynita Harris Slide Collection.  The original is a 35 mm color transparency (2 x 2 in. slide mount) </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Old Center Elementary School (Goodlettsville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture--Tennessee--Goodlettsville; Buildings--Tennessee-- Goodlettsville; Elementary schools--Tennessee--Goodlettsville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs

</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1981-06</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives </dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Harris Slides   566 Old Center Elementary June81</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Claynita Harris Slide Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1980-1989</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/7174</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>