<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Robert Marshall remembers his Korean War service, 2007 September 17</dc:title>
<dc:description>An edited excerpt with transcript and photograph from an interview with Robert Marshall, conducted on 17 September 2007 by StoryCorps Facilitator Kate Wingate at the Nashville StoryCorps StoryBooth, located in the Nashville Room of the Nashville Public Library. Marshall shares memories from his Korean War service, including checking fishing boats for mines and how one of his sailors who was originally supposed to be discharged from the military saved the lives of everyone on his ship.  The complete, un-edited interview, as well as an index, is available in the Special Collections Division. These interviews were recorded by StoryCorps at the Nashville Public Library with the support of the Nashville Public Library Foundation and are provided courtesy of StoryCorps, a national initiative of Sound Portraits Productions to record and collect oral history interviews. www.storycorps.net</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Marshall, Robert, 1930- --Interviews</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>United States. Navy -- History -- Korean War, 1950-1953</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Popular Culture; Military History; Korean War; Storytelling--Tennessee--Nashville; Korean War, 1950-1953--Personal narratives, American; Korean War, 1950-1953--Veterans--Tennessee--Interviews; Sailors; Korean War, 1950-1953--Naval operations, American; Minesweepers</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Korea--History</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Marshall, Robert, 1930- (Interviewee); Wingate, Kate, 1979-  (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>StoryCorps (Project)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>2007-09-17</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3 (3 min., 12 sec.)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>NPL000005_excerpt.mp3; NPL000005_transcript.pdf; NPL000005_g2.jpg</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from:  NPL1000005 original StoryCorps interview edited by Aimee James in May 2008.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville StoryCorps StoryBooth Interviews 2007-2008</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1664</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>