<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Vanderbilt University, Nashville, Tenn., 1901</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard of the Main Building on the Vanderbilt Campus in 1901.  Vanderbilt University was made possible in 1873 through a one million dollar gift from Commodore Cornelius Vanderbilt, a shipping and rail tycoon who had never even visited the South.  Vanderbilt's hope in supporting a university in the South was that it would "contribute to strengthening the ties which should exist between all sections of our common country."  At the University's onset, the campus consisted of the Main Building, an astronomical observatory and houses for professors.  The original Vanderbilt Library was housed in the Main Building.  In 1905 a fire consumed the Main Building and it was rebuilt with one tower as Kirkland Hall in honor of the school's longest serving Chancellor, James H. Kirkland.  Kirkland guided the rebuilding process and also navigated the University through the separation from the Methodist Church.  The new building houses the administration offices and sits off of West End Avenue.  Forms part of the Nashville Room Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Vanderbilt University</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Education; Colleges and Universities; Buildings; Architecture; Schools; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Education--Tennessee--Nashville; Universities and colleges--Tennessee--Nashville; School facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Details; Towers--Tennessee--Nashville; Methodist universities and colleges--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Educational facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Universities &amp; colleges--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; West End Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Intellectual life</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Detroit Photographic Co. (Publisher)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1901</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Nash - 94 - Vanderbilt University, Nashville, Tenn.</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1900-1909</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/850</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>