<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Tennessee Theatre exterior, marquee and neon sign on opening night, 1952 February 28</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of the grand opening of the million-dollar Tennessee Theatre (built on the first floor of the 1930's Sudekum building) on February 28, 1952, featured appearances by state and local politicians, celebrities and the cast of the movie About Face, which had its premier that evening. The Tennessee, built into the first floor of the 1930s Sudekum building, seated 2,020 people and was hailed as the fulfillment of a dream of the late Tony Sudekum, founder of the Crescent Amusement Company that built the theatre, and as a keystone in Nashville's growth and development. Live performances as well as motion pictures were featured at the Tennessee. The American Ballet Theatre appeared there on October 25, 1957. Its orchestra director was Kenneth Schermerhorn, future conductor of the Nashville Symphony. The theatre which stood on the corner of 6th Avenue and Church Street was demolished in 1990. Forms part of the Nashville Banner Archives. 1 photograph : b &amp; w ; 8 x 10 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Tennessee Theatre (Nashville, Tenn.); Sudekum Building (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Performing Arts; Architecture; Buildings; Business; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Popular Culture; Entertainment; Motion picture theaters--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Marquees--Tennessee--Nashville; Electric signs--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Church Street (Nashville, Tenn.); Sixth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1952-02-28</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BP - Nash-Theaters-TennesseeTh2</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/2322</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>