<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Watkins Institute Building, Nashville, Tennessee, 1942 May</dc:title>
<dc:description>The Watkins Institute in downtown Nashville at 605 Church Street, circa May, 1942.  The Watkins Institute was founded by Samuel Watkins (1794-1880) through a gift in his will to establish a school for adult education.  This school was located at Sixth and Church in downtown Nashville, Tennessee.  The Watkins Building also held many office spaces such as the Nashville Electric Service.  The Flagg Bros. Shoe Store is pictured next to the school.  The Watkins Institute relocated when the new Nashville Public Library was built.  Forms part of Record Group 412, Photographs Collection. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Watkins Institute</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Schools--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Church Street (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1942-05</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 412 081 Watkins Institute Bldg in 1942 001</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 412</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/5138</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>