<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of Noel Hotel during construction, 1929 August 15</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of the Noel Hotel located at 200 Fourth Avenue North and corner of Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, during construction. The property had been in the Noel family since 1854, at which time a huge spring flowed, furnishing most of the water for residents living along the Cumberland River. The 12-story, 250-room hotel was built by John and Oscar Noel. It was designed by Marr, Holman Architects with Nicholson Company as general contractors.  The hotel opened on 6 January 1930 it was considered a luxury hotel and over the years was host to local residents such as the "Kaffee Klatsch" where businessmen gathered to share coffee and business as well as for celebrity guests, included Eleanor Roosevelt, Babe Ruth, Roy Rogers and Jayne Mansfield. It closed as a hotel 30 September 1972 when it was bought by Hamilton Bank. Forms part of the Nashville Banner Archives. 1 photograph : b &amp; w ; 8 x 10 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Noel Hotel (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Architects--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings; Business; Tourism; Capital City; Downtown Nashville;  Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Building construction--Tennessee--Nashville; Hotels--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Fourth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Church Street (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1929-08-15</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/tiff</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BP-Nash-Hotels-Noel Hotel</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1920-1929</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/467</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>