<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>U.S. Judge Elmer Davies, 1939 July</dc:title>
<dc:description>Pictured: Judge Elmer D. Davies, Sr., a United States federal judge.  Davies received an L.L. B. from Vanderbilt University in 1922.  He was in private practice in Nashville, Tennessee from 1922 to 1939, and served as a Tennessee state senator from 1935 to 1939.  In 1939, Davies was nominated by President Franklin D. Roosevelt to a seat on the United States District Court for the Middle District of Tennessee vacated by John J. Gore.  Davies was confirmed by the United States Senate on July 12th, 1939 and commissioned the same day.  He served as chief judge from 1954 until his death in 1957.  Forms part of Record Group 412, Photographs Collection. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Davies, Elmer David, 1899-1957</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>District courts--Tennessee, Middle; Judges</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Tennessee, Middle--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1939-07</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 412 196 Judge Elmer Davies July 1939 002</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 412</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/5347</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>