<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of participants in the Poor People's March, Nashville, Tennessee, 1968 May 08</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of participants in the 1968 Poor People's March, Nashville, Tennessee, May 8, 1968. In March 1968, Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. announced plans for the Poor People's Campaign for the purposes of organizing and uniting the poor across racial lines as well as calling national conscience to granting aid to the American poor. Demonstrators arrived in Washington, DC from nine major caravans that included modes of transportation from Greyhound buses to mule-drawn wagons.  The Poor People's Campaign was one of the major priorities of Dr. King's final years and eventually was headed by Reverend Ralph Abernathy. Forms part of the Nashville Banner Archives. 1- 35 mm black &amp; white photograph negative.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Civil Rights; African Americans; Race Relations; Capital City; Transportation; African Americans--Civil rights--Tennessee--Nashville; Poor People's Campaign; Student protesters--Tennessee--Nashville; Demonstrations--Tennessee--Nashville; Civil rights--Tennessee--Nashville; Civil rights workers--Tennessee--Nashville; African Americans--Tennessee-Nashville--History--Sources; Segregation--Tennessee--Nashville; Activists--American--Tennessee--Nashville; Protest movements--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social conditions; Southern States--Race relations--History--20th century--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Gunter, Jack (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1968-05-08</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/tiff</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BN 1968-1209-n14</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/562</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>