<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Tree planting event at City Office Building on Second Avenue South, Nashville, Tennessee, 1961 August 12</dc:title>
<dc:description>A tree planting event for landscape beautification at the City Office Building (Metropolitan Office Building), Nashville, Tennessee, June 3rd, 1965.  This structure, located at 800 2nd Avenue S, was renovated by Metro government as an office building.  The original project was to establish a teaching hospital to be called Galloway Memorial Hospital, a joint venture between Vanderbilt and the Methodist Episcopal Church.  The new hospital construction began at Vanderbilt&#8217;s south campus starting in 1916, at the southwest corner of the old University of Nashville in the &#8220;College Hill&#8221; area.  However, this structure was only partially completed, as work on the new Vanderbilt hospital complex was instead established on the West End campus.  The partially completed Galloway Hospital building in south Nashville stood vacant until purchased by the City for office space in the 1930s.  The construction was finished and the structure was utilized as a local government office building.  The area immediately around the campus became zoned for light industrial use or became a part of I-265 through South Nashville.  During the 1980s some of the neighborhood became converted back to residential use.  The hill is known as &#8220;Rutledge Hill&#8221; or &#8220;Rolling Mill Hill.&#8221;  Forms part of Record Group 3, Metro Davidson County Photographer. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 2.5 x 2.5 in. </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Office buildings--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc. ; Second Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1961-08-12</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG3 1267 City Office Bldg 2nd and Lindsley Tree Planting Aug12 1961 004</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3 Metro Davidson County Photographer   </dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/6938</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>