<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Legislative Plaza, Tennessee State Capitol and War Memorial Building, circa 1978 September 04</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of the Legislative Plaza, Tennessee State Capitol and War Memorial Building viewed from Union Street in Nashville, Tennessee circa 4 September 1978. The Legislative Plaza is seen at ground level, South of the State Capitol, built by the state in 1975. The project created an underground structure consisting of office spaces for state officials and some lawmakers as well as levels for parking. The construction of the multi-million facility occupies the area between Charlotte, Union and Sixth Avenue adjacent to the Tennessee War Memorial Auditorium and replaced Memorial Square courtyards. The Tennessee War Memorial Building, on the left, was built in 1925 to honor soldiers and sailors who died in World War I. The State Capitol, pictured in the central background, was constructed between 1845 and 1859. It was designed in Greek Revival style by architect William Strickland (1788-1854). Photographed by the Nashville architect Charles Wesley Warterfield, Jr. (1926-1998); the architectural photograph forms part of the Charles Warterfield Architectural Collection. Gift of: The Estate of Charles W. Warterfield, Jr., F. A. I. A. The original is a 35 mm color transparency (2 x 2 in. slide mount).</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Tennessee State Capitol (Nashville, Tenn.); War Memorial Building (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architects--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Capitols--Tennessee--Nashville; Public buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Plazas--Tennessee--Nashville; Government facilities--American--Tennessee--Nashville; Columns--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Tennessee--Capital and capitol; Legislative Plaza (Nashville, Tenn.); Charlotte Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Sixth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Warterfield, Charles W. (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Estate of Charles W. Warterfield, Jr., F.A.I.A. (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1978-09-04</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Slides; Photographs; Architectural photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>WSC 4169</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Charles Warterfield Architectural Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1970-1979</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/2244</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>