<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Pilgrim Emanuel Baptist Church, 1969</dc:title>
<dc:description>Photograph of Pilgrim Emanuel Baptist Church, located at 945 Douglas Avenue. Pilgrim Emanuel Baptist Church was founded in the late 1880s, with the congregation gathering above an ice cream company's offices on 6th Avenue South. The church was moved to Peabody Street in 1907 and it later moved to Division Street. The new church building on Douglas Avenue was dedicated in February of 1969. Photographed by R.W. Ray of the Nashville Housing Authority, 1969. Forms part of the MDHA Photograph Collection. 1 photograph : b &amp; w. </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Nashville Housing Authority (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Baptist church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Baptist church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville, Brick churches--Tennessee-Nashville; Baptist churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; African American churches--Tennessee--Nashville;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.); Douglas Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Nashville Housing Authority/Metropolitan Development and Housing Agency</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1969</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photograph</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>MDHA Photos Box 3 Fol 87 Pilgrim Emmanuel Baptist Church 001</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>MDHA Photograph Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>	
U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/12804</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>