<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Oral history interview with Charles Tony Moorman, 2007 August 09</dc:title>
<dc:description>Excerpts from an interview with civil rights leader Charles Tony Moorman on 09 August 2007 by Larry Patterson as part of the Civil Rights Oral History Project.  In the excerpts Moorman discusses when the Washington Junior High School basketball team became the first African-American junior high school team to get their picture printed in the Nashville Banner as well as basketball tradition at Pearl High School.  The complete interview is available in the Special Collections Division.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Moorman, Charles Tony--Interviews; Lawson, Ronald R.; Swanigan, Teddy; Watkins, Boo	</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Washington Junior High School (Nashville, Tenn.); Pearl High School (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville Banner	</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African Americans; Civil Rights; Race Relations; Education; Junior High Schools; High Schools; Sports &amp; Recreation; Basketball--Tennessee--Nashville; Basketball stories--Tennessee--Nashville; Basketball teams--Tennessee--Nashville; African American schools--Tennessee--Nashville; Public schools--Tennessee--Nashville; Junior high schools--Tennessee--Nashville; High schools--Tennessee--Nashville; African American basketball players--Tennessee--Nashville	</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Education; Nashville (Tenn.)--Race relations; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social conditions; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Moorman, Charles Tony (Interviewee); Patterson, Larry, 1944- (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2007-08-09</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CROHPMoormanC1005clip1.mp3; CROHPMoormanC1010and1011clip1.mp3; CROHPMoormanC_transcript.pdf</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from: CROHPMoormanC digital recording converted from wav to mp3 format in 2007.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Civil Rights Oral History Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1617</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>