<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>WSM radio cast presents broadcasts about college life, 1933</dc:title>
<dc:description>During the fall of 1933, WSM radio presented a radio "newsreel" of outstanding colleges in the nation. They broadcasted a total of 28 shows on Mondays and Fridays. The broadcasts recreated college life and sports events, complete with legitimate actors, singers and a variety of musicians.  The newspaper ad for the program read, "Yes, sir! It's here at last, something new in radio. Your favorite college presented on the air! The drama, the color, the spectacle of university campus life - history unveiled in your own loudspeakers - the human interest side of these great institutions. Who started them, how, when, where, what? Authentic, created and staged in collaboration with university authorities! Famous football heroes brought out of the past, famous games, dusted off and given life again through the miraculous voice of radio. The newsiest, breeziest, most entertaining program on the air. Thirty minutes packed full of action, rousing music, and drama."  Forms part of the Madge West Joseph Scrapbooks.  1 photograph : b &amp; w; 8 x 10 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Performing Arts; Music; Theatre; Education; Colleges and Universities; Sports &amp; Recreation; Sports Teams; Popular Culture; Entertainment; Business; Industries; Performing arts--Tennessee--Nashville; Radio programs--Tennessee--Nashville; Universities and colleges; Musicians--Tennessee--Nashville; Radio broadcasting--Tennessee--Nashville; Actors--Tennessee--Nashville; Singers--Tennessee--Nashville; Entertainers--Tennessee--Nashville; Entertainment--Tennessee--Nashville; Universities &amp; colleges; Radio industry--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1933</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>MWJS - WSM broadcast photo</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Madge West Joseph Scrapbooks</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1025</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>