<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Glimpses of Nashville, Tennessee:  Scene on Cumberland River</dc:title>
<dc:description>A view of the steamer &#8220;Henry Harley&#8221; docked at the loading area along the Cumberland River, in downtown Nashville, Tennessee. This steamboat was a low water boat in the Louisville-Evansville trade.  Steamboats, in their heyday, provided the fastest, most convenient, and most economical method of transportation available. The "Henry Harley" sank in 1906 at Buffalo Landing, between Granville and Carthage, after hitting a big rock while backing in during landing.  
Forms part of Glimpses of Nashville. 1 booklet 
</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rivers--Tennessee--Nashville; River boats--Cumberland River (Ky. and Tenn.); Boats--Tennessee--Nashville; Business enterprises--Tennessee--Nashville </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Cumberland River (Ky. and Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Manx, Chicago </dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1900s</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Glimpses of Nashville Book013 boat scene on Cumberland River</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Glimpses of Nashville, Tennessee booklet   </dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1900-1909</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/7694</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>