<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Excerpt 1 from oral history interview with George Boyles, 1988 July 20</dc:title>
<dc:description>An excerpt from an oral history interview with George Boyles, conducted on 20 July 1988 by Mary Glenn Hearne.  Boyles discusses the construction of several colleges in Nashville during the period 1910-1930, including Peabody College, Scarritt College, and the Southern YMCA Graduate College.  The complete interview, as well as a partial index, is available in the repository.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Boyles, George Herbert, 1905-1997--Interviews</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Vanderbilt University. Peabody College; George Peabody College of Education; Scarritt College for Christian Workers; Scarritt-Bennett Center; Young Men's Christian Association, Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Schools; Education; Colleges and Universities; School facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; College facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; School buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Universities and colleges--Tennessee--Nashville; Educational facilities--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Boyles, George Herbert, 1905-1997 (Interviewee); Hearne, Mary Glenn (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1988-07-20</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3 (1.31 MB; 1 min., 26 sec.)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Boyles8bclip1</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from:  Boyles audio cassette recording converted to mp3 format in 2006.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:coverage>1980-1989</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/205</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>