<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Hume-Fogg High School - Nashville, Tenn., between 1930 and 1945</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard of Hume-Fogg High School, a public high school located at 700 Broadway in Nashville, Tennessee.  In 1912 Hume High School and Fogg High School merged into Hume-Fogg at the school's current site on Broadway.  The building was constructed in the Tudor Revival style by architects William B. Ittner and Robert Sharp.  In 1942 Hume-Fogg was recast as a Technical and Vocational School.  In 1982 it was restructured to serve as an academic magnet school for Nashville's gifted and talented students.  Hume-Fogg was added to the National Registry of Historic Places in 1974.  Forms part of the Norton Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Hume-Fogg High School (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; High Schools; Education; Capital City Downtown Nashville; Public Schools; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Schools--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Public schools--Tennessee--Nashville; School facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; High schools--Tennessee--Nashville; Educational facilities--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Broadway Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Zibart Bros. (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>between 1930 and 1945</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Norton - 0381</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Norton Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939; 1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1981</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>