<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Tents serve as temporary housing in the Saudi Arabian desert for members of the Tennessee National Guard, circa 1990 November 15</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of several Tennessee National Guard soldiers walking across an open area in front of a load of supplies, surrounded by numerous tents serving as living quarters for the troops in the Saudi Arabian desert during Operation Desert Shield. The photograph was taken by Nashville Banner photographer Larry McCormack on assignment in Saudi Arabia in November 1990.  Forms part of the Nashville Banner Archives. 1 photograph transparency : col ; 35mm.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Tennessee. National Guard; Tennessee. Military Dept.; United States. National Guard Bureau; Tennessee. Army National Guard</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Military History; Persian Gulf War; Operation Desert Shield, 1990-1991; Persian Gulf War, 1991; Soldiers--Tennessee; Deserts--Saudi Arabia; Military personnel--American--Tennessee; Tents; Military camps--American--Saudi Arabia--1990; Deserts; Military life--American; Military service--United States</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Saudi Arabia--History--20th century--Sources; Saudi Arabia--Military relations--United States; United States--Military relations--Saudi Arabia; Tennessee--History--Sources; Saudi Arabia--Environmental conditions</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>McCormack, Larry (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1990-11-15</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Transparencies; Film transparencies</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BT 1990-2105-35a</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1990-1999</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1646</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>