<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Brazilian officials visit Nashville, Tennessee, 1956 June  </dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph related to the visit of several Brazilian government officials and wives, circa June 16th, 1956, who were on a goodwill tour of several United States cities to study government planning.  Each of the Brazilian officials was made an honorary citizen of Nashville by Mayor Ben West, and was presented with a kit of reports which showed the full scope of Nashville&#8217;s county and city planning in regards to metropolitan government.  During their visit to Nashville, the group dined with local civic leaders at the Colemere Club on Murfreesboro Road.  Forms part of Record Group 3, Metro Davidson County Photographer. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in. </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Hand, Irving; West, Ben, 1911-1974; Silva, Clovis N. da</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Banner; Colemere Club (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Mayors--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Businesses--Tennessee--Nashville; Planning--Tennessee--Nashville; Public officers--Tennessee--Nashville; Public officers--Brazil</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Officials and employees--History--Sources; Brazil--Officials and employees--History--Sources; Sa&#771;o Paulo (Brazil)--Officials and employees--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1956-06</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG3 8050 Brazilian visitors at Colemere Club etc June 1956 005</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3 Metro Davidson County Photographer   </dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/7593</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>