<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Letter to mother from Jessie Wallace, 1945 January 07</dc:title>
<dc:description>A two-page typewritten letter by Jessie Wallace to her mother, Mrs. C.M. (Lorine) Wallace of Ames, Iowa.  Jessie grew up in Oklahoma and her family moved to Iowa during the Depression. During World War II, Jessie Wallace (later McNutt) served in the Army as a dietician with the 100th General Hospital and the 77th Evacuation Hospital in Europe.  She wrote her mother often while overseas, where she was stationed in England, France, Belgium and Germany. She was transferred to a hospital near the front lines during the Battle of the Bulge.  Her letters are detailed and provide a vivid description of life overseas as woman in military service from 1944 to 1945.  In this particular letter Wallace is in Belgium, serving with the 77th Evacuation Hospital.  She comments on the good and steady supply of food that has been coming in from the states, sometimes getting meat twice a day!  She mentions her living quarters and the social conditions in the particular Belgium town she is stationed in.  She tells her mother not to worry; she is safe, but she explains she is still sometimes jumpy, and proceeds to tell a little about her trip to her new assignment in the midst of the Battle of the Bulge, a few weeks earlier. She describes some of the other members of her unit (both men and women), and also tells about an informal New Years party, including entertainment.  Her closing appears on the backside of the second page.  Envelope is included.  Forms part of the Veterans History Project. 1 letter: col; 8.5 x 11 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>McNutt, Jessie L. Wallace, 1920-; Wallace, Lorine</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>United States. Army. Evacuation Hospital, 77th</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Military History; Food; World War II; Women; Popular Culture; War; Veterans--Tennessee--History--Sources; Veterans--Iowa--History--Sources; World War, 1939-1945--Hospitals; World War, 1939-1945--Women; World War, 1939-1945--Participation, Female; Women veterans--Tennessee--History--Sources; Women veterans--Iowa--History--Sources; Correspondence; Letters; Cookery; World War, 1939-1945--Personal narratives, American; Nutritionists--Personal narratives; Nutritionists--Correspondence; Women--Iowa--Correspondence; Military service--United States; Military life--American; Military cookery--American</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Belgium</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>McNutt, Jessie L. Wallace, 1920-</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1945-01-07</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text; Letters (correspondence)</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>VHP-WWII-McNutt-F5-Jan 7</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Veterans History Project Collection, World War II Series, Jessie L. Wallace McNutt Papers</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1217</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>