<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Oral history interview with James Carlew, 2004 March 25, excerpt 06</dc:title>
<dc:description>An excerpt from an oral history interview with Nashville veteran James Carlew, conducted on 25 March 2004 by Larry Patterson as part of the Nashville Public Library's Veterans History Project.  Carlew, who served in the Navy during World War II and in the Korean War, discusses the experience of escaping his tank after it had been hit by a mortar attack in Korea.  He tells about ammunition exploding on the outside of the tank, making escape impossible through the top hatches, and having to exit the tank from the bottom.  He also tells about the experience of fear during war.  The complete interview, as well as an index, is available in the repository.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Carlew, James, 1927- --Interviews</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Veterans History Project (U.S.); United States. Army. Infantry Division, 2nd, United States. Army. Tank Battalion, 72nd</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Military History; Veterans--Tennessee--Interviews; Korean War; African Americans; Korean War, 1950-1953--Tank warfare; Korean War, 1950-1953--Veterans--Tennessee--Interviews; Korean War, 1950-1953--Sources; Korean War, 1950-1953--Participation, African American; Korean War, 1950-1953--Personal narratives, American; Tanks (Military science); Combat--Psychological aspects; Fear</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Korea</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Carlew, James, 1927- (Interviewee); Patterson, Larry, 1944- (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2004-03-25</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/MP (2 min., 17 sec. )</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>VHPCarlewJ2bclip1</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpt from:  VHPCarlewJ audio cassette recording converted to mp3 format in 2006.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Veterans History Project collection, World War II and Korean War series</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/638</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>