<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Sketch from the Albert Hadley Interior Design Collection</dc:title>
<dc:description>Albert Hadley (1920-2012), a native of Nashville, was a renowned interior designer whose clients included the Vice President Albert Gore family, Jacqueline Kennedy Onassis, Diane Sawyer, and the Astor and Getty families. The Albert Hadley Interior Design Collection includes over 800 titles from his personal and professional book collection, as well as sketches and ephemera. Please contact the Main Library Reference Department at (615) 862-5800 to make an appointment to view this item.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Hadley, Albert, 1920-2012</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Interior design drawings--1940-2010;Interior design firms;Interior design library;Interior designers;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>New York (N.Y.);Nashville (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Hadley, Albert</dc:creator>
<dc:contributor>Brennan, Jared (Digitization, Metadata Cataloger)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>Original sketches span the late 1940's through circa 2010. Digital surrogates created in January 2012.</dc:date>
<dc:type>Image</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Hadley 038</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Black and white jpeg images derived from  8 bit 400 dpi TIFF archival masters. Color jpeg images derived from 24 bit 400 dpi TIFF archival masters. Original sketches consist of a variety of media types, including ink, watercolor, and pencil on leafs of xerox paper, copy paper, yellow legal-pad paper, and brown paper shopping bags.</dc:source>
<dc:relation>Albert Hadley Interior Design Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1947-2010</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Main Library Reference Department of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5800.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/3948</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>