<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Dudley Park, Nashville, Tennessee, between 1916 and 1935</dc:title>
<dc:description>A landscape view of Dudley Park (Louise and Rebecca Dudley Park), located at Chestnut Street and Third Avenue South in Nashville, Tennessee.  When purchased in 1913, it was known as the Chestnut Street Park and served as a playground for that park of South Nashville.  The Board renamed it the Louise and Rebecca Dudley Park in 1914 in memory of the two daughters of Park Commissioner Robert M. Dudley, who died when a train hit the family car at Glidden, Iowa.  A swimming pool, bathhouse, bandstand and ball diamond were built in the park in 1920, and it became a site of the annual park baseball championship tournaments during the 1920s.  The Works Progress Administration renovated the park during the 1930s and completed there the second community center with a gymnasium built in the park system, using materials donated by city government from wrecked public buildings.  In addition to a community center, the park added ball diamonds and tennis courts.  Forms part of Metro Archives Record Group 327, Metro Parks and Recreation Collection.  1 b &amp; w photograph.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.) Board of Parks and Recreation--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Parks--Tennessee--Nashville; Urban parks--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Parks; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc. ; Third Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Chestnut Street (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Patterson, R. S. (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>between 1916 and 1935</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Parks - Dudley Park - 002</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>RG 327, Metro Parks Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1910-1919; 1920-1929; 1930-1939</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/6824</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>