<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Oral history interview with Frances Lusky, 1976 July 21, excerpt 02</dc:title>
<dc:description>An excerpt from an oral history interview with Frances Lusky, conducted on 21 July 1976 by Leonard Wood as part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. Tennessee Centennial Project.  Lusky discusses watching the sculptors, native Nashvillian Belle Kinney Scholz and her husband, Austrian Leopold Scholz, work on the second Parthenon replica.  The complete interview is available in the Special Collections Division.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Lusky, Frances Blum, 1890-1980--Interviews; Scholz, Belle Kinney, 1890-1959; Scholz, Leopold F., 1877-1946</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Parthenon (Art museum : Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Exhibitions--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Exhibition buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Sculptors--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.; Lusky, Frances Blum, 1890-1980 (Interviewee); Wood, Leonard  (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1976-07-21</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3 (57 sec.)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>HNITCPLuskyclip2</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from:  HNITCPLusky audio cassette recording converted to mp3 format in 2006.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Tennessee Centennial project: oral history</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1970-1979</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/937</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>