<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum gala opening, circa 1967</dc:title>
<dc:description>A gala opening of the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum building, located on Music Row (Music Square East and Division Street) circa 1967.  This original facility would include educational programs, the CMF Press and CMF Records, the Country Music Foundation Library (1968), and the historic sites RCA Studio B (1977) and Hatch Show Print (1986).  The Music Row location was closed December 31, 2000.  The building was later razed and a private parking lot for employees of music licensing firm BMI occupied the site.  The entity moved to a new location at 222 Fifth Avenue S, in downtown Nashville.  Forms part of Record Group 3, Metro Davidson County Photographer. 8 negatives, filmstrip: b &amp; w.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Minnie Pearl; Arnold, Eddy, 1918-2008; Briley, Beverly, 1914-1980</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Country music--Tennessee--Nashville; Music facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Country musicians--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1967</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 3 707 Buildings, companies 005; 006; 010; 011; 012; 014; 022; and 024.</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3 Metro Davidson County Photographer</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4835</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>