<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Trinity United Methodist Church, 2001 May</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of Trinity United Methodist Church located at 204 Trinity Lane in Nashville, Tennessee.  The cornerstone indicates that the congregation was formed in 1857 with the original name of Trinity Methodist Church, while the church was built in 1904.  The foundation is made of rough cut stone blocks.  The exterior walls are brick.  The roof is gabled with tar shingles.  The windows include an oculus on the front facade and gothic arched stained glass windows on the side walls.  The front doors are wooden.  Special features include two small towers over the front doors.  Forms part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project. 1 photograph : col. ; 4  x 6  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Trinity United Methodist Church (Nashville, Tenn.); Trinity Methodist Church (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Popular Culture; Religion; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Religious facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Church architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Methodist church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Protestant church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Towers--Tennessee--Nashville; Arches--Tennessee--Nashville; Brick churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Gables--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture, Gothic--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Details; Churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Methodist churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Protestant churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural details--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs; Trinity Lane (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2001-05</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>SSSP - Trinity United Meth</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1546</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>