<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>On the subject of national defense, circa 1955</dc:title>
<dc:description>An original political cartoon drawing created by Jack Knox, the Nashville Banner editorial cartoonist from the mid-1940s to early 1970s.  A cartoon portrait of President Dwight D. Eisenhower, who served as the thirty-fourth President of the United States (1953-1961).  At the time of this editorial cartoon, circa 1955, there was growing concern by the Eisenhower administration about improvements to national defense during the Cold War period.  It also became one of the campaign issues in the presidential election of 1956.  In the cartoon, a dignified Eisenhower holds a document ("Security Decisions").  Below him on a trail are two men marching along with political signs: Tennessee Senator Estes Kefauver (with carpetbag and coonskin cap) holding "The country would be safer with Adlai &amp; me."  Behind him is Stevenson with "End Draft, Etc. Etc."  In 1956 the Stevenson-Kefauver ticket lost to the Eisenhower-Nixon ticket.  Forms part of the Jack Knox Political Cartoon Collection. 1 original cartoon drawing : b &amp; w ; 14.5 x 19.5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969--Caricatures and cartoons; Kefauver, Estes,  1903-1963--Caricatures and cartoons; Stevenson, Adlai E. (Adlai Ewing), 1835-1914--Caricatures and cartoons</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Banner</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Capital City; Military History; Politics; Political cartoons--United States--20th century; Political cartoons--Tennessee--Nashville; Caricatures and cartoons--Tennessee--Nashville; Cartoonists--Tennessee--Nashville; Editorial cartoonists--Tennessee--Nashville; Generals as presidents--Caricatures and cartoons; Presidents--United States--Caricatures and cartoons; Cartoonists; Economic &amp; political systems; Presidents--United States</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>United States--Politics and government--20th century--Caricatures and cartoons; United States--Defenses--20th century--Caricatures and cartoons</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Knox, Jack, 1910- (Cartoonist)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Knox, Joseph T. (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1955</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Caricatures; Cartoons (Commentary); Editorial cartoons</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Knox NPL-312</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Jack Knox Political Cartoon Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/883</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>