<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Glimpses of Nashville, Tennessee: Capitol Grounds</dc:title>
<dc:description>A view of the grounds at the Tennessee State Capitol Building, with the Andrew Jackson Statue.  This statue depicts Andrew Jackson at the Battle of New Orleans and was sculpted by American sculptor Clark Mills. The statue is the first design of a person on horseback ever cast in the United States. It is one of three identical statues located at Nashville, New Orleans, and Washington, D.C. respectively. The monument was dedicated during Nashville's centennial celebration in May 1880. This Tennessee State Capitol building is a National Historic Landmark, located in downtown Nashville, Tennessee.  Monuments on the Capitol grounds include statues of two of the three Tennessee residents who served as President of the United States: Andrew Jackson and Andrew Johnson by Jim Gray.  The second President from Tennessee, James K. Polk, is buried in a tomb (pictured) on the grounds, together with his wife, Sarah Childress Polk. The building was signed by architect William Strickland, it is one of Nashville's most prominent examples of Greek Revival architecture. Forms part of Glimpses of Nashville, Tennessee. 1 booklet </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Mills, Clark, 1810-1883; Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845--Statues </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Tennessee State Capitol (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Public buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.  </dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Manx, Chicago </dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1900s</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Glimpses of Nashville Book012 Capitol Grounds</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Glimpses of Nashville, Tennessee booklet   </dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1900-1909</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/7693</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>