<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Excerpt 2 from oral history interview with Beverly Briley,  1980 April 03</dc:title>
<dc:description>An excerpt from an oral history interview with former Nashville Mayor Beverly Briley, conducted on 3 April 1980 by Paul Clements as part of the Century III Nashville:  Nashville Heritage Project.  Briley, who was Mayor of Nashville from 1963 to 1975 and was the first mayor after the consolidation of the city and county government, discusses mass transit in Nashville.  The complete interview, as well as a transcript, is available in the repository.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Briley, Beverly, 1914-1980--Interviews</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Capital City; Transportation; Mayors--Tennessee--Nashville; Transportation--Tennessee--Nashville; Local transit--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History; Nashville (Tenn.)--Economic conditions; Tennessee--Capital and capitol</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Briley, Beverly, 1914-1980 (Interviewee); Clements, Paul, 1947- (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1980-04-03</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3 (1.37 MB; 1 min., 30 sec.)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CentIIIBriley7bclip1</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from:  CentIIIBriley audio cassette recordings converted to mp3 format in 2006.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Century III Nashville: Nashville Heritage Project : oral history</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1980-1989</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/214</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>