<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Program from Annual Banquet, Tennessee Chapter, American Institute of Architects, 1923 October 3. Front cover.</dc:title>
<dc:description>This program from the 1923 Annual Banquet of the Tennessee Chapter of the American Institute of Architects, held at the Centennial Club, boasts a number of distinguished guests, including architect and past president Henry C. Hibbs.  Henry C. Hibbs was elected as a member of the American Institute of Architects in March 1919.  From 1919 to 1920, he served as a sponsor, charter member and first president of the Tennessee Chapter of the A.I.A.  Forms part of the Henry C. Hibbs Papers. 1 program : col. ; 5.25 in. x 9.5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Hibbs, Henry C. (Clossen), 1882-1949</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>American Institute of Architects. Middle Tennessee Chapter; Centennial Club of Nashville--History</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Architects; Buildings; Associations, institutions, etc.--Tennessee--Nashville; Dinners and dining--Tennessee--Nashville; Clubs--Tennessee--Nashville; City and town life--Tennessee--Nashville; Banquets--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1923</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text; Programs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/tiff (35.9 KB)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>HCHP-Prof-Docs-b1, f2, front</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Henry C. Hibbs Papers</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1920-1923</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/306</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>