<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Dinah Shore visits here on way to Capital, 1941 March 14</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of Dinah Shore surrounded by family and friends at the Nashville Airport. This partial text accompanied the photograph appearing in the Nashville Banner newspaper on March 15, 1941: "Dinah Shore, radio and record artist, stopped for about ten minutes in her native Nashville Friday afternoon to receive the praises and greeting of relatives and friends who had not seen the dark-eyed contralto since she was here in June two years ago&#8230;.Delighted, she chatted with the throng until the second call for her plane, then left for Washington, D. C. where she will sing tonight at the White House Correspondents Association dinner party." Forms part of the Nashville Banner Archives. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 3.25 x 4.25 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Shore, Dinah, 1917-1994</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>American Airlines, inc.; Metropolitan Nashville Airport Authority--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Performing Arts; Music; Capital City; Popular Culture; 
Entertainers--Tennessee--Nashville; Musicians--Tennessee--Nashville; Women singers--Tennessee--Nashville; Airports--Tennessee--Nashville; Celebrities--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Nashville Banner staff photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1941-03-14</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BN 1941-154-1</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/2347</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>