<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Church of Christ, 2001 December</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of the former Church of Christ located at Third Avenue North, in Nashville, Tennessee.  This church went through many name changes over the years.  In the 1960s the name changed to Third Avenue Church of Christ.  In the 1990s the building was home to A.A. Allen Lock and Key Repair Services.  At the time of this survey and photograph, the church was being used for the Church of God in Christ congregation.  Lastly, in 2004 the church was called Pentecostal Church of God.  In 2005 the address stopped appearing in Nashville city directories.  The building's foundation was concrete block that had been painted red.  The exterior walls were vinyl siding.  The roof was gabled with tar shingles.  The windows were clear glass with metal frames.  The doors were metal.  Forms part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project. 1 photograph : col. ; 4  x 6  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Church of Christ (Nashville, Tenn.); Third Avenue Church of Christ (Nashville, Tenn.); Church of God in Christ (Nashville, Tenn.); Pentecostal Church of God (Nashville, Tenn.); A.A. Allen Lock and Key Repair Services (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Popular Culture; Religion; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Religious facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Church architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Churches of Christ--Tennessee--Nashville; Churches--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs; Third Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2001-12</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>SSSP - Church of Christ</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/745</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>