<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Antiwar demonstrators march against war in Cambodia, 1970 May</dc:title>
<dc:description>In 1970, in response to President Nixon&#8217;s widening of the Vietnam War into Cambodia, students throughout the nation protested with anti-war demonstrations.  Nixon ordered U. S. troops into Cambodia on April 30th, 1970, and protests against the war mounted.  On May 4, 1970, about 500 Vanderbilt faculty and students joined a community march from the campus to the Federal Building downtown. That same day the National Guard shot more than a dozen student protesters, killing four, at Kent State University in Ohio.  A few days later, hundreds of Vanderbilt students and faculty voted at a meeting to walk out of their classes to protest events in Southeast Asia and Ohio.  In these photographs, the anti-war protestors are pictured in downtown along Broadway, marching towards the Federal Office Building.  Forms part of Record Group 3, Metro Davidson County Photographer.  Filmstrip negatives : b &amp; w.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Anti-war demonstrations--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1970-05</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text; Wills</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 3 1467 Demonstrations Cambodia004, 009, 011, 014, 017, 018, 019, 20, 30, 32, 33, and 37.</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3 Metro Davidson County Photographer</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1970-1979</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4819</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>