<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Glimpses of Nashville, Tennessee: Tomb of Andrew Jackson</dc:title>
<dc:description>A view of President Andrew Jackson's Tomb at the Hermitage, the handsome old estate of "Old Hickory" the seventh President of the United States. Andrew Jackson died in 1845 at the Hermitage reaching the age of 77. His burial was beside his beloved wife Rachel Donelson Jackson, who had died in 1828 just before he took the office of President. The funerary monument designed by Nashville architect David Morrison is a Doric "tempietto" as well as a "monopteron" an architectural element from Greek antiquity of cylindrical form surrounded by a single row of columns. The Hermitage is a National Historic Landmark that is preserved by the Ladies' Hermitage Association. In December 1960, the National Park Service designated The Hermitage as one of Tennessee's first National Historic Landmarks and in 1971 the property was formally listed in the National Register of Historic Places. The Tulip Grove mansion was individually listed in the National Register in 1984. The Hermitage is located approximately 16 miles from downtown Nashville, Tennessee.  Forms part of Glimpses of Nashville. 1 booklet </dc:description>
<dc:subject>	
Hermitage (Hermitage, Tenn.); Ladies Hermitage Association
</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture--Tennessee--Hermitage; Tombs &amp; sepulchral monuments--Tennessee--Hermitage; Monuments &amp; memorials--Tennessee--Hermitage</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Hermitage (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Hermitage (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Manx, Chicago </dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1900s</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Glimpses of Nashville Book055 Tomb of Andrew Jackson</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Glimpses of Nashville, Tennessee booklet   </dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1900-1909</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/7757</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>