<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Oral history interview with Henry L. Douglass, 1981 November 11, excerpt 01</dc:title>
<dc:description>An excerpt from an oral history interview with Nashville doctor and urologist Henry L. Douglass, conducted on 11 November 1981 by Ophelia Paine as part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. 1910-1935 Oral History Project.  Douglass describes Madison, Tennessee, at the turn of the twentieth century, including churches, buildings, businesses, the railroad station, and the "century party."  The complete interview, as well an index, is available in the Special Collections Division.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Douglass, Henry L., 1891-1990--Interviews</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Business; Medicine; Enterprise; Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Capital City; Transportation; Popular Culture; Physicians--Tennessee--Nashville; Urologists--Tennessee--Nashville; Church buildings--Tennessee--Madison; Buildings--Tennessee--Madison; Railroads--Buildings and structures--Tennessee--Madison; Railroad stations--Tennessee--Madison; Business enterprises--Tennessee--Madison; Parties--Tennessee--Madison</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Madison (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Madison (Tenn.)--Description and travel; Madison (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Madison (Tenn.)--Commerce; Madison (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.; Douglass, Henry L., 1891-1990 (Interviewee); Paine, Ophelia (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1981-11-11</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3 (1 min., 36 sec.)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>HNIOHDouglassHJaclip1</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from:  HNIOHDouglassH audio cassette recording converted to mp3 format in 2006.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. 1910-1935 Oral History Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1980-1989</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/891</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>