<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Excerpt 2 from oral history interview with Wilbur Foster Creighton, Jr., 1976 August 18</dc:title>
<dc:description>An excerpt from an oral history interview with Wilbur Foster Creighton, Jr., conducted on 18 August 1976 by Ann Wells as part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. Tennessee Centennial Project:  Oral History .  Creighton discusses the Women's Building, part of the Tennessee Centennial Exposition of 1897, and how it was designed by female architect and artist Sarah Ward Conley and built by contractors George Moore and Sons.   The complete interview, as well as an index, is available in the repository.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Creighton, Wilbur F., 1906-2004--Interviews; Conley, Sarah Ward, 1859-1944</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Tennessee Centennial and International Exposition (1897 : Nashville, Tenn.); George Moore and Sons (Firm : Nashville, Tenn.); Women's Building (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Popular Culture; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architects--Tennessee--Nashville; Building construction--Tennessee--Nashville; Exhibition buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Women architects--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Tennessee--Centennial celebrations, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Creighton, Wilbur F., 1906-2004 (Interviewee); Wells, Ann (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1976-08-18</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3 (709 KB; 45 sec.)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>HNITCPCreightonclip2</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from:  HNITCPCreighton audio cassette recording converted to mp3 format in 2006.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Tennessee Centennial project: oral history</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1970-1979</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/207</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>