<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Avon N. Williams, Jr.,  and Marie Bontemps celebrate after Tennessee state Senate race, 1968 August 01</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of Avon N. Williams, Jr., being congratulated by his wife, Marie Bontemps, and supporters after his successful bid to become the first African American senator in Tennessee since Reconstruction.  He ran for state senator from the 19th District in Nashville. Born in Knoxville, Tenn., Avon N. Williams, Jr., was one of the leading African American lawyers in Tennessee. After practicing law in Knoxville, he became law partners with prominent Nashville attorney, Z. Alexander Looby. His role as attorney for the NAACP Legal Defense Fund sparked a long history of involvement with the civil rights movement.  His role with Geier v. Blanton helped to bring about merger of University of Tennessee and Tennessee State University. The former Nashville campus of UT Nashville was later named the Avon Williams Jr. Campus of Tennessee State University. He also cosponsored the law requiring public schools to teach African American history. He was a member of Tennessee state senate from 1968 -1990.  Forms part of the Nashville Banner Archives. 1 photograph : b &amp; w ; 8 x 10 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Williams, Avon N., 1921-1994; Bontemps, Marie</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Tennessee. General Assembly. Senate--Elections, 1968</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Civil Rights; African Americans; Race Relations; Capital City; Politics; Race relations--Tennessee--History--20th century; Civil rights--Tennessee--Nashville--History--20th century; Social change--Tennessee--Nashville--History--20th century; African Americans--Civil rights--Tennessee--Nashville--History--20th century; African American lawyers--Tennessee--Nashville--History--20th century; African American politicians--Tennessee--Nashville--History--20th century; Activists--Tennessee--1960-1970</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--20th century--Sources; Tennessee--Politics and government--History--20th century</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Ray, Bob (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1968-08-01</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BP - Williams, Avon - 08-01-1968</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital image. This image is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Nashville Room, Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/2229</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>