<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Exterior view of St. Mary of the Seven Sorrows Church, Nashville, Tennessee, 1977 June </dc:title>
<dc:description>A view of St. Mary's Catholic Church located at 330 Fifth Avenue North in downtown Nashville, Tennessee.  St. Mary's Catholic Church, the first Roman-Catholic Cathedral in Tennessee, was designed by William Strickland, architect for the Tennessee State Capitol. The edifice was erected in the Greek Revival style at Summer Street (now Fifth Avenue) and Cedar Street (now Charlotte Street) in 1844 and officially dedicated as St. Mary of the Seven Sorrows Catholic Church on October 31, 1847. During the Civil War, this church was converted into a hospital. St. Mary's which was placed on the National Register of Historic Places in 1970, was the cathedral in the Nashville diocese until 1914, when the Cathedral of the Incarnation was built on West End Avenue. The foundation is made of smooth cut stone blocks. The exterior walls are brick and front facade is limestone. Special features include two ionic columns, a portico and a bell tower. Forms part of the Claynita Harris Slide Collection.  The original is a 35 mm color transparency (2 x 2 in. slide mount) </dc:description>
<dc:subject>St. Mary&#8217;s Church (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Catholic church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Catholic churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church architecture--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1977-06</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives </dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Harris Photo          392 St Marys downtown Nashville</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Claynita Harris Slide Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1970-1979</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/7036</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>