<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Dedication of Wharton Elementary School, Nashville, Tennessee, 1959 February </dc:title>
<dc:description>A scene from the 1959 dedication of Wharton Elementary School, related to a new school facility built at 1625 18th Avenue North in Nashville, Tennessee.  Wharton Elementary School was named for Arthur Dickson Wharton (1840-1900), scholar, Confederate naval hero, and educator.  The original school building was located at 1515 18th Avenue N in North Nashville.  In 1959 a new school facility was built a block away, to accommodate 800 students in grades 1-9, replacing the original structure which had housed grades 1-4.  The enrollment would further increase, with building expansion. The original building was later demolished.  Forms part of Record Group 3, Metro Davidson County Photographer. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.   </dc:description>
<dc:subject>West, Ben, 1911-1974</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Public schools--Tennessee--Nashville; Schools--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Teachers--Tennessee--Nashville; Educators--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Eighteenth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1959-02</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives </dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG3 7265 Wharton School dedication Feb1959 001</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3 Metro Davidson County Photographer   </dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/7225</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>