<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>State Prison, Nashville, Tennessee, circa 1940s</dc:title>
<dc:description>
A postcard of the State Prison (Tennessee State Penitentiary), circa 1940s.  The prison facility, located off of Centennial Boulevard in West Nashville was built in 1897.  This structure takes on the appearance of a Gothic castle. At the time of its construction, this building was considered one of the most modern and humane prisons in the United States. It was built almost entirely of materials indigenous to the state. S.M. Patton of Chattanooga served as the architect for the project. The complex consists of the four-story, turreted Administration Building, the main prison building and the walled compound. The white brick Administration Building is connected by a passageway to the main prison building. Architectural elements include a central tower with turrets and dormers, conical roofs, arched windows and decorative corbelling. In 1992, the 400-cell prison ceased operations, and all remaining inmates were moved to one of the state's other corrections facilities. Since then, the empty building has been used various times as a movie and television set.  Forms part of the Ridley Wills II Nashville Postcards Collection.  1 postcard.  
</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Wills, Ridley, 1934-</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture, Gothic--Tennessee--Nashville; Prisons--Tennessee--Nashville </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc. </dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Ridley Wills II (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1940s</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RidleyWillsPostcards Box 2 117 State Prison Nashville Tenn</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Ridley Wills II Nashville Postcards Collection  </dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/9319</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>