<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Andrew Price Memorial United Methodist Church, 2002 January</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of the Andrew Price Memorial United Methodist Church located at 2846 Lebanon Road in Nashville, Tennessee.  The roots of the church started around 1850.  At that time a group of Methodists organized the Donelson Methodist Episcopal Church, South.  When the congregation outgrew their church on Donelson Pike, Mr. and Mrs. Andrew Price, owners of Clover Bottom Farm, donated two acres of their land on Lebanon Road on which to build.  In 1904 the new church was built, and in 1907 it was renamed for Andrew Price.  The word "memorial" was added to the name following Price's death in 1909.  Throughout the years, additions were made to the church as membership increased.  By 1958, a larger sanctuary was required, and the current brick sanctuary was added to the original structure.  In 1974 the original sanctuary was restored as the church's chapel.  The foundation of the church is made of rough cut stone blocks and smooth cut capping stone.  The exterior walls are red brick.  The roof is gabled and comprised of tar shingles.  The windows are gothic arched stained glass with storm windows attached.  The doors are made of wood and glass.  Forms part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project. 1 photograph : col. ; 4  x 6  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Andrew Price Memorial United Methodist Church (Nashville, Tenn.); Donelson Methodist Episcopal Church, South (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Popular Culture; Religion; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Religious facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Church architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Brick churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Methodist church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Protestant church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Chapels--Tennessee--Nashville; Churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Methodist churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Protestant churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville; Steeples</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs; Lebanon Road (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2002-01</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>SSSP - Andrew Price Memorial</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/719</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>