<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of crowd, Fehr Elementary School, corner of Fifth Avenue and Garfield Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 1957 September 09</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of irate segregationists exchanging words with supporters of desegregation at Fehr Elementary School, Nashville, Tennessee, 9 September 1957.  Police officers escorted African American students into the school, marking the first day of public school desegregation in Nashville, Tennessee and what was known as the Nashville Plan, a plan to desegregate one grade per year starting with the first grade. Forms part of the Nashville Banner Archives. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 3.25 x 4.25 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Fehr Elementary School (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Civil Rights; African Americans; Race Relations; Education; Elementary Schools; Capital City; Education--Tennessee--Nashville; African Americans--Civil rights--Tennessee--Nashville; Civil rights movements--Tennessee--Nashville; African Americans--Segregation--Tennessee--Nashville; Segregation in education--Law and legislation--United States--History; Discrimination in education--Law and legislation--United States--History; School integration--United States; School children--Tennessee--Nashville; Schools--Tennessee--Nashville; Public schools--Tennessee--Nashville; Students--Tennessee--Nashville; School integration--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Race relations; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social conditions; Southern States--Race relations--History--20th century--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Malone, John (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1957-09-09</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/tiff (32.3 MB)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BN 1957-2290-n2</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/553</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>