<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Radnor College, Nashville, Tenn., circa 1910</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard of Radnor College in Nashville, Tennessee.  Radnor College was started in 1906 on a hill overlooking Nolensville Pike by Presbyterian minister Andrew Nelson Eshman.  Famous for its free four-week travel program, this women's college sent students on a trip each year that encompassed stops in New York, Washington, D.C., Buffalo, Niagara Falls, Cincinnati, Cleveland, Albany, Atlantic City, Baltimore and Philadelphia, before returning back to campus for regular schoolwork.  While it was only in operation until 1914, the school had a lasting impact on the surrounding community, as numerous businesses, churches, a South Nashville neighborhood, and a state natural area bear now encorporate the name "Radnor." It is uncertain as to where Eshman came up with the name, though it is speculated that he may have brought it back from a trip to the Radnor township in Pennsylvania.  The school's main building burned in 1921.  An historical marker was erected at the corner of Nolensville Road and McClellan Avenue in 1995 to commemorate the school.  Forms part of the Nashville Room Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Radnor College (Nashville, Tenn.)--History</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Education; Colleges and Universities; Buildings; Architecture; Schools; Private Schools; Women; Capital City; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Women's colleges--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Education--Tennessee--Nashville; Universities and colleges--Tennessee--Nashville; School facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Women--Tennessee--Nashville; Educational facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Universities &amp; colleges--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources, Nolensville Pike (Nashville, Tenn.);  Nashville (Tenn.)--Intellectual life; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; McClellan Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1910</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Nash - 87 - Radnor College, Nashville, Tenn.</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1910-1919</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/819</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>