<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Ferro Enamel Company Plant, Nashville, Tennessee, 1946 June 28</dc:title>
<dc:description>The construction site of the Ferro Enamel Plant, an enamel frit processing facility established in Nashville, Tennessee.  By 1948, the Ferro Enamel Corporation, a Cleveland, Ohio producer of vitreous porcelain enamels and allied products had opened its new clay processing plant in Nashville.  There was an increased postwar demand for home building materials in the years after WWII. The consulting engineers on the project were the Foster &amp; Creighton General Contractors.  The Foster &amp; Creighton construction contracting firm was founded in 1885 by Wilbur F. Foster and Robert T. Creighton, who had both served as City Engineer of Nashville.  Forms part of the Foster &amp; Creighton General Contractors Collection. 1 b &amp; w photograph.  </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Ferro Enamel Corporation--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Business enterprises--Tennessee--Nashville; Construction industry--Tennessee--Nashville; Enamel and enameling--Tennessee--Nashville
  
</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Wiles-Hood (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Creighton III, Wilbur (donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>between 1946 and 1955 </dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Creighton Coll Nash Projects-Ferro Enamel Plant 005</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Foster &amp; Creighton General Contractors Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949; 1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/8493</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>