<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>The University of Nashville, circa 1859</dc:title>
<dc:description>A page from a mounted and bound volume of twenty-five pen-and-ink wash drawings, and two pen-and-ink maps of Nashville created by William A. Eichbaum during the 1850s.  Eichbaum was a Nashville bookseller and resident for fifty years.  The drawing on this page is of the main buildings on the University of Nashville campus.  Built in downtown Nashville between 1853 and 1854, this building was designed by Adolphus Heiman, one of Nashville's earliest architects.  Heiman incorporated elements of the Gothic Revival style in his design for this limestone structure.  The University of Nashville evolved from Nashville's first school, Davidson Academy, which was established in 1785 through the efforts of James Robertson, a Founder of Nashville in 1779.  The academy was renamed Cumberland College (1806), and then the University of Nashville (1826).  During the Civil War the university buildings, including this one, were used as a Federal hospital and barracks.  The University of Nashville closed in 1911.  Forms part of the William A. Eichbaum Sketchbook. 1 drawing : col. ; 5.75  x 9  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Eichbaum, William A., 1787-1873--Notebooks, sketchbooks, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>University of Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Education; Colleges and Universities; Downtown Nashville; Capital City; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Greek revival (Architecture)--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Universities and Colleges--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Drawing--Tennessee--Nashville; Universities &amp; colleges--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; College Hill (Nashville, Tenn.); Second Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Eichbaum, William A., 1787-1873</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1859</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Drawings; Sketchbooks</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Eich - 06 - University of Nashville</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>William A. Eichbaum Sketchbook</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1850-1859</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/276</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>