<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Brentwood, Tennessee, landholders honored by Hillsboro Hounds, 1936 November 21</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of "women of the Brentwood Methodist 
Church who prepared lunch for the group, including Mrs. Milton McArthur, Mrs. McArthur, Mrs. George S. Herbert, Mrs. Ewing Bradford, Mrs. Charles Howell, Sr., who served as chairman, Mrs. Charles Howell, Jr., Mrs. Dorris Gillespie, Miss Julia Calloway, Mrs. S. P. Cappa, Mrs. Marion Oden, Mrs. Wash Herbert, Mrs. William Puryear, Mrs. J. H. Jones, Misses Katherine and Madeline Goodwin, Mrs. W. L. Poole, and Mrs. W. F. Morgan. Scenes from an old time barbecue is appropriate title for these pictures, taken yesterday afternoon at an entertainment given by members of the Hillsboro Hounds at Green Pastures, farm of Mason Houghland, for landholders of the Brentwood section and members of their families." This article appeared in the Nashville Banner newspaper November 22, 1936. Forms part of the Nashville Banner Archives. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 3.25 x 4.25 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Houghland, Mason</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Hillsboro Hounds (Organization); Brentwood United Methodist Church (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Sports &amp; Recreation; Organizations; Popular Culture; Food; 
Associations, institutions, etc.--Tennessee--Williamson County; Farms--Tennessee--Williamson County; Dinners and dining--Tennessee--Williamson County; Women in the Methodist Church--Tennessee--Williamson County; Landowners--Tennessee--Williamson County; Manners &amp; customs--Tennessee--Brentwood</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Brentwood (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Brentwood (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Williamson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Williamson County--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Hood, John E. (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1936-11-21</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BN 1936-20-07</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/2346</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>