<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Turtle race at Colemere Club, Nashville, Tennessee, 1959 May 27</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of Middle Tennessee food industry businessmen racing turtles at the Colemere Club in Nashville, Tennessee. A photograph similar to this one appeared in the May 27, 1959 Nashville Banner newspaper with the following caption: "H. G. Hill, Jr., peers over the shoulders of Julian Ragland, of C.B. Ragland Co., John Duffy, Kroger Co., as turtles 'scratch off' at the Middle Tennessee Food Brokers derby Wednesday night at the Colemere Club." Forms part of the Nashville Banner Archives. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 3.25 x 4.25 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Hill, H. G., 1900-1993; Ragland, Julian; Duffy, John</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Colemere Club (Nashville, Tenn.); Middle Tennessee Food Brokers Association</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Business; Sports &amp; Recreation; Capital City; Popular Culture; Businessmen--Tennessee--Nashville; Food brokers--Tennessee--Nashville; Food industry and trade--Tennessee--Nashville; Men--Societies and clubs; Grocery trade--Tennessee--Nashville; Turtles--Tennessee--Nashville </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Commerce</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Schleicher, Paul (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1959-05-27</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BN 1959-1370</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/2319</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>