<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Guests of Martha Dobson, from the Nashville Times, 1940</dc:title>
<dc:description>A captioned photo from the Nashville Times (1940), about the guests of Miss Martha Dobson. The caption reads: &#8220;Popular visitors in Nashville for the festivities that marked the opening week of the New Year were Miss Virginia Moseley of Bowling Green, Ky., right, and Miss Judy Frazier of Tacoma, Wash., left, who were guests of Miss Martha Dobson, center, at the home of her parents, Mr. and Mrs. Allen Dobson, on Jackson Boulevard. Miss Moseley and Miss Frazier are both students at Finch Junior College in New York, and Miss Dobson attends Gunston Hall in Washington.&#8221; Forms part of the Nashville Times newspaper collection. 1 digital photo.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Dobson, Martha; Dobson, Allen; Moseley, Virginia; Frazier, Judy</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>College students; Best friends--Tennessee--Nashville; Female friendship</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1940</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>GuestsofMarthaDodson2--NT-1940</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Times Newspaper Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4233</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>