<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Riverfront Park Fourth of July Celebration in downtown Nashville, Tennessee, 1983 July 04</dc:title>
<dc:description>A scene from Nashville&#8217;s first 4th of July Festival at Riverfront Park in 1983.  The site is right on the Cumberland River front in the heart of downtown Nashville just off Broadway and 1st Avenue.  Forms part of the Kolleen Hudgins, Director of Special Events, Mayor&#8217;s Office Collection.  1 b &amp; w photograph.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Hudgins, Kolleen; Fulton, Richard</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Fourth of July--Tennessee--Nashville; Families--Tennessee, Middle; Urban parks--Tennessee--Nashville; Parks--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Broadway Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); First Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Cumberland River (Ky. and Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1983-07-04</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Kolleen Hudgins Collection Box 3 f 17 Riverfront Park Opening July 4 1983 015</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Kolleen Hudgins, Director of Special Events, Mayor&#8217;s Office Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1980-1989</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/6522</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>