<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Portrait of Dewey W. Grantham, 2006</dc:title>
<dc:description>Dewey Grantham, with dark hair and wearing a brown suit and black tie.  He is leaning and seems as if in conversation.  Born in 1921 in Georgia, Dewey W. Grantham was a Vanderbilt University professor and scholar of twentieth-century southern history and politics.  He attended the University of Georgia, served during World War II, and attended the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill before beginning his career at Vanderbilt in 1952.  Grantham retired in 1991 after a distinguished career, having authored numerous books and having received multiple awards and honors for his work.  In 2001, Grantham donated his personal library to the Nashville Public Library, where it is housed in the Special Collection Division.  Grantham died in 2004.  Oil on canvas.  The artist completed the portrait in 2006 from a photograph and it was donated to the library by the Grantham Family in 2007.  The portrait is currently on display in the Nashville Room on the Nashville Public Library's second floor, near the Grantham book collection.  

The library's portraits were photographed as part of the National Society of The Colonial Dames of America in Tennessee's Tennessee Portrait Project (http://www.tnportraits.org/index.htm).  </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Grantham, Dewey W.--Portraits</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Vanderbilt University--Faculty</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Popular Culture; Education; Portraits, American--20th century; Portraits--Tennessee--Nashville; Author--Tennessee--Nashville; College teachers--Tennessee--Nashville; Educators--Tennessee--Nashville; Historians--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>King, Sandra (Artist)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>National Society of The Colonial Dames of America in Tennessee</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>2006</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Portraits; Paintings</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>grantham-dewey-lg</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Portrait Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1856</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>