<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Ward Seminary College Preparatory Class, published in &#8220;The Iris&#8221; Yearbook of Ward&#8217;s Seminary for Young Ladies, Nashville, Tennessee, 1902 </dc:title>
<dc:description>The College Preparatory officers, membership, and motto, as published in the 1902 &#8220;Iris&#8221; yearbook of Ward&#8217;s Seminary for Young Ladies.  The motto is &#8220;Get wisdom, get understanding,&#8221; The Officers: Ethel Chappell, President; Nannie Overton, Vice-President; Lillian Smith, Secretary; and Alice Carroll, Treasurer.  The members: Virna Colby, Bonito Hinton, Helen Hinton, Anna Cooper, Anna Blanton, Reba Willis, Margaret Yarbrough, Kathleen Carr, Amelia Sawrie, Katie May Landrum, Theo. Scruggs, Nannie Overton, Alice Carroll, Lillian Smith, and Ethel Chappell.  This prestigious school for girls was founded in 1865 by Dr. William E. Ward, a Presbyterian Minister and his wife, Eliza Hudson Ward. The school was located at 15 South Spruce Street (Eighth Avenue) in Nashville, Tennessee, next to the Savage House, a townhouse in downtown Nashville. Pictured at the entranceway are some of the students, faculty, and Reverend Ward. The school was regarded as one of the leading schools for young women in the South. It offered training in fine arts and the "refinement of young ladies" in addition to its preparatory and collegiate curriculum. Reverend Ward directed the school until his death in 1887, after which it continued to operate for several years. On June 1, 1913, Ward's Seminary and Belmont College for Young Women merged and chartered Ward-Belmont, the first junior college in the South to receive full accreditation by the Southern Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools.  Forms part of the Christine Webb Collection. 1 yearbook. </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Webb, Christine; Colby, Virna; Hinton, Bonito; Hinton, Helen; Cooper, Anna; Blanton, Anna; Willis, Reba; Yarbrough, Margaret; Carr, Kathleen; 
Sawrie, Amelia; Landrum, Katie May; Scruggs, Theo.; Overton, Nannie; Carroll, Alice; Smith, Lillian; Chappell, Ethel
</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Ward Seminary for Young Ladies (Nashville, Tenn.) </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Women in education--Tennessee--Nashville; Schools--Tennessee--Nashville; Private schools--Tennessee--Nashville; Teachers--Tennessee--Nashville; Boarding schools--Tennessee--Nashville; Girls--History--Sources; Women--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1902</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>ChristineWebbColl Wards Seminary Iris Yearbook 1902 051 - 052</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Christine Webb Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1900-1909</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/9284</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>