<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Industrial Arts building, Peabody College, Nashville, circa 1916</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard of the Industrial Arts building at the George Peabody College for Teachers in Nashville, Tennessee.  In an effort to create a major Southern teachers' college, the grounds and buildings of the former Peabody Normal School were donated to the George Peabody College for Teachers in 1909.  After 1911, Peabody College was geographically re-located directly across the street from the campus of Vanderbilt University.  It later became affiliated with Vanderbilt University, and is now known as the Peabody College of Education and Human Development at Vanderbilt University.  Forms part of the Nashville Room Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>George Peabody College for Teachers; Vanderbilt University. Peabody College</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Education; Colleges and Universities; Buildings; Architecture; Schools; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Education--Tennessee--Nashville; Universities and colleges--Tennessee--Nashville; School facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Teachers colleges--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Details; Gables--Tennessee--Nashville; Industrial arts--Tennessee--Nashville; Columns--Tennessee--Nashville; Educational facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Universities &amp; colleges--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Intellectual life; Twenty-first Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Edgehill Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Zibart Bros. (Publisher)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1916</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Nash - 81 - Industrial Arts Building, Peabody College, Nashville</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1910-1919</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/818</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>