<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Glimpses of Nashville, Tennessee: Overton Hall </dc:title>
<dc:description>An exterior view of Overton Hall, a Tudor-styled residence built in 1900 by Jesse Maxwell Overton.  The land on which Overton Hall stands was granted by the United States government to Jesse Maxwell, for services in the Revolutionary War.  Jesse Maxwell Overton was a businessman and stockbreeder, and he built the home for his wife Saidee Williams, daughter of banker John P. Williams. Overton Hall was built on the original Travellers&#8217; Rest south of Nashville, and he ran a farm, famous for the breeding of Berkshire hogs and Jersey cattle. This manor house was located in a beautiful wooded area in the present-day Crieve Hall subdivision about nine miles south of downtown Nashville, two miles north of Brentwood and east of Franklin Pike.  The second owners Herbert and Ritchey Farrell renamed it Crieve Hall, after a family ancestral home in Northern Ireland. It stood until the early 1950s when it was razed for a housing development.  Forms part of Glimpses of Nashville. 1 booklet </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Overton family; Overton, Jesse Maxwell, 1863-1922--Homes and haunts; Farrell family</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture, Domestic--Tennessee--Nashville; Mansions--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Fillmore Street (Nashville, Tenn.); Franklin Pike (Nashville, Tenn.); Farrell Parkway (Nashville, Tenn.) </dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Manx, Chicago </dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1900s</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Glimpses of Nashville Book006 Overton Hall</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Glimpses of Nashville, Tennessee booklet   </dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1900-1909</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/7746</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>