<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Mayor Ben West and son Jay visit residents at the Knowles Home, 1961 December 23</dc:title>
<dc:description>A scene from a December 23rd, 1961 visit by Mayor Ben West and his son Jay West to the Knowles Home during the holiday season.  The Knowles (Joseph B.) Memorial Home for Aged People was then located at 1501 23rd Avenue N and Ridley Road NW corner Hamilton.  Mayor Ben West was in office as mayor of Nashville, Tennessee from 1951 to 1963.  Forms part of Record Group 3, Metro Davidson County Photographer. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>West, Ben, 1911-1974; West family</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>J.B. Knowles Home for the Aged (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Mayors--Tennessee--Nashville; Old age homes--Tennessee--Nashville; Group homes for older people--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1961-12-23</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 3 9074 Mayor West and Jay at Knowles Home Dec23 1961 002</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/5983</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>