<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Girls&#8217; Cotillion Club, from the Nashville Times, 1940</dc:title>
<dc:description>A captioned photo from the Nashville Times (1940), about new members in the Girls&#8217; Cotillion Club. The caption reads: &#8220;An attractive and popular group of girls elected to membership in the Girls&#8217; Cotillion Club, seen at the home of the new secretary, Miss Margaret White, are, left to right: Miss Clarene Smith, Miss Ellen Bowers, Miss Marion Latta, Miss Laura Whitson, Miss Martha Beasley, Miss Virginia Sturdivant, and Miss Genevieve Baird. Other new members not present &#8230; are Miss Keith Glasgow, Miss Virginia McEwen, and Miss Esther Allen, Miss Juanita Roberts, Miss Martha Greene and Miss Margaret Greene. The new members will be presented at the spring dance to be given by the Cotillion Club at the Belle Meade Country Club.&#8221; Forms part of the Nashville Times newspaper collection. 1 digital photo.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Belle Meade Country Club (Nashville, Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Cotillions--Tennessee--Nashville; Women--Tennessee, Middle--History--Sources; Women--Societies and clubs</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1940</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>GirlsCotillionClub--NT-1940</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Times Newspaper Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4206</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>