<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Tennessee National Guardsman hugs girl carrying flower,  1991 March 15</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of an unidentified Tennessee National Guardsman hugging a girl carrying a flower. The soldier is one of 63 members of the 130th Rear Area Operations Center, which returned to the Grubbs-Kyle Training Center at the Smyrna Armory on March 15, 1991. The unit was the first state Army Guard unit to be deployed to the Middle East on August 30, 1990, serving in Saudi Arabia during the Persian Gulf War.  Forms part of the Nashville Banner Archives. 1 photograph transparency : col ; 35mm.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Tennessee. National Guard; Tennessee. Military Dept.; United States. National Guard Bureau. Rear Area Operation Center, 130th; Tennessee. Army National Guard</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Military History; Persian Gulf War; Persian Gulf War, 1991; Soldiers--Tennessee--Smyrna; Families of military personnel; Homecoming; Celebrations; Military demobilizations--Tennessee--Smyrna; Military personnel--American--Tennessee--Smyrna; Homecomings; Families; Fathers; Men; Children; Girls; Hugging; Manners &amp; customs</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Smyrna (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Rutherford County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Tennessee--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Rode, Ed (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1991-03-15</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Transparencies; Film transparencies</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BT 1991-0631-25a</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1990-1999</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1648</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>