<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Excerpt from Ednaearle Burney Oral History Interview, 2011 February 24</dc:title>
<dc:description>Excerpt from an oral history interview with Ednaearle Burney, conducted on February 24, 2011 by Susannah Gibbons and Jared Brennan as part of the Flood 2010 Digital History Project. The topics discussed include some of Ednaearle&#8217;s losses from the flooding and the support she received in the aftermath. Though she lost her beloved piano, her brother, also a musician, gave her a keyboard shortly after the flood. 

The complete interview is in the Special Collections Division.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Burney, Ednaearle, 1936- --Interviews</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>St. Paul AME Church</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Community response;Natural disasters--Nashville (Tenn.);Storytelling--Nashville (Tenn.);Oral history--Sources;Oral history--Library resources;Musicians--Nashville (Tenn.)--Interviews;Flood damage;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--Floods;Nashville (Tenn.)--History--21st century;Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Burney, Ednaearle (Interviewee); Brennan, Jared (Interviewer); Gibbons, Susannah (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Warkentin, Bettina, 2012 (Transcriber)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>2011-02-24</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3 (2.76 MB; 01min., 30sec.)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>FDHBurneyEClip001</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from:  Ednaearle Burney Oral History Interview. Born-digital recording(s) converted to mp3 format for online access in 2012 from 16bit 44.1khz WAV file archival master recording.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Flood 2010 Digital History Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2010-2019</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/3717</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>