<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Nashville Iris Association, from the Nashville Times, 1940</dc:title>
<dc:description>A captioned photo, from the Nashville Times (1940), about the Nashville Iris Association&#8217;s president Jesse E. Wills, &#8220;whose garden at his home on Belle Meade Boulevard always attracts a large number of visitors during Iris Week. Pictured in the garden are his wife and children, left to right, William Ridley Wills, II, Ellen McClung Wills, Mrs. Wills, and Matthew Buckner Wills. The dog is Micky.&#8221;  The Nashville Iris Association, established in 1931, gained national and even international attention for its efforts in breeding and growing irises. The iris is the Tennessee State Cultivated Flower.  Forms part of the Nashville Times newspaper collection. 1 digital photo.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Wills family; Wills, Jesse; Wills, Ridley, 1934-</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Iris Association (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Civic leaders--Tennessee--Nashville; Flower gardening--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Belle Meade Boulevard (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1940</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RidleyWellsandFamily--NT-1940</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Times Newspaper Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4170</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>