<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Nashville&#8217;s Schools teach democratic principles and prepare to defend them, 1941 April 18</dc:title>
<dc:description>&#8220;Nashville&#8217;s public school officials have planned a program based on democracy and defense.  Not only are young people taught the fundamentals of their form of government, but they are taught the necessary principles of preserving it &#8230; with airplane motors as his eventual problem, Jack Hurst, 19, is working at present on automobile motors in his eleventh grade studies at Hume-Fogg, but hopes to become an airplane mechanic some day.  He is typical of the many young men over the city who are learning their trades through the public schools.&#8221; Source: Nashville Banner, April 18th, 1941.  Forms part of Record Group 412, Photographs Collection. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Hurst, Jack</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Banner; Hume-Fogg High School (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Schools--Tennessee--Nashville; Civil defense--Tennessee--Nashville; Public schools--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1941-04-15</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 412 768 Schools Nashville City DefenseApr15 1941 010</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 412</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/5636</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>