<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Judge Cornelius&#8217; Court, 1969 May 02</dc:title>
<dc:description>Judge Allen Robinson Cornelius&#8217; Court, May 2nd, 1969.  Nashville native, Allen Cornelius was born on December 27, 1920, and graduated from West End High School in 1938.  A 1947 graduate of Cumberland Law School, he began his career working as an insurance agency attorney.  In 1953 he was elected to the 78th General Assembly, and served a two-year term as a member of the Tennessee House of Representatives.  In 1958, Cornelius was elected Davidson County General Sessions Judge, and served in this capacity until 1968, when he became the first to preside over the Division III Criminal Court.  He was appointed to the Court of Criminal Appeals in 1978, where he served until his retirement in 1986.  Forms part of Record Group 3, Metro Davidson County Photographer.  3 photograph negatives : b &amp; w. 
</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Cornelius, Allen R., 1920-2007</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Judges--Tennessee--Nashville; Criminal courts--Tennessee--Nashville; Courts--Tennessee--Nashville; Lawyers--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1969-05-02</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 3 2638 Judge Cornelius Court 001-003</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3 Metro Davidson County Photographer</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4672</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>