<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Portrait of Adeline Sanders Mosely Battle, ca. 186-?</dc:title>
<dc:description>Mrs. Adeline Sanders Mosely Battle in middle age, with salt-and-pepper hair, light blue eyes, and wearing a dark dress.  At her neck she is wearing a miniature of her husband, Col. Joel A. Battle, who served as a colonel in the Twentieth Tennessee Volunteer Infantry during the Civil War, State Treasurer of the State of Tennessee from 1862 until the end of the war, and Superintendent of the State Prison in 1872.  Battle was the mother of Mary Francis "Fannie" Battle (1842-1924), a Nashville humanitarian and social worker who was known during her lifetime as "The Angel of the Poor" because of her great humanitarian spirit and compassionate service to benefit underprivileged children.  Oil on canvas, artist unknown, currently not on display.  Donated to the library by the Fannie Battle Day Home in 2007.  
The library's portraits were photographed as part of the National Society of The Colonial Dames of America in Tennessee's Tennessee Portrait Project (http://www.tnportraits.org/index.htm).</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Battle, Adeline Sanders Mosely--Portraits</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Popular Culture; Portraits, American--19th century; Portraits--Tennessee--Nashville; Mothers--Tennessee--Nashville; Wives--Tennessee--Nashville; Women--Tennessee--Nashville--Portraits</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>National Society of The Colonial Dames of America in Tennessee</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 186-?</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Portraits; Paintings</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>battle-mrs-joel-lg</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Fannie Battle Day Home Records</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1840</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>