<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Derby nominee leaves Nashville, Tennessee for Churchill Downs, 1936 April 08</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of a horse being loaded into a van for a trip to the Kentucky Derby. This caption accompanied the photo in the Nashville Banner Newspaper on April 8, 1936: "Marcellus Frost's Pop Hour is shown just before being shipped to Louisville to prepare for the sixty-third running of the Kentucky Derby at Churchill Downs. The three-year-old has been in winter training at Cumberland Park. Pop's Hour is by Hourless out of No Quarter." Forms part of the Nashville Banner Archives. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 3.25 x 4.25 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Frost, Marcellus B., 1888-1974</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Churchill Downs (Louisville, Ky. : Racetrack)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Sports &amp; Recreation; Popular Culture; Entertainment; Horse racing -- Kentucky; Horses; Race horses--Tennessee, Middle</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Banner Staff Photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1936-04-08</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BN 1936-15</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/2323</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>