<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Immaculate Mother Academy, Nashville, Tennessee, n.d. </dc:title>
<dc:description>An exterior view of the Immaculate Mother Academy, located at 7th Avenue South between the intersections of Drexel Street and Middleton Street, in Nashville, TN.  The text from the historical marker reads:  &#8220;In 1904, a Philadelphia nun and heiress, Mother Mary Katherine Drexel, purchased this site for Immaculate Mother Academy, which included a primary school and the first Catholic secondary school for black students in Tennessee. Holy Family Catholic Church was moved here in 1919, and the primary school was renamed for it. Immaculate Mother became a fully accredited high school in 1940. Until their closing in 1954, the schools were staffed by the Sisters of the Blessed Sacrament of Bensalem, PA.&#8221; In 1954, Nashville Catholic schools became some of the nation&#8217;s first to adhere to Brown v. Board of Education and the students of Immaculate Mother Academy transferred to Father Ryan and Cathedral School when the school closed.  Immaculate Mother&#8217;s alumni included Robert E. Lillard, one of Nashville&#8217;s first African-American city councilmen, lawyer and judge. Forms part of the Metro Archives Photographs - School Collection. 1 photograph.   </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Catholic Church--Education--Tennessee--Nashville; Immaculate Mother Academy (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Education--Tennessee--Nashville; Schools--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>n.d.</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Metro Archives Photos - Immaculate Mother Academy 001</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Metro Archives Photographs, Schools Collection </dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880. </dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/10389</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>