<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Portrait of Margaret Ann Craig Robinson, December 2003</dc:title>
<dc:description>Portrait of Margaret Ann Robinson seated in her garden. Informal. Blue attire w/red &amp; white scarf. Setting: garden chair, trees, shrubbery, flowers, stone wall.  Margaret Ann Robinson joined the Metropolitan Library Board in 1977 and has served as its Chair since 1986. The library courtyard, named in their honor, was a gift of Mrs. Robinson and her late husband, Walter M. Robinson, Jr.  Oil on canvas.  Painted by Ann Street in 2003; dedicated and hung in the Nashville Public Library in 2004. Commissioned and donated by David K. Wilson through the Nashville Public Library Foundation.  The portrait is currently on display on the Nashville Public Library's second floor.  

The library's portraits were photographed as part of the National Society of The Colonial Dames of America in Tennessee's Tennessee Portrait Project (http://www.tnportraits.org/index.htm).  </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Robinson, Margaret Ann--Portraits</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Popular Culture; Capital City; Portraits, American--20th century; Portraits--Tennessee--Nashville; Library trustees--Tennessee--Nashville; Public library trustees--Tennessee--Nashville; Women library trustees--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Street, Ann  (Artist)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>National Society of The Colonial Dames of America in Tennessee</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>2003-12</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs; Portraits;</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>robinson-margaret-ac-lg</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Public Library Art Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1863</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>