<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Percy Warner Park, Nashville, Tennessee, circa 1990s   </dc:title>
<dc:description>Views of Percy Warner Park, located at 7311 Highway 100, Nashville, Tennessee.  The historic marker reads: &#8220;Percy Warner Park, 2058.1 acres.  Percy Warner (1861-1927) was a pioneer in electric utilities and hydroelectric development in the South.  As chairman of the Park Board, he expanded Nashville&#8217;s park system.  Preservation of this natural area was one of his greatest civic projects.  Named in his honor by the Park Board in 1927, this land constitutes the largest municipal park in Tennessee.&#8221; Another historic marker reads: &#8220;Luke Lea Heights, 5 miles ahead on Scenic Drive.  Luke Lea (1879-1945) envisioned this park, gave to the city in 1927 the original 868 acres, and asked that the land be named for his father-in-law, Percy Warner.  Founder of &#8216;The Nashville Tennessean,&#8217; Lea was a key developer of Belle Meade, a U.S. senator, organizer and colonel of the 114th Field Artillery, WWI.  To honor him the Park Board named a high hill and overlook Lea Heights.&#8221; During the late 1930s, the 9-hole Percy Warner Golf Course opened; additional property was acquired that allowed Edwin to join his brother as park namesake. The board voted to name all land south of Old Hickory Boulevard as &#8216;Edwin Warner Park.&#8217;  The Warner Parks are managed by the Metropolitan Board of Parks and Recreation of Nashville and Davidson County.  Forms part of the Paul Bates Collection - Travel Guide West End.  Photographs, color.   </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Parks--Tennessee--Nashville; Urban parks--Tennessee--Nashville; Sports--Tennessee--Nashville </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Percy Warner Park (Nashville, Tenn.)

</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1990s</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Paul Bates Col TravGuide West End nr 91 Percy Warner Park 001 - 012</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Paul Bates Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1990-1999</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/7745</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>