<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Professor William L. Dudley, between 1889 and 1908</dc:title>
<dc:description>A cabinet card portrait photograph of Dr. W. L. Dudley, a distinguished scientist, lecturer, and head of the Department of Chemistry, Vanderbilt University, Nashville, Tennessee. Dudley was born in 1859 in Covington, Kentucky. He earned his undergraduate degree in 1880 from the University of Cincinnati. Dudley served as a Commissioner of the Cincinnati Industrial Exposition from 1881 to 1885. He earned an honorary degree of Doctor of Medicine at Miami Medical College in 1885, where he held a position as demonstrator of chemistry. He continued his distinguished career at Vanderbilt University from 1886 until his retirement in 1912. In addition to his scientific research and contributions, the professor was also very dedicated to the advancement of college athletics and served as president of the Southern Intercollegiate Athletic Association from its inception in 1894 until his death in 1914. Dudley Field, in the sports history of Vanderbilt University, was named in his honor. In addition to his work in the SIAA, Dudley helped establish the Vanderbilt Athletic Association and was the organizer and president of the University Club. The verso of this cabinet card features the W. G. and A. J. Thuss Photographic Art Studio logo, with an address at 228 &amp; 230 N. Cherry St., McGavock Block, Nashville, Tenn. Forms part of the Nashville Room Historic Photographs Collection. 1 cabinet card photograph : sepia ; 4.25 x 6.25 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Dudley, W. L. (William Lofland), 1859-1914</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Vanderbilt University--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Education; Colleges and Universities; Sports &amp; Recreation; Scientists--Tennessee--Nashville; College teachers--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>W. G. and A. J. Thuss Photographic Art Studio (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>between 1889 and 1908</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>P-4458</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Historic Photographs Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1880-1889; 1890-1889; 1900-1909</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/2364</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>