<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of the Warner Children, circa 1895</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of Sadie, Mary Louise and Margaret, the daughters of Percy and Margaret Lindsley Warner, blowing soap bubbles with their friends.  The photograph was probably taken at the Warner home at 125 North Spruce Street, now the southwest corner of Eighth Avenue and Commerce Street.  Individuals represented in the image include: Margaret Warner, Thomas Kaeling, Lula Mai Raulsin, Sadie Warner, Lillian Davidson, Porter Raulsin, Jennie Louise Davidson, Martha Thomas, Elizabeth Davidson, Mrs. McConnell, Charles Davidson, and Mary Louise Warner.  Forms part of the Nashville Room Historic Photographs Collection. 1 photograph : b &amp; w ; 8 x 10 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Frazer, Sadie Warner, 1885-1974; Warner, Mary Louise; Warner, Margaret; Kaeling, Thomas; Raulsin, Lula Mai; Davidson, Lillian; Raulsin, Porter; Davidson, Jennie Louise; Thomas, Martha; Davidson, Elizabeth; Davidson, Charles; Warner family</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Sports &amp; Recreation; Children's History; Entertainment; Popular Culture; Play--Tennessee--Nashville; Bubbles; Playmates--Tennessee--Nashville; Children--Tennessee--Nashville; Play (Recreation)--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Spruce Street (Nashville, Tenn.); Eighth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Commerce Street (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville, Tenn.--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Warden, Margaret Lindsley (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1895</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>P-2625</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Historic Photographs Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1890-1899</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/318</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>