<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Oral history interview with King M. Hollands, 2006 June 28</dc:title>
<dc:description>Excerpts from an interview with civil rights movement participant King M. Hollands, conducted on 28 June 2006 by Larry Patterson as part of the Nashville Public Library's Civil Rights Oral History Project.  Hollands was one of the first students to desegregate Father Ryan High School in Nashville, Tennessee, the first school in Nashville to integrate in 1954.  Hollands was also a student activist during the Nashville sit-in movement of the 1960s.  In the excerpts, Hollands discusses the social environment and school integration at Father Ryan High School; the atmosphere of camaraderie in jail upon arrest during the Nashville sit-in movement; the parents' support of the jailed activists; and his personal values of being a civil rights movement participant.  The complete interview is available in the Special Collections Division.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Hollands, King M., 1941- --Interviews</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Father Ryan High School (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African Americans; Civil Rights; Race Relations; Education; High Schools; Private Schools; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; High schools--Tennessee--Nashville; Catholic high schools--Tennessee--Nashville; Segregation in education--Tennessee--Nashville; School integration--Tennessee--Nashville; African Americans--Civil rights--Tennessee--Nashville; African Americans--Social conditions--Tennessee--Nashville; Social change--Tennessee--Nashville; School integration--Tennessee--Nashville; Civil rights movements--Tennessee--Nashville; Civil rights workers--Tennessee--Nashville; High school students--Tennessee--Nashville; Civil rights demonstrations--Tennessee--Nashville; Education--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Race relations; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social conditions; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Hollands, King M., 1941- (Interviewee); Patterson, Larry, 1944- (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2006-06-28</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3</dc:format>
<dc:source>Excerpted from: CROHPHollandsK digital recording converted from wav to mp3 format.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Civil Rights Oral History Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1683</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>