<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Aerial of Knapp Farm near Nashville Airport, 1961 January 03</dc:title>
<dc:description>An aerial photograph of the Knapp Farm acreage near the present-day Nashville International Airport, January 3, 1961.  Knapp Farm, approximately 300 acres, was once a flourishing demonstration farm, owned and operated by the Knapp School of Country Life of the George Peabody College for Teachers.  The farm, a memorial to Seaman Knapp, an agronomist and leader in farm demonstration work, featured a 25-acre orchard and fields used to experiment with crops suited to the local climate.  Knapp Farm was famous for its dairy and herd of purebred Holsteins. The Peabody Board of Trustees sold the farm and its club house in 1965.  Forms part of Record Group 412, Photographs Collection. 1 photographic negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Seaman A. Knapp School of Country Life--History--Sources; George Peabody College for Teachers--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Landscapes--Tennessee--Nashville; Milk trade--Tennessee--Nashville; Dairy products industry--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1961-01-03</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 412 906 Aerials Knapp Farm 1-3-1961 from negative  011</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 412</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/6160</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>