<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Du Pont, Old Hickory rayon plant is "World's Safest Plant," 1953 June 27</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph made at Du Pont's rayon plant in Old Hickory, Tennessee.  Employees pose with a sign giving the latest statistics for their safety records.  They anticipated being given the title of "The World's Safest Plant" at midnight that day.  Pictured from left to right are Sgt. J. F. Moore; R. L. Magee, service superintendent; and F. M. Acker, plant manager.  Forms part of the Nashville Banner Archives. 1 photograph : b &amp; w ; 8 x 10 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Moore, J.F.; Magee, R.L.; Acker, F.M.</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Old Hickory Plant (E.I. du Pont de Nemours &amp; Company)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Business; Enterprise; Industries; Chemical industry--Tennessee--Old Hickory; Business enterprises--Tennessee--Old Hickory; Rayon industry and trade--Tennessee--Old Hickory; Factories--Tennessee--Old Hickory; Corporations--Tennessee--Old Hickory; Industrial safety--Tennessee--Nashville; Safety; Industrial facilities--Tennessee--Old Hickory; Textile industry--Tennessee--Old Hickory; Industry--Tennessee--Old Hickory</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Old Hickory (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Old History (Tenn.)--Commerce</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Howe, Jack (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1953-06-27</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BP Du Pont - Old Hickory Plant 6-27-1953</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/874</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>