<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Nashville City Reservoir on Eighth Avenue, Nashville, Tennessee, n.d. </dc:title>
<dc:description>An aerial view of the Nashville City Reservoir, located at 1401 8th Avenue in Nashville, Tennessee.  The reservoir was built between 1887 and 1889.  The structure was constructed on top of Kirkpatrick Hill, the site of Federal Blockhouse Casino during the Civil War, built by the Federal occupation forces as part of the fortifications surrounding the city to the south and the west.  The structure of the reservoir is elliptical in shape, and major axis is approx. 603 feet.  The distance around the reservoir at the top of the wall is about one-third of a mile. The capacity of the big water basin is approx. 51,000,000 gallons.  The reservoir was built when Charles P. McCarver was Mayor, and the Board of Public Works was composed of Messrs. Ewing, Nestor and Kercheval.  J. A. Jowett was the City Engineer.  Forms part of Record Group 3, Metro Davidson County Photographer. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 2.5 x 2.5 in. </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Reservoirs--Tennessee--Nashville; Water supply--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Neighborhood--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Eighth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Kirkpatrick Hill (Nashville, Tenn.); Fort Casino (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>n.d.</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG3 1384 8th Ave Resevoir ND   002</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3 Metro Davidson County Photographer   </dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/6971</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>