<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of columns and capitals from the Tennessee State Capitol Building, Nashville, Tennessee, circa 1996</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of a collection of a portion of the original columns and capitals from the Tennessee State Capitol Building in Nashville, Tennessee. The building was designed by architect William Strickland (1788-1854) and built between 1845 and 1859, using mostly local construction materials. The Tennessee limestone eroded over time and most of it had to be replaced during a building restoration project in 1956-1960. In the 1990s, architect Charles W. Warterfield, who had worked both on that project and a later restoration in 1984-1988, located the old columns and capitals in a field near the state penitentiary. He placed them at the southeast base of Capitol Hill in the arrangement seen in the photograph. An additional arrangement was later placed on the Bicentennial Mall, just north of Capitol Hill.  Photographed by the Nashville architect Charles Wesley Warterfield, Jr. (1926-1998); the architectural photograph forms part of the Charles Warterfield Architectural Collection. Gift of: The Estate of Charles W. Warterfield, Jr., F. A. I. A. The original is a 35 mm color transparency (2 x 2 in. slide mount)</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Tennessee State Capitol (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Public buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville;  Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architects--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Details; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville; Government facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Columns--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Tennessee--Capital and capitol; Capitol Hill (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Warterfield, Charles W. (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Estate of Charles W. Warterfield, Jr., F.A.I.A. (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1996</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Slides; Photographs; Architectural photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/tiff</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>WSC 0919</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Charles Warterfield Architectural Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1990-1999</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/486</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>