<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Gospel Tabernacle, 2001 December</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of Gospel Tabernacle Church of God in Christ located at 1101 Jackson Street in Nashville, Tennessee.  According to the cornerstone the church was built in 1916 as Jackson Street Baptist Church, and remodeled in 1941 by Reverend William Kilcrease.  In 1978 the church's name changed to Jackson Street Church of God.  In 1982 the name changed again to Bethel A.O.H. Church of God.  In 1990 it switched to New Revelation Church of God in Christ, and in 1994 it underwent a final name alteration, becoming the Gospel Tabernacle Church of God in Christ.  The foundation is made of rough cut stone blocks that have been painted white.  The exterior walls are red brick.  The roof is gabled and made of tar shingles.  The windows are tall and rectangular with colored and frosted glass panes.  The lower windows have been boarded up. All of the windows have metal bars over the outside.  The front doors are glass.  The back doors are steel.  Forms part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project. 1 photograph : col. ; 4  x 6  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Jackson Street Baptist Church (Nashville, Tenn.); Jackson Street Church of God (Nashville, Tenn.); Bethel Apostolic Overcoming Holy Church of God (Nashville, Tenn.); New Revelation Church of God in Christ (Nashville, Tenn.); Gospel Tabernacle Church of God in Christ (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Popular Culture; Religion; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Religious facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Church architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Baptist church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Brick churches--Tennessee--Nashville; African American churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Baptist churches--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs; Jackson Street (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2001-12</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>SSSP - Gospel Tabernacle</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1042</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>