<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Collection boxes to be wrapped, circa 1951 December 07</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph, circa 7 December 1951, of Mrs. Jack Eakin, assistant to the general chairman, and Mrs. Fitzsimmons Murphree, box chairman, of the Fannie Battle Carol Committee, seen chatting with L.A. Warner, Jr., as they canvass the cigar counters for boxes that they would wrap in the "traditional red and green paper, to collect the contributions made by a populace imbued with the spirit of Christmas" at the annual Christmas Eve carol singing in Nashville and Davidson County to benefit the Fannie Battle Day Home.  This photograph illustrated the newspaper article "B. Banner Gets Christmas Spirit with Carol Committee," published in the 7 December 1951 issue of the Nashville Banner.  Forms part of the Fannie Battle Day Home Records.  1 photograph :  b &amp; w ; 10 x 8.25 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Eakin, Jack, Mrs.; Murphree, Fitzsimmons, Mrs.; Warner, Lemuel A., d. 1986</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Fannie Battle Day Home; Fannie Battle Social Workers</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Capital City; Organizations; Popular Culture; Children's History; Performing Arts; Music; Business; Women social reformers--Tennessee--Nashville; Charity--Tennessee--Nashville; Charities--Tennessee--Nashville; Day care centers--Tennessee--Nashville; Child care workers--Tennessee--Nashville; Social workers--Tennessee--Nashville; Child care--Tennessee--Nashville; Women in charitable work--Tennessee--Nashville; Altruism--Tennessee--Nashville; Benevolence--Tennessee--Nashville; Social work with children--Tennessee--Nashville; Children--Social conditions; Children--Charities; Child welfare; Christmas carols; Caroling--Tennessee--Nashville; Holidays--Tennessee--Nashville; Newspapers--Tennessee--Nashville; Newspaper publishing--Tennessee--Nashville; Nonprofit organizations--Tennessee--Nashville; Women in nonprofit organizations--Tennessee--Nashville; Charitable organizations--Tennessee--Nashville; Community service--Tennessee--Nashville; Economic &amp; social conditions--Tennessee--Nashville; Organizations--Tennessee--Nashville; Public relations</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social conditions; Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Davidson County (Tenn.)--Social conditions</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Malone, John (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1951-12-07</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>FBDHR-SB-Carol Publicity-1951-B11, f37-p2</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Fannie Battle Day Home Records</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1847</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>