<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of a stone carving of the face of a woman, 5th Avenue North, Nashville, Tennessee, between 1980 and 1989</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of a stone carving of the face of a woman over the archway of one entrance to the 5th Avenue side of Saint Cloud Corner, 500 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee. Part of the building occupies the former site of the Saint Cloud Hotel, a prominent hostelry in 19th century Nashville, located at the corner lot of Summer (now 5th Avenue) and Church Street. The adjoining six-story structure, accessed through the arched entrance with the carving seen here, was built in 1890 on the 5th Avenue side (211 5th Avenue North) to serve as a store for Connell-Hall-McLester Company. The building later housed several department stores, including Castner-Knott, Cain-Sloan, and Harvey's. It was refurbished in 1979-1980 to be used as office, retail and restaurant space. Some restoration work may have been done on the carving at that time. Details in the image, including the reflection in the window, very closely resemble those of photographs taken in 2006, suggesting that the image was created after the 1980 restoration. Photographed by the Nashville architect Charles Wesley Warterfield, Jr. (1926-1998); the architectural photograph forms part of the Charles Warterfield Architectural Collection. Gift of: The Estate of Charles W. Warterfield, Jr., F. A. I. A. The original is a 35 mm color transparency (2 x 2 in. slide mount)</dc:description>
<dc:subject>St. Cloud Hotel (Nashville, Tenn.)--History</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Business; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architects--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Commercial buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Urban renewal--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Commercial facilities; Business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Streets--Tennessee--Nashville; Arches--Tennessee--Nashville; Bas-reliefs--Tennessee--Nashville; Sculpture--Tennessee--Nashville; Stone carving--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; St. Cloud Corner (Nashville, Tenn.); Fifth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Church Street (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Warterfield, Charles W. (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Estate of Charles W. Warterfield, Jr., F. A. I. A. (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>between 1980 and 1989</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still image; Slides; Architectural photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>WSC 3976</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Charles Warterfield Architectural Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1980-1989</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/49</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>