<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>U.S. Weather Bureau Airport Station, Nashville, Tennessee, 1961 October 01</dc:title>
<dc:description>Pictured: Staff operating the weather instruments at the U. S. Weather Bureau Airport Station, Nashville, Tennessee, October 1st, 1961.  The Signal Service office for Nashville opened circa 1870, remaining downtown when the Weather Bureau took over.  A separate facility at Berry Airport (currently Nashville International Airport) was opened in June 1937, and the two facilities were consolidated there in on 12/18/1950.  A WSR-3 radar was installed in 1957.  Forms part of Record Group 3, Metro Davidson County Photographer. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Metropolitan Nashville Airport Authority--History--Sources; United States. Weather Bureau--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Airports--Tennessee--Nashville--History; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Meteorological stations--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1961-10-01</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 3 120 Airport001</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/6109</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>