<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>J.C. Napier with the Nashville Housing Authority, c.1930s</dc:title>
<dc:description>Photograph of James Carroll Napier visiting a housing project with the Nashville Housing Authority, c.1930s. Napier was a prominent African American businessman, politician, lawyer, and civil rights leader from Nashville, Tennessee. He was the first African American president of the city council, and was instrumental in founding numerous civic institutions in the city that went on to benefit the African American buisness community, with special emphasis on education. Photographed by Wiles Photographers. Forms part of the MDHA Photograph Collection. 1 photograph : b &amp; w. </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Napier, J.C. 1845-1940</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Housing Authority (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Housing developments; Housing--Tennessee--Nashville; Urban renewal--Tennessee--Nashville; Urban renewal--Tennessee--Nashville--History; African American businesspeople--Tennessee--Nashville; African American civil rights workers--Tennessee--Nashville; African American lawyers--Tennessee--Nashville; African American men--Tennessee--Nashville; African American political activists--Tennessee--Nashville--History--Sources; African American politicians--Tennessee--Nashville--History--20th century;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Nashville Housing Authority/Metropolitan Development and Housing Agency</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>c.1930s</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photograph</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>MDHA Photos Box 5 Fol 67 JC Napier With NHA c1930s 001</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>MDHA Photograph Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>	
U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/12898</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>