<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Mack scores again, from the Nashville Times, 1940</dc:title>
<dc:description>A captioned photo from the Nashville Times (1940), about Colonial Foods. The caption reads: &#8220;This Mack truck, together with three Mack tractors equipped with trailers, recently delivered to the C. B. Ragland Company, wholesale grocers. Dependable delivery and economical operation, which the Mack always gives, prompted the purchase. Mack Sales &amp; Services, 516 McGavock Street, Howard Youree, Distributor.&#8221; The 1941 City Directory cites C. B. Ragland Company: C. S. Ragland, President; F. W. Wharton, Vice-Pres., wholesale grocers and coffee roasters, Colonial Foods and Coffee, 300-314 2nd Avenue S. Forms part of the Nashville Times newspaper collection. 1 digital photo.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Ragland family</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>C. B. Ragland (Nashville, Tenn.); Colonial Foods (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Mack trucks--Tennessee--Nashville; Businessmen--Tennessee--Nashville; Food brokers--Tennessee--Nashville; Food industry and trade--Tennessee--Nashville; Grocery trade--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Commerce</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1940</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>ColonialFoodsTruck--NT-1940</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Times Newspaper Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4192</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>