<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Oral history interview with Betty Nixon, 2004 June 16</dc:title>
<dc:description>Excerpts from an interview with Betty Nixon on 16 June 2004 by Kathryn G. Bennett as part of the Nashville Public Library's Civil Rights Oral History Project.  Nixon discusses childhood experiences that led to her awareness of segregation and racist sentiments in Nashville, Tennessee.  The complete interview as well as an index is available in the Special Collections Division.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Nixon, Betty Chiles, 1936- --Interviews</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>West End United Methodist Church (Nashville, Tenn.); Walter O. Parmer School (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Civil Rights; African Americans; Race Relations; Education; Elementary Schools; Popular Culture; Children's History; Architecture; Churches; African Americans--Segregation--Tennessee--History--20th century; Racism--Tennessee--Nashville; Civil rights--Tennessee--Nashville; African Americans--Social conditions; Anti-racism--Tennessee--Nashville; Methodists--Tennessee--Nashville; Elementary schools--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--Race relations; Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social conditions</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Nixon, Betty Chiles, 1936- (Interviewee); Bennett, Kathryn G. (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>James, Carolyn (Transcriber); Lawson, Rachel (Videographer); Public Library of Nashville and Davidson County</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>2004-06-16</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CROHPNixon1aclip1.mp3; CROHPNixon1_transcript.pdf</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from: CROHPNixon1a audio cassette recording(s) converted to mp3 format in 2006.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Civil Rights Oral History Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1484</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>