<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Oral history interview with Mildred Owsley Buchanan, 1980 November, excerpt 02</dc:title>
<dc:description>An excerpt from an oral history interview with Nashville educator Mildred Owsley Buchanan., conducted on two dates in November 1980 by Paul Clements as part of the Century III Nashville: Nashville Heritage Project.  Buchanan, a home economics teacher in Nashville city schools from the late 1920s through ca. 1963, discusses education during the early 1900s.  She describes the interior of Corley School on Lebanon Road, which she attended for grades 1 through 7 from 1909 to 1914.  The complete interview is available in the repository.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Buchanan, Mildred Owsley, 1902-2000--Interviews</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Corley Elementary School (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Education; Elementary Schools; Architecture; Schools; Teachers--Tennessee--Nashville; Country life--Tennessee; Schools--Tennessee--Nashville; School buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Education--Tennessee--Nashville; Education, Elementary--Tennessee--Nashville; Elementary schools--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Intellectual life; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social conditions; Tennessee--Rural conditions; Lebanon Road (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Buchanan, Mildred Owsley, 1902-2000  (Interviewee); Clements, Paul, 1947-  (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1980-11</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3 (2 min., 33 sec.)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CentIIIBuchanan1bclip1</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from:  CentIIIBuchanan audio cassette recording converted to mp3 format in 2006.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Century III Nashville: Nashville Heritage Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1980-1989</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/580</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>