<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Old Stone Bridge marker in Goodlettsville, Tennessee, n.d.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Pictured: An historic plaque related to the Old Stone Bridge over Mansker's Creek in Goodlettsville, Tennessee. This historic bridge is one of Tennessee's oldest bridges made of stone with masonry arch construction. This dual arch bridge was built circa 1837-1849 as part of the stagecoach road that connected Nashville to Louisville. The Old Stone Bridge is located about 12 miles north of Nashville. The text on the Tennessee Historical Commission plaque reads: &#8220;Immediately to the east is one of the stone bridges over which passed the old stage road from Nashville to Louisville.  The stage line operated until the railfroad was completed in 1859.&#8221;  Forms part of the Bill Goodman Photographic Slides Collection.  1 35 mm negative.  </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Historic markers--Tennessee, Middle; Bridges--Tennessee--Goodlettsville; Stone bridges--Tennessee--Goodlettsville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Goodlettsville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Goodlettsville (Tenn.)--History--Sources

</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Goodman, Bill (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>n.d.</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Goodman Slide Old Stone Bridge Marker</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Bill Goodman 35 mm Slides Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/10415</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>