<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Nashville, Tenn. Court Square - Market Day, between 1901 and 1907</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard of Court Square on Market Day.  Court Square, also referred to as Court House Square or Public Square, was located right in the center of the city.  The square, with the county courthouse, city hall and market center, was a focus of wholesale commerce and political activity for the city for many years. On market days the square was especially busy.  The old city hall, dating from the 1850s, was replaced by a new city hall and courthouse in 1937. Most of the remaining buildings were destroyed in the 1970s as part of urban renewal projects.  RaphoType Postcard no. 5184, "Nashville, Tenn."  Forms part of the Nashville Room Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Business; Popular Culture; Shopping; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Commercial buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Public spaces--Tennessee--Nashville; Public buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Courthouses--Tennessee--Nashville; City halls--Tennessee--Nashville; Carriages and carts--Tennessee--Nashville; Shopping--Tennessee--Nashville; Government facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; City &amp; town halls--Tennessee--Nashville; Plazas--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Public Square (Nashville, Tenn.)--History--Sources; Court House Square (Nashville, Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Commerce</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Raphael Tuck &amp; Sons (Publisher)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>Between 1901 and 1907</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Nash-30-Nashville, Tenn. Court Square - Market Day</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1900-1909</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/668</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>