<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Italian Street Fair event sponsored by the Nashville Symphony Guild benefiting the Nashville Symphony Orchestra, 1956 October 06</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of four women in costume selling tickets to the Italian Street Fair. An article about the event appeared in the Nashville Banner newspaper on October 8, 1956, citing: "Pizza, pepperoni and puppets abounded Saturday afternoon and evening as the gates of the second annual Italian Street Fair swung open at the corner of Natchez Trace and West End Ave, (Nashville, TN). All the color and charm of the boot country were transported to the Nashville scene as gaily costumed workers for the Nashville Symphony Association hawked everything from succulent spaghetti to baby bootees midst a scene made gay by folk dances, strolling street singers, and contests galore designed to catch the eye of toddlers, teenster et al. The Fair, which launched Symphony Week&#8230;..was sponsored by the Nashville Symphony Guild for the benefit of the Nashville Symphony Orchestra." Forms part of the Nashville Banner Archives. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 3.25 x 4.25 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Nashville Symphony Orchestra</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Performing Arts; Sports &amp; Recreation; Popular Culture; Entertainment; Entertainment events--Tennessee--Nashville; Performing arts--Tennessee--Nashville; Fairs--Tennessee--Nashville; Moneymaking projects--Tennessee--Nashville; Fund raising--Tennessee--Nashville; Manners &amp; customs--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; West End Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Natchez Trace (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Schleicher, Paul (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1956-10-06</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BN 1956-2722-01</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/2318</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>