<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Progressive Sunrise Baptist Church, 2001 November</dc:title>
<dc:description>According to the survey, this is a photograph of Progressive Sunrise Baptist Church located at 530 Meridian Street in Nashville, Tennessee.  The original church structure was built around 1938 on the corner of Berry and Meridian Streets, facing Berry Street.  It was listed under 230 Berry Street as Berry Street Church of God in the city directories until an addition to the building changed its frontward orientation to Meridian Street.  In the 1940s the church name changed to Meridian Street Church of God, but the address stayed the same.  In 1960 the address changed to 224 Meridian Street due to a building addition and a modified orientation. In 1985 the building became home to Big Harpeth United Primitive Baptist Church after being vacant for approximately eight years.  Today Big Harpeth United Primitive Baptist Church still occupies the building located at (now) 522 Meridian Street as indicated by the city directories.  There is no record of Progressive Sunrise Baptist Church at this address nor is there a listing for 530 Meridian Street as indicated on the survey.  The foundation is brick.  The exterior walls are brick with stone at some corners.  The roof is gabled and composed of tar shingles.  The windows are square with colored glass panes.  The doors are metal and glass.  This church is no longer listed in the Nashville City Directory.  Forms part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project. 1 photograph : col. ; 4  x 6  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Progressive Sunrise Baptist Church (Nashville, Tenn.); Meridian Street Church of God (Nashville, Tenn.); Berry Street Church of God (Nashville, Tenn.); Big Harpeth United Primitive Baptist Church (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Popular Culture; Religion; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Religious facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Church architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Baptist church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Details; Gables--Tennessee--Nashville; Awnings--Tennessee--Nashville; Brick churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Baptist churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs; Meridian Street (Nashville, Tenn.); Berry Street (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2001-11</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>SSSP - Progressive Sunrise Bap Ch</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1326</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>