<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Nashville Tennessee, a city of fine churches, between 1930 and 1945</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard of five churches of different denominations located in downtown Nashville.  In the upper left is McKendree Methodist Church.  In the lower left is the Cathedral of the Incarnation.  In the center is First Baptist Church.  In the upper right is Christ Church Episcopal.  Lastly, in the lower right corner, is Westminster Presbyterian Church.  Forms part of the Norton Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>McKendree Methodist Church (Nashville, Tenn.); Cathedral of the Incarnation (Nashville, Tenn.); First Baptist Church (Nashville, Tenn.); Christ Church Episcopal (Nashville, Tenn.); Westminster Presbyterian Church (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Popular Culture; Religion; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Religious facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Church architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Baptist church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Methodist church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Catholic church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Episcopal church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Details; Towers--Tennessee--Nashville; Arches--Tennessee--Nashville; Pediments--Tennessee--Nashville; Porticoes--Tennessee--Nashville; Protestant church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Steeples; Baptist churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Protestant churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Methodist churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Episcopal churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Catholic churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Presbyterian churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Capitol News Co. (Publisher)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>between 1930 and 1945</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Norton - 0234</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Norton Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939; 1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1953</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>