<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Fisk Jubilee Singers' Male Quartet performs at Peabody College, 1948 July 26</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of  the Male Quartet of the Fisk Jubilee Singers performing at Peabody College, July 26, 1948.  Directed by 20-year veteran Mrs. James A. Myers, the group had recently completed their first tour of Latin America and the Caribbean, appearing in Mexico City, Cuba, Venezuela and Haiti.  Pictured from left to right are Starling Hatchett, tenor; Norton Evans, tenor; Brooks Alexander, baritone; and Samuel Floyd, bass.  Forms part of the Nashville Banner Archives. 1 photograph : b &amp; w ; 8 x 10 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Hatchett, Starling; Evans, Norton; Alexander, Brooks; Floyd, Samuel</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Fisk University; Jubilee Singers</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Performing Arts; Music; African Americans; Education; Colleges and Universities; Popular Culture; Entertainment; Performances--Tennessee--Nashville; Performing arts--Tennessee--Nashville; Concerts--Tennessee--Nashville; Musicians; Music--Tennessee--Nashville; African American entertainers--Tennessee--Nashville; Entertainment events--Tennessee--Nashville; Singers--Tennessee--Nashville; Singing--Tennessee--Nashville; African American singers; African Americans--Music; African American gospel singers--Tennessee--Nashville; African American male singers--Tennessee--Nashville; Entertainment--Tennessee--Nashville; Gospel singers</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1948-07-26</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BP Nash - Fisk - Jubilee Singers</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/875</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>