<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of Nashville ice storm, 1951 February 2</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of a residential street in the Hillsboro/Belmont area during the record breaking snow and ice storm of 1951. Bone chilling weather brought sub-zero temperatures to most of Tennessee during a winter storm spanning January 31st through February 2nd of 1951.  This three-day storm blanketed the western two-thirds of the state with eight inches of snow and ice.  Nashville's temperature reached a low of 13 degrees below zero on February 2nd according to the official U.S. Weather Bureau thermometer.  An estimated 20,000 homes were left without power, while approximately 1,500 telephones were out of service.  Nashville's public transportation system was shut down, and only a handful of private automobiles were able to move along the snow and ice covered roads.  Forms part of the Nashville Room Historic Photographs Collection. 1 photograph : b &amp; w ; 8 x 10 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Disasters; Natural Disasters; Capital City; Transportation; Weather--Tennessee--Nashville; Winter storms--Tennessee--Nashville; Ice storms--Tennessee--Nashville; Transportation, Automotive--Tennessee--Nashville; Snow--Tennessee--Nashville; Natural phenomena--Tennessee--Nashville; Winter--Tennessee--Nashville; Temperature--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Hillsboro-West End (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>McCown, Julie (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1951-02-02</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>P-2692</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Historic Photographs Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/322</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>