<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Inglewood Church of God, 2001 January</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of the former Inglewood Church of God located at 1085 Zophi Street in Nashville, Tennessee.  When this photograph was taken in 2001, the name of the church had changed to Full Gospel Pentecostal Church.  The address first appears in the city directory in 1947 as Church of God, soon changing to Inglewood Church of God.  Over the years the church has been listed under various names including Eastwood Baptist Church, Grace Chapel Church, Calvary Assembly of God, Harvest Time Publishers, House of Prayer, Faith is the Victory Teaching Center, Abundant Life Church of God, Home Mission Holiness Church, Brotherly Love Pentecostal Church, and Church of God of the Bible.  As of 2007 this address is no longer listed in the Nashville City Directory.  The exterior walls are brick.  The doors are wooden.  An awning hangs above the front entrance.  Forms part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project. 1 photograph : col. ; 4  x 6  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Inglewood Church of God (Nashville, Tenn.); Full Gospel Pentecostal Church (Nashville, Tenn.); Eastwood Baptist Church (Nashville, Tenn.); Grace Chapel Church (Nashville, Tenn.); Calvary Assembly of God (Nashville, Tenn.); Harvest Time Publishers (Nashville, Tenn.); House of Prayer (Nashville, Tenn.); Faith is the Victory Teaching Center (Nashville, Tenn.); Abundant Life Church of God (Nashville, Tenn.); Home Mission Holiness Church (Nashville, Tenn.); Brotherly Love Pentecostal Church (Nashville, Tenn.); Church of God of the Bible (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Popular Culture; Religion; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Religious facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Church architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Brick churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Pentecostal churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Baptist church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Details; Awnings--Tennessee--Nashville; Churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Baptist churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs; Zophi Street (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2001-01</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>SSSP - Inglewood Ch of God</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1075</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>