<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Dance recital number "Glinda's Girl Army," presented for the Drought-Relief Fund, 1931 February 07</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of a dance number entitled "Glinda's Girl Army" from "The Wonderful Land of Oz," presented by advanced students of the Dance Department, Nashville Conservatory of Music. The recital was sponsored by the Al Menah Temple for the benefit of the Drought-Relief Fund, American Red Cross (Nashville Chapter), and held at the Scottish Rite Temple, 7th Avenue North on Saturday evening, February 7, 1931, at 8:15. The admission was 50 cents for adults and 25 cents for children.  The Conservatory had not charged admission for performances until this benefit. Dancers left to right: Ann Elizabeth Derryberry, Stella Rosenblum, Ann Vaughn, Frances Carter, Eveline Uthman and Dorothy Longhurst. Dancer Sarah Jeter and pianist Louise Smith owned and operated several dancing schools, including this one, from 1927-1940 in Nashville, Tennessee.  Forms part of the Jeter-Smith Dance Collection. 1 photograph : b &amp; w : 8 x 10 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Derryberry, Ann Elizabeth; Rosenblum, Stella; Vaughn, Ann; Carter, Frances; Uthman, Eveline; Longhurst, Dorothy</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Conservatory of Music (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Performing Arts; Dance; Popular Culture; Entertainment; Capital City; Organizations; Children's History; Education; Performing arts--Tennessee--Nashville; Ballet--Tennessee--Nashville; Dance--Tennessee--Nashville; Dance--Study and teaching--Tennessee--Nashville; Dancers--Tennessee--Nashville; Child dancers--Tennessee--Nashville; Ballet dancers--Tennessee--Nashville; Dance recitals--Tennessee--Nashville; Ballerinas--Tennessee--Nashville; Dance schools--Tennessee--Nashville; Humanitarianism--Tennessee--Nashville; Entertainers--Tennessee--Nashville; Entertainment--Tennessee--Nashville; Children--Tennessee--Nashville; Girls--Tennessee--Nashville; Charitable organizations--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Jeter, Sarah, 1903-1985 (Collector); Smith, Louise Showers, 1904-1983 (Collector)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1931-02-07</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>JSDC - 33</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Jeter-Smith Dance Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/861</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>