<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Salvage scrap drive in Nashville and Middle Tennessee region, 1942 October</dc:title>
<dc:description>Pictured: &#8220;Plan scrap movie: the suburban theaters operated by the Crescent Amusement Company will cooperate in the Banner scrap drive when a special program for young and old will be held Saturday morning at 10 o&#8217;clock with 10 pounds of scrap metal for general admission price for all ages.  The suburban theaters as well as other theaters of the Crescent chain throughout Middle Tennessee will observe the movie scrap day.  Shown at the county scrap pile at the City Testing Station are a group of local theater managers as they get a preview of the items that will pile up before their theaters on Saturday morning.  They are (left to right): J. J. Binkley, manager of the State Theater; Rama Oakes, elite Theater; Carl Rice, Belmont Theater; J. A. Lawrence, Woodland Theater; E. J. Jordan, Belle Meade Theater; Lloyd S. Lawrence, Madison Theater; W. A. McPherson, Capitol Theater; and J. O. Bowen, Melrose Theater; Charles Bess, manager of the Woodbine Theater, was not present when the picture was made.  Tony Sudekum is president of the Crescent Amusement Company.&#8221; During World War II Americans were active with scrap drives to help the war effort.  Local communities were salvaging raw materials such as metal, rags, rubber, and paper to be used to supply troops.  These special home front war programs were often well-coordinated through committees that engaged widespread urban and rural participation and motivated patriotism and community spirit.  Forms part of Record Group 412, Photographs Collection. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in. </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Nashville Banner</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>World War, 1939-1945--War work--Tennessee, Middle; World War, 1939-1945--Civilian participation--Tennessee, Middle; Salvage--Tennessee, Middle; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Tennessee, Middle--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1942-10</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 412 199 Salvage scrape drive Oct 1942 004</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 412</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/5220</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>