<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Hall Memorial Missionary Baptist Church, 2002 January</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of Hall Memorial Missionary Baptist Church historically located at 5990 Mt. View Road in Antioch, Tennessee.  Although most recently recorded as having a 6005 Mt. View Road address, this church is no longer listed in the Nashville City Directory and neither are either of its past addresses.  According to the survey the foundation was made of concrete blocks.  The exterior walls were vinyl siding.  The roof was gabled with tar shingles.  The windows used clear glass.  The doors were wooden with metal and glass storm doors on the outside.  Other features included a small wooden "HM" over the front door and a miniature tower with shingle roof.  The survey also indicates a cemetery on the church property with very few grave stones, several of which are unmarked.  The oldest marked stone was marked 1889, while the most recent was marked 1984.  Forms part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project. 1 photograph : col. ; 4  x 6  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Hall Memorial Missionary Baptist Church (Antioch, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Popular Culture; Religion; Architecture--Tennessee--Antioch; Buildings--Tennessee--Antioch; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Antioch; Church buildings--Tennessee--Antioch; Religious facilities--Tennessee--Antioch; Church architecture--Tennessee--Antioch; Baptist church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Details; Towers--Tennessee--Antioch; Churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Baptist churches--Tennessee--Antioch; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Antioch</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Antioch (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Antioch (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Antioch (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs; Mount View Road (Antioch, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2002-01</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>SSSP - Hall Memorial M B</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1067</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>