<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Joe Torrence and United Way, 1974 August</dc:title>
<dc:description>Joe E. Torrence (pictured on the right) with an unidentified man at an August 1974 United Way event.  It was in 1954 when Nashville business leaders established the United Givers Fund (UGF), replacing the Community Chest, soliciting funds within the community-wide workplace.  Circa 1974 UGF joined with similar organizations nationwide to become United Way of Middle Tennessee, promoting community human services.  Torrence was the Director of Finance, Metropolitan Government of Nashville and Davidson County from 1963-76, serving prior years as acting director.  From 1972-77 he held honorary positions with Senior Citizens, Heart Fund and United Way.  He was Chairman of United Way Fund Drive, 1975 and Chairman of the Board, 1976.  His distinguished career spanned from 1933 to 1994, when he retired at the age of 82.  Forms part of Record Group 3, Metro Davidson County Photographer.  2 photograph negatives : b &amp; w.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Torrence, Joseph E., 1912-2002</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>United Way</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Businesspeople--Tennessee--Nashville; Businessmen--Tennessee--Nashville; Charity--Tennessee, Middle; Altruism; Associations, institutions, etc.--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1974-08</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 3 2841 Joe Torrence UGF 001-002</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3 Metro Davidson County Photographer</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1970-1979</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4675</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>