<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Greetings from On Maneuvers in Tennessee, circa 1942</dc:title>
<dc:description>Front of a black and white postcard, circa 1942, depicting WWII military maneuvers in Tennessee, from official photographs of the U. S. Army and Marine Corps. Between September 1942 and March 1944 nearly one million soldiers trained in the Tennessee Maneuvers area, located in Middle Tennessee. Forms part of the Nashville Room Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5 x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>United States. Army--Maneuvers</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Military History; World War II; Aviation; Industries; 
World War, 1939-1945; Parachuting--Tennessee; Skydiving--Tennessee; Military maneuvers--Tennessee; War games--Tennessee; Soldiers--Training of--Tennessee; Veterans--Tennessee--History--Sources; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Military service--United States; Military vehicles--American--Tennessee</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Tennessee, Middle--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Graycraft Card Co. (Publisher)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1940-1949</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TN-180-Greetings Maneuvers</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/606</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>