<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Election of Buford Ellington for Governor, Nashville, Tennessee, 1958 </dc:title>
<dc:description>These photographs are related to the 1958 election of Buford Ellington for Governor of Tennessee, including several photographs of family and friends.  Governor Earl Buford Ellington, a Democrat, held two terms of office: 1st term: Jan 19, 1959 - Jan 15, 1963, and 2nd term: Jan 16, 1967 - Jan 16, 1971.  After his four-year term as governor, he sat out the 1962 race as required by the state constitution, and once again Frank Clement was elected governor. Ellington served as vice president of the Louisville-Nashville Railroad until he took a position in President Johnson's civil rights program. He was reelected governor in 1966 and served from 1967 until 1971. Shortly after leaving the governor's office, Ellington died while playing golf in Florida. He was buried in Lone Oak Cemetery in Lewisburg, Tennessee. Forms part of Nashville Banner Negatives Collection.  1 photographic negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in. </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Ellington family; Ellington, Buford, 1907-1972</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Banner</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Governors--Tennessee--History--Sources; Governors--Election; Public officers--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Cumberland River (Ky. and Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1958</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Banner Buford Ellington at City Room Election Night 1958 - 2274 001 - 0025</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Negatives Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/8892</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>