<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Mayor Ben West&#8217;s tour of Kfar Chabad in central Israel, 1960 November</dc:title>
<dc:description>Pictured: Nashville Mayor Ben West presented with a gavel of olive wood by the Mayor of Kfar Chabad, made by the students in the woodworking school.  This photo relates to Mayor West&#8217;s tour of Kfar Chabad, when he traveled to the Chabad circa November 1960.  Kfar Chabad was established in 1949 and the first inhabitants were mostly immigrants from the Soviet Union, survivors of World War II and Stalinist oppression.  The Chabad is located just outside Lod and about 8 km southeast of Tel Aviv, it serves as the headquarters of the Chabad-Lubavitch Chassidic movement in Israel.  It includes agricultural lands as well as numerous educational institutions.  Mayor Ben West was in office as mayor of Nashville, Tennessee from 1951 to 1963.  Forms part of Record Group 3, Metro Davidson County Photographer. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>West, Ben, 1911-1974</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Mayors--Tennessee--Nashville; Habad--Israel--History--Sources; Hasidism--Israel--History--Sources; Jews--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Kefar H&#803;abad (Israel)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1960-11</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 3 9041 Ben West trip to Israel village of Kfar Chabad Nov1960 013</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/5993</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>