<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Program, The Nashville Community Playhouse, presentation of &#8220;Rain,&#8221; 1946-1947 Season </dc:title>
<dc:description>A Nashville Community Playhouse program for a theatrical production of &#8220;Rain,&#8221; by John Colton and Clemence Randolph, founded on W. Somerset Maugham&#8217;s Story, &#8220;Miss Thompson,&#8221; presented during the 1946-47 season.  The production was directed by Raymond Johnson; Setting by Hayden B. Johnson; Lighting by Bill Adler; Detailed set painting by Frank Suiter, and Costumes by Brook&#8217;s, New York.  The Cast consisted of Kate Wells, Tommy Glover, Emily Glover, Gene Sullivan, Charles Wallace, Richard C. Dunn, Al Margolin, and Catherine Winnia.  The Nashville Community Playhouse was known for its excellence in the arts, located at 2102 Belcourt Avenue.  The play, &#8220;Rain,&#8221; was presented January 15th-22nd, 1947.  Forms part of the Wilhelmina Webb Collection. 1 program. </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Johnson, Raymond</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Community Playhouse (Nashville, Tenn.)--History--Sources; Belcourt Theatre (Nashville, Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>
Performances--Tennessee--Nashville; Performing arts--Tennessee--Nashville; Entertainment--Tennessee--Nashville; Advertising--Tennessee--Nashville; Community theater--Tennessee--Nashville; Theater--Tennessee--Nashville; Theatrical companies--Tennessee--Nashville
</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Belcourt Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1947</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Programs; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Wilhelmina Webb Collection Nash Community Playhouse progs 1940-47 Rain 001 - 018</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Wilhelmina Webb Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/9174</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>