<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>YMCA Community Action Project Headquarters, circa 2001</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of the YMCA Community Action Project building located at 1021 Russell Street in the East Nashville neighborhood of Nashville, Tennessee.  This structure was originally built as Russell Street Presbyterian Church in about 1910 and has served as home to both Presbyterian and Baptist congregations over the years.  Nashville Funeral Home was also based in the building for a time.  The structure was placed on the National Register of Historic Places in 1981.  In 1996 the building was auctioned off and became home to the YMCA Community Action Project's headquarters in November of 1997.  The foundation is made of rough cut stone blocks and smooth cut capstone.  The exterior walls are brick.  The roof is gabled with tar shingles.  Some of the windows are arched.  The doors are made of wood and glass.  Forms part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project. 1 photograph : col. ; 4  x 6  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>YMCA of Middle Tennessee; Russell Street Presbyterian Church (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville Funeral Home (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Popular Culture; Religion; Organizations; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Religious facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Church architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Presbyterian church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Towers--Tennessee--Nashville; Arches--Tennessee--Nashville; Gables--Tennessee--Nashville; Pediments--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Details; Brick churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Protestant church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Remodeling for other use--Tennessee--Nashville; Commercial buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Nonprofit organizations--Tennessee--Nashville; Funeral homes--Tennessee--Nashville; Churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural details--Tennessee--Nashville; Protestant churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Presbyterian churches--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs; Russell Street (Nashville, Tenn.); East Nashville (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 2001</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>SSSP - YMCA Mem Found</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1572</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>