<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Aerial of Riverfront Park development area before it was completed as an urban park, Nashville, Tennessee Nashville, Tennessee, 1973 July 29 </dc:title>
<dc:description>A view of the urban area that would later be developed into Riverfront Park, located on the left bank of the Cumberland River at Broad Street and First Avenue N in downtown Nashville, Tennessee.  The Park Board requested Mayor Richard Fulton to use specific land to create a riverfront park as a historical project commemorating the Nashville Bicentennial.  On November 5, 1980, Sandra (Mrs. Richard) Fulton and Betty Brown co-chairman of a Century III special project committee, presented plans developed by the committee for a riverfront park and requested the assistance of the Park Board in securing federal funding assistance with park development.  The Nashville District, U.S. Army Corps of Engineers, on December 17, 1981, entered into an agreement with city government on a cost-sharing basis for development of the park, the plan costing about $4.2 million.  This cost was shared by the federal government and community development funds, with a small amount coming from the Department of Conservation&#8217;s Tennessee Land and Conservation Fund.  The three-phase park construction program proceeded, and the first phase was completed and opened with a gala riverfront celebration on July 10, 1983.  Third phase construction, including a boat dock, was approved at the end of 1984, and was in progress in 1985.  Forms part of Metro Archives Record Group 327, Metro Parks and Recreation Collection.  1 b &amp; w photograph.  </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Ingram Barge Company--History--Sources; Life and Casualty Insurance Company of Tennessee--History--Sources; Sam Davis Hotel (Nashville, Tenn.); WKDA (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); Washington Manufacturing Company (Nashville, Tenn.); Ryman Auditorium (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Parks--Tennessee--Nashville; Urban parks--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; River boats--Tennessee--Nashville; Boats--Tennessee--Nashville; Rivers--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Bridges--Tennessee--Nashville </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Parks; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; First Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Cumberland River (Ky. and Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>White, Gene (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1973-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Parks - Riverfront Park - 009 -7-29-73</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>RG 327, Metro Parks Collection </dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1970-1979</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/6896</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>