<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Lake Watauga, Centennial Park, Nashville, Tenn., circa 1907</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard view of row boating on Lake Watauga, Centennial Park. This man-made lake was built for the Tennessee Centennial Exposition, held in Nashville in 1897 to celebrate Tennessee's one-hundredth anniversary of statehood. During the celebration, gondolas were a feature with native gondoliers from Venice, Italy. There was a replica of Venice's Rialto Bridge on the lake. Lake Watauga lies at the foot of the terrace in Centennial Park which is crowned by a full-scale replica of the original Greek Parthenon. Lake Watauga was named in honor of the first settlers of Tennessee who were known as the Watauga or Cumberland settlers. Forms part of the Nashville Room Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Tennessee Centennial and International Exposition (1897 : Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Sports &amp; Recreation; Lakes; Parks; Capital City; Popular Culture; Entertainment; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Parks--Tennessee--Nashville; Lakes--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Adolph Selige (Publisher)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1907</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Nash - 282</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1900-1909</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/2293</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>