<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Sparkman Street Bridge, Nashville, Tennessee, between 1909 and 1928</dc:title>
<dc:description>The Sparkman Street Bridge, later renamed Shelby Street Bridge was completed in 1909, spanning the Cumberland River to link East Nashville to the downtown area. The multi-storied Nashville Bridge Company can be seen in the background on the east side of the river. The Foster &amp; Creighton Company were the contractors for the bridge (specifically Foster-Creighton-Gould Company), a family-owned construction company founded in Nashville circa 1885 by Wilbur Fisk Foster and Robert T. Creighton. Some of their early works included the Parthenon, Union Station, and the Sparkman/Shelby Street Bridges. In 1986, the bridge was added to the National Register of Historic Places. In 2003, the bridge reopened as a pedestrian walkway.  The bridge was the first one in North America to have concrete arched trusses. Howard M. Jones, a railroad engineer, was employed by the county as its designer. The original official name was the Broadway Bridge. Forms part of the Foster &amp; Creighton General Contractors Collection. 1 photograph : b &amp; 2 ; 8 x 10 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Foster &amp; Creighton Company; Nashville Bridge Company </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Bridges--Tennessee--Nashville; Building construction--Tennessee--Nashville; Business enterprises--Tennessee--Nashville; Industries--Tennessee--Nashville; Steel industry and trade--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Transportation--Tennessee--Nashville; Rivers--Tennessee--Nashville; Pedestrian bridges--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Cumberland River (Ky. and Tenn.)--Navigation; Sparkman Street Bridge (Nashville, Tenn.); Shelby Street Bridge (Nashville, Tenn.); Broadway Bridge (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Wiles Photographers, Arcade (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Creighton III, Wilbur (donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>between 1909 and 1928</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>1fl10.1 Shelby Bridge Creighton-b1</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Foster &amp; Creighton General Contractors Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1900-1909; 1910-1919; 1920-1929</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4405</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>