<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Aerial photograph of interstate construction in West Nashville, ca. 1968</dc:title>
<dc:description>Aerial photograph of West Nashville, looking slightly southwest, circa 1968, taken by Metro Photographer, William M. King. The image shows Interstate 40 under construction, with ground cleared and leveled, dirt roadway in place, and some bridges, overpasses, and retaining walls already constructed. In the foreground is the interchange of I-40 entering the picture from the lower right and continuing toward the top of the photograph (heading westward), intersecting with the future Interstate 440 headed east in the lower left side of the photograph. No locations on the image have been labelled, but there are several identifiable landmarks. Preston Taylor Homes public housing is at the right middleground, with Clifton Avenue curving in the upper right. Overpasses have already been constructed on I-40 to the west above 40th Avenue (first overpass) and a second nearby overpass over a railroad near 42nd Avenue (to the west). Discernable in the distance, just to the right of these overpasses and running parallel and adjacent to the interstate, is Delaware Avenue.  The smokestack in the distance, left of the overpasses, likely marks the site of Park Avenue School. Forms part of the Nashville Room Historic Photographs Collection. 1 photograph : b &amp; w ; 8 x 10 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Preston Taylor Homes (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Capitol City; Transportation; Express highways--Tennessee--Nashville; Roads--Design and construction--Tennessee--Nashville; Roads--Design and construction--Aerial photographs; Neighborhoods--Tennessee--Nashville; Streets--Tennessee--Nashville; Housing--Tennessee--Nashville; City planning--Tennessee--Nashville; Transportation--Tennessee--Nashville; Public housing--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--20th century; Nashville (Tenn.)--Aerial photographs; Interstate 40; Interstate 440 (Nashville, Tenn.); Delaware Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Clifton Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Fortieth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); West Nashville (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>King, William M. (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1968</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>p-0015 &#8211; Nash aerial, interstate area</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Historic Photographs Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969; 1970-1979</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/12406</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>