<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>St. Cecilia Academy.  Nashville, Tenn., 1906</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard of St. Cecilia Academy, a private, all-girls Roman Catholic high school founded in 1860 by the Dominican Sisters.  This building is located in North Nashville at Eighth Avenue North and Clay Street. The original Victorian-style building was built in 1862 as a four-story structure with 18-inch thick brick walls and bay windows.  As enrollment increased, the school later added a west wing in 1880 and an east wing in 1903.  In 1953 ground was broken in West Nashville on Harding Road for a new building where the school still operates today.  The original building in North Nashville is still used as a convent, the official Motherhouse of the Dominican Sisters.  It was added to the National Register of Historic Places in 1976.  Forms part of the Norton Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : b &amp; w ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>St. Cecilia's Academy (Nashville, Tenn.); Dominican Sisters of the Congregation of Saint Cecilia; Catholic Church--Education--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Education; Private Schools; Religion; Schools; Capital City; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Catholic schools--Tennessee--Nashville; School facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Details; Architecture, Victorian--Nashville--Tennessee; Convents--Tennessee--Nashville; Educational facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville; Wings (Building divisions)--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Eighth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Clay Street (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Duncan R. Dorris (Publisher)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1906</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Norton - 0028</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Norton Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1900-1909</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1946</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>