<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of the Washington Manufacturing Company building, after the fire, circa 1985</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of the Washington Manufacturing Company building at 200 and 210 Second Avenue North, after it was gutted by fire on October 12, 1985. The building occupied two addresses and may at one time have been two separate buildings. At the time of the fire, it was one of the oldest buildings on Second Avenue, in downtown Nashville, dating to at least the Civil War. An 1864 photograph of the building identifies it as a hospital. It also housed the Manhattan Carriage Company in the late 1800's. It was part of the multi-building complex of the Washington Manufacturing Company during much of the twentieth century. This section of Second Avenue was listed on the National Register of Historic Sites in 1972. Eventually, the entire east side of the block, from Church Street north to Bank Street, was razed. Photographed by the Nashville architect Charles Wesley Warterfield, Jr. (1926-1998); the architectural photograph forms part of the Charles Warterfield Architectural Collection. Gift of: The Estate of Charles W. Warterfield, Jr., F. A. I. A. The original is a 35 mm color transparency (2 x 2 in. slide mount)</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Washington Manufacturing Company (Nashville, Tenn.)--Fire, 1985</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Business; Industries; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Architects--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Commercial buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Commercial facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Business districts--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Warterfield, Charles W. (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Estate of Charles W. Warterfield, Jr., F. A. I. A. (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1985</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still image; Slides; Architectural photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>WSC 3892</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Charles Warterfield Architectural Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1980-1989</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/55</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>