<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Oral history interview with David K. Wilson, 2006 September 13, excerpt 04</dc:title>
<dc:description>An excerpt from an oral history interview with Nashville business and civic leader David Kirkpatrick "Pat" Wilson, conducted on 13 September 2006 by Cabot Pyle and Kenneth L. Roberts as part of the Nashville Public Library's Nashville Business Leaders Oral History Project:  The Turner Interviews.  Wilson discusses the business climate in Nashville during the 1940s and how business leaders of the time, particularly those in the insurance industry, were active in their own areas but were not particularly active in the community.  The complete interview, as well as an index, is available in the repository.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Wilson, David Kirkpatrick, 1919- --Interviews</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Business; Enterprise; Insurance; Businesspeople--Tennessee--Nashville; Civic leaders--Tennessee--Nashville; Business enterprises--Tennessee--Nashville; Insurance companies--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Commerce</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Wilson, David Kirkpatrick, 1919-  (Interviewee); Pyle, Cabot Pollard (Interviewer); Roberts, Kenneth L., 1932- (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2006-09-13</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3 (1 min., 14 sec.)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>NBLWilsonD1005clip1</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from:  NBLWilsonD digital recording converted from wav to mp3 format in 2006.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Business Leaders Oral History Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/696</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>