<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Grace Apostolic Church, 2001 November</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of Grace Apostolic Church (formerly Grace Baptist Church) located at 1100 Lischey Avenue in Nashville, Tennessee.  This church was erected in 1925 for the Grace Baptist congregation with the entrance located at 1103 Stainback Avenue.  In 1981 an Apostolic congregation moved into the structure and renamed the church Grace Apostolic Church.  Today, at its new Lischey Avenue address, the complex takes up an entire block and includes administrative offices, dozens of classrooms, two full kitchens and two dining areas, a gymnasium/auditorium, and facilities for a full childcare center.  The foundation is made of rough cut stone blocks.  The exterior walls are brick.  The roof is a combination of flat and gabled, comprised of tar shingles.  The windows are a combination of clear and tinted glass.  The lower level windows have been bricked-in.  The doors are wooden.  Other features include four round columns at multiple entrances.  Forms part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project. 1 photograph : col. ; 4  x 6  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Grace Apostolic Church (Nashville, Tenn.); Grace Baptist Church (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Popular Culture; Religion; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Religious facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Church architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; African American churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Baptist church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Gables--Tennessee--Nashville; Columns--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Details; Churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville; Steeples; Baptist churches--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs; Lischey Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Stainback Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2001-11</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>SSSP - Grace Apostolic</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1043</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>