<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Letter to parents from James H. Neese, 1943 July 18</dc:title>
<dc:description>A two-page handwritten letter by James Neese to his parents, Mr. and Mrs. T.L. Neese, Jr. of Nashville, Tenn.  James often wrote to his parents and brother in Nashville to tell them about his experiences in the Army infantry serving in Africa and Italy from 1943 to 1945.  In this particular letter Neese writes on American Red Cross stationary.  He talks about being in North Africa and relaxing by the beaches.  He comments on the makeup of the population, stating it is mostly French, Jews, and Natives.  He reports that the local children bother the soldiers for candy and gum quite often, tells of the nice beachside building they have taken over and transformed into their service club.  Neese closes the letter by predicting the war will not last too much longer, and lastly asking for everyone to send mail.  Includes envelope.  Forms part of the Veterans History Project. 1 letter: col. ; 6 x 10 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Neese, James H., 1921-2007; Neese, T.L.</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>American Red Cross; United States. Army. Infantry Division, 34th; United States. Army. Infantry Regiment, 168th.</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Military History; World War II; Popular Culture; War; Veterans--Tennessee--History--Sources; Beaches--Africa, North; World War, 1939-1945--Personal narratives, American; Correspondence; Letters; World War, 1939-1945--Children; Military service--United States; Military life--American</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Africa, North -- Description and travel</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Neese, James H., 1921-2007</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1943-07-18</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text; Letters (correspondence)</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>VHP-WWII-Neese-F2-Letter, July 18</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Veterans History Project Collection, World War II Series, James H. Neese Papers</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1258</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>