<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Tennessee welcomes Hollywood at the Tennessee Theater, Nashville, Tennessee, circa 1952</dc:title>
<dc:description>Pictured: Mayor Ben West presenting a key to the City of Nashville to Jack Wesson? at the Tennessee Theater in downtown Nashville, Tennessee, circa 1952.  The Tennessee Theater opened circa February 28, 1952 in Nashville, Tennessee.  This palatial Art Deco movie palace was located in downtown Nashville at 527 Church Street.  It featured a 2,000-seat auditorium adjoining the Sudekum Building.  The gala opening featured a Technicolor musical called &#8220;About Face&#8221; and many onlookers watched the arrival and announcement of movie stars such as Gordon MacRae, Phyllis Kirk, Lex Barker, and others.  Many local VIPS attended the gala ceremony and Owen Bradley and his orchestra played inside on stage that night.  Some of the outside activities included broadcasts by WSIX radio and WSM television, a concert by the American Legion Post 5 band, and the arrival of the honored celebrities.  Forms part of Record Group 3, Metro Davidson County Photographer. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>West, Ben, 1911-1974</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Tennessee Theatre (Nashville, Tenn.); Sudekum Building (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Celebrities--United States; Motion picture theaters--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Businessmen--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Church Street (Nashville, Tenn.); Sixth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1952</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 3 1133 Tennessee Theater Opeining 1951 Lobby View  001</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3 Metro Davidson County Photographer</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/6297</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>