<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Varallo&#8217;s Restaurant at 817 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 1958 November</dc:title>
<dc:description>Pictured: Varallo&#8217;s Restaurant, located at the corner of Church and Ninth Avenue in downtown, Nashville, Tennessee circa November 1958.  Also pictured is an asphalt pavement roller and equipment making road improvements on Church Street and Ninth Avenue.  Nashville&#8217;s oldest restaurant was founded by Frank Varallo, Sr., a traveling violinist from Viggiano, Italy, who opened a restaurant in 1907 featuring a secret bean soup recipe called &#8220;chile&#8221; (then located on Broadway near Hume-Fogg Academic High School).  Frank Varallo, Jr. and his brother Nick took over from their father in 1937, and Frank became sole owner soon after.  He and his wife, Eva, with many of the Varallo family have worked in the restaurant over the years.  The restaurant closed operation on Church Street in December 1998, but was continued at a new location on Fourth Avenue N, downtown, headed by Todd Varallo, the great-grandson of the founder.  Forms part of Record Group 3, Metro Davidson County Photographer. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Varallo family</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Varallo&#8217;s Restaurant (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Family-owned business enterprises--Tennessee--Nashville; Businesspeople--Tennessee--Nashville; Restaurateurs--Tennessee--Nashville; Restaurants--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Pavements, Asphalt--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Church Street (Nashville, Tenn.); Ninth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1958-11-09</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 3 1160 Varallos Restaurant Church at 9th Nov 1958 001</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3 Metro Davidson County Photographer</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/6370</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>