<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Overextended, between 1950 and 1956</dc:title>
<dc:description>An original political cartoon created by Jack Knox, the Nashville Banner editorial cartoonist from the mid-1940s to the early 1970s.  This caricature depicts a worried President Gamal Nasser of Egypt straddling two sides of the Suez Canal while holding a sign that says "Egyptian Seizure." For several years, circa the 1950s, there was a practice of interference with commercial shipping bound to or from Israel.  Nasser nationalized the Suez Canal in July 1956, which caused immediate concern internationally in regards to maritime traffic in the Canal.  Forms part of the Jack Knox Political Cartoon Collection. 1 original cartoon drawing : b &amp; w ; 14.25 x 19.5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Nasser, Gamal Abdel, 1918-1970--Caricatures and cartoons</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Banner</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Capital City; Politics; Military History; Political cartoons--United States--20th century; Political cartoons--Tennessee--Nashville; Caricatures and cartoons--Tennessee--Nashville; Cartoonists--Tennessee--Nashville; Editorial cartoonists--Tennessee--Nashville; World politics--Caricatures and cartoons; Presidents--Egypt--Caricatures and cartoons; Cartoonists; Canals--Egypt--Port Said; Heads of state--Egypt; Presidents--Egypt; Economic &amp; political systems</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Suez Canal (Egypt)--Caricatures and cartoons; Egypt--History--20th century--Caricatures and cartoons; Egypt--Politics and government--20th century--Caricatures and cartoons</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Knox, Jack, 1910- (Cartoonist)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Knox, Joseph T. (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>between 1950 and 1956</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Caricatures; Cartoons (Commentary); Editorial cartoons</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Knox NPL-234</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Jack Knox Political Cartoon Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/864</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>