<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>United Primitive Baptist Church, 2000 December</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of United Primitive Baptist Church located at 2911 Clifton Road (now Avenue) in Nashville, Tennessee.  Now reportedly being used as a duplex home with barbecue smoking equipment in the back, this structure began as St. Phillip's African Methodist Episcopal Church in 1913.  By 1930, the address was listed as Benevolent Hall.  In the late 1930s the name changed to St. John's Union Baptist Church, quickly followed by another slight name change in 1940 to St. John's United Primitive Baptist Church.  By 1954 the address no longer appeared in the directories.  The building has a block foundation.  The exterior walls are cinder block.  The roof is gabled with shingles.  Storm windows have been installed.  Forms part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project. 1 photograph : col. ; 4  x 6  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>St. John's United Primitive Baptist Church (Nashville, Tenn.); United Primitive Baptist Church (Nashville, Tenn.); Benevolent Hall (Nashville, Tenn.); St. Phillip's African Methodist Episcopal Church (Nashville, Tenn.); St. John's Union Baptist Church (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Popular Culture; Religion; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Religious facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Church architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Baptist church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Houses--Tennessee--Nashville; Methodist Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Episcopal church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Baptist churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Methodist churches--Tennessee--Nashville, Episcopal churches--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs; Clifton Road (Nashville, Tenn.); Clifton Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2000-12</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>SSSP - United Primitive Bap</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1550</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>