<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Christmas services bulletin, 1945</dc:title>
<dc:description>A Japanese-inspired Christmas bulletin listing the service times for Catholic mass and Protestant services to be held for the 10th Marines, 2nd Marine Division in Kyushu, Japan, 1945.  This bulletin was collected by American Marine, Melvin C. Dodson.  Dodson served in the First and Second Marine Divisions during World War II.  He was stationed in Pacific theater and saw action in the battle of Saipan and was stationed in Nagasaki.  He also served in the Korean War.  An excerpt from St. Luke, chapter two is printed inside the card.  Greetings from both Protestant (Roger B. McShane) and Catholic (James W. Lutz) chaplains are included.  Two carols are printed on the back: Silent Night and It Came Upon the Midnight Clear.  Forms part of the Veterans History Project. 1 bulletin: col. ; 5.75 x 8 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>McShane, Roger B.; Lutz, James W.; Dodson, Melvin C., 1920-2006</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>United States. Marine Corps. Division, 2nd; United States. Marine Corps. Marines, 10th.</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Military History; World War II; Popular Culture; Religion; War; Veterans--Tennessee--History--Sources; World War, 1939-1945--Caricatures and cartoons; World War, 1939-1945--Art and the war--Pictorial works; World War, 1939-1945--Religious aspects--Christianity; World War, 1939-1945--Chaplains; World War, 1939-1945--Social aspects; Religious gatherings--Japan; Christmas service; Holidays; Religious meetings--Japan; Religious services--Japan; Military service--United States; Military life--American</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Kyushu (Japan)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Brownson, E. James (Artist)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Dodson, Melvin C., 1920-2006 (Collector)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1945</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text; Ephemera</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>VHP-WWII-Dodson - F2 - Merry Christmas, Front; VHP-WWII-Dodson - F2 - Merry Christmas, Inside; VHP-WWII-Dodson - F2 - Merry Christmas, Back</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Veterans History Project Collection, World War II Series, Melvin Dodson Papers</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1212</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>