<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Strother's Meeting House, 2000 May</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of Strother's Meeting Center located on the southeast section of the Scarritt-Bennett Center campus.  This log cabin church was the meeting place for the first Methodist conference in Middle Tennessee.  That first conference took place in 1802 when the church was located in Sumner County.  In 1931 the building was taken apart, moved and reassembled on the campus of Scarritt College.  In 1940 the building was transplanted again to a new location on the Scarritt campus to make room for a new dorm.  Over the years Methodist relics of early days have gradually accumulated inside.  Today the church is used as a teaching museum, open to all who wish to examine Methodist records and furniture of two centuries ago.  The foundation is rock.  The exterior walls are made of logs.  The roof is gabled with wood shingles.  The doors are wood.  Forms part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project. 1 photograph : col. ; 4  x 6  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Strother's Meeting House (Nashville, Tenn.); Scarritt-Bennett Center</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Popular Culture; Religion; Universities and Colleges; Education; Schools; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Religious facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Church architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Methodist church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Protestant church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Museums--Tennessee--Nashville; Small museums--Tennessee--Nashville; Historical museums--Tennessee--Nashville; Universities and colleges--Tennessee--Nashville; Education--Tennessee--Nashville; Methodist universities and colleges--Tennessee--Nashville; Log cabins--Tennessee--Nashville; Churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Methodist churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Universities &amp; colleges--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Intellectual life</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2000-05</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>SSSP - Strothers Meeting House</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1534</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>