<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Nashville Military Institute, Announcement 1896-97, Nashville, Tennessee, 1896 </dc:title>
<dc:description>A pamphlet published by the Nashville Military Institute, announcing the 1896-97 school year. This military school was established through a merger of the Western Military Institute and the University of Nashville in 1855.  The merger was brought about by John Berrien Lindsley and was established as a part of the University of Nashville.  The Board of Instruction and Management Officers of the Nashville Military Institute:  G.N. Tillman, Chairman Board of Directors; A.B. Bayless, Secretary; H. White Hall, Treasurer.  The Board of Directors: G.N. Tillman, Chairman; Joe M. Warren; C.F. Sharpe; John T. Benson; and James S. Dunbar.  The pamphlet lists the names of the stockholders.  The Faculty listed are: D.T. Wilson, M.A. (Vanderbilt), Principal: Mathematics, History and Geography; Capt. A.B. Bayless, Commandant: Military Science, and Bookkeeping; S.A. Myatt, B.A. (Vanderbilt): Latin, Greek, and French; D.H. Bishop, A.M. (Emory and Henry): English and German; J.R. Shapard, M.D., Surgeon.  The pamphlet discusses the chief aim of the Institute, the location, the buildings, social training, preparation for college, courses of study, lectures, examination, prizes, honor roll, the Military Department, Athletics, School Regulations, Admission, and testimonials.  The location of the Nashville Military Institute was at the terminus of the Woodland Street Electric Railway. During the Civil War, the military school did not offer instruction from 1862 to 1865, at that time the campus building served as a Union hospital for Federal officers.  The University of Nashville was an educational institution that existed as a distinct entity from 1826 until 1909.  Forms part of the Arcade Music Collection, Printed Material. 1 pamphlet.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Tillman, G. N. (George Newton), 1851-1923</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Military Institute (Nashville, Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Military education--Tennessee--Nashville; Universities and colleges--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1896</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text </dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Arcade Music Coll-Printed-Nash Military Institute 001 - 030</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Arcade Music Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1890-1899</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/9363</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>