<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Church Street West from Sixth Avenue by Night, Nashville, Tennessee, circa 1910</dc:title>
<dc:description>A color postcard of Church Street west as pictured from 6th Avenue, in downtown Nashville, circa the 1910s.  The Watkins Institute, as well as the Nashville Railway and Light Company are pictured.  The Watkins Institute was established through the philanthrophy of Samuel Watkins, who in his will bequeathed the sum of $100,000 to be used to establish a building to house the Watkins Institute for the education of the citizens of Nashville.  The gift was accepted by legislative enactment by the State of Tennessee in 1881.  Forms part of the Ridley Wills II Nashville Postcards Collection.  1 postcard.  </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Wills, Ridley, 1934-</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Watkins Institute; Nashvile Railway and Light Company (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; City and town life--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Church Street (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Ridley Wills II (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1910</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RidleyWillsPostcards Box 2 229 Nashville Railway and Light Church Street Sixth Ave</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Ridley Wills II Nashville Postcards Collection  </dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1900-1909; 1910-1919</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/9373</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>