<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Morning Star Missionary Baptist Church, 2001 February</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of Morning Star Missionary Baptist Church located at 19 Hart Street in Nashville, Tennessee.  This church was built in approximately 1894 as Mount Gilead Baptist Church.  In 1981, the name changed to Prince of Peace Baptist Church, but quickly switched again in 1982 to its current name, Morning Star Missionary Baptist Church.  The foundation is rough cut stone.  The exterior walls are red brick.  The roof is gabled with green tar shingles.  The windows are tall and rectangular shaped with blue and yellow colored glass.  The doors are glass with metal frames.  There is a stone porch with arches and a large rectangular stained glass window above the front porch, set into the fa&#231;ade.  Buttresses with stone caps align the side walls.  Since this survey, the church has announced plans to tear down the current building and replace it with a larger, more modern facility on the same lot.  Forms part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project. 1 photograph : col. ; 4  x 6  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Morning Star Missionary Baptist Church (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Popular Culture; Religion; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Religious facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Church architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Baptist church building--Tennessee--Nashville; Buttresses--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Details--Tennessee--Nashville; Brick churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Porches--Tennessee--Nashville; Arches--Tennessee--Nashville; Churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Baptist churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs; Hart Street (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2001-02</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>SSSP - Morning Star Bap Ch</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1090</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>