<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Publicity preparations, circa 1951 December 07</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of Mrs. Ned Lentz, publicity chairman for the Fannie Battle Carolers, and Mrs. David Huggins, Jr. seen at the Nashville Banner newspaper building in 1951 during their publicity preparations for the Fannie Battle Social Workers' annual Christmas project to bring the Christmas Eve carolers into the homes of Nashville and Davidson County.  This photograph illustrated the newspaper article "B. Banner Gets Christmas Spirit with Carol Committee," published in the 7 December 1951 issue of the Nashville Banner.  Forms part of the Fannie Battle Day Home Records.  1 photograph :  b &amp; w ; 6.25 x 10 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Lentz, Ned, Mrs.; Huggins, David, Mrs.</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Fannie Battle Day Home; Fannie Battle Social Workers; Nashville Banner</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Capital City; Organizations; Popular Culture; Children's History; Performing Arts; Music; Business; Printing/Publishing; Downtown Nashville; Women social reformers--Tennessee--Nashville; Charity--Tennessee--Nashville; Charities--Tennessee--Nashville; Day care centers--Tennessee--Nashville; Child care workers--Tennessee--Nashville; Social workers--Tennessee--Nashville; Child care--Tennessee--Nashville; Women in charitable work--Tennessee--Nashville; Altruism--Tennessee--Nashville; Benevolence--Tennessee--Nashville; Social work with children--Tennessee--Nashville; Children--Social conditions; Children--Charities; Child welfare; Christmas carols; Caroling--Tennessee--Nashville; Holidays--Tennessee--Nashville; Newspapers--Tennessee--Nashville; Newspaper publishing--Tennessee--Nashville; Nonprofit organizations--Tennessee--Nashville; Women in nonprofit organizations--Tennessee--Nashville; Charitable organizations--Tennessee--Nashville; Community service--Tennessee--Nashville; Economic &amp; social conditions--Tennessee--Nashville; Organizations--Tennessee--Nashville; Public relations</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social conditions; Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Davidson County (Tenn.)--Social conditions</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1951-12-07</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>FBDHR-SB-Carol Publicity-1951-B11, f37-p1</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Fannie Battle Day Home Records</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1846</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>