<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Portrait of Colonel Joseph A. S. Acklen, Belmont Mansion, Nashville, Tennessee, 1979 December </dc:title>
<dc:description>A portrait of Colonel Joseph Alexander Smith Acklen, photographed at Belmont Mansion circa December 1979.  Acklen was a lawyer, planter, and veteran of the Texas Revolution.  He was the second husband of Adelicia Hayes Franklin, later Cheatham, and the man with whom Adelicia built her summer home, Belmont, near Nashville, Tennessee.  He was the son of Samuel Black Acklen and his wife, the former Elizabeth Hunt.  He was born in Huntsville, Alabama in 1816.  Acklen died in Louisiana, USA, on September 11th, 1863.  Originally buried in Louisiana, he was later moved to the Acklen family mausoleum in Nashville.  Forms part of the Claynita Harris Slide Collection.  The original is a 35 mm color transparency (2 x 2 in. slide mount) </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Acklen, Adelicia, 1817-1887--Homes and haunts; Acklen, Joseph Alexander Smith, 1816-1863--Homes and haunts</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Belmont (Nashville, Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Portrait painting--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Businesspeople--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1979-12</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives </dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Harris Slides   533 Joseph Acklen portrait</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Claynita Harris Slide Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1970-1979</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/7032</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>