<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>A class in Modern Dance at Ward-Belmont College, 1933 March</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of a class in modern dance at Ward-Belmont College located at 1900 Belmont Boulevard in Nashville, Tennessee. Pictured are Claudia Whitson (top center), (down left to right) Jane Bagley, Yvette Franz, Obduha Rafferty, Betty Lou Gibson, Clemence Dow, Katherine Harris, Margaret Street, unidentified, Jean Goode, Dollie Dearman, and next two unidentified. Dancer Sarah Jeter and pianist Louise Smith owned and operated several dancing schools together from 1927-1940 in Nashville, Tennessee. Jeter was a graduate of Ward Belmont and later on the faculty with Smith.  Forms part of the Jeter-Smith Dance Collection. 1 photograph : b &amp; w ; 8 x 10 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Whitson, Claudia; Bagley, Jane; Franz, Yvette; Rafferty, Obduha; Gibson, Betty Lou; Dow, Clemence; Harris, Katherine; Street, Margaret; Goode, Jean; Dearman, Dollie</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Ward-Belmont College (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Performing Arts; Dance; Popular Culture; Entertainment; Education; Colleges and Universities; Performing arts--Tennessee--Nashville; Modern dance--Tennessee--Nashville; Dance--Tennessee--Nashville; Dance--Study and teaching--Tennessee--Nashville; Dance schools--Tennessee--Nashville; Dancers--Tennessee--Nashville; Women dancers--Tennessee--Nashville; Entertainers--Tennessee--Nashville; Entertainment--Tennessee--Nashville; Choreography</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Commercial Photograph Co. (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Jeter, Sarah, 1903-1985 (Collector); Smith, Louise Showers, 1904-1983 (Collector)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1933-03</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>JSDC - 51</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Jeter-Smith Dance Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/877</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>