<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Confederate Soldiers Home, Nashville, Tenn., circa 1908</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard of the Confederate Soldiers' Home.  The Confederate Soldiers' Home was built on the original Hermitage properties in 1892 and served as a retirement home for civil war soldiers.  On land southwest of the Hermitage mansion, the soldiers' home was a two-story brick building with a stone foundation, complete with galleries, and a rounded portico, sustained by fluted pillars.  A hospital was at the back of the main building where the veterans could receive medical care.  All rooms of the home were furnished by individual donations.  The last part of the home was demolished in 1953, after serving for a while as an apartment residence for Hermitage employees.  Many of the soldiers who occupied the home are buried in a cemetery on the Hermitage grounds, about a mile away from the old home.  Forms part of the Nashville Room Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Tennessee Confederate Soldiers' Home; Hermitage (Hermitage, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Capital City; Buildings; Civil War; Military History; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Soldiers' homes--Tennessee; Confederate States of America--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Veterans; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Veterans--Tennessee--History--Sources; Retired military personnel-- Tennessee--History--Sources; Soldiers' homes--Confederate States of America; Soldiers' homes--Southern States</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Hermitage (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>International Post Card Co. (Publisher)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1908</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Nash-26-Confederate Soldiers Home, Nashville, Tenn.</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1900-1909</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/663</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>