<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Mayor Briley and dignitaries at the groundbreaking ceremony of the Acuff-Rose Music Publishing building, Nashville, Tennessee, 1966</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of the 1966 groundbreaking ceremony for Acuff-Rose Music Publishing with Nashville Mayor Briley and country music singer Roy Acuff and others.  Acuff was an American country music singer, fiddler, and promoter.  He joined the Grand Ole Opry in 1938 and was a leading figure for nearly four decades.  Acuff co-founded the first major Nashville-based country music publishing company with Fred Rose: Acuff-Rose Music, which signed such acts as Hank Williams, Roy Orbison, and The Everly Brothers.  In 1962, Acuff became the first living inductee into the Country Music Hall of Fame.  The 1969 Nashville Suburban Directory cites the address at 2510 Franklin Road.  The original business enterprise was founded by Fred Rose and Roy Acuff in 1942.  Forms part of Record Group 3, Metro Davidson County Photographer. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 2.5 x 2.5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Briley, Beverly, 1914-1980; Acuff, Roy; Rose, Fred</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Acuff-Rose Publications (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Entertainers--Tennessee--Nashville; Country musicians--Tennessee--Nashville; Mayors--Tennessee--Nashville; Celebrities</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Franklin Road (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1966</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG3 583 Acuff Rose groundbreaking 1966 007</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3 Metro Davidson County Photographer</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/6593</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>