<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Railroad workers' strike ends, 1955 May 09</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of picketers holding the Nashville Banner newspaper's morning extra announcing the settlement of the 57-day-old strike of Louisville &amp; Nashville and Nashville Chattanooga &amp; Saint Louis railway workers. They were picketing at Eleventh Avenue and McGavock Street, Nashville, Tennessee, at the entrance to the downtown railroad yards.  Forms part of the Nashville Banner Archives. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 3.25 x 4.25 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Nashville Banner; Louisville and Nashville Railroad Company; Nashville, Chattanooga, and St. Louis Railway</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Business; Enterprise; Industries; Journalism; Printing/Publishing; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Transportation; Labor; Organizations; Business enterprises--Tennessee--Nashville; Industries--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Transportation--Tennessee--Nashville; Railroads--Tennessee--Nashville; Journalism--Tennessee--Nashville; Newspaper publishing--Tennessee--Nashville; Feature stories--Tennessee--Nashville; Mass media--Tennessee--Nashville; Newspapers--Tennessee--Nashville; Strikes and lockouts--Tennessee--Nashville; Picketing--Tennessee--Nashville; Railroad yards--Tennessee--Nashville; Railroad companies--Tennessee--Nashville; Collective bargaining--Railroads--Tennessee--Nashville; Railroad strikes--Tennessee--Nashville; Business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Industry--Tennessee--Nashville; Transportation industry--Tennessee--Nashville; Newspaper industry--Tennessee--Nashville; Railroad shops &amp; yards--Tennessee--Nashville; Railroad and locomotive industry--Tennessee--Nashville; Railroad employees; Railroad employees' unions--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Eleventh Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); McGavock Street (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>McCormac, D. B. (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1955-05-09</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives; Film negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BN 1955 - 1309</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/860</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>