<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Students give folk dance at Lockeland School, from the Nashville Times, 1940</dc:title>
<dc:description>A captioned photo from the Nashville Times (1940), about a student folk dance. The caption reads: &#8220;With Parent-Teacher Association groups everywhere observing Founders&#8217; Day at their February meetings, the local associations have cooperated by presenting special programs to commemorate the founding of the organization on February 17, 1898. At Lockeland School an attractive part of the P.T.A. Founders&#8217; Day program was folk dancing by a group of students. Folk dancing is being taught at the school to provide exercise for the students during the bad weather. Children pictured from left to right are: Katherine Dinkins, Barbara Anderson, Betty Jean Haley, Willene Bone, Mary Peeler, Mary Ann Oliphant, Mary Ann Allen, Walter Morgan, Ewing Collier, Billy Fuson, Orin Williams, Philip Meade, Bob McElroy, and France Tice.&#8221; Forms part of the Nashville Times newspaper collection. 1 digital photo.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Lockeland Elementary School (Nashville, Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>School children--Tennessee--Nashville; Arts in education--Tennessee--Nashville; Elementary schools--Tennessee--Nashville; Entertainment events--Tennessee--Nashville; Dance--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1940</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>LockelandSchoolDane--NT-1940</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Times Newspaper Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4249</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>