<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Aerial photograph of North Nashville, ca. 1968.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Aerial photograph of North Nashville in the Buena Vista neighborhood, looking southwest, circa 1968, taken by Metro Photographer, William M. King. Photograph shows a wooded residential area. Streets identified in the photo include Buchanan St., Jane St., and Wheless St. along with 9th Ave. North, 11th Ave. North, and Arthur Avenue. Streets visible in the image but not marked are 10th Ave. North in between 9th Ave. North and Arthur Ave.; and a second section of Jane St. intersecting with 9th Ave. in the lower left hand corner, indicated by the First Evangelical United Brethren Church on the corner.  A small part of Jones School is visible as the first building on the bottom right, below 9th Avenue where it intersects with Buchanan. Wharton School is the large elongated building at the top center, where Wheless St. ends at the intersection of 18th Ave. North, which is not visible. Forms part of the Nashville Room Historic Photographs Collection. 1 photograph : b &amp; w ; 8 x 10 in.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Interstate 265 would pass near this location when it was built between 1968 and 1971. In 2000, Interstate 265 ceased to exist, and was redesignated as part of Interstate 65.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Wharton School (Nashville, Tenn.); Jones School (Nashville, Tenn.); First Evangelical United Brethren Church (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Capitol City; Transportation; Express highways--Tennessee--Nashville; Roads--Design and construction--Tennessee--Nashville; Roads--Design and construction--Aerial photographs; Neighborhoods--Tennessee--Nashville; Streets--Tennessee--Nashville; Housing--Tennessee--Nashville; City planning--Tennessee--Nashville; Transportation--Tennessee--Nashville; African American neighborhoods--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--20th century; Nashville (Tenn.)--Aerial photographs; Jane Street (Nashville, Tenn.); Buchanan Street (Nashville, Tenn.); Wheless Street (Nashville, Tenn.); Arthur Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Ninth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Tenth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Eleventh Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>King, William M. (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1968</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>p-0017 &#8211; Nash aerial, interstate area</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Historic Photographs Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969; 1970-1979</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/12501</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>