<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Mid-state business women meet here, from the Nashville Times, 1940</dc:title>
<dc:description>A captioned photo from the Nashville Times (1940), about a semi-annual meeting of the Middle Tennessee District of the Tennessee Federation of Business and Professional Women&#8217;s Clubs. They gathered in Nashville and &#8220;among those at the speakers&#8217; table were, left to right, above: Miss Sallie Duncan, Nashville; Miss Carolyn Akin, Franklin; Miss Mildred Hearne, Lebanon; Mrs. Edna Uffelmann, Clarksville; Mrs. Amelia Copenhaver, Bristol, president of the state organization; Mrs. Virginia MacKenzie Ritter, Nashville, director of the Middle Tennessee District; Mrs. Lula Holladay, Cookeville, first vice-president; Mrs. Gladys Bragg, Murfreesboro; Miss Mary Spiva Beasley, Nashville; Miss Olivia Short, Clarksville.&#8221; Forms part of the Nashville Times newspaper collection. 1 digital photo.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Tennessee Federation of Business and Professional Women&#8217;s Clubs</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Business--Tennessee, Middle--History--Sources;  Businesspeople--Tennessee, Middle; Women--Tennessee, Middle; Women--Societies and clubs</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Tennessee, Middle--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1940</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BusinesswomensMeeting--NT-1940</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Times Newspaper Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4207</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>