<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>New viaduct, Church Street, Nashville, Tenn., between 1915 and 1930</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard of the Church Street viaduct right after completion between 1915 and 1930.  This structure was built to carry car traffic over the railroad tracks.  A new viaduct was built to replace this one in the 1990s.  Forms part of the Norton Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Transportation; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Bridges--Tennessee--Nashville; Streets--Tennessee--Nashville; Automobiles--Tennessee--Nashville; Transportation--Tennessee--Nashville; Viaducts--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Church Street (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>E.C. Kropp Co. (Publisher)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>between 1915 and 1930</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Norton - 0217</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Norton Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1910-1919; 1920-1929; 1930-1939</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1810</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>