<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Athenaeum Rectory, Maury County, Tennessee, 1978 May</dc:title>
<dc:description>An exterior view of the Athenaeum Rectory in Columbia, Tennessee, located at 808 Athenaeum Street.  The Athenaeum Rectory was begun circa 1835 as a residence for Samuel Polk Walker, nephew of President James K. Polk.  This historic building features both Gothic and Moorish architectural elements; it was designed by Adolphus Heiman and built by master builder of Maury County Nathan Vaught.  The Franklin Gillette Smith family lived in the Rectory for three generations from 1838-1973. Reverend Mr. Franklin Gillette Smith was a graduate of Princeton University.  He came with his family to Tennessee to be president of the Columbia Female Institute, an Episcopal school for girls.  The Columbia Athenaeum was located to the south of the home.  The Athenaeum School was a group of buildings that was built on the back lot of the Rectory.  The two buildings that remain have since been associated with the Athenaeum name.  In 1851, he resigned from the Institute to found The Columbia Athenaeum School and the Smith family home continued to be the Athenaeum Rectory.  The Columbia Athenaeum was in operation for 52 years and developed a national reputation for its quality and breadth of curriculum.  After The Reverend Mr. and Mrs. Smiths' deaths, the Athenaeum was operated by the son, Captain Robert Davis Smith, until 1904. The property was sold by the Smith heirs, and the school became the high school until 1914. In 1915, a high school was built by the City of Columbia on the property. The rectory was retained by the Smith family members as their residence until 1973, when it was given to the Association for the Preservation of Tennessee Antiquities for the use of the people of Maury County by Franklin Gillette Smith's grand-daughter, Fannie Louise Smith Davis of Lamesa, Texas.  Forms part of the Claynita Harris Slide Collection.  The original is a 35 mm color transparency (2 x 2 in. slide mount) </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Architecture--Tennessee--Maury County; Buildings--Tennessee--Columbia; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Maury County </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Columbia (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Maury County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Columbia (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Columbia (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1978-07</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives </dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Harris Photo            512 Athenaeum Rectory Maury Co July78</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Claynita Harris Slide Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1970-1979</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/7071</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>