<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Dedication First Tennessee Infantry Memorial, Percy Warner Park, Nashville, Tennessee, 1937 April </dc:title>
<dc:description>A WPA program pamphlet of the official commemoration ceremony and dedication of the First Tennessee Infantry Memorial held at Percy Warner Park on Sunday, April 25th, 1937.  The Master of Ceremonies for the dedication program was Col. Harry S. Berry, Colonel 1st Tennessee Infantry and 115th Field Artillery, with Tennessee Governor Gordon Browning and other dignitaries participating in the ceremony.  A brief history of the &#8220;First Tennessee&#8221; by Col. Harry S. Berry, Regimental Commander is published in the pamphlet.  The Memorial to the Dead of the First Tennessee Infantry was erected as a Works Progress Administration Project.  Forms part of the Ophelia Payne Collection, 1 pamphlet.  </dc:description>
<dc:subject>World War, 1914-1918--Monuments; World War, 1914-1918--Tennessee--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library 

</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1937</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Ophelia Payne Coll Nash history First Tenn Infantry Memorial 001</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Ophelia Payne Collection - Nashville History Papers</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/9603</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>