<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>State capitol, Nashville, Tenn., circa 1907</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard of the Tennessee State Capitol and landscaped grounds along the hillside overlooking the city of Nashville, bordered by Charlotte and Sixth Avenue, with the equestrian statue of Andrew Jackson on the right. The Greek Revival building was designed by Philadelphia architect William Strickland and constructed over a period of ten years from 1845 to 1855. The architect died a year before the building's completion and is entombed in its northeast wall. Forms part of the Nashville Room Postcards Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5 x 5.5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Tennessee State Capitol (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Capital City; Architecture; Buildings; Downtown Nashville; Capitals (cities)--Tennessee; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Public buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Equestrian statues--Tennessee--Nashville;  Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Capitols--Tennessee--Nashville; Government facilities--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Sixth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Charlotte Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville (Tenn)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Adolph Selige Publishing Co. (Publisher)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1907</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/tiff (20 MB)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Nash-18-State Capitol, Nashville</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1900-1909</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/507</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>