<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Frances Garrett of Lebanon, Tennessee serving in Saudi Arabia with the Tennessee National Guard, circa 1990 November 15</dc:title>
<dc:description>A close-up photograph of Frances Garrett of Lebanon, Tennessee, wearing a desert camouflage "boonie" hat, mirrored sunglasses, and a scarf tied about her neck. She is a soldier in the Tennessee National Guard, serving in Saudi Arabia during the buildup of American troops during Operation Desert Shield. The photograph was taken by Nashville Banner photographer Larry McCormack on assignment in Saudi Arabia in November 1990. Forms part of the Nashville Banner Archives. 1 photograph transparency : col ; 35mm.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Garrett, Frances</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Tennessee. National Guard; Tennessee. Military Dept.; United States. National Guard Bureau; Tennessee. Army National Guard</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Military History; Persian Gulf War; Operation Desert Shield, 1990-1991; Persian Gulf War, 1991--Women; Women soldiers; Soldiers--Tennessee--Lebanon; African American soldiers; Camouflage (Military science)--United States; Military personnel--American--Tennessee--Lebanon; Women; Clothing &amp; dress; Hats; Military life--American; Military service--United States</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Saudi Arabia--History--20th century--Sources; Saudi Arabia--Military relations--United States; United States--Military relations--Saudi Arabia; Lebanon (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Wilson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Tennessee--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>McCormack, Larry (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1990-11-15</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Transparencies; Film transparencies</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BT 1990-2105-40</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1990-1999</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1647</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>