<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Nashville Public Library staff, circa 1942 January 14</dc:title>
<dc:description>This photograph of Librarian F. K. W. Drury and staff of the Nashville Public Library, Main (originally named the Carnegie Library of Nashville) appeared in the Nashville Banner 14 January 1942 issue illustrating the article "Library Completes 40 Years." Pictured front row, left to right: Miss Bertha Vanderford, Miss Ruth Horn, Mrs. Marcelle Workman, Mr. F. K. W. Drury, librarian, and Mrs. Virginia Mitchell. Back row, left to right: Mrs. Richard Williams (Betty Williams), Mr. Liston Lewis, Miss Bettye Bell, Mrs. Marion Latimer (Martha H. Latimer), Mrs. Laurence Benson (Margaret Benson), Miss Flavel Wilkin, Mrs. J. I. Brown (Lillie H. Brown), Miss Ann Hester Fox, Miss Sara Andrews, and Mrs. Lee Witcher (Esther G. Witcher). The article states: "Misses Felicia Porter and Elizabeth May were not present when picture was made." Drury was educated at Rutgers and the University of Illinois. He came to Nashville to serve as Carnegie Librarian in 1931, a position he held until his retirement in 1946. Forms part of the Nashville Room Historic Photographs Collection. 1 photograph : b &amp; w ; 8 x 10 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Drury, Francis K. W. (Francis Keese Wynkoop), 1878-1954; Lewis, Meriwether Liston; Vanderford, Bertha; Horn, Ruth; Workman, Marcelle; Mitchell, Virginia; Williams, Betty; Bell, Bettye; Latimer, Martha H.; Benson, Margaret; Wilkin, Flavel; Brown, Lillie H.; Fox, Ann Hester; Andrews, Sara; Witcher, Esther G.; Porter, Felicia; May, Elizabeth</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Public Library of Nashville and Davidson County--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Libraries; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Popular Culture; Librarians--Tennessee--Nashville; Public librarians--Tennessee--Nashville; Library employees--Tennessee--Nashville; Carnegie libraries--Tennessee--Nashville; Interiors--Tennessee--Nashville; Social &amp; civic facilities--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1942-01-14</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>P-2242</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Historic Photographs Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/2246</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>