<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Victory Needles, 1943</dc:title>
<dc:description>During the years of World War II it was considered your patriotic duty to sacrifice and make do with what you had. There was rationing in food, gas and even fabrics for clothing. One of the ways women could help with the war effort was to be frugal with their clothing. Taking an old item and making it new was all the rage during these years.  This pamphlet was produced by the American Thread Company as a guide to help the home seamstress remake her old clothing into up-to-date fashionable garments.  Forms part of the Veterans History Project. 1 pamphlet : col. 8.5 x 11 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>American Thread Company</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Military History; Women; World War II; Home Front; Popular Culture; War; Women--History--Sources; World War, 1939-1945--War work; World War, 1939-1945--Social aspects; World War, 1935-1945--Women; Sewing; Needlework; Clothing and dress--Alteration; Clothing and dress-- Remaking; Fashion--United States--History--20th Century--Sources; Fashion--United States--Periodicals; Sewing--American</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social conditions</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>American Thread Company</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Dodson, Melvin C., 1920-2006 (Collector)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1943</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Ephemera; Pamphlets</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>VHP-WWII-Dodson-F5-Victory Needles</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Veterans History Project Collection, World War II Series, Melvin Dodson Papers</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1221</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>