<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of Vine Street Temple, Nashville, Tennessee, 1954 May 27</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of the Vine Street Temple (Congregation Ohabai Shalom) which was located at 136 Seventh Avenue North (Vine Street became Seventh Avenue in 1904), Nashville, Tennessee. The Byzantine style building had nine domes and was dedicated on 27 May 1876. It was Nashville's first synagogue and home to its Jewish reform congregations for eighty years.  After the congregation moved to Harding Road, one of the domes was struck by lightning, and it was sold and demolished in 1955. Forms part of the Nashville Banner Archives.  1 photograph : b &amp; w ; 8 x 10 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Congregation Ohabai Sholom (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Synagogues--Tennessee--Nashville; Domes--Tennessee--Nashville; Decoration and ornament, Architectural--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville Religious facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Temples--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Seventh Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Vine Street (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Gunter, Jack (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1954-05-27</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/tiff</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BP-Nash-Churches-Vine St. Temple</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/465</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>