<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Tennessee State Fair Grounds, Nashville, Tenn., circa 1910</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard of the Tennessee State Fairgrounds showing the Women's Building, Grandstand, and track.  Located just one mile south of downtown Nashville, the fairgrounds opened in 1891 as Cumberland Park.  The park was built as a harness racing track with a grandstand that seated 7,000 people.  In 1904 the harness racing track hosted its first automobile race.  Then in 1906 the first Tennessee State Fair was held.  Over the years the fairgrounds has been host to nighttime airplane rides, a swimming pool, an amusement park, and stock car races, among other things.  In 1965 a fire at the fairgrounds destroyed several buildings (including the Women's Building pictured here), the grandstands and numerous restaurants.  Today the fairgrounds is used for various conferences, expos, and trade shows, along with the annual Tennessee State Fair.  Forms part of the Nashville Room Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Tennessee State Fairgrounds (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Enterprise; Industries; Business; Sports &amp; Recreation; Parks; Popular Culture; Entertainment; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Parks--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic parks--Tennessee--Nashville; Horse sports--Tennessee--Nashville; Racing--Tennessee--Nashville; Racetracks (Automobile racing)--Tennessee--Nashville; Sports facilities; Fairs--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Grandstands--Tennessee--Nashville; Racetracks--Tennessee--Nashville; Sports &amp; recreation facilities--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville, Tenn.--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Recreational activities</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1910</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Nash-42b-Tennessee State Fair Grounds, Nashville. Tenn.</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1910-1919</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/761</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>