<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Tarbox School in Nashville, Tennessee, circa 1932</dc:title>
<dc:description>A Real Photo postcard of the Tarbox School, originally belonging to Sara Webb, a student who was in the fifth or sixth grade around 1932. This view shows the front exterior of the three-story school building prior to the structural damage caused by the April 1, 1932 fire. Tarbox School was one of Nashville's most respected public grammar schools that originally opened in 1880 in a one-story frame house on 17th Avenue between Hayes Street and West End Avenue. In 1886, the school expanded to an impressive three-story brick school with a multi-story clock and bell tower, built at 1803 Broadway. The school was named for Luther G. Tarbox, a Hume-Fogg High School principal and George B. Elliot served as the first principal in the new building. The school served a large neighborhood and accommodated more than 1,000 students. On April 1, 1932, a fire destroyed the tower and front of the school building. Everyone was safely evacuated from the building without a single injury. The building was rebuilt with only two stories instead of three. The school closed in 1960 and was subsequently razed circa 1964 except for the 1929 addition that was renovated to house the Knowles Senior Center. Forms part of the Nashville Room Historic Photographs Collection. 1 Real Photo postcard : sepia ; 3.5 x 5.5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Tarbox School (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Schools; Education; Elementary Schools; Children's History; Schools--Tennessee--Nashville; Public schools--Tennessee--Nashville; Towers--Tennessee--Nashville; Bell towers--Tennessee--Nashville; Clock towers--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Broadway (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Wiles (Photographer); Webb, Sara (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1932</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>P-1313</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Historic Photographs Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/2266</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>