<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Diary of Flex Rains Drake, January 1896 - December 1896</dc:title>
<dc:description>A twenty-eight page typescript diary of Flex Rains Drake, spanning the year 1896.  The topics include agricultural farm work, livestock, weather, herbal medicine, the Nashville Hay Market, family relatives, neighbors and religious revivals.  He describes a fish feast and music &#8220;from banjo played by George Pascall,&#8221; while living in Middle Tennessee.  Another section of his diary discusses &#8220;bumming&#8221; rides on trains to the mid-west and into the west.  Topics include Pueblo Indians, New Mexico, adobe houses, hoboes travelling via train, and seeking work through hiring agents to work at saw mills and other hard labor jobs.   Forms part of the Doug Drake Collection.  1 typescript.   </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Drake family; Dozier family; Scott, Henry; Pascall, George; Stump, Tom</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Agriculture--Tennessee, Middle; Crops--Tennessee, Middle; Livestock--Tennessee, Middle; Tramps--United States; Rogues and vagabonds--United States</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library 

</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1896</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Typescript; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DougDrakeColl f Flex Rains Drake Diary of 1896 001 - 028.  </dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Doug Drake Collection  </dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1890-1899</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/9632</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>