<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Lawrence Avenue Church of Christ, 2001 December</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of Lawrence Avenue Church of Christ located at 904 Lawrence Avenue in Nashville, Tennessee.  The church building was constructed in approximately 1912 as the Lawrence Avenue Christian Church, and has seen many different congregations over the years.  The church's current congregation was founded in 1906.  Initially meeting on Horton Street in South Nashville, they were forced to relocate in the late 1940s due to the building of the nearby housing project complex on Twelfth Avenue South (Edgehill Homes).  In the early 1950s the congregation ultimately purchased the Lawrence Avenue building from the now Concord Avenue Church of Christ congregation.  The purchase included the educational building next door, and in 1994 construction began to connect the two buildings.  In 1997 the connection project was finished and the two buildings were joined.  The foundation is made of rough cut stone blocks that have been painted white.  The exterior walls are brick that have been painted red.  The roof is gabled and hipped with tar shingles.  The windows are colored glass and frosted glass.  The doors are made of wood and metal.  Forms part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project. 1 photograph : col. ; 4  x 6  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Lawrence Avenue Church of Christ (Nashville, Tenn.); Lawrence Avenue Christian Church (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Popular Culture; Religion; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Religious facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Church architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Churches of Christ--Tennessee--Nashville; Brick churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Columns--Tennessee--Nashville; Gables--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Details; Churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs; Lawrence Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2001-12</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>SSSP - Lawrence Ave CoC</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1092</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>