<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Colemere Club dinner with entertainer Tommy Sands, Nashville, Tennessee, 1958</dc:title>
<dc:description>A scene from a dinner at the Colemere Club with entertainer Tommy Sands, circa 1958.  Thomas Adrian "Tommy" Sands, a popular teen idol of circa 1950s - 1960s, became an overnight sensation when he appeared on the Kraft Television Theater in January 1957 as &#8220;The Singin&#8217; Idol,&#8221; and his song &#8220;Teen Age Crush&#8221; reached No. 2 Billboard&#8217;s Hot 100 and No. 1 on Cashbox.  In 1960 he married Nancy Sinatra and for a time they were the toast of Hollywood until their divorce in 1965.  Sands also performed in several films including &#8220;Mardi Gras&#8221; in 1959, &#8220;Babes in Toyland&#8221; in 1961, &#8220;The Longest Day&#8221; in 1962, &#8220;Ensign Pulver&#8221; in 1964, and &#8220;None But the Brave,&#8221; in 1965.  The music genres Sands performed, besides pop music, included Country, Countrypolitan, Pop Music, and Rockabilly.  Sands&#8217; pioneering contribution to the genre of Rockabilly has been recognized by the Rockabilly Hall of Fame.   Forms part of Record Group 3, Metro Davidson County Photographer. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Sands, Tommy, 1937-</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Colemere Club (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Government executives--Tennessee--Nashville; Men--Societies and clubs; Entertainers--United States; Entertainment--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1958</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 3 5257 Tommy Sands Colemere Club Dinner in 1958 005</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3 Metro Davidson County Photographer</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/6427</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>