<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Excerpt 1 from oral history interview with Beverly Briley,  1980 April 16</dc:title>
<dc:description>An excerpt from an oral history interview with former Nashville Mayor Beverly Briley, conducted May 1980 by Paul Clements as part of the Century III Nashville:  Nashville Heritage Project.  Briley, who was Mayor of Nashville from 1963 to 1975 and was the first mayor after the consolidation of the city and county government, discusses what Nashville would be like in 1980 if the city and county governments had not consolidated to form the Metropolitan Government of Nashville and Davidson County (Metro).  The complete interview, as well as a transcript, is available in the repository.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Briley, Beverly, 1914-1980--Interviews</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Capital City; City Government; Consolidation; County Government; Politics; Metropolitan Government; Metropolitan areas--Tennessee--Nashville; Mayors--Tennessee--Nashville; Urbanization--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--Politics and government--20th century; Nashville (Tenn.)--Economic conditions; Tennessee--Capital and capitol; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Briley, Beverly, 1914-1980 (Interviewee); Clements, Paul, 1947- (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1980-05</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound.Interview</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3 (1.40 MB; 1 min., 32 sec.)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CentIIIBriley9aclip1</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from:  CentIIIBriley audio cassette recordings converted to mp3 format in 2006.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Century III Nashville: Nashville Heritage Project : oral history</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1980-1989</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content. This image is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/202</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>