<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Third Baptist Church, (Hopewell Baptist Church)</dc:title>
<dc:description>Third Baptist Church was organized in 1876.  In 1877 the membership erected a building on a Jefferson Street site given to the congregation by First Baptist Church.  In 1899 the congregation purchased a lot on Monroe Street and in 1904, using brick from the old building on Jefferson Street, built a new church.  In 1959 the members moved to a new location on Buena Vista Road.  The building on Monroe Street was sold to the Hopewell Baptist congregation, and the Hopewell Missionary Baptist Church on Monroe Street began meeting in the building in June of 1960 under the leadership of Pastor James Tolbert Ridley.  Hopewell Baptist was organized in 1914 and was located for many years at Grant St. and 12th Ave. North.  The church building was listed in the National Register of Historic Places in November of 1979. 3 x 5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Third Baptist Church; Hopewell Baptist Church</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Churches</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.); Monroe Street; Buena Vista Road</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:type>Negative</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CDM 067; RG3 527</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1942 - 1980</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/155</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>