<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of the Sam Davis Hotel, Nashville, Tennessee, being demolished, 1985 February 16</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of the Sam Davis Hotel being imploded on 16 February 1985.  It was located at 132 Seventh Avenue North and corner of Commerce Street, Nashville, Tennessee. In about 15 seconds the explosives sent the 56-year-old hotel down into its basement. The 12-story, 250-room hotel named for Sam Davis, the Confederate hero, opened on Friday, 23 December 1927. The hotel's slogan during the depression was "A room and a bath for three and a half." It was demolished to make way for Nashville's Downtown Convention Center. Forms part of the Nashville Banner Archives. 1 - 35 mm black &amp; white photograph negative.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Sam Davis Hotel (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Business; Tourism; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville; Hotels--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Seventh Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Commerce Street (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Goodman, Bill (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1985-02-16</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/tiff</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BN-1985-614-8</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1980-1989</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/462</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>