<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Atlas of the city of Nashville 1908. [Plate 01B ]</dc:title>
<dc:description>1 map; 58 x 75 cm. A plat map of downtown Nashville, Tennessee, originally published in 1908 by G. M. Hopkins Company, showing the various buildings, landscapes, acreage, and street routes for several blocks in each direction from the County Jail. Several original building structures are depicted on the map, such as the Davidson County Court House, Old City Hall and Market House, Brandon Printing Company, Police Station, John Hauck Brewing Company, Duncan Hotel, Church of the Holy Family, Odd Fellows Hall, National Baptist Publishing Board; Swift's Nashville Beef and Provision Company, Nashville Railway &amp; Light Electric Power House, L &amp; N Terminal Company, City Work House, Red Fox Shoe Factory, Hayden Building, Davidson County Court House, Bijou Theatre, and the Vanderbilt University Law Department.  This plat map is reproduced from the source: Atlas of the city of Nashville, Tennessee : from official records, private plans and actual surveys, G. M. Hopkins, [Philadelphia, Pa.] 1908.  Scale 100 feet to an inch. The original dimensions of the map, in the atlas publication: 15 &#189; x 22 &#190; in. (i.e. 58 x 75 cm.)</dc:description>
<dc:subject>American Bread Company (Nashville, Tenn.); Louisville and Nashville Railroad Company; Odd Fellows Hall (Nashville, Tenn.); Church of the Holy Family (Nashville, Tenn.); Red Fox Shoe Factory (Nashville, Tenn.); National Baptist Publishing Board; Swift's Nashville Beef and Provision Company; Nashville Railway &amp; Light Company (Nashville, Tenn.); Bijou Theatre (Nashville, Tenn.); Duncan Hotel (Nashville, Tenn.); Vanderbilt University. Law Dept.; Union Bank and Trust Company (Nashville, Tenn.); City Hall (Nashville, Tenn.); Davidson County Court House (Nashville, Tenn.); Brandon Printing Company (Nashville, Tenn.); Fidelity Trust and Safety Vault Company (Nashville, Tenn.); John Hauk Brewing Company (Nashville, Tenn.); City Work House (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville Railway and Light Electric Power House (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Education; Colleges and Universities; Business; Industries; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Public Utilities; Transportation; Printing/Publishing; Police--Tennessee--Nashville--Maps; Real property--Tennessee--Nashville--Maps; Neighborhood--Tennessee--Nashville--Maps; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville--Maps; Transportation--Tennessee--Nashville--Maps; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville--Maps; Railroads--Tennessee--Nashville--Maps; Bridges--Tennessee--Nashville--Maps; Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville--Maps;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Maps; Tennessee--Maps; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--Maps; Cumberland River (Ky. and Tenn.)-- Maps</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Hopkins, Griffith Morgan (Publisher)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1908</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Maps; Plat books</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>NPM 1908 - Plate 1B</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Atlas of the city of Nashville, Tennessee : from official records, private plans and actual surveys, G. M. Hopkins, [Philadelphia, Pa.] 1908.</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1900-1909</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/912</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>