<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>The K. Gardner Building, Nashville, Tennessee, circa 1947</dc:title>
<dc:description>A color postcard of The K. Gardner Building (formerly Masonic Temple) located at 419 - 421 Fourth Avenue North in downtown Nashville, Tennessee, circa 1947. The verso of the postcard states that &#8220;located in this building are some of the finest medical clinics, x-ray, specialists, dentists, attorneys, photographers, beauticians, spacious dining room 4th floor, club rooms and dance hall on the 5th floor and balcony.&#8221;  An inset picture of K. Gardner is on the postcard, with an exterior view of the building.  Forms part of the Ridley Wills II Nashville Postcards Collection.  1 postcard.  </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Gardner, Kossie, d. 1990; Wills, Ridley, 1934-</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>K. Gardner Building (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Fourth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Ridley Wills II (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1947</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RidleyWillsPostcards Box 2 474 K Gardner Building</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Ridley Wills II Nashville Postcards Collection  </dc:relation>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/9326</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>