<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Front hall of the Hermitage, circa 1930</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard featuring the front entry hall of the Hermitage, home of General Andrew Jackson, seventh President of the United States.  The wallpaper represents the legend of the travels of Telemachus, a figure in Greek mythology, and was imported by Jackson in 1835.  Also pictured is a circular staircase leading up to the second level.  Forms part of the Norton Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845--Homes and haunts--Tennessee--Hermitage</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Hermitage (Hermitage, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Buildings; Architecture; Popular Culture; Tourism; Postcards--Tennessee--Hermitage; Buildings--Tennessee--Hermitage; Architecture--Tennessee--Hermitage; Corridors--Tennessee--Hermitage; Mansions--Tennessee--Hermitage; Architecture--Details; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Hermitage; Dwellings--Tennessee--Hermitage; Entrance halls--Tennessee--Hermitage; Wallpaper--Tennessee--Hermitage; Staircases--Tennessee--Hermitage; Interior decoration--Tennessee--Hermitage; Historic house museums--Tennessee--Hermitage; Houses--Tennessee--Hermitage; Interiors--Tennessee--Hermitage; Wallpapers; Chandeliers</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Hermitage (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Hermitage (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Wiles (Publisher)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1930</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Norton - 0290</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Norton Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1812</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>