<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Christmas carol chairman and son, circa 1940 December 04</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of Mrs. Miller G. Kimbrough, chairman for the Fannie Battle Day Home Christmas Eve carol choirs, seen with her son, Miller, Jr., who is having "visions of sugar plums" as his mother reads "The Night Before Christmas."  This photograph illustrated the newspaper article "Fannie Battle Workers Make Plans for Carol Singing: Chairmen for Christmas Eve Choirs Named," published in the 4 December 1940 issue of the Nashville Banner.  Forms part of the Fannie Battle Day Home Records. 1 photograph :  b &amp; w ; 9 x 7 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Kimbrough, Miller G., Mrs.; Kimbrough, Miller G., b. ca. 1939</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Fannie Battle Day Home; Fannie Battle Social Workers</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Capital City; Organizations; Popular Culture; Children's History; Women in charitable work--Tennessee--Nashville; Charity--Tennessee--Nashville; Charities--Tennessee--Nashville; Day care centers--Tennessee--Nashville; Altruism--Tennessee--Nashville; Benevolence--Tennessee--Nashville; Social work with children--Tennessee--Nashville; Women--Charities; Child welfare; Holidays--Tennessee--Nashville; Books and reading--Tennessee--Nashville; Reading (Early childhood)--Tennessee--Nashville; Holidays--Tennessee--Nashville; Charitable organizations--Tennessee--Nashville; Community service--Tennessee--Nashville; Economic &amp; social conditions--Tennessee--Nashville; Christmas decorations</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Davidson County (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1940-12-04</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>FBDHR-SB-Carol Publicity-1940-B1, f8</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Fannie Battle Day Home Records</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1909</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>