<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Capers Memorial Christian Methodist Episcopal (C.M.E.) Church, 2002 November</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of the Capers Memorial Christian Methodist Episcopal (C.M.E.) Church located at 319 Fifteenth Avenue North, Nashville, Tennessee.  This building was built in 1925 by the nation's first African-American-owned architectural firm, McKissack and McKissack.  It is a two-story Neo-Classical brick structure featuring a sheet metal pediment on the main facade supported by four stone Doric pilasters.  The congregation has a rich history, whose forebears worshipped as Christian slaves in a brick house near the Sulphur Spring as early as 1832.  Capers was a mission of McKendree Methodist Church located downtown.  McKendree helped the congregation build this first church.  Leading this African Mission was William Capers, a South Carolina slave owner who became a Methodist bishop.  As pastor to the slaves, he was considered the slaves' most sympathetic spokesman.  In 1853 when the church moved from Sulphur Springs to a new building on Eleventh Avenue North, the church was officially named for Bishop Capers.  In 1887 the Capers Church moved to a new building at 1111 Church Street until 1925, when it moved to its present site, 319 Fifteenth Avenue North.  The present church has a concrete foundation.  The exterior walls are red brick with stone accents.  The roof is gabled.  The windows are stained glass, tall, arched, and covered by plexiglass.  Frosted glass windows line the basement level.  The doors use both metal and glass materials.  In 1985 Capers Memorial C.M.E. Church was added to the National Register of Historic Places.  Forms part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project. 1 photograph : col. ; 4  x 6  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Capers Memorial Christian Methodist Episcopal Church (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Popular Culture; Religion; Capital City; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Religious facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Church architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; African American churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Brick churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Protestant church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Methodist church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Episcopal church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Methodist churches-- Tennessee -- Nashville; Episcopal churches--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs; Fifteenth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2002-11</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>SSSP - Capers Memorial</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/736</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>