<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Glimpses of Nashville, Tennessee: Confederate Monument </dc:title>
<dc:description>The Confederate Monument in the center of Confederate Circle at the Mt. Olivet Cemetery, located at 1101 Lebanon Pike, Nashville, Tennessee, circa 1904.  It was erected in 1892 by the Ladies&#8217; Memorial Association. This granite obelisk is topped with a nine-foot statue of a Confederate soldier.  According to the Tennessee Historical Marker: &#8220;After the War Between the States, the women of Nashville bought land at Mount Olivet, and formed Confederate Circle.  The remains of about 1,500 Confederate soldiers were moved here from area battlefields.  Seven Confederate generals were buried in or around the circle.  They are William B. Bate, William N. R. Bealle, Benjamin Franklin Cheatham, William H. Jackson, George E. Maney, James E. Rains, and Thomas Benton Smith.  Other prominent Nashville Confederates, Colonels Adolphus Heiman and Randall McGavock, lie nearby.  A 45-foot granite monument marks the center of the circle.&#8221;  Forms part of Glimpses of Nashville. 1 booklet </dc:description>
<dc:subject>	
Mount Olivet Cemetery (Nashville, Tenn.)
</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Statues--Tennessee--Nashville; Cemeteries--Tennessee--Nashville; Veterans--Tennessee--Nashville; Soldiers--Tennessee--History--Sources; War memorials--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Tennessee--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Sources </dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Manx, Chicago </dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1900s</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Glimpses of Nashville Book051 Confederate Monument</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Glimpses of Nashville, Tennessee booklet   </dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1900-1909</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/7755</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>