<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>The Stage Coach of General Andrew Jackson, between 1930 and 1945</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard of the Stage Coach of General Andrew Jackson, Seventh President of the United States. The vehicle is pictured next to the old Smoke House at The Hermitage, home of President Jackson, located 12 miles east of downtown Nashville. The Jackson family carriage was a horse-drawn vehicle that was purchased while Jackson was president. The trip from the Hermitage into Nashville would have taken approximately an hour and a half. Forms part of the Nashville Room Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845--Homes and haunts--Tennessee--Hermitage</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Hermitage (Hermitage, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Transportation; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Stagecoaches--Tennessee--Nashville; Carriages &amp; coaches--Tennessee--Nashville; Smokehouses--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Hermitage (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Hermitage (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Wiles Photographers (Publisher)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>between 1930 and 1945</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Nash - 192</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939; 1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/2270</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>