<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>King Temple Church of God in Christ, 2001 November</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of King Temple Church of God in Christ.  The survey indicates that this church is located at 1301 Lischey Avenue in Nashville, Tennessee; however, all city directories list the address as being 1310 Lischey Avenue.  The cornerstone indicates that the building was built in 1910 under the name Lischey Avenue Church of Christ.  In 1983 the name changed to Twelve Robes Baptist Church, before changing once again in 1988 to its current name, King Temple Church of God in Christ.  The foundation is made of rough cut stone blocks.  The exterior front walls are made of rough cut stone blocks, while the side walls consist of red brick and the back walls are concrete block.  The roof is both gabled and hipped with tar shingles.  The windows are composed of colored glass and are arched on the side walls.  The doors are metal with glass windows.  Forms part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project. 1 photograph : col. ; 4  x 6  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Lischey Avenue Church of Christ (Nashville, Tenn.); Twelve Robes Baptist Church (Nashville, Tenn.); King Temple Church of God in Christ (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Popular Culture; Religion; Downtown Nashville; Capital City; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Religious facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Church architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Churches of Christ--Tennessee--Nashville; Baptist church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Baptist churches--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs; Lischey Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2001-11</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>SSSP - King Temple</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1084</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>