<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Nashville Then and Now, 1780-1930 by Maude Weidner, Hermitage Publishing Company, 1930 </dc:title>
<dc:description>&#8220;Nashville Then and Now, 1780-1930,&#8221; by Maude Weidner (Mrs. Maude Weidner Jessen) was published in Nashville, Hermitage Publishing Co., 1930.  This pamphlet provides a selection of significant phases of the history of Nashville, the development of the city spanning 1780-1930.  The subject areas are: The Spirit of the pioneer--Such was the beginning--The good boat Adventure--Before the settlers came--Nashboro--The Cumberland Compact--Nashboro and Davidson County--The Courthouse--First mill--First road laid off--Difficulties in early life, Indian invasions--The darkest clouds--Romance of roadways--The settlement grows--The Natchez Trace--Contemporary records of early Nashville--The art of living--The colleges and universities--The public schools--After the school came the library--The romance of the printed page: newspapers--Nashville printing center of South--Nashville as an historic community--Indian battle sites--First marriage here--Original land grant--When Tennessee was part of North Carolina--Lasting as the pyramids--Battlefield of Nashville markers--The Maxwell House--The State Capitol--The Parthenon--The Hermitage, shrine of the Nation--Nashville as an economic center: transportation--Commercial activity as it was--Work of the civic clubs--A glimpse of Nashville yesterday, dramatic episodes--The &#8216;Why&#8217; of the &#8220;Athens of the South&#8221;--Nashville, 1780-1930--And tomorrow?--What do we know about your eyes?--The Southern school of printing--Through the ages, cleanliness has chartered the path of Civilization--A famous dessert of a famous hostess--The romance of the fresh milk industry.  This pamphlet consists of 85 pages, illustrations, portraits, and advertising included in the paging.  The business advertisements include, but are not limited to: Nashville Bridge Company, Burrus Filling Station, Ambrose Printing Company, Methodist Publishing House, Vanderbilt University School of Nursing, Scarritt College for Christian Workers, National Life and Accident Insurance Company, Ward-Belmont, Holsum Bread, Sterchi Bros. Stores, Inc., Nashville Gas &amp; Heating Company, Union Ice Cream, Upchurch Mattress Company, Period Furniture Company, Superior Baking Company, Tennessee College for Women, Betty-Lou Bread and Cake, Jacobs Packing Company, Nashville Pure Milk Company, Dixie Life &amp; Accident Insurance Company, Ira Lamb &amp; Sons, Antrim&#8217;s Ice Cream, American Dry Cleaners Tasty Potato Chips, Taylor Roofing Company, Edward Rehorn &amp; Son, Mrs. A. Letty Funeral Home, Woodlawn Memorial Park, Nashville Automobile Club, Winn &amp; Campion Grocery Co., Mount Olivet Cemetery, Bradford&#8217;s Furniture, Shield Life Insurance, Fisk University, Jersey Farms Milk Service, Green Vale Milk Company, Fred B. Cassetty Coal Co., Life &amp; Casualty Insurance Co., Julius Jacob &#8220;A Department Store,&#8221; Wiles Commercial Photographers, Smotherman Drug. Co., Hermitage Printing Co., Baptist Sunday School Board, Marshall &amp; Bruce Co., Tennessee Products Corporation, and Keith Hardware Stores.  Forms part of the James H. Kilgore Collection-Publications.  1 pamphlet.  </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Kilgore family; Kilgore, James H., 1919-2014; Jessen, Maude Weidner </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Pioneers--Cumberland River (Ky. and Tenn.); Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Pioneers--Tennessee; Pioneers--Tennessee, Middle; Frontier and pioneer life; Tennessee, Middle-History; Tennessee, Middle--Genealogy; Tennessee--History; Advertising--Tennessee, Middle; Business enterprises--Tennessee, Middle </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Cumberland River (Ky. and Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Kilgore, Fay (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1930</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Kilgore coll publications NVL Then and Now 1930 001 - 090</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>James H. Kilgore Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/7856</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>