<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Meharry Medical College, Harold D. West Basic Science Center, Nashville, Tennessee, circa 1976</dc:title>
<dc:description>Eleven construction site photographs of the Harold D. West Basic Science Center building, Meharry Medical College, circa 1976.  The architects were McKissack &amp; McKissack, with the building construction by the Hardaway Construction Company.  The Design Consultants were Curtis &amp; Davis; and Mechanical and Electrical Engineers: L.C. Thomasson &amp; Associates.  This campus building, located at 1023 21st Ave. N, opened in December 1976 and is named in honor of Meharry&#8217;s first African-American president, Harold Dadford West, Ph.D.   Forms part of the Metro Archives Photographs - Buildings Collection. 11 b &amp; w photographs.  </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Meharry Medical College. Harold D. West Basic Science Center--History--Sources; Meharry Medical College--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Universities and colleges--Tennessee--Nashville; African American universities and colleges--Tennessee--Nashville </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1976</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>MetroArchivesPhotos-Bldgs Meharry Med College 001 - 011</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Metro Archives Photographs, Buildings Collection </dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1970-1979</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/8607</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>