<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Gordon Memorial United Methodist Church, 2001 May</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of Gordon Memorial United Methodist Church, historically located at 2336 Herman Street in Nashville, Tennessee.  The current city directory lists the address as 2334 Herman Street.  With the congregation originally founded in 1903, this present building was built in 1931 under the name Gordon A.M.E. Church.  The foundation is made of rough cut stone blocks.  The exterior walls are red brick.  The roof gabled and composed of tar shingles.  The windows are a combination of colored glass and clear glass.  The front facade displays stained glass windows.  The doors are metal.  At the time of this survey, renovations were underway for a large new building to be added as an addition to the complex.  Forms part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project. 1 photograph : col. ; 4  x 6  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Gordon Memorial United Methodist Church (Nashville, Tenn.); Gordon African Methodist Episcopal Church (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Popular Culture; Religion; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Religious facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Church architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Methodist church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Brick churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Columns--Tennessee--Nashville; Gables--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Details--Tennessee--Nashville; Protestant church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; African American churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville; Methodist churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Protestant churches--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs; Herman Street (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2001-05</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>SSSP - Gordon Memorial United Methodist Church</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1041</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>