<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Captain Eddie Rickenbacker at Berry Field, Nashville, Tennessee, 1950 June</dc:title>
<dc:description>Three unidentified men at Berry Field anticipating the welcome of Captain Eddie Rickenbacker to Nashville, Tennessee, circa June 1950.  The famous aviator was met at the airport by city officials, the media, and admiring fans upon his arrival via an Eastern Airlines jet.  Edward &#8220;Eddie&#8221; Vernon Rickenbacker was an American fighter ace in World War I and Medal of Honor recipient.  Rickenbacker became General Manager of Eastern Airlines circa 1933, and in 1938, with a group of investors, bought the company and became its president, managing the enterprise profitably for twenty years.  Forms part of Record Group 3, Metro Davidson County Photographer. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rickenbacker, Eddie, 1890-1973</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Eastern Air Lines; Metropolitan Nashville Airport Authority--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Airports--Tennessee--Nashville--History; Commerce--Tennessee--Nashville; Airlines--Tennessee--Nashville; Airways--Tennessee--Nashville; Celebrities; Air pilots--United States; Aeronautics--United States</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1950-06</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 3 5200 Capt Eddie Rickenbacker at Berry Field June 1950 006</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3 Metro Davidson County Photographer</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/6381</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>