<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Parkway Towers, Nashville, Tennessee, circa 1968</dc:title>
<dc:description>Parkway Towers, a high-rise office building located at 404 James Robertson Parkway, in downtown Nashville, Tennessee, circa 1968.  Construction of the building was completed in 1968, the building height 261 ft. with 21 floors above ground.  There is a Commerce Union Bank sign in front of the building.  The structure was designed in a modernist style.  Forms part of Record Group 3. The original is a 35 mm color transparency (2 x 2 in. slide mount).</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Parkway Towers (Nashville, Tenn.); Commerce Union Bank (Nashville, Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Office buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Tall buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Skyscrapers--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; James Robertson Parkway (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1968</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Slide 593 Parkway Towers</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/5844</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>