<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Excerpt 6 from oral history interview with James Stephen Turner, 2006 June 21</dc:title>
<dc:description>An excerpt from an oral history interview with Nashville business and civic leader James Stephen (Steve) Turner, conducted on 21 June 2006 by Andrea Blackman as part of the Nashville Public Library's Nashville Business Leaders Oral History Project:  The Turner Interviews.  Turner discusses the fact that much of his involvement has been in the arts because he believes that people can better relate to one another as human beings through the arts.  The complete interview, as well as an index, is available in the repository.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Turner, James Stephen--Interviews</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Performing Arts; Popular Culture; Entertainment; Performing arts--Tennessee--Nashville; Arts--Tennessee--Nashville; Businesspeople--Tennessee--Nashville; Civic leaders--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Description and travel; Nashville (Tenn.)--Intellectual life</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Turner, James Stephen (Interviewee); Blackman, Andrea (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2006-06-21</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3 (578 KB; 37 sec.)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>NBLTurner1019clip2</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from:  NBLTurner digital recording converted from wav to mp3 format in 2006.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Business Leaders Oral History Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/495</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>