<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Marian Anderson Contralto, 1932</dc:title>
<dc:description>A program for a recital by Marian Anderson on February 5, 1932, at the Ryman Auditorium, located on Fifth Avenue North in downtown Nashville.  Marian Anderson was an African American contralto, most remembered for her performance on Easter Sunday, 1939 on the steps of the Lincoln Memorial in Washington, D.C.  In 1955 she became the first African American member of the Metropolitan Opera in New York City.  Forms part of the Naff Collection. 1 program : col. ; 6 x 9 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Anderson, Marian, 1897-1993</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Ryman Auditorium (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Performing Arts; Music; Popular Culture; Entertainment; Music; Downtown Nashville; Performances--Tennessee--Nashville; Performing arts--Tennessee--Nashville; Concerts--Tennessee--Nashville; Music--Tennessee--Nashville; Musicians; Singing--Tennessee--Nashville; Contraltos--United States; Concert programs--Tennessee--Nashville; African American singers; Women singers; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Entertainers--Tennessee--Nashville; Entertainment--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Fifth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Robinson, Francis, 1910- (Donor); Naff, Lula C., 1875-1960 (Collector)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1932</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text; Ephemera; Programs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Naff 2-2 Marian Anderson</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Naff Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/829</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>