<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Victory Memorial Bridge, Governor Clement signs bridge bill at State Capitol, Nashville, Tennessee, 1953 April</dc:title>
<dc:description>Pictured: Tennessee Governor Clement signing the bridge bill with the Davidson County delegation at the State Capitol, circa April, 1953.  Victory Memorial Bridge connects the public square and the central business district, on the western side of the Cumberland River, to Main Street in East Nashville.  M. S. Poteat&#8217;s firm was contracted to building the bridge approaches, as well as the bridge substructure.  For the final phase, the superstructure and decking, the contract went to the Nashville Bridge Company.  State engineer Roy Higgs was in charge of the project.  The Victory Memorial Bridge originated in part from a 1948 public movement to recognize Nashville and Davidson County military soldier casualties from World War II; officials later favored a joint memorial including Korean war names.  Constructed of 1,900 feet of modern steel in stone, it officially opened May 19, 1956, with Mayor Ben West cutting the ribbon and reading a poem titled &#8220;The Bridge Builder&#8221; by local poet Miss Will Allen Dromgoole.  Victory Memorial Bridge formally opened May 19, 1956, as a special feature of the Armed Forces Day parade and celebration Forms part of Record Group 3, Metro Davidson County Photographer. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Clement, Frank Goad</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Bridge Company--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Bridges--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Rivers--Tennessee--Nashville; Bridges--Design and construction--Tennessee--Nashville; Engineering--Tennessee--Nashville; Transportation--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Cumberland River (Ky. and Tenn.); Victory Memorial Bridge (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1953-04</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 3 234 Bridges 001</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/5700</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>