<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Marion Jenkins, Sharon Parrish, and Brenda Wynn remember their mother, 2007 September 15</dc:title>
<dc:description>An edited excerpt with transcript and photograph from an interview with Marion R. Jenkins and Sharon Y. Parrish, conducted on 15 September 2007 by their sister, Brenda P. Wynn, at the Nashville StoryCorps StoryBooth, located in the Nashville Room of the Nashville Public Library.  The sisters share memories of their mother, Rosa L. Parrish, who died in 2006.  This was the first interview conducted in the Nashville StoryCorps StoryBooth.  The complete, un-edited interview, as well as an index, is available in the Special Collections Division.  These interviews were recorded by StoryCorps at the Nashville Public Library with the support of the Nashville Public Library Foundation and are provided courtesy of StoryCorps, a national initiative of Sound Portraits Productions to record and collect oral history interviews.  www.storycorps.net</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Jenkins, Marion R., 1954- --Interviews; Parrish, Sharon Y., 1955- --Interviews; Parrish, Rosa Lee, 1938-2006</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Popular Culture; African Americans; Women; Storytelling--Tennessee--Nashville; Family--Folklore--Tennessee--Nashville; African American families--Tennessee--Nashville; African American women--Tennessee--Nashville; Women--Tennessee--Nashville; Family--Tennessee--Nashville; Mothers--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social conditions</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Jenkins, Marion R., 1954- (Interviewee); Parrish, Sharon Y., 1955- (Interviewee); Wynn, Brenda P., 1956- (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>StoryCorps (Project)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>2007-09-15</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3 (1 min., 31 sec.)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>NPL000001_excerpt; NPL000001_g1; NPL000001_transcript</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from:  NPL1000001 original StoryCorps interview edited by interns Claire Ploegman and Jessica Harrell in November 2007.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville StoryCorps StoryBooth Interviews 2007-2008</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1266</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>