<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Construction crews work on street car tracks on Fifth Avenue North, between 1910 and 1914</dc:title>
<dc:description>Photograph of men working on street car tracks on Fifth Avenue North looking north between the intersections of Church and Union Streets. Crews are using steam-operated cement mixers and shovels. Visible businesses include Model laundry and dry cleaning, Alhambra Theatre, Skalowski's ice cream parlor and candy store, The Cue, Elite Theatre, Walk-Over, S.H. Kress &amp; Co., and Beckett Value. Forms part of the Nashville Room Historic Photographs Collection. 1 photograph : b &amp; w ; 8 x 10 in.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The proposed street car route down Fifth Avenue initially met opposition from business owners who claimed the street was one of the few thoroughfares downtown that remained unobstructed by street car traffic and accessible for convenient travel.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Capital City; Transportation; Downtown Nashville; Labor; Laborers--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Street-railroads--Tennessee--Nashville; Streets--Tennessee--Nashville; Construction--Tennessee--Nashville; Transportation industry--Tennessee--Nashville;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Fifth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville (Tenn.)--History--20th century;</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>Between 1910-1914</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>P-1735</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Historic Photographs Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1910-1919</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/13049</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>