<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Otey's Center, 1964</dc:title>
<dc:description>A calendar from 1964 advertising Otey's Center, which included a supermarket, launderette, shoe shop, and a realty company.  Flem B. Otey headed the Otey Enterprises firm which was comprised of the various operations highlighted on the calendar.  Located at 1801 Jefferson Street, Otey's Grocery was the first African American-owned grocery firm in Nashville.  Originally, a small business known as Green's Grocery occupied the Jefferson site.  Otey assumed direction of this small store and developed the business into the large Cee-Bee affiliate, Otey's Grocery.  Photos of Green's Grocery are also shown on the calendar.  Forms part of the Businesses Ephemera Subject Files. 1 calendar : col. ; 14  x 10.75  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Green, I.E., 1880-1894; Otey, Flem B., 1903-1963</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Otey's Center (Nashville, Tenn.); Green's Grocery (Nashville, Tenn.); Otey's Quality Grocery (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Business; Capital City; African Americans; Downtown Nashville; Food; Enterprise; Industries; Shopping; Advertisements; Grocery shopping--Tennessee--Nashville; Grocery trade--Tennessee--Nashville; Self-service laundries--Tennessee--Nashville; Supermarkets--Tennessee--Nashville; Business--Tennessee--Nashville; Business enterprises--Tennessee--Nashville; African American business enterprises--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Calendars--Tennessee--Nashville; Businesspeople--Tennessee--Nashville; Real property--Tennessee--Nashville; Advertising--Grocery trade--Tennessee--Nashville; Advertising--Real estate business--Tennessee--Nashville; Business districts--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Commerce; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Jefferson Street (Nashville, Tenn.); Eighteenth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Otey's Center (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1964</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Ephemera; Calendars</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>ESF - Bus - Otey's Center</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Ephemera Subject Files</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1964</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/825</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>