<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Cumberland River and Shelby Street Bridge, c.1980s</dc:title>
<dc:description>Photograph of the Shelby Street Bridge over the Cumberland River, with the General Jackson Showboat underneath, circa 1980s. The Nashville Bridge Company building is visible on the left. Completed in 1909 and spanning the Cumberland River to link East Nashville to the downtown area, the Shelby Street Bridge was considered very innovative, with concrete trusses making a new underneath support system. Originally known as the Sparkman Street Bridge, it is now known as the John Seigenthaler Pedestrian Bridge. The bridge was added to the National Register of Historic Places in 1986, and it was later reopened after extensive renovations as a pedestrian walkway in 2003. Photographed by the Nashville Housing Authority. Forms part of the MDHA Photograph Collection. 1 photograph : b &amp; w. </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Nashville Housing Authority (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville Bridge Company;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Bridges--Tennessee--Nashville; Bridges, Truss--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Rivers--Tennessee--Nashville; Pedestrian bridges--Tennessee--Nashville; Boats--Tennessee--Nashville; Showboats;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.); Cumberland River (Ky. and Tenn.); Sparkman Street Bridge (Nashville, Tenn.); Shelby Street Bridge (Nashville, Tenn.); John Seigenthaler Pedestrian Bridge (Nashville, Tenn.)--History--Sources;</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Nashville Housing Authority/Metropolitan Development and Housing Agency</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>c.1980s</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photograph</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>MDHA Photos Box 11 Fol 6 Cumberland River and Shelby St Bridge nd 001</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>MDHA Photograph Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1980-1989</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>	
U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/13216</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>