<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of buildings on the north side of the Public Square in Nashville, Tennessee, 1959</dc:title>
<dc:description>Harris-Davis and Company, J. L. Turner and Son, J. S. Reeves and Company, and D. F. Siler Company were among the buildings that once delineated the outer perimeter of the public square in Nashville. The square, with the county courthouse, city hall and market center, was a focus of wholesale commerce and political activity for the city for many years. The old city hall, dating from the 1850s, was replaced by a new city hall and courthouse in 1937. Most of the remaining buildings were destroyed in the 1970s as part of urban renewal projects. These buildings, located at 206-216 Public Square North, formed part of the north side of the square, running west from 2nd Avenue North. Among them are the last of the perimeter buildings to be demolished. The Reeves Building, 208-210 Public Square North, is believed to have been constructed in the late 1850s. It was built by Samuel D. Morgan to as a home to his wholesale dry goods business. Iron cores were used in the columns of the building. J. S. Reeves purchased the building, which became the home of his dry goods business until 1964. It, along with the buildings to the left of it in the picture, was demolished in 1975. The building located at 206 Public Square North, occupied by D. F. Siler Company in the picture, had a cornerstone that dated it to 1882 and it once housed the Sunday School Union of the African Methodist Episcopal Church. In the late1970s it was home to The Judges Chambers, a restaurant frequented by attorneys and city government officials, and was the last of these buildings to be demolished. It was razed in 1981 when the entire block became the building site of the Metro Criminal Justice Center. Photographed by the Nashville architect Charles Wesley Warterfield, Jr. (1926-1998); the architectural photograph forms part of the Charles Warterfield Architectural Collection. Gift of: The Estate of Charles W. Warterfield, Jr., F. A. I. A. The original is a 35 mm color transparency (2 x 2 in. slide mount)</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Morgan, Samuel D.; Reeves, J. S.</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>D. F. Siler Company (Nashville, Tenn.); Harris-Davis and Company (Nashville, Tenn.); J. L. Turner and Son (Nashville, Tenn.); Reeves Building (Nashville, Tenn.); Morgan Building (Nashville, Tenn.); The Judges Chambers (Nashville, Tenn.); African Methodist Episcopal Church (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Business; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Popular Culture; Shopping; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architects--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Streets--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Commercial buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Urban renewal--Tennessee--Nashville--History; Law--Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville--History; Cornerstones--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Windows--Tennessee--Nashville; Streets--Tennessee--Nashville; Business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Sidewalks--Tennessee--Nashville; Roofs--Tennessee--Nashville; Signs (Notices)--Tennessee--Nashville; Arches--Tennessee--Nashville; Automobiles--Tennessee--Nashville; Parking--Tennessee--Nashville; Plazas--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Public Square (Nashville, Tenn.)--History; Court House Square (Nashville, Tenn.)--History</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Warterfield, Charles W. (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Estate of Charles W. Warterfield, Jr., F. A. I. A. (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1959</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still image; Slides; Architectural photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>WSC 3912</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Charles Warterfield Architectural Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/61</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>