<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Glimpses of Nashville, Tennessee: High Street, from Union, looking north </dc:title>
<dc:description>A street view of High Street (Sixth Avenue N) looking north from Union in downtown Nashville, Tennessee. There are several horse-drawn vehicles driving on the road.  The building that became the Elks Lodge No. 72 is the second building pictured on the right, with a high spire and tall chimney. The lodge was home to the Elks, beginning in 1904, serving numerous community functions and charity projects for the next several decades.  The exact date of the construction of the Elks Lodge is unknown although it appears as a dwelling on the 1888 fire insurance maps.  There are several horse-drawn vehicles on the road.  Forms part of Glimpses of Nashville. 1 booklet </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Elks (Fraternal order). Lodge No. 72 (Nashville, Tenn.)--History--Sources </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Statues--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Streets-Tennessee--Nashville; Transportation--Tennessee--Nashville </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; High Street (Nashville, Tenn.); Sixth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Manx, Chicago </dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1900s</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Glimpses of Nashville Book043 High Street from Union looking North</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Glimpses of Nashville, Tennessee booklet   </dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1900-1909</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/7747</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>