<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Spanish War daughters feted, from the Nashville Times, 1940</dc:title>
<dc:description>A captioned photo from the Nashville Times (1940), about a banquet related to Spanish-American War veterans. The caption reads: &#8220;As a preliminary event for today&#8217;s reunion of Spanish-American War veterans, the above group of Spanish Daughters were given a banquet last night at Shacklett&#8217;s Cafeteria. Reading, left to right above, are Olleen Greer, Margaret Whetstone, Ann Elizabeth Long, Mary Cravens, of Memphis, Norma Dunn, Ethylin Murphy, Tillie Howard, Elsie? H. Newell, Cliffie May Kinnard, Mildred Chumbley, Frances Garrett, Eunice Caldwell, Helen Craver, Mrs. Margaret Whetstone, Esther Murphy, and Arizona Greer.&#8221; Forms part of the Nashville Times newspaper collection. 1 digital photo.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Spanish-American War Veterans--History--Sources; Schacklett&#8217;s Cafeteria (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Patriotism--Tennessee--Nashville; Cafeterias--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1940</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>1940 group2 093</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Times Newspaper Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4242</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>