<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Katherine Polk Gale, between 1898 and 1916</dc:title>
<dc:description>A portrait photograph of Katherine Polk Gale (1838-1916), the author of "Recollections of Life in the Southern Confederacy, 1861-1865." Katherine was a daughter of Episcopalian Bishop Leonidas Polk, a Confederate general in the American Civil War and a second cousin of President James K. Polk. She was the wife of William Dudley Gale, a staff officer in the Confederate Army. Mrs. Katherine Polk Gale was very active in Christ Church Cathedral, Nashville. She was a leader in the work of the Woman's Auxiliary and at one time the Diocesan President. 1 photograph : sepia ; 5 x 7 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Polk family; Gale family; Gale, Katherine Polk, 1838-1916</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Religion; Authors--Tennessee--Nashville; Family--Tennessee--social life and customs; Episcopalian women--Tennessee--Nashville; Women--Tennessee--Nashville; Portrait photographs--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>between 1898 and 1916</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>P-0191</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Historic Photographs Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1890-1899; 1900-1909</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/2271</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>