<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of school registration, Glenn Elementary School, Cleveland Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 1957 August 27</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of Harold D. Street enrolling his daughter, Lajuanda (girl looking at camera) and Mary Griffith enrolling her daughter, Jacqueline (girl looking to the right) at Glenn Elementary School, Nashville, Tennessee, 27 August 1957. Enrollment came under a court-approved plan, which called for desegregation of the first grade level, three years after the Brown v. Board of Education decision. This photograph documents the desegregation of public schools in Nashville, Tennessee and implementation of the Nashville Plan, a plan to desegregate one grade per year starting with the first grade. Forms part of the Nashville Banner Archives. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 3.25 x 4.25 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Street, Harold D.; Harley, Lajuanda Street; Griffith, Mary; Griffith, Jacqueline</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Glenn Elementary School (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Civil Rights; African Americans; Race Relations; Education; Elementary Schools; Capital City; African Americans--Civil rights--Tennessee--Nashville; Civil rights movements--Tennessee--Nashville; African Americans--Segregation--Tennessee--Nashville; Segregation in education--Law and legislation--United States--History; Discrimination in education--Law and legislation--United States--History; School integration--United States; School children--Tennessee--Nashville; Schools--Tennessee--Nashville; Public schools--Tennessee--Nashville; Students--Tennessee--Nashville; School integration--Tennessee--Nashville; Education--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Race relations; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social conditions; Southern States--Race relations--History--20th century--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Ray, Bob (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1957-08-27</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/tiff (10.8 MB)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BN 1957-2217-n12</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/551</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>