<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Portrait of Mary Hannah Johnson Claxton in profile, ca. between  1900 and 1920</dc:title>
<dc:description>A young Mary Hannah Johnson, shown in profile view from the right side.  Her shoulders are bare and she is wearing a pearl choker.  A native of Nashville, Tennessee, and an active suffragist, Mary Hannah Johnson began and developed the free library system in Nashville and built cooperation with the public schools. She served as the first librarian at Nashville's Carnegie Library, from ca. 1904 to 1912.  In April 1912, Johnson married American educator Philander Priestly Claxton.   She died in Washington, DC, in 1955.  Oil on canvas, artist unknown.  The portrait is currently on display in the Nashville Room on the Nashville Public Library's second floor.  

The library's portraits were photographed as part of the National Society of The Colonial Dames of America in Tennessee's Tennessee Portrait Project (http://www.tnportraits.org/index.htm).  </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Claxton, Mary Johnson, 1879-1955--Portraits</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Popular Culture; Capital City; City Government; Portraits, American--20th century; Portraits--Tennessee--Nashville; Public librarians--Tennessee--Nashville; Librarians--Tennessee--Nashville; Suffragists--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>National Society of The Colonial Dames of America in Tennessee</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. between 1900 and 1920</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Portraits; Paintings</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>johnson-mary-head-lg</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Portrait Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1900-1909; 1910-1919; 1920-1929</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1861</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>