<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Sonja Henie receives key to City of Nashville, Tennessee, 1954 April</dc:title>
<dc:description>Celebrity figure skater and film actress Sonja Henie, with unidentified men at a hotel desk, during her visit to Nashville, circa April 1954.  Henie was presented a key to the City and also Honorary Citizenship of the City of Nashville.  Henie was a Norwegian figure skater and film star who won more Olympic and World titles than any other ladies figure skater (Olympic Champion: 1928, 1932, 1936; World Champion 1927-1936, and European Champion 1931-1936.  Henie became a very successful Hollywood movie star after signing a long term contract at Twentieth Century Fox circa 1936.  She became one of the wealthiest women in the world in her time through her film career, figure skating and ice shows, and lucrative endorsement contracts.  Forms part of Record Group 3, Metro Davidson County Photographer. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Henie, Sonja, 1912-1969</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Celebrities; Women figure skaters--Norway--History--Sources; Figure skaters--Norway--History--Sources; Motion picture actors and actresses; Women Olympic athletes--Norway--History--Sources; Civic leaders--Tennessee--Nashville; Politicians--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1954-04</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 3 4561 Sonja Henie key to city Apr1954 002</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3 Metro Davidson County Photographer</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/5836</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>