<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Trying to feed him with a bit in his mouth, between 1933 and 1936</dc:title>
<dc:description>
An original political cartoon drawing created by Jack Knox, the Nashville Banner editorial cartoonist from the mid-1940s to early 1970s.  This cartoon relates to President Franklin D. Roosevelt's New Deal strategy and governmental intervention in the form of American farm subsidies.  When Roosevelt became president in 1933, he supported the Agricultural Adjustment Act, which dealt with the problem of oversupply in the market by paying farmers not to produce to maximum capacity.  Depicted in the cartoon is an angry horse ("U.S. Farmer") that is choking on a bit ("subsidy plan").  A man holds a bucket in one hand ("His necessary sustenance") while holding the reins in the other ("New Deal Domination and Regimentation").  Forms part of the Jack Knox Political Cartoon Collection. 1 original cartoon drawing : b &amp; w ; 16.25 x 24 in. </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945--Caricatures and cartoons</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Capital City; Politics; Business; Popular Culture; Political cartoons--United States--20th century; Agricultural subsidies--United States--Caricatures and cartoons; Agriculture--Economic aspects--United States--Caricatures and cartoons; Farmers--United States--Economic conditions--Caricatures and cartoons; Agriculture and state--United States--Caricatures and cartoons; Family farms--Government policy--United States--Caricatures and cartoons; Cartoonists; Politics &amp; government--United States; Economic &amp; political systems; Farmers--United States</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>United States--Politics and government--20th century--Caricatures and cartoons</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Knox, Jack, 1910- (Cartoonist)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Knox, Joseph T. (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>between 1933 and 1936</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Caricatures; Cartoons (Commentary); Editorial cartoons</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Knox NPL-313</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Jack Knox Political Cartoon Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/884</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>