<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Nashville Electric Service building, 1952 September</dc:title>
<dc:description>Exterior views of the Nashville Electric Service (NES) building, September 1952.  The architectural design includes a large dome on top of the building.  The Nashville City Directory (1954) cites Leonard Sisk, Genl. Mgr., at 1200-98 Church Street at 13th Avenue N 3.  NES is one of the largest public electric utilities in the nation, founded in 1939 when the Tennessee Valley Authority purchased the assets of the Tennessee Electric Power Co. and the newly created Nashville Electric Service was established.  Forms part of Record Group 3, Metro Davidson County Photographer. 2 photograph negatives : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Nashville Electric Service</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Electric utilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Electric power--Tennessee--Nashville; Public utilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Business enterprises--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Church Street (Nashville, Tenn.); Thirteenth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1952-09</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 3 1303 NES Bldg 001 - 002</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3 Metro Davidson County Photographer</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4648</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>