<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Historian Dr. Merle R. Eppse and Tennessee Agricultural &amp; Industrial State University Student Group with Nashville Mayor Ben West at City Hall, 1954 February</dc:title>
<dc:description>Historian Dr. Merle R. Eppse, pictured with a Tennessee Agricultural &amp; Industrial State University Student Group in Mayor Ben West&#8217;s office at City Hall, Nashville, Tennessee, circa February 1954.  Mayor West is pictured holding an ink pen and a document or proclamation.  Dr. Eppse, a distinguished historian, taught history and geography at Tennessee A &amp; I (the school was later renamed Tennessee State University in 1968).  Forms part of Record Group 3, Metro Davidson County Photographer. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>West, Ben, 1911-1974; Eppse, Merl R. (Merl Raymond), 1893-</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Tennessee Agricultural and Industrial State University--Students--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African Americans; College students--Tennessee--Nashville; Universities and colleges--Tennessee--Nashville; Mayors--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--Politics and government; Southern States--Race relations--History--20th century--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1954-02</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 3 4331 Dr Merl R Eppse &amp; A&amp;I group in MayorOffice Feb 1954 003</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3 Metro Davidson County Photographer</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/6420</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>