<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Minnie Pearl with Jim Perkins and others at Zibart&#8217;s Book Store, 1954 January</dc:title>
<dc:description>A scene from Minnie Pearl&#8217;s book signing, hosted at Zibart&#8217;s Book Store, circa January 1954.  Sarah Ophelia Colley Cannon, known professionally as Minnie Pearl, was an American country comedian who appeared at the Grand Ole Opry for more than 50 years and on the television show Hee Haw from 1969 to 1991. The book signing event featured Minnie Pearl autographing copies of her book &#8220;Minnie Pearl&#8217;s Diary,&#8221; self-published in 1953. The Zibart Brothers Bookstore was owned and ran by Carl Zibart and his brother, Alan, located at 719 Church Street in downtown Nashville.   1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Minnie Pearl</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Zibart&#8217;s Books (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Celebrities; Bookstores--Tennessee--Nashville; Entertainment events--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Church Street (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1954-01</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 3 4067 Minnie Pearl et al @ Zibart's Book Store Jan1954 006</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3 Metro Davidson County Photographer</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/6369</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>