<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Wightman Chapel, Scarritt College for Christian Workers, Nashville, Tennessee, circa 1940s</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard of the Wightman Chapel on the campus of Scarritt College for Christian Workers in Nashville, Tennessee.  The Wightman Chapel, designed by architect Henry C. Hibbs in the Gothic Revial style, was built with Crab Orchard stone and completed in 1928.  It was part of the Belle Bennett Memorial which included Scarritt Hall, Bennett Hall, Wightman Chapel and the Tower, as well as the Susie Gray Dining Hall began in 1925.  The Wightman Chapel was named in honor of Maria Davies Wightman, the wife of Bishop William May Wightman.  Forms part of the Ridley Wills II Nashville Postcards Collection.  1 postcard.  </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Wills, Ridley, 1934-</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Wightman Chapel (Nashville, Tenn.); Scarritt College for Christian Workers--History--Sources; Scarritt Bennett Center--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Chapels--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc. </dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Wiles-Hood  </dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Ridley Wills II (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RidleyWillsPostcards Box 2 414 Wightman Chapel Scarritt College</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Ridley Wills II Nashville Postcards Collection  </dc:relation>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/9315</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>