<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Portrait of John Shelby, ca. 1840</dc:title>
<dc:description>John Shelby in his middle age, with dark hair and wearing a dark jacket and white shirt.  Born in 1786, John Shelby was a physician, a Postmaster, and a civic and church leader. He is said to have been the first child of European descent born in Sumner County.   Shelby married Anna Maria Minnick of Philadelphia in 1809.  He served as Hospital Surgeon under Andrew Jackson in Col. Edward Bradley's regiment during the Creek War.  He was wounded and lost an eye as a result.  After the war he returned to practice medicine in Sumner County and served as state Senator for Sumner County from 1815 to 1817.  Shelby moved from Sumner County to Nashville in 1817 and set up a medical partnership with his neighbor, Dr. Boyd McNairy.  He served as Postmaster of Nashville from 1849 to 1853.  Shelby played a role in the establishment of the short-lived Shelby Medical School in 1858.  He died in May 1859 and was interred at Nashville City Cemetery.  Oil on canvas, artist unknown.  Presented to the library in member of Shelby's great granddaughter Anna Williams Fassman by her daughter Shelby S. Cox.  
The portrait is currently on display in the Nashville Room on the Nashville Public Library's second floor.  

The library's portraits were photographed as part of the National Society of The Colonial Dames of America in Tennessee's Tennessee Portrait Project (http://www.tnportraits.org/index.htm).  </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Shelby, John, 1786-1859--Portraits</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Popular Culture; Education; Capital City; Portraits, American--19th century; Portraits--Tennessee--Nashville; Physicians--Tennessee--Nashville;  Physicians--Tennessee--Sumner County; State governments--Officials and employees; Veterans--Tennessee--Nashville; Creek War, 1813-1814--Veterans; Postmasters--Tennessee--Nashville; Educators--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Sumner County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>National Society of The Colonial Dames of America in Tennessee</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1840</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Portraits; Paintings</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>shelby-dr-john-lg</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Portrait Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1840-1849</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1865</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>