<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>The Three Stooges at Nashville Police Show in downtown Nashville, Tennessee, 1962 November 16</dc:title>
<dc:description>The Three Stooges (Moe, Curly-Joe, and Larry) seated on a motorcycle clowning around as part of a special entertainment event for policemen in a downtown Nashville, Tennessee venue on November 16, 1962.  The Three Stooges were taking &#8220;The Three Stooges Go Around the World in a Daze&#8221; to various opening throughout the country.  The Three Stooges were an American vaudeville and comedy act of the mid-20th century (1930-1975).  They were famous for their numerous short subject films in the style of physical farce and slapstick.  Forms part of Record Group 3, Metro Davidson County Photographer. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Three Stooges (Comedy team)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Police--Tennessee--Nashville; Comedians--United States; Celebrities; Actors--United States; Entertainers--United States</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1962-11-16</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 3 5436 Three Stooges at Police Show Nov16 1962 002</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3 Metro Davidson County Photographer</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/6395</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>