<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Oral history interview with John S. Bransford, Sr., 1980 July 09, excerpt 10</dc:title>
<dc:description>An excerpt from an oral history interview with Nashville investor John S. Bransford, Sr., conducted on 9 July 1980 by Leanne Thornton as part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. 1910-1935 Oral History Project.  Bransford discusses his family's ownership of one of the first two Dodges in Nashville. The complete interview, as well an index, is available in the Special Collections Division.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Bransford, John Sterling, 1906-1984--Interviews</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Business; Enterprise; Capital City; Transportation; Popular Culture; Businesspeople--Tennessee--Nashville; Capitalists and financiers--Tennessee--Nashville; Transportation--Tennessee--Nashville; Vehicles--Tennessee--Nashville; Automobiles; Automobile ownership; Dodge automobile</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Commerce; Nashville (Tenn.)--Economic conditions; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.; Bransford, John Sterling, 1906-1984 (Interviewee); Thornton, Leanne (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1980-07-09</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3 (21 sec.)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>HNIOHBransfordJbclip3</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from: HNIOHBransfordJ audio cassette recording converted to mp3 format in 2006.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. 1910-1935 Oral History Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1980-1989</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/808</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>