<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Tennessee State Fairgrounds, Nashville, Tennessee, 1958 September </dc:title>
<dc:description>People enjoying the Tennessee State Fair in Nashville, Tennessee, September, 1958.  The fairgrounds, located approx. one mile south of downtown Nashville, opened in 1891 as Cumberland Park. The park was built as a harness racing track with a grandstand that seated 7,000 people. In 1904 the harness racing track hosted its first automobile race. In 1906 the first Tennessee State Fair was held. Over the years, the fairgrounds have been host to nighttime airplane rides, a swimming pool, an amusement park, and stock car races, among other things. In 1965 a fire at the fairgrounds destroyed several buildings, the grandstands and numerous restaurants. Today the fairgrounds are used for various conferences, expos, and trade shows, along with the annual Tennessee State Fair. Forms part of Nashville Banner Negatives Collection.  1 photographic negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in. </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Tennessee State Fairgrounds (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville Banner</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Parks--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic parks--Tennessee--Nashville; Sports &amp; recreation facilities--Tennessee--Nashville </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Parks; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Recreational activities </dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Cooley, Vic (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1958-09-17</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Banner 1958-2673 Fair features Sept17 1958 Cooley 002</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Negatives Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/7645</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>