<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Old Hickory Church of Christ, 2001 February</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of Old Hickory Church of Christ located at 1001 Hadley Avenue in Old Hickory, Tennessee.  This church is situated in the heart of Historic Old Hickory Village.  According to the survey the building was constructed in 1940.  The foundation cement block that has been plastered.  The exterior walls are brick.  The roof is gabled.  Additions have been built onto the original structure.  Three arched windows on the front facade have been bricked in.  Forms part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project. 1 photograph : col. ; 4  x 6  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Old Hickory Church of Christ (Old Hickory, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Popular Culture; Religion; Architecture--Tennessee--Old Hickory; Buildings--Tennessee--Old Hickory; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Old Hickory; Church buildings--Tennessee--Old Hickory; Religious facilities--Tennessee--Old Hickory; Church architecture--Tennessee--Old Hickory; Brick churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Churches of Christ--Tennessee--Old Hickory; Gables--Tennessee--Old Hickory; Churches--Tennessee--Old Hickory; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Old Hickory</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Old Hickory (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Old Hickory (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Old Hickory (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs; Hadley Avenue (Old Hickory, Tenn.); Old Hickory Village (Old Hickory, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2001-02</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>SSSP - Old Hickory CoC</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1308</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>