<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>State capitol, Nashville, Tenn., circa 1920</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard of the Tennessee State Capitol and landscaped grounds along the hillside overlooking the city of Nashville, bordered by Charlotte and Sixth Avenue. The architectural idea is that of a Greek Ionic Temple. The Greek Revival building is made entirely of Tennessee material, and is fireproof. It was designed by Philadelphia architect William Strickland and constructed over a period of ten years from 1845 to 1855. The architect died a year before the building's completion and is entombed in its northeast wall.  This postcard is embossed and embellished with gold leafing.  Forms part of the Nashville Room Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Tennessee State Capitol (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Public buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Capitals (Cities)--Tennessee; Government facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville; Capitols--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Tennessee--Capital and capitol; Charlotte Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Sixth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1920</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Nash-24c-State Capitol, Nashville, Tenn.</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1920-1929</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/725</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>