<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Tobacco field near Nashville, Tenn., between 1901 and 1907</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard of a tobacco field near Nashville, Tennessee.  Two people's heads are visible among the plants, one wearing a white hat and one holding an umbrella and wearing a reddish hat.  Tobacco has always been a profitable crop for the state of Tennessee.  Forms part of the Nashville Room Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Enterprise; Industries; Business; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Agriculture--Tennessee--Nashville; Industries--Tennessee--Nashville; Tobacco--Tennessee--Nashville; Tobacco farms--Tennessee--Nashville; Tobacco industry--Tennessee--Nashville; Field crops--Tennessee--Nashville; Industry--Tennessee--Nashville; Tobacco plantations--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Economic conditions</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Owens Bros-Hillson Co. (Publisher)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>between 1901 and 1907</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Nash - 264 - Tobacco Field near Nashville, Tenn.</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1900-1909</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/918</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>