<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Oral history interview with Margaret Thompson, 1976 July 10, excerpt 01</dc:title>
<dc:description>An excerpt from an oral history interview with Margaret Thompson, conducted on 10 July 1976 by Ophelia Paine as part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. Tennessee Centennial Project.  Thompson describes visiting the Vanity Fair and Streets of Cairo sections at the Centennial and riding the Giant See-saw and the Shooting the Chute ride.  The complete interview is available in the Special Collections Division.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Thompson, Margaret Campbell Lipscomb, 1887-1979--Interviews</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Tennessee Centennial and International Exposition (1897 : Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Popular Culture; Exhibitions--Tennessee--Nashville; Amusements--Tennessee--Nashville; Amusement rides</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Tennessee--Centennial celebrations, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Tennessee--Exhibitions</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.; Thompson, Margaret Campbell Lipscomb, 1887-1979 (Interviewee); Paine, Ophelia (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1976-07-10</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3 (52 sec.)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>HNITCPThompsonaclip1</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from:  HNITCPThompson audio cassette recording converted to mp3 format in 2006.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Tennessee Centennial project: oral history</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1970-1979</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/966</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>