<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Bill of sale for Betty, an enslaved woman, and her two sons, in Williamson County, Tennessee, from Francis T. Reid to William Harrison, Jr., 1843 January 25</dc:title>
<dc:description>A bill of sale from Williamson County, Tennessee documenting the transfer of Betty, an enslaved woman,  about twenty one years of age, and her two children, Louis-Randolph about age four, and William Henry about twelve months old, from Francis T. Reid to William Harrison, Jr. for the sum of eight hundred dollars, dated Jan. 25, 1843. The document was witnessed by Lemuel B. McConnico, County Clerk of Williamson County, Tennessee.  The document was recorded by J.R. Hunter, Register, on Jan. 27, 1843.  Forms part of the Harrison House collection.  1 document : b &amp; w ; 20 x 20 cm.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Reid, Francis T.; Harrison, William, 1825-1889; McConnico, Lemuel B.; Hunter, J.R.; Reid family; Harrison family</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Harrison House (Franklin, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African Americans; Business; African Americans--Tennessee--Williamson County--Genealogy; African Americans--Tennessee--Franklin--Genealogy; Slave bills of sale--Tennessee--Williamson County; African Americans--Social conditions--19th century; African Americans--Tennessee, Middle--History--Sources; Slavery--Tennessee--Williamson County; Plantation owners--Tennessee--Franklin; Plantation owners--Tennessee--Williamson County; Economic &amp; political systems; Slavery--Tennessee--Franklin; Slaves--Tennessee--Franklin</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Williamson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Williamson County (Tenn.)--Social conditions--19th century</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1843-01-25</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>HHC - f2, front - slave bill 1843; HHC - f2, verso - slave bill 1843</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Harrison House Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1840-1849</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1125</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>