<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Saint Cecelia Academy diploma (photocopy) of Ann Louise Cashel, Nashville, Tennessee, 1922 June </dc:title>
<dc:description>A photocopy of a Saint Cecelia Academy diploma, certifying that &#8220;Annie Louise Cashel has completed in a satisfactory manner the Classical Course of study prescribed for this Institution and is entitled to receive this diploma.&#8221;  The document is dated June 1st, 1922, signed by school officials. Miss Cashel, according to the 1930 Census, was born abt 1905.  The names of her parents are: William Patrick Cashel and Katie (nee Moran) Cashel.  Saint Cecelia Academy was established in 1860 by the Dominican Sisters, the address for the original campus location was atop a hill at Eighth Avenue and Clay Street in North Nashville on the property known as Mount Vernon Gardens until the late 1950s (the school has since relocated to 4210 Harding Road). The academy was named for St. Cecilia, patroness of music. The original building in North Nashville is still used as a convent, the official Motherhouse of the Dominican Sisters (801 Dominican Drive). St. Cecilia's Academy is Nashville's oldest private high school.  Forms part of the John Lawrence Connelly Collection.  </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Cashel family; Cashel, Ann Louise </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>St. Cecilia's Academy (Nashville, Tenn.); Dominican Sisters of the Congregation of Saint Cecilia; Catholic Church--Education--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Catholic schools--Tennessee--Nashville--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1922-06</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>JohnConnellyColl Anne Louise Cashel folder 020</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>John Lawrence Connelly Collection </dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1920-1929</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/9293</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>