<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>West Nashville United Methodist Church, circa 2001</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of West Nashville United Methodist Church located at 4710 Charlotte Avenue in Nashville, Tennessee.  The congregation was organized as the West Side Mission around 1880.  Their first chapel was built under the name of Clifton Methodist Episcopal Church South at the corner of present day Delaware and Fortieth Avenues (then Clifton Pike).  In 1888 the congregation acquired a lot at the corner of Forty-eighth Avenue North and Charlotte Avenue where the West Nashville Methodist Church now stands.  The cornerstone for the new church was laid in August of 1888.  According to the survey, the current building was constructed in 1957 on the same property.  The original foundation is stone.  The exterior walls are red brick with wood panels on the front facade.  The roof is gabled and hipped with tar shingles.  Many of the windows are arched with a combination of clear glass and colored glass.  The doors are wood, glass and metal.  Forms part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project. 1 photograph : col. ; 4  x 6  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>West Nashville United Methodist Church (Nashville, Tenn.); Clifton Methodist Episcopal Church South (Nashville, Tenn.); West Side Mission (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Popular Culture; Religion; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Religious facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Church architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Methodist church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Brick churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Gables--Tennessee--Nashville; Arches--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Details; Churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Methodist churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs; Charlotte Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 2001</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>SSSP - W Nash UMC</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1559</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>