<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>St. Patrick Catholic Church, 2001 June</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of St. Patrick Catholic Church located at 1219 Second Avenue South in Nashville, Tennessee.  The church was built in 1890 to serve the mainly Irish neighborhood, and so was named after St. Patrick.  The red brick structure was constructed in the Second Empire Style, a style popular during the reign of France's Napoleon III.  Until 1954, the upper floor of the church was used for St. Patrick's School, which offered classes in first through eighth grade.  In 1998 the church was struck by lightning in the middle of a renovation project.  Renovations were eventually completed, and roof repairs were made.  The foundation is made of rough cut stone blocks, capped by finished stone blocks.  The exterior walls are red brick.  The roof is composed of slate shingles.  The windows are a combination of arched and rectangular.  The doors are metal and glass.  Other features include a tower with stone accents, a stained glass window over the entrance and a large cornerstone.  Forms part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project. 1 photograph : col. ; 4  x 6  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>St. Patrick Catholic Church (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Popular Culture; Religion; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Religious facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Church architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Catholic church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Brick churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Towers--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Details; Churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Catholic churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs; Second Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2001-06</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>SSSP - St Patricks Church</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1519</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>