<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Nashville, Tenn. Cumberland River, between 1901 and 1908</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard of the Cumberland River Wharf in downtown Nashville as seen from the Shelby Street Bridge.  Several boats are docked at the river bank.  A number of businesses line First Avenue.  Both the Woodland Street Bridge and the Jefferson Street Bridge are pictured in the distance.  Forms part of the Norton Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Business; Enterprise; Industries; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Transportation; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Wharves--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Rivers--Tennessee--Nashville; Transportation--Tennessee--Nashville; Boats and boating--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Business enterprises--Tennessee--Nashville; Bridges--Tennessee--Nashville; Truss bridges--Tennessee--Nashville; Business districts--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Cumberland River (Ky. and Tenn.)--Navigation; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Commerce; Jefferson Street Bridge (Nashville, Tenn.); Woodland Street Bridge (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>between 1901 and 1908</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Norton - 0027</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Norton Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1900-1909</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1765</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>