<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>John Q. Public Cab Stand, or Take Us to 1600 Pennsylvania Avenue, circa 1960</dc:title>
<dc:description>An original political cartoon created by Jack Knox, the Nashville Banner editorial cartoonist from the mid-1940s to the early 1970s.  Based on an original metal plate, this printed reproduction shows John F. Kennedy and Bobby Kennedy heading a group at the "John C. Public Cab Stand" with the caption "Take us to 1600 Pennsylvania Ave."  The entourage includes Chester Bowles, Walter Reuther, Adam Clayton Powell, Lyndon Johnson, Frank Sinatra and others.  Forms part of the Jack Knox Political Cartoon Collection. 1 printed reproduction : b &amp; w ; 12.5 x 14 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963--Caricatures and cartoons; Kennedy, Robert F., 1925-1968--Caricatures and cartoons; Bowles, Chester, 1901-1986--Caricatures and cartoons; Reuther, Walter, 1907-1970--Caricatures and cartoons; Powell, Adam Clayton, 1908-1972--Caricatures and cartoons; Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973--Caricatures and cartoons; Sinatra, Frank, 1915-1998--Caricatures and cartoons</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Banner</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Capital City; Politics; Popular Culture; Political cartoons--United States--20th century; Political cartoons--Tennessee--Nashville; Caricatures and cartoons--Tennessee--Nashville; Cartoonists--Tennessee--Nashville; Editorial cartoonists--Tennessee--Nashville; Presidents--United States--Election--1960--Caricatures and cartoons; Cartoonists; Politics &amp; government--United States--Washington, D.C.; Presidential transitions--United States; Democracy--United States; Economic &amp; political systems; Presidents--United States</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>United States--Politics and government--20th century--Caricatures and cartoons</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Knox, Jack, 1910- (Cartoonist)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Knox, Joseph T. (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1960</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Caricatures; Cartoons (Commentary); Editorial cartoons</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Knox NPL-252</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Jack Knox Political Cartoon Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/865</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>