<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Historic home typical of antebellum days, from the Nashville Times, 1940</dc:title>
<dc:description>A captioned photo from the Nashville Times (1940), of &#8220;The Crest,&#8221; historic home in Murfreesboro, Tennessee, circa June 22nd, 1940. The caption reads: &#8220;Embodying all the charm and culture of the Old South, the stately antebellum home of LeGrand H. and Catherine Lytle Carney, &#8220;The Crest,&#8221; is pictured above. This spacious mansion stood on the site now occupied by the S. F. Houston and W. E. Knox homes, and was the scene of &#8216;the most beautiful wedding celebration ever held in Murfreesboro,&#8217; the &#8216;infair&#8217; given in honor of the marriage of Maria Laura Butler and William Joseph Carney in 1856. It was at this home that 1,000 persons gatherered for this brilliant social event. A number of Nashvillians are grandchildren and great-grandchildren of the LeGrand Carneys. This historic old home was built on the green fields granted to Capt. William Lytle for his services during the Revolutionary War.&#8221; LeGrand Carney (1808-1884) was a successful merchant and landowner in Murfreesboro, Tennessee. Forms part of the Nashville Times newspaper collection. 1 digital photo.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Carney family; Carney, LeGrand, 1808-1884</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Buildings--Tennessee--Murfreesboro Historic buildings--Tennessee--Murfreesboro; Mansions--Tennessee--Murfreesboro</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Murfreesboro (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Murfreesboro (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Murfreesboro (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Rutherford County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1940</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:identifier>HistoricHomenowgoneTHECREST--NT-1940</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Times Newspaper Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4186</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>