<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Oral history interview with Nell Barnes, 1982 August 07, excerpt 03</dc:title>
<dc:description>An excerpt from an oral history interview with Nell Barnes, conducted on 7 August 1982 by Ophelia Paine as part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. 1910-1935 Oral History Project.  Barnes discusses attending the opening of the Hermitage Hotel in downtown Nashville and the fashions worn by the ladies in attendance.  The complete interview, as well an index, is available in the Special Collections Division.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Barnes, Nell (Nellie Marie Gardner), b. 1909--Interviews</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Hermitage Hotel (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Business; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Architecture; Buildings; Popular Culture; Business enterprises--Tennessee--Nashville; Hotels--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville;  Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Clothing and dress--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.; Barnes, Nell (Nellie Marie Gardner), b. 1909 (Interviewee); Paine, Ophelia (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1982-08-07</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3 (1 min., 18 sec.)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>HNIOHBarnesNaclip3</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from:  HNIOHBarnesN audio cassette recording converted to mp3 format in 2006.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. 1910-1935 Oral History Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1980-1989</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/794</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>