<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Richard Nixon visits Nashville during campaign, 1952 September 27</dc:title>
<dc:description>Vice-presidential candidate Richard Nixon and wife Patricia visited Nashville during his campaign rally and public address at Memorial Square in downtown Nashville on September 27, 1952.  Nixon was Dwight D. Eisenhower&#8217;s running mate, as the vice-presidential candidate. Only a few days before his arrival in Nashville, Nixon had appeared on television to publicly deny improper use of funds in the famous &#8220;Checkers&#8221; speech televised on September 23rd.  The Republican Eisenhower-Nixon ticket defeated the Democratic ticket of Adlai Stevenson II and John Sparkman.  Nixon became vice-president on January 20, 1953.  The election was the first since 1928 in which the Republican presidential nominee was elected in a decisive victory, taking over 55% of the popular vote and winning 39 of the 48 states.  Forms part of Record Group 412, Photographs Collection. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-1994; Nixon, Pat, 1912-1993</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Vice-Presidential candidates</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1952-09-27</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 412 667 Nixon visit 1952 Sept 27 014</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 412</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/5003</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>