<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Go ahead with your future plant in Nashville Tennessee, 1947</dc:title>
<dc:description>An informational pamphlet put out by the Nashville Chamber of Commerce urging manufacturers to consider locating their future plants in Nashville, Tennessee.  Content includes maps showing Nashville's central location, an explanation of available resources and a list of industry needs that Nashville meets.  Transportation and labor statistics for the time are also quoted.  Forms part of the Nashville Area Chamber of Commerce Publications and Reports. 1 pamphlet : col. ; 8.5  x 11  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Nashville Chamber of Commerce; Nashville Area Chamber of Commerce</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Business; Advertisements; Enterprise; Industries; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Organizations; Business enterprises--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Industries--Tennessee--Nashville; Industrial promotion--Tennessee--Nashville; City promotion--Tennessee--Nashville; Advertising--Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Public relations--Tennessee--Nashville; Culture and tourism--Tennessee--Nashville; Natural resources--Tennessee--Nashville; Business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Industry--Tennessee--Nashville; Chambers of commerce--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Commerce--Statistics; Nashville (Tenn.)--Economic conditions</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Nashville Area Chamber of Commerce</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1947</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text; Pamphlets</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Nash Area Chamber of Commerce pub &amp; reports - F3 - brochure - Go Ahead - 1947</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Area Chamber of Commerce Publications and Reports</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1162</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>