<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Advertising card for Joy&#8217;s Flowers, 1929</dc:title>
<dc:description>A blue advertising card for Joy&#8217;s Flowers, featuring a happy cartoon elephant printed in black ink. She is walking on her hind legs and wears a dress and earring. She carries a bouquet of flowers twisted in her trunk and is smiling broadly over her shoulder. Above the bouquet is a small banner reading: &#8220;From Joy&#8217;s&#8221;. A poem appears beneath the elephant, promoting Joy&#8217;s Flowers. Joy Floral Company was the oldest florist in Nashville, established in 1877 by Canadian immigrants Thomas C. Joy and his father, Thomas S. Joy. At the time of this ad, their main retail location was at 601 Church Street. Forms part of the Businesses Ephemera Subject Files. 1 advertising card ; col. ;  3 x 6 in. </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Joy Floral Company (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Business; Capital City; Florists--Tennessee--Nashville; Business enterprises--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Advertising cards; Advertising; Animals in advertising; Elephants--Caricatures and cartoons; Wit and humor in advertising; Poetry--Humor;
 Stores and shops--Tennessee--Nashville; Advertisements</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Commerce; Church Street (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Joy Floral Company (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1929</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Cartoons (humorous images); Text; Advertisements; Ephemera</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>ESF - Bus - Joys Elephant</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Ephemera Subject Files </dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1920-1929</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/11804</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>