<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Garage storage building, Department of Aviation, Berry Field, Nashville, Tennessee, circa 1950 </dc:title>
<dc:description>An exterior view of garage storage building at Berry Field, Nashville, Tennessee, circa 1950.  Named in honor of Colonel Harry S. Berry, state administrator of the WPA, Berry Field consisted of a terminal building, two hangars, a 4,000-foot concrete runway and a flashing beacon. The three letter identifier, BNA, stands for Berry Field Nashville. American and Eastern airlines were the first air carriers to serve Nashville, and within the year, 189,000 passengers had used the facilities. During World War II, Berry Field became the military base for the 4th Ferrying Command, and the federal government added additional acreage for its military operations. In 1946, after the war ended, the military returned a 1,500-acre airport site to the city.  Forms part of the City of Nashville Property Photographs, album v1, b &amp; w photograph.  </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Berry Field (Tenn.); Metropolitan Nashville Airport Authority--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Airports--Tennessee--Nashville--History</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1950</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Metro Property vI  021 Berry Field, Garage Storage Building</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>City of Nashville Property Photographs</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/8565</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>