<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Nashville, 1896</dc:title>
<dc:description>An 1896 street map of downtown Nashville.  Streets are clearly labeled.  Labeled landscape features include Currey Hill, St. Cloud Hill, and the city reservoir.  Some prominent buildings are also depicted, including the State Capitol, Peabody Normal College, City Hall, the Court House, City Hospital, Tennessee School for the Blind and the State Penitentiary.  Forms part of the Ann Harwell Wells Tennessee Map Collection. 1 map : col. ; 33 x 26 cm.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Tennessee School for the Blind; Peabody Normal College; Tennessee State Capitol (Nashville, Tenn.); Davidson County Court House (Nashville, Tenn.); City Hospital (Nashville, Tenn.); Tennessee State Penitentiary</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Downtown Nashville; Transportation; Capital City; Neighborhood--Tennessee--Nashville--Maps; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Real property--Tennessee--Nashville--Maps; Railroads--Tennessee--Nashville--Maps; Neighborhoods--Tennessee--Nashville; Streets--Tennessee--Nashville;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Maps; Tennessee--Maps; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--Maps; Cumberland River (Ky. and Tenn.)--Navigation--Maps; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc. </dc:subject>
<dc:creator>George F. Cram Company (Publisher)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1896</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Maps</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Wells Maps - 138</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Ann Harwell Wells Tennessee Map Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1890-1899</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1185</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>