<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Nashville on the Cumberland River, circa 1970</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard of the Nashville city skyline taken from the Jefferson Street Bridge looking south, down the Cumberland River.  The Railroad Bridge is visible, as is the Victory Memorial Bridge, just behind it.  Other discernable landmarks include the Nashville Municipal Auditorium, the Tennessee State Capitol, and the Metropolitan Courthouse.  Forms part of the Norton Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Tennessee State Capitol (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville Municipal Auditorium (Tenn.); Metropolitan Courthouse (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Transportation; Business; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Skyscrapers--Tennessee--Nashville; Office buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Bridges--Tennessee--Nashville; Railroad bridges--Tennessee--Nashville; Rivers--Tennessee--Nashville; Boats and boating--Tennessee--Nashville; Business enterprises--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Transportation--Tennessee--Nashville; Public buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Municipal buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Railroads--Tennessee--Nashville; Auditoriums--Tennessee--Nashville; Business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Government facilities--American--Tennessee--Nashville; Courthouses--Tennessee--Nashville; Cultural facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Cityscapes</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Cumberland River (Ky. and Tenn.)--Navigation; Jefferson Street Bridge (Nashville, Tenn.); Victory Memorial Bridge (Nashville, Tenn.); Railroad Bridge (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Southern Post Card Co. (Publisher); Miley, Bruce (Photographer)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1970</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Norton - 0592</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Norton Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1970-1979</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1819</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>