<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Oglesby Community House, n.d.</dc:title>
<dc:description>An exterior view of the Oglesby Community House and its landscape beautification.  The National Register of Historic Places marker reads: &#8220;Oglesby Community House: Built 1898, the Mary Lee Academy, the second school in the Oglesby Community, was named for its first teacher, Miss Mary Lee Clark.  The county bought the school in 1906.  The name changed to Oglivie in honor of the land donor, Benton H. Ogilvie, and later became Oglesby.  In 1943, the schoolhouse was given back to the Oglesby Community.&#8221; The school closed in 1931 and the Oglesby community has used the building since 1935 for various activities including meetings and events for the Ladies Home Demonstration Club and Oglesby Community Club.  The old Oglesby community is now known as Nippers Corner.  This historic site is located at 5724 Edmondson Pike near Old Hickory Boulevard, approximately 12 miles from downtown Nashville, Tennessee.  Forms part of Record Group 412, Photographs Collection. 1 color photographic print, 3.5 x 5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Schools--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>n.d.</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 412 985 Oglesby Community Club - Beautification 001</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 412</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/6269</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>