<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>How's your fiscal fitness?, between 1960 and 1963</dc:title>
<dc:description>An original political cartoon drawing created by Jack Knox, the Nashville Banner editorial cartoonist from the mid-1940s to early 1970s.  In this cartoon, a tattered, exhausted man ("U.S.") tries to run and keep his balance on a barrel ("Red Ink Treadmill").  President Kennedy looks on, urging him to do "&#8230;12 or 15 billion quick time &#8230;."  In 1961, President John F. Kennedy signed into law a bill cutting taxes across the board, followed by his 1963 proposal submitted to Congress for a major tax reform which included huge tax cuts to bolster the economy and provide tax relief.  However, many Americans were opposed to the tax plan and concerned about its impact on the national economy.  The federal budget expenditures on defense spending also increased during the Cold War and the escalation in the Vietnam conflict.  Forms part of the Jack Knox Political Cartoon Collection. 1 original cartoon drawing : b &amp; w ; 15.25 x 24 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963--Caricatures and cartoons</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Banner</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Capital City; Politics; Political cartoons--United States--20th century; Political cartoons--Tennessee--Nashville; Caricatures and cartoons--Tennessee--Nashville; Cartoonists--Tennessee--Nashville; Editorial cartoonists--Tennessee--Nashville; Government spending policy--United States--Caricatures and cartoons; Fiscal policy--United States--Caricatures and cartoons;  Cartoonists; Economic &amp; political systems; Politics &amp; government--United States--Washington, D.C.</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>United States--Politics and government--20th century--Caricatures and cartoons</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Knox, Jack, 1910- (Cartoonist)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Knox, Joseph T. (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>between 1960 and 1963</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Caricatures; Cartoons (Commentary); Editorial cartoons</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Knox NPL-321</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Jack Knox Political Cartoon Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/982</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>