<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Restoration Work on the State Capitol, City Beautiful Scrapbooks, 1957, Vol. 4 p. 129</dc:title>
<dc:description>Photograph of restoration work on the State Capitol building, January 1957. The Tennessee State Capitol was designed by architect William Strickland, who modeled it after the Greek Ionic temple. The cornerstone was laid on July 4th, 1845 and the building was completed in 1859. Photographer unknown. Photograph used by the City Beautiful Commission of Nashville, Tennessee, 1957. The City Beautiful Commission was established by the Mayor and City Council in June of 1953, for the purpose of improving the sanitation, cleanliness, and overall appearance of the City of Nashville. The Commission later became a division of Metro Parks in 1975, and then a part of the Metro Public Works division in 2005. Forms part of the City Beautiful Commission Scrapbook Collection. 1 photograph : b &amp; w.
</dc:description>
<dc:subject>City Beautiful Commission</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Urban beautification; Capitols; Tennessee State Capitol (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Urban beautification; Capitols; Capitols--Tennessee--Nashville; Capitol Restoration Project;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.); Capitol Hill (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>City Beautiful Commission</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library
</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1957
</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photograph
</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg
</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>City Beautiful Vol 4 p129 Remodeling State Capitol 1957 001</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>City Beautiful Scrapbook Collection
</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959
</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880
</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/12353</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>