<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Fourth Avenue, Nashville, Tennessee, circa 1959 April 14</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph, circa April 1959, of downtown Nashville along Fourth Avenue North of Church Street from the corner of the Maxwell House Hotel. Several buildings and landmarks may be seen, such as the Maxwell House Hotel's marquee sign and the very popular radio station WMAK that broadcast from the studios in the lower floor there. Additional commercial enterprises across the street are the Noel Hotel (200 Fourth Avenue North), the Palace Hatters &amp; Cleaners, Louis J. Hartman Liquors, George's Place (hatters), Sherwin Williams Company, and the First American National Bank at Fourth Avenue, North, and Union Street. Photographed by the Nashville architect Charles Wesley Warterfield, Jr. (1926-1998); the architectural photograph forms part of the Charles Warterfield Architectural Collection. Gift of: The Estate of Charles W. Warterfield, Jr., F. A. I. A. The original is a 35 mm color transparency (2 x 2 in. slide mount).</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Maxwell House Hotel (Nashville, Tenn.); Noel Hotel (Nashville, Tenn.); WMAK (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); Palace Hatters and Cleaners (Nashville, Tenn.); Louis J. Hartman Liquors (Nashville, Tenn.); George's Place (Nashville, Tenn.); Sherwin-Williams Company (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Business; Advertisements; Popular Culture; Tourism; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architects--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Streets--Tennessee--Nashville--History; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville--History; Commercial buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Business enterprises--Tennessee--Nashville; Hotels--Tennessee--Nashville; Public laundries--Tennessee--Nashville; Liquor stores--Tennessee--Nashville; Radio stations--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; City &amp; town life--Tennessee--Nashville; Commercial streets--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Fourth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Church Street (Nashville, Tenn.); Union Street (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville (Tenn.)--Commerce; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Warterfield, Charles W. (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Estate of Charles W. Warterfield, Jr., F.A.I.A. (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1959-04-14</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Slides; Photographs; Architectural photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>WSC 4165</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Charles Warterfield Architectural Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/2243</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>