<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Hicks-Hill bridal party seen following wedding, from the Nashville Times, 1940</dc:title>
<dc:description>A captioned photo from the Nashville Times (1940), about the Hicks-Hill wedding. The caption reads: &#8220;Seen at the Edgefield Baptist Church following the marriage of Miss Dorothy J. Hill to John E. Hicks, are members of the bridal party, as follows: left to right, Miss Mary Elizabeth Hill, Clayborne McLemore, Mrs. L. E. Thomas, Harry Thomas, the bridal couple, Thomas W. Jarrell, Miss Billie Sue Carell, Alfred Rutherford, Miss Martha Bartlett, Hugh J. Bradley, and in the front row, the flower girls, Barbara Feldkircher, daughter of Mr. and Mrs. C. E. Feldkircher; Sara Mavis Bradley, daughter of Mr. and Mrs. Hugh J. Bradley, and Jane Carter, daughter of Mr. and Mrs. John E. Carter. The bride is the daughter of Mr. and Mrs. Frank B. Hill, and the bridegroom, the son of Mrs. C. W. Fitzgerald. Mr. and Mrs. Hicks will make their home in Detroit.&#8221; Forms part of the Nashville Times newspaper collection. 1 digital photo.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Hill family; Hicks family</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Marriage customs and rites--Tennessee--Nashville; Marriage--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1940</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>HicksHill--NT-1940</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Times Newspaper Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4232</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>