<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Reservoir, Nashville, Tenn., circa 1910</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard of the Nashville Reservoir located on Eighth Avenue South.  An electric streetcar is pictured on the road.  In 1889 the city built the reservoir on top of Kirkpatrick Hill on the site of Fort Casino just south of downtown Nashville.  The reservoir was built with rock from the Meridian quarry and supplied water to the entire city.  On 5 November 1912, a section of the reservoir wall collapsed, sending twenty-five million gallons of water into the neighborhood pictured in the foreground of this postcard, significantly damaging over twenty-five homes.  The reservoir was repaired and re-opened to the public allowing residents to walk or bike along its walls.  In 1917 the reservoir was closed to the public due to the outbreak of World War I and the fear that Germany might try to poison the city's water supply if they had access to it.  Forms part of the Norton Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Capital City; Public Utilities; Buildings; Architecture; Transportation; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Reservoirs--Tennessee--Nashville; Water supply--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Neighborhood--Tennessee--Nashville; Transportation--Tennessee--Nashville; Street-railroads--Tennessee--Nashville; Electric railroads--Tennessee--Nashville; Electric railroads--Cars--Tennessee--Nashville; Street railroads--Tennessee--Nashville; City &amp; town life--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Eighth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Kirkpatrick Hill (Nashville, Tenn.); Fort Casino (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>E.C. Kropp Co. (Publisher)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1910</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Norton - 0093</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Norton Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1910-1919</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1832</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>