<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>SNCC leaders H. Rap Brown, Stokely Carmichael, and George Ware leaving the U.S. Courthouse in Nashville, Tennessee, 1967 May 23</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of  leaders from the Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (SNCC) leaving the Estes Kefauver Federal Building and United States Courthouse in downtown Nashville, Tennessee, on May 23, 1967.  They were attending a trial of a suit contesting anti-riot laws following riots in North Nashville.  In the black and white photo by Nashville Banner staff photographer Vic Cooley are (from left to right):  H. Rap Brown , Stokely Carmichael, and George Ware.  The picture ran in the Nashville Banner on July 27, 1967.  Forms part of the Nashville Banner Archives. 1 photograph : b &amp; w ; 8 x 10 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Carmichael, Stokely; Al-Amin, Jamil, 1943- ; Ware, George Washington</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (U.S.); Estes Kefauver Federal Building and United States Courthouse (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville Banner</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Civil Rights; African Americans; Race Relations; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; African Americans--Civil rights--Tennessee--Nashville--History--20th century; Race riots--Tennessee--Nashville--History--20th century; Civil rights--Tennessee--Nashville--History--20th century; Trials--Tennessee--Nashville--History--20th century; African American political activists--Tennessee--Nashville--History--Sources; Law--Political aspects; Activists--American--Tennessee--Nashville; Civil rights leaders--Tennessee--Nashville--1960-1970</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Cooley, Vic (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1967-05-23</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BP - Segregation - SNCC Metro Trial - 1967</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/2228</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>