<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Letter from Governor Prentice Cooper to Mrs. John M. Donnelly, 1940 December 12</dc:title>
<dc:description>A typed letter, signed, dated 12 December 1940, from Tennessee Governor Prentice Cooper, to Mrs. John M. Donnelly, the Christmas Carol Publicity Chairman of the Fannie Battle Day Home Social Workers in 1940.  In the letter, Governor Cooper commends the organization for their social work and community service.  The Tennessee Executive Chamber stationery with its gold-embossed seal includes an image of a plow, a sheaf of wheat, and a cotton plant under the Roman numerals XVI, representing Tennessee as the 16th state to enter the Union.  The word "Agriculture" is on the center of the seal and the lower half displays a boat and boatman, with the word "Commerce" and "1796," the year of statehood.  Forms part of the Fannie Battle Day Home Records. 1 letter : col. ; 8 x 10.5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Cooper, Prentice, 1895-1969--Correspondence; Donnelly, John M., Mrs.--Correspondence</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Fannie Battle Day Home; Fannie Battle Social Workers</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Capital City; Organizations; Popular Culture; Children's History; Performing Arts; Music; Women in charitable work--Tennessee--Nashville; Charity--Tennessee--Nashville; Charities--Tennessee--Nashville; Day care centers--Tennessee--Nashville; Child care workers--Tennessee--Nashville; Social workers--Tennessee--Nashville; Child care--Tennessee--Nashville; Altruism--Tennessee--Nashville; Benevolence--Tennessee--Nashville; Social work with children--Tennessee--Nashville; Women--Charities; Child welfare; Christmas carols; Caroling--Tennessee--Nashville; Holidays--Tennessee--Nashville; Governors--Correspondence--Tennessee; Charitable organizations--Tennessee--Nashville; Community service--Tennessee--Nashville; Economic &amp; social conditions--Tennessee--Nashville; Organizations--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Davidson County (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Cooper, Prentice, 1895-1969</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1940-12-12</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text; Letters (correspondence)</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>FBDHR-SB-Carol Publicity-1940-B1-f29</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Fannie Battle Day Home Records</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1911</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>