<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Faculty members of Boscobel College for Young Ladies, featured in the Yearbook &#8220;Salmagundi,&#8221; of the Boscobel College for Young Ladies, Nashville, Tennessee, 1907  </dc:title>
<dc:description>Pictured: The faculty members of Boscobel College for Young Ladies, as well as information about their education credentials.  They are: Miss Catherine Herring, Miss Eleanor Few, Mrs. Luane Everett, Miss Mary Parker, Mr. W.G. Dodd, Mrs. J.O. Rust (President), Mrs. Catherine Vaughn, Miss Carrie May Jenkins, Miss Lela Lowe, Miss Effie Ryan, and Miss Grace Venable (Presiding Teacher).  The Boscobel College for Young Ladies was a college in East Nashville, founded in 1889 as the Nashville Baptist Female College by the Tennessee Baptist Convention.  The college operated for twenty-five years--until 1914.  The campus was built around an East Nashville mansion, formerly owned by Anna Shelby Williams.  The mansion stood atop a tree-covered hill overlooking the Cumberland River.  The campus covered ten wooded acres on Sevier Street near South Seventh Street (then called Foster Street), south of Sylvan Street.  In 1918, the property became home to the National Baptist Seminary and Missionary Training School, which functioned until 1931. The buildings were razed in 1940.  Forms part of the yearbook collection: Boscobel College, &#8220;Salmagundi,&#8221; 1907.  1 volume </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Venable, Grace; Herring, Catherine; Few, Eleanor; Everett, Luane; Parker, Mary; Dodd, W.G.; Rust, J.O.; Vaughn, Catherine; Jenkins, Carrie May; Lowe, Lela; Ryan, Effie; Throne, Amelie; Cantrell, Ella; Alexander, Reine; Parker, Mary C. </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Boscobel College (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Universities and colleges--Tennessee--Nashville; Women--Tennessee--Nashville; School facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Education--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Intellectual life</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Davis, Betty Dorris (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1907</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Boscobel College 1907  013 faculty; Boscobel College 1907  014 faculty list</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Boscobel College Yearbook 1907</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1900-1909</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/8536</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>