<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>I'd like to make a suggestion, Mr. Kennedy, circa 1963</dc:title>
<dc:description>An original political cartoon drawing created by Jack Knox, the Nashville Banner editorial cartoonist from the mid-1940s to early 1970s.  As John Q. Public looks on, President John F. Kennedy holds a giant pair of scissors.  One blade of the scissors is real ("Solid Tax-Cut Plan"), but the other blade is just a strip of paper ("Flimsy Budget Cut Suggestions").  Many Americans were opposed to President Kennedy's tax plan reform proposed to Congress in 1963, with a concern about the impact on the national economy.  The increase in federal budget expenditures on defense spending became controversial with proponents of domestic spending.  On February 26, 1964, the  Kennedy tax cut was enacted as the United States Revenue Act of 1964, signed by President Lyndon Johnson.  It was one of the largest tax cuts in the post-WWII era.  Forms part of the Jack Knox Political Cartoon Collection. 1 original cartoon drawing : b &amp; w ; 16.25 x 24 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963--Caricatures and cartoons</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Banner</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Capital City; Politics; Political cartoons--United States--20th century; Political cartoons--Tennessee--Nashville; Caricatures and cartoons--Tennessee--Nashville; Cartoonists--Tennessee--Nashville; Editorial cartoonists--Tennessee--Nashville; Government spending policy--United States--Caricatures and cartoons; Budget--United States--Caricatures and cartoons; Fiscal policy--United States--Caricatures and cartoons; Taxation--United States--Caricatures and cartoons; Cartoonists; Presidents--United States; Economic &amp; political systems; Economic policy--United States; Tax cuts--United States--Washington, D.C.; Tax reform--United States--Washington, D.C.</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>United States--Politics and government--20th century--Caricatures and cartoons</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Knox, Jack, 1910- (Cartoonist)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Knox, Joseph T. (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1963</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Caricatures; Cartoons (Commentary); Editorial cartoons</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Knox NPL-319</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Jack Knox Political Cartoon Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/981</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>