<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Excerpt 1 from oral history interview with Angeline Butler, 2005 March</dc:title>
<dc:description>An excerpt from an oral history interview with Nashville Civil Rights Movement participant Angeline Emma Butler, conducted in March 2005 by Rachel Lawson as part of the Nashville Public Library's Civil Rights Oral History Project. Butler discusses how she got involved in the Movement and met other people who were involved, such as James Bevel, Bernard LaFayette, and John Lewis, through a group of the American Friends (Quakers) that met at Fisk University.   The complete interview, as well as a transcript, is available in the repository.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Butler, Angeline Emma--interviews; Bevel, James L. (James Luther), 1936-; LaFayette, Bernard; Lewis, John, 1940 Feb. 21-</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Fisk University</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Civil Rights; African Americans; African Americans--Social conditions; African Americans--Civil rights--Tennessee--Nashville; Civil rights--Tennessee--Nashville; Civil rights workers--Tennessee--Nashville; Civil rights movements--Tennessee--Nashville; Society of Friends--Tennessee--Nashville; Quakers--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--Race relations; Nashville (Tenn.)--History</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Butler, Angeline Emma (Interviewee); Lawson, Rachel (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>James, Carolyn (Transcriber)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>2005-03</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound.Interview</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3 (2.18 MB; 2 min., 23 sec.)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CROHPButler11bclip1</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from:  CROHPButler audio cassette recording(s) converted to mp3 format in 2006.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Civil Rights Oral History Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content. This image is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/190</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>