<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Easter Parade in downtown Nashville, Tennessee, 1980</dc:title>
<dc:description>A decorated carriage sponsored by R &amp; R Uniforms, advertising &#8220;Sheriff Fate Thomas,&#8221; at the 1980 Easter Parade in downtown Nashville. A Dalmatian dog is pictured behind the vehicle.  Harvey&#8217;s Department Store sponsored the parade.  This festive springtime parade was enjoyed by many people, with its decorated parade floats, entertainers, and community participation.  The event was organized by Kolleen Hudgins, Director of Special Events, under the administration of Mayor Richard Fulton.  Forms part of the Kolleen Hudgins, Director of Special Events, Mayor&#8217;s Office Collection.  1 b &amp; w photograph.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Hudgins, Kolleen; Fulton, Richard</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Harvey&#8217;s Department Store (Nashville, Tenn.); Zales Jewelry (Nashville, Tenn.); R and R Uniforms (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Easter--Tennessee--Nashville; Families--Tennessee, Middle; Parades--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Dalmatian dog; Business enterprises--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Church Street (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1980</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Kolleen Hudgins Collection - Box 2- F11 Easter Parade 1980 015</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Kolleen Hudgins, Director of Special Events, Mayor&#8217;s Office Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1980-1989</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/6687</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>