<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Sgt. K. C. Henry of Lafayette takes down the Tennessee state flag, circa 1990 November 15</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of Sgt. K. C. Henry of Lafayette, Tenn. who prepares to take down the Tennessee state flag from its makeshift but sturdy flagpole at a campsite in Saudi Arabia during Operation Desert Shield. The campsite, nicknamed "Hotel California" because of its tennis court and a cracked swimming pool, was home to the 1175th Quartermaster Company of the Tennessee National Guard, based out of Carthage and Lafayette, Tenn.  The unit was leaving "Hotel California" in mid-November 1990 for a new location further north toward Kuwait. The photograph was taken by Nashville Banner photographer Larry McCormack on assignment in Saudi Arabia in November 1990. Forms part of the Nashville Banner Archives. 1 photograph transparency : col ; 35mm.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Henry, K. C.</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Tennessee. National Guard; Tennessee. Military Dept.; United States. National Guard Bureau. Quartermaster Company, 1175th; Tennessee. Army National Guard</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Military History; Persian Gulf War; Operation Desert Shield, 1990-1991; Persian Gulf War, 1991; Soldiers--Tennessee--Lafayette; Flags--United States--States; Flags--Tennessee; Military; Military personnel--American--Tennessee--Lafayette; Flags; State flags; Men; Military life--American; Military service--United States; Military camps--American--Saudi Arabia--1990</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Saudi Arabia--History--20th century--Sources; Saudi Arabia--Military relations--United States; United States--Military relations--Saudi Arabia; Lafayette (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Macon County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Tennessee--History--Sources; Hotel California (United States military camp : Saudi Arabia)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>McCormack, Larry (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1990-11-5</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Transparencies; Film transparencies</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BT 1990-2105-21</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1990-1999</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1645</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>