<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Group of five soldiers in woods during training, between 1939 and 1945</dc:title>
<dc:description>A snapshot of a group of five soldiers posed casually in the woods outside of a large tent next to a tree serving as a signpost.  Two homemade signs reading "5th Ave." and "Church Street," are nailed into the tree as if marking that intersection.  During the 1940s, those streets were known as the heart of the shopping district in downtown Nashville.  It is believed that all five men in the photograph came from Nashville and that one of the men is Floyd Melvin Hooper.  This photo was taken early in World War II during training.  Forms part of the Veterans History project. 1 photograph : b &amp; w : 3.5 x 4.5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Hooper, Floyd Melvin, 1918-1959</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>United States. Army Air Forces</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Military History; World War II; War; Veterans--Tennessee--History--Sources; World War, 1939-1945--Photography; Street signs--Tennessee--Nashville; World War, 1939-1945--Social aspects; Military training camps; Soldiers--Recreation; Nostalgia; Homesickness; Tents; Military life</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Phillip H. Davis (Donor); Hooper, Floyd Melvin, 1918-1959 (Collector)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>between 1939 and 1945</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>VHP-WWII-Hooper-p23</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Veterans History Project collection, World War II series, Floyd Melvin Hooper snapshots</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939; 1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1099</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>