<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Warner Elementary School, Nashville, Tennessee, n.d.</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard of the Warner Elementary School, named for James C. Warner, a member of the Percy Warner family who had been a member of the Edgefield Board of Education before the area was annexed to Nashville in 1880.  The first Warner School was built in 1892 to replace the Main Street School. The original buiding which housed grades 1-8 was totally destroyed in the 1916 East Nashville fire.  Warner was rebuilt but fire struck again in 1941, and the roof and top floor were destroyed.  In 1949 the west wing containing nine classrooms and a cafeteria was built to accommodate the growing population.  At one time, Warner housed more than a thousand students and had the largest enrollment of any Nashville elementary school.  Warner School currently stands on its original site on Russell Street in East Nashville.  Forms part of the Ridley Wills II Nashville Postcards Collection.  1 postcard.  </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Wills, Ridley, 1934-</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Warner Elementary School (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Public schools--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Russell Street (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc. </dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Ridley Wills II (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>n.d.</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RidleyWillsPostcards Box 2 322 Warner School East Nashville</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Ridley Wills II Nashville Postcards Collection  </dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/9321</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>