<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Operetta presented by du Pont students, from the Nashville Times, 1940</dc:title>
<dc:description>A captioned photo, published in the Nashville Times (1940), about the operetta presented by du Pont students.  The text reads: &#8220;The &#8216;Fanfare&#8217; chorus pictured above participated in a du Pont High School operetta entitled &#8216;Hollywood Bound,&#8217; pictured above, are: Louise Crosslin, Mary Ruth Temple, Flora Hagewood, Betsy Foster, Mildred Gann, Mary Beth Bentley, Ed Schwartz, Janice Brazier, Loraine Gray, Kathrine Vaughn and Dale Dedman. Leading characters in the play were Farris Brown, John Crosslin, Virginia Williams, Joe Gothard Puckett, Ernes? Pitts, Ray Brown, Leroy Downs, Billie Jo Jared, Jean Deal, Betty Ann Harris, Carl Stevens, Charles Shaver, William Lewis, Robert Thomas, Mary Lou Sturm, Howard Baker, Faye Winston, Charlene Thompson, Janice Brazier, Billie Baker, Robert Porch and Paul (Frederick?). The play was directed by Mrs. Mildred Dark.&#8221;  Forms part of the Nashville Times newspaper collection. 1 digital photo.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Du Pont High School (Old Hickory, Tennessee)--History--Sources
</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>High schools--Tennessee--Old Hickory; High schools--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Old Hickory (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1940</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DuPontStudents--NT-1940</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Times Newspaper Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4176</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>