<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>American Cancer Society National Officers visit Nashville, Tennessee, 1955 April </dc:title>
<dc:description>A photo related to the visit of the American Cancer Society National Officers to Nashville, Tennessee circa April 1955. The American Society, a volunteer agency, was formed in 1913 and reorganized in 1945.  The Society&#8217;s governing body consisted of a Board of Directors of men and women, many from the medical and scientific professions.  Gen. William J. Donovan served as ACS Honorary Director of the American Cancer Society, Inc.  During his visit with the group, Gen. Donovan was presented an Honorary Citizen of Nashville award by Mayor Ben West and the City of Nashville.  The local Cancer Crusade in Nashville was chaired by Mrs. Robert J. Anderson.  Forms part of Record Group 3, Metro Davidson County Photographer. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Donovan, William J. (William Joseph), 1883-1959; Anderson, Mrs. Robert J.; West, Ben, 1911-1974 </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>American Cancer Society--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Cancer--Prevention--History--Sources; Fund raising--Tennessee--Nashville--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1955-04</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives </dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG3 7906 American Cancer Soc Natl Officers Visit April 1955 01</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3 Metro Davidson County Photographer   </dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/7536</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>