<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>J. W. Barnes, from the Nashville Times, 1940</dc:title>
<dc:description>A published photo from the Nashville Times (1940), of J. W. Barnes, the last surviving CSA Veteran. James W. Barnes was with Company I, 55th (McKoin&#8217;s) Tennessee Infantry and Company I, 44th Tennessee Infantry. Barnes was born on June 16th, 1843, in Burke Hollow, Williamson County, Tennessee. The 44th Tennessee Infantry Regiment was first organized at Camp Trousdale, Tennessee, on December 16th, 1861. 
There is an autobiography about the Confederate soldier available online at http://www.tennessee-scv.org/4455/barnes.html  Forms part of the Nashville Times newspaper collection. 1 digital photo.  </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Barnes, James W., 1843-1944</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>United Confederate Veterans--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Soldiers--Tennessee, Middle--History--Sources; Patriotic societies--Tennessee, Middle--History--Sources; Veterans--Tennessee, Middle--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Confederate States of America--History--Sources; Tennessee--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Williamson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Tennessee--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Veterans--Sources; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Veterans--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1940</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>LastSurvivingCSAVetJWBarnes--NT-1940</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Times Newspaper Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4211</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>