<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>U.S. Customs House, Nashville, Tennessee, 2015 August </dc:title>
<dc:description>An exterior view of the U.S. Customs House located at 701 Broadway, Nashville, Tennessee circa August 2015.  The cornerstone of the Customs House was laid by President Rutherford B. Hayes on September 19, 1877. Approval for a federal building dates to 1856, but construction delays and the Civil War caused Nashville to wait for more than twenty years for a facility to house federal courts, customs, and post office. Treasury architect William Appleton Potter designed this grand example of the Victorian Gothic style. From its massive yet ornate stone block a central clock tower soars. The many rich details include the Gothic lancet windows and a deeply inset triple-arch entrance. In the 1990s the Customs House was declared surplus property by the federal government and was turned over to Metro Nashville government which worked toward its renovation and reuse. The building is listed in the National Register of Historic Places.  Additional buildings that are partially visible in this photograph are the First Baptist Church, Renaissance Nashville Hotel, and the AT&amp;T Building, colloquially known as the &#8220;Batman Building.&#8221;  Forms part of the  Leanne Garland Photograph Collection.  1 digital photograph.  </dc:description>
<dc:subject>First Baptist Church (Nashville, Tenn.)--Pictorial works; AT &amp; T (Firm)--History--Sources; Marriott International, Inc.--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Customhouses--Tennessee--Nashville; Baptist Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Hotels--Tennessee--Nashville </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Broadway Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Eighth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Garland, Leanne (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-08</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>LGar US Customs Bldg 2015a</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Leanne Garland Photograph Collection </dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2010-2019</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/7668</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>