<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Oral history interview with Judge Alfred Thompson Adams, 1980 September 16, excerpt 08</dc:title>
<dc:description>An excerpt from an oral history interview with Nashville lawyer and judge Alfred Thompson Adams, conducted on 16 September 1980 by Leanne Thornton as part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. 1910-1935 Oral History Project.  Adams, who served Nashville as Chancellor of Part Two of the Davidson County Chancery Court from 1957 to 1970, discusses his family's history with the First Presbyterian Church (later the Downtown Presbyterian Church) and the Second Presbyterian Church.  He also discusses the First Presbyterian Church being converted into a hospital by Union forces during the Civil War.  The complete interview is available in the repository.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Adams, Alfred Thompson, 1898-1982--Interviews</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>First Presbyterian Church (Nashville, Tenn.)--History; Downtown Presbyterian Church (Nashville, Tenn.)--History; Second Presbyterian Church (Nashville, Tenn.)--History</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Popular Culture; Religion; Military History; Civil War; Judges--Tennessee--Nashville; Lawyers--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Presbyterian church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Hospitals</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.; Adams, Alfred Thompson, 1898-1982 (Interviewee); Thornton, Leanne  (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1980-09-16</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3 (1 min., 50 sec.)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>HNIOHAdamsA1aclip8</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from:  HNIOHAdamsA audio cassette recording converted to mp3 format in 2006.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. 1910-1935 Oral History Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1980-1989</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/614</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>