<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Excerpt from Mary Margaret Lambert Oral History Interview, 2011 April 30</dc:title>
<dc:description>Excerpt from an oral history interview with Mary Margaret Lambert conducted on April 30, 2011 by Susannah Gibbons as part of the Flood 2010 Digital History Project. Away from Nashville at the time of the flood, Mary Margaret Lambert describes finding out about the death of her father Joseph Formosa Jr. and his wife Bessie Formosa, returning to Nashville, support from a neighbor who had lost everything.

The complete interview is available in the Special Collections Division.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Lambert, Mary Margaret--Interviews</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Natural disasters--Nashville (Tenn.);Storytelling--Nashville (Tenn.);Oral history--Sources;Oral history--Library resources;Drowning--Accidents--Nashville (Tenn.);Flood damage;Emergency vehicles;       </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--Floods;Nashville (Tenn.)--History--21st century;Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources;</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Lambert, Mary Margaret (Interviewee); Gibbons, Susannah (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Warkentin, Bettina (Transcriber)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>2011-04-30</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3 (8.17MB; 04min., 27sec.)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>FDHLambertMClip001</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from:  Mary Margaret Lambert Oral History Interview. Born-digital recording(s) converted to mp3 format for online access in 2012 from 16bit 44.1khz WAV file archival master recording.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Flood 2010 Digital History Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2010-2019</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/3693</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>