<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Bennie Dillon Building, Nashville, Tennessee, 2015 October 08</dc:title>
<dc:description>Exterior views of the Bennie Dillon building located on the corner of Church Street and 7th Avenue N in downtown Nashville, Tennessee.  This high-rise building was built by the construction firm Foster &amp; Creighton circa 1925-1927 for George Bennie, a businessman who served as the President of the Nashville Chamber of Commerce, and William Dillon, a real estate developer.  It was designed in the Renaissance Revival architectural style by the architectural team Asmus &amp; Clark.  The structure features elaborate terra cotta decoration, topped by an expressive Goth arch theme on its roofline.  The Bennie Dillon is an adaptive reuse of a twelve-story office building into mixed-use development.  It was renovated in the late 1990s when the building was converted to apartments in 1998-1999; the structure was renovated again in 2005.  The Bennie-Dillon Building was added to the National Register of Historic Places in 1984.  Forms part of the Leanne Garland Photograph Collection.  5 digital photog</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Bennie Dillon Building (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Business enterprises--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Church Street (Nashville, Tenn.); Seventh Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Leanne Garland (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2015-10-08</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>LGar Bennie Dillon bldg Oct8 2015a - e </dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Leanne Garland Photograph Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2010-2019</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/8898</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>