<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Andrew Jackson equestrian statue at Tennessee State Capitol Building, 1953</dc:title>
<dc:description>Pictured: the Clark Mills equestrian bronze statue of General Andrew Jackson at the Battle of New Orleans.  It is one of the three identical statues sculpted by the artist.  This statue stands upon the front lawn to the Tennessee State Capitol Building in downtown Nashville.  The other two statues are at New Orleans, Louisiana and Washington, D. C.  It is the first design of a person on horseback ever cast in the United States.  The monument was dedicated during Nashville&#8217;s centennial celebration in May 1880.  Forms part of Record Group 3, Metro Davidson County Photographer. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Mills, Clark, 1810-1883; Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845--Statues</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Tennessee State Capitol (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Presidents--United States--Monuments; Sculpture--Tennessee--Nashville; Equestrian statues--Tennessee--Nashville; War memorials--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1953</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 3 1428 Andrew Jackson statue 1953 001</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3 Metro Davidson County Photographer</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/5806</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>