<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Views of Nashville, Tenn., 1907</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard depicting several Nashville landmarks, including the State Penitentiary, the Confederate Monument in Mt. Olivet Cemetery, the Parthenon in Centennial Park, two images of the United States Post Office and Custom House, Union Station, Andrew Jackson equestrian statue, Tennessee State Capitol, the Hermitage, the tomb of James K. Polk, and the Duncan Hotel.  Forms part of the Norton Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : b &amp; w ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845--Homes and haunts--Tennessee--Hermitage; Polk, James K. (James Knox), 1795-1849--Tomb; Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845--Monuments</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Tennessee State Penitentiary; Mount Olivet Cemetery (Nashville, Tenn.); Parthenon (Art museum : Nashville, Tenn.); United States Post Office (Nashville, Tenn.); United States Custom House (Nashville, Tenn.); Union Station (Nashville, Tenn.); Tennessee State Capitol (Nashville, Tenn.); Hermitage (Hermitage, Tenn.); Duncan Hotel (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Buildings; Business; Parks; Architecture; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Tourism; Transportation; Industries; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Advertising postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Prisons--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Details; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Equestrian statues--Tennessee--Nashville; Capitols--Tennessee--Nashville; Public buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Hotels--Tennessee--Nashville; Tombs--Tennessee--Nashville; Cemeteries--Tennessee--Nashville; Monuments--Tennessee--Nashville; Tourism--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic house museums--Tennessee--Hermitage; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville; Business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Post offices--Tennessee--Nashville; Customhouses--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Centennial Park (Nashville, Tenn.); United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Monuments</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1907</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Norton - 0006</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Norton Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1900-1909</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1830</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>