<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Cheri Silverstein recalls her September 11, 2001, experiences, 2007 October 06</dc:title>
<dc:description>An edited excerpt with transcript and photograph from an interview with Cheri Silverstein, conducted on 6 October 2007 by her friend Andrea Rodriguez at the Nashville StoryCorps StoryBooth, located in the Nashville Room of the Nashville Public Library.  Cheri, a Nashville physician, recalls her experiences on September 11, 2001, while working in a hospital in New Jersey within sight of the World Trade Center.  The complete, un-edited interview, as well as an index, is available in the Special Collections Division. These interviews were recorded by StoryCorps at the Nashville Public Library with the support of the Nashville Public Library Foundation and are provided courtesy of StoryCorps, a national initiative of Sound Portraits Productions to record and collect oral history interviews. www.storycorps.net</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Silverstein, Cheri, 1976- --Interviews</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>World Trade Center (New York, N.Y.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Popular Culture; Disasters; Storytelling--Tennessee--Nashville; Physicians--Tennessee--Nashville; Hospitals--New Jersey; Medical students--New Jersey; Women medical students--New Jersey; Terrorism--United States; September 11 Terrorist Attacks, 2001--Personal narratives</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; New York (N.Y.)--History; New Jersey--History</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Silverstein, Cheri, 1976-  (Interviewee); Rodriguez, Andrea, 1976-  (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>StoryCorps (Project)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>2007-10-06</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3 (3 min., 09 sec.)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>NPL000025_excerpt.mp3; NPL000025_transcript.pdf; NPL000025_g1.jpg</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from:  NPL000025 original StoryCorps interview edited by Aimee James in November and December 2008.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville StoryCorps StoryBooth Interviews 2007-2008</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/2005</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>