<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Tulane Hotel demolition in downtown Nashville, Tennessee, circa 1957</dc:title>
<dc:description>A view of the Tulane Hotel, located at Church and Eighth Avenue North, NE corner in downtown Nashville, Tennessee circa 1957.  This hotel, built in the renaissance revival style, was erected in 1894 as the Nicholson Hotel on the site of the old Nicholson House, a fancy boarding housing beginning in the 1860s and the residence of I. C. Nicholson. In 1896, the hotel, with its renovation and expansion, was renamed the &#8220;Tulane&#8221; for one of the new owner&#8217;s relatives.  In 1897, during the Tennessee Centennial Exposition, it held visitors from all over the world.  In 1911, Anne Dallas Dudley and several other women met in a parlor of the Tulane Hotel and founded the Nashville Equal Suffrage League, an activist organization in support for the right of women to vote.  During the 1940s there were many elegant formal balls, election year celebrations, Christmases, and entertainment for soldiers during World War II.  In 1947, Castle Studio, Nashville first major recording studio was established at the site.  In the 1950s, National Life and Accident Insurance purchased the building for approximately $850,000.  The Tulane closed its doors April 1956 and a few months later this hotel was razed to make way for a parking lot.  Forms part of Record Group 3, Metro Davidson County Photographer. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Tulane Hotel (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Hotels--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Streets--Tennessee--Nashville; Commercial buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Eighth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Church Street (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1957</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 3 1148 Tulane Hotel demolition in 1957 002</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3 Metro Davidson County Photographer</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/6271</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>