<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Swimming class at Sevier Park pool, Nashville, Tennessee, 1965</dc:title>
<dc:description>Pictured: Swimming instructor Doris Cumming teaching a youth how to float on the water, as part of the &#8220;Learn to Swim&#8221; classes conducted at 15 pool locations in 1965.  Sevier Park, located in the 12th South neighborhood of Nashville, was purchased by the Park Board in 1945 from the estate of Colonel Granville Sevier, a retired Army officer and descendent of a brother to the first Governor of Tennessee.  Sunnyside Mansion in the park was the home before the Civil War of Mrs. Jesse Benton, whose husband was the brother of Thomas H. Benton.  The park was dedicated by Mayor Thomas Cummings on June 7, 1948.  Forms part of Metro Archives Record Group 327, Metro Parks and Recreation Collection.  1 b &amp; w photograph.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Cumming, Doris</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.) Board of Parks and Recreation--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Parks--Tennessee--Nashville; Urban parks--Tennessee--Nashville; 
Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville
</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Parks; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Twelfth Avenue South (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>King, William M. (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1965</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Parks - Sevier Park - 002 - Swim Lessons - 1965</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>RG 327, Metro Parks Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/6763</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>