<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>The Madison Street United Methodist Church in Clarksville, Tennessee, circa 1975 June 02</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of the Madison Street United Methodist Church located at 319 Madison Street in downtown Clarksville, Tennessee circa 2 June 1975. Originally built in 1882, the church was designed by architect C. G. Rosenplanter in the Gothic Revival style. The structure has been listed on the National Historic Register since 1976. In 1999, a F3 tornado came through downtown Clarksville and essentially destroyed the sanctuary, the gymnasium, and most of the education building. The spires and roof of the building were lost. In 2000, when rebuilt by Everton Oglesby Architects, the twin steeples were replaced with copper-clad, structural steel outlines of the original towers. Photographed by the Nashville architect Charles Wesley Warterfield, Jr. (1926-1998); the architectural photograph forms part of the Charles Warterfield Architectural Collection. Gift of: The Estate of Charles W. Warterfield, Jr., F. A. I. A. The original is a 35 mm color transparency (2 x 2 in. slide mount).</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Madison Street United Methodist Church (Clarksville, Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Buildings--Tennessee--Clarksville; Architecture--Tennessee--Clarksville; Methodist church buildings--Tennessee--Clarksville; Church architecture--Tennessee--Clarksville; Religious facilities--Tennessee--Clarksville; Tornadoes--Tennessee--Clarksville; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Clarksville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Clarksville; Steeples--Tennessee--Clarksville; Methodist churches--Tennessee--Clarksville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Clarksville (Tenn.)--Churches; Clarksville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Clarksville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Clarksville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Warterfield, Charles W. (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Estate of Charles W. Warterfield, Jr., F.A.I.A. (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1975-06-02</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Slides; Photographs; Architectural photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>WSC 0284</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Charles Warterfield Architectural Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1970-1979</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/2235</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>