<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Pulchritudinous publicists, circa 1955 December 02</dc:title>
<dc:description>Two photographs, published in a 2 December 1955 Nashville Banner newspaper feature about the carol program and Yuletide project of the Fannie Battle Social Workers, titled "Fannie Battle Carolers." The captions are "Pulchritudinous Publicists," and "Party Patter."  In the top photograph, left to right are: Mrs. Russell Dorris, radio; Mrs. Charles Andrews, store-ads; Mrs. James W. Blazer, Jr., clerical chairman; Mrs. Phillip Lee, posters and civic letters; and Mrs. Thomas Summers, television, as they leave a planning session to publicize the annual project. Next, below, is Mrs. Frank P. Provost, Jr., civic clubs chairman, and Mrs. R.M. Foote, public relations chairman, seen discussing the forthcoming Fannie Battle Christmas party.  Forms part of the Fannie Battle Day Home Records. 1 photograph :  b &amp; w ; 9.5 x 12.75 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Dorris, Russell, Mrs.; Andrews, Charles, Mrs.; Blazer, James W., Mrs.; Lee, Phillip, Mrs.; Summers, Thomas, Mrs.; Provost, Frank P., Mrs.; Foote, R.M., Mrs.</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Fannie Battle Day Home; Fannie Battle Social Workers</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Capital City; Organizations; Popular Culture; Children's History; Music; Women in charitable work--Tennessee--Nashville; Charity--Tennessee--Nashville; Charities--Tennessee--Nashville; Day care centers--Tennessee--Nashville; Altruism--Tennessee--Nashville; Benevolence--Tennessee--Nashville; Social work with children--Tennessee--Nashville; Women--Charities; Christmas carols; Caroling--Tennessee--Nashville; Holidays--Tennessee--Nashville; Charitable organizations--Tennessee--Nashville; Community service--Tennessee--Nashville; Economic &amp; social conditions--Tennessee--Nashville; Social values--Tennessee--Nashville; Manners &amp; customs--Tennessee--Nashville  </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social conditions; Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Davidson County (Tenn.)--Social conditions</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Malone, John (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1955-12-02</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>FBDHR-SB-Carol Publicity-1955-B16, f33-p1, p2</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Fannie Battle Day Home Records</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/2233</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>