<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>V-mail letter from Sergeant John B. Johnson to Ann Cashel, Nashville, Tennessee, 1944 August 08 </dc:title>
<dc:description>A V-mail letter from Sergeant John B. Johnson to Ann Cashel, 1025 Iverson Avenue, dated August 8th, 1944.  In the letter he states that &#8220;today marks 34 months in the army&#8221; and that &#8220;recently &#8230;. I was privileged to visit the ruins of Pompeii &#8230; [that] in addition to the ruins, in the present city of Pompeii there is a cathedral which is second to the Vatican in beauty.&#8221;  He also states: &#8220;Naples is quite a nice city although both our own armies and those of the enemy did a pretty thorough job in tearing up the place.&#8221;  He states in closing that &#8220;Most of us would be willing to dispense with all afternoons off if it would get this war over with any sooner, but like machinery we need an occasional idling period, too.&#8221;  Miss Cashel graduated from Saint Cecilia Academy in Nashville, Tennessee, June, 1922.  The 1930 Census cites her birth date abt. 1905, residing at home with her widowed mother Katie B. Cashel, at a 10th Ave. N address in Ward 2 of the City of Nashville, Tennessee.  The names of her parents are: William Patrick Cashel and Katie (nee Moran) Cashel.  Forms part of the John Lawrence Connelly Collection, 1 letter.  </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Cashel family; Cashel, Ann Louise; Johnson, John B. </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>V-mail; World War, 1939-1945--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1944-08-08</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>JohnConnellyColl Anne Louise Cashel folder 003</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>John Lawrence Connelly Collection </dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/9295</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>