<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Tennessee State Capitol Building, Nashville, Tennessee, n.d.</dc:title>
<dc:description>A view of the cupola of the Tennessee State Capitol building, located in downtown Nashville. The State Capitol was constructed between 1845 and 1859. It was designed in Greek Revival style by architect William Strickland (1788-1854). Strickland died before construction was completed and was interred in the walls of the north portico. His son, Francis W. Strickland, oversaw the completion of the project. The cupola was reputedly modeled on a Greek monument to Lysicrates and designed to be illuminated at night like a lantern. The building was constructed of Tennessee Limestone and underwent major restoration from 1956-1960. During the restoration, much of the limestone, including most in the cupola and the Ionic columns and capitals, was replaced with Indiana limestone. The grounds contain monuments to famous people and events in Tennessee history, such as the Edward Ward Carmack statue in the foreground. The Capitol was placed on the National Register of Historic Places in 1970. Forms p</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Public buildings--Tennessee--Nashville
Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville; Capitols--Tennessee--Nashville; Cupolas--Tennessee--Nashville

</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Tennessee--Capital and capitol

</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Goodman, Bill (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>n.d.</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Goodman Slides121</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Bill Goodman 35 mm Slides Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/10423</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>