<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Group of Fannie Battle Social Workers territorial chairmen, circa 1949 December 16</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph showing several additional carol chairmen announced by Mrs. Ernest Jones, Jr., 1948 carol chairman for the Fannie Battle Social Workers, in preparations for Christmas Eve caroling in 1949.  Pictured here, seated left to right, are Mrs. Lawrence Houck, Mrs. L.G. Sadler, Mrs. Norman McAtee and Mrs. L.L. Treanor.  Standing in the background are Mrs. W.P. Chambers, Mrs. Howard Pardue and Mrs. H.H. Hudson.  The Fannie Battle Day Home Social Workers, continuing the organization's holiday tradition, sent volunteer carolers throughout the city and its suburbs to sing at homes where a candle in the window signified their desire to contribute to the Fannie Battle Day Home.  This photograph illustrated the newspaper article "Young matrons serving as territorial carol chairmen," published in the 16 December 1949 issue of the Nashville Banner.  Forms part of the Fannie Battle Day Home Records. 1 photograph :  b &amp; w ; 7.25 x 9.25 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Houck, Lawrence, Mrs.; Sadler, L.G., Mrs.; McAtee, Norman, Mrs.; Treanor, L.L., Mrs.; Chambers, W.P., Mrs.; Pardue, Howard, Mrs.; Hudson, H.H., Mrs.</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Fannie Battle Day Home; Fannie Battle Social Workers</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Capital City; Organizations; Popular Culture; Children's History; Performing Arts; Music; Women social reformers--Tennessee--Nashville; Charity--Tennessee--Nashville; Charities--Tennessee--Nashville; Day care centers--Tennessee--Nashville; Child care workers--Tennessee--Nashville; Social workers--Tennessee--Nashville; Child care--Tennessee--Nashville; Women in charitable work--Tennessee--Nashville; Altruism--Tennessee--Nashville; Benevolence--Tennessee--Nashville; Social work with children--Tennessee--Nashville; Children--Social conditions; Children--Charities; Child welfare; Christmas carols; Caroling--Tennessee--Nashville; Holidays--Tennessee--Nashville; Charitable organizations--Tennessee--Nashville; Community service--Tennessee--Nashville; Economic &amp; social conditions--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social conditions; Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Davidson County (Tenn.)--Social conditions</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Malone, John (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1949-12-16</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>FBDHR-SB-Carol Publicity-1949-B8, f9</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Fannie Battle Day Home Records</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1820</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>