<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Fannie Battle Social Workers, from the Nashville Times, 1940</dc:title>
<dc:description>A captioned photo, published in the Nashville Times (1940), about the Fannie Battle Social Workers.  The caption reads: &#8220;The Fannie Battle Social Workers are seen at a recent meeting at Centennial Club, where they planned the program of their work for the year. Left to right standing are: Mrs. John Donnelly, Mrs. Frank Wharton, Mrs. W. R. Manier, Jr., Mrs. George A. Ralston, Mrs. Robert T. Turner, Mrs. Thomas W. Estes, Mrs. William R. Maddux, Mrs. Austin W. Wilson, and Mrs. Fred Greve. Left to right seated are: Mrs. John Geny, Mrs. Charles H. Potter, president; Mrs. Charles Blackard, vice-president; Mrs. W. O. Vaughn, secretary; Mrs. David Huggins, treasurer, and Mrs. Clarence Taylor.&#8221;  
Forms part of the Nashville Times newspaper collection. 1 digital photo.  </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Fannie Battle Social Workers; Fannie Battle Day Home</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Women social reformers--Tennessee--Nashville; Charity--Tennessee--Nashville; Charities--Tennessee--Nashville; Day care centers--Tennessee--Nashville; Child care workers--Tennessee--Nashville; Women in charitable work--Tennessee--Nashville; Altruism--Tennessee--Nashville; Benevolence--Tennessee--Nashville; Social work with children--Tennessee--Nashville; Children--Charities</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1940</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>FannieBattleSocialWorkers--NT-1940</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Times Newspaper Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4178</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>