<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Excerpt 3 from oral history interview with Gilbert S. Fox, 2004 March 01</dc:title>
<dc:description>An excerpt from an oral history interview with Gilbert S. Fox, conducted on 1 March 2004 by Robert P. Richardson as part of the Nashville Public Library's Veterans History Project.  Fox, an Executive Officer on board LSM-80 in the US Navy during World War II, discusses the most frightening experiences during his naval service, including his ship being on fire and being attacked by kamikaze pilots.  The complete interview, as well as a transcript, is available in the repository.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Fox, Gilbert S., 1920- --Interviews</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Veterans History Project (U.S.); United States. Navy--Officers--Interviews; LSM-80 (Ship)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Military History; World War II; World War, 1939-1945--Veterans--Tennessee--Nashville; Veterans--Tennessee--Interviews; World War, 1939-1945--Campaigns--South Pacific Ocean; World War, 1939-1945--Naval operations; Kamikaze airplanes; Kamikaze pilots; World War, 1939-1945--Aerial operations, Japanese; World War, 1939-1945--Participation, Jewish</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Pacific Ocean--Description and travel</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Fox, Gilbert S., 1920- (Interviewee); Richardson, Robert Price, 1926- (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Davis, Ellen (Transcriber)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>2004-03-01</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3 (1.22 MB; 1 min., 20 sec.)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>VHPFoxG2bclip1</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from:  VHPFoxG (VHP tapes 225 &amp; 226) audio cassette recording converted to mp3 format in 2006.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Veterans History Project collection, World War II series</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/230</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>