<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Bill Wilkerson Hearing and Speech Center, City Beautiful Scrapbooks, 1957, Vol. 5 p. 111</dc:title>
<dc:description>Photograph of the exterior of the Bill Wilkerson Hearing and Speech Center building, located on 19th Avenue South. The facility was constructed circa 1956, and it was named for the son of the founder, Dr. Welsey Wilkerson. Bill Wilkerson, a soldier in World Wark II, was killed in the the Battle of the Builge at age 19. During the next few decades,m a modern facility was built at Vanderbilt University's Medical Center East and the scope of its program mission expanded. Photographer unknown. Photograph used by the City Beautiful Commission of Nashville, Tennessee, 1957. The City Beautiful Commission was established by the Mayor and City Council in June of 1953, for the purpose of improving the sanitation, cleanliness, and overall appearance of the City of Nashville. The Commission later became a division of Metro Parks in 1975, and then a part of the Metro Public Works division in 2005. Forms part of the City Beautiful Commission Scrapbook Collection. 1 photograph : b &amp; w.
</dc:description>
<dc:subject>City Beautiful Commission
</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Urban beautification; Bill Wilkerson Hearing and Speech Center;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Urban beautification; Health care facilities; Health care facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Health department; Health facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Hearing clinics--Tennessee--Nashville; Speech clinics--Tennessee--Nashville;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.); Nineteenth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>City Beautiful Commission
</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library
</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1957
</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photograph
</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg
</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>City Beautiful Vol 5 p111 Bill Wilkerson Center 1957 001</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>City Beautiful Scrapbook Collection
</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959
</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880
</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/12255</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>