<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Belmont United Methodist Church, 2001 May</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of Belmont United Methodist Church located at 2007 Acklen Avenue in Nashville, Tennessee.  Belmont United Methodist underwent extensive remodeling during a $1.6 million renovation that started in 1987 and was completed in 1991.  The original building structure was built in 1927 with an original address of 2009 Acklen Avenue.  The foundation is built out of rough cut stone.  The exterior walls are made of finished stone blocks.  The roof is flat.  The windows include both stained and frosted glass varieties.  Doors are wooden.  Ornate carvings of wreathes provide ornamentation to the exterior facade.  Six columns stand at the entryway.  Forms part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project. 1 photograph : col. ; 4  x 6  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Belmont United Methodist Church (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Popular Culture; Religion; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Religious facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Church architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Methodist church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Protestant church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Protest churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Methodist churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville; Columns--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs; Acklen Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2001-05</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>SSSP - Belmont United Methodist Church</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/724</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>