<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Dinah Shore at Vanderbilt University, 1957 January 23</dc:title>
<dc:description>Pictured: Dinah Shore seated, with unidentified students and officials, on stage at a Vanderbilt ceremony, January 23rd, 1957.  American popular singer, born Francis Rose Shore, in Winchester, Tennessee.  She graduated from Vanderbilt University with a major in sociology in 1938 and sang on local radio.  She moved to New York to pursue a musical career with the Xavier Cugat orchestra. She became well-known as Dinah Shore via her first recordings with the bandleader.  After World War II, she had her own television shows, achieving the highest audience ratings.  She made LPs for Victor, Columbia, and several other labels.  Shore received numerous Emmy awards for television specials and productions and appeared in many films.  Forms part of Record Group 412, Photographs Collection. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Shore, Dinah, 1917-1994</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Vanderbilt University</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Singers--United States; Women entertainers--United States; Celebrities; Universities and colleges--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Goodman, Bill (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1957-01-23</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 412 099 Dinah Shore at Vanderbilt in 1957 002</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 412</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/5174</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>