<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Models of James Robertson and John Donelson statuary by sculptor Thomas Puryear Mims, 1958 June</dc:title>
<dc:description>A sculpted model of the Nashville pioneers James Robertson and John Donelson, created by Nashville sculptor Puryear Mims.  These are early renditions, at Vanderbilt University, circa June 1958.  In 1962 the completed bronze statuary was ready for placement inside the stockade of the replicated Fort Nashborough overlooking the Cumberland River in downtown Nashville.  Robertson is depicted by the figure shouldering an axe as he shakes the hand of Donelson, who holds a rifle and was captain of flagship Adventure leading the flatboat flotilla over treacherous waterways to join Robertson&#8217;s 1779 overland party on the Cumberland bluffs on April 24, 1780.  Forms part of Record Group 3, Metro Davidson County Photographer. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Mims, Thomas Puryear, 1906-1975; Robertson, James, 1742-1814; Donelson, John, ca. 1718-ca. 1780</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Sculptors--Tennessee--Nashville; Models (Clay, plaster, etc.)--Tennessee--Nashville; Frontier and pioneer life--Tennessee, Middle</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1958-06</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 3 1426 statuary for James Robertson pkwy June 1958 001</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3 Metro Davidson County Photographer</dc:relation>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/5826</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>