<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Christ the King Catholic Church, 2001 May</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of Christ the King Catholic Church, located at 3001 Belmont Boulevard in Nashville, Tennessee.  The church's first mass was held in 1937 inside of a two-story brick house that was situated on the property bought for the church by the Diocese.  The proper church was finished two months later, and the brick house was instead used as a chapel, school, parish house, social center, and recreation hall.  After the church's new school opened in 1946, the brick house was renovated and used as a residence for the pastor.  In 1953, Rev. Thomas P. Duffy, former pastor of St. Mary's Church in Nashville, was appointed pastor of Christ the King.  Plans for the construction of an addition to the school, a new rectory and a new church were made soon after Duffy's appointment.  The firm of Woolwine, Harwood and Clark was contracted for the architecture.  Boone Construction Company was named general contractor for the project.  During construction the old two-story brick structure that had served multiple purposes throughout the years was razed.  By 1956 construction on all structures was completed.  The new church was built in the form of a Latin cross and the style is a modification of the Tudor Gothic Architecture.  The foundation is comprised of smooth cut finished stone.  The exterior walls are made of red brick and smooth cut finished stone.  The roof is gabled and the shingles are slate.  The stained glass windows are gothic arched.  The doors are made of both wood and metal and have glass windows.  Special features include a 144 ft. bell tower and steeple.  Extensive renovations and a new parish center were completed in 1999.  Forms part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project. 1 photograph : col. ; 4  x 6  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Christ the King Catholic Church (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Popular Culture; Religion; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Religious facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Church architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Catholic church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Chapels--Tennessee--Nashville; Brick churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture, Gothic--Tennessee--Nashville; Churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Catholic churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Steeples; Bell towers--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs; Belmont Boulevard (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2001-05</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>SSSP - Christ the King</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/743</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>