<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Maxwell House Hotel being razed, Nashville, Tennessee, 1962 July 20</dc:title>
<dc:description>The Maxwell House Hotel during the razing phase of the structure.  The hotel, which stood at the northeast corner of Fourth Avenue, North, and Church Street in downtown Nashville, was a prominent hotel at which several US Presidents and other dignitaries stayed, as well as being for years the center of Nashville&#8217;s social and political life.  It was built by Colonel John Overton Jr. and named for his wife, Harriet Maxwell Overton.  The architect was Isaiah Rogers.  The Maxwell House Hotel was destroyed by fire on Christmas night 1961.  Forms part of Record Group 412, Photographs Collection. 1 photograph negative on film strip: b &amp; w.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Maxwell House Hotel (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Fourth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Church Street (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1962-07-20</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 412 891 Maxwell House Being Razed 7-20-1962 002</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 412</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/6113</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>