<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Excerpt from Lori Harrington Oral History Interview, 2011 August 27</dc:title>
<dc:description>Excerpt from an oral history interview with Lori Harrington conducted on 27 August 2011 by Jared Brennan as part of the Flood 2010 Digital History Project. Lori Harrington discusses being rescued from her flooded home in the Richland Creek area of West Nashville during the May 2010 flood. 

The complete interview is available in the Special Collections Division.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Harrington, Lori--Interviews</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Facebook (Electronic resource);</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Community Response; Rescue; Rescue work; Flood damage; Floods--Nashville (Tenn.); Natural disasters; Storytelling--Nashville (Tenn.); Volunteer response--Nashville (Tenn.); Natural disasters--Nashville (Tenn.); Oral history--Library resources; Oral history--Sources;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--Floods; Nashville (Tenn.)--History--21st century; Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources;</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Harrington, Lori (Interviewee); Brennan, Jared (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Gibbons, Susannah (Transcriber)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>2011-08-27</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3 (9.72 MB; 05 min., 18 sec.)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>FDHHarringtonLClip001</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from:  Lori Harrington Oral History Interview. Born-digital recording(s) converted to mp3 format for online access in 2012 from 16bit 44.1khz WAV file archival master recording.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Flood 2010 Digital History Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2010-2019</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/3670</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>