<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Groundbreaking of the Lentz Center, Nashville, Tennessee, 1958 June </dc:title>
<dc:description>A photo related to the groundbreaking of the John J. Lentz Health Center on 23rd Avenue, North, officiated with Nashville Mayor West and County Judge Briley and other dignitaries, circa June 1958.  Dr. John J. Lentz was director of Health for the Davidson County Health Department.  The new facility became the main clinic for public health activities of Nashville and Davidson County, located at 311 23rd Avenue N.  Dr. Lentz started his career as a country doctor in 1906 and became director of public health for Davidson County in December, 1920. Forms part of Record Group 3, Metro Davidson County Photographer. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.   </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Lentz, John J.; Briley, Beverly, 1914-1980; West, Ben, 1911-1974</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Medical care--Tennessee--Nashville; Public health--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Twenty-third Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--Politics and government</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1958-06</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives </dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG3 1777 Lentz Center Groundbreaking Jun 1958004</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3 Metro Davidson County Photographer   </dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/7248</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>