<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Sunshine brings out golfers, and caddies smile, from the Nashville Times, 1940</dc:title>
<dc:description>A captioned photo from the Nashville Times (1940), about golfers in Nashville. The caption reads: &#8220;When Old Sol comes out golfers can&#8217;t be far behind &#8230; pictures above were taken at Richland Golf Club when the divot-diggers emerged in proverbial droves after being held indoors by recent continued rains and sloppy weather. At top three members of a foursome watch their partner get off a long drive as the caddies look on. At lower left Dr. R. L. Dozier watches Mrs. Howell Warner sink a put. Mrs. Warner is one of the city&#8217;s top-notch women golfers. Those grins on the caddies at lower right mean that spring is almost here and their business is picking up. And, no kidding, golfers are more generous with tips in spring.&#8221; The Richland Golf Club was organized in 1920.  Forms part of the Nashville Times newspaper collection. 1 digital photo.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Dozier, R. L.; Warner, Howell, Mrs.</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Richland Golf Club (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Women golfers--Tennessee--Nashville; Golfers--Tennessee--Nashville; Caddies--Tennessee--Nashville; Golf courses--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1940</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>GolfersNashville--NT-1940</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Times Newspaper Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4200</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>