<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Oh, thank you! Thank you!, 1957</dc:title>
<dc:description>An original political cartoon drawing created by Jack Knox, the Nashville Banner editorial cartoonist from the mid-1940s to early 1970s.  This cartoon pertains to the crisis in Syria of 1957.  A man ("Syria") reaches out to take "Economic Aid" from the point of a giant sickle (U.S.S.R.) that surrounds the man and is held by a giant hand.  Circa August 1957, at the height of the Cold War, Syria signed an agreement with Moscow for military and economic aid.  A few months earlier the U.S. Congress passed what became known as the "Eisenhower Doctrine," which named "international communism" as the greatest threat to the Syrian region.  This cartoon appeared in the Nashville Banner on October 29, 1957.  Forms part of the Jack Knox Political Cartoon Collection. 1 original cartoon drawing : b &amp; w ; 14 x 19 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Nashville Banner</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Capital City; Politics; Political cartoons--United States--20th century; Political cartoons--Tennessee--Nashville; Caricatures and cartoons--Tennessee--Nashville; Cartoonists--Tennessee--Nashville; Editorial cartoonists--Tennessee--Nashville; World politics--Caricatures and cartoons; Arab nationalism--Caricatures and cartoons; Communism--Caricatures and cartoons; Cartoonists; Economic &amp; political systems; Hammer &amp; sickle</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Middle East--Politics and government--20th century--Caricatures and cartoons; United States--Foreign relations--Middle East--Caricatures and cartoons; United States--Foreign relations--1953-1961--Caricatures and cartoons</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Knox, Jack, 1910- (Cartoonist)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Knox, Joseph T. (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1957-10</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Caricatures; Cartoons (Commentary); Editorial cartoons</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Knox NPL-322</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Jack Knox Political Cartoon Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/986</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>