<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Class officers, Hume-Fogg Yearbook, "The Echo" Nashville, Tennessee, 1925</dc:title>
<dc:description>The class officers, pictured in the 1925 yearbook of Hume-Fogg High School.  Left to right: Edmund Rogers (Salutatorian); Frances Carter (Valdictorian-Poet); Miriam Garfinkle (Salutatorian); William Quick (President); Matilda Treanor (Secretary); Frank McCall (Treasurer); Leah Rose Bernstein (Historian); Mary Eastes (Prophet); Daisy Marie Tucker (Will-Writer); and, Mary Jane Lowenheim (Assistant Will-Writer).  The Hume-Fogg High School is a public high school located at 700 Broadway in Nashville, Tennessee. In 1912 Hume High School and Fogg High School merged into Hume-Fogg at the school's current site on Broadway. The building was constructed in the Tudor Revival style by architects William B. Ittner and Robert Sharp. In 1942 Hume-Fogg was recast as a Technical and Vocational School. In 1982 it was restructured to serve as an academic magnet school for Nashville's gifted and talented students. Hume-Fogg was added to the National Registry of Historic Places in 1974. Forms part of the Hume-Fogg High School Yearbook Collection. 1 yearbook. </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rogers, Edmund; Carter, Frances; Garfinkle, Miriam; Quick, William; Goodlett, Frances; Treanor, Matilda; McCall, Frank; Bernstein, Leah Rose; Eastes, Mary; Tucker, Daisy Marie; Lowenheim, Mary Jane </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Hume-Fogg High School (Nashville, Tenn.)--History--Sources </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Public schools--Tennessee--Nashville; High schools--Tennessee--Nashville; 
Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville;  Schools--Tennessee--Nashville
</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Broadway Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1925</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Hume Fogg Yearbook 1925  009</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Hume-Fogg High School Yearbook Collection.</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1920-1929</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/10182</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>