<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Souvenir Program, The Board of the Martha O'Bryan Settlement Presents: Lucrezia Bori in Concert, 1926</dc:title>
<dc:description>A souvenir program from a concert performed by Lucrezia Bori, a celebrated Spanish operatic singer.  The show was at the Ryman Auditorium on November 26, 1926, presented by the Board of the Martha O'Bryan Settlement.  The Ryman Auditorium is located downtown on Fifth Avenue North in Nashville, Tennessee.  Forms part of the Naff Collection. 1 program : b &amp; w ; 8.5 x 11 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Bori, Lucrezia, 1887-1960</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Ryman Auditorium (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Performing Arts; Popular Culture; Entertainment; Music; Downtown Nashville; Advertisements; Performances--Tennessee--Nashville; Performing arts--Tennessee--Nashville; Concerts--Tennessee--Nashville; Music--Tennessee--Music; Advertising--Tennessee--Nashville; Musicians; Sopranos (Singers); Entertainers--Tennessee--Nashville; Entertainment--Tennessee--Nashville; Opera singers</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Fifth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Robinson, Francis, 1910- (Donor); Naff, Lula C., 1875-1960 (Collector)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1926</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text; Ephemera; Souvenir programs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Naff 8-K-8 Lucrezia Bori</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Naff Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1920-1929</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/847</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>