<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Oral history interview with Charles E. Kimbrough, 2005 September 14</dc:title>
<dc:description>An oral history interview with Dr. Charles Kimbrough, conducted on September 14, 2005 by Gwen Smith as part of the Nashville Public Library's Civil Rights Oral History Project.  Dr. Kimbrough marked the 100th interview conducted for the Civil rights Oral History Project.  Kimbrough discusses the modern civil rights movement in Tuskegee, Alabama and being the first black veterinarian in the state of Tennessee.  The complete interview and transcript are available in the Special Collections Division.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Kimbrough, Charles E.--Interviews</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Tuskegee Institute. School of Veterinary Medicine</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Civil Rights; Race Relations; African Americans; Education; Colleges and Universities; Civil rights movements--Alabama--History--20th century; Civil rights--Alabama--Macon County; Civil rights--Alabama--Tuskegee; Voting--Alabama; Civil rights--Tennessee--Nashville; African Americans--Civil rights--Tennessee--History--20th century; African Americans--Social conditions;  African American veterinarians--Tennessee; Veterinarians--Tennessee--Nashville; Race discrimination--Alabama</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--Race relations; Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Tuskegee (Ala.)--Race Relations; Tuskegee (Ala.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Kimbrough, Charles E. (Interviewee); Smith, Gwen (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>James, Carolyn (Transcriber); Public Library of Nashville and Davidson County</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>2005-09-14</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CROHPKimbrough11aclip1.mp3; CROHPKimbrough11aclip2.mp3; CROHPKimbrough1_transcript.pdf</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from:  CROHPKimbrough1 digital recording converted from wav to mp3 format in 2007.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Civil Rights Oral History Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1502</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>