<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Alfred Jackson, Nashville, Tennessee, n.d. </dc:title>
<dc:description>An undated photograph of &#8220;Uncle Alfred&#8221; Jackson, a formerly enslaved manservant to President Andrew Jackson.  He was born at the Hermitage prior to the Civil War and lived there his entire life.  He was responsible for maintaining the wagons and farm equipment on the estate.  After his emancipation, he became a tenant farmer on The Hermitage.  He also worked as a handyman and tour guide for the Ladies&#8217; Hermitage Association when the house opened as a museum. Alfred lived at The Hermitage longer than any other person on record.  He married Gracy and they had two children.  Upon his death in 1901, his funeral was held in the center hall of the mansion. He is buried in the Hermitage garden, near the tomb of President Jackson and his wife, Rachel.  Forms part of the Sarah Hunter Hicks Green Collection - Carl and Otto Giers Studio Photographs.  1 digitized glass-plate negative.   </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Giers family; Jackson, Alfred </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Hermitage (Hermitage, Tenn.) </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Portrait photography--History-20th Century ; Commercial photography--Tennessee--Nashville; Photographers--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Metro Historical Commission - Sarah Hunter Hicks Green; Carl &amp; Otto Giers Studio photographs </dc:contributor>
<dc:date>n.d.</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Group B Number 453--Alfred Jackson, body servant to Andrew Jackson, 1901 030</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Sarah Hunter Hicks Green Collection - Carl and Otto Giers Studio Photographs</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>19th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/10496</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>