<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Nashville Municipal Auditorium construction, 1961 February 18</dc:title>
<dc:description>The construction site, including an aerial view, of the Nashville Municipal Auditorium, circa February 18th, 1961.  This facility, located on Fourth Avenue N in downtown Nashville, opened on October 7th, 1962 and was the first public assembly facility in the Mid-South with air-conditioning.  In addition to being a music venue, it has hosted religious conferences and sporting events.  The aerial view shows the construction site from above, as well as two Greek Revival style buildings designed by William Strickland: St. Mary&#8217;s Catholic Church (Fifth Avenue N, right foreground) and the Tennessee State Capitol Building (bordered by Sixth Avenue and Charlotte).  Several government office facilities are seen, along with several buildings that are non-extant.  Forms part of Record Group 3, Metro Davidson County Photographer.  3 photograph negatives : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Nashville Municipal Auditorium (Tenn.); Tennessee State Capitol (Nashville, Tenn.); Tennessee State Office Building (Nashville); Nashville Bridge Company</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Public buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Capitols--Tennessee--Nashville; Auditoriums--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Fourth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Fifth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Sixth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Charlotte Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Tennessee--Capital and capitol</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1961-02-18</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 3 1221 Municipal Auditorium 001 - 003</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3 Metro Davidson County Photographer</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4665</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>