<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Martin Brady remembers the literary career of his father, Leo Brady, 2007 September 19</dc:title>
<dc:description>An edited excerpt with transcript and photograph from an interview with Martin Brady, conducted on 19 September 2007 by Deanna Larson at the Nashville StoryCorps StoryBooth, located in the Nashville Room of the Nashville Public Library.  Brady shares memories of his father's literary career, including his collaborations with Walter Kerr.  Out of Leo Brady's many works, Martin describes two plays (Yankee Doodle Boy, a play based on the life of George M. Cohan; Brother Orchid, based on a short story), a Broadway musical revue (Count Me In), and four novels (Edge of Doom, which was made into a movie by Samuel Goldwyn; Signs and Wonders; The Quiet Gun; and The Love Tap).  The complete, un-edited interview, as well as an index, is available in the Special Collections Division. These interviews were recorded by StoryCorps at the Nashville Public Library with the support of the Nashville Public Library Foundation and are provided courtesy of StoryCorps, a national initiative of Sound Portraits Productions to record and collect oral history interviews. www.storycorps.net</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Brady, Martin, 1952- --Interviews; Brady, Leo, 1917- ; Kerr, Walter, 1913-1996; Cohan, George M. (George Michael), 1878-1942; Goldwyn, Samuel, 1882-1974</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Popular Culture; Entertainment; Performing Arts; Theatre; Storytelling--Tennessee--Nashville; Authors, American--20th century--Biography; Dramatists, American--20th century--Biography; Drama--20th century; Playwrighting--20th century; Revues--20th century; Fiction--20th century; Novelists, American--20th century--Biography</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; United States--Intellectual life--20th century; United States--Social life and customs--20th century</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Brady, Martin, 1952- (Interviewee); Larson, Deanna, 1961-  (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>StoryCorps (Project)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>2007-09-18</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3 (3 min., 39 sec.)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>NPL000009_excerpt.mp3; NPL000009_transcript.pdf; NPL000009_g2.jpg</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from:  NPL000009 original StoryCorps interview edited by Aimee James in June 2008.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville StoryCorps StoryBooth Interviews 2007-2008</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1758</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>