<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Wendell J. Gore remembers his childhood paper route adventures, 2007 October 24</dc:title>
<dc:description>An edited excerpt with transcript and photograph from an interview with Wendell J. Gore, conducted on 24 October 2007 by StoryCorps facilitator Kate Wingate at the Nashville StoryCorps StoryBooth, located in the Nashville Room of the Nashville Public Library.  Gore shares memories of carrying a paper route while he was in high school.  The complete, un-edited interview, as well as an index, is available in the Special Collections Division.  These interviews were recorded by StoryCorps at the Nashville Public Library with the support of the Nashville Public Library Foundation and are provided courtesy of StoryCorps, a national initiative of Sound Portraits Productions to record and collect oral history interviews.  www.storycorps.net</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Gore, Wendell J., 1938- --Interviews</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Popular Culture; Business; Journalism; Storytelling--Tennessee--Nashville; Newspaper carriers--Tennessee--Nashville; Paperboys--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social conditions</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Gore, Wendell J., 1938- (Interviewee); Wingate, Kate (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>StoryCorps (Project); Public Library of Nashville and Davidson County</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>2007-10-24</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3 (2 min., 23 sec.)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>NPL000051_excerpt.mp3; NPL000051_gl.jpg; NPL000051_transcript.pdf</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from:  NPL1000051 original StoryCorps interview edited by interns Claire Ploegman and Jessica Harrell in November 2007.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville StoryCorps StoryBooth Interviews 2007-2008</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1392</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>