<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Stahlman Building in downtown Nashville, Tennessee, circa 1959 April 02</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of the Stahlman Building, located at Third Avenue North and Union Street (211 Union Street), circa April 2, 1959.  The twelve-story tall structure was built by newspaper publisher Major E. B. Stahlman. It was considered one of the city's first "skyscrapers" when it was built circa 1905-06. The Stahlman Building opened its doors on June 22, 1907. The building was designed by Otto Eggers of New York and J. Edwin Carpenter and Walter Dabney Blair, from Nashville. Carpenter, who also designed the Hermitage Hotel and other landmark buildings, was the first Tennessee-born architect to study at the Ecole des Beaux-Arts in Paris. The Stahlman Building first housed the Fourth National Bank and was the first in the city to have modern elevators. The architectural design features a base composed of a Greek Doric colonnade rising three floors with the fourth floor treated as a parapet, with seven identical floors above, and with two floors below a stylized neoclassical cornice (the later which has been removed). The building was renovated in the 1950s and art deco features were added, such as modern light fixtures and signage on Union Street. In 1971 Metro Government purchased the building and housed offices and courtrooms until circa 2003. The building reopened in 2007 as an apartment building, featuring retail and office space as well. Photographed by the Nashville architect Charles Wesley Warterfield, Jr. (1926-1998); the architectural photograph forms part of the Charles Warterfield Architectural Collection. Gift of: The Estate of Charles W. Warterfield, Jr., F. A. I. A. The original is a 35 mm color transparency (2 x 2 in. slide mount).</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Stahlman Building (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Business; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architects--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Third Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Union Street (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Warterfield, Charles W. (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Estate of Charles W. Warterfield, Jr., F.A.I.A. (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1959-04-02</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Slides; Photographs; Architectural photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>WSC 4509</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Charles Warterfield Architectural Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/2335</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>