<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>His foot's in an "Oregon boot!" now, circa 1944</dc:title>
<dc:description>An original political cartoon drawing created by Jack Knox, cartoonist with the Memphis Commercial Appeal from the early 1930s to circa 1944.  This anti-Nazi cartoon depicts the cloud of "D-Day" in the background, while a fearful Hitler has a heavy boot brace ("The weight of Allied Attacks") weighing down his foot ("17 or more Nazi Divisions") as he stands in Italy.  The Western Allied effort to liberate mainland Europe from Nazi occupation in a series of invasions and operations had a designated D-Day, such as the Battle of Normandy on June 6, 1944.  Prior to defeat by the Allies, Nazi Germany and the Axis Powers occupied most of Europe.  Hitler was aware of the caricatures and threatened to punish American cartoonists after the war.  Cartoonist Jack Knox worked for the Memphis Commercial Appeal following a short stint on the Evening Tennessean in Nashville.  Knox had written to the renowned cartoonist J. P. Alley asking if he could understudy with him on the Commercial Appeal.  When Alley became ill, he recommended Knox take his place on the staff.  In the mid-1940s, Knox returned to his native Nashville to accept a job as the editorial cartoonist with the Nashville Banner.  Forms part of the Jack Knox Political Cartoon Collection. 1 original cartoon drawing : b &amp; w ; 14. 17.5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Hitler, Adolf, 1889-1945--Caricatures and cartoons</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Commercial appeal, Memphis</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Military History; World War II; Capital City; Politics; Political cartoons--United States--20th century; Caricatures and cartoons--Tennessee--Memphis; Cartoonists--Tennessee--Memphis; Editorial cartoonists--Tennessee--Memphis; World War, 1939-1945--Caricatures and cartoons; Heads of state--Germany--Caricatures and cartoons; World War, 1939-1945--Italy--Caricatures and cartoons; World War, 1939-1945--Germany--Caricatures and cartoons; Cartoonists; Economic &amp; political systems; Military art &amp; science; Militarism--Germany; War allies</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Germany--Politics and government--1933-1945--Caricatures and cartoons; Germany--History--1933-1945--Caricatures and cartoons</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Knox, Jack, 1910- (Cartoonist)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Knox, Joseph T. (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1944</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Caricatures; Cartoons (Commentary); Editorial cartoons</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Knox NPL-316</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Jack Knox Political Cartoon Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>ca. 1944</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/980</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>