<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>The Megaphone, Central High School, Commencement Number, Nashville, Tennessee, 1919</dc:title>
<dc:description>The 1919 Commencement Number publication of Central High School known as &#8220;The Megaphone,&#8221; a student publication "affectionately dedicated by the editors" to Grover Cleveland Carney, Principal.  Central High School was founded in 1917 as the first public high school in the county system. One of the earliest student government associations in the South began here.  Many graduates became city and county political leaders, such as Nashville City Government Mayor Ben West and the first Metro Government Mayor, Beverly Briley. The last graduating class was 1971 after which the school, located in south Nashville on the hill above the State Fairgrounds on Raines Avenue between Wedgewood Avenue, and Southgate Avenue, was torn down and converted to a Public Television Station.  Forms part of the Nashville Yearbooks Collection.  1 yearbook. 
</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Carney, Grover Cleveland</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Central High School (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Public schools--Tennessee--Nashville; Education--Tennessee--Nashville; High Schools--Tennessee--Nashville </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1919</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Megaphone Central High 1919 Yearbook 001 through 099</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Yearbooks Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1910-1919</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/9989</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>