<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Nashville, the workings of the City under its new form of government: a statement in detail showing financial operations from October 1, 1883, to September 30, 1884, Reports of the various officers connected with the different departments, compiled for publication by James T. Bell </dc:title>
<dc:description>An official publication of the City of Nashville, Tennessee, titled 
&#8220;Nashville, the workings of the City under its new form of government: a statement in detail showing financial operations from October 1, 1883, to September 30, 1884, Reports of the various officers connected with the different departments, compiled for publication by James T. Bell.&#8221;  Mayor C. Hooper Phillips is pictured in the frontispiece of the book.  
Forms part of the Publications Collection: Nashville, the Workings of the City under its New Form of Government, A Statement in Detail showing Financial Operations from October 1, 1883, to September 30, 1884, Reports of the Various Officers Connected with the Different Departments, compiled for publication by James T. Bell, Recorder.  1 book publication. 
</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Phillips, C. Hooper;  Bell, James T.</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Mayors--Tennessee--Nashville--History--Sources; Public health--Tennessee--Nashville; Education--Tennessee--Nashville; Financial statements--Tennessee--Nashville--History--Sources; Public works--Tennessee--Nashville; Infrastructure (Economics)--Tennessee--Nashville--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1885</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Nashville workings of the city 1883 to 1884 001</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Annual Statement City of Nashville, 1884</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1880-1889</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/10810</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>