<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Hermes and Vasso Pan visit Nashville, Tennessee, 1939 February 10</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of Vasso and Hermes Pan, sister and brother who were visiting Nashville. An article titled "Noted Hollywood Dance Director Visits Nashville," ran in the 10 February 1939 edition of the Nashville Banner newspaper.  "Hermes Pan, native of Memphis and reared in Nashville, who is now dance director of RKO Radio Studios, arrived in Nashville with his sister, Vasso, yesterday by train from New Orleans for a few days' visit to his former home." The article ran with a headshot of Pan. This photo was taken by a Banner staff photographer but did not run with the article. Children of Panelis and Mary Huston Panagiotopulos, this elegant brother and sister were both dancers. Hermes was born in Memphis, TN in 1905.  His family moved to Nashville when he was twelve, where he studied several years at Miss Georgia's Private School. From 1927-1930 he was a Broadway dancer. Pan came to Hollywood as part of a choreography team with his sister, Vasso. He first worked with Fred Astaire and Ginger Rogers on the film Flying Down to Rio in 1933. Combining classical dance elements with tap influenced athleticism, he went on to choreograph a series of musicals for the team. For Fred Astaire and Ginger Rogers he created the dances "The Continental" and "The Carioca". Hermes Pan won an Academy Award in 1937, the last one given for choreography, and an Emmy in 1961. He passed away in Hollywood in 1990.  Forms part of the Nashville Banner Archives. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 3.25 x 4.25 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Pan, Hermes, 1905-1990; Meade, Vasso Pan, 1906-2001</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Performing Arts; Dance; Popular Culture; Entertainment; Performing arts--Tennessee--Nashville; Dance--Tennessee--Nashville; Dancers--Tennessee--Nashville; Entertainers--Tennessee--Nashville; Brothers and sisters--Tennessee--Nashville; Choreographers--Tennessee--Nashville; Entertainment--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1939-02-10</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives; Film negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BN 1939-090</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1944</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>