<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Hooberry&#8217;s Book Store, Country Kitchen and Clifton Apartments, Nashville, Tennessee, circa 1950</dc:title>
<dc:description>Two photographs showing an apartment building above the Hooberry&#8217;s Book Store at 140 Fifth Avenue N in downtown Nashville, Tennessee, with the Country Kitchen restaurant, and some vacant spaces.  The 1949 City Directory cites the Clifton Apartments at 140 Fifth Avenue N, and a restaurant owned or managed by Solon L. Boyd, though not identified specifically as &#8220;Country Kitchen.&#8221;  The 1950 and 1957 City Directories list the Hooberry&#8217;s Book Store at 140 Fifth Avenue N.  A poster advertising an upcoming music at the Ryman Auditorium featuring the gospel singing groups Oak Ridge, Speer Family and others on the Friday May 7th performance date.  Forms part of Record Group 3, Metro Davidson County Photographer. 2 photograph negatives: b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Hooberry&#8217;s Book Store (Nashville, Tenn.); Clifton Apartments (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Business--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Bookstores--Tennessee--Nashville; Restaurants--Tennessee--Nashville; Apartments--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1950</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 3 706 Buildings, companies 001; RG 3 706 Buildings, companies 002</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3 Metro Davidson County Photographer</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4923</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>