<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>S. Hurok Inc. presents Anna Pavlowa and her Ballet Russe, 1924</dc:title>
<dc:description>A program from a dance program performed by Anna Pavlowa and her Ballet Russe on February 27, 1924, presented on tour by concert agent-impresario Sol Hurok.  The show was at the Ryman Auditorium on Fifth Avenue North in Nashville, Tennessee.  Anna Pavolwa was a world-famous Russian ballet dancer who later became an early film star for Universal.  Forms part of the Naff Collection. 1 program : col. ; 5.5 x 8 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Pavlova, Anna, 1881-1931; Hurok, Sol, 1888-1974</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Ryman Auditorium (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Performing Arts; Popular Culture; Entertainment; Dance; Downtown Nashville; Performances--Tennessee--Nashville; Performing arts--Tennessee--Nashville; Ballet--Soviet Union; Ballet programs--Tennessee--Nashville; Dancers--Soviet Union; Concert agents--United States; Impresarios--United States; Ballet dancers--Soviet Union; Ballerinas--Soviet Union; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Entertainers--Tennessee--Nashville; Entertainment--Tennessee--Nashville; Ballet--Tennessee--Nashville; Ballet dancers--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Fifth Avenue North (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Robinson, Francis, 1910- (Donor); Naff, Lula C., 1875-1960 (Collector)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1924</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text; Ephemera; Programs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Naff 2-46 Anna Pavlowa</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Naff Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1920-1929</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/830</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>