<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Greetings from Nashville, Tenn., circa 1965</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard of the Tennessee State Capitol and Tennessee State Office Building, along with the Nashville Municipal Auditorium.  The Nashville Municipal Auditorium was the primary indoor sports and concert venue in Nashville from the time of its completion in 1962 until the completion of the Nashville Arena (now Sommet Center) in 1996.  Forms part of the Norton Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Tennessee State Capitol (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville Municipal Auditorium (Tenn.); Tennessee State Office Building (Nashville)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Downtown Nashville; Capital City; Buildings; Architecture; Entertainment; Popular Culture; Sports &amp; Recreation; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Public buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Office buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Auditoriums--Tennessee--Nashville; Government facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Cultural facilities--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Southern Post Card Co. (Publisher)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1965</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Norton - 0554</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Norton Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1817</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>