<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Letter from P.J. Williamson to his wife, Eunice, during the Civil War, 1862 December 25</dc:title>
<dc:description>A letter from Dutch immigrant Peter J. Williamson back home to his wife, Eunice, during the Civil War.  In 1862, Williamson enlisted as a Private in the 1st Wisconsin Cavalry, Company F and was ultimately promoted to Full 1st Lieutenant.  During the war, Williamson's regiment was involved in scouting and raids in Missouri and Arkansas and saw battle in the Middle Tennessee, Chickamauga, and Atlanta campaigns. In this letter from Camp Davidson, Missouri, on Christmas Day, Williamson talks about the difficulty of fording a particularly high river en route to Pocahontas, Arkansas, and the decision to march back to Lesterville, Missouri, where his regiment remains camped at the present time.  He mentions that each officer contributed five dollars to purchase beer for all the soldiers to celebrate the holiday.  Next Williamson expresses sadness for the soldiers who lost their lives fighting at Fredericksburg, Virginia.  He requests that Eunice send all letters to Pilots Knob.  He warns her not to worry if he is not able to write regularly.  He assures her that most of the unit is in very good health, and says that if he were sick he would have somebody else write for him.  Williamson closes out the letter by mentioning the warm weather and asking to hear from various friends and family.  Forms part of the Peter J. Williamson Letters. 1 letter : col. ; 7.5  x 12  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Williamson, Peter J., 1823-1907; Williamson, Eunice Leihy, 1840-1928</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>United States. Army. Wisconsin Cavalry Regiment, 1st (1861-1865); United States. Army--Military life</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Military History; Civil War; Popular Culture; War; Soldiers--United States--Correspondence; Soldiers--United States--Personal narratives; Immigrants--Wisconsin; Immigrants' writings, Dutch; Christmas; Military camps--Missouri--Davidson; Marching; Transportation--Missouri; Battle casualties</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--19th century--Sources; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Personal narratives; Tennessee--History--Civil War, 1861-1865; Missouri --History--Civil War, 1861-1865</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Williamson, Peter J., 1823-1907</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Currey, Martha T. (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1862-12-25</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text; Letters (correspondence)</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>PJW - f, 20</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Peter J. Williamson Letters</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1922</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>