<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Statue of Commodore, Vanderbilt University, Nashville, Tenn., between 1907 and 1914</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard of the statue of Commodore Cornelius Vanderbilt in front of Kirkland Hall on the campus of Vanderbilt University in Nashville, Tennessee. The university is named for shipping and rail tycoon "Commodore" Cornelius Vanderbilt. He was 79 years old when he decided to donate a one million dollar endowment gift that founded Vanderbilt University in the spring of 1873. Commodore Cornelius Vanderbilt had a vision of a university that would "contribute to strengthening the ties that should exist between all sections of our common country." Forms part of the Nashville Room Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Vanderbilt, Cornelius, 1794-1877--Statues</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Vanderbilt University</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Education; Colleges and Universities; Private Schools; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Universities and colleges--Tennessee--Nashville; Statues--Tennessee--Nashville; Universities &amp; colleges--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>R. M. Mills Book Store (Publisher)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>between 1907 and 1914</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Nash - 94a</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1900-1909; 1910-1919</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/2298</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>