<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Porte cochere closeup of the Bonnie Brae residence, Nashville, Tennessee, n.d.</dc:title>
<dc:description>
The residence known as &#8220;Bonnie Brae,&#8221; once rested on twenty-two acres along the hillside of the present-day southwestern corner of Woodlawn Drive and I-440.  The Villager Condominiums stand there now. &#8220;Bonnie Brae&#8221; derives its name from the Scottish meaning &#8220;excellent or pretty, slope or hill.&#8221; Built by Bertrand Howe in 1914, this was home to Bertram and his wife Lelia from 1914-1921. The next owners were Howell H. and Elise Campbell beginning in 1922 and continuing for almost fifty years. &#8220;Bonnie Brae&#8221; was a grand estate. These digital reproductions were scanned from the &#8220;Bonnie Brae&#8221; photo album, belonging to the Campbell&#8217;s granddaughter Ann Dobson Tidwell. 1 digital photograph. </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Howe family; Campbell family</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Porticoes--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture, Domestic--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Dwellings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Mansions--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Hillsboro Pike (Nashville, Tenn.); Woodlawn Drive (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>n.d.</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Port Cochere closeup027</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Ann Dobson Tidwell Digital Images Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4332</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>