<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Woodland Street Presbyterian Church, 2002 January</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of Woodland Street Presbyterian Church located at 211 North Eleventh Street in the East Nashville neighborhood of Nashville, Tennessee.  Woodland Presbyterian Church was organized in 1858 as the First Presbyterian Church of Edgefield at Fifth and Woodland Street, and was renamed when Edgefield became part of Nashville toward the end of the 19th century. When its grand second building, completed in 1890, was destroyed by fire in 1916, the congregation voted to relocate "near the edge of the city" -- the present location at North 11th Street and Gartland Avenue. The main part of the present building, constructed during World War I, was finished in 1917 and dedicated in November of 1918.  The foundation is made of smooth cut stone blocks.  The exterior walls are also made of smooth cut stone blocks.  The roof is made of tar shingles.  The windows are narrow and arched.  Some are composed of stained glass.  The doors are wood.  Special features include a dome with red metal roofing, pediments and columns.  Forms part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project. 1 photograph : col. ; 4  x 6  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Woodland Street Presbyterian Church (Nashville, Tenn.); First Presbyterian Church of Edgefield (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Popular Culture; Religion; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Religious facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Church architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Presbyterian church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Details; Domes--Tennessee--Nashville; Arches--Tennessee--Nashville; Porticoes--Tennessee--Nashville; Columns--Tennessee--Nashville; Pediments--Tennessee--Nashville; Churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Protestant churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Presbyterian churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural details--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs; Eleventh Street (Nashville, Tenn.); East Nashville (Nashville, Tenn.); Edgefield (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2002-01</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>SSSP - Woodland St Pres</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1568</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>