<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Christmas card from Mrs. Chauncey C. Foster and Elizabeth, n.d.</dc:title>
<dc:description>A Christmas card of the second &#8220;Fairview&#8221; home of the Foster family, located on the Hillsboro Road at Abbott Lane in Nashville, Tennessee.  After the first home was destroyed by fire circa 1933, this home was built upon the foundation of the old.  The structure was designed by Henry C. Hibbs, architect, and was built by Boone Construction Company.  It was an attractive seven-room modern structure that was of brick construction with a cement shingle roof.  This was the home of Mrs. Chauncey C. Foster and Elizabeth.  Located at 3901 Hillsboro Road at Abbott Martin Road, this was a residential home from 1933 until January, 1955. These digital reproductions were scanned from the scrapbook of Mrs. Frank A. Wilk (Alva Herbert Wilk). 1 digital photograph.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Foster family</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture, Domestic--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Dwellings--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Mansions--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Hillsboro Pike (Nashville, Tenn.); Abbott Martin Road (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>n.d.</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Wilk scrapbook pg 021 Fairview holiday card</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Mrs. Frank A. Wilk Digital Photographs Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4930</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>