<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>The Hippodrome, circa 1968 February</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of the Hippodrome arena, located across from Centennial Park at 2613 West End Avenue in Nashville, Tennessee. Advertised as "the South's largest, finest roller rink," this multi-purpose facility served as a roller skating rink, ball room, sports arena and entertainment center from circa 1914 until 1968. It was at the time the largest and most popular indoor arena and entertainment center in town, providing decades of fun and popularity. Tony Sudekum, founder of the Crescent Amusement Company, owned the Hippodrome for most of its history. There were big-band dances in the late 1940s that included such famous acts as Benny Goodman, Xavier Cugat, Harry James and Sonny Dunham. Earlier, during the Depression years, there were walk-a-thons. Circa 1934, the Nashville Tennessean newspaper sponsored the city's first Golden Gloves boxing tournament at the Hippodrome, a very popular event that continued for the next thirty years. During World War II, the Hippodrome served as a USO facility where many soldiers enjoyed the social events and refreshments. The building was razed in 1968 to make way for construction of the Holiday Inn-Vanderbilt. Loyal fans of the Hippodrome staged a "last lap" skating party March 26, 1968, before demolition began. Demolition crews had been tearing down the structure when a June 13 fire caused by sparks from acetylene torches used by workers on the roofing beams hastened the building's demise. Photographed by the Nashville architect Charles Wesley Warterfield, Jr. (1926-1998); the architectural photograph forms part of the Charles Warterfield Architectural Collection. Gift of: The Estate of Charles W. Warterfield, Jr., F. A. I. A. The original is a 35 mm color transparency (2 x 2 in. slide mount).</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Hippodrome Skating Rink (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Business; Sports &amp; Recreation; Popular Culture; Entertainment; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architects--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Roller-skating rinks--Tennessee--Nashville; Skating rinks--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Sports facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Arenas--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville; Sports &amp; recreation facilities--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; West End Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Warterfield, Charles W. (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Estate of Charles W. Warterfield, Jr., F.A.I.A. (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1968-02</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Slides; Photographs; Architectural photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>WSC 0771</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Charles Warterfield Architectural Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/2237</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>