<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Nashville Vols baseball team celebrate a win, 1948 September 21</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of the Nashville Vols baseball team celebrating after a win in their club house. This photograph ran in the 22 September 1948 edition of the Nashville Banner with the caption, "Vols Hope To Rubber Stamp This Scene Soon - Twice now, the Vol club house has been the scene of a mild celebration such as you see here after Nashville's 18-2 victory over Mobile last night which put the Gilbertmen in the playoff finals against Birmingham. A similar demonstration took place after the pennant was clinched. It's a scene the Vols hope to duplicate with extra touches after the series with the Barons. The winner will play in the Dixie Series. In the first row (left to right) are Batboy Skeets Thompson, Carmen Mauro, Manager Larry Gilbert, Road Secretary W. A. Lillard, Pete Mallory (who bear the Bears with a six-hit job), Coach George Hennessey and Buster Boguskie.  Identified in the back row are Roy Easterwood, Joe Damato (just over Mauro's left shoulder), Lee Holloman, George Byam, Chuck Workwood, Ray Woodward (behind Workman) and Charlie Gilbert." Forms part of the Nashville Banner Archives. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 3.25 x 4.25 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Thompson, Skeets; Mauro, Carmen; Gilbert, Larry; Lillard, W.A.; Mallory, Pete; Hennessey, George; Boguskie, Buster; Easterwood, Roy; Damato, Joe; Holloman, Lee; Byam, George; Workwood, Chuck; Woodward, Ray; Gilbert, Charlie</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Vols (Baseball team)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Sports &amp; Recreation; Sports Teams; Baseball; Popular Culture; Entertainment; Baseball--Tennessee--Nashville; Baseball players--Tennessee--Nashville; Baseball teams--Tennessee--Nashville; Clubhouses--Tennessee--Nashville; Baseball coaches--Tennessee--Nashville; Baseball uniforms--Tennessee--Nashville; Sports--Tennessee--Nashville; Sports teams--Tennessee--Nashville; Baseball managers--Tennessee--Nashville; Athletes--American--Tennessee--Nashville; Celebrations--Tennessee--Nashville; Coaches (Athletics)--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Morgan, Walter (photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1948-09-21</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives; Film negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BN 1948-16</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1949</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>