<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>The Fourth Stanza of The Song of the Night Writers, Watkins Institute, 1968</dc:title>
<dc:description>&#8220;The Fourth Stanza of The Song of the Night Writers&#8221; is a publication by &#8220;The Night Writers&#8221; of Watkins Institute in 1968.  The index of titles and authors consists of: Brentwood by Rosalie C. Batson -- All My Sheep All My Lambs by Mary Louise Derseweh -- The Art League, Its Growing Years by Ella Mae Harris -- A Day at Cheekwood by Maggie B. Treadway -- Harpeth Presbyterian Church by Felix H. Treadway -- Nashville is Well-Watered by Reda C. Goff -- My Favorite Soldier by Lucile McDonald -- This is Your Life, Troy Lynn by Edna Mullins -- The Streets of Nashville Can Talk by Martha Morris -- Mamma, Mamma, Here He Comes by Ruth Witt -- Paul Fitzsimmons Eve, Surgeon Extraordinary by Nona Sparks -- The Land That Was by Edna Lewis -- Nashville&#8217;s &#8216;Senior Citizens&#8217; by Josephine Bamback -- A Great Teacher by Flossie L. Turner -- Christmas Panic! By Betty Casha -- Nashville by Juanita Cate -- Zachariah White, Pioneer by Mary Glenn Hearne -- The Finest Teacher I Ever Knew by William F. Kautzman -- A Day to Remember by Peggy Williams -- Transformation, A Dream by Lois Meguiar Hadley -- Evergreen Place, A House in Nashville History -- Nashville, 2000 A.D. by John Stroud.  Forms part of the Betty Hadley Collection.  </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Crabb, Alfred Leland, 1884-1979</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Watkins Institute (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Education--Tennessee--Nashville; Urban life--Tennessee--Nashville; Manners and customs--Tennessee--Nashville </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Intellectual life</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Betty Hadley (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Betty Hadley Coll Song of Night Writers 1968</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Betty Hadley Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/11522</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>