<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Oral history interview with James H. Crowder, 1986 August 28, excerpt 15</dc:title>
<dc:description>An excerpt from an oral history interview with Nashville barbershop owner James H. Crowder, conducted on 28 August 1986 by Reavis Mitchell as part of the Homecoming '86 Oral History Project.  Crowder discusses how his father ran a ten-chair barber shop and barber college.  The complete interview, as well an index, is available in the Special Collections Division.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Crowder, James Henry, 1908-1997--Interviews</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Business; Enterprise; African Americans; Education; Businesspeople--Tennessee--Nashville; Barbers--Tennessee--Nashville; African Americans--Tennessee--Nashville; African American business enterprises--Tennessee--Nashville; Business enterprises--Tennessee--Nashville; Barbershops--Tennessee--Nashville; Barbering--Study and teaching--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Commerce</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Crowder, James Henry, 1908-1997 (Interviewee); Mitchell, Reavis (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1986-08-28</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3 (43 sec.)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>OHP86Crowderbclip7</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from:  OHP86Crowder audio cassette recording converted to mp3 format in 2006.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Homecoming '86 Oral History Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1980-1989</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/846</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>