<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>That would certainly be more [practical], circa 1963</dc:title>
<dc:description>An original political cartoon drawing created by Jack Knox (1910-1985), the Nashville Banner editorial cartoonist from the mid-1940s to early 1970s.  This caricature relates to the city and county governments' finding a practical solution in establishing a consolidated Metro government.  It shows a man ("Greater Nashville") standing with each foot in separate rowboats ("City Gov't" and "County Gov't").  As he tries to row, he aims toward a single rowboat ("One Gov't").  In 1963, Beverly Briley was elected the first mayor of the Metropolitan Government of Nashville and Davidson County, and he served in that capacity from 1963 to 1975.  Forms part of the Jack Knox Political Cartoon Collection. 1 original cartoon drawing : b &amp; w ; 12.5 x 20 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Briley, Beverly, 1914-1980--Caricatures and cartoons</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Banner</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Capital City; City Government; County Government; Consolidation; Metropolitan Government; Politics; Political cartoons--United States--20th century; Political cartoons--Tennessee--Nashville; Caricatures and cartoons--Tennessee--Nashville; Cartoonists--Tennessee--Nashville; Editorial cartoonists--Tennessee--Nashville; Metropolitan government--Tennessee--Nashville; Editorial cartoons--Tennessee--Nashville; Mayors--Tennessee--Nashville--Caricatures and cartoons; Annexation (Municipal government)--Tennessee--Nashville; Metropolitan areas--Tennessee--Nashville; Cartoonists; Politics &amp; government--Tennessee--Nashville; Economic &amp; social conditions--Tennessee--Nashville; Government officials--American--Tennessee--Nashville; Economic &amp; political systems</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--Politics and government; Tennessee--Capital and capitol</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Knox, Jack, 1910- (Cartoonist)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Knox, Joseph T. (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1963</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Caricatures; Cartoons (Commentary); Editorial cartoons</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Knox NPL-150</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Jack Knox Political Cartoon Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/862</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>