<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Davidson County Court House, Nashville, Tenn., between 1910 and 1915</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard of the Davidson County Court House as it appeared around 1910.  The courthouse was designed in 1857 by Francis Strickland, son of William Strickland, who built the State Capitol. Construction on the building started in 1859 and finished in 1863. This Strickland courthouse served as the epicenter for a bustling Nashville for eighty years. In 1909-1910 the Court House was remodeled and enlarged by the replacement of its gable roof with a fourth story as pictured on this postcard. The building was demolished in 1935, and in 1937 the present Metropolitan Court House was completed to replace it.  Forms part of the Nashville Room Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Davidson County Court House (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architects; Buildings; City Government; Downtown Nashville; Capital City; County Government; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Details; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Public buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Municipal buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Plazas--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville; Columns--Tennessee--Nashville; Government facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Courthouses--Tennessee--Nashville; Business districts--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Public Square (Nashville, Tenn.)--History--Sources; Court House Square (Nashville, Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>between 1910 and 1915</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Nash-30b-Davidson County Court House, Nashville, Tenn.</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1900-1909; 1910-1919</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/729</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>