<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Oral history interview with John H. Arriola, 2007 June 05</dc:title>
<dc:description>Oral history excerpts from an oral history interview with Nashville businessman, former State Representative for the 53rd District, civic leader and Davidson County, Tennessee Clerk John H. Arriola, Jr., conducted on 05 June 2007 by James T. Havron as part of the Nashville Business Leaders Oral History Project.  In the excerpts, Arriola discusses growing up in Nashville; attending Fall Elementary School; his family's history in small business; his mother's experience in the service industry; the Powers' family fish market; his college business education at the University of Tennessee at Martin; participation in a unique internship opportunity and how it turned into a job in the healthcare industry; the startup of Norman Couser's Country Cooking and the "meat and three" style menu; the decline in locally grown produce as a result of urbanization; his parents' significant role and pride in the family business; how the business will stay in the family and how both immediate and extended family are involved in upkeep and improvement; and Arriola's advice about starting a business in the service industry, emphasizing time commitment.  The complete interview, as well as an index, is available in the Special Collections Division.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Arriola, John H.--Interviews; Powers, Addie; Powers, Harry; Baker, William H., d. 1984; Stone, John M., d. 2006; Elliott, J.D.</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Fall School (Nashville, Tenn.); Metropolitan Nashville General Hospital; Nashville Memorial Hospital (Tenn.); Norman Couser's Country Cooking (Nashville, Tenn.);
Croft House (Davidson County, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Education; Elementary Schools; Colleges and Universities; Business; Enterprise; Restaurants; Popular Culture; Food; Businesspeople--Tennessee--Nashville; Food service--Tennessee--Nashville; Restaurants--Tennessee--Nashville; Fish trade--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Businesspeople--Interviews; Service industries--Tennessee--Davidson County; Family-owned business enterprises--Tennessee--Nashville; Hospitality industry--Tennessee--Nashville; Hospitals--Tennessee--Nashville; Public hospitals--Tennessee--Nashville; Internship programs--Tennessee--Nashville; Hospital and community--Tennessee--Nashville; Health facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Cookery, American--Southern style; Farm produce--Tennessee--Nashville; Agriculture and state--Tennessee--Nashville; Urbanization--Tennessee--Davidson County; Entrepreneurship</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Commerce; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Eighth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Chestnut Street (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Arriola, John H. (Interviewee); Havron, James T., 1960- (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Public Library of Nashville and Davidson County</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>2007-06-05</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>NBLArriolaJ1001clip1; NBLArriolaJ1003clip1; NBLArriolaJ1005and1006clip1; NBLArriolaJ1008clip1; NBLArriolaJ1009clip1; NBLArriolaJ1001clip2; NBLArriolaJ1010clip1</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from:  NBLArriolaJ digital recording converted from wav to mp3 format in 2007.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Business Leaders Oral History Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1464</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>