<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Nashville Decatur Railroad depot in Nashville, Tennessee, n.d.</dc:title>
<dc:description>An undated photograph of the non-extant Nashville &amp; Decatur Railroad depot building, built in 1868. The original immense Gothic Revival structure was located at the corner of Chestnut Street and Fourth Avenue (Cherry Street) and constructed of handmade brick and lime mortar with wooden beam framework. The Nashville and Decatur (N&amp;D) ran from Nashville through Columbia to Tennessee's southern border at Alabama; it also extended from Columbia to Mt. Pleasant. The company originated on July 1, 1861, when the Central Southern, Tennessee &amp; Alabama, and Tennessee &amp; Alabama Central Railroads renewed an annual agreement to operate as three financial entities under the name Nashville &amp; Decatur Railroad. The Nashville &amp; Decatur did not become a single corporation until 1867. In the 1930s, the Nashville Cotton Oil Mill began operation in the Old Cherry Street Depot. It was purchased by Bass Business Storage in1988. Photographed by the Nashville architect Charles Wesley Warterfield, Jr. (1926-1998); the architectural photograph forms part of the Charles Warterfield Architectural Collection. Gift of: The Estate of Charles W. Warterfield, Jr., F. A. I. A. The original is a 35 mm color transparency (2 x 2 in. slide mount).</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Nashville and Decatur Railroad Company--History--Sources; Nashville Cotton Oil Mill (Tenn.); Bass Business Storage (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Business; Capital City; Transportation; Architects--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Public buildings; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Railroads--Tennessee--History--Sources; Railroad stations--Tennessee--Nashville; Business enterprises--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Fourth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Cherry Street (Nashville, Tenn.); Chestnut Street (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Warterfield, Charles W. (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Estate of Charles W. Warterfield, Jr., F.A.I.A. (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>19--</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Slides; Photographs; Architectural photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>WSC 3858</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Charles Warterfield Architectural Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/11</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>