<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Andrew Jackson behind pickets, from the Nashville Times, 1940</dc:title>
<dc:description>A captioned photo from the Nashville Times (1940), about &#8220;three pickets kept vigil before the Andrew Jackson hotel today after 185 employees walked out on strike.&#8221;  The Andrew Jackson hotel opened in August of 1924 on the east side of Memorial Plaza on the corner of Sixth Avenue and Deaderick Street. The massive brick structure boasted 400 guest rooms. During the impact of urban renewal efforts, the hotel was demolished circa 1971, to make room for the Tennessee Performing Arts Center and the James K. Polk State Office Building.  Forms part of the Nashville Times newspaper collection. 1 digital photo.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Andrew Jackson Hotel (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Strikes and lockouts--Tennessee--Nashville; Picketing--Tennessee--Nashville; Hotels--Tennessee--Nashville; Labor--Tennessee--Nashville--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1940</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>LaborStrikesAndrewJacksonHotel--NT-1940</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Times Newspaper Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4188</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>