<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>"Put a candle in the window" as sung by the Christ the King's Boys' Choir, circa 1950 December 05</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of the Christ the King's Boys' Choir singing "Put a candle in the window" at the 1950 Fannie Battle Social Workers' Christmas tea, held at the home of Mrs. Tony Sudekum.  From left to right, the singers are: Robert Kirchner, Joe Patrick, Danny Badacour, Johnny Lawrence, William Morrison, Billy Boyd, Charles York, George Patrick, Shelton Johnson and Paul St. Charles.  This photograph illustrated the newspaper article "Betty Banner Heeds Bid to Fannie Battle Holiday Tea," published in the 5 December 1950 issue of the Nashville Banner.  Forms part of the Fannie Battle Day Home Records. 1 photograph :  b &amp; w ; 9.5 x 7.5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Kirchner, Robert; Patrick, Joe; Badacour, Danny; Lawrence, Johnny; Morrison, William; Boyd, Billy; York, Charles; Patrick, George; Johnson, Shelton; St. Charles, Paul; Sudekum, Nettie Fessler, b. ca. 1893--Homes and haunts--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Fannie Battle Day Home; Fannie Battle Social Workers</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Capital City; Organizations; Popular Culture; Children's History; Performing Arts; Music; Women in charitable work--Tennessee--Nashville; Charity--Tennessee--Nashville; Charities--Tennessee--Nashville; Day care centers--Tennessee--Nashville; Altruism--Tennessee--Nashville; Benevolence--Tennessee--Nashville; Social work with children--Tennessee--Nashville; Women--Charities; Child welfare; Christmas carols; Caroling--Tennessee--Nashville; Holidays--Tennessee--Nashville; Boys' choirs--Tennessee--Nashville; Children's choirs--Tennessee--Nashville; Charitable organizations--Tennessee--Nashville; Community service--Tennessee--Nashville; Economic &amp; social conditions--Tennessee--Nashville; Boys--Tennessee--Nashville; Boys--Tennessee--Nashville; Choirs (Music)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Davidson County (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Morgan, Walter H. (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1950-12-05</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>FBDHR-SB-Carol Publicity-1950-B9, f27-p1</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Fannie Battle Day Home Records</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1914</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>