<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of  McKendree Methodist Church, Nashville, Tennessee, next door to the Princess Theatre, between 1930 and 1940</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of McKendree Methodist Church at 523 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, circa 1930s.  The church was named for Bishop William McKendree, the first American bishop. This is the fourth McKendree Methodist Church building to occupy this site. The first building was completed in 1833 and hosted the funeral of James K. Polk, 11th President of the United States.  In 1876, a new larger Gothic building was erected. Three years later it burned, and a third building was erected in 1882.  This building was also destroyed by fire in 1905. The present church was dedicated 12 October 1912. Additions to this marble, Neo-classic structure were made in 1966.  The Princess Theatre, which began as a vaudeville theatre and later became a movie theatre, is visible next door to the church.  Forms part of the Nashville Banner Archives.  1 photograph : b &amp; w ; 8 x 10 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>McKendree Methodist Church (Nashville, Tenn.); Princess Theatre (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Performing Arts; Theatre; Popular Culture; Entertainment; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Methodist church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Neoclassicism (Architecture)--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Church Street (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>between 1930 and 1940</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/tiff (28.9 MB)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BP-Nash-Churches-McKendree Methodist Church</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/464</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>