<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>First Baptist Church, of Nashville, Tennessee, showing an early phase of architectural razing during the new building project, circa 1967</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of the First Baptist Church, Nashville, Tennessee, located at 108 Seventh Avenue South, on the corner of Broadway and 7th Avenue South, showing the original steeple tower and adjacent upper arch structures, during an early phase of the building project of October 1967 to 1970. The building was razed, though the original steeple tower was maintained and incorporated, to establish a new and larger church building. The First Baptist Church was originally organized in the year 1820, then later relocating to Broadway in 1886. The architectural style is American Gothic, with a variety of arches adorning the building. Photographed by the Nashville architect Charles Wesley Warterfield, Jr. (1926-1998); the architectural photograph forms part of the Charles Warterfield Architectural Collection. Gift of: The Estate of Charles W. Warterfield, Jr., F. A. I. A. The original is a 35 mm color transparency (2 x 2 in. slide mount).</dc:description>
<dc:subject>First Baptist Church (Nashville, Tenn.)--Pictorial works</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Baptist Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Church architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Architects--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Religious facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; 
Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; 
Arches--Tennessee--Nashville; Steeples--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Seventh Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Broadway (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Warterfield, Charles W. (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Estate of Charles W. Warterfield, Jr., F. A. I. A. (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1967</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still image; Slides; Architectural photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>WSC 3885</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Charles Warterfield Architectural Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/51</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>