<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Christian Care Center, 2001 March</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of Rains Avenue Christian Care Center, located at 136 Rains Avenue in Nashville, Tennessee.  This ministry center was opened in April 1985 when the members of Hillsboro Church of Christ in Nashville recognized a need in their community.  Volunteers and staff members work daily to distribute donated food, clothing, furniture, and other common household items to those in need.  The building was built in the 1920s and was originally used as a church for the Rains Avenue Church of Christ congregation.  The foundation is stone.  The exterior walls are brick with the original stone underneath.  The basement walls are still comprised of the original stone.  According to the Sacred Sites Survey form, a renovation took place in the 1950s and an addition was added to the church in the 1960s.  The roof is made of asphalt shingles.  The original doors were wood, while the current doors are plate glass.  
Forms part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project. 1 photograph : col. ; 4  x 6  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Rains Avenue Christian Care Center (Nashville, Tenn.); Hillsboro Church of Christ (Nashville, Tenn.); Rains Avenue Church of Christ (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Popular Culture; Religion; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Religious facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Church architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Churches of Christ--Tennessee--Nashville; Churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Missions--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs; Rains Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2001-03</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>SSSP - Christian Care Center</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/744</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>