<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Judge Beverly Briley receiving a polio vaccine at Vanderbilt Hospital, circa 1959 October 29</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of Davidson County Judge Beverly Briley receiving the polio vaccine at one of the special anti-polio vaccine clinics at Vanderbilt Hospital in Nashville, Tennessee. He is seen grinning as the nurse, Mrs. Mary Scott, prepares to inject a dose of the vaccine into his upper arm. The clinic's poster cites the one dollar fee for "all ages," at a time when modern mass inoculations were being developed to combat poliomyelitis. Beverly Briley, first mayor of the Metropolitan Government of Nashville and Davidson County (1963-75), was born in Nashville in 1914. Originally from the Nashville Banner newspaper, this photograph was published in the October 29, 1959 issue. Forms part of the Jack Knox Artist Reference Files. 1 photograph : b &amp; w ; 8 x 10 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Briley, Beverly, 1914-1980; Scott, Mary</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Banner--History--Sources; Vanderbilt University. Hospital</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Colleges and Universities; Capital City; Public Health; Judges--Tennessee--Nashville; Poliomyelitis vaccine--Tennessee--Nashville; Viral vaccines--Tennessee--Nashville; Clinics--Tennessee--Nashville; Nurses--Tennessee--Nashville; Health care--Tennessee--Nashville; Vaccinations--Tennessee--Nashville; Injections--Tennessee--Nashville; Medical personnel--Tennessee--Nashville; Government officials--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Banner--History--Sources; Vanderbilt University. Hospital</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Gunter, Jack (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Pipes, Steven (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1959-10-29</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Knox ArtistRef-b1, f6 p1</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Jack Knox Artist Reference Files</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/2284</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>