<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Capitol Hill Redevelopment and Honorary Citizenship of Nashville for Hon. Neal J. Hardy, 1961 March 22 </dc:title>
<dc:description>A photo related to the Capitol Hill Redevelopment Luncheon and planning sessions hosted in honor of the Federal Housing Commissioner Neal J. Hardy.  Mr. Hardy was made an Honorary Citizen of the City of Nashville, presented by Mayor Ben West.  Hardy was an executive of the National Association of Home Builders when President John F. Kennedy nominated him to head the Federal Housing Administration in 1961.  The agency was a predecessor of the Department of Housing and Urban Development.  Forms part of Record Group 3, Metro Davidson County Photographer. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.
</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Hardy, Neal J., 1914-1999; West, Ben, 1911-1974
</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Tennessee State Capitol (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Capitols--Tennessee--Nashville; Public buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Urban renewal--Tennessee--Nashville </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1961-03-22</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives </dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG3 2743 Capitol Hill Redevelopment Luncheon for Hon Neal J Hardy March 22 1961005</dc:identifier>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/7544</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>