<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Avenge Pearl Harbor, Nashville, Tennessee 1942 June</dc:title>
<dc:description>
A scene from the parade and ceremony for &#8220;Avenge Pearl Harbor,&#8221; when more than 100 &#8216;Pearl Harbor Avengers&#8217; swore an oath of Naval allegiance in front of the War Memorial Building in Nashville, Tennessee, on Sunday, June 7th, 1942.  This event was part of a national enlistment campaign commemorating the six-month anniversary of Pearl Harbor.  According to the Nashville Banner, 195 enlistees took the oath in Tennessee following parades and ceremonies held at 12 cities throughout the state.  On Sunday evening, part of the &#8220;Avengers&#8221; embarked via train at Union Station, with another contingent departing on Monday June 8th.  Source: Nashville Banner newspaper.  Forms part of Record Group 412, Photographs Collection. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.  </dc:description>
<dc:subject>United States. Navy-- Recruiting, enlistment, etc.; Union Station (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>World War, 1939-1945--United States; Military service, Voluntary--Tennessee, Middle; Recruiting and enlistment--Tennessee, Middle</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Tennessee, Middle--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1942-06</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 412 276 Avenge Pearl Harbor June1942 007</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 412</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/5441</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>