<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Norman Binkley Elementary School, Nashville, Tennessee, 1961 April 09</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph related to the dedication ceremony of Norman Binkley School, April 9th, 1961.  Participants, in addition to school children and community, included Mayor Ben West, Rev. R. L. Thomas, Miss Iva Simms, Principal, Dick Battle, E. B. Garrett, J. E. Moss, Owen Luallen, and Pamela Arnold.  The school, located at 4700 West Longdale Drive, opened in September, 1960, with nine classrooms serving approximately 300 children in grades 1-6.  During construction the school was called Caldwell Hall and was built to serve part of the Crieve Hall, Elysian Meadows, Caldwell Hall and Elysian Park subdivisions.  The Davidson County Board of Education officially named the school in honor of Norman Binkley, a former state senator, who lived in the Woodbine area.  Ten rooms were added in 1961 and six rooms in 1963 to accommodate a fast growing community.  School enrollment peaked near the 1,000 mark during the school year 1965-66.  Forms part of Record Group 3, Metro Davidson County Photographer. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.   </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Norman Binkley Elementary School (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Public schools--Tennessee--Nashville; Schools--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Teachers--Tennessee--Nashville; Educators--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; West Longdale Drive (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1961-04-09</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives </dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG3 7197 Norman Binkley School dedication Apr9th 1961 005</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3 Metro Davidson County Photographer   </dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/7243</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>