<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Excerpt from consolidation interview with Elizabeth Jacobs, December 22, 1994</dc:title>
<dc:description>An excerpt from an interview with Elizabeth Jacobs, conducted on December 22, 1994 by Carole Bucy as part of the Metro Consolidation Oral History Interviews.  Jacobs discusses her role in the consolidation of the city and county governments.  She also comments briefly on other individuals and their contributions. The complete record of the interview is available at the Metro Government Archives.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Allen, Clifford; Adams, Alfred Jr.; Briley, Beverly; Bucy, Carole; Caldwell, Camilla; Cummings, Tom; Flippen, H. E.; Fulton, Richard; Henry, Douglas Jr.; Hickman, Litton; May, Dan; North, Ira; Sharp, Al; Sharp, Al Jr.; Werthan, Bernard Jr.; West, Ben;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Metro Nashville Goverment;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Annexation (Municipal government); Charters; Consolidation; Education;  Hospitals; Housing; Newspapers; Politics &amp; government; Race relations; Social services; Annexation (Municipal government)--Tennessee--Nashville; Education--Tennessee--Nashville; Housing--Tennessee--Nashville; Newspapers--Tennessee--Nashville; Politics &amp; government--Tennessee--Nashville;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--Education; Nashville (Tenn.)--History; Nashville (Tenn.)--Politics and government; Nashville (Tenn.)--Race relations;</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Metro Historical Commission</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Metro Historical Commission</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>12/22/1994</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3 (1.67 MB; 1 min., 49 sec.)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Metro Consolidation Oral History Interviews 25</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from: Metro Consolidation Oral History Interview(s) converted to mp3 2007</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Metro Consolidation Oral History Interviews</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>12/22/1994</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1298</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>