<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Oral history interview with Salynn McCollum, 2007 June 29</dc:title>
<dc:description>An oral history interview with Salynn McCollum, conducted on 29 June 2007 by Larry Patterson as part of the Nashville Public Library's Civil Rights Oral History Project.  Salynn McCollum was one of the Nashville students who participated in the Freedom Rides. These excerpts are part of the second interview with the participant. The topics discussed include fostering Dr. King's notion of a Beloved Community; nonviolence as a methodology and practice; along with justice and dignity for everyone. The complete interview and transcript is available in the Special Collections Division.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>McCollum, Mary Salynn, 1940- --Interviews; Nash, Diane, 1938-; Lewis, John, 1940 Feb. 21-</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Civil Rights; Race relations; Women; Civil rights movements--Tennessee--History--20th century; Civil rights movements--Illinois--History--20th century; Civil rights--Tennessee--Nashville; Civil rights workers--Tennessee--Nashville; Civil rights workers--Illinois--Cairo; Freedom Rides, 1961; Nonviolence--United States; Communication in organizations--United States; Organizational effectiveness; Equality; African Americans--Civil Rights--United States; Social justice--United States; Social change--United States; Political violence--Middle East</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--Race relations; Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Cairo (Ill.)--Race Relations; Cairo (Ill.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>McCollum, Mary Salynn, 1940- (Interviewee); Patterson, Larry, 1944- (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Public Library of Nashville and Davidson County</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>2007-06-29</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CROHPMcCollumS1007clip1.mp3; CROHPMcCollumS1009clip1.mp3; CROHPMcCollumS_transcript.pdf</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from:  CROHPMcCollumS digital recording converted from wav to mp3 format in 2007.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Civil Rights Oral History Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1491</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>