<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Students to impersonate ancestors formerly attending same school, from  the Nashville Times, 1940</dc:title>
<dc:description>A captioned photo, from the Nashville Times (1940), about students of the Robertson Academy. The caption reads: &#8220;A novel event Friday evening will be the revue &#8230; at Robertson Academy, in which students in the school will impersonate their ancestors who at one time attended the academy. The antebellum miss pictured above is Patricia Potter, daughter of Mr. and Mrs. Ed Potter. She will take the part of her ancestor, Susan Hardeman, who later married Constantine Perkins Sneed and who built the Sneed home on the Old Smyrna Road, now owned by William A. Puryear. Pictured at the lovely old Moore home at Brentwood are Vernon Sharpe, III, seated, son of Mr. and Mrs. Vernon Sharpe, Jr. and Frank Stockell, Jr., son of Mr. and Mrs. Stockell. They will impersonate two outstanding alumni, Robert and Allen Moore. The revue &#8230; should be a gay event, as students are frantically searching old albums and records to discover ancestors who attended the school &#8230;. Lavender and old lace, pantalets, and Confederate uniforms are at a premium &#8230;.&#8221;  The Robertson Academy was established by an Act of the General Assembly September 13, 1806, which provided for an academy in each of the then 27 counties. The school, named for James Robertson, the founder of Nashville, has operated continually since that time.  Forms part of the Nashville Times newspaper collection. 1 digital photo.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Potter family; Hardeman family; Sneed family; Puryear family; Sharpe family; Stockell family; Moore family</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Robertson Academy (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Schools--Tennessee--Nashville; Pageants--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Manners and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1940</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RobertsonAcademy--NT-1940</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Times Newspaper Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4169</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>