<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Meharry Medical College - Nashville, Tenn., circa 1943</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard of Meharry Medical College located adjacent to the Fisk University campus on D.B. Todd Jr. Boulevard in Nashville, Tennessee.  The school was first organized in 1876 as the largest professional college in the world for the training of African American youth in medicine, dentistry, pharmacy and nursing.  New buildings were completed and dedicated in 1931.  Forms part of the Norton Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Meharry Medical College</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Education; Colleges and Universities; Capital City; Medicine; African Americans; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Education--Tennessee--Nashville; Universities and colleges--Tennessee--Nashville; African American universities and colleges--Tennessee--Nashville; Medical colleges--Tennessee--Nashville; African Americans--Education; School facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Schools--Tennessee--Nashville; Educational facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Universities &amp; colleges--Tennessee--Nashville; Medical education--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Intellectual life; D.B. Todd Jr. Boulevard (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Capitol News Co. (Publisher)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1943</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Norton - 0379</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Norton Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1980</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>