<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Aerial of Nashville downtown parking, circa 1970s</dc:title>
<dc:description>A 1970s aerial view of downtown Nashville, Tennessee showing parking lots within the central business district, around Fifth Avenue to Seventh Avenue near Church Street and Commerce.  Includes an aerial view of several businesses, such as Cain-Sloan and the Sam Davis Hotel (at 132 7th Avenue N and the corner of Commerce).  Forms part of Record Group 3. The original is a 35 mm color transparency (2 x 2 in. slide mount).</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Cain-Sloan Department Store (Nashville, Tenn.); Sam Davis Hotel (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Department stores--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Parking lots--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Fifth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Sixth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Church Street (Nashville, Tenn.); Seventh Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Commerce Street (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1970s</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Slide1225 Aerial Downtown Parking</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1970-1979</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/5807</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>