<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of the American Trust Building, corner of Third Avenue and Union Streets, Nashville, Tennessee, circa 1925</dc:title>
<dc:description>This elevated view of the American Trust Building, on the corner of Third Avenue and Union Streets, taken from the window of a building across the street, highlights architect Henry C. Hibbs' design of an addition of ten stories to the top and fifteen stories to the west of the original five-story structure. Also visible are an electric trolley car (bottom left) and cars parked along Union Avenue. Forms part of the Henry C. Hibbs Papers. 1 photograph : b &amp; w; 8 x 10 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>American Trust Building (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Business; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; 
Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Commercial buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Transportation--Tennessee--Nashville; Street-railroads--Tennessee--Nashville; Electric railroads--Tennessee--Nashville; Vehicles--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Third Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Union Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Wiles Photographers (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Hibbs, Henry C. (Clossen), 1882-1949 (Architect)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1925</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/tiff (32.6 MB)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>HCHP-Bldg-American Trust-p1</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Henry C. Hibbs Papers</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1920-1929</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/471</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>