<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Glimpses of Nashville, Tennessee: Tennessee School for the Blind </dc:title>
<dc:description>An exterior view of the Tennessee School for the Blind, Nashville, Tennessee, circa 1904.  This school was conceived in the mind of James Champlin, founded circa 1844 for the establishment of a &#8220;state&#8221; school for the blind.  Following the Civil War, the school struggled to survive until support arrived from philanthropist Judge John M. Lea, who purchased the Claiborne Mansion on Fillmore St. (108 Hermitage Ave.) and donated it to the state for the school.  In 1898, the school had a total of 150 pupils.  The institution flourished at this location for some 80 years. Forms part of Glimpses of Nashville. 1 booklet </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Tennessee School for the Blind</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Blind--Education--Tennessee; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Fillmore Street (Nashville, Tenn.); Hermitage Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.) </dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Manx, Chicago </dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1900s</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Glimpses of Nashville Book040 Tennessee School for the Blind</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Glimpses of Nashville, Tennessee booklet   </dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1900-1909</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/7748</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>