<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>City Hospital, Nashville, Tenn., circa 1913</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard of Nashville's City Hospital (later known as Nashville General Hospital, 72 Hermitage Avenue) as it appeared circa 1913. This stately edifice was designed by Thompson &amp; Gibel, Architects. It was the first city-owned and operated hospital, built upon the Cumberland River Bluff in the spring of 1890, through action of the City Council and the Board of Public Works. The City Hospital, with its capacity of sixty beds, had two floors and a basement with dumb waiters and laundry chutes going to each floor. Doctor Charles Brower of the University of Nashville Medical Department was appointed Superintendent. In 1891, a school of nursing was opened with Miss Charlotte E. Perkins as Superintendent. This was the first training school for nurses between the Ohio River and New Orleans. This hospital building served as a healthcare facility until circa 1970, when it was partially razed for construction of a new modern complex on the site. In early 1998, Nashville General Hospital relocated to the former Meharry-Hubbard Hospital building on Albion Street under a merger plan creating Nashville General Hospital at Meharry. Forms part of the Nashville Room Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>City Hospital (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Public Health; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Hospitals--Tennessee--Nashville; Public hospitals--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Health care facilities--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Hermitage Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>S.H. Kress &amp; Co. (Publisher)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1913</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Nash - 218</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1910-1919</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/2268</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>