<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Bird's eye view of Nashville, circa 1907</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard aerial view of the Rutledge Hill area of Nashville and old Howard School with its bell tower visible in the foreground, circa 1907. The Nashville skyline is visible in the background. Forms part of the Nashville Room Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Howard School (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Schools; Capital City; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Schools--Tennessee--Nashville; Neighborhood--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville; Neighborhoods--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Rutledge Hill (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Souvenir Post Card Co. (Publisher)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1907</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Nash-4b dup1-Bird's Eye View</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1900-1909</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/597</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>