<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Letter to parents from Clarence Jackson "Jack" Davis, 1951 October 18</dc:title>
<dc:description>A one-page (front and back) handwritten letter by Clarence Jackson "Jack" Davis, to his parents, Mr. Benton V. Davis and Mrs. Mildred Jackson Davis, of Nashville, Tenn.  Jack Davis joined the Marine Corps Reserve to help finance his education at Vanderbilt University.  Within six months he found himself on the frontlines in Korea, in an infantry company bearing the ominous nickname "Bloody George."  He wrote home to his family frequently, often daily.  In this letter Davis describes improvements he made to his bunker to ensure better protection during combat.  He includes a labeled sketch showing two different views of his safety-enhanced foxhole.  Forms part of the Veterans History Project. 1 handwritten letter, with envelope.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Davis, Jack (Clarence Jackson), 1932-2004</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>United States. Marine Corps. Division, 1st.; United States. Marine Corps. Regiment, 1st. Battalion, 3rd. Company G; United States. Marine Corps--History--Korean War, 1950-1953</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Military History; Korean War; War; Veterans--Tennessee--History--Sources; Korean War, 1950-1953--Sources; Korean War, 1950-1953--Personal narratives, American; Bunkers (Fortification); Intrenchments; Military life--American; Military service--United States</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Korea--History--20th century</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Davis, Jack (Clarence Jackson), 1932-2004</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1951-10-18</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text; Letters (correspondence)</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>VHP- Korea - Davis, Jack - f9, letter - Oct 18, 1951</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Veterans History Project collection, Korean War Series, Clarence Jackson "Jack" Davis Papers</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1396</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>