<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Memorial Chapel, Fisk University, Nashville, Tenn., circa 1930</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard of The Fisk Memorial Chapel on the campus of Fisk University in Nashville, Tennessee.  The chapel was built in 1892 by means of a legacy from General Clinton B. Fisk, (for whom the University is named), which, according to family wishes, was devoted to the erection of a memorial building.  The steeple stands 91 feet tall.  The African American university was established in 1865, with classes convening on Jan. 9, 1866.  The University was incorporated as Fisk University on August 22, 1867.  Booker T. Washington and Dr. Martin Luther King are among the noted speakers who have lectured in the chapel.  Genuine Curteich-Chicago "C.T. Art-Colortone" Post Card.  Forms part of the Nashville Room Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Fisk, Clinton Bowen, 1828-1890--Memorials</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Fisk University</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Education; Colleges and Universities; Buildings; Architecture; Schools; Private Schools; African Americans; Capital City; Religion; Popular Culture; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Education--Tennessee--Nashville; Universities and colleges--Tennessee--Nashville; School facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Details; African American universities and colleges--Tennessee--Nashville; Chapels--Tennessee-Nashville; Towers--Tennessee--Nashville; Churches--Tennessee--Nashville; African Americans--Education; Educational facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Universities &amp; colleges--Tennessee--Nashville; Steeples; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Intellectual life; Nashville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Capitol News Co. (Publisher)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1930</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Nash - 73 - Memorial Chapel, Fisk University, Nashville, Tenn.</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/815</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>