<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Portrait of William Little Brown (mp4 video clip, 16.2 MB file available to download) </dc:title>
<dc:description>A video clip depicting the oil portrait of William Little Brown (1789-1830).  Brown studied and practiced law prior to becoming the Solicitor General (1814-1915).  He was elected a member of the Tennessee State Senate in 1819.  During his time as a member of the Senate, he successfully concluded a treaty concerning the Kentucky/Tennessee boundary line.  At the conclusion of his term, Brown returned to Nashville and opened a highly-respected and successful law firm, partnering with Ephraim H. Foster.  In 1822, he was elected to be a judge on the Supreme Court.  His term was short-lived however, with Brown resigning from the position in 1823.  He resigned at a time when many fellow colleagues highly respected both his character and professional reputation.  His portrait was presented by "unknown admirers" soon after the establishment of the State Library in 1858.  1 video clip, Metro Archives Portraits Collection. </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Brown, William L., 1789-1830</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Judges--Tennessee--History--Sources; Lawyers--Tennessee--History--Sources; Legislators--United States--History--Sources

</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Tennessee--Politics and government--19th century; United States--Politics and government--19th century</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1858</dc:date>
<dc:type>Video Clip; Still Image; Portraits </dc:type>
<dc:format>video/mpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Portrait_of_William_Little_Brown_video_clip_view_of_the_original_oil_portrait_</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Metro Archives Portraits Collection </dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>19th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/9323</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>