<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Edwin W. Craig receives award, 1962 May 03</dc:title>
<dc:description>Edwin W. Craig, Chairman of National Life and Accident Insurance Company, receives a resolution from Mayor Ben West on May 3rd, 1962. Craig advised L&amp;A&#8217;s board to venture into radio as a good marketing tool, and WSM-AM radio was born.  Soon, the Grand Ole Opry radio show was introduced to become the best-known and longest running radio program in history.  Craig was a leading figure in nationwide insurance circles, following his father&#8217;s footsteps to the presidency of the South&#8217;s largest insurance company.  He was recognized as the father of radio station WSM.  In 1934, he was instrumental in organizing the Clear Channel Broadcasting Service, a group of high-powered stations including WSM.  Forms part of Record Group 3, Metro Davidson County Photographer.  1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Craig, Edwin W., 1893-1969; West, Ben, 1911-1974</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Businesspeople--Tennessee--Nashville; Businessmen--Tennessee--Nashville; Insurance executives--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1962-05-03</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 3 4183 Edwin Craig Natl Life001</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3 Metro Davidson County Photographer</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4706</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>