<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Oral history interview with Dr. Rodney N. Powell, 2005 March 29</dc:title>
<dc:description>Excerpts from an interview with civil rights leader Dr. Rodney N. Powell on 29 March 2005 by Kathy Bennett as part of the Civil Rights Oral History Project.  In the excerpts Rodney Powell talks about social conscience; being part of the student movement in Nashville as a student at Meharry Medical College; and Meharry faculty during the sit-ins, including Dr. Matthew Walker's support to student participation.. The complete interview, as well as a transcript, is available in the Special Collections Division.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Powell, Rodney N.--Interviews; Walker, Matthew, 1906-1978</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Meharry Medical College</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Civil Rights; Race Relations; Education; Civil rights movements--Tennessee--Nashville; African Americans--Civil rights--Tennessee--Nashville; Education--Tennessee--Nashville; Universities and colleges--Tennessee--Nashville; African American universities and colleges--Tennessee--Nashville; Universities and colleges--Faculty--Tennessee--Nashville; African American universities and colleges--Faculty--Tennessee--Nashville;  Medical colleges--Tennessee--Nashville; Medical colleges--Faculty--Tennessee--Nashville; Students--Attitudes--Tennessee--Nashville; Students--Political activity--Tennessee--Nashville; Civil rights demonstrations--Tennessee--Nashville; Student movements--Tennessee--Nashville; Civil rights workers--Tennessee--Nashville; African American civil rights workers--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Race relations; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social conditions; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Powell, Rodney N. (Interviewee); Bennett, Kathryn G. (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>James, Carolyn (Transcriber)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>2005-03-29</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CROHPPowellaclip1.mp3; CROHPPowellaclip2.mp3; CROHPPowell_transcript.pdf</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from: CROHPPowell digital recording converted from wav to mp3 format in 2007.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Civil Rights Oral History Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1677</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>