<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>N.G. Tucker, M.D., Health Officer of Nashville, circa 1897 </dc:title>
<dc:description>A picture of Dr. Newton G. Tucker, Health Officer of Nashville, sourced from the &#8220;Reports of departments of the City of Nashville for the fiscal year ending December 31, 1897.&#8221; Dr. Tucker was born in Williamson County, Tennessee, March 29, 1836.  His parents moved to Marshall County when he was a child, for fifteen years, then returned to Williamson County.  At the age of 20 he studied medicine, graduating in the Medical Department of the University of Nashville in 1861.  After several years practicing medicine, he was elected Mayor of Lewisburg in 1870, which position he held until his removal to Nashville three years later.  In 1875 he was elected a member of the Nashville City Council, holding the office of President of this body for six years.  In 1892 he was elected City Health Officer, which position he held for six years.  For a number of years we held the Chair of Theory and Practice of Medicine in the Meharry Medical College.  He was a member of the North High Street Methodist Church.  Shortly after receiving his degree of M.D., he married Miss Mary E. Cochran, of Pontotoc, Mississippi.  The yearbook consists of official reports of the City Government of Nashville, Tennessee, with a Message of the Mayor R.H. Dudley to the City Council members, dated Jan. 13, 1898.  This publication was prepared for the press by James T. Bell, Recorder.  Forms part of the City of Nashville published reports.  1 yearbook. </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Tucker, Newton G. </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Municipal government--Tennessee--Nashville; Municipal reports--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Politics and government</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Brandon Printing Company (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1898</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>City of Nashville 1897 Yearbook 068b DrTucker Health</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Publications, City of Nashville reports, 1897 yearbook</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1890-1898</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880. </dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/10387</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>