<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Boscobel College, Nashville, Tenn., circa 1914</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard of Boscobel College in Nashville, Tennessee.  This school for young ladies consisted of an Anna Shelby Williams' old east Nashville mansion and another large brick building atop a tree-covered hill.  The ten acre campus was on Sevier Street near South Seventh Street.  Boscobel College was in operation from 1889 until 1914.  Around 1918, the buildings and campus became home to the National Baptist Seminary and Missionary Training School, an institution that functioned until 1931. In 1940 the buildings were razed and sold for scrap.  Much of the site of the old school is now public housing.  Forms part of the Nashville Room Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Boscobel College (Nashville, Tenn.); National Baptist Seminary and Missionary Training School (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Education; Colleges and Universities; Capital City; Buildings; Architecture; Schools; Religion; Private Schools; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Education--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Universities and colleges--Tennessee--Nashville; Women--Tennessee--Nashville; School facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Educational facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Universities &amp; Colleges--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; East Nashville (Nashville, Tenn.); Sevier Street (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville (Tenn.); Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Intellectual life</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>S.H. Kress &amp; Co. (Publisher)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1914</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Nash - 71 - Boscobel College, Nashville, Tenn.</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1910-1919</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/813</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>