<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Nashville Youth Orchestra presents their instruments, 1951 December</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of the seventh and eighth grade Nashville Youth Orchestra holding paper replicas of their instruments made at the Julia Andrews School, in the Berry Hill neighborhood off Thompson Lane.  The Nashville Youth Orchestra gave the first of its season concerts at War Memorial Auditorium.  Front row (seated, left to right): Calvin Hollon, Don Hite, Shirley Taylor, Jeannette White
Back row: Polly Ash, Barbara Ashcraft, Jimmy Newsom, Lois Tidwell, Bobby Cato, Gerald Cannon, Elmer Christian, Wylie Hembre, Henry Harris, Roger Marks, Ellen Chandler, Janie Krise.  Forms part of the Nashville Banner Archives. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 3.25 x 4.25 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Hollon, Calvin; Hite, Don; Taylor, Shirley; White, Jeannette; Ash, Polly; Ashcraft, Barbara; Newsom, Jimmy; Tidwell, Lois; Cato, Bobby; Cannon, Gerald; Christian, Elmer; Hembre, Wylie; Harris, Henry; Marks, Roger; Chandler, Ellen; Krise, Janie</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Julia Andrews School (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville Youth Orchestra</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Performing Arts; Music; Education; Junior High Schools; Popular Culture; Entertainment; Children's History; Capital City; Organizations; Children--Tennessee--Nashville; Students--Tennessee--Nashville; Child musicians--Tennessee--Nashville; Middle schools--Tennessee--Nashville; Junior high schools--Tennessee--Nashville; Music as recreation--Tennessee--Nashville; Youth orchestras--Tennessee--Nashville; Orchestras--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Berry Hill (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Gallenbeck, Warren (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1951-12</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives; Film negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BN 1951-290-n4</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/859</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>