<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Gas war in Nashville, Tennessee, 1955 September 08</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of a man contemplating gas prices at two local service stations.  This photo appeared on the front page of the 8 September 1955 edition of the Nashville Banner.  The caption states, "Confusion in the gas war - John W. Thomas scratches his head in amazement at the conflicting gasoline prices this morning. The 22.9 cents a gallon sign is at Doc Byrd's Gulf Service Center at 16th Avenue and Demonbreun Street. Across the street, Robinson Service Station went along with a number of other stations in boosting its price to 28.9 cents a gallon." The two brands of gas in the photograph are Esso and Gulf.  Forms part of the Nashville Banner Archives. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 3.25 x 4.25 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Thomas, John W.</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Doc Byrd's Gulf Service Center (Nashville, Tenn.); Robinson Service Station (Nashville, Tenn.); Esso Chemical Company; Gulf Oil Corporation</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Transportation; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Popular Culture; Shopping; Business; Advertisements; Service stations--Tennessee--Nashville; Automobiles--Tennessee--Nashville; Automobiles--Fuel consumption; Gasoline--Tennessee--Nashville; Signs and signboards--Tennessee--Nashville; Gasoline--Prices--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Gasoline pumps--Tennessee--Nashville; Business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Automobile service stations--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Commerce; Demonbreun Street (Nashville, Tenn.); Sixteenth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Foster, Don (photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1955-09-08</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives; Film negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BN 1955-3387</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1829</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>