<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Fairview, Hillsboro Road, between 1925 and 1932</dc:title>
<dc:description>This was the elegant home &#8220;Fairview,&#8221; of Mrs. Wilbur F. Foster and Mr. and Mrs. C. C. Foster, located on the Hillsboro Road at Abbott Lane in Nashville, Tennessee.  The home was later destroyed by fire circa 1933 and was rebuilt on the same site.  These digital reproductions were scanned from the scrapbook of Mrs. Frank A. Wilk (Alva Herbert Wilk). 1 digital photograph.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Foster family</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture, Domestic--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Dwellings--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Mansions--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Hillsboro Pike (Nashville, Tenn.); Abbott Martin Road (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>between 1925 and 1932</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Wilk scrapbook pg 019 Fairview on Hillsboro Rd a</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Mrs. Frank A. Wilk Digital Photographs Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1920-1929; 1930-1939</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4924</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>