<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Jefferson Street Missionary Baptist Church, 2001 May</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of Jefferson Street Missionary Baptist Church located at 2708 Jefferson Street in Nashville, Tennessee.  Historically called Jefferson Street Baptist, this church's congregation was founded in 1887 when a coffin maker started a Sunday School in a storefront building on North College Street.  The church took the name of the street, and when the city changed the street name to Third Avenue, the church changed its name as well, becoming Third Avenue Baptist Church.  Then, in 1920, property on Jefferson Street was chosen as the site for a new church, and the name switched again to reflect its fresh location.  In 1974, the property adjacent to the church was purchased as a site for a new sanctuary.  Bricklaying members of the church did the masonry work on the new building with help from other men in the congregation.  The new church was dedicated in May of 1977.  The foundation is brick.  The exterior walls are red brick.  The gabled and flat roof is made of tar shingles.  The windows are composed of frosted blue glass.  The doors are metal.  Forms part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project. 1 photograph : col. ; 4  x 6  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Jefferson Street Missionary Baptist Church (Nashville, Tenn.); Jefferson Street Baptist Church (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Popular Culture; Religion; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Religious facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Church architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Baptist church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Brick churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Details; Churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Baptist churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville--Tennessee; Steeples</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs; Jefferson Street (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2001-05</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>SSSP - Jefferson St Mis Bap</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1080</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>