<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>
Mayor Beverly Briley and the U.S.S. Nashville&#8217;s ship commissioning, 1970 February 14 
</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph related to Nashville Mayor Beverly Briley&#8217;s participation in the U.S.S. Nashville&#8217;s (LPD 13) ship commissioning at Puget Sound Naval Shipyard, Bremerton, Washington on February 14, 1970, with Captain Frank R. Fahland in command. It is an Amphibious Transport Dock (LPD) of the Austin-class, designed to embark, transport, and land elements of a landing force by sea or air during expeditionary warfare missions. It is the third ship of the United States Navy to be named for the capital city of Tennessee.  The U.S.S. Nashville was decommissioned on 30 September 2009 at the Norfolk Naval Station in Norfolk, Virginia. Mayor Briley, the first mayor of the newly consolidated metropolitan government of Nashville and Davidson County in Tennessee, served in the U.S. Navy during World War II as a quartermaster aboard the U.S.S. David Taylor.  Forms part of the Metro Archives Photographs Collection - Mayor Briley, USS Nashville.  1 b &amp; w photograph. </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Briley, Beverly, 1914-1980; Fahland, Frank R. </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>USS Nashville (Amphibious transport dock : LPD 13); Puget Sound Naval Shipyard</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Naval ceremonies, honors, and salutes--United States; Mayors--Tennessee--Nashville--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1970-02</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Metro Photos Coll - Mayor Briley - USS Nashville 1970  009</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Metro Archives Photographs Collection - Mayor Briley, USS Nashville</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1970-1979</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/9038</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>