<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Historic home residence Travellers Rest, Nashville, Tennessee, 1911</dc:title>
<dc:description>Travellers Rest gained its name from the fact of the many guests it has entertained. John Overton, afterward Justice of the Supreme Court, came from Virginia in 1793 and built a two-room log house on the site of the present building. He was one of the first lawyers to practice in this section of the country, and the little brick office in the yard was also the first law school. Here many of the pioneer lawyers were educated, making their home meanwhile with Judge Overton in the house which had been enlarged to meet the growing needs of his hospitality. During the Civil War, the house was never closed, and although situated on the battle field, it escaped practically uninjured. In the winter of 1864, when Hood made his remarkable march into Tennessee, the present sitting room at Travellers Rest was his headquarters for a few days. Mrs. Overton was often heard to say that the proudest day of her life was during a cold, bleak day in December when seven Confederate Generals sat at her dining table. Saved from demolition in 1954 by the Tennessee Society of the National Society of the Colonial Dames of America, the historic house, built originally in 1799 was restored to interpret the early 19th century life of Judge John Overton, one of the state&#8217;s first Supreme Court Justices, the founder of Memphis, and a close personal friend of Andrew Jackson. Today, Historic Travellers Rest Plantation, a National Register property, is recognized as a model of preservation excellence. The site is located at 636 Farrell Parkway in Nashville, Tennessee. This digital photo is reproduced from the book &#8220;Historical and Beautiful Country Homes Near Nashville,&#8221; compiled by Mrs. James E. Caldwell and published in 1911. 1 digital photo, title supplied by cataloger.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Overton family; Overton, John, 1766-1833-- Homes and haunts</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture, Domestic--Tennessee--Nashville; Dwellings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Mansions--Tennessee--Nashville; Law schools--Tennessee--Nashville; Judges--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Farrell Parkway (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Wiles, Marvin W. (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Dickenson III, Jacob McGavock (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1911</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>1911-Travellers Rest frontpiece; 1911-Travellers Rest; 1911-Travellers Rest grounds; 1911-Travellers Rest grounds 2</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Historical and Beautiful Country Homes Near Nashville 1911</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1910-1919</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4395</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>