<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Confederate Veteran J. R. Sadler, between 1924 and 1943</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of Sgt. J. R. Sadler, a Tennessee Confederate veteran in a military uniform, perhaps as part of a reunion ceremony.  Sadler lived to be 98 years old and the September 29th, 1943 Banner newspaper states: &#8220;... Sgt. J. R. Sadler, 98, Confederate veteran who was wounded in the Battle of Franklin when he fought with Gen. Nathan Bedford Forrest&#8217;s cavalry nearly 80 years ago, will be held tomorrow morning at 10 o&#8217;clock at the Marshall Funeral Home.  Dr. W. F. Powell will officiate, and burial will be in Mt. Olivet Cemetery.  He died yesterday afternoon in General Baptist.  Sergeant Sadler joined the army as a drummer-boy in 1863.  During the Battle of Franklin he was hit on the head with the butt of a gun and bore a scar to the time of his death.  He was captured at that time and held a prisoner in Nashville by the Northern Army.  Two of his brothers were killed and two other brothers and his father were wounded in that battle.  Sergeant Sadler farmed most of his life, worked for a time as a cabinetmaker, and was for a period of 25 years a city policeman in Nashville.  He retired in 1916 and had been living for many years in the Raleigh Apartments.  He attended every reunion of the Confederate Veterans but one, members of his family said this morning.  In 1940 he was one of four veterans to attend the 50th annual reunion in Washington, D. C., where he insisted on riding a horse in the parade; in 1941 he journeyed to Atlanta for the meeting, and last year was present at the state reunion in Chattanooga.  Survivors are his widow, Mrs. Ella Sadler, and four step-children, Misses Earline and Jessie Meadors, Robert Meadors and John Meadors, all of Nashville.  Pallbearers will be H. B. Moore, Ben Cockrill, Clarence Carter, Ed Stout, Haggard Oldham, and Police Chief John Griffin.&#8221;  Forms part of Record Group 412, Photographs Collection. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Sadler, J. R.</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Veterans--Tennessee--History--Sources; Soldiers--Tennessee--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Tennessee--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>between 1924 and 1943</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 412 882 Confed Vet Sgt Sadler of Forrest Cav001</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 412</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1920-1929; 1930-1939; 1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/6158</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>