<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>View of Capitol Hill and State Capitol, 1962</dc:title>
<dc:description>Photograph of the Tennessee State Capitol, 7 February 1962. Constructed between 1845 and 1859, the State Capitol was designed in the Greek Revival style by architect William Strickland. Strickland died before construction was completed and was interred in the walls of the north portico. His son, Francis W. Strickland, oversaw the completion of the project. The Capitol was placed on the National Register of Historic Places in 1970. Photographed by the Nashville Housing Authority. Forms part of the MDHA Photograph Collection. 1 photograph : b &amp; w. </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Nashville Housing Authority (Nashville, Tenn.); Tennessee State Capitol (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Public buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Public buildings--Tennessee--Nashville Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Capitols--Tennessee--Nashville; Urban renewal--Tennessee--Nashville;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.); Capitol Hill (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Nashville Housing Authority/Metropolitan Development and Housing Agency</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1962</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photograph</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>MDHA Photos Box 4 Fol 60 State Capitol 1962 001</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>MDHA Photograph Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1962</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>	
U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/12869</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>