<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Parking Garage Site at 4th and Charlotte, City Beautiful Scrapbooks, 1958, Vol. 2 p107</dc:title>
<dc:description>Photograph of a site for a new parking garage at 4th Avenue North and Charlotte Avenue, May 1958. Lowenstein's Department Store in the background. Taken by the City Beautiful Commission of Nashville, Tennessee, 1958. The City Beautiful Commission was established by the Mayor and City Council in June of 1953, for the purpose of improving the sanitation, cleanliness, and overall appearance of the City of Nashville. The Commission later became a division of Metro Parks in 1975, and then a part of the Metro Public Works division in 2005. Forms part of the City Beautiful Commission Scrapbook Collection. 1 photograph : b &amp; w.
</dc:description>
<dc:subject>City Beautiful Commission</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Urban beautification; Department stores; Parking garages;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Urban beautification; Construction; Department stores; Department stores--Tennessee--Nashville; Park facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Parking garages--Tennessee--Nashville;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.); Fourth Avenue North (Nashville, Tenn.); Charlotte Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>City Beautiful Commission</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library
</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1958
</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photograph
</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg
</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>City Beautiful Vol 2 p107 Parking Garage Site 4th and Charlotte 1958001</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>City Beautiful Scrapbook Collection
</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959
</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880
</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/12023</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>