<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>A First Step toward school integration, 1958 June</dc:title>
<dc:description>Pamphlet written by Anna Holden in cooperation with the Nashville Congress of Racial Equality group, 1958. The pamphlet tells how a CORE group helped parents and children, despite the violence of segregationist mobs, to desegregate public schools in Nashville, Tennessee in the fall of 1957. This pamphlet also addresses southern communities that did not accept the 1954 Brown v. Board decision along with a chronology of all major events in the Nashville school desegregation struggle through April 1958. Forms part of the Civil Rights Ephemera Collection. 1 pamphlet : col. ; 6 x 8.5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>McKinley, Linda Gail; McKinley, Grace</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Fehr Elementary School (Nashville, Tenn.); Congress of Racial Equality</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Civil Rights; African Americans; Race Relations; Education; Capital City; School integration--United States; African Americans--Civil rights--Tennessee--Nashville; Segregation in education--Law and legislation--United States--History; Discrimination in education--Law and legislation--United States--History; Social change--Tennessee--Nashville; School integration--Tennessee--Nashville; Social justice--Tennessee--Nashville; Civil rights movements--Tennessee--Nashville; Civil rights workers--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social conditions; Nashville (Tenn.)--Race relations</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Holden, Anna (Author)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Congress of Racial Equality (Publisher)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1958</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text; Pamphlets</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/tiff</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CRE-School Deseg-A First Step</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Civil Rights Ephemera Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/567</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>