<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Glimpses of Nashville, Tennessee: Jewish Synagogue </dc:title>
<dc:description>An exterior view of the Jewish Synagogue, located in downtown Nashville, Tennessee, circa 1904.  The Vine Street Temple (Congregation Ohabai Shalom) was located at 136 Seventh Avenue North (Vine Street became Seventh Avenue in 1904).  The Byzantine style building had nine domes and was dedicated on 27 May 1876. It was Nashville's first synagogue and home to its Jewish reform congregations for eighty years. After the congregation moved to Harding Road, one of the domes was struck by lightning, and it was sold and demolished in 1955.  Forms part of Glimpses of Nashville. 1 booklet </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Congregation Ohabai Sholom (Nashville, Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Businesses--Tennessee--Nashville; Streets--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Temples--Tennessee--Nashville; Domes--Tennessee--Nashville; Synagogues--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Seventh Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Vine Street (Nashville, Tenn.)
</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Manx, Chicago </dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1900s</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Glimpses of Nashville Book054 Jewish Synagogue</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Glimpses of Nashville, Tennessee booklet   </dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1900-1909</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/7696</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>