<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Oral history interview with Mary Manier Cooper, 1980 November 10</dc:title>
<dc:description>Excerpts from an oral history interview with Nashvillian Mary Manier Cooper, conducted on 10 November 1980 by Fred Cooper as part of the Century III Nashville: Nashville Heritage Project.  In these excerpts, Cooper discusses riding the streetcars; going to attend movies; and receiving medical treatment from a pediatric surgeon in New York when she was two years old, during the late 19th century.   The complete interview, as well as an index, is available in the Special Collections Division.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Cooper, Mary Manier, 1891-1987--Interviews</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Capital City; Transportation; Popular Culture; Entertainment; Medicine; Transportation--Tennessee--Nashville; Street-railroads--Tennessee--Nashville; Motion pictures--Social aspects--Tennessee--Nashville; Motion picture audiences--Tennessee--Nashville; Medicine--United States--History--19th century; Pediatric surgeons--New York; Pediatrics--United States--History--19th century</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; New York (N.Y.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Cooper, Mary Manier, 1891-1987 (Interviewee); Cooper, Fred (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1980-11-10</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CENTIIICooperMaclip1.mp3; CENTIIICooperMaclip2.mp3; CENTIIICooperM_transcript.pdf</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from:  CENTIIICooperM audio cassette recording converted to digital format in 2006.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Century III Nashville: Nashville Heritage Project : oral history</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1980-1989</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1788</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>