<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of "Don't be a Heel, mind your traffic manners" campaign poster being put up Nashville, Tennessee, 1951 December 17</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of an orange and black poster saying "Don't be a Heel, mind your traffic manners", being put up on a utility pole by Traffic Inspector Hubert O. Kemp (right foreground) and (left to right) Traffic Lt. Braxton Duke, Randolph Tucker, a member of the committee on poster display, and F. C. Sowell, chairman of the Chamber of Commerce traffic safety committee. The posters were placed on utility poles in the downtown and business section and neighborhood trading centers by members of the traffic division of the Nashville Police Department. The Chamber traffic safety committee in cooperation with the police department launched the campaign, as part of an intensive campaign to prevent traffic accidents during the holiday season.  Forms part of the Nashville Banner Archives. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 3.25 x 4.25 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Kemp, Hubert O.; Duke, Braxton; Tucker, Randolph; Sowell, F.C.</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.). Metropolitan Police Dept. Traffic Division; Nashville Area Chamber of Commerce</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Capital City; City Government; Downtown Nashville; Transportation; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Transportation--Tennessee--Nashville; City traffic--Tennessee--Nashville; Traffic safety--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Underwood, Doug (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1951-12-17</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/tiff (42.6 MB)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BN 1951-67</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/457</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>