<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Pastor given new auto for Christmas, from the Nashville Times, 1940</dc:title>
<dc:description>A captioned photo from the Nashville Times (1940), about Reverend W. S. Marshall, &#8220;pastor of the West Nashville Cumberland Presbyterian Church takes his hat off to his friends and his church members who, on Christmas Day, presented him with a new 1940 &#8216;Ford DeLuxe &#8230; left to right front row: Supt. F. L. Estes, Mr. and Mrs. R. A. Elizer, Mrs. W. S. Marshall and the Rev. Marshall, Mr. and Mrs. Aubrey Murff, Miss Dora Travis, Ruth Marshall, and the Rev. Marshall&#8217;s little grandson, little Jim Hooker.&#8221; Forms part of the Nashville Times newspaper collection. 1 digital photo.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>West Nashville Cumberland Presbyterian Church (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Protestant churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Presbyterian churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Ford automobile--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1940</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>PastorMarshall--NT-1940</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Times Newspaper Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4191</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>