<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of Nashville's Cedar Street electric streetcar, ca. 1900</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of the electric streetcar that transported passengers along the Cedar Street (Charlotte Avenue) line in Nashville. The Tennessee State Capitol is shown in the background. A reproduced photographic print from the original. Forms part of the Nashville Room Historic Photographs Collection. 1 photograph : b &amp; w ; 8 x 10 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Tennessee State Capitol (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Capital City; Transportation; Downtown Nashville; Street-railroads--Tennessee--Nashville; Electric railroads--Tennessee--Nashville; Transportation--Tennessee--Nashville; Capitals (Cities)--Tennessee; Street railroads--Tennessee--Nashville; Capitols--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Cedar Street (Nashville, Tenn.); Charlotte Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Tennessee--Capital and capitol</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1900</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/tiff (33.3 MB)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>P-1952</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Historic Photographs Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1900-1909</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/349</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>