<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of a second story window and the porchtop of Lynnlawn mansion in Nashville, Tennessee, 1959</dc:title>
<dc:description>A close-up photograph of a window structure and porchtop of the Lynnlawn mansion in Nashville, Tennessee, built by Thomas E. Stratton circa 1852. Designed in the Italian Renaissance style, the facade of the architecture has been attributed to William Strickland. The mansion was located at 617 Gallatin Road, between Stratton and Eastland, adjacent to 12th Street. It remained in the Stratton family until sold to H. G. Hill in the late 1950's. The structure was razed for commercial development. Photographed by the Nashville architect Charles Wesley Warterfield, Jr. (1926-1998); the architectural photograph forms part of the Charles Warterfield Architectural Collection. Gift of: The Estate of Charles W. Warterfield, Jr., F. A. I. A.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Strickland, William, 1787-1854; Stratton, Thomas E.; Stratton family; Hill family</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Lynnlawn (Nashville, Tenn.); H. G. Hill (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Houses--Tennessee--Nashville; Dwellings--Tennessee--Nashville; Windows--Tennessee--Nashville; Shutters--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architects--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture, Domestic--Tennessee--Nashville; Mansions--Tennessee--Nashville; Porches--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture, Italian--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Warterfield, Charles W. (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Estate of Charles W. Warterfield, Jr., F. A. I. A. (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1959</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Slides; Architectural photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>WSC 3957</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Charles Warterfield Architectural Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital image.  This image is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Nashville Room, Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/29</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>