<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Kirkland Hall, Vanderbilt University Campus, Nashville, Tennessee, circa 1955</dc:title>
<dc:description>A view of Kirkland Hall, located on the campus of Vanderbilt University in Nashville, Tennessee.  Kirkland Hall is one of the original buildings of Vanderbilt University in Nashville, Tennessee.  It was built to replace Vanderbilt's Main Building that burned in 1905. Vanderbilt University was made possible in 1873 through a one million dollar gift from Commodore Cornelius Vanderbilt, a shipping and rail tycoon who had never even visited the South. Vanderbilt's hope in supporting a university in the South was that it would "contribute to strengthening the ties which should exist between all sections of our common country." At the University's onset, the campus consisted of the Main Building, an astronomical observatory and houses for professors. The original Vanderbilt Library was housed in the Main Building. In 1905 a fire consumed the Main Building and it was rebuilt with one tower as Kirkland Hall in honor of the school's longest serving Chancellor, James H. Kirkland. Kirkland guided the rebuilding process and also navigated the University through the separation from the Methodist Church. Today Kirkland Hall houses the administration offices and sits off of West End Avenue. The statue in front of the building is that of Cornelius Vanderbilt, the 19th century American railway magnate and philanthropist for whom the university was named.  Forms part of the Metro Archives Photographs - Buildings Collection. 1 photograph. </dc:description>
<dc:subject>	
Vanderbilt University--History--Sources
</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Universities and colleges--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; West End Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1955</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs </dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Metro Archives Photos - Buildings Box 2 Kirkland Tower Vanderbilt Univ 007</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Metro Archives Photographs, Buildings Collection </dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880. </dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/10404</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>