<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Oral history interview with James Carlew, 2004 March 25, excerpt 05</dc:title>
<dc:description>An excerpt from an oral history interview with Nashville veteran James Carlew, conducted on 25 March 2004 by Larry Patterson as part of the Nashville Public Library's Veterans History Project.  Carlew, who served in the Navy during World War II and in the Army in the Korean War, discusses his experiences in basic training at Fort Jackson, South Carolina, as he entered Army service during the Korean War.  He provides vivid descriptions of  his training including obstacle courses, being in a trench while a tank crossed above him, and shells exploding and machine guns firing nearby.  The complete interview, as well as an index, is available in the repository.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Carlew, James, 1927- --Interviews</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Veterans History Project (U.S.); United States. Army</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Military History; Veterans--Tennessee--Interviews; Korean War; African Americans; Basic training (military education); Infiltration (military science); Korean War, 1950-1953--Veterans--Tennessee--Interviews; Korean War, 1950-1953--Sources; Korean War, 1950-1953--Personal narratives, American</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Fort Jackson (S.C.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Carlew, James, 1927- (Interviewee); Patterson, Larry, 1944- (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2004-03-25</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3 (50 sec.)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>VHPCarlewJ2aclip1</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpt from:  VHPCarlewJ audio cassette recording converted to mp3 format in 2006.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Veterans History Project collection, World War II and Korean War series</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/637</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>