<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Fire razes handsome Belle Meade home, from the Nashville Times, 1940</dc:title>
<dc:description>A published photo from the Nashville Times (1940), about a fire that gutted a home on Lynwood Boulevard. The caption reads: &#8220;Fire which broke out shortly after noon today gutted the home of J. A. Hawkinson on Lynwood Boulevard. Apparently starting in the attic of the home, the fire swept over the entire structure, destroying all furniture except on the first floor. The home was almost a total loss. The Belle Meade Fire Department and City Fire Company No. 17 answered the call.&#8221; Forms part of the Nashville Times newspaper collection. 1 digital photo.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Hawkinson, J. A.</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture, Domestic--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Fire departments--Tennessee--Nashville--History--Sources; Fire departments--Tennessee--Belle Meade--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Belle Meade (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Belle Meade (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Lynwood Boulevard (Belle Meade, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1940</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>FireHawkinsonHome--NT-1940</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Times Newspaper Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4210</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>