<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Original wills, Ahlum, Alvin F., 1911 February 09</dc:title>
<dc:description>Related to the last will and testament and of Alvin F. Ahlum.  Illustrates the first page of a form stating &#8220;we have examined the records and files in the office of the Surrogate of the County of New York, do find there remaining, a certain record of the last will and testament of Alvin F. Ahlum, deceased, together with the probate thereof and the Letters Testamentary granted thereon (said will having been duly admitted to probate as a will of real and personal property on the eleventh day of March in the year one thousand nine hundred and ten &#8230;.&#8221;  The last will and testament (a typescript) of Alvin F. Ahlum, cites &#8220;the Township of East Orange, in the County of Essex and State of New Jersey,&#8221; dated January 24th, 1902.  The probate filing date, February 9th, 1911. Forms part of Record Group 16, Original Wills, 1780-1925.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Ahlum family</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Wills--New York--New York County</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Davidson County (Tenn.)--Wills; Davidson County (Tenn.)--History; Davidson County (Tenn.)--Genealogy; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; New York County (N.Y.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1911-02-09</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text; Wills</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Original Wills--Ahlum, Alvin F 1911</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Record Group 16, Original Wills, 1780-1925</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1900-1909; 1910-1919</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4349</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>