<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Zeitgeist Society, featured in the Yearbook &#8220;Salmagundi,&#8221; of the Boscobel College for Young Ladies, Nashville, Tennessee, 1907  </dc:title>
<dc:description>Pictured here are members of the Zeitgeist Society of Boscobel College for Young Ladies, circa 1907.  These are Robin Naylor, Mary Cooper, Cherie Bashaw, Alice Singletery, Minnie Waggoner, Frances Coleman, Mabel Watson, Felicia Johnson, Muriel Waggoner, Kate Officer, Lula Estes, Elsie Toliver, Ouida Webb, Ora Cude, Florence Russell, Katharine Tanner, Margaret Bilbrey, Etta Officer, Cora Bradley, Gladdys Kimbrough, and Jimmie Thompson.  The colors of the Zeitgeist Society are Blue and Gold; the Flower: Violet; and the Motto &#8220;We live in the present.&#8221;  The Officers of the first half of the club are Katharine Tanner, President; Eva Linebaugh, Vice-President; Sallie Johnson, Secretary; and Elsie Toliver, Treasurer.  The Officers of the second half of the club are Eva Linebaugh, President; Elsie Toliver, Vice-President; Mabel Watson, Secretary; and Anna White, Treasurer.  The Boscobel College for Young Ladies was a college in East Nashville, founded in 1889 as the Nashville Baptist Female College by the Tennessee Baptist Convention.  The college operated for twenty-five years--until 1914.  The campus was built around an East Nashville mansion, formerly owned by Anna Shelby Williams.  The mansion stood atop a tree-covered hill overlooking the Cumberland River.  The campus covered ten wooded acres on Sevier Street near South Seventh Street (then called Foster Street), south of Sylvan Street.  In 1918, the property became home to the National Baptist Seminary and Missionary Training School, which functioned until 1931. The buildings were razed in 1940.  Forms part of the yearbook collection: Boscobel College, &#8220;Salmagundi,&#8221; 1907.  1 volume </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Naylor, Robin; Cooper, Mary; Bashaw, Cherie; Singletery, Alice; Waggoner, Minnie; Coleman, Frances; Watson, Mabel; Johnson, Felicia; Waggoner, Muriel; Officer, Kate; Estes, Lula; Toliver, Elsie; Webb, Ouida; Cude, Ora; Russell, Florence; Tanner, Katharine; Bilbrey, Margaret; Officer, Etta; Bradley, Cora; Kimbrough, Gladdys; Thompson, Jimmie; Linebaugh, Eva; Johnson, Sallie; White, Anna </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Boscobel College (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Universities and colleges--Tennessee--Nashville; Women--Tennessee--Nashville; School facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Education--Tennessee--Nashville; Women--Societies and clubs--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Intellectual life

</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Davis, Betty Dorris (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1907</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Boscobel College 1907 071 zeitgeist society photo; Boscobel College 1907 072 zeitgeist society </dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Boscobel College Yearbook 1907</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1900-1909</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/8865</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>