<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Nashville Children's Theatre Carnival, 1941 May 13</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of a portion of the children who attended the Nashville Children's Theatre Carnival. This excerpt ran with the Nashville Banner newspaper story on May 14, 1941 about the event: "The parking space at the side of the Community Playhouse on Carleton Avenue was transformed into the carnival site yesterday afternoon as J. B. Hager, president of Union Ice Cream Company, entertained children who regularly attend the performances of the Children's Theatre, a Junior League sponsored project. This carnival started three years ago when Mrs. Walter Fort was talking to Hager about the way children attending the performances destroyed their programs. The Union Ice Cream Company president hit upon the idea to let his company sponsor an entertainment to regard all those good children who preserved their programs. The carnival is given for all children who can present the complete set of programs from Children's Theatre performances as admission to the annual entertainment." Forms part of the Nashville Banner Archives. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 3.25 x 4.25 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Nashville Children's Theatre; Junior League of Nashville; Union Ice Cream Company (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Performing Arts; Theatre; Popular Culture; Children's History; Entertainment; Capital City; Organizations; Entertainers--Tennessee--Nashville; Performing arts--Tennessee--Nashville; Children's theater--Tennessee--Nashville; Entertainment events--Tennessee--Nashville; Carnivals--Tennessee--Nashville; Children--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Carleton Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.) </dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1941-05-13</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BN 1941-145-4</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/2316</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>