<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Ninth Annual Southeastern Regional Ballet Festival, 1964 April</dc:title>
<dc:description>A program from the Ninth Annual Southeastern Regional Ballet Festival in Nashville, Tennessee.  The show ran from April 24-26, 1964.  The program contains a list of performing companies, advertisements for local businesses, performance credits, photographs, and names of donors.  Forms part of the Albertine Society Collection. 1 program : col. ; 8.5 x 11 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Southeastern Regional Ballet Association</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Performing Arts; Dance; Entertainment; Popular Culture; Parades and Festivals; Performing arts--Tennessee--Nashville; Ballet programs--Tennessee--Nashville; Dancers--Tennessee--Nashville; Ballet dancers--Tennessee--Nashville; Ballet--United States; Dance festivals--United States; Ballet companies--United States; Entertainers--Tennessee--Nashville; Entertainment--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--20th century--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1964-04</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Ephemera; Programs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>ASC - Ballet Festival, Nashville, 1964</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Albertine Society Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/901</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>