<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of Tillman William "Bill" Bratton, 1969 March</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of Tillman William "Bill" Bratton standing in a U.S. military camp in Quang Tri Province, South Vietnam during the Vietnam War.  In this photograph, Bratton is holding an M-16 rifle and wearing a helmet and flak vest.  He served in the 1st Battalion, 3rd Marine Regiment, 3rd Marine Division during the Vietnam War from February 1968 to February 1972, seeing time in Vietnam, Okinawa, Camp Lejeune, North Carolina, in the Mediterranean Sea with NATO forces, and in Albany, Georgia.  His training prepared him for mechanical engineering duties, maintenance and handling of mobile vehicles and electrical generator machinery.  He was also well-prepared for combat, where he engaged in fire fights, mainly defensive maneuvers, against the North Vietnam Army near the DMZ line.  Forms part of the Veterans History Project. 1 polaroid : col. ; 4 x 3.25 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Bratton, Bill (Tillman William), 1947-</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>United States. Marine Corps. Division, 3rd. Regiment, 3rd. Battalion, 1st</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Military History; Vietnam War; War; Veterans--Tennessee--History--Sources; Vietnam War, 1961-1975; Military training camps; Rifles; Military life--American; Marines (Military personnel); Military personnel--American--Tennessee---Nashville; Military service--United States</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Quang Tri (Vietnam)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Bratton, Bill (Tillman William), 1947- (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1969-03</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>VHP-Vietnam-Bratton, Tillman-3</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Veterans History Project Collection, Vietnam Series, Tillman W. "Bill" Bratton Papers</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1516</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>