<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Second report of the Board of Health to the Honorable City Council of the City of Nashville, for the year ending July 4, 1877 </dc:title>
<dc:description>An official publication of the City of Nashville, Tennessee, titled &#8220;Second Report of the Board of Health to the Honorable City Council of the City of Nashville, for the year ending July 4, 1877.&#8221;  Forms part of the Publications Collection: Report of the Board of Health of City of Nashville, 1877. 1 book publication. </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Foster, Wilbur F., 1834-1922; Plunket, J.D.; Nowlin, J.B.W.; Draughon, John A.; Buist, J.R.; Kercheval, Thomas A.; Lindsley, J. Berrien, 1822-1897; Hawkins, B.M.; Kerrigan, Martin; Stone, William P.; Safford, James M., 1822-1907; Lupton, N. T. (Nathaniel Thomas), 1830-1893; Blackie, George Stodart, 1834-1881; Nelson, Anson </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Public health--Tennessee--Nashville; Epidemics--Tennessee--Nashville; Cholera--Tennessee--Nashville--History--Sources; Mortality; Parks--Tennessee--Nashville; Health--Statistics </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1877</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>City Health Dept Report 1877 001</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Report of the Board of Health of City of Nashville, 1877</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1870-1879</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/10739</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>