<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Miss Nashville Pageant at War Memorial Auditorium, 1961 June 17</dc:title>
<dc:description>Pictured: Nashville Mayor Ben West with &#8220;Miss Congeniality&#8221; co-winners: Margie Patterson (left), and Linda June Morton (right), of the Miss Nashville Pageant held at War Memorial Auditorium on June 16th and 17th, 1961. The contestants and sponsors: Carole Faye Bishop (Miss Woodbine Jaycees), Marilyn Hill (Miss Service Wholesale Company); Linda Ruth Himes (Miss Allen&#8217;s); Patricia Jones (Miss Beaman Bottling Company); Mary Penelope Llewellyn (Downtown Sertoma Club); Delores Ann Martin (Miss Tennessee Glass Company); Carolyn Jewel Mayes (Miss Chapman Ford, Inc.);  Nancy Moore (Miss Madison Square Shopping Center); Linda Faye Morris (Miss Rent-All Center); Linda June Morton (Miss WMAK); Margie Patterson (Miss Mary Kay Fabric Shop); Judy Paul Phillips (Miss Nashville Office Equipment Company); Patricia Sue Schmidt (Miss Nick Lambos Academy of Dancing); Jo Ann Spencer (Miss Coca-Cola Bottling Company); Lynda Louise Stockfisch (Miss Karl&#8217;s Shoe Company); Sheila Louise Wadley (Miss John Hardy Shoe Company); Margaret Davis Warren (Miss Strike &#8216;N Spare Bowling Lanes); Barbara Gayle White (Miss Cooper Realty Company).  The Judges were Mrs. Louis Nicholas, Music Teacher at Free Will Baptist College; Mr. Richard Fulton, former State Senator-Producer of the East High Talent Show; Mr. Dan Fitzgerald, Public Relations Director at Harvey&#8217;s, Mr. John Sellers, President of Nashville Art Director&#8217;s Club; and Miss Audrey Holmes, Director of Women&#8217;s Programs at Radio Station WLAC.  Patricia Sue Schmidt was crowned Miss Nashville and Penny Llewellyn Miss Davidson County.  There were other awardees in the contest for &#8220;Miss Congeniality,&#8221; &#8220;Miss Talent,&#8221; and &#8220;1st Runner-Up.&#8221;  Forms part of Record Group 3, Metro Davidson County Photographer. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>War Memorial Building (Nashville, Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Beauty contests--Tennessee--Nashville; Beauty contestants--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>McClurkan, Milton (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1961-06-17</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 3 8382 Miss Nashville contest June17 1961 009</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3 Metro Davidson County Photographer</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/5796</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>