<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Crowd of onlookers at opening of Tennessee Theatre, 1952 February 28</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of crowd of onlookers who thronged Church Street watching the arrival of movie stars and local VIPS at the gala opening of the Tennessee Theatre February 28, 1952 in downtown Nashville, Tennessee. Outside activities included broadcasts by WSIX radio and WSM television, a concert by the American Legion Post 5 band, and the arrival of the honored guests, each with an individual police escort. Each star was introduced to the crowd from a street platform before entering the building. Banner caption announced "New Theater Opens With All The Glamour of Hollywood" on the next day story.
Forms part of the Nashville Banner Archives. 1 photograph : b &amp; w ; 8 x 10 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Tennessee Theatre (Nashville, Tenn.); Sudekum Building (Nashville, Tenn.); Barton's (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville Shirt Shops (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Performing Arts; Architecture; Buildings; Business; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Popular Culture; Entertainment; Motion picture theaters--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Crowds--Tennessee--Nashville; People--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Church Street (Nashville, Tenn.); Sixth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>White, Bob (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1952-02-28</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BP - Nash-Theaters-TennesseeTh1</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/2321</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>