<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Blue Triangle Branch of the YWCA participates in camp show series, Nashville, Tennessee, 1952 November 08</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of "The Business and Professional Women's Club of the Blue Triangle Branch of the YWCA, in cooperation with the local USO, Friday night opened what is planned to be a series of camp show entertainments for airmen at Sewart Air Force Base. Shown above preparing to board a Sewart bus to the base from downtown Nashville, the group includes, from left, Mose J. Davie, USO steering committeeman; Mrs. P. M. Nixon, USO director; Esther Gray, Miss Louise Gullatte, Blue Triangle director, Mary Pearl Ragganer, Vera Flint, Yvonne Paschal, Esther Avant, Barbara Whitehead, Eunice Douglas, Tillie Faulkerson, Janet Fisher, Mrs. Edith Hendley, USO hostess at Sewart, Elizabeth Brooks, Ruby Moody, Sally Cunningham, Margaret Curtis, Miss Mary D. Shane, Flossie Duncan, Callie Orr, DeLois Lambert, Mrs. Indiana Whitlock, Mary Jamison, Mrs. Thelma Mason, Lois White, BP&amp;W president, George Berry, Bill Powell, of WSOK, who served as master of ceremonies of the show, and Mary Jamison." This photograph appeared in the Nashville Banner Newspaper on November 8, 1952 with the article "Camp Show Series Planned at Sewart." Forms part of the Nashville Banner Archives. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 3.25 x 4.25 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Davie, Mose J.; Nixon, P. M., Mrs.; Gray, Esther; Gullatte, Louise; Ragganer, Mary Pearl; Flint, Vera; Paschal, Yvonne; Avant, Esther; Whitehead, Barbara; Douglas, Eunice; Faulkerson, Tillie; Fisher, Janet; Hendley, Edith; Brooks, Elizabeth; Moody, Ruby; Cunningham, Sally; Curtis, Margaret; Shane, Mary D.; Duncan, Flossie; Orr, Callie; Lambert, DeLois; Whitlock, Indiana; Jamison, Mary; Mason, Thelma; White, Lois; Berry, George; Powell, Bill; Jamison, Mary</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>YWCA of Nashville and Middle Tennessee (Nashville, Tenn.)--History--Sources; Sewart Air Force Base (Smyrna, Tenn.); United Service Organizations (U.S.). Service Club (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Performing Arts; Music; Military History; Home Front; Business; Capital City; Popular Culture; Entertainment; African American women--Tennessee--Nashville; African American men--Tennessee--Nashville; Entertainment events--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Smyrna (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Howe, Jack (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1952-11-08</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BN 1952-288</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/2354</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>