<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Engagement announcement of Kathryn Parrish, Nashville, Tennessee, circa 1933 </dc:title>
<dc:description>A scrapbook page related to the engagement announcement of Miss Kathryn Parrish, daughter of Mr. and Mrs. William McMurray Parrish, to James Collins Thurman (Mr. and Mrs. James Collins Thurman, Jr.). The Parrish-Thurman announcement was published in the newspaper, stating &#8220;The wedding will take place in June [of 1933].  Miss Parrish, a popular member of the younger social set, received her college and dancing certificate from Ward-Belmont, and is a member of the Girls&#8217; Cotillion Club.&#8221;  Another clipping states &#8220;Mr. Thurman, the son of Mr. and Mrs. James C. Thurman of Chattanooga, attended McCallie Preparatory School, and later Vanderbilt University, where he was a member of Phi Delta Theta fraternity and a member of the varsity football and track teams.&#8221;  Forms part of the James C. Thurman Collection.  1 scrapbook page ; b &amp; w. </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Parrish, Kathryn; Thurman family; Thurman, James C. </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Marriage--Tennessee--Nashville; Families--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1933-06</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Thurman Coll Photos - Scrapbook1 Kathryn Parrish 002</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Thurman Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/7296</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>