<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Oral history interview with James Carlew, 2004 March 25, excerpt 02</dc:title>
<dc:description>An excerpt from an oral history interview with Nashville veteran James Carlew, conducted on 25 March 2004 by Larry Patterson as part of the Nashville Public Library's Veterans History Project.  Carlew, who served in the Navy during World War II and in the Army in the Korean War, discusses his experience as the youngest man in his company, at age 15.  His fellow sailors had some fun at his expense, challenging him to smoke a cigar, after which he promptly became sick.  They also looked out for him, nicknaming him "Young Blood."  The complete interview, as well as an index, is available in the repository.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Carlew, James, 1927- --Interviews</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Veterans History Project (U.S.); United States. Navy--Military Life</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Military History; Veterans--Tennessee--Interviews; World War II; African Americans; World War, 1939-1945--Participation, African-American; World War, 1939-1945--Personal narratives, American; Salilors--Tennessee--Biography; Cigars--Humor; Cigars--Social aspects; African American young men--Social conditions; Basic training (military education)--United States; Male friendship</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Great Lakes Naval Traning Center (Great Lakes, Ill.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Carlew, James, 1927- (Interviewee); Patterson, Larry, 1944- (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2004-03-25</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3 (43 sec.)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>VHPCarlewJ1aclip2</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpt from:  VHPCarlewJ audio cassette recording converted to mp3 format in 2006.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Veterans History Project collection, World War II and Korean War series</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/634</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>