<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Girl Scouts welcome old king winter with a smile, from the Nashville Times, 1940</dc:title>
<dc:description>A captioned photo from the Nashville Times (1940), about the Girl Scouts. The caption reads: &#8220;Fun all year round is an important part of Girl Scouting. This recreational program for girls believes in laughter as in integral part of normal living. Good, sound fun in the out-of-doors, with the woods ringing to the hearty laughter of fellow Girl Scouts tumbling in the snow, or gliding over the ice-covered lake, is a prelude to learning to live with a smile. The girls above take a minute from their fun to illustrate what we mean. Chores over for the day, they&#8217;re making the most of snow and ice with sleds, skates, weenies, and laughter!&#8221; Forms part of the Nashville Times newspaper collection. 1 digital photo.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Entertainment events--Tennessee--Nashville; Frankfurters--Tennessee--Nashville; Sledding--Tennessee--Nashville; Brownie Girl Scouts--Tennessee--Nashville; Girl Scouts--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1940</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>GirlScouts--NT-1940</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Times Newspaper Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4247</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>