<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Oral history interview with Bobby and Margo Cain, 2007 June 13</dc:title>
<dc:description>Excerpts from an interview with civil rights movement participant Robert "Bobby" Cain, Jr., and his wife, Margo Cain, conducted on 13 June 2007 by Gwen Smith.  Cain, one of the "Clinton 12," was the first African-American student to graduate from an integrated public high school in the South, in the late spring of 1957 at Clinton High School in Anderson County, Tennessee.  In the excerpts, Cain discusses the mood of the community prior to his first day of school during the desegregation of Clinton High School in 1956-1957; the violent mob attack on Reverend Paul Turner after escorting the twelve students to school; and the Green McAdoo Cultural Center.  Margo Cain discusses two media sources about her husband as well as talking about her grandmother's introduction to him when they were students at Tennessee State University.  The complete interview is available in the Special Collections Division.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Cain, Bobby (Robert) L., 1939-  --Interviews; Turner, Paul W.; Cain, Margo--Interviews</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Clinton High School (Clinton, Tenn.); Green McAdoo Cultural Center (Clinton, Tenn.); Tennessee State University</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African Americans; Civil Rights; Race Relations; Education; High Schools; Colleges and Universities; High schools--Tennessee--Clinton; Segregation in education--Tennessee--Clinton; School integration--Tennessee--Clinton; African Americans--Civil rights--Tennessee--Clinton; African American students--Education (Secondary)--United States; African Americans--Education--Tennessee--Clinton; High school students--Tennessee--Clinton; Social change--Tennessee; Social justice--Tennessee--Clinton; Civil rights movements--Tennessee--Clinton; Civil rights workers--Tennessee--Clinton; Racism--Tennessee--Clinton; Race relations--Religious aspects--Christianity</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Clinton (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Education; Clinton (Tenn.)--Race relations; Clinton (Tenn.)--Social conditions; Clinton (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Tennessee--Race relations</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Cain, Bobby (Robert) L, 1939- (Interviewee); Cain, Margo (Interviewee); Smith, Gwen (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2007-06-13</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CROHPCainB1004clip1.mp3; CROHPCainB1007clip1.mp3; CROHPCainB1012clip1.mp3; CROHPCainB_transcript.pdf</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from: CROHPCainB digital recording converted from wav to mp3 format.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Civil Rights Oral History Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1806</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>