<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Paramount Theater, a "palatial playhouse" part of the Publix Theater chain, circa 1930</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of the Paramount Theatre at 721-727 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee circa 1930. The marquee advertises "Gary Cooper &amp; Marlene Deitrich - Morocco - C. Sharpe Minor at the Organ - Eddie Canter." The $500,000 theater opened November 14, 1930, ads boasted "A New Show World in Tomorrow's Theater - a new standard of luxury, comfort and entertainment - a theater to match the achievements of Nashville - Come, marvel, thrill to the living screen." A reported 2,500 patrons visited the theater on opening night, at 60 cents each, outnumbering the seating capacity by 500. The theater was remodeled in 1949 and demolished after 1978. Forms part of the Nashville Banner Archives. 1 photograph : b &amp; w ; 8 x 10 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Dietrich, Marlene</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Paramount Theatre (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Performing Arts; Architecture; Buildings; Business; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Popular Culture; Entertainment; Motion picture theaters--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Theaters--Tennessee--Nashville; Art deco (Architecture)--Tennessee--Nashville; Cultural facilities--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Church Street (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Nashville Banner staff photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1930</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BP Nash-Theaters-ParamountTh</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/2355</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>