<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Lower Broad Street, circa 1970s</dc:title>
<dc:description>A color postcard of Lower Broad Street (now Broadway), near the Ryman Auditorium, where country music started in Nashville and country music stars were often seen prior to performances. The street has some of the oldest buildings in town and is a popular tourist venue. It was originally called Broad Street, named for its width. Forms part of the Nashville Room Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Business; Restaurants; Tourism; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Popular Culture; 
Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Music and tourism--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Business enterprises--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Tourism--Tennessee--Nashville; Commercial streets--Tennessee--Nashville </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Broadway Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Broad Street (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Scotty Post Card Co. (Distributor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1970-1979</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Nash - 355 - Lower Broad St</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1970-1979</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/605</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>