<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Nashville Female Academy Exhibition, June 6-8, 1859</dc:title>
<dc:description>Five printed sheets of colored paper, glued vertically, to form one lengthy broadside, announcing the 43rd annual exhibition by students at the Nashville Female Academy, held as part of commencement exercises on June 6-8, 1859 in Nashville, Tenn. Events include musical performances and essay readings. Titles of pieces are listed, along with names of students and their hometowns. Most students are from Middle Tennessee, but numerous girls come from Kentucky, Mississippi, and Alabama. Students include: Mary E. Swearingen; Teloula C. Weaver; Lavinia J. Crutcher; Annie Thompson; Mary E. Blanchard; Lucy A. Dabbs; Hattie E. Boxley; Anna E. Dunaway; Lucy P. Moore; Georgia E. Burton; Zorilda L. Snead; Sally W. Newsom; Mary H. Hadly; Irene Stuart; Tranquilla Reed; Katie S. Page; Kate C. Hodges; Felicia Kittrell; Anna S. March; Annie E. Hester; Michal Harris Wynn; Mary Mathison; Ellen K. Rains; Emma Reynolds; Corinne Reeves; Mary R. Mosby; Maggie McFerran; Pattie Wade; Josephine B. Reeves; Mattie Powell; Mattie G. Moore; Susan V. M&#8217;Nairy (McNairy); Emma S. Anderson; Leonora Hamilton; Kate Norvell; Rebecca B. Harris; Bettie Childress; Annie L. Boddie; M. Ludie Baugh; Maria E. Topp; Bettie W. Pointer; Leah A. Cannon; Mollie E. Sims; Maria H. Jones; Mary S. Abbay; Mary A. Catchings; Hattie E. Moore; Mary D. Jones; Ella Reynolds; Lizzie G. Otis; Lizzie M. Moore; Mollie E. Martin; Mary D. McClelland; Alethia Allison; Mary R. Brabston; Lou Fortson; and Mary W. Evans. Forms part of the Schools Ephemera Subject Files. 1 format: col.; 6.5 x 55 in</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Nashville Female Academy (Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Music; Performing Arts; Popular Culture; Entertainment; Education; Women; Education--Tennessee--Nashville; Students--Tennessee--Nashville; Children--Tennessee--Nashville; Girls--Tennessee--Nashville; Commencement ceremonies--Tennessee--Nashville; Girls&#8217; schools--Tennessee--Nashville; Schools--Tennessee--Nashville; Music--Instruction and study--Tennessee--Nashville; Performances--Tennessee--Nashville;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--19th century--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Intellectual life; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs;</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1859-06</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text; Manuscripts; Broadsides; Programs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>ESF-Sch-NashFemaleAcad-Exhibition 1859</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Ephemera Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1850-1859</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/11625</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>