<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Noah&#8217;s Ark Show at Hadley Park, Nashville, Tennessee, 1958 August</dc:title>
<dc:description>A scene from the Noah&#8217;s Ark Show held at Hadley Park in Nashville, Tennessee circa August 1958.  Hadley Park was built in honor of Nashville&#8217;s African American citizens.  It opened under the administration of Mayor Hilary Howse in 1912, the first U.S. city park dedicated for African Americans. The entrance gates were built in the late 1930s by the Works Progress Administration.  On each side of the main entrance, the stone columns contain a list of the names of 11 African American soldiers from Davidson County who were killed during World War I.  The 1958 City Directory cites the address at 1001 28th Avenue N.  Forms part of Record Group 3, Metro Davidson County Photographer. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Urban parks--Tennessee--Nashville; Parks--Tennessee--Nashville; African Americans--Tennessee--Nashville--History--Sources; Children--Tennessee--Nashville; Entertainment events--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Twenty-eighth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1958-08</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 3 3766 Hadley Park Noahs Ark Show Aug1958 004</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3 Metro Davidson County Photographer</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/6257</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>