<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Advertisement from Nashville City Directory, 1871 </dc:title>
<dc:description>An advertisement of the Evansville, Henderson &amp; Nashville Railroad, published in the 1871 Nashville City Directory.  It states: &#8220;This route is 21 miles shorter from Nashville to St. Louis than any other route ... through tickets and information can be obtained at the General Tick Office, Maxwell House, and at the Depot of the Edgefield &amp; Kentucky and Louisville and Nashville Railroads, College Street, Nashville., H.L. Shepherd, Superintendent; Hugh Pitcairn, Asst. Supt.&#8221; The Evansville, Henderson &amp; Nashville Railroad was incorporated by act of the Kentucky Legislature, approved January 29, 1867, with power to construct and operate a railroad from Henderson to the Kentucky-Tennessee state line in the direction of Nashville.  On October 1, 1872, the E. H. &amp; N., with three other roads, consolidated into the St. Louis &amp; Southeastern Railway Company.  Forms part of Nashville City Directory Collection, Metro Archives. 1 digital image. </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Evansville, Henderson, and Nashville Railroad Company</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Railroads--Southern states--History; Railroads--United States--History; Advertising--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1871</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>NVL City Directory of 1871 ad Evansville Henderson&amp;Nashville Railroad</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville City Directory Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1870-1879</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/7561</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>