<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>"Do you think prayer has a prayer, chief?" between 1954 and 1962</dc:title>
<dc:description>An original political cartoon created by Jack Knox, the Nashville Banner editorial cartoonist from the mid-1940s to the early 1970s.  In the foreground, Chief Justice Earl Warren and another judge look at a "No Prayer Decree" and look out the window at the Capital ("Congress").  In 1962, a landmark United State Supreme Court case (Engel v. Vitale) determined that it was unconstitutional for state officials to compose an official school prayer and require classroom recitation in public schools.  The ruling did not apply to parochial or private schools in general.  Forms part of the Jack Knox Political Cartoon Collection. 1 original cartoon drawing : b &amp; w ; 14 x 19 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Warren, Earl, 1891-1974-- Caricatures and cartoons</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Banner; United States.  Congress--Caricatures and cartoons; United States.  Supreme Court--Caricatures and cartoons</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Capital City; Education; Politics; Popular Culture; Religion; Political cartoons--United States--20th century; Political cartoons--Tennessee--Nashville; Caricatures and cartoons--Tennessee--Nashville; Cartoonists--Tennessee--Nashville; Editorial cartoonists--Tennessee--Nashville; Religion in the public schools--Caricatures and cartoons; Moral education--Caricatures and cartoons; Religious education--Caricatures and cartoons; Jurisdiction--United States--Caricatures and cartoons; Cartoonists; Politics &amp; government--United States--Washington, D.C.; Economic &amp; political systems</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>United States--Politics and government--20th century--Caricatures and cartoons; United States--Officials and employees--Caricatures and cartoons</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Knox, Jack, 1910- (Cartoonist)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Knox, Joseph T. (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>between 1954 and 1962</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Caricatures; Cartoons (Commentary); Editorial cartoons</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Knox NPL-280</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Jack Knox Political Cartoon Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959; 1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/867</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>