<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Geedville girls win Cannon County tourney, from the Nashville Times, 1940</dc:title>
<dc:description>A captioned photo from the Nashville Times (1940), about the Geedville girls in the basketball tournament. The caption reads: &#8220;Here are the Geedville girls of the Fifth District of Cannon county who breezed through to win the Cannon county elementary basketball tournament. First row, left to right: Virginia Smithson, Juanita Smithson, Lora Rogers, and Ruby Mitchell. Back row: Georgia Lee Young, Marjorie Davenport, Coach William Rogers, Fern Smithson and Iown? Young. 
Forms part of the Nashville Times newspaper collection. 1 digital photo.  </dc:description>
<dc:subject>
Basketball--Tournaments</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Cannon County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Basketball coaches--Tennessee--Cannon County; Women basketball coaches--Tennessee--Cannon County</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1940</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>GeedvilleGrils--NT-1940</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Times Newspaper Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4251</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>