<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Laying granite along Walnut Street and Union Depot, circa 1897 </dc:title>
<dc:description>A picture of men at work laying granite along Walnut Street (10th Avenue), sourced from the &#8220;Reports of departments of the City of Nashville for the fiscal year ending December 31, 1897.&#8221;  Includes a view of the Union Depot, which played an important role to advance the Tennessee Centennial Exposition of 1897.  The yearbook consists of official reports of the City Government of Nashville, Tennessee, with a Message of the Mayor R.H. Dudley to the City Council members, dated Jan. 13, 1898.  This publication was prepared for the press by James T. Bell, Recorder.  Forms part of the City of Nashville published reports.  1 yearbook. </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Union Station (Nashville, Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Municipal government--Tennessee--Nashville; Municipal reports--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Transportation--Tennessee--Nashville; Railroads--Buildings and structures--Tennessee--Nashville; Transportation buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Railroad stations--Tennessee--Nashville </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Politics and government; Walnut Street (Nashville, Tenn.); Tenth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Brandon Printing Company (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1898</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>City of Nashville 1897 Yearbook 060a Walnut Street</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Publications, City of Nashville reports, 1897 yearbook</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1890-1898</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880. </dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/10386</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>