<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Metro Nashville Fireman with a high-powered hose, circa 1969</dc:title>
<dc:description>A Metro Nashville Fireman using a high-powered hose, circa 1969.  Historically, it was circa May of 1807, when the city formed its&#8217; first volunteer fire fighting unit. The Nashville Fire Department was organized as a paid department on July 24, 1860, with John S. Dashiell as its first chief. The first horse drawn steam fire engine was called the "Hamilton," named after Mr. J. M. Hamilton, who was a prominent hardware man of the time. Two other horse drawn engines, the "Eclipse", and the "Deluge" were also in service. In 1861, a hook and ladder company was added to Nashville's growing fire department. Nashville put its&#8217; first motorized fire engine in service in 1912.  Forms part of Record Group 3. The original is a 35 mm color transparency (2 x 2 in. slide mount).</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.). Fire Department</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Fire departments--Tennessee--Nashville; Fire fighters--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1969</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Slide1101 Metro fireman with high powered hose</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/5835</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>