<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of Eddy Arnold and his secretary Mary Grizzard, 1959 June 16</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of country music performer and businessman Eddy Arnold with Mrs. Leslie (Mary) Grizzard, his secretary. The photograph appeared in the Nashville Banner newspaper as part of a series of articles about Nashville employers and their secretaries. Mr. Arnold's definition of a secretary was "a loyal, alert and friendly person who wants to be a part of a business." Mrs. Grizzard agreed that "a secretary has to understand the business, have its interests at heart and consider it as your business".  Forms part of the Nashville Banner Archives. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 3.25 x 4.25 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Arnold, Eddy, 1918- ; Grizzard, Mary</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Business; Enterprise; Industries; Popular Culture; Entertainment; Performing Arts; Music; Business enterprises--Tennessee--Nashville; Music industry--Tennessee--Nashville; Businessmen--Tennessee--Nashville; Musicians--Tennessee--Nashville; Secretaries--Tennessee--Nashville; Country musicians--Tennessee--Nashville; Office workers--Tennessee--Nashville; Business people-- Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Commerce; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Gunter, Jack  (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1959-06-16</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negative; Film negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BN 1959 - 1321</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/871</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>