<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>From Acorn to Oak:  Quarter Century Achievement of The National Life &amp; Accident Insurance Co., 1902-1926</dc:title>
<dc:description>The front cover of a twenty-fifth anniversary booklet celebrating the quarter century of achievements for the National Life and Accident Insurance Company.  The front cover shows a rough sketch of an oak tree and a detailed drawing of the stone building that the company occupied on the northwest corner of Seventh Avenue and Union Street.  The booklet is loosely bound together with a blue string.  National Life and Accident began in 1900 as the National Sick and Accident Association, a mutual company. It was reorganized as a stock company and adopted the National Life name shortly after.  Known for its creative marketing development, National Life began WSM radio in 1923.  Taking its call sign (WSM) from the company's motto We Shield Millions, the station began to broadcast advertising from inside the National Life office building in downtown Nashville.  Not long later, in 1925, the popular and historic Grand Ole Opry show began on WSM making country music mainstream.  Forms part of the Businesses Ephemera Subject Files. 1 pamphlet : col. ; 11.5  x 9  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>National Life and Accident Insurance Company, inc. Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Business; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Architecture; Buildings; Enterprise; Industries; Insurance; Business enterprises--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Insurance--Tennessee--Nashville; Insurance companies--Tennessee--Nashville; Financial institutions--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Details; Business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Seventh Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Union Street (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Commerce</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>National Life and Accident Insurance Company, Inc. Nashville</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1926</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Ephemera; Pamphlets</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>ESF - Bus - Nat Life &amp; Accid - 1926</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Ephemera Subject Files</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1920-1929</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/824</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>