<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Oral history interview with Judge Alfred Thompson Adams, 1980 September 16, excerpt 06</dc:title>
<dc:description>An excerpt from an oral history interview with Nashville lawyer and judge Alfred Thompson Adams, conducted on 16 September 1980 by Leanne Thornton as part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. 1910-1935 Oral History Project.  Adams, who served Nashville as Chancellor of Part Two of the Davidson County Chancery Court from 1957 to 1970, discusses his World War I service.  He also discusses coming back home to Nashville, attending Vanderbilt University's Law School, and entering into law practice with Robert S. Henry.  The complete interview is available in the repository.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Adams, Alfred Thompson, 1898-1982--Interviews; Henry, Robert Selph, 1889-</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Vanderbilt University. School of Law</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Education; Colleges and Universities; Business; Military History; World War I; Judges--Tennessee--Nashville; Lawyers--Tennessee--Nashville; Universities and colleges--Tennessee--Nashville; Practice of law--Tennessee--Nashville; Law offices--Tennessee--Nashville; Veterans--Tennessee--History--Sources; World War, 1914-1918</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Commerce; Nashville (Tenn.)--Intellectual life</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.; Adams, Alfred Thompson, 1898-1982 (Interviewee); Thornton, Leanne  (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1980-09-16</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3 (1 min., 43 sec.)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>HNIOHAdamsA1aclip6</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from:  HNIOHAdamsA audio cassette recording converted to mp3 format in 2006.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. 1910-1935 Oral History Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1980-1989</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/612</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>