<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>First dance with Lyndon, circa 1964</dc:title>
<dc:description>An original political cartoon drawing created by Jack Knox, the Nashville Banner editorial cartoonist from the mid-1940s to early 1970s.  This caricature depicts President Lyndon Baines Johnson with a "Civil Rights Hop Program Dance" card in his pocket as he awkwardly dances with a reluctant woman ("Dixie Dems").  Historically, a dissenting group of Southern Democrats known as Dixiecrats split from the party in 1948 to form the States' Rights Party.  In the 1960s, during the years of segregation politics, many of the party members went Republican all through the South when Lyndon Johnson supported the Civil Rights Voting Act bills and other progressive programs.  Forms part of the Jack Knox Political Cartoon Collection. 1 original cartoon drawing : b &amp; w ; 14.25 x 19 in. </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973--Caricatures and cartoons</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Banner; Democratic Party (U.S.)--Caricatures and cartoons; States' Rights Democratic Party--Caricatures and cartoons</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Capital City; Politics; Civil Rights; Political cartoons--United States--20th century; Political cartoons--Tennessee--Nashville; Caricatures and cartoons--Tennessee--Nashville; Cartoonists--Tennessee--Nashville; Editorial cartoonists--Tennessee--Nashville; Presidents--Election--20th century--Caricatures and cartoons; African Americans--Civil rights; Cartoonists; Politics &amp; government--United States--Washington, D.C.; Economic &amp; social conditions--United States--Washington, D.C.; Economic &amp; political systems; Presidents--United States</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Southern States--Politics and government--20th century--Caricatures and cartoons; United States--Politics and government--20th century--Caricatures and cartoons; United States--Race relations--History--20th century--Caricatures and cartoons</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Knox, Jack, 1910- (Cartoonist)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Knox, Joseph T. (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1964</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Caricatures; Cartoons (Commentary); Editorial cartoons</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Knox NPL-318</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Jack Knox Political Cartoon Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/956</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>