<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Historic home residence Overton Hall, Nashville, Tennessee, 1911</dc:title>
<dc:description>Overton Hall, &#8220;the residence of Mr. and Mrs. Jesse Maxwell Overton was built in 1900 by Mr. Overton. It is after the Tudor style of architecture for manor houses, and stands in the midst of a large park, thickly wooded with giant forest trees &#8230; with the closely clipped hedges which surround the formal garden and greenhouses, carry out the idea and appearance of its English architecture and planting. The land on which Overton Hall stands was granted by the United States government to Jesse Maxwell, the great grandfather of its present owner, for services in the Revolutionary War.&#8221; Overton was a businessman and stockbreeder, and he built the home for his wife Saidee Williams, daughter of banker John P. Williams. Overton Hall was built on the original Travellers&#8217; Rest south of Nashville, and he ran a farm, famous for the breeding of Berkshire hogs and Jersey cattle. The second owners Herbert and Ritchey Farrell renamed it Crieve Hall, after a family ancestral home in Northern Ireland. It stood until the early 1950s when it was razed for a housing development. The Tudor brick home was located about nine miles south of downtown Nashville, two miles north of Brentwood and east of Franklin Pike. One of its streets is Farrell Parkway, named for the family. This digital photo is reproduced from the book &#8220;Historical and Beautiful Country Homes Near Nashville,&#8221; compiled by Mrs. James E. Caldwell and published in 1911. 1 digital photo, title supplied by cataloger.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Overton family; Overton, Jesse Maxwell, 1863-1922--Homes and haunts; Farrell family</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture, Domestic--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Dwellings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Mansions--Tennessee--Nashville; Jersey cattle--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Franklin Pike (Nashville, Tenn.); Farrell Parkway (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Wiles, Marvin W. (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Dickenson III, Jacob McGavock (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1911</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>1911-Overton Hall frontpiece; 1911-Overton Hall; 1911-Overton Hall grounds; 1911-Overton grounds</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Historical and Beautiful Country Homes Near Nashville 1911</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1910-1919</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4400</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>