<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Ypres album-vues avant et apres la guerre Legia, circa 1919</dc:title>
<dc:description>A booklet of World War I era postcards showing scenes in and around Ypres, Begium, before and after the destruction caused by the war, titled &#8220;Ypres album-vues avant et apres la guerre Legia, published circa 1919.  This booklet has 20 monochrome postcards of various buildings damaged during WWI.  Each postcard has an informative caption in French and English.  The individual postcards are: Ypres, The Cloth Halls--The ruins of Ypres Cloth Halls in 1919--Ypres, St. Martin&#8217;s Church--The ruins of Ypres St. Martin&#8217;s Church in 1918--Ypres, Town Hall and Conciergerie--The ruins of Ypres Town Hall and Concierges--Ypres, The Inside of the Cloth Halls--The ruins of Ypres The Inside of the Cloth Halls in 1918--Ypres, Hospital--The ruins of Ypres Hospital--Ypres, St. Martin&#8217;s Church, South Portal--The ruins of Ypres St. Martin&#8217;s Church (South)--Ypres, Furnes&#8217;s Road and the Water Tower--The ruins of Ypres Furnes&#8217;s Road and the Water Tower--Ypres, The Cloth Halls--The ruins of Ypres The Cloth Halls </dc:description>
<dc:subject>World War, 1914-1918--Pictorial works; World War, 1914-1918--History--Sources;  Lost architecture--Belgium; World War, 1914-1918--Ypres (Belgium)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Ypres (Belgium)--Pictorial works; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Ieper (Belgium)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Alford Collection WWI album Ypres Avant et ApreslaGuerre 001 - 012</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Clarence Alford Collection   </dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2010-2019</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/8157</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>