<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Tullahoma - Arnold AFB, Tullahoma, Tennessee, between 1953 and 1956</dc:title>
<dc:description>Photographs, dated between 1953 and 1956, related to the construction of the Gas Dynamics Facility and the Ram Jet addition at the Arnold Air Force Base.  The military base is located in Coffee and Franklin counties, Tennessee, adjacent to the city of Tullahoma.  The airfield was decommissioned in 2009.  This United States Air Force base continues as part of the Air Force Test Center (AFTC) and Air Force Material Command (AFMC).  The Foster &amp; Creighton construction contracting firm was founded in 1885 by Wilbur F. Foster and Robert T. Creighton, who had both served as City Engineer of Nashville.  Forms part of the Foster &amp; Creighton General Contractors Collection. 14 b &amp; w photographs.  </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Arnold Air Force Base (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Business enterprises--Tennessee--Nashville; Construction industry--Tennessee--Nashville  </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Creighton III, Wilbur (donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CreightonColl ProjectsTenn Tullahoma Arnold AFB 1953-1956 </dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Foster &amp; Creighton General Contractors Collection
1970-1979
</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/9018</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>