<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Dick Battle and photographers ready for a helicopter flight at the Nashville Airport, 1954 November</dc:title>
<dc:description>Nashville Banner reporter Dick Battle (pictured on right) and two photojournalists on a helicopter flight at the airport, November 1954. Battle came to Nashville from his native St. Louis in 1916.  He graduated from Goodlettsville High School in 1925.  Battle next studied as a draftsman and commercial artist at Washington University in St. Louis.  He returned to Nashville and joined the staff of the &#8220;Evening Tennessean&#8221; in 1932.  He became a reporter for the &#8220;Banner&#8221; for 40 years, beginning in 1933 as a police reporter and graduating to the City Hall beat in 1937.  His &#8220;City Hall&#8221; column gained a wide readership over the years and he became well known in the community.  He retired from news reporting in 1973, and later worked with former Mayor Beverly Briley as a public relations consultant.  Forms part of Record Group 3, Metro Davidson County Photographer. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Battle, Dick</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville banner</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Journalists--Tennessee--Nashville; Photojournalists--Tennessee--Nashville; Helicopter industry--Tennessee--Nashville; Newspaper industry--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1954-11</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 3 3940 Dick Battle helicoper flight 001</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3 Metro Davidson County Photographer</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4556</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>