<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Letter from P.J. Williamson to his wife, Eunice, during the Civil War, 1864 August 13</dc:title>
<dc:description>A letter from Dutch immigrant, Peter J. Williamson, back home to his wife, Eunice, during the Civil War.  In 1862 Williamson enlisted as a Private in the 1st Wisconsin Cavalry, Company F and was ultimately promoted to Full 1st Lieutenant.  During the war, Williamson's regiment was involved in scouting and raids in Missouri and Arkansas and saw battle in the Middle Tennessee, Chickamauga, and Atlanta campaigns. In this letter from Cartersville, Georgia, Williamson writes that they are away from the front for a couple of months and describes it as being "lonesome" without the excitement of the war.  He provides a favorable description of his accommodations and the region and expresses his wish that he could send for her to join him.  He states that he lost two hundred dollars worth of his belongings in the raid but accepts that as a fact of war.  He predicts that he will get paid soon and wishes Eunice to let him know how her finances are holding up.  He tells her he will try to send a picture showing his state after he returned from the raid but warned her that it would not be flattering.  He closes by apologizing for the short letter and in a post script asks for a copy of the Appleton Crescent.  Forms part of the Peter J. Williamson Letters. 1 letter : col. ; 8  x 10 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Williamson, Peter J., 1823-1907; Williamson, Eunice Leihy, 1840-1928; Williamson, Peter, b. 1862; McCook, Edward M. (Edward Moody), 1833-1909; La Grange, Oscar Hugh, 1837-1915</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>United States. Army. Wisconsin Cavalry Regiment, 1st (1861-1865); United States. Army--Military life; Appleton crescent (Appleton, Wis. : Weekly : 1853)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Military History; Civil War; Popular Culture; War; Soldiers--United States--Correspondence; Soldiers--United States--Personal narratives; Immigrants--Wisconsin; Immigrants' writings, Dutch; Family; Wound healing; McCook's Raid, Ga., 1864; War--Economic aspects</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--19th century--Sources; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Personal narratives; Tennessee--History--Civil War, 1861-1865; Cartersville (Ga.)--History--Civil War, 1861-1865</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Williamson, Peter J., 1823-1907</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Currey, Martha T. (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1864-08-13</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text; Letters (correspondence)</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>PJW - f, 60</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Peter J. Williamson Letters</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/2115</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>