<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>First Presbyterian Church, Nashville, Tennessee, 1951 April 10</dc:title>
<dc:description>An exterior view of First Presbyterian Church (Downtown Presbyterian Church), April 10th, 1951.  The church is located at the corner of Fifth Avenue and Church Street.  Forms part of Record Group 412, Photographs Collection. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Downtown Presbyterian Church (Nashville, Tenn.); First Presbyterian Church (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Presbyterian church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture, Egyptian--Tennessee--Nashville; Presbyterian churches--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs; Fifth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Church Street (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1951-04-10</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 412 638 First Pres Apr10th1951 013</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 412</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/5536</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>