<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Henry Schofield, 1941 December</dc:title>
<dc:description>Pictured: Henry J. Schofield, a prominent Nashville photographer, with his camera, December, 1941. The first photograph he ever had published appeared in the Tennessean newspaper, where he became a staff photographer in the 1940s after spending a couple of years with the Nashville Times and Chattanooga Times.  He later joined the Marine Corps as a photographer with a sergeant&#8217;s rank, during which time he met his wife Edna Wagar Schofield, whom he married in 1943. They established the Henry Schofield Studio in Hillsboro Village, Nashville, a successful business enterprise that they ran with their son Henry J. (Chip) Schofield III for several decades.  Forms part of Record Group 412, Photographs Collection. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Schofield, Henry J.</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Photographers--Tennessee--Nashville; Businessmen--Tennessee--Nashville; Photojournalists--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1941-12</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 412 220 Henry Schofield Dec 1941 004</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 412</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/5356</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>