<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Excerpt 1 from oral history interview with George Boyles, 1987 October 27</dc:title>
<dc:description>An excerpt from an oral history interview with George Boyles, conducted on 27 October 1987 by Mary Glenn Hearne.  Boyles discusses the two-year debate among McKendree Methodist Church members over plans by church officials to build a high-rise office building over the church and an arcade leading up to the church door.   The complete interview, as well as a partial index, is available in the repository.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Boyles, George Herbert, 1905-1997--Interviews</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>McKendree Methodist Church (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Methodist church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources
</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Boyles, George Herbert, 1905-1997 (Interviewee); Hearne, Mary Glenn (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1987-10-27</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3 (1.39 MB; 1 min., 31 sec.)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Boyles3bclip1</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from:  Boyles audio cassette recording converted to mp3 format in 2006.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:coverage>1980-1989</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/204</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>