<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Put a candle in the window, circa 1953 December 24</dc:title>
<dc:description>An illustrated newsclipping of the front page of the 24 December 1953 Nashville Banner, showing one of the youth choirs for the Fannie Battle carol singing on Christmas Eve, a festive tradition in support of the Fannie Battle Day Home.  The inspirational caption reads: "Look into a child's face at Christmas time--above the paradoxical smile of angelic impishness and beneath the brow uncreased by burdens of futurity.  For it's a child's eyes that mirror the true Christmas Story--reaffirming a weary world's belief in things unseen but the only realities worthy of belief.  There's the twinkling star of ageless promise, the candle's flame of hope, the glowing light of love, the confident stare of faith, the sparkle of divine expectancy, the calm pool of peace, the openness of innocence and frankness of friendliness.  If these eyes could but hypnotize their older counterparts, excoriating greed and hate, fear and distrust, then the brotherhood of man, nurtured in Bethlehem's manager, would be redeemed again.  What better wish for all mankind this Christmas, 1953?"  In the color picture by Banner Staff Photographer John Malone, are (front row, from left) Pat Trimble, son of Mr. and Mrs. Benson Trimble; Russell B. Davis, Jr., son of Mr. and Mrs. Russell B. Davis; Benny Trimble, twin brother of Pat.  Others (from left) are Jackie Husband, son of Mr. and Mrs. Jack Husband; Fraser Orman, Jr., son of Mr. and Mrs. John F. Orman; and Lloyd McAdams, son of Mr. and Mrs. Joe L. McAdams.  Forms part of the Fannie Battle Day Home Records. 1 newsclipping, mounted on scrapbook sheet :  col. ; 11.25 x 13 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Trimble, Pat; Davis, Russell B.; Trimble, Benny; Husband, Jackie; Orman, Fraser; McAdams, Lloyd</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Fannie Battle Day Home; Fannie Battle Social Workers</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Capital City; Organizations; Popular Culture; Children's History; Performing Arts; Music; Altruism--Tennessee--Nashville; Benevolence--Tennessee--Nashville; Social work with children--Tennessee--Nashville; Child welfare; Christmas carols; Caroling--Tennessee--Nashville; Holidays--Tennessee--Nashville; Boys' choirs--Tennessee--Nashville; Holidays--Tennessee--Nashville; Charitable organizations--Tennessee--Nashville; Community service--Tennessee--Nashville; Economic &amp; social conditions--Tennessee--Nashville; Boys--Tennessee--Nashville; Choirs (Music)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Davidson County (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Malone, John (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1953-12-24</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Clippings</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>FBDHR-SB-Carol Publicity-1953-B13, f13</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Fannie Battle Day Home Records</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1917</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>