<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Church St., Independent Life Bldg., Nashville, circa 1910s</dc:title>
<dc:description>A color postcard view down Church Street to the Independent Life Building at Fourth Avenue, in Nashville, Tennessee. An additional title on the card reads "Nashville, the Powder City of the World." Forms part of the Nashville Room Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5  x 5.5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Independent Life Building (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Business; Enterprise; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Transportation; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Transportation--Tennessee--Nashville; Business enterprises--Tennessee--Nashville; Commercial buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Insurance companies--Tennessee--Nashville; City and town life--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville; Business districts--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Fourth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Church Street (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Zibart Bros. (Publisher)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1910s</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Nash-354-Church St. Independent Life Bldg</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1910-1919</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/604</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>