<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Excerpt 2 from oral history interview with Joseph R. O'Donnell, 2003 July 07</dc:title>
<dc:description>An excerpt from an oral history interview with Joseph R. O'Donnell, conducted on 7 July 2003 by Robert P. Richardson as part of the Nashville Public Library's Veterans History Project.  After his separation from service as a Marine photographer in the late 1940s, he worked for the United States Information Agency (USIA) as the White House photographer, and he kept a photographic record of his association with five US presidents - Truman, Eisenhower, Kennedy, Johnson, and Nixon.  In this excerpt, O'Donnell discusses a humorous incident involving Eleanor Roosevelt.  The complete interview, as well as a transcript, is available in the repository.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>O'Donnell, Joe (Joseph Roger), 1922- --Interviews; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Veterans History Project (U.S.); United States. Marine Corps--Interviews</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Military History; World War II; World War, 1939-1945--Veterans--Tennessee--Nashville; Veterans--Tennessee--Interviews; Photographers--Interviews; Presidents' spouses--United States--Anecdotes</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>O'Donnell, Joe (Joseph Roger), 1922- (Interviewee); Richardson, Robert Price, 1926- (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>James, Carolyn (Transcriber)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>2003-07-07</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3 (813 KB; 52 sec.)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>VHPODonnelJ2aclip1</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from:  VHPODonnellJ (VHP tapes 169 &amp; 170) audio cassette recording converted to mp3 format in 2006.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Veterans History Project collection, World War II series</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/235</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>