<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of Mayor Beverly Briley and Vice Mayor George H. Cate, Jr. shaking hands, 1963, April 1</dc:title>
<dc:description>Nashville Banner photograph of Mayor Beverly Briley and Vice Mayor George H. Cate, Jr. shaking hands at their inauguration as the first mayor and vice mayor of the new Metropolitan Government of Nashville and Davidson County. </dc:description>
<dc:description>The consolidation of City of Nashville and Davidson County governments into the Metropolitan Government of Nashville and Davidson County (Metro) was the first consolidation of a city and a county government in the nation. Voters elected Beverly Briley mayor, George Cate vice-mayor, and a council of forty persons and the day the officials took office was the same day that the consolidation of the city and county governments took effect.
</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Briley, Beverly, 1914-1980; Cate, George H., Jr.</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville Banner; Metropolitan Government of Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Mayors--Tennessee--Nashville; Metropolitan areas--Tennessee--Nashville; Civic leaders--Tennessee, Middle;
Lawyers--Tennessee--Nashville; Public officers--Tennessee--Nashville; Capital City; City Government; County Government; Consolidation; Metropolitan Government; Metropolitan government--Tennessee--Nashville; Politics &amp; government--Tennessee--Nashville;
Government officials--American--Tennessee--Nashville
</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--Politics and government</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Schleicher, Paul (photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1963-04-01</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives; Film negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BN 1963-1056-6 Briley and Cate</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/12943</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>