<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Mayor West and the Eastern Airlines Constellation plane model, 1953 April</dc:title>
<dc:description>Mayor Ben West, with Mr. Ogden and Mr. Borum and the new Constellation plane model of Eastern Airlines, circa 1953. The first Constellation flight at the Nashville Airport was on April 26th, 1953.  The airliner was manufactured by Lockheed and represented the ultimate in airline performance and luxury during the 1950s.  Nashville's airport officially opened in 1937 as Berry Field, in honor of Colonel Harry S. Berry, the state administrator of the Works Progress Administrator, or WPA. Berry Field became the military base for the 4th Ferrying Command during World War II and was returned to the city when the war ended. The airport&#8217;s name was officially changed to Nashville International Airport in 1988, but the original three-letters BNA, which stands for Berry Field Nashville, remains. Forms part of Record Group 3, Metro Davidson County Photographer. 3 photograph negatives : b &amp; w ; 4 x 5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Metropolitan Nashville Airport Authority--History--Sources; Eastern Air Lines, inc.</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Airports--Tennessee--Nashville--History; Airplanes--Tennessee--Nashville; Jet planes--Tennessee--Nashville; Commerce--Tennessee--Nashville; Airlines--Tennessee--Nashville; Airways--Tennessee--Nashville; Business enterprises--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1953-04</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RG 3 69 Airport001; RG 3 69 Airport002; RG 3 69 Airport003</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Record Group 3 Metro Davidson County Photographer</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Metro Archives, Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/4694</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>