<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Tomb of President Polk, Capitol, Nashville, between 1907 and 1914</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard of the tomb of James Knox Polk (1795-1849), the 11th president of the United States. Designed by William Strickland, the tomb was originally located in the garden at Polk Place, a mansion in downtown Nashville, where the former president and his wife Sarah Childress Polk (1803-1891) resided upon their return to Tennessee. 
In 1891, when Mrs. Polk died, she was buried next to the president at their home and was later reinterred with him at the state capitol. Today, Polk's tomb is located to the east side of the Tennessee State Capitol grounds. Forms part of the Nashville Room Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Polk, James K. (James Knox), 1795-1849--Tomb; Polk, Sarah Childress, 1803-1891--Tomb</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Memorials--Tennessee--Nashville; Presidents--United States--Tombs; Presidents--United States--Monuments; Tombs &amp; sepulchral monuments--Tennessee--Nashville; Monuments &amp; memorials--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>between 1907 and 1914</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Nash - 281</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1900-1909; 1910-1919</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/2314</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>