<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Tennessee Supreme Court, Nashville, Tennessee, circa 1940</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard of the Tennessee Supreme Court Building located at 401 Seventh Avenue North, adjacent to the Capitol and War Memorial Building.  This structure exemplifies a Greek Doric design that was very modern for its time.  Built of Tennessee marble at a cost of $750,000, this Tennessee Supreme Court Building was dedicated December 4th, 1937.  Forms part of the Nashville Room Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Tennessee. Supreme Court</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Architecture; Buildings; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture, Greek--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture, Modern--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Municipal buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Public buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville; Government facilities--American--Tennessee--Nashville; Courthouses--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Seventh Avenue (Nashville; Tenn.); Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Capitol News Co. (Publisher)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1940</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Nash-45a-Tennessee Supreme Court, Nashville, Tennessee</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/764</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>