<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Oral history interview with Catherine Berry Pilcher Avery, 1981 February , excerpt 06</dc:title>
<dc:description>An excerpt from an oral history interview with Catherine Berry Pilcher Avery, conducted on the 09 February 1981 and the 13 February 1981 by Leanne Thornton as part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. 1910-1935 Oral History Project.  Avery, the great-granddaughter of early Nashville bookstore owner William Tyler Berry and member of the Ladies Hermitage Association, discusses traveling by automobile during the early 1900s and how her family had to stay in tourist homes.  The complete interview is available in the repository.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Avery, Catherine Berry Pilcher, 1894-1982--Interviews</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Transportation; Popular Culture; Automobile travel; Tourist camps, hostels, etc.--United States</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.; Avery, Catherine Berry Pilcher, 1894-1982 (Interviewee); Thornton, Leanne  (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1981-02-09; 1981-02-13</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3 (56 sec.)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>HNIOHAveryCaclip6</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from:  HNIOHAveryC audio cassette recording converted to mp3 format in 2006.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. 1910-1935 Oral History Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1980-1989</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/626</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>