<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Masonic Home, Nashville, Tenn., 1908</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard of the Masonic Widows and Orphans Home in Nashville Tennessee.  The home was located on White's Creek Pike, six miles north of Nashville.  It was established around 1892.  Today several surviving historic structures stand at the former Masonic Widows and Orphans Home site.  These include "Maplewood" (the Home for the Aged Masons) and the Masonic Home School.  Forms part of the Nashville Room Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Masonic Widows and Orphans Home (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Capital City; Buildings; Popular Culture; Architecture; Organizations; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Orphanages--Tennessee-Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Masonic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Fraternal organizations--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>International Post Card Co. (Publisher)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1908</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Nash-36d-Masonic Home, Nashville, Tenn.</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1900-1909</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/753</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>