<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of a massive crowd of silent marchers, Nashville, Tennessee, 1960 April 19</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of a massive crowd of silent marchers at the Court House Square, Davidson County Courthouse, James Robertson Parkway, Nashville, Tennessee, April 19, 1960. A crowd of over 3000 participants marched in silence from the campus of Tennessee A &amp; I University to the office of Mayor Ben West at City Hall to protest the bombing of the home of civil rights attorney Z. Alexander Looby.  Upon arriving at the Court House Square, students and leaders confronted Mayor Ben West about his viewpoints on lunch counter segregation.  This was the first major step in desegregating public accommodations in Nashville. Forms part of the Nashville Banner Archives. 1 photograph: b &amp; w; 8 x 10 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Nash, Diane, 1938-; LaFayette, Bernard; Lawson, James M., 1928-</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Civil Rights; African Americans; Race Relations; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; African Americans--Civil rights--Tennessee--Nashville; Civil rights workers--Tennessee--Nashville; African Americans--Segregation; African Americans--Suffrage; Civil rights demonstrations--Tennessee--Nashville; Civil rights movements--Tennessee--Nashville; Social change--Tennessee--Nashville; Student protesters--Tennessee--Nashville; Activists--American--Tennessee--Nashville; Civil rights leaders--Tennessee; Protest movements--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social conditions; Southern States--Race relations--History--20th century--Sources; Court House Square (Nashville, Tenn.)--History; Public Square (Nashville, Tenn.)--History; James Robertson Parkway (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville (Tenn.)--Race relations</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1960-04-19</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/tiff</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BP-Segregation-Nash-TN-April 1960-crowd</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/565</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>