<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Eighth Street Missionary Baptist Church, 2002 January</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of Eighth Street Missionary Baptist Church in Nashville, Tennessee.  Built by Reverend R.L. Watson in 1945, this church building initially housed First Emmanuel Church.  The Eighth Street Baptist Church was organized in 1913.  In the 1950s the congregation moved to this church, located at 1223 Sixth Avenue North.  Foundation materials include cut limestone and concrete blocks painted brown.  Exterior walls are concrete blocks painted tan.  Doors are made of wood.  Roof materials consist of gabled tar shingles.  Windows are a mix of frosted glass and arched, clear glass.  Originally this church had a steeple.  Forms part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project. 1 photograph : col. ; 4  x 6  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Eighth Street Missionary Baptist Church (Nashville, Tenn.); First Emmanuel Church (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Popular Culture; Religion; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Religious facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Church architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Baptist church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Protestant church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Protestant churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Baptist churches--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs; Sixth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2002-01</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>SSSP - 8th St Miss Baptist</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/712</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>