<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Tulip Grove historical marker, Nashville, Tennessee, n.d. </dc:title>
<dc:description>An historical marker for Tulip Grove that reads: &#8220;Designed by Jos. Reiff, who was also builder of the Hermitage, this house was built in 1832 [1836] for Andrew J. Donelson, Jackson&#8217;s namesake and secretary.  A West Point graduate, Donelson was at one time minister to Prussia, and held other offices.  In 1856 he was candidate for vice-president on ticket with Millard Fillmore.&#8221;  In 1858, Donelson sold the property to the parents of painter Mayna Treanor Avent (1868-1959), who grew up at Tulip Grove.  Later, it passed through successive owners until circa 1964 when it was acquired by the Ladies&#8217; Hermitage Association.  Tulip Grove is representative of the Greek Revival style that was popular before the American Civil War.  Forms part of the Claynita Harris Slide Collection.  The original is a 35 mm color transparency (2 x 2 in. slide mount</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Donelson family </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Historical markers--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville  </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Lebanon Pike (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc. </dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>n.d.</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives </dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Harris Photo          322 Tulip Grove plaque</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Claynita Harris Slide Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>20th century</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/7053</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>