<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Bijou Theatre, Nashville, Tenn., 1908</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard of the Bijou Theatre located at 423 Fourth Avenue North in Nashville, Tennessee.  This 1624 seat theatre was erected in 1904 on the site of a previous theatre that had burned two years prior.  Events included live stage performances and silent films.  In 1916 the Bijou became one of the South's leading theatres for African American audiences.  This popularity lasted until it was demolished in the winter of 1957-1958 for the building of the Municipal Auditorium.  Forms part of the Nashville Room Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Bijou Theatre (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Downtown Nashville; Capital City; Popular Culture; Entertainment; African Americans; Architecture; Buildings; Performing Arts; Theatre; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Theaters--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Cultural facilities--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Fourth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>International Post Card Co. (Publisher)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1908</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Nash-36e-Bijou Theatre, Nashville, Tenn.</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1900-1909</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/754</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>