<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Historic postal cashier window, Frist Center for the Visual Arts, Nashville, Tennessee, 2016 June 04</dc:title>
<dc:description>The former main post office cashier window, with stylistic decorative motifs based in a marble exterior, pictured at the Frist Center for the Visual Arts.  The historical post office was constructed from 1933 to 1934 under the direction of the local architectural firm of Marr &amp; Holman, the building was financed by monies appropriated by Congress during the Hoover administration.  Following guidelines from the Office of the Supervising Architect for such public buildings, Nashville&#8217;s post office displays both of the most distinctive architectural styles of the period: classicism and Art Deco.  The building was listed on the National Register of Historic Sites in 1984.  It served as the main U.S. Post Office for Nashville until 1986, when a new central processing facility opened in Donelson.  It continued to serve as a downtown branch of the post office after that time. The building was transferred to the city of Nashville in 1998 in preparation for its use as the home to the Frist Center for the Visual Arts. The Downtown Branch USPO moved into new quarters on the lower level, Tenth Avenue side, of the building in 1999. The Frist Center opened in 2001. The lobby of the Frist has been restored to the 1934 design; with the exception of glass doors leading to exhibit galleries and Art Deco style benches that were added to the interior. Forms part of the Leanne Garland Photograph Collection.  1 digital photograph.    </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Frist Center for the Visual Arts (Nashville, Tenn.); United States Post Office (Nashville, Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Post offices--Tennessee--Nashville; Government facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Broadway Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Garland, Leanne (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2016-06-04</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>LGar Frist bldg old post office window June 4 2016</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Leanne Garland Photograph Collection </dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2010-2019</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/8782</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>