<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Letter from P.J. Williamson to his wife, Eunice, during the Civil War, 1865 February 24</dc:title>
<dc:description>A letter from Dutch immigrant, Peter J. Williamson, back home to his wife, Eunice, during the Civil War.  In 1862 Williamson enlisted as a Private in the 1st Wisconsin Cavalry, Company F and was ultimately promoted to Full 1st Lieutenant.  During the war, Williamson's regiment was involved in scouting and raids in Missouri and Arkansas and saw battle in the Middle Tennessee, Chickamauga, and Atlanta campaigns. In this letter from Nashville, Tennessee, Williamson writes that he had just received her letter.  He states he would enclose money but does not want to delay the current letter.  He acquiesces to her moving to Nashville given the circumstances in Appleton.  He briefly discusses packing and asks if she can leave some items with Mr. Allen.  He tells her to expect some money and a ticket a couple days after receiving this letter.  Williamson then describes in detail her itinerary from Appleton to Nashville including dates and times as well as the procedure for checking her baggage. Other important cities along the route include Chicago, Illinois; Michigan City, Indiana; Lafayette, Indiana; Indianapolis, Indiana; Jeffersonville, Indiana; and Louisville, Kentucky.  He hopes to meet her in Louisville if his employer permits.  He closes by telling her to write immediately after receiving the letter including if she needs any further instructions. Forms part of the Peter J. Williamson Letters. 1 letter : col. ; 8 x 10 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Williamson, Peter J., 1823-1907; Williamson, Eunice Leihy, 1840-1928; Williamson, Peter, b. 1862; Williamson, Willy (William), b. 1859</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>United States. Army. Wisconsin Cavalry Regiment, 1st (1861-1865); United States. Army--Military life; Louisville and Nashville Railroad Company</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Military History; Civil War; Popular Culture; Business; War; Soldiers--United States--Correspondence; Soldiers--United States--Personal narratives; Immigrants--Wisconsin; Immigrants' writings, Dutch; Family; Moving, Household; Housing--Wisconsin--Appleton--History--Civil War, 1861-1865; Railroad travel--United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--19th century--Sources; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Personal narratives; Tennessee--History--Civil War, 1861-1865; Appleton (Wis.)--History--Civil War, 1861-1865; Louisville (Ky.)--History--Civil War, 1861-1865; Chicago (Ill.)--History--Civil War, 1861-1865; Michigan City (Ind.)--History--Civil War, 1861-1865; Lafayette (Ind.)--History--Civil War, 1861-1865; Indianapolis (Ind.)--History--Civil War, 1861-1865; Jeffersonville (Ind.)--History--Civil War, 1861-1865</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Williamson, Peter J., 1823-1907</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Currey, Martha T. (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1865-02-24</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text; Letters (correspondence)</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>PJW - f, 72</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Peter J. Williamson Letters</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/2162</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>