<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of woman modeling an Easter hat designed to resemble a bird cage, decorated with two birds and flowers, 1956</dc:title>
<dc:description>Head and shoulders black-and-white photograph of an unidentified woman, smiling and holding her gloved hands to her face, modeling a whimsical hat designed to look like a birdcage with ornamental birds and flowers. Photograph taken at Castner Knott Department Store during the Easter season of 1956 by photographer Paul Schleicher of the Nashville Banner newspaper. Forms part of the Nashville Banner Archives. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 3.25 x 4.25 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Women; Popular culture; Women&#8217;s hats; Women&#8217;s clothing--United States; Easter--Social life and customs; Easter--Humor; Women--Tennessee--Nashville; Women--Social life and customs; Holidays--1950-1960</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Schleicher, Paul (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1956</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Negatives; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BN 1956-765-10</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1956</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital image.  This image is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without written permission.  Please contact the repository for permission to use this image.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/11618</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>