<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>First Baptist Church of Old Hickory, 2001 January</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of First Baptist Church of Old Hickory located at 1106 Hadley Avenue in Old Hickory, Tennessee.  According to the church's current website, the First Baptist Church of Old Hickory was organized with twenty-two members in 1924. With the help of the State Mission Board this small band of members bought a tar-covered structure for $800 and leased the lot from DuPont in the exact location where the present church stands.  In 1930, the tar-papered building was razed and the foundation was laid for the present church building.  In 1958 a wing was added to the educational facilities.  In 1968 all of the facilities were completely remodeled.  The exterior walls are brick.  The windows are painted glass.  The church has changed its name to First Family First Baptist Church.  Forms part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project. 1 photograph : col. ; 4  x 6  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>First Baptist Church of Old Hickory (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Popular Culture; Religion; Architecture--Tennessee--Old Hickory; Buildings--Tennessee--Old Hickory; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Old Hickory; Church buildings--Tennessee--Old Hickory; Religious facilities--Tennessee--Old Hickory; Church architecture--Tennessee--Old Hickory; Baptist church buildings--Tennessee--Old Hickory; Brick churches--Tennessee--Old Hickory; Protestant church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Churches--Tennessee--Old Hickory; Baptist churches--Tennessee--Old Hickory</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Old Hickory (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Old Hickory (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Old Hickory (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs; Hadley Avenue (Old Hickory, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2001-01</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>SSSP - First River Baptist Church</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/890</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>