<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Zion Christian Center, 2001 December</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of the former Belmont Baptist Church, now Hope Center located at 2415 Twelfth Avenue South in Nashville, Tennessee.  This church was erected in 1906 on the corner of 12th Avenue South and Beechwood Avenue.  Its address was originally listed as 2411 Twelfth Avenue South.   In 1921 the church was sold and became Waverly Belmont Church of Christ.  In 1956 the address changed to 2415 Twelfth Avenue South.  In 1975 the property was purchased by another entity and used in various capacities until 1990 when it became home to the Zion Hill First African Baptist Church.  In 2002 it changed hands once more when renovations began and a new church moved in, Zion Christian Center.  The Zion Christian Center recently changed its name to the Hope Center but is still under the same leadership.  The foundation is made of rough cut stone blocks.  The exterior walls are brick.  The roof is hipped with tar shingles.  The windows are tall with frosted glass panes.  The doors are wood and glass.  Special features include a tower, ornate brickwork under the eaves, and stone accenting.  Forms part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project. 1 photograph : col. ; 4  x 6  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Zion Christian Center (Nashville, Tenn.); Hope Center (Nashville, Tenn.); Waverly-Belmont Church of Christ (Nashville, Tenn.); Belmont Baptist Church (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Popular Culture; Religion; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Religious facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Church architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Churches of Christ--Tennessee--Nashville; Towers--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Details; Baptist church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville; Baptist churches--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs; Twelfth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2001-12</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>SSSP - Zion Christian Center</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1573</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>