<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Portrait of Randal William McGavock, ca. 1850</dc:title>
<dc:description>A young Randal McGavock is standing in front of a column and red drape, right hand (complete with pinky ring) on hip and left hand holding a book.  He is wearing a dark suit with a white vest.  The frame is massive and elaborate.  Randal William McGavock was born in Nashville on 10 August 1826.  He received an A.B. degree from the University of Nashville in October 1846 and a degree from Harvard Law School on 18 July 1849.  McGavock married Seraphine Deery in 1855.  From 1858 to 1859 he served as Mayor of Nashville.  During the Civil War, McGavock served as Lieutenant Colonel and Colonel of the 10th Tennessee Volunteer Infantry Regiment and was held as a prisoner of war at Fort Warren on George's Island in Boston Harbor from March to August 1862.  He was killed in action at the Battle of Raymond, Mississippi, on 12 May 1863.  Presented to the library by McGavock's great-niece, Margaret Lindsley Warden, in January 1966.  The portrait was treated in 2002 by the Cumberland Art Conservation Center.  Oil on canvas, on display in the Nashville Room on the Nashville Public Library's second floor.  

The library's portraits were photographed as part of the National Society of The Colonial Dames of America in Tennessee's Tennessee Portrait Project (http://www.tnportraits.org/index.htm).</dc:description>
<dc:subject>McGavock, Randal William, 1826-1863--Portraits</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Confederate States of America. Army. Tennessee Infantry Regiment, 10th</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Popular Culture; Capital City; City Government; Military History; Civil War; Portraits, American--19th century; Portraits--Tennessee--Nashville; Mayors--Tennessee--Nashville; Soldiers--Confederate States of America--Portraits; Veterans--Confederate States of America--Portraits</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Prisoners and prisons</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Cooper, Washington Bogart, 1802-1889 (Artist)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>National Society of The Colonial Dames of America in Tennessee</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1850</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Portraits; Paintings</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>mcgavock-randal-metro-lg</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Portrait Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1850-1859</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1842</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>