<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Victor Cooley and unidentified sailor, between 1943 and 1945</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of Coast Guard sailor Victor Cooley (left) and an unidentified sailor aboard the destroyer escort, USS Mosley (DE-321), one of several Navy vessels manned by Coast Guard crews during World War II.  The Mosley served on patrol in the Mediterranean, primarily in the vicinity of Tunisia and French Morocco.  The two men pose casually by a deck gun with an American flag waving in the background.  Forms part of the Veterans History project. 1 photograph : b &amp; w : 3.5 x 4.5 in. print.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Cooley, Victor, 1919-2001</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Mosley (Destroyer escort); United States. Coast Guard--History--World War, 1939-1945</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Military History; World War II; War; Veterans--Tennessee--History--Sources; World War, 1939-1945--Photography; World War, 1939-1945--Naval operations, American; Destroyer escorts--United States; World War, 1939-1945--Mediterranean Region; Decks (Ships); Naval warfare--American</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Mediterranean Sea</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Cooley, Peggy (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>between 1943 and 1945</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>VHP-WWII-Cooley p41</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Veterans History Project collection, World War II series, Victor Cooley papers</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1098</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>