<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>It may be far to Tipperary it's a longer way to Tennessee, 1914</dc:title>
<dc:description>Based on the English Music Hall song, "It's A Long Way To Tipperary" (1912, by Harry Williams and Jack Judge) which became a favorite and famous marching song of the British Expeditionary Force at the very outbreak of World War I in August, 1914, this Tin Pan Alley takeoff by lyricist Arthur J. Lamb and composer Alfred Solman was written in those first months of war (1914) and features a soldier with a sweetheart not from Tipperary (Ireland) but rather from Tennessee, already famous as the Volunteer State. Forms part of the Kenneth A. Kanter American Music and Theatre Collection. 1 sheet music publication (5 p.)</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Performing Arts; Music; Military History; World War I; World War, 1914-1918--Songs and music; Popular music--1911-1920</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Tipperary (Ireland)--Songs and music; Tennessee--Songs and music</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Solman, Alfred, 1868-1937 (Composer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Lamb, Arthur J. (Lyricist); Joe Morris Music Co. (Publisher)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1914</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text; Sheet music covers; Scores, music</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/tiff</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>KAKC-It May Be Far to Tipperary-TN</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Kenneth A. Kanter American Music and Theatre Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1910-1919</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/472</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>