<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Davidson County Court House and Public Square showing wagon market, Nashville, Tenn., 1909</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard of the Davidson County Court House and Public Square showing the wagon market.  Also referred to as Court House Square, this area was located right in the center of the city.  The square with the county courthouse, city hall and market center was a focus of wholesale commerce and political activity for the city for many years.  On market days the square was especially busy.  The crowded market area on this card shows a large group of vendor wagons and townspeople.  The courthouse was demolished in 1935, and in 1937 the present Metropolitan Court House was completed to replace it.  Most of the remaining buildings making up the square were destroyed in the 1970s as part of urban renewal projects.  Forms part of the Norton Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Davidson County Court House (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Capital City; Downtown Nashville, Business; Popular Culture; Shopping; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Commercial buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Public spaces--Tennessee--Nashville; Courthouses--Tennessee--Nashville; Carriages and carts--Tennessee--Nashville; Shopping--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Municipal buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Government facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Plazas--Tennessee--Nashville; Business districts--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Public Square (Nashville, Tenn.)--History; Court House Square (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville (Tenn.)--Commerce</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>E. C. Kropp (Publisher)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1909</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Norton - 0066</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Norton Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1900-1909</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1643</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>