<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>A Profile of the Nashville Economy, June, 1972</dc:title>
<dc:description>&#8220;A Profile of the Nashville Economy,&#8221; a June, 1972 published report of the Planning Commission, Metropolitan Government of Nashville and Davidson County, Tennessee.  According to the preface, this report &#8220;is directed toward organizing previously published &#8220;Census of Business&#8221; results which needed to be analyzed regarding our local conditions&#8221; and further stating that &#8220;this report traces the substantial growth in durable goods manufacturing between 1958 and 1963, as reflected by a rapid percentage increase in capital investment in that sector which resulted in an increase in manufacturing value added well above the national growth of that period.  Personal income and retail sales, on the other hand, had moderate gains during the late 1950s and early sixties, but more than doubled their rates of increase during the middle sixties, while manufacturing capital investment increases were significantly reduced in the same period.  Thus, increases in durable goods manufacturing capital investment and the consequent improvement in productivity appears to have had a subsequent impact on personal income and retail sales.  This sequence of events portends the question of the source of new increases in productivity and the resulting rounds of reinvestment and economic growth in Nashville-Davidson County.&#8221;  Forms part of the Metro Planning Commission Minutes and Reports.  1 printed publication.  </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Urban economics--Tennessee--Nashville; Regional economics--Tennessee, Middle; Urbanization--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--Economic conditions; Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Nashville and Davidson County--Economic conditions
</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1972</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Text </dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Metro Planning report Nashville Economy 1972</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Planning Commission Minutes and Reports, 1963-1986</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1970-1979</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/11319</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>