<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>We Shall Overcome (Festival Edition), circa 1959</dc:title>
<dc:description>Based on a 1903 gospel version by Reverend Charles Tindley of Philadelphia, and in 1946, the song for striking employees of the American Tobacco Company, "We Shall Overcome" spread through the country as an anthem for southern African American labor unions and civil rights activists in 1959. During the 1960s the song was associated with Joan Baez and the 1969 Woodstock festival and later sung in South Africa during the anti-apartheid movement. Forms part of the Civil Rights Ephemera Collection. 1 sheet music : col. ; 7 x 10.5 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Music; Civil Rights; African Americans; Race Relations; Popular Culture; Protest songs--United States; Labor--Songs and music; Race relations--United States--History--Sources; Nonviolence--History--Sources; Civil rights movements--Southern States--History--20th century--Sources; African Americans--Civil rights; Folk songs; Songs; Grass roots politics</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Southern States--History--20th century; Southern States--Race relations; Southern States--Social conditions; Southern States--Songs and music</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Horton, Zilphia, 1910-1956; Seeger, Pete, 1919- ; Hamilton, Frank; Carawan, Guy</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Ringwald, Roy, 1910- (Arranger); Shawnee Press (Publisher)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1959</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text; Sheet music covers</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/tiff</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CRE-TN-We Shall Overcome</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Civil Rights Ephemera Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/570</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>