<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Program, The Nashville Community Playhouse, presentation of &#8220;Cradle Snatchers,&#8221; 1947-1948 Season </dc:title>
<dc:description>A Nashville Community Playhouse program for a theatrical production of the &#8220;Cradle Snatchers,&#8221; by Russell G. Medcraft and Norma Mitchell, presented during the 1947-48 season.  The staff of the Playhouse: Raymond Johnson, Director; Wyman Kane, Technical Director; Mary Bloker, Business Director.  The board of directors: Whitworth Stokes, President; Charles S. Mitchell, First Vice-President; Jim Reppert, Second Vice-President; Catherina Winnia, Secretary; F.K.W. Drury, Treasurer; with Mrs. Walter Fort, Sam Tarpley, Martha Gillespie, John Thompson, Hayden B. Johnson, Terry Tomlin, and Mrs. William B. Tyne.  The Nashville Community Playhouse was known for its excellence in the arts, located at 2102 Belcourt Avenue.  The play, &#8220;Cradle Snatchers,&#8221; was one of the top two of the season, presented March 10th-17th, 1948.  Forms part of the Wilhelmina Webb Collection. 1 program. </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Nashville Community Playhouse (Nashville, Tenn.)--History--Sources; Belcourt Theatre (Nashville, Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Performances--Tennessee--Nashville; Performing arts--Tennessee--Nashville; Entertainment--Tennessee--Nashville; Advertising--Tennessee--Nashville; Community theater--Tennessee--Nashville; Theater--Tennessee--Nashville; Theatrical companies--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville and Davidson County (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Belcourt Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library </dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1948</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Programs; Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Wilhelmina Webb Collection Nash Community Playhouse progs 1940-47 Cradle Snatchers 001 - 016</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Wilhelmina Webb Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1940-1949</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/9155</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>