<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Old Hickory lock and dam, circa 1957</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard of the Old Hickory lock and dam located on the Cumberland River twenty five miles upstream from Nashville.  The reservoir behind the dam is Old Hickory Lake named after President Andrew Jackson who was nicknamed "Old Hickory."  Construction on the project began in 1952 and was completed in 1957.  Designed by the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers, the lock allows barges and recreational boats to navigate the Cumberland River.  Forms part of the Norton Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Transportation; Lakes; Sports &amp; Recreation; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Dams--Tennessee--Nashville; Lakes--Tennessee--Nashville; Rivers--Tennessee--Nashville; Locks (Hydraulic engineering)--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Cumberland River (Ky. and Tenn.)--Navigation; Old Hickory Lake (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Southern Post Card Co. (Publisher)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1957</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Norton - 0591</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Norton Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1950-1959</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1818</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>