<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Photograph of the Arcade, Nashville, Tennessee, 1964</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of the Arcade, Nashville, Tennessee. The Arcade opened in 1903, running east to west between what were then Cherry Street and Summer Street; present day Fourth Avenue North and Fifth Avenue North. It was conceived by Nashville resident Daniel Buntin as an enclosed, two story pedestrian passage to house 52 retail shops. Mr. Buntin patterned the concept after Italian arcades that he had seen during his travels abroad, particularly one he had seen in Milan. It was added to the National Register of Historic Places in 1973. The date of image was written on the slide mount.
Photographed by the Nashville architect Charles Wesley Warterfield, Jr. (1926-1998); the architectural photograph forms part of the Charles Warterfield Architectural Collection. Gift of: The Estate of Charles W. Warterfield, Jr., F. A. I. A. The original is a 35 mm color transparency (2 x 2 in. slide mount)</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Arcade, The (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Business; Enterprise; Popular Culture; Shopping; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Architects--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Shopping--Tennessee--Nashville; Arcades (Shopping facilities)--Tennessee--Nashville; Mercantile facilities--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Commerce; Fourth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Fifth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Cherry Street (Nashville, Tenn.); Summer Street (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Warterfield, Charles W. (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Estate of Charles W. Warterfield, Jr., F.A.I.A. (Donor); Buntin, Daniel Carter (Architect)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1964</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Slides; Architectural photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/tiff</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>WSC 0736</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Charles Warterfield Architectural Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission. Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/505</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>