<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Oral history interview with Marion F. "Sonny" Smith, 2007 September 25</dc:title>
<dc:description>Excerpts from an oral history interview with Marion F. "Sonny" Smith, conducted on 25 Sept. 2007 by Larry Patterson as part of the Nashville Public Library's Veterans History Project.  Smith served with the 503rd Parachute Infantry Regiment of the 173rd Airborne Brigade (Separate) during the Vietnam War. Smith discusses his first jump training as a paratrooper; his arrival at Bien Hoa airbase in South Vietnam in 1966, where he witnessed American coffins being loaded on airplanes for shipment home; ambush training, including use of Claymore mines, booby traps, trip flares, and an anti-intrusion device; an incident when they were ambushed, a sergeant was shot during his effort to aid Smith, and the next group sent on patrol was named Operation Revenge in honor of the wounded sergeant; and an especially close call when his company was pinned down by a sniper in the jungle.  The complete interview is available in the repository.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Smith, Marion F. (Sonny), 1939- --Interviews</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>United States. Army. Airborne Brigade, 173rd; United States. Army. Parachute Regimental Combat Team, 503rd.; United States. Army--Parachute troops</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Military History; Vietnam War; Coffins; Booby traps; Explosives; Tropical forests; Soldiers; Military life; Veterans; Paratroopers; Military personnel; Veterans--Tennessee--Biography; Soldiers--Training of--United States; Ambushes and surprises; Vietnam War, 1961-1975--History--Sources; Vietnam War, 1961-1975--Jungle warfare; Vietnam War, 1961-1975--Personal narratives, American; Vietnam War, 1961-1975--Casualties; Operation Revenge, 1967; Airborne operations (Military science); Snipers--Vietnam</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Vietnam (Republic)--History--Sources; Bie?n Ho?a (Vietnam)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Smith, Marion F. (Sonny), 1939-  (Interviewee); Patterson, Larry, 1944-  (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>VHPSmithM1006and1007clip1.mp3; VHPSmithM1011clip1.mp3; VHPSmithM1013and1014clip1.mp3; VHPSmithM1016clip1.mp3; VHPSmithM_transcript.pdf</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from:  VHPSmithM digital recording converted from wav to mp3 format in 2007.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Veterans History Project:  Vietnam War series</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1776</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>