<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>True Christian Pentecostal Witnesses Church, 2001 January</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of True Pentecostal Witnesses Church, formerly Foster Chapel Baptist Church, located at 936 Lebanon Road in Nashville, Tennessee.  The Foster Chapel congregation was organized in 1901, and their church building was constructed in 1907.  In 1971 the building was remodeled.  In 1996 the church was sold to the True Pentecostal Witnesses Church congregation, and Foster Chapel moved to a new building.  The architectural style is Vernacular Gothic.  The foundation is brick.  The exterior walls are stretcher bond brick.  The roof is asphalt shingle.  The windows are frosted glass in the sanctuary, but clear on all other parts of the building.  The doors are glass and wood.  Forms part of the Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project. 1 photograph : col. ; 4  x 6  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>True Christian Pentecostal Witnesses Church (Nashville, Tenn.); Foster Chapel Baptist Church (Nashville, Tenn.); Foster Chapel Missionary Baptist Church (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Churches; Popular Culture; Religion; Architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Church buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Religious facilities--Tennessee--Nashville; Church architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Baptist church buildings--Tennessee-Nashville; Brick churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Architecture, Gothic--Tennessee--Nashville; Pentecostal churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Churches--Tennessee--Nashville; Baptist churches--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Religious life and customs; Lebanon Road (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Historic Nashville, Inc.</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2001-01</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>SSSP - True Pent Witness</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Historic Nashville, Inc. Sacred Sites Survey Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1547</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>