<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Nashville's Easter fashion parade, 1936 April 12</dc:title>
<dc:description>A photograph of Governor and Mrs. Hill McAlister after leaving Easter services at Vine Street Christian Church, located at 140 7th Avenue North, Nashville, Tennessee.  They are pictured with their car and chauffeur in foreground. The background shows the 7th Avenue Sandwich Shop with Gerst Beer and Coca-Cola ad signs for the eatery. Similar photos for Easter clothing and dress appeared in the Nashville Banner newspaper April 13, 1936. Forms part of the Nashville Banner Archives. 1 photograph negative : b &amp; w ; 3.25 x 4.25 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>McAlister, Hill, 1875-1959; McAlister, Hill, Mrs.</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Vine Street Christian Church (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Popular Culture; Religion; Governors--Tennessee--Nashville; Clothing and dress--Tennessee--Nashville; Women's clothing--Tennessee--Nashville; Women's hats--Tennessee--Nashville; Easter--Tennessee--Nashville; Men's clothing--Tennessee--Nashville; Married people--Tennessee--Nashville; Chauffeurs--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Seventh Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social life and customs</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Nashville Banner staff photographer</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1936-04-12</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>BN-1936-07-11</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Banner Archives</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1930-1939</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/2349</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>