<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Portrait of Anna Maria Minnick Shelby, ca. 1840</dc:title>
<dc:description>Anna Shelby, with dark hair in an elaborate arrangement and wearing a dark dress with ruffled lace collar.  She is in front of a red drape with gold fringe and tassels, and is near what appears to be either a window or a large landscape painting.  Born in 1793, Anna Maria Minnick Shelby was the wife of John Shelby, Nashville physician, Postmaster, and civic and church leader, whom she married in 1809.  Oil on canvas, artist unknown.  Presented to the library in member of Shelby's great granddaughter Anna Williams Fassman by her daughter Shelby S. Cox.  The portrait is currently on display in the Nashville Room on the Nashville Public Library's second floor.  

The library's portraits were photographed as part of the National Society of The Colonial Dames of America in Tennessee's Tennessee Portrait Project (http://www.tnportraits.org/index.htm).  </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Shelby, Anna Maria Minnick, 1793-1873--Portraits</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Popular Culture; Portraits, American--19th century; Portraits--Tennessee--Nashville; Physicians' spouses--Tennessee--Nashville;  Physicians' spouses--Tennessee--Sumner County</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Sumner County (Tenn.)--History--Sources</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>National Society of The Colonial Dames of America in Tennessee</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>ca. 1840</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Portraits; Paintings</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>shelby-anna-m-minnick-lg</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Portrait Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1840-1849</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1864</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>