<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Fifth Ave., looking south from Union, Nashville, Tenn., 1910</dc:title>
<dc:description>A postcard of Fifth Avenue looking south from Union Avenue in downtown Nashville.  Both sides of the street are lined with businesses including Houck's, a music shop, and S. H. Kress &amp; Co., a five and dime retail store.  Horses and carriages are parked outside the storefronts.  One automobile is discernable outside the Kress building.  Forms part of the Norton Postcard Collection. 1 postcard : col. ; 3.5  x 5.5  in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>O.K. Houck Piano Company (Nashville, Tenn.); S.H. Kress &amp; Co.</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Architecture; Buildings; Business; Enterprise; Industries; Capital City; Downtown Nashville; Transportation; Popular Culture; Entertainment; Shopping; Postcards--Tennessee--Nashville; Lost architecture--Tennessee--Nashville; Transportation--Tennessee--Nashville; Business enterprises--Tennessee--Nashville; Commercial buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Central business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Historic buildings--Tennessee--Nashville; Sidewalks--Tennessee--Nashville; Streets--Tennessee--Nashville; Awnings--Tennessee--Nashville; Stores, Retail--Tennessee--Nashville; Shopping--Tennessee--Nashville; Carriages and carts--Tennessee--Nashville; Horses--Tennessee--Nashville; Stores &amp; shops--Tennessee--Nashville; Business districts--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural elements--Tennessee--Nashville; Carriages &amp; coaches--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Nashville (Tenn.)--Buildings, structures, etc.; Nashville (Tenn.)--Commerce; Union Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Fifth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1910</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Postcards</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Norton - 0150</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Norton Postcard Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1910-1919</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1770</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>