<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Aerial photograph of interstate construction in North Nashville, ca. 1968.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Aerial photograph of interstate construction in North Nashville, looking southwest, circa 1968, taken by Metro Photographer William M. King. Photograph shows a wooded residential area on the right side of the image, with Bush Lake visible above the tree line in the top right. I-65 and I-24 run horizontally in the foreground. They connect in an interchange with I-265, which crosses the Cumberland River marked by a bridge in the middle of the image. The buildings in the foreground are near the intersection of Dickerson Pike and Whites Creek Pike. The buildings at the top of the image are part of an unidentified industrial area. Forms part of the Nashville Room Historic Photographs Collection. 1 photograph : b &amp; w ; 8 x 10 in.</dc:description>
<dc:description>In 2000, Interstate 265 ceased to exist, and was redesignated as part of Interstate 65. Additionally, the land above the Cumberland River later became the eastern section of the future MetroCenter development.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Capitol City; Transportation; Express highways--Tennessee--Nashville; Roads--Design and construction--Tennessee--Nashville; Roads--Design and construction--Aerial photographs; Neighborhoods--Tennessee--Nashville; Streets--Tennessee--Nashville; Housing--Tennessee--Nashville; City planning--Tennessee--Nashville; Transportation--Tennessee--Nashville; Bridges--Design and construction--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--20th century; Nashville (Tenn.)--Aerial photographs; Cumberland River (Ky. and Tenn.); Bush Lake (Nashville, Tenn.); Dickerson Pike (Nashville, Tenn.); Whites Creek Pike (Nashville, Tenn.); Interstate 24; Interstate 65; Interstate 265 (Nashville, Tenn.); MetroCenter (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>King, William M. (Photographer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>ca. 1968</dc:date>
<dc:type>Still Image; Photographs</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>p-0026 &#8211; Nash aerial, interstate area</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Nashville Room Historic Photographs Collection</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1960-1969; 1970-1979</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/12505</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>