<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Letter from P.J. Williamson to his wife, Eunice, during the Civil War, 1865 May 16</dc:title>
<dc:description>A letter from Dutch immigrant, Peter J. Williamson, back home to his wife, Eunice, during the Civil War.  In 1862 Williamson enlisted as a Private in the 1st Wisconsin Cavalry, Company F and was ultimately promoted to Full 1st Lieutenant.  During the war, Williamson's regiment was involved in scouting and raids in Missouri and Arkansas and saw battle in the Middle Tennessee, Chickamauga, and Atlanta campaigns. In this letter from Nashville, Tennessee, Williamson has received Eunice's letter from the 7th.  He relates to her a message he sent concerning a debt they owe and he expresses optimism about finding them a house in Nashville soon and at a reasonable price.  He tells her that he and a partner have agreed to open an architectural office and predicts to do well in time given there are no other architects in Nashville at the time.  He reports that Captain Seaton is probably going to Georgia and Mrs. Seaton back north.  Williamson mentions that Jefferson Davis' train is scheduled to be traveling through Nashville that night on its way to Washington although he will not be leaving his car due to fears of assassination.  He closes by speaking of friends and family including a request to help find a former soldier with the 21st Wisconsin Infantry Regiment.  Forms part of the Peter J. Williamson Letters. 1 letter : col. ; 8 x 10 in.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Williamson, Peter J., 1823-1907; Williamson, Eunice Leihy, 1840-1928; Davis, Jefferson, 1808-1889--Captivity, 1865-1867; Seaton, Algernon S.</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>United States. Army. Wisconsin Cavalry Regiment, 1st (1861-1865); United States. Army--Military life; United States. Army. Wisconsin Infantry Regiment, 21st (1862-1865)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Military History; Civil War; Popular Culture; Architecture; Architects; Capital City; Housing; War; Soldiers--United States--Correspondence; Soldiers--United States--Personal narratives; Immigrants--Wisconsin; Immigrants' writings, Dutch; Family; Architects--Tennessee--Nashville; Architectural offices--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--History--19th century--Sources; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Personal narratives; Tennessee--History--Civil War, 1861-1865; Georgia--History--Civil War, 1861-1865; Wisconsin--History--Civil War, 1861-1865; Washington (D.C.)--History--Civil War, 1861-1865; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Transportation</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Williamson, Peter J., 1823-1907</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Currey, Martha T. (Donor)</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1865-05-16</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text; Letters (correspondence)</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>PJW - f, 75</dc:identifier>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Peter J. Williamson Letters</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/2166</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>