<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Oral history interview with Douglas G. Odom, Jr., 2007 June 05</dc:title>
<dc:description>Excerpts from an interview with Madison businessman Douglas G. Odom, Jr., conducted on 05 June 2007 by James T. Havron as part of the Nashville Business Leaders Oral History Project.  In the excerpts, Odom discusses his family's business, Odom's Tennessee Pride Sausage, including the role his mother, Louise Odom, played in the businesses' success; his service in the Marine Corps; how his grandfather and father got started in the meat industry; how his father started the sausage business with a loan from Henry Powell, a family friend; the involvement of his entire family in the business; the company's involvement with the American Meat Institute; the creation of the trademark farm boy icon; how the company has focused its advertising over the years; the success of Odom's Tennessee Pride Sausage as a small business; the strength of his business competitors; his mother's role as crew chief for the sausage wrappers; and the role copyright has played in protecting the company's trademark.  The complete interview, as well as an index, is available in the Special Collections Division.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Odom, Douglas G., 1929- --Interviews; Culbertson, Bill; Odom, Louise Smith, d. 1994; Odom, Douglas G., 1902-1977; Odom, William Martin, 1871-1952; Odom, William Martin, Jr.; Powell, Henry; Griscom, Tom; Wilkerson, Judy Odom; Odom, Richard A., b. 1933</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Odom's Tennessee Pride Sausage; American Meat Institute-Membership; United States. Marine Corps--History--Korean War, 1950-1953;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Advertisements; Business; Education; Enterprise; Military History; Korean War; Businesspeople--Tennessee--Madison; Businesswomen--Tennessee--Madison; Family-owned business enterprises--Tennessee--Madison; New business enterprises--Tennessee--Madison; Businesspeople--Tennessee--Interviews; Meat industry and trade--Tennessee--Madison; Pork industry and trade--Tennessee--Madison; Slaughtering and slaughter-houses--Tennessee--Nashville; Sausages--Tennessee--Madison; Veterans--Tennessee--Interviews; Military education--United States; Street vendors--Tennessee--Nashville; Merchants--Tennessee--Nashville; Merchants--Tennessee--Madison; Peddlers and peddling--Tennessee--Madison; Grocers--Tennessee--Nashville; Loans; Professional associations--United States; Industry--size; Small business; Competition; Advertising--Pork; Television advertising; Radio advertising; Advertising characters; Copyright--Caricatures and cartoons; Copyright infringement; Packaging; Sausage casings; Mothers--Employment; Women--Employment; Women supervisors--Tennessee--Nashville; Bookkeepers--Tennessee--Madison</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Madison (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Madison (Tenn.)--Commerce; Nashville (Tenn.)--History--Sources; Madison (Tenn.)--Social life and customs; Fourteenth Avenue (Nashville, Tenn.); Buchanan Street (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Odom, Douglas G., 1929- (Interviewee); Havron, James T., 1960- (Interviewer)</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Public Library of Nashville and Davidson County</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>2007-06-05</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; Oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>NBLOdomD1002clip1.mp3; NBLOdomD1002clip2.mp3; NBLOdomD1003clip1.mp3; NBLOdomD1003clip2.mp3; NBLOdomD1003and1004clip1.mp3; NBLOdomD1005and1006clip1.mp3; NBLOdomD1008clip1.mp3; NBLOdomD1009clip1.mp3; NBLOdomD1009clip2.mp3; NBLOdomD1009clip3.mp3; NBLOdomD1014clip1.mp3; NBLOdomD1016clip1.mp3; NBPOdomD_transcript.pdf</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from:  NBLOdomD digital recording converted from wav to mp3 format in 2007.</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Nashville Business Leaders Oral History Project</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>2000-2009</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact the Special Collections Division of the Nashville Public Library, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219. Telephone (615) 862-5782.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1455</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>