<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Excerpt 03 from consolidation interview with John Seigenthaler, June 1, 1995</dc:title>
<dc:description>An excerpt from an interview with John Seigenthaler, conducted on June 1, 1995 by Carole Bucy as part of the Metro Consolidation Oral History Interviews.  Seigenthaler discusses his role in the consolidation of the city and county governments.  He also comments briefly on other individuals and their contributions. The complete record of the interview is available at the Metro Government Archives.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Allen, Clifford; Battle, Dick; Branstetter, Cecil; Briley, Beverly; Bucy, Carole; Cochran, Carmack; Cummings, Tom; Evans, Amon Carter; Evans, Silliman; Flippen, H. E.; Galbreath, Charles; Hickman, Litton; Howse, Hillary; Johnson, Victor; Lentz, John; Lillard, Robert; Looby, Z. Alexander (Zephaniah Alexander); May, Dan; Sanders, Guynell; Seigenthaler, John; Stahlman, Jimmy; West, Ben;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Metro Nashville Goverment;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Annexation (Municipal government)--Tennessee--Nashville; Charters; Consolidation; Education; Health department; Legislation; Newspapers; Police departments; Politics &amp; government; Race relations; Annexation (Municipal government)--Tennessee--Nashville; Education--Tennessee--Nashville; Legislation--Tennessee--Nashville; Newspapers--Tennessee--Nashville; Politics &amp; government--Tennessee--Nashville; Race relations--Tennessee--Nashville;</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Nashville (Tenn.)--Education; Nashville (Tenn.)--History; Nashville (Tenn.)--Politics and government; Nashville (Tenn.)--Race relations; Nashville (Tenn.)--Social conditions;</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Metro Historical Commission</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Metropolitan Nashville/Davidson County Archives, Nashville Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Metro Historical Commission</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>6/1/1995</dc:date>
<dc:type>Sound; oral histories</dc:type>
<dc:format>audio/mp3 (2.29 MB; 2 min., 30 sec.)</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Metro Consolidation Oral History Interviews 19</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Excerpted from: Metro Consolidation Oral History Interview(s) converted to mp3 2007</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:relation>Metro Consolidation Oral History Interviews</dc:relation>
<dc:coverage>6/1/1995</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>U.S. and international copyright laws protect this digital content, which is provided for educational purposes only and may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed for any other purpose without written permission.  Please contact: Metro Nashville Archives, 615 Church Street, Nashville, Tennessee, 37219.  Telephone (615) 862-5880.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://nashville.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/nr/id/1291</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>