<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Grand Ole Opry - Prince Albert - 1943-09-25 - Part 1</dc:title>
<dc:description>Part 1 of Prince Albert tobacco sponsored Grand Ole Opry segment from September 25, 1943. Featuring Louie Buck (announcer), George D. Hay (announcer), Whitey Ford/the Duke Of Paducah (as host and performer respectively) and performers Curley Williams and his Georgia Peach Pickers, Pee Wee King and his Golden West Cowboys, Minnie Pearl, Ford Rush, and Mac McGar. Held at Ryman Auditorium, Nashville, TN.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1943-09-25</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Curley Williams; Georgia Peach Pickers; Pee Wee King; Golden West Cowboys; Minnie Pearl; Ford Rush</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Opening statement (Louie Buck) -- Opening theme -- Opening statement (George D. Hay) -- Whitey Ford introduces Curley Williams and his Georgia Peach Pickers -- Columbus Stockade Blues (Curley Williams and his Georgia Peach Pickers) -- Whitey Ford introduces Pee Wee King and his Golden West Cowboys -- Tennessee Wagoner (Pee Wee King and his Golden West Cowboys) -- Whitey Ford introduces Minnie Pearl -- Comedy routine (Minnie Pearl) -- Jealous Hearted Me (Minnie Pearl, Pee Wee King, Golden West Cowboys) -- Prince Albert commercial (Minnie Pearl, Louie Buck) -- Whitey Ford introduces Ford Rush -- There'll Be A Lot Of Happy Mothers (Ford Rush) -- Whitey Ford introduces Trudy Brown -- Trudy Brown interviews service men [continued in part 2]</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>16 inch glass-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR000059</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2006-10-16</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); National Broadcasting Company; Grand ole opry (Radio program); Ryman Auditorium (Nashville, Tenn.); Buck, Louis, 1910-1971; Hay, George D. (George Dewey), 1895-1968; King, Pee Wee, 1914-2000; Golden West Cowboys (Musical group); Minnie Pearl; Rush, Ford, 1895-; McGar, Mac; Williams, Curley, 1913-1970; Georgia Peach Pickers (Musical group); Smith, Hal, 1923-2008; Duke of Paducah, 1901-1986</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/986</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>