<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Ralph Emery Interviews Lee Greenwood Parts 1, 2 and 3</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording is from Ralph Emery's (entertainer) interview of Lee Greenwood (performer) for the Ralph Emery Show. Recording is from June 29, 1982.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1982-06-29</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Ralph Emery; Lee Greenwood</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Lee Greenwood radio spot for the Ralph Emery Show -- (00:17) Wings of an Eagle [excerpt] (Bobby Goldsboro) [Featuring Ralph Emery introduction voiceover] -- (00:42) Greenwood and Emery joke about Greenwood's recent success -- (02:07) Emery invites Greenwood to describe who he is for the audience -- (04:36) "She's Lying" is discussed by Emery and reflected on as a strong single by Goldsboro -- (05:48) Emery invites Goldsboro to be the performing disc jockey for Janie Fricke's "Don't Worry About Me Baby" -- (06:56) Emery has Goldsboro discuss how he had created the same commercial as Fricke -- (07:55) Emery addresses Goldsboro prompting him to sing his McDonald's commercial -- (09:21) Goldsboro reflects on the success of "IT Turns Me Inside Out" and the number of records he recorded that were never released -- (13:03) Emery invites Goldsboro to introduce the Statler Brothers' "Whatever," and how he met them at RCA -- (13:53) Goldsboro discusses how he wrote "A Love Song" for Kenny Rodgers -- (14:17) Wings of an Eagle [excerpt] (Bobby Goldsboro) [Featuring Ralph Emery and Lee Greenwood outro voiceover] -- (15:41) Wings of an Eagle [excerpt] (Bobby Goldsboro) [Featuring Ralph Emery and Lee Greenwood introduction voiceover] -- (16:01) Greenwood reveals he is moving and emery introduces "I'll be Your Man Around the House" -- (16:41) Emery invites Greenwood to reflect on the fear following a successful release -- (18:32) Emery and Greenwood discuss how long Greenwood had been on successful on the charts -- (19:45) Emery divulges some strong words from his mother -- (20:44) Emery and Greenwood discuss the decisions made for Nashville Alive -- (22:10) Emery recalls a story about his discussion with Marty Robbins about performing with Ray Conniff -- (23:18) Greenwood reflects on working with Ricky Skaggs for the Jimmy Rodgers Festival -- (24:10) Emery invites Greenwood to reflect on his track scholarship he received -- (25:45) Greenwood reveals a new dance has been associated with "Ain't No Trick (It Takes Magic)" -- (26:54) Emery reflects on when he did not play "Folsom Prison Blues" while interviewing Bobby Bare -- (28:37) Emery recalls meeting Susie McEntire and Greenwood expresses his desire to have a brother -- (29:34) Emery inquires about the writing success of Greenwood only to be cut off -- (30:26) Wings of an Eagle [excerpt] (Bobby Goldsboro) [Featuring Ralph Emery and Lee Greenwood outro voiceover] -- (31:48) Wings of an Eagle [excerpt] (Bobby Goldsboro) [Featuring Ralph Emery and Lee Greenwood introduction voiceover] -- (32:11) Emery introduces Greenwood who introduces Waylon Jennings' "Women Know How to Carry On" -- (32:40) Emery reintroduces the question of the success that Greenwood has had as a songwriter -- (34:26) Emery reveals a speech Jimmy Davis gave -- (35:06) Emery and Greenwood discuss how Greenwood's "Thank You For Saving My Life" was written for Ronnie Milsap -- (35:57) Emery and Greenwood joke about the difficulties B-Side tapes have received -- (37:33) Emery inquires about the amount of people Greenwood has met in Nashville -- (38:49) Greenwood discusses working with the Kendalls -- (39:47) Emery inquires about Greenwood's family and moving status -- (42:33) Greenwood and Emery discuss Calamity Jane and "Walking After Midnight" -- (44:27) Emery invites Greenwood to reflect on the talent he was surrounded with, and Greenwood reveals his mother's eccentric mannerisms  -- (46:38) Wings of an Eagle [excerpt] (Bobby Goldsboro) [Featuring Ralph Emery and Lee Greenwood outro voiceover]</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1364_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1364</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-04-09</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Emery, Ralph; Greenwood, Lee;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8768</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>