<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Country Music Hall of Fame Medallion Ceremony - 2002-05-05</dc:title>
<dc:description>Country Music Hall of Fame Medallion ceremony as broadcast/or streamed by WSM Radio.  From the Rotunda of the Country Music Hall of Fame on May 5, 2002.  Inductees are Bill Anderson, the Delmore Brothers, the Everly Brothers, Don Gibson, Homer &amp; Jethro, Waylon Jennings, the Jordanaires, Don Law, the Louvin Brothers, Ken Nelson, Webb Pierce, Sam Phillips.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2002-05-05</dc:date>
<dc:creator>the Nitty Gritty Dirt Band; Jimmy Martin; Gary Scruggs; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Eddie Stubbs conducts interviews from the Curb Conservatory with EmmyLou Harris,Bud Wendell, Charlie Louvin, Robyn Young, Bill Anderson, Eddy Arnold, Dolly Parton, Governor Don Sundquist, talks with Kyle Cantrell.  Ceremony takes place in the Hall of Fame Rotunda.  Performances include "Grand Ole Opry Song" Jimmy Martin and the Sunny Mountain Boys with the Nitty Gritty Dirt Band -- "I Saw the Light" Jimmy Martin with the Nitty Gritty Dirt Band -- "Earl's Breakdown" Gary Scruggs with the Nitty Gritty Dirt Band -- comments from Little Jimmie Dickens and Brenda Lee  --  presentation of medallions - "Will The Circle Be Unbroken" The Nitty Gritty Dirt Band -- "Will The Circle Be Unbroken" assembled Hall of Fame members -- comments from Eddie Stubbs and Kyle Cantrell.  Interview with Gordon Stoker  </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>CD-R;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>PP0035</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2015-10-22</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Nitty Gritty Dirt Band; Martin, Jimmy; Scruggs, Gary;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/2566</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>