<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Hallmarks of Country Music - Skeeter Davis</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of an interview of Skeeter Davis (musician). The interview is hosted by Rick Phillips (army sergeant/ radio host) for the Hallmarks of Country Music segment. The tape was recorded on an unidentified date.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Skeeter Davis; Rick Phillips</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Promotion for Hallmarks of Country Music featuring Rick Phillips introducing Skeeter Davis -- (00:48) Hallmarks tune [featuring Rick Phillips introduction voiceover] ([Unidentified]) -- (01:20) Michigan Vietnam era veteran's bonus commercial spot hosted by Phillips -- (02:17) Crib death commercial spot hosted by and unidentified host -- (03:14) I Forgot More Than You'll Ever Know (About Him) (Skeeter Davis) -- (05:45) Planned Parenthood commercial spot hosted by an unidentified host -- (06:15)  What Does it Take to Keep a Man Like You Satisfied (Skeeter Davis) -- (08:52) Phillips inquires about "What Does it Take to Keep a Man Like You Satisfied," and Davis reflects on not singing in a club where people drink -- (10:55) I Can't Stay Mad at You (Skeeter Davis) -- (13:00) Army Reserve radio spot hosted by an unidentified group -- (14:11) One Tin Solider (Skeeter Davis) -- (17:13) Phillips inquires about Davis' inspiration for "One Tin Solider," and Davis reflects on the concerns of releasing the same record as someone else -- (22:33) Gonna Get Along Without You Now (Skeeter Davis) -- (24:40) An unidentified host performs a dishonorable discharge radio spot -- (25:16) I'm a Lover Not a Fighter (Skeeter Davis) -- (27:36) Love commercial spot hosted by Steve Allen -- (28:26) I Will (Skeeter Davis) -- (30:55) Skeeter reflects on working with Ernest Tubb and the Grand Ole Opry -- (35:42) There's a Fool Born Every Minute (Skeeter Davis) -- (37:57) January recruiting goals radio spot hosted by Phillips -- (38:38) Something Precious (Skeeter Davis) -- (40:46) M. O. S. career management radio spot hosted by Phillips -- (41:13) I Can't Help You (I'm Falling Too) (Skeeter Davis) -- (43:51) Davis reflects on "I Can't Help You (I'm Falling Too)" being an answer to Jeannie Black; additionally, Davis' international popularity is discussed -- (48:30) The End of the World (Skeeter Davis) -- (51:04) Cal Smith hosts an army commercial spot -- (51:40) I Can't Believe it's All Over (Skeeter Davis) -- (53:55) Hallmarks outro tune [featuring Rick Phillips outro voiceover] ([Unidentified]) -- (56:02) Phillips introduces next weeks guest: Moe Bandy -- (56:14) I Just Started Hatin' Cheating Songs Today (Moe Bandy) -- (58:59) Phillips and Bandy converse about 'honky-tonk' music -- (1:00:31) Hallmarks tune ([Unidentified])</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Insert is of program information. The insert features time stamps.</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1720_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1720</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-06-17</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Davis, Skeeter; Phillips, Rick;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9106</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>