<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Anita Bryant Interview - Biff Collie</dc:title>
<dc:description>Tape 1 of 2. Recording of an interview with Anita Bryant (performer) conducted by Biff Collie.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1990-02-22</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Anita Bryant; Biff Collie</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Biff Collie directs Anita Bryant away from mic -- (00:10) Bryant greets herself -- (00:13) Bryant tells about talking with Collie during a radio spot radio spot -- (00:21) Bryant attempts audiobiography radio spot with Collie correcting her and Bryant does a retake -- (00:43) Bryant attempts audiobiography radio spot with Collie telling her to be more playful and Bryant does a retake -- (01:16) Bryant thirty minute radio spot -- (01:26) Bryant midway point radio spot -- (01:40) Bryant audiobiography radio spot for a commercial break -- (01:53) Thirty minute remaining radio spot -- (02:04) Bryant misspeaks Collie's name and does a outro radio spot retake -- (02:22) Collie asks Bryant to do a couple more radio spots -- (02:34) Bryant radio spot for the Music City Album Review -- (02:40) Collie instructs Bryant on a Music City Album Review and to mention her album -- (03:04) Bryant radio spot of the Music City Album Review and her album Anita With Love Volumes One and Two -- (03:18) Collie instructs Bryant on album review radio spot -- (03:35)  Bryant messes up radio spot of the Music City Album Review and her album Anita With Love Volumes One and Two (03:51)  Bryant radio spot of her album Anita With Love Volumes One and Two and the Music City Album Review -- (04:01) Collie instructs for simplicity the directions for the show and Bryant jokes about payment -- (04:40) Collie continues to ask Bryant about album details -- (05:04) Bryant tells Collie that the track he had listed was incorrectly listed as Marie Osmond instead of hers then discusses using other people's tracks -- (06:08) Bryant tells Collie "Paper Roses," "Til There Was You," and "My Little Corner of The World" were not written by her but performed live -- (07:20) Collie talks about small print and a Peggy walks in on set -- (07:50) Bryant introduces her first song, mentions her pageantry experience, and dating Kenny Rodgers  -- (09:21) Collie and Bryant discuss Paper Roses and how it is known as a Marie Osmond song -- (09:58) Bryant discusses "Out Here On My Own" as a performing number -- (10:30) "I Won't Last A Day Without You" is described as a love song -- (10:50) Marie Osmond and Bryant's connection to "My Little Corner of the World" is discussed and Collie mentions that Sunny James had originally produced "Paper Roses" -- (11:48) Collie mentions Bette Midler on the Grammys and Bryant calls her gutsy -- (12:17) Collie and Bryant discuss Bryant's value system, how it influenced her performances, and roly-poly toys -- (13:54) Collie and Bryant talk about how she fringes between contemporary and country with her background of church and Opry -- (15:00) Bryant talks about her families country heritage and Little Jimmy Dickens -- (15:30) Bryant and Collie talk about what being on the Opry would mean to her -- (15:56) "Til There Was You" is talked about in conjunction with her first pageant -- (17:42) "Two Late Roses" by Bryant is described as a nob to a person from Selma and "Paper Roses" -- (19:04) Bryant and Collie talks about Lionel Richie giving feedback on "Two Late Roses" -- (19:44) Bryant talks about almost joining the Boone family -- (20:52) Bryant talks about heartbreak and life experience leading to multi dimensional writing -- (22:19) Collie talks about Johnny Russell describing writing as a necessity for healing and Bryant agrees -- (23:16) "Don't Cry Out Loud" is joked about and Bryant calls it a gutsy song -- (24:00) "What The World Needs Now" is talked about by Bryant as a necessity for the world to recognize love -- (25:47) Bryant talks about the double standards of action versus talk and Collie responds with a memory of his mothers death -- (27:27) Bryant talks about working with a publisher and discovering a book named The Art of Mentoring -- (30:00) Collie talks about how modern times are more hands off teaching and Bryant responds with declaring how much people are observed -- (31:51) Collie shifts gears and talks about "Had To Be You" and Shelby Lynne cutting the track -- (32:18) Bryant talks about having a manger who would teach her older ballads to expand her knowledge -- (33:05) Collie and Bryant talk about Willie Nelson and recording of older tracks -- (33:50) Bryant talks about performing "What Will I Do" and Collie talks about what Eddy Arnold believed to be the most important part of his show -- (34:50) Bryant talks about drawing an intimacy with a crowd and "The More I See You" -- (35:31) "My Romance" is discussed by Bryant as only needing the man you love -- (35:55) Collie and Bryant talk about "You'll Never Know" and Collie's personal connection -- (36:18) I'll Get By" is said to be a simplistic swing -- (37:39) Anita With Love production is addresses as a live to two track -- (40:15) Bryant gives the 1-800 number and direct mail address for the album -- (41:00) Bryant and Collie talk about bringing Bryant back on the show to discuss her other volumes of Anita With Love -- (41:48) Bryant gives her sign off</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1128_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1128</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-12-28</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Bryant, Anita; Collie, Biff;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8324</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>