<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Opryland Music Demo Recordings - Y-105</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording is of a group of demo recordings from Opryland Music. Recordings are from an unknown date and recorded by a number of unknown bands. Tape is labeled Y-105. </dc:description>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Can't Let Go (Bobby Lile) -- (02:20) Country News Polka (J. Gilbertson) -- (04:38) Can't You Hear Me (Call Your Name) (Beam, Jiles, and Stevenson) -- (07:09) Cecil Know Better Now (Stevenson) -- (09:55) Castle of my Dreams (F. Renaud) -- (12:11) Christmas (Eddie Miller) -- (14:21) The Chant (D. Warren and L. Miller) -- (16:18) Counting Every Hour (M. Weber) -- (17:55) Cry for Me (M. Holcomb) -- (20:12) Cryin' and A-Hurtin' (C. Belew) -- (22:01) China Heart (R. Jiroudek, D. Hampton, and R. Whitaker) -- (24:10) Chicksaw Chick (A. Gunn and H. Griffis) -- (26:32) Cute Little Pet (F. Wilson and R. Baker) -- (27:34) Cherokee Rose (K. Poage) -- (28:52) My Baby Loves Me (J. Holiday and W. S. Stevenson) -- (30:20) My Lonely Christmas Tree (A. Murphy and Stevenson) -- (32:54) My Foolish Pride (Pete Peters) -- (33:49) My Oh Me Oh My (Pete Graves) -- (35:44) My Faith is Built Upon the Rock (R. Baker) -- (37:56) Mistake in Life (J. Wilson) -- (40:36) Memories (N. Oleachea and W. S. Stevenson) -- (42:21) My Wedding Song to You (Frankie Miller) -- (44:37) May Heaven Guide You (F. Whitney) -- (47:12) My Dreams Aren't Made to Last (B. Flournoy) -- (48:23) My Heart I'll Offer (B. Flournoy) -- (49:23) The Big Chief Say (Landry, Stapleton, and Stevenson) -- (50:47) Baby You Done Lit My Flame (J. Walton and B. Roberts) -- (53:17) A Big Black Sombrero (S. Masters and W. S. Stevenson) -- (55:03) Baby Me Baby (H. Crow and K. Swalley) -- (56:43) Bologna in Your Lunch Box (L. Lewis) -- (58:54)  The Bells (Ruby Smith) -- (1:01:31) Be My Honey Bee (E. Oleachea, N. Oleachea, and Stevenson) -- (1:03:42) Brown Eyes or Blue Eyes (V. F. Stewart) -- (1:06:37) Blue Moon Over Las Vegas (D. E. Brown) -- (1:08:57) Big Door (G. Brown and W. S. Stevenson) -- (1:10:57) Behind Closed Doors (E. Miller and Stevenson) -- (1:12:42) Bad Man's Blues (J. Reagan and Stevenson) -- (1:14:06) Blue Rendezvous (J. Starr and Betty Jo Starr) -- (1:16:18) Blue Bonnets (T. Allen and D. Williams) -- (1:18:41) Jole Brunette (E. Wellman and T. Cooley) -- (1:22:16) Jim and Mary (J. W. Burk) -- (1:25:07) Just You and I (Y. Ball) -- (1:28:17) Just for Tonight (E. Christian) -- (1:31:19) Jealous Love (D. S. Brown)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1301_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1301</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-03-13</dcterms:created>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8634</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>