<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>F. Bostick Wester show (KYOR) w/ guest Smokey Smith - 1948-03-06 - Part 1</dc:title>
<dc:description>Part 1 of a broadcast of F. Bostick Wester's KYOR radio program, featuring guest Smokey Smith. Originally broadcast 1948-03-06 at 1:00 pm. Smokey announces that he is to appear at a barn dance at the American Legion Hall in La Mesa on Saturday, March 13, 1948.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1948-03-06</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Smokey Smith</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Station announcement -- Opening statement (F. Bostick Wester) -- Gold Coast Express (Smokey Smith) -- F. Bostick Wester and Smokey Smith talk -- I Wonder If You Meant To Break My Heart? (Smokey Smith) -- Smokey Smith and F. Bostick Wester talk -- Shenandoah Waltz (Smokey Smith) -- Smokey Smith reads poem The Old-Time Family -- Smokey Smith announces an upcoming appearance -- Smokey Smith and F. Bostick Wester talk -- Signed Sealed and Delivered (Smokey Smith) -- Smokey Smith and F. Bostick Wester talk -- (Last Night) I Heard You Crying In Your Sleep (Smokey Smith) -- Smokey Smith and F. Bostick Wester talk -- I'm A Fool To Care (Smokey Smith)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>16 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR001689</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2015-10-20</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>KYOR (Radio station : San Diego, Calif.); Smith, Smokey, 1922-; Wester, Bostick, 1914-1998</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/2559</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>