<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Words and Music Night - 2002-05-09</dc:title>
<dc:description>Words and Music Night program held in the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on May 9, 2002.  Hosted by Patsy Bruce.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2002-05-09</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Patsy Bruce; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Opening comments by Kyle Young / (03:50) Introduction of Justine Gregory with comments and introduction of the host, Patsy Bruce / (06:00) Comments by Patsy Bruce / (08:35) Tennessee (Kim Copeland with Rachel Head and Desiree Garrison) / (14:30) My Love Is Real (Jeff Pearson with Azra Medic) / (19:41) School is fun (Steven Farmer with the Kindergarten Club) / (24:37) Leave Me Alone (Kathy Hussey with Travis Roman and Ben Johnson) / (30:34) Love for you Mama (Les Kerr with Ebony Bowers, Keirra Hobbs and Brittany Lewis) / (37:06) Math Homework (Rich Fagan with Christine Thompson) / (42:00) On the way to California (Bill Golay and Bill Stevens with Lyle Reed) / (49:29) Cows (Bob Spanburgh with Collier Gailmard) / (55:08) Oak Hill blues (Dwight Liles with Jordan Sherman) / (59:55) Kelley Jones comments about the Words and Music program / (01:04:00) Be Alone (Rick Bennett with Mary Catherine Overbey) / (01:08:43) Elements of Life (Richard Shaluly with Reanna Bruey and Leigh Steele) /</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(01:14:22) Someday, little lady (Simon McCain with Chelsea Ferguson) / (01:21:59) When my dog died (Dwight Liles with William Decker) / (01:26:19) Kid with constant hunger (Casey Kelly with Spencer Huff) / (01:34:28) Nanny (Tim Carroll with Lindsey Byrne) / (01:39:00) The Struggle and the Hustle (Les Kerr with David Pope) / (01:44:16) I'm running in (Sheila Lawrence and Kyle Woods) / (01:49:53) Playground bully (Casey Kelley with Briana Grysbowski) / (01:57:05) Patsy Bruce with songwriter goals and inspiration and closing comments / END OF PROGRAM.</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>RDAT digital tape;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RS.2014.0128</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2017-10-19</dcterms:created>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/5989</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>