<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Poets and Prophets - Billy Joe Shaver - 2018-09-15</dc:title>
<dc:description>An interview program on the career and life to date of songwriter Billy Joe Shaver from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on September 15, 2018. Includes audio from video and performances.  Moderated by Michael Gray. Presented in support of the exhibit Outlaws &amp; Armadillos: Country&#8217;s Roaring &#8217;70s.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2018-09-15</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Billy Joe Shaver; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Walk-in Music / (04:46) Opening comments and introductions by Michael Gray / (10:27) Opening comments by Billy Joe / (10:53) Performs Honky Tonk Heroes / (12:43) Billy Joe tells the story about the song Honky Tonk Heroes, tells story about his Mother and the inspiration for the song / (21:48) Billy Joe talks about his grandmother who raised him / (24:00) Billy Joe talks about his father / (25:38) Billy Joe talks about starting to perform musically / (27:07) Billy Joe tells about the encouragement he received in the early days of songwriting / (30:00) Billy Joe talks about joining the Navy / (30:27) Talks about leaving the Navy and meeting his first wife Brenda / () Talks about his son Eddie and what Billy Joe did to make ends meet / (32:35) Billy Joe tells story about losing his fingers in a sawmill accident and going to the doctor's office /  (39:18) Tells story about having appendicitis and getting a circumcision at the same time / (42:40) Talks about coming to Nashville in 1966 for the first time and how he got there / (46:14) Talks about the Eddie Rabbitt being on of the first people in Nashville who believed in him / (47:47) Talks about the first people to record his songs and tells story about Bobby Bare / (52:57) Plays video from a TV show performing Ride Me Down Easy / (55:26) Talks about writing the song Ride Me Down Easy / (58:10) Michael lists names of artists who recorded his songs in the early days and talks about  how pivotal the year 1973 was for Billy Joe's career / (58:40) Billy Joe tells story about his album Old Five And Dimers Like Me and the song Christian Soldier / (01:00:24) Talks about the song Old Five And Dimers / (01:01:33) Performs Old Five And Dimers Like Me / (01:04:05) Talks about his religious belief / (01:04:50) Talks about the Grateful Dead and tells story / (01:08:40) Tells story about meeting Waylon Jennings and him hearing the first Billy Joe song / (01:10:25) Talk about chasing Waylon and showing up at a Waylon recording session and playing him more songs / (01:15:00) Plays video of Waylon Jennings performing two Billy Joe songs / (01:17:25) Talks about turning his life around / (01:18:34) Tells the story about writing the song I'm Just An Old Chunk Of Coal (But I'm Gonna Be a Diamond Some Day) / (01:24:48) Talks about the songs Long In The Tooth and I'm In Love and the help that he got from Willie Nelson / (01:26:27) Performs I'm Just An Old Chunk Of Coal (But I'm Gonna Be a Diamond Some Day) / (01:28:19) Plays video of Eddie Shaver performing Georgia On A Fast Train / (01:30:12) Talks about Eddie Shaver and when he started playing guitar and tells Dickie Betts story / (01:31:59) Talks about Eddie's death / (01:33:19) Talks about the song Day By Day / (01:33:56) Talks about Eddie's version of Georgia On A Fast Train and the current drug epidemic / (01:35:09) Talks about the song You Can't Beat Jesus Christ / (01:35:32) Performs Yesterday Tomorrow Was Today / (01:38:26) Applause and final comments / (01:39:02) Closing comments / (01:39:34) Walk-out Music / (01:41:38) FILE END                             </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 48/24</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0146</dc:identifier>
<dc:subject>Shaver, Billy Joe; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8883</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>