<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Mae Boren Axton interviewed by Bob Battle/BMI Awards 1980</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is Mae Boren Axton being interviewed by Bob Battle. The recording takes place on an unidentified date. The next part of the tape contains a speech from Ed Cramer at the 1980 BMI Awards.          </dc:description>
<dc:date>1980</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Mae Boren Axton; Frances W. Preston</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Side One - (0:13) -- Bob Battle speaks with Mae Boren Axton about her weekend. (0:44) -- Bob Battle asks about Grandmother Minnie Mae. (1:14) -- Bob Battle asks about the funeral of Grandmother Minnie Mae. (1:40) - End of phone call. (1:58) -- Vice president of BMI Frances Preston's introduction of BMI's president Ed Cramer. (3:28) -- Ed Cramer's speech about BMI's goals. (5:46) -- Ed Cramer describes meeting with the United States senate about songwriting legislation. Ed Cramer mentions that a particular United States senator did not believe that songwriters live regular lives. (9:05) -- Ed Cramer asks for help when fighting for royalties. (10:35) -- Ed Cramer's speech conclusion of the previous year. (10:55) -- Ed Cramer gives the floor back to Frances Preston. (11:53) -- Frances Preston gives an award to "All The Gold In California." (12:40) -- Bob Battle interviews Barbara Mandrell. Barbara speaks about working with the Nashville Symphony and a show made in California with her sisters Irlene and Louise. Barbara Mandrell discusses filming a movie and making a new live album. (15:28) -- Barbara Mandrell mentions she just signed a new contract with MCA. (16:18) -- Bob Battle asks Barbara Mandrell about her plans on making her first gospel album. (18:24) -- Charley Pride interview with Bob Battle. Charley Pride mentions that he wants to make new music, films, and TV. (19:21) -- Bob Battle asks Charley Pride about his future goals. (21:00) -- Introduction of Charlie Daniels "The Devil Went Down To Georgia."  </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>audio cassette, compact;</dc:format>
<dc:format>1.75 ips;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CAS4678_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>CAS4678</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-08-30</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Axton, Mae Boren; Preston, Frances Williams, 1928-2012;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9470</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>