<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Tom T. Hall interview - Biff Collie - Happy Hour - 1983-01-24</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of an interview with Tom T. Hall (performer/songwriter), conducted by Biff Collie for his radio program Happy Hour on January 24, 1983.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1983-01-24</dc:date>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Tom T. Hall talks about not having a middle initial until he came to Nashville -- Biff Collie talks about meeting Tom T. Hall in New York -- Hall talks about coming to Nashville from Roanoke, VA. And being born in Kentucky -- Hall talks about going to school for writing in Roanoke and also doing radio work -- Hall talks about the first song he wrote, D. J. For A Day -- Hall talks about his father being an ordained preacher -- Hall talks about having religious influence in some of his songs -- Hall talks about his songwriting process -- Hall talks about how music as an art form generates so much money -- Hall talks about Doug Kershaw -- Hall talks about teaching songwriting and the different types of people who write songs -- Hall talks about serving in the army -- Hall talks about his favorite song often being the ones he is currently working on -- Hall concludes the interview</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-7-04032_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-7-04032</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-07-16</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Hall, Tom T.; Collie, Biff;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/7876</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>