<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Pulsebeat Radio Show: New Year's Show - Part 1</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of Kim Spangler (host) dictating the Pulsebeat section of the Voice of the Heartland Radio Show. The episode features sections of interviews from: Kim Spangler (musician), Tom T. Hall (musician), Johnny Cash (musician), Willie Nelson (musician), Larry Boone (musician), Dolly Parton (musician), Vern Gosdin(musician), Randy Travis(musician), and T. Graham Brown (musician). The episode was set to air for the week of December 26, 1988. The episode is part 1 of 2.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1988-12-26</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Kim Spangler; Tom T. Hall; Johnny Cash; Willie Nelson; Larry Boone; Dolly Parton; Vern Gosdin; Randy Travis; T. Graham Brown</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:01) Kim Spangler introduces the upcoming Pulsebeat show -- (00:33) Tom T. Hall reflects on why he enjoys Johnny Cash's "Understand Your Man" -- (01:09) Understand Your Man (Johnny Cash) -- (03:32) Spangler introduces the commercial break -- (03:38) An unidentified voice performs a John Willingham Barbeque commercial spot -- (05:18) Spangler calls Larry Boone a complete artist -- (05:32) Boone reflects on why he loves "I Have You" -- (05:54) I Have You (Larry Boone) -- (09:08) Spangler introduces Holly Dunn; Dunn calls Willie Nelson's "Stardust" album her favorite -- (09:37) Blue Skies (Willie Nelson) -- (13:21) Spangler reintroduces the program and Don Williams -- (13:38) Williams is blindsided by the question of what song he would like to hear -- (13:49) Wildflowers (Dolly Parton) -- (17:15) Spangler reflects on Exile's changing style -- (17:37) The members of Exile discuss how they can not agree on a song -- (17:57) Chiseled in Stone (Vern Gosdin) -- (21:35) Spangler introduces the commercial break -- (21:42) An unidentified voice performs a John Willingham Barbeque commercial spot -- (23:13) Spangler praises T. Graham Brown -- (23:32) Brown reveals his classmates wrote "1982" -- (24:18) 1982 (Randy Travis) -- (27:13) Unidentified tune [featuring Kim Spangler outro discussion] ([Unidentified])</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-0965_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-0965</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-09-09</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Spangler, Kim; Hall, Tom T.; Cash, Johnny; Cash, Johnny, 1932-2003; Nelson, Willie, 1933-; Boone, Larry; Parton, Dolly; Parton, Dolly, 1946-; Gosdin, Vern; Travis, Randy; Brown, T. Graham;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9519</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>