<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Minnie Pearl Comedy Routines - Disc 1, 2, 3, 4</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of a variety of clips featuring Minnie Pearl's comedy routines. The various stand up recordings feature: Ernest Tubb (musician), Rod Brasfield (comedian), Grant Turner (musician), Hank Snow (musician), Jimmie Dickens (musician), and Ray Price (musician). The recordings are labeled disc number one, two, three, and four. The recordings are believed to take place at the Grand Ole Opry. The first recording is from May of 1952. The second recording is from the Spring of 1955. The remaining recordings are from a number of unidentified dates.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1952-05</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Minnie Pearl; Ernest Tubb; Grant Turner; Rod Brasfield; Hank Snow; Jimmie Dickens; George Morgan</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:01) Minnie Pearl asks the crowd what they think of her dress; additionally, Ernest Tubb and Pearl associate Pearl's figure to a battle -- (01:08) Pearl introspects about Lucifer Hucklehead's experiments; additionally, Pearl jokes about her brother performing in a boxing match -- (04:12) Unidentified fiddle riff ([Unidentified]) -- (04:22) Pearl shows her discomfort without people kissing her; additionally, Pearl reveals that Uncle Naybob is in trouble with Aunt Rosy -- (06:00) Grant Turner asks how Pearl would handle being courted in New York -- (07:19) Rod Brasfield reveals that New York City, New York is covered in treasure; additionally, Pearl reveals there are wolves in New York -- (08:03) Unidentified fiddle riff ([Unidentified]) -- (08:12) Unidentified fiddle riff ([Unidentified]) -- (08:16) Pearl reflects on her love of crowded buses, and Pearl reveals to Brasfield that she had a man going in circles -- (09:25) Brasfield and Pearl discuss whether or not Pearl would be a cover girl -- (09:57) Pearl asks Brasfield what color buttercups and hiccups are -- (11:03) Pearl reveals to Brasfield that she had been hit on the head; additionally, Pearl calls Brasfield an adolescence -- (12:39) Unidentified fiddle riff ([Unidentified]) -- (12:50) Unidentified fiddle riff [fades out] ([Unidentified]) -- (12:57) Pearl reveals the sweetest thing a man has ever told her -- (14:44) Brasfield doesn't appreciate Pearl given his lineage, and Pearl reveals uncle Naybob is raising fleas -- (15:35) Pearl and Brasfield discuss trick dogs -- (16:42) Unidentified fiddle riff ([Unidentified]) -- (16:57) Unidentified fiddle riff ([Unidentified]) -- (17:12) Pearl reveals to Jimmie Dickens that she got him a Valentine; additionally, Pearl says a bus driver did not want her dog on the bus -- (19:55) Unidentified fiddle riff ([Unidentified]) -- (20:07) Unidentified fiddle riff ([Unidentified]) -- (20:14) Pearl asks Tubb where she saw his face before; additionally, Tubb declares that Pearl enjoys getting kissed -- (21:50) Pearl asks if Tubb had kissed uglier girls than her -- (22:30) Unidentified fiddle riff ([Unidentified]) -- (22:43) Pearl and George Morgan discuss Morgan's dream about Pearl, and Pearl says love 'kicked her in the face' -- (24:36) Brasfield reveals he has a goat with no nose; additionally, Pearl declared the West to be 'below cold' -- (26:04) Pearl discusses how someone tried to sell her the Grand Canyon -- (26:37) Unidentified fiddle riff ([Unidentified]) -- (26:43) Unidentified fiddle riff ([Unidentified]) -- (26:53) Pearl reveals to Ray Price that girls with lisps kiss better than other girls; additionally, Pearl reveals Brother landed on a pitch fork -- (28:27) Pearl and Rodney Brasfield joke about a three-point landing and a 'willie wagon' -- (30:11) Pearl jokes about her friend's new home</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-0217_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-0217</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-08-28</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Pearl, Minnie; Tubb, Ernest; Tubb, Ernest, 1914-1984; Turner, Grant; Brasfield, Rod; Brasfield, Rod, 1910-1958; Snow, Hank; Dickens, Little Jimmy, 1920-2015; Morgan, George, 1925-1975;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9436</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>