<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Various introductions - Biff Collie</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of various artist introductions for Biff Collie (host), on Collie's Corner.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1989-02-09</dc:date>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>[Unidentified] -- Steve Wariner -- Minnie Pearl -- Don Williams -- Jerry Reed -- Sonny James -- Arlene Harden -- Wilma Burgess -- Bud Logan -- Wade Ray -- Gordon Terry -- Pam Miller -- Jim Glaser -- Tommy Overstreet -- Billy Swan -- Bobby Bare -- Bobby G. Rice -- La Costa Tucker -- Doyle Holly -- Stonewall Jackson -- Carl Smith -- Roy Drusky -- Jack Greene -- Grandpa Jones -- Tom T. Hall -- Cal Smith -- Penny DeHaven -- Mac Wiseman -- Red Sovine -- Little Jimmy Dickens -- Hank Snow -- Justin Tubb -- Osborne Brothers -- Eddy Arnold -- Connie Smith -- Bob Luman -- Burch Sisters -- Tanya Tucker -- Garth Brooks -- Suzy Bogguss -- Gatlin Brothers Band -- Restless Heart -- Mickey Gilley -- John Conlee -- Foster &amp; Lloyd -- Billy Joe Royal -- Hank Thompson -- Eddy Raven -- Earl Thomas Conley -- Vern Gosdin -- Johnny Rodriguez -- Lacey J. Dalton -- Kathy Mattea -- Patty Loveless -- Clint Black -- Charlie Pride -- Forester Sisters -- Dean Dillon -- Holly Dunn -- Cece [Unidentified] -- T. Graham Brown -- Don Williams -- Eddy Rabbitt -- Stella Parton -- Lionel Cartwright -- Forester Sisters -- Johnny Cash -- Porter Wagoner -- George Morgan -- Freddie Hart -- Hank Thompson -- Wilburn Brothers -- Skeets McDonald -- Charlie Walker -- Justin Tubb -- Roy Drusky -- Tex Ritter -- Gordon Terry -- Ernest Tubb -- Jim Reeves -- Goldie Hill -- Bobby Lord -- Floyd Tillman -- Eddy Noack -- Cowboy Copas -- Ray Price -- Tab Hunter -- Willie Nelson -- Bill Phillips -- Johnny Western -- Rusty &amp; Doug -- James O. Glenn -- [Unidentified child] -- Dick Curless -- Eddy Arnold -- Shorty Bacon -- Billy Mize -- Jeannie Sterling -- Webb Pierce -- Johnny Cash -- Porter Wagoner -- Freddie Hart -- Hank Thompson -- Wilburn Brothers -- Charlie Walker -- Justin Tubb -- Roy Drusky -- Gordon Terry -- Hank Snow -- Carl Smith -- Goldie Hill -- Bobby Lord -- Little Jimmy Dickens -- [Unidentified] -- [Unidentified] -- Johnnie &amp; Jack -- Warren Smith -- Johnny Bond -- Merle Travis -- Bob Wills -- Ray Price -- Jimmie Skinner -- George Morgan -- Wilburn Brothers -- Skeets McDonald -- Tex Ritter -- Ernest Tubb -- Jim Reeves</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips; 15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-7-03970_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-7-03970</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-06-28</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Collie, Biff; Wariner, Steve; Minnie Pearl; Cannon, Sarah Ophelia, 1912-1996; Williams, Don, 1939-2017; Reed, Jerry; James, Sonny; Harden, Arlene; Burgess, Wilma; Logan, Bud; Ray, Wade, 1913-1998; Terry, Gordon; Miller, Pam; Glaser, Jim; Overstreet, Tommy; Swan, Billy; Bare, Bobby, 1935-; Rice, Bobby G.; Holly, Doyle; Jackson, Stonewall (musician); Smith, Carl, 1927-2010; Drusky, Roy; Greene, Jack (Singer); Jones, Grandpa, 1913-1998; Hall, Tom T.; Smith, Cal; DeHaven, Penny; Wiseman, Mac; Sovine, Red; Dickens, Little Jimmy, 1920-2015; Snow, Hank; Tubb, Justin; Osborne Brothers; Arnold, Eddy, 1918-2008; Smith, Connie, 1941-; Luman, Bob, 1937-1978; Burch Sisters; Tucker, Tanya, 1958-; Brooks, Garth; Bogguss, Suzy; Gatlin Brothers; Gatlin, Larry; Restless Heart (Musical group); Gilley, Mickey; Conlee, John; Foster &amp; Lloyd; Royal, Billy Joe; Thompson, Hank; Raven, Eddy, 1944-; Gosdin, Vern; Rodriguez, Johnny, 1951-; Dalton, Lacy J., 1946-; Mattea, Kathy; Loveless, Patty; Black, Clint; Pride, Charley, 1938-; Forester Sisters; Dillon, Dean; Dunn, Holly; Brown, T. Graham; Rabbitt, Eddie, 1941-1998; Parton, Stella; Cartwright, Lionel; Cash, Johnny, 1932-2003; Wagoner, Porter, 1927-2007; Morgan, George, 1925-1975; Hart, Freddie; Wilburn Brothers; McDonald, Skeets 1915-1968; Walker, Charlie, 1926-2008; Tubb, Justin; Ritter, Tex, 1905-1974; Tubb, Ernest, 1914-1984; Terry, Gordon; Reeves, Jim; Hill, Goldie; Lord, Bobby; Tillman, Floyd; Noack, Eddie, 1930-1978; Copas, Cowboy; Price, Ray, 1926-2013; Hunter, Tab, 1931-; Nelson, Willie, 1933-; Phillips, Bill (Vocalist); Western, Johnny; Rusty &amp; Doug; Mize, Billy; Sterling, Jeannie; Pierce, Webb, 1921-1991; Johnnie &amp; Jack; Travis, Merle, 1917-1983; Wills, Bob, 1905-1975; Skinner, Jimmie, 1909-1979; </dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/7708</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>