<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Various record and radio excerpts</dc:title>
<dc:description>Various recordings of performances featuring various performers, mostly pertaining to the Sons Of The Pioneers and other unidentified performers</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Sons Of The Pioneers; Texas Troubadours; Dick Foran; Karl Farr; Hugh Farr; Bob Nolan</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Test tones -- Here Comes The River Robin (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- [Unidentified fiddle tune] (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- [Unidentified guitar tune] (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- Cattle Round (Sons Of The Pioneers) [unconfirmed] -- Hello Way Up Yonder (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- Trail Herdin' Cowboy (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- [Unidentified tune] (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- [Unidentified tune] (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- Cherokee Strip (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- Rise And Shine (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- [Unidentified guitar tune] (Karl Farr) -- The Timber Trail (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- Dusty Skies (Bob Nolan) -- Down By The Riverside (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- [Unidentified guitar tune] (Karl Farr and Hugh Farr) -- [Unidentified tune] (Karl Farr) -- My Old Pal, Pal Of Mine ([Unidentified]) -- [Unidentified tune] (Karl Farr) -- He's Ridin' Home (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- The Covered Wagon Rolled Right Along (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- Saddle Your Worries (Sons Of The Pioneers) [unconfirmed] -- Cowboys And Indians (Sons Of The Pioneers) [unconfirmed] -- [Unidentified tune] (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- The Glendy Burk (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- Comin' Through The Rye (Karl Farr) -- El Rancho Grande ([Unidentified]) -- Comedy routine ([Unidentified]) (incomplete) -- Riding On The Sunshine Trail ([Unidentified]) [unconfirmed] -- [Unidentified tune] -- Froggie Went A Courtin' (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- All Because Of You (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- Cajun Stomp (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- Song Of The Bandit (Sons Of The Pioneers) (incomplete -- [Unidentified guitar tune] (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- Yellow Rose Of Santa Fe (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- My Bonnie Lies Over The Ocean (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- Outlaw Rag (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- Trail Herdin' Cowboy (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- You Ain't Heard Nothin' Til You Hear Him Roar (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- Cajun Stomp (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- Lone Coyote (Sons Of The Pioneers) [unconfirmed] -- Turkey In The Straw (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- Cherokee Strip (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- [Unidentified tune] (incomplete) -- Hickman Rag (Texas Troubadours) -- Don Juan (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- [Unidentified tune] (Dick Foran)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-0065_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-0065</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2017-09-21</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Sons of the Pioneers; Texas Troubadours; Foran, Dick, 1910-1979; Farr, Karl, 1909-1961; Farr, Hugh, 1903-1980; Nolan, Bob;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/5819</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>