<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Excerpt from Molle Mystery Theatre - 1944-01-25 ; Excerpt from the NBC War Bond Parade - Grand Ole Opry - 1944-02-05</dc:title>
<dc:description>Excerpt from the January 25, 1944 broadcast of Molle Mystery Theatre, episode 20 entitled The Thursday Turkey Murders, featuring Bernard Lenlow as Geoffrey Barnes. Excerpt from the February 5, 1944 broadcast of the NBC War Bond Parade on the Grand Ole Opry, featuring the Duke Of Paducah and Roy Acuff and His Smoky Mountain Boys. The NBC War Bond Parade has a correlating item in the archive located with call number TR000647.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Roy Acuff</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(0:00) [Blank] / (4:55) [Unidentified bird sounds and music] / (5:39) Geoffrey Barnes [played by Bernard Lenlow] advertises next week's episode of Molle Mystery Theatre [incomplete] / (7:02) [Unidentified announcer] talks [incomplete] / (7:11) Introduction for NBC's War Bond Parade in Nashville, TN featuring Duke Of Paducah and Roy Acuff / (7:33) Duke Of Paducah announces the opening statements / (7:58) Roy Acuff and His Smokey Mountain Boys perform "Wait For The Light To Shine" [incomplete]</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>10 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR003807_2</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>TR003807</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:isPartOf>TRB010_1</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-03-20</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Duke of Paducah, 1901-1986; NBC War Bond Parade (Radio program); Mystery theater (Radio program); Acuff, Roy, 1903-1992</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/7113</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>