<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>WSM Radio delayed broadcast of the Country Music Hall of Fame medallion ceremony - 2008-05-12.  Tape two of two.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Delayed broadcast by WSM radio of the Country Music Hall of Fame medallion ceremony with tributes and performances of the 2008 ceremony honoring Ernest V. "Pop" Stoneman and Emmylou Harris from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on May 12, 2008.  Delayed broadcast on WSM Radio.   Includes portions of the Eddie Stubbs radio show and numerous sponsored segments of the Grand Ole Opry from an unidentified date. </dc:description>
<dc:date>2008-05-12</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Eddie Stubbs; Kyle Young; Jim Lauderdale; The Jordanaires; Patsy Stoneman; Roni Stoneman; Patty Griffin; Buddy Miller; The Whites; Connie Smith; Brad Paisley; John Conlee; Keith Bilbrey; Mel McDaniel; Waddy Mitchell; Dierks Bentley; Hal Ketchum; Jimmy C. Newman;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Recording begins in progress.  (00:00) WSM weather break / (02:49) Kyle Young continues with the Stoneman segment / (03:50) Introduction of Jim Lauderdale and the Jordanaires who perform Are You Washed In The Blood? /  (10:12) Eddie Stubbs with WSM break-in / (11:15) Eddie Stubbs interviews Jim Lauderdale during post-ceremony festivities / (14:50) WSM announcements and commercial break in / (23:30) Kyle Young continues with the Stoneman segments / (25:44) Introduction of Francis Preston with official induction and medallion presentation / (29:30) Patsy Stoneman and Roni Stoneman acceptance (30:31) Comments and recognition of Stoneman family members /  (32:00) Eddie Stubbs with WSM break in / (41:06)  Patsy Stoneman medallion acceptance speech / (42:12) Kyle Young introduces the Medallion All Star band members / (43:02) Kyle Young introduces the Emmylou Harris segment / (49:18) Introduction of Patty Griffin and Buddy Miller who perform Love Hurts / </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(52:40) Eddie Stubbs with WSM break in and top of the hour news update from CBS network / (01:01:39) Kyle Young continues with the Emmylou Harris segment / (01:07:28) Eddie Stubbs with WSM break in / (01:08:37) Eddie Stubbs interviews Sharon, Cheryl and Buck White during the pre-ceremony festivities / (01:17:50) WSM break in / (01:24:39) Kyle Young continues with the Emmylou Harris segment / (01:25:58) Introduction of Sam Bush, Vince Gill, Patty Griffin, Buddy Miller and Jon Randall who perform Green Pastures / (01:29:18) Eddie Stubbs with WSM break in / (01:34:26) Kyle Young continues with the Emmylou Harris segment / (01:36:10) Eddie Stubbs interviews Emmylou Harris / (01:41:23) Kyle Young continues with the Harris segment / (01:42:37) Introduction of Charlie Louvin with official induction and medallion presentation / ( 01:45:18) Emmylou Harris acceptance speech / 02:01:25) Eddie Stubbs with WSM break / (02:05:03) CBS news break and local weather and WSM announcements / </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>RDAT digital tape;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source tape recorded at 48/16</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RS.2014.0125</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2017-10-12</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Stubbs, Eddie; Young, Kyle; Lauderdale, Jim; The Jordanaires (Musical group); Griffin, Patty; Miller, Buddy; White, Sharon; White, Buck; White, Cheryl; Smith, Connie; Paisley, Brad; Conlee, John; Bilbrey, Keith; McDaniel, Mel; Mitchell, Waddy; Bentley, Dierks; Ketchum, Hal; Newman, Jimmy C.; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/5987</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>