<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Alan Jackson Interview - Biff Collie</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of an interview with Alan Jackson (performer) conducted by Biff Collie. </dc:description>
<dc:creator>Alan Jackson; Biff Collie</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Alan Jackson expresses his appreciation for "Ace of Hearts" writers Carson Chamberlain, Ron Moore, and Lonnie Wilson -- (00:23) Jackson reflects on "Ace of Hearts" being the up-tempo song in the album to break from the large number of ballads -- (00:53) Collie has Jackson reflect on why he chose  "Here in the Real World" to be the title track -- (01:33) Collie introduces Jackson and Jackson gives his background information -- (02:35) Collie introduces "Blue Blooded Woman" and Jackson reflects on writing with Roger Murrah and Keith Stegall -- (03:28) Collie has Jackson pick a George Jones song, and Jackson chooses the Grand Tour -- (04:01) Collie introduces Jackson's album and Collie and Jackson reflect on Jackson growing up in Newnan, Georgia with his four sisters -- (05:20) Jackson tells that football is his favorite sport -- (05:55)  "Wanted" is reveal by Jackson to be inspired by a scene with John Wayne and a wanted poster -- (06:46)  "Chasin' That Neon Rainbow" is told by Collie as a track that reminds him of clubs; Jackson reveals  "Chasin' That Neon Rainbow" is based on his live performances -- (08:28) Jackson reflects on Vern Gosdin and the power of "If You're Gonna Do Me Wrong (Do It Right)" -- (08:55) Collie and Jackson express their delight in Gosdin's recent success -- (09:19) Collie and Jackson discuss how Jackson is the first country artist to sign with Arista Records -- (09:41) "She Don't Get the Blues" is revealed to be about a women who had her heart broken too many times -- (10:13) Jackson reveals his first public performance to probably be when he performed a play in church -- (11:34) Collie and Jackson discuss how Jackson moved to Nashville to pursue his musical career -- (12:08) Jackson recalls writing "I'd Love You All Over Again" for his wife -- (12:44) Collie has Jackson reflect on Hank Williams; Jackson reveals he did not know about Williams when he was younger -- (13:47) Collie introduces Jackson's album and Jackson reflects on why he chose to sing country over other genres -- (14:42)  "Dog River Blues" is discussed by Jackson to be about an actual river from his hometown -- (15:29) Collie and Jackson discuss how to remember Jackson's hometown Coweta -- (16:03) "Home" is reflected on as a story about his family after he moved to Nashville -- (17:19) Jackson and Collie discuss how Jackson originally would work on other people's band; Jackson would always perform "Rose Colored Glasses" -- (18:01) Collie has Jackson reflect on the support he has received from his wife -- (18:59)  "Short Sweet Ride" is a song revealed by Jackson to have not followed the original design -- (19:50) Collie questions Jackson's hosting history -- (20:34) Collie has Jackson say his goodbye statement </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1187_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1187</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-01-25</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Jackson, Alan; Jackson, Alan, 1957-; Jackson, Alan, 1958-; Collie, Biff;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8426</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>