<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Nashville Cats program - Joey Miskulin - 2018-04-14</dc:title>
<dc:description>Interview program on the life and career to date of Joey Miskulin from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on April 4, 2018.  Program moderated by Peter Cooper.  Includes recorded audio excerpts, audio from video and live performance.  </dc:description>
<dc:date>2018-04-14</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Joey Miskulin; Andy Reiss; Josh Hunt; Denis Solee; Roger Spencer; Ranger Doug Green; Fred LaBour; Woody Paul; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Walk-in music / (02:30)  Opening comments by Abi Tapia with introduction of Peter Cooper / (03:40) Peter with introduction of Joey Miskulin / (08:10) Opening comments from Joey / (08:32) Joey talks about the accordion / (10:25) Joey talks about Pee Wee King / (11:33) Talks about his performing background / (13:05) Talks about growing up and finding the accordion / (15:38) Talks about learning to play the instrument / (16:30) Talks about meeting Frank Yankovic and his influence on him / (18:48) Talks about missing high school playing music and still graduating / (20:44) Talks about learning to play with other musicians in both studio and live settings / (24:20) Talks about opening a nightclub in Cleveland Ohio and getting married / (26:34) Talks about his television show and Dottie West coming by when she lived in Ohio / (28:18) Plays video clip from the Polka Time USA / (30:28) Joey introduces the musicians seen in the video /                          </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(31:23) Mentions that Jerry Douglas watching the show / (31:40) Talks about Steve Popovich watching the show and getting his start in the record business / (34:44) Talks about Steve introducing Polka music to Cowboy Jack Clement and their friendship / (35:33) Cowboy Jack meets Joey and brings him to Nashville / (36:36) Talks about the Nashville music community and the accordion / (37:10) Talks about working with Johnny Cash / (38:16) More talk about Cowboy Jack / (40:27) Talks about recording in Memphis with rock group U2 on the Rattle and Hum project / (43:30) Plays video of Angel From Harlem from the Rattle and Hum video / (45:12) Talks about becoming Joey the Cowpolka King, meeting Vic Willis and starting to work with Fred "Too Slim" Labour and Riders In The Sky / (52:11) Plays video of Riders In The Sky performing Ghost Riders In The Sky and winning Toy Story 2 Grammy / (54:58) Joey talks about joining the Riders trio / (55:48) Joey talks about working with Shania Twain /                       </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/24;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0103</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2019-01-04</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Miskulin, Joey; Riders In The Sky (Musical group);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8420</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>