<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Hallmarks of Country Music - Mickey Gilley</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of an interview of Mickey Gilley (musician). The interview is hosted by Rick Phillips (army sergeant/ radio host) for the Hallmarks of Country Music segment. The tape was recorded on an unidentified date.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Mickey Gilley; Rick Phillips</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Promotion for Hallmarks of Country Music featuring Rick Phillips introducing Mickey Gilley -- (0:37) Hallmarks tune [featuring Rick Phillips introduction voiceover] ([Unidentified]) -- (01:11) Veteran's Association benefits radio spot hosted by Phillips -- (01:55) I Overlooked an Orchid (Mickey Gilley) -- (04:40) Phillips introduces Gilley and inquires about Gilley's 'over-night success' -- (06:56) San Antonio Rose (Mickey Gilley) -- (09:25) Re-enlistment commercial spot hosted by an unidentified host -- (10:30) Faded Love (Mickey Gilley) -- (12:05) Gilley reflects on ""Faded Love"" and ""San Antonio Rose;"" additionally, Gilley is asked to reflect on his time performing in the 1960s -- (15:30) Lonely Wine (Mickey Gilley) -- (17:34) Survivor's benefits of military families commercial spot hosted by Phillips -- (18:30) Turn Around (Mickey Gilley) -- (21:18) Gilley reveals he recorded ""Turn Around"" three times, and Phillips inquires as to when ""It's the End of the Line"" was recorded -- (23:32) It's the End of the Line (Mickey Gilley) -- (24:15) Phillips and Gilley both describe the change in Gilley's voice -- (24:49) Room Full of Roses (Mickey Gilley) -- (27:36) V. A. school benefits commercial spot hosted by Phillips -- (28:03) Veteran's Association commercial spot hosted by an unidentified host -- (28:33) Gilley reflects on when he first released ""Room Full of Roses"" -- (31:25) Don't be Angry (Mickey Gilley) -- (33:50) Red Cross commercial spot hosted by an unidentified host -- (35:00) I Love You So Much it Hurts Me (Mickey Gilley) -- (36:55) Gilley expresses his thanks to his audience, and Gilley reflects on his relationship to Jerry Lee Lewis -- (42:02) United States Customs commercial spot hosed by an unidentified host -- (42:56) City Lights (Mickey Gilley) -- (45:37) Gilley recaps ""City Lights"" and his future plans -- (48:36) Fraulein (Mickey Gilley) -- (51:26) Is it Wrong (Mickey Gilley) -- (53:20) Hallmarks outro tune [featuring Phillips outro voiceover] ([Unidentified]) -- (55:27) Phillips introduces the guest disk jockey, Paul Berlin, and both praise Gilley -- (58:24) Phillips and Berlin reflect on how KNUZ-KQUE was a country station</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Insert is of program information. The insert features time stamps.</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1630_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1630</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-06-12</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Gilley, Mickey; Phillips, Rick;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9083</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>