<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Performance - Outlaws and Armadillos exhibit opening concert - 2018-05-26</dc:title>
<dc:description>Concert performance from the CMA Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on May 26, 2018.  Hosted by Peter Cooper and Shooter Jennings. Performers include Bobby Bare, Jessi Colter, Shooter Jennings, Joe Ely, Michael Martin Murphey, Gary P. Nunn, Ray Wiley Hubbard, Waylon Pauyne, Kimmie Rhodes (appearing with Delbert McClinton), Billy Joe Shaver, Bobby Earl Smith, Tanya Tucker, Jason Boland, Jack Ingram, Jason Isbell, Jamey Johnson, Ashley Monroe, Elizabeth Cook, Amanda Shires and Colter Wall.  Band leaders Shooter Jenning and Dave Cobb.  In conjunction with the opening of the museum&#8217;s major exhibition Outlaws &amp; Armadillos: Country&#8217;s Roaring &#8217;70s.  </dc:description>
<dc:date>2018-05-26</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Bobby Bare; Jessi Colter; Shooter Jennings; Joe Ely; Michael Martin Murphey; Gary P. Nunn; Ray Wiley Hubbard; Waylon Payne; Kimmie Rhodes; Billy Joe Shaver; Bobby Earl Smith; Tanya Tucker; Jason Boland; Jack Ingram; Jason Isbell; Jamey Johnson; Ashley Monroe; Elizabeth Cook; Amanda Shires; Colter Wall; Dave Cobb;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Walk-in music / (08:46) Opening pre-recorded announcements to audience / (09:46) Walk-in music continues / (17:29) Opening pre-recorded announcements to audience over musicians warm up / (18:23) Walk-in continues with musician warm up / (19:36) Introduction of Shooter Jennings and Jamey Johnson / Performs Blue Yodel #1 [T for Texas] (Shooter Jennings and Jamey Johnson) / (24:18) Opening comments by Peter Cooper and introduction of Bobby Bare / (25:07) Bobby Bare with comments and introduction of next song / (26:17) Performs Marie Laveau (Bobby Bare) / (30:34) Peter talks about the concert and introduction of Billy Joe Shaver / (31:43) Performs Honky Tonk Heroes (Billy Joe Shaver) / (34:32) Billy Joe comments on Bobby Bare / (34:51) Performs Georgia On A Fast Train (Billy Joe Shaver) / (37:46) Peter introduces Amanda Shires / (38:27) Amanda with comments and introduction of next song / (40:05) Performs Star In My Heart (Amanda Shires) / (42:28) Amanda introduces Jason Isbell / (43:05) Jason with comments and introduces the next song / (43:42) Performs Pancho And Lefty (Jason Isbell) / (49:22) Peter with comments and introduces Colter Wall / (50:08) Performs Red Headed Stranger (Colton Wall) / (54:44) Peter introduces Jack Ingram / (55:33) Jack Ingram with comments / (56:11) Performs Desperados Waiting For A Train (Jack Ingram) / (01:01:44) Peter with comments and introduces Ashley Monroe and Waylon Payne / (01:02:35) Performs Help Me Make It Through The Night (Ashley Monroe with Waylon Payne) / (01:06:23) Peter introduces the house band consisting of Brian Allen-bass, Chris Powell-drums, Chris Hennesee-harmonica , Maureen Murphy-vocals, Kristen Rodgers-vocals, Amanda Shires-fiddle and vocals, Robbie Turner-pedal steel guitar, Chris Shiflett-guitar, Charlie Worsham-guitar, Jason Isbell-guitar and band leaders Shooter Jennings-keyboards and Dave Cobb-guitar / (01:07:33) Peter introduces Gary P. Nunn / (01:08:10) Gary comments and thanks the concert sponsors and introduces the next song / (01:08:57) Performs London Homesick Blues (Gary P. Nunn) / (01:14:20) Peter introduces Kimmie Rhodes and Delbert McClinton / (01:15:17) Performs Two More Bottles Of Wine (Kimmie Rhodes and Delbert McClinton) / (01:18:50) INTERMISSION with pre-recorded fill music / (01:32:18) Five minute warning / (01:40:09) Peter with welcome back comments and introduces Michael Martin Murphey / (01:41:08) Michael welcomes special people in the audience and introduces his co-vocalists / (01:43:18) Performs Cosmic Cowboy (Michael Martin Murphey) / (01:47:36) Michael with comments / (01:47:48) Peter introduces Bobby Earl Smith / (01:49:00) Bobby Earl with comments and introduces his co-performers / (01:50:01) Performs Contrabandistas (Bobby Earl Smith and Kimmie Rhodes) / (01:53:14) Peter with introduction of Ray Wiley Hubbard / (01:53:54) Ray introduces the next song / (01:56:50) Performs Up Against The Wall Redneck Mother (Ray Wylie Hubbard) / (02:00:29) Peter brings the house band back up / (02:01:12) Shooter Jennings with comments about Steve Young / (02:02:08) Performs Rock Salt And Nails (Shooter Jennings) / (02:06:50) Shooter introduces Tanya Tucker / (02:07:49) Tanya with comments and introduces her co-performers / (02:09:05) Performs Would You Lay With Me (In A Field Of Stone) (Tanya Tucker) / (02:12:03) Shooter introduces Jason Bolin / (02:12:20) Jason with comments / (02:12:35) Performs She Ain't Goin' Nowhere (Jason Bolin) / (02:16:28) Peter with introduction of Joe Ely/ (02:17:24) Performs I Had My Hopes Up High (Joe Ely) / (02:21:27) Performs Dallas (Joe Ely) / (02:25:50) Peter introduces Jamey Johnson / (02:26:40) Jamey talks off mic / (02:27:19) Jamey comments / (02:28:02) Performs You Asked Me Too (Jamey Johnson) / (02:32:11) Jamey thanks Robbie Turner for his performance on the song / (02:32:44) Performs Good Hearted Woman (Jamey Johnson) / (02:39:27) Shooter mentions Elizabeth Cook and introduces Jessi Colter and Jamey sings Happy Birthday to her / (02:40:05) Jessi comments and introduces the next song / (02:40:53) Performs I Ain't The One (Jessi Colter and Jamey Johnson) / (02:44:11) Jessi comments / (02:44:37) Shooter and Jessi with comments / (02:45:53) Performs I'm Not Lisa (Jessi Colter) / (02:49:20) Shooter introduces Elizabeth Cook / (02:49:45) Performs Why You Been Gone So Long (Jessi Colter with Elizabeth Cook and Shooter Jennings) / (02:53:42) Audience applause / (02:54:19) Walk-out music / (02:57:42) Walk-out music ends / (02:58:47) FILE END         </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0174</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2019-07-17</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Bare, Bobby; Colter, Jessi; Jennings, Shooter; Ely, Joe; Murphey, Michael Martin; Nunn, Gary P.; Hubbard, Ray Wiley; Payne, Waylon; Rhodes, Kimmie; McClinton, Delbert; Shaver, Billy Joe; Smith, Bobby Earl; Tucker, Tanya; Boland, Jason; Ingram, Jack; Isbell, Jason; Johnson, Jamey; Monroe, Ashley; Cook, Elizabeth; Shires, Amanda; Wall, Colter; Cobb, Dave; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9454</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>