<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Billy Sherrill  Interviewed by Bob Allen in 1982</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of Billy Sherrill being interviewed by Bob Allen. The interview takes place on 12-22-82. The beginning of the tape consists of Bob Allen speaking to Jim Flugg (Energy Action).            </dc:description>
<dc:date>1982-12-22</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Billy Sherrill </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Side One - (0:05) -- Bob Allen introduction of his purpose of interviewing Jim Flugg. Bob is writing a piece about the oil industry's expansion into coal. (0:48) -- Bob Allen asks Jim Flugg about the oil industry's control over the coal industry. (2:00) -- Tape cuts to Bob Allen interviewing Billy Sherrill. (2:19) -- Bob Allen asks Billy Sherrill about Pete Drake's steel guitar playing. (2:48) -- Billy Sherrill speaks about Kenny Malone, a well-known session drummer. Kenny Malone always wanted to know the lyrics before playing with a vocalist. (3:26) -- Billy Sherrill speaks about Pete Drake's performance on "Stand By Your Man" by Tammy Wynette. (5:25) -- Billy Sherrill about speaking with musicians about specific arrangements for tunes. (7:05) -- Billy Sherrill speaks about working with Tanya Tucker. (9:51) -- Bob Allen asks about "Behind Closed Doors" by Charlie Rich. (11:36) -- Bob Allen asks Billy Sherrill about Charlie Rich's decline. (12:40) -- Bob Allen asks Billy Sherrill about his decision not to work with Johnny Paycheck. (13:55) -- Bob Allen asks about the record "Take This Job And Shove It." Billy Sherrill discusses the phaser effect used on the bass part. (15:15) -- Bob Allen asks about the pop market in Nashville, TN. (17:47) -- Bob Allen asks Billy Sherrill about the recent marketing change in popular music. (18:01) -- "I know that if you do something unique, and if you do something good, it's going to sell." - Billy Sherrill. (19:20) -- Bob Allen asks Billy Sherrill about working with Tammy Wynette. Billy Sherrill mentions that their professional relationship ran out of steam. (21:52) -- Bob Allen asks Billy Sherrill about whether producing still excites him on a daily basis. (23:32) -- Bob Allen asks about the producing "tricks" Billy Sherrill used on "He Stopped Loving Her Today" by George Jones. (26:15) -- Tape cuts. (26:34) -- Bob Allen asks Billy Sherrill about his use of strings. (27:36) -- Billy Sherrill discusses tracking strings. (28:21) -- Bob Allen asks Billy Sherrill about recording vocals. (30:22) -- Bob Allen asks Billy Sherrill about his musical knowledge of strings. (31:08) -- Bob Allen asks Billy Sherrill about synthesizers. (33:26) -- Bob Allen asks Billy Sherrill about the band Queen. (34:07) -- Continued discussion of the pop market in 1982. (39:12) -- Billy Sherrill speaks about the songwriting trends in Nashville. (39:47) -- Bob Allen asks Billy Sherrill about his future producing plans. (40:59) -- Bob Allen asks Billy Sherrill about his retirement plans. (43:21) -- Billy Sherrill speaks about Charlie Rich's musical influences. (44:20) -- Bob Allen asks about the studio technology available to Billy Sherrill in the 1960's.</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>audio cassette, compact;</dc:format>
<dc:format>1.75 ips;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CAS4680_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>CAS4680</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-09-03</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Sherrill, Billy;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9473</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>