<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Hallmarks of Country Music - Conway Twitty</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of an interview of Conway Twitty (musician). The interview is hosted by Rick Phillips (army sergeant) for the Hallmarks of Country Music segment. The tape was recorded on an unidentified date.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Conway Twitty; Rick Phillips</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) There's a Honky Tonk Angel [Featuring Conway Twitty and unidentified voice voiceover introducing the Hallmarks of Country Music] (Conway Twitty) -- (00:22) Hallmark introduction tune ([Unidentified]) -- (00:34) Unidentified tune [featuring Rick Phillips voiceover] -- (01:01) Next in Line (Conway Twitty) -- (03:47) Rick Phillips asks Conway Twitty where his name came from -- (06:58) Commercial spot hosted by an unidentified voice -- (07:58) It's Only Make Believe (Conway Twitty) -- (10:04) Phillips and Twitty reflect on "It's Only Make Believe" -- (11:44) Image of Me (Conway Twitty) -- (14:33) Enlistment commercial spot hosted by an unidentified voice -- (15:12) Phillips invites Twitty to reflect on Harlan Howard's influence in Twitty's decision to become a recording artist -- (19:50) Polio shot commercial spot hosted by an unidentified voice -- (20:21) An unidentified voice introduces "Louisiana Woman, Mississippi Man" -- (20:30) Louisiana Woman, Mississippi Man (Conway Twitty and Loretta Lynn) -- (22:45) Phillips asks Twitty to reflect on Twitty's songwriting process -- (25:43) You've Never Been This Far Before (Conway Twitty) -- (28:34) Twitty recalls working on "You've Never Been This Far Before" in Nashville; additionally, Phillips inquires about Twitty's honorary status as Chieftain of the Choctaw Indians -- (31:16) How Much More Can She Stand (Conway Twitty) -- (34:06) Military Picture of the Year commercial spot hosted by an unidentified voice -- (35:05) Fifteen Years Ago (Conway Twitty) -- (38:02) Commercial spot hosted by an unidentified voice -- (38:33) Hello Darlin' (Conway Twitty) -- (40:55) Twitty discusses how he did not believe "Hello Darlin'" would be a hit; additionally, Phillips acquires about the music that Twitty listens to on the road -- (45:17) Goodbye Time (Conway Twitty) -- (48:11) Military commercial spot hosted by Tom T. Hall and an unidentified voice -- (49:04) I See the Want to in Your Eyes (Conway Twitty) -- (51:49) Phillips asks Twitty about his biggest thrill since joining country music; additionally, both say goodbye -- (53:37) Unidentified tune [featuring unidentified voiceover] ([Unidentified])</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1543_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1543</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-06-05</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Twitty, Conway; Phillips,Rick;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8976</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>