<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Johnny Lee Interview - Biff Collie</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of an interview with Johnny Lee (performer) conducted by Biff Collie. </dc:description>
<dc:date>1990-03-23</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Johnny Lee; Biff Collie</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Johnny Lee radio spot addressing his album New Directions and the Music City Album Review -- (00:13) Lee radio spot addressing his triple-platinum record; additionally, Lee addresses his album New Directions and the Music City Album Review -- (00:39) Lee addresses Biff Collie while introducing the commercial break as a disc jockey in a radio spot -- (00:50) Lee addresses the listeners when doing a Music City Album Review radio spot -- (01:00) Lee laughs and says, 'I love it' -- (01:05) Lee radio spot addresses the New Directions album -- (01:19) Lee radio spot predicting his album will bring Lee success -- (01:41) Lee radio spot addressing Collie and the Music City Album Review -- (01:52) Lee radio spot telling the audience to visit their local library to find his book as Collie laughs in the background -- (02:08) Lee reflects on being born in Texas City, Texas; as well as, his grandmother influencing his name after Johnnie Lee Wills -- (02:20) Lee addresses working on a dairy farm and how Santa Fe had changed its name -- (02:45) Lee recalls his first show, being a talent show, was sponsored by the Future Farmers of America -- (03:11) Collie and Lee reflect on the meaning of the name New Directions and how Lee had changed producers and recording companies -- (03:57) "You Can't Fly Like an Eagle" is discussed by Collie and Lee as a track with a huge message and Lee describes the emotional impact of the song -- (05:27) Lee reflects on the first time he heard "Cardboard Mansion" -- (05:49) Lee's first reaction to "I Can Be a Heartbreaker Too" led him to think that it was a song that expressed a rare message -- (06:42) Lee and Collie talk about the reason they named the album New Directions was because of the variation in song styles -- (08:18) "Cross My Heart" is described as a 'Johnny Lee Two-step' about love by Lee -- (09:07) Lee reflects on working on "Maybe I Won't Love You Anymore" when writer Gene Thomas had it snuck into the demo tapes -- (10:23) Lee reflects on his favorite line out of "Maybe I Won't Love You Anymore" -- (10:41) Collie and Lee discuss how Lee would frequent Gilley's and how "Looking for Love" gave him an opportunity to perform for a movie -- (12:31) Lee recalls working in a room filled with tapes, discovering "Looking for Love," and how the song came from a group of second-grade children -- (14:10) Collie brings up "The Anniversary Song" and Lee describes it as a song about his love for his wife -- (15:10) Lee recalls a time a man in the army sent him a post-card about "The Anniversary Song" -- (15:44) Lee describes the act of recording "Heart to Heart Talk" -- (16:43) Lee and Collie discuss seeing the Cornelius Brothers and Sister Rose live -- (16:57) Lee describes the feeling he had for "Treat Her Like a Lady" and Collie and Lee converse about how working at a club influenced Lee's variety -- (18:21) Lee and Collie discuss Sam Neely's contribution on "I'm Not Over You" -- (20:05) "By-Pass Row" is discussed by Lee and Collie as a real place that has a lot of backing from the fans and Lee's producer -- (22:00) Lee describes how his grandmother used to listen to Collie, and Collie and Lee reflect on how "Chew Tobacco Rag" was Lee's first song -- (22:52) Collie reveals to Lee that he is about to play "Chew Tobacco Rag" -- (23:08) Lee introduces the song "Chew Tobacco Rag" and reveals how it is the first time he had done so -- (23:28) "Anni" is revealed by Lee to be the first song he ever wrote to be produced by a large recording company -- (23:59) Lee reflects on working at the Palomino Club, where he met Anni, and how he tried to get Anni to record with him -- (26:29) Lee reflects on the Music City Album Review show -- (26:47) Lee asks Collie to remind the listeners about his book </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1183_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1183</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-01-24</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Lee, Johnny, 1946-; Collie, Biff;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8417</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>