<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum - Ralph Emery recorded song introductions - Nashville Skyline Jamboree - 2000-06-15</dc:title>
<dc:description>Country Music Hall of Fame radio personality Ralph Emery recorded song introductions to be played during intermission of the first annual Nashville Skyline Jamboree, which was held on June 15, 2000 in the parking lot of the music row Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum.  Recording made at RCA Studio B.  Date of recording is unidentified.  Songs introduced are not recorded on tape.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2000-06-15</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Ralph Emery;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Ralph Emery with welcome and introductory comments / (00:47) Introduction of Birmingham Bounce by Red Foley / (00:57) Welcome and introductory comments and introduction of Birmingham bounce take two / (02:04) Welcome and introductory comments and introduction of Birmingham bounce take three / (03:01) Introduction of Foggy Mountain Breakdown by Flatt and Scruggs / (03:35) Sign off / (04:18) Introduction of Moaning the Blues by Hank Williams / (04:44) Introduction of I Love You A Thousand Ways by Lefty Frizzell / (05:15) Introduction of Chattanooga Shoe Shine Boy by Red Foley / (05:52) Introduction of Salty Boogie by Little Jimmie Dickens / (06:28) Introduction of The Golden Rocket by Hank Snow / (06:58) Introduction of Slow Poke by Pee Wee King and the Golden West Cowboys / (07:26) Story of and introduction of Tennessee Waltz by Patti Page / (08:02) Introduction of Wildwood Flower by Hank Thompson / (08:35) Introduction of Why, Baby Why by Webb Pierce and Red Sovine / </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(09:07) Introduction of I'm A One Woman Man by Johnny Horton / (09:50) Introduction of Blue Suede Shoes by Carl Perkins / (10:27) Introduction of Any Old Time by Webb Pierce / (10:44) Introduction of You Are The One by Carl Smith / (11:10) Introduction of You Don't Know Me by Eddy Arnold / (11:51) Introduction of Honky Tonk Song by Webb Pierce / (12:12) Introduction of Dixie Fried by Carl Perkins / (12:39) Introduction of My Special Angel by Bobby Helms / (13:11) Introduction of Knee Deep In The Blues by Marty Robbins / (13:47) Introduction of Pick Me Up On Your Way Down by Charlie Walker / (14:18) Introduction of Cigarettes and Coffee Blues by Lefty Frizzell / (15:01) Introduction of Bird Dog by The Everly Brothers /  (15:30) Introduction of I Ain't Never by Webb Pierce / (16:00) Story and introduction of Walk On By by Leroy Van Dyke / (16:48) Introduction of Ring Of Fire by Johnny Cash / (17:30) Introduction of Six Days On The Road by Dave Dudley / </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>RDAT digital tape;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RS.2014.0166</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2018-01-26</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Emery, Ralph; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/6752</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>