<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Hank Snow Benefit at the Grand Ole Opry - Year 5 - Part 2</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of the Hank Snow Benefit Concert at the Grand Ole Opry. The segment is hosted by T. Tommy Cutrer (musician) and features performances by:  Merle Kilgore (musician), the Bama Band (musical group), and Hank Williams Jr. (musician). The recording is from an unidentified date. The tape is identified as the fifth year of the program. The tape is part two of three.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>The Bama Band; Hank Williams Jr.; Merle Kilgore</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:06) T. Tommy Cutrer reflects on what causes a delay I shows -- (00:49) The Wabash Cannonball (The Bama Band) -- (03:22) Hank Williams Junior [featuring T. Tommy Cutrer and Merle Kilgore voiceover] (Merle Kilgore) -- (05:15) Honky Tonkin' (Hank Williams Jr.) -- (07:12) Dixie on My Mind (Hank Williams Jr.) -- (09:56) La Grange (Hank Williams Jr.) -- (15:47) Old Habits (Hank Williams Jr.) -- (19:36) The South's Gonna Rattle Again (Hank Williams Jr.) -- (22:47) Leave Them Boys Alone (Hank Williams Jr.) -- (26:10) The Pressure is on (Hank Williams Jr.) -- (30:06) Blueberry Hill (Hank Williams Jr.) -- (30:56) Whole Lot of Shakin' Going on (Hank Williams Jr.) -- (33:33) Your Cheatin' Heart (Hank Williams Jr.) -- (36:05) Hi-Heel Sneakers (Hank Williams Jr.) -- (41:08) Midnight Rider (Hank Williams Jr.) -- (42:30) Dinosaur (Hank Williams Jr.) -- (43:13) The Coalition to Ban Coalitions (Hank Williams Jr.) -- (44:58) The American Dream (Hank Williams Jr.) -- (47:08) If Heaven Ain't Alot Like Dixie (Hank Williams Jr.) -- (49:05) Blues Man [incomplete] (Hank Williams Jr.)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1072_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1072</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-08-05</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Bama Band (Musical group); Williams, Hank, Jr., 1949-; Kilgore, Merle;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9308</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>