<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Various radio spots - WCMS</dc:title>
<dc:description>Various radio spots featuring Jack Blanchard, Misty Morgan, Tex Ritter, David Rogers, Murray Kellum, Johnny Mathis, Liz Anderson, Jean Shepard, Bobby Penn, Freddie Baker, Tommy Cash, Leroy Van Dyke, and the Kendalls, for radio station WCMS (Norfolk, Va.)</dc:description>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Jack Blanchard and Misty Morgan radio spot -- David Rogers What Time Is It? radio spot -- Murray Kellum What Time Is It? radio spot -- Johnny Mathis What Time Is It? radio spot -- Liz Anderson What Time Is It? Radio spot -- Jean Shepard What Time Is It? radio spot -- Jack Blanchard and Misty Morgan What Time Is It? radio spot -- Bobby Penn safe holiday driving radio spot -- Bobby Penn happy new year radio spot -- Tex Ritter safe holiday driving radio spot -- Tex Ritter happy mothers day radio spot -- Freddie Baker valentines day radio spot -- Freddie Baker safe driving radio spot -- Freddie Baker happy new year radio spot -- Leroy Van Dyke country music month radio spot -- Leroy Van Dyke CMA awards radio spot -- Tommy Cash CMA awards radio spot -- Tommy Cash country music Christmas radio spot -- Tex Ritter safe holiday driving radio spot -- Tex Ritter happy new year radio spot -- Tex Ritter country music Christmas radio spot -- Tex Ritter valentines day radio spot -- Tex Ritter happy mothers day radio spot -- Tex Ritter country music month radio spot -- Tex Ritter CMA awards radio spot -- Leroy Van Dyke safe holiday driving radio spot -- Leroy Van Dyke happy new year radio spot -- Leroy Van Dyke country music Christmas radio spot -- Leroy Van Dyke valentines day radio spot -- Leroy Van Dyke happy mothers day radio spot -- Leroy Van Dyke country music month radio spot -- Leroy Van Dyke CMA awards radio spot -- Leroy Van Dyke CMA awards radio spot -- Bobby Penn country music Christmas radio spot -- Bobby Penn valentines day radio spot -- Bobby Penn happy mothers day radio spot -- Freddie Baker safe holiday driving radio spot -- Freddie Baker happy new year radio spot -- Freddie Baker country music Christmas radio spot -- Freddie Baker valentines day radio spot -- Freddie Baker happy mothers day radio spot -- Tommy Cash safe holiday driving radio spot -- Tommy Cash happy new year radio spot -- Tommy Cash country music Christmas radio spot -- Tommy Cash valentines day radio spot -- Tommy Cash happy mothers day radio spot -- Tommy Cash country music month radio spot -- Tommy Cash CMA awards radio spot -- Tommy Cash CMA awards radio spot -- David Rogers safe holiday driving radio spot -- David Rogers happy new year radio spot -- David Rogers country music Christmas radio spot -- David Rogers valentines day radio spot -- David Rogers happy mothers day radio spot -- David Rogers country music month radio spot -- David Rogers CMA awards radio spot -- David Rogers CMA awards radio spot -- Murray Kellum safe holiday driving radio spot -- Murray Kellum happy new year radio spot -- Murray Kellum country music Christmas radio spot -- Murray Kellum valentines day radio spot -- Murray Kellum happy mothers day radio spot -- Murray Kellum country music month radio spot -- Murray Kellum CMA awards radio spot -- Murray Kellum CMA awards radio spot -- Johnny Mathis safe holiday driving radio spot -- Johnny Mathis happy new year radio spot -- Johnny Mathis country music Christmas radio spot -- Johnny Mathis valentines day radio spot -- Johnny Mathis happy mothers day radio spot -- Johnny Mathis country music month radio spot -- Johnny Mathis CMA awards radio spot -- Johnny Mathis CMA awards radio spot -- Liz Anderson safe holiday driving radio spot -- Liz Anderson happy new year radio spot -- Liz Anderson country music Christmas radio spot -- Liz Anderson valentines day radio spot -- Liz Anderson happy mothers day radio spot -- Liz Anderson country music month radio spot -- Liz Anderson CMA awards radio spot -- Liz Anderson CMA awards radio spot -- Jack Blanchard and Misty Morgan safe holiday driving radio spot -- Jack Blanchard and Misty Morgan happy new year radio spot -- Jack Blanchard and Misty Morgan Christmas radio spot -- Jack Blanchard and Misty Morgan valentines day radio spot -- Jack Blanchard and Misty Morgan happy mothers day radio spot -- Jack Blanchard and Misty Morgan country music month radio spot -- Jack Blanchard and Misty Morgan CMA awards radio spot -- Jack Blanchard and Misty Morgan CMA awards radio spot -- Kendalls safe holiday driving radio spot -- Kendalls happy new year radio spot -- Kendalls country music Christmas radio spot -- Kendalls valentines day radio spot -- Kendalls happy mothers day radio spot -- Kendalls country music month radio spot -- Kendalls CMA awards radio spot -- Kendalls CMA awards radio spot</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-7-01840_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-7-01840</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-11-27</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Blanchard, Jack; Morgan, Misty; Ritter, Tex, 1905-1974; Rogers, David, 1936-; Kellum, Murry; Mathis, Johnny; Anderson, Liz; Shepard, Jean, 1933-2016; Penn, Bobby; Cash, Tommy; Van Dyke, Leroy, 1929-; Kendalls (Musical group);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8249</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>