<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Chet Atkins Interviewed by Bob Allen in 1985 Side One</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of Bob Allen interviewing Chet Atkins. The recording takes place on 03-04-1985.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1985-03-04</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Chet Atkins</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Side One - (0:06) -- Bob Allen begins by asking Chet Atkins about his home studio. Chet responds that his studio is 24-track. (2:00) -- Chet Atkins further discusses his studio gear and equipment. (3:12) -- Bob Allen asks Chet Atkins what drum machine he currently owns. Chet mentions that he uses a LinnDrum. (4:54) -- Chet Atkins mentions he makes his own guitar pedals that he uses on other instruments. (6:04) -- Bob Allen asks about Chet's new album, "Stay Tuned." (7:42) -- Bob Allen asks Chet Atkins about his personal soundboard. (9:26) -- Chet Atkins discusses the origins of his home studio. (10:18) -- Chet Atkins discusses that he owned a reverb unit that came from a Hammond organ. The creator of the Hammond organ owned a patent for spring reverb until the 50's. (12:02) -- Bob Allen asks Chet Atkins whether he still owns anything from the old RCA studios. (14:30) -- Chet Atkins further discusses the equipment he's owned through the years. (16:36) -- Bob Allen asks Chet Atkins about his previous album to "Stay Tuned." (17:29) -- Bob Allen asks Chet Atkins about why he prefers recording with a 16-track. (18:20) -- Bob Allen asks how Chet Atkins records his guitar. Chet records through the soundboard. (19:14) -- Chet Atkins mentions that he is currently using a Peavey 130 Amplifier. (19:31) -- Chet Atkins discusses his preferred microphone arrangement when recording. (20:47) -- Chet mentions that he uses a Shure microphone for guitar. (22:04) -- Chet Atkins discusses recording with a plate microphone. (23:23) -- Chet Atkins mentions that he often uses a delay line to achieve the effect of tape echo on the guitar. (24:04) -- Bob Allen asks Chet Atkins about his personal practicing time in the studio. (27:10) -- Bob Allen asks whether Chet Atkins is currently interested in producing for others. </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>audio cassette, compact;</dc:format>
<dc:format>1.75 ips;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CAS4656_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>CAS4656</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-08-26</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Atkins, Chet;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9405</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>