<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Red Foley Show</dc:title>
<dc:description>Excerpt from radio program the Red Foley Show, featuring Red Foley (host/performer), Norma Jean (performer), Chet Atkins, (performer), the Tall Timber Boys (performers), Carl Smith (performer), and Cliff Carlisle (performer), date and episode number unknown.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Red Foley; Norma Jean; Chet Atkins; Tall Timber Boys; Carl Smith; Cliff Carlisle</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Opening statement and theme (Red Foley) -- (00:34) Tennessee Border (Red Foley) -- (02:27) Foley thanks the audiences -- (02:45) commercial -- (03:23) Foley introduces Norma Jean -- (03:34) It's A Little More Like Heaven (Norma Jean) -- (05:11) Foley thanks Norma and introduces Chet Atkins -- (05:31) Atkins talks with Foley and introduces the next tune -- (06:02) Tiger Rag (Chet Atkins electric guitar) -- (07:30) Foley thanks Atkins -- (07:40) Foggy River (Red Foley) -- (10:00) Foley thanks the audience, and introduces the Tall Timber Boys -- (10:28) This Little Girl Of Mine (Tall Timber Boys) -- (12:08) Foley talks and introduces Carl Smith -- (12:27) Smith and Foley talk and introduce the next tune -- (12:41) Loose Talk (Carl Smith) -- (15:00) Saturday Night Rag (Cliff Carlisle fiddle) [unconfirmed] -- (16:13) Foley thanks Cliff and introduces the next tune -- (16:30) Catch A Falling Star (Red Foley) -- (18:40) Closing statements and theme (Red Foley)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-7-01003_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-7-01003</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-01-29</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Red Foley show (Radio program); Foley, Red, 1910-1968; Jean, Norma; Atkins, Chet; Tall Timber Boys (Musical group); Smith, Carl, 1927-2010; Smith, Carl; Carlisle, Cliff, 1904-1983; </dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8435</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>