<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Chet Atkins Interview/Performance at Blair School of Music. </dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of Chet Atkins being interviewed and performing at The Blair School Of Music. </dc:description>
<dc:creator>Chet Atkins </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Side One - (0:10) -- Introduction of Chet Atkins by the dean of Blair School of Music. (2:45) -- Chet Atkins self-introduction to audience. Chet describes his family history. His father was a voice/piano teacher and piano tuner. His parents were divorced early on. (4:00) -- Chet Atkins speaks about his half-brother, who was a guitar player. (5:08) -- Chet Atkins speaks about learning ukulele at a young age before guitar. (5:50) -- Chet Atkins speaks on the difficulties of first learning the guitar at a young age. (6:24) -- Chet Atkins mentions that the first guitar player he heard was Karl Farr of The Sons of The Pioneers. (8:18) -- Chet Atkins describes his brother's first job in Nebraska playing on a radio station singing country music. (8:36) -- Chet Atkins describes his brother's work on the National Barn Dance. His brother met Rhubarb Red (Les Paul) there. (9:49) -- Chet Atkins mentions that Les Paul's guitar idol was Django Reinhardt. (10:23) -- Chet Atkins discusses working for the WLX Orchestra in Knoxville. "The boss of the show would let me play a solo, every other day or so" - Chet Atkins. (11:27) -- Chet Atkins discusses the difficulties of learning tunes and the guitar before method books were popularized. (11:48) -- Chet Atkins discusses the influence of Django Reinhardt's guitar playing. (12:29) -- Chet Atkins describes first hearing Merle Travis on his hand-built radio. (13:50) -- Chet Atkins mentions accidentally discovering his method of playing guitar like a stride piano player. Chet was trying to emulate Merle Travis, but ended up developing his own technique for solo guitar arrangements. (15:25) -- Chet Atkins speaks about his early success. "If you wonder why I've been successful, it's because I got there first." - Chet Atkins. (17:40) -- Chet Atkins introduces his daughter, Merle Atkins. (17:58) -- John Johns' introduction of Chet Atkins and Jim Fogelsong. (18:28) -- John Johns asks Chet Atkins about the first fiddle he owned. (19:10) -- Chet Atkins still owns his first fiddle. (19:42) -- Chet Atkins explains exactly when he first decided to become a guitar player. (21:06) -- Chet Atkins mentions a few guitar players from Kentucky that influenced him - Mose Rager, Ike Everly, and Kennedy Jones. Chet mentions that Mose Rager. (21:56) -- Chet Atkins tells a story about building a gymnasium at the age of 15 for NYA (National Youth Administration) in order to save enough money for an amplifier and guitar pickup. (23:05) -- Chet Atkins describes playing gigs without electricity. (23:55) -- John Johns asks Chet Atkins about his autobiography, "Country Gentleman", asks Chet to tell a story about his work on the radio. (26:08) -- Chet Atkins discusses making his first professional recording in 1945. (27:47) -- John Johns asks Chet Atkins about the layout of the first recording studios. (28:38) -- Chet Atkins discusses working with Steve Sholes. (29:02) -- Chet Atkins mentions Steve Sholes buying Elvis Presley's contract from Sun Records in 1955. Chet worked as Steve Sholes assistant at first. (30:48) -- Chet Atkins discusses how he was able to work in the music business and as a performer/arranger at the same time for over twenty years. (33:45) -- Chet Atkins speaks about how learning the melody to a song in fifteen different places on the guitar helped his arranging abilities. (34:30) -- "There's good music and melodies everywhere. It's in all the different areas of music." - Chet Atkins. (35:03) -- "The words in country music are more important than the melody, unfortunately. But once in a while somebody will write a song that has both - a great melody and great lyric." - Chet Atkins. (37:34) -- Chet Atkins speaks about Dolly Parton's songwriting. (40:15) -- Chet Atkins speaks about Jerry Reed's influence on his guitar playing. (41:18) -- Chet Atkins plays an instrumental written by Jerry Reed. (43:15) -- Chet Atkins plays a snippet of "Scarecrow."  (44:58) -- John Johns asks Chet Atkins when he first became interested in playing a 'classical' guitar, or nylon string guitar. (46:10) -- Chet Atkins discusses playing guitar for Segovia.
</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>audio cassette, compact;</dc:format>
<dc:format>1.75 ips;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CAS4670_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>CAS4670</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-08-28</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Atkins, Chet;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9447</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>