<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Highway 101 Interview - Biff Collie</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of an interview with Highway 101 (performance group) conducted by Biff Collie.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1990-04-12</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Highway 101; Biff Collie</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Biff Collie tells the Highway 101 group about the radio spots -- (00:57) Scott "Cactus" Moser and Curtis Stone introduce themselves as part of Music City Album Review radio spot -- (01:08) Collie and Moser discuss tweaking his radio spot -- (01:28) Moser and Stone introduce themselves as part of Music City Album Review radio spot  -- (01:38) Paint the Town album review messed up by Stone and  Moser and Stone introduce themselves as part of Music City Album Review radio spot -- (02:03) Moser miss speaks -- (02:06) Moser radio spot invitation to the Music City Album Review -- (02:14) Stone and Moser joke about the "Biffer" and introduce album in thirty minute radio spot -- (02:35) Moser and Stone  introduce album in hour radio spot -- (02:53) Moser misspeaks -- (03:00) Moser and Stone Music City Album review hour radio spot -- (03:10) Stone introduce themselves back from midway break for radio spot -- (03:18) Moser and Stone introduce album in Music City Album Review radio spot -- (03:38) Stone and Moser Music City Album Review radio spot -- (3:47) Stone and Moser thank the listeners in radio spot -- (03:58) Moser and Stone Music City Album review ninety minute radio spot -- (04:05) Moser asking if viewers want a big finish radio spot -- (04:11) Stone and Moser say they enjoy hosting in radio spot -- (04:27) Moser messes up first attempt so Moser and Stone present goodbye radio spot -- (04:47) Collie tells Moser and Stone how to be the host -- (05:11) "I Can't Love You Baby" is discussed by Moser regarding his drum intro and Stone discusses his solo -- (06:05) Stone tells about the first time the group got together in Denver, Colorado and Paulette Carlson joining through Chuck Morris -- (07:30) Moser and Stone talk about Chuck Morris' importance and success -- (09:09) Stone talks about the first time he talked to Carlson, sending her tapes to Minnesota, and meeting Moser in a club -- (10:35) "If Love Had a Heart" is discussed by Stone as the debate with Matraca Berg to the identity of the song -- (11:32) Collie Moser and Stone joke about who is Moser and Moser describes how he got the his love for drums through a childhood desire to hit -- (13:30) Moser tells that he got the same Cactus when he was playing in Rock bands while being from the country -- (14:20) Collie, Moser and Stone joke about being able to write and work in music -- (15:04) "While You Slept Last Night" is discussed by Moser and Stone and they address their friendship with song-write Pam Tillis -- (16:07) Moser talks about the decision making process behind every song to reach the album -- (16:40) Moser and Stone talks about "This Side of Goodbye" how there were mistakes on writing credits -- (17:30) Moser talks about being a writer at Warner Brothers and the relaxed feeling of work -- (18:22) Collie and Stone discuss Stone's past about Collie's familiarity of his family -- (18:52) Stone discusses about living in north Hollywood with his father Cliffie Stone and his father discovering Tennessee Ernie Ford -- (20:30) Stone jokes about getting upset at his father -- (21:14) Stone talks about Central Songs and the connections to music publishing -- (22:25) Stone talks about going to a Christmas show with Cash (Johnny) and Cash getting hit on the head -- (23:01) Collie talks about the first time he talked to Cliffie Stone while he was with Hank Williams and Stone talks about hearing Collie's name at home -- (24:40) Stone and Moser talk about "Walkin', Talkin', Cryin', Barely Beatin' Broken Heart" and working with a humorous Roger Miller on the music video -- (25:46) Moser talks about finding older songs from publishers noticing their underlying energy --  (27:03) "I'll Paint the Town" is discussed by Stone as Mark Brown coming to him and Stone being unsure if it was a country song and Moser talks about working with Gretchen Peters and the music community in whole -- (29:03) Collie and Moser discuss being both a writer and an artist and being able to step outside of emotional ties to songs -- (30:05) Stone talks about their numerous recordings in Nashville beyond their album -- (30:37) Collie and Stone talk about the dramatic change for the band from four years prior -- (31:57) Stone talks about his age and the variety of projects he had been in before success -- (32:45) Collie recalls a quote from Arnold about hit records -- (33:34) Stone calls "Rough and Tuble Heart" his favorite off the album and Stone, Moser and Collie reflect on Tillis -- (35:29) Collie addresses Larry Gatlin and Stone and Moser reflect on the intimidation of demoing songs -- (37:03) "Midnight Angel" and Carlson are reflected on as having jaded purity to her -- (40:06) Collie, Moser and Stone reflect on being a unit and removing personal attachments to success and Alabama's original spark -- (41:31) Stone talks about the change of styling when recording "Who's Lonely Now" and his hesitation while Moser discusses his instant love with the track -- (43:02) Collie, Stone and Moser talk about guitarist Jack Daniels, his first shows with Freddy Heart and visiting the Grand Ole Opry -- (44:27) Moser reflects on how people react to his and Daniel's names and Daniel's versatility -- (46:10) Moser reflects on getting James Taylor's "Sweet Baby James" to perform live -- (48:10) Stone and Moser reflect on the technical components on deciding to leaving the track natural -- (48:50) Stone and Moser discuss the breakup of Highway 101; or more correctly, the rumor that Highway 101 was breaking up -- (52:31) Collie talks about how Loretta Lynn about how she perceived the press -- (53:20) Moser, Stone and Collie say goodbye and Stone says he will tell his father hello for Collie </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1129_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1129</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-12-28</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Highway 101 (Musical group); Collie, Biff;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8328</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>