<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Artist in Residence - Jason Isbell - 2017-12-05</dc:title>
<dc:description>First of three Artist in Residence performances by Jason Isbell, along with Amanda Shires from the CMA Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on December 5, 2017. </dc:description>
<dc:date>2017-12-05</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Jason Isbell; Amanda Shires;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Walk-in music / (23:36) Opening comments and introduction of Jason Isbell and Amanda Shire by Peter Cooper / (29:51) Opening comments from Jason / (30:13) Performs Different Days (Jason with Amanda) / (34:58) Comments from Jason thanking Carter's Vintage Guitars and comments about previous artist in residence artists / (36:18) Performs 24 Frames (Jason and Amanda) / (39:34) Jason talks about the previously performed songs and about 24 Frames winning a Grammy award / (41:27) Introduces the next song / (42:14) Performs Traveling Alone (Jason and Amanda) / (47:16) Talks about coming up with the idea for the previous song, recording it and tells story about having dinner with John Prine / (50:00) Tells story about Bruce Springsteen singing the song Traveling Alone to him / (51:43) Performs Tour Of Duty (Jason and Amanda) / (55:24) Introduces the next song / (56:26) Performs Yvette (Jason and Amanda) / (01:02:05) Introduces the next song / (01:03:33) Performs Alabama Pines (Jason with Amanda) / (01:07:44) Performs Anxiety (Jason with Amanda) / (01:13:07) Talks about the previous song / (01:13:39) Talks about co-writing songs together and introduces the next song / (01:15:33) Performs Pale Fire (Amanda with Jason) / (01:19:00) Performs Something To Love (Jason and Amanda) / (01:22:57) Takes about the previous song / (01:23:27) Amanda talks about her attire and the photo shoot with their daughter / (01:24:44) Performs Speed Town Trap (Jason with Amanda) /  (01:29:45) Comments on tuning / (01:30:26) Performs If It Takes A Lifetime (Jason and Amanda) / (01:34:10) Talks about the rarity of performing as a duo / (01:35:13) Introduces the next song / (01:35:41) Performs Last Of My Kind (Jason and Amanda) / (01:41:14) Introduces the next song / (01:41:20) Performs Swimming (Amanda with Jason) / (01:44:31) Talks about the previous song / (01:44:47) Performs Elephant (Jason and Amanda) / (01:49:28) Performs Outfit (Jason and Amanda) / (01:54:23) Thanks the Country Music Hall of Fame / (01:54:49) Performs If We Were Vampires (Jason and Amanda) / (01:58:47) Closing comments by Jason / (01:58:54) Audience applause / (02:00:35) Crowd acknowledgement from Jason / (02:00:52) Jason talks about a friends comments about a sick bust out, hitting the note and bringing out the hose / (02:02:34) Performs Flagship (Jason and Amanda) / (02:07:46) Talks about the last song / (02:08:45) Closing comments / (02:08:54) Performs Cover Me Up (Jason and Amanda) / (02:14:32) Final comments by Jason / (02:14:57) Audience applause / (02:15:34) Walk-out (02:16:23) FILE END     </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0168</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2019-06-19</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Isbell, Jason; Shires, Amanda; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9270</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>