<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Grand Ole Opry  - 1987-06-13 - WSM</dc:title>
<dc:description>Excerpt from Grand Ole Opry Show from June 13, 1987 from 10:00-11:00. Featuring Jim Ed Brown (host, performer),  Hank Snow (performer), Skeeter Davis (performer), Justin Tubb (performer), and George Hamilton IV (performer) on radio station WSM (Nashville, Tenn.) According to tape case label, this segment features the last appearance of Howard Forrester on the Opry.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1987-06-13</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Jim Ed Brown; Hank Snow; Skeeter Davis; Justin Tubb; George Hamilton IV</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Test tones -- [Unidentified] talks -- Heil HVAC commercial ([Unidentified]) -- Jim Ed Brown talks -- Scarlet Ribbons (Jim Ed Brown) -- Closing statement (Jim Ed Brown and [Unidentified]) -- Sweet Sue chicken and dumplings jingle and commercial -- [Unidentified tune] -- [Unidentified] introduces Hank Snow -- Between Fire And Water (Hank Snow) -- Hank Snow talks -- Coca Cola jingle and commercial -- Hank Snow introduces Skeeter Davis -- Skeeter Davis talks -- My Last Date (With You) (Skeeter Davis) -- Silver Threads And Golden Needles (Skeeter Davis) -- The End Of The World (Skeeter Davis) -- [Unidentified] introduces Justin Tubb -- Justin Tubb talks -- Be Better To Your Baby (Justin Tubb) -- Coca Cola jingle and commercial -- [Unidentified] introduces Pat Travis -- Pat Travis talks about her book -- Hank Snow talks -- Hanks Snow introduces George Hamilton IV -- Hamilton talks -- Forever Young (George Hamilton IV) (incomplete)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-0120_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-0120</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2017-10-12</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); Grand ole opry (Radio program); Brown, Jim Ed, 1934-2015; Snow, Hank; Davis, Skeeter; Tubb, Justin; Hamilton, George, IV, 1937-; Forrester, Howdy, 1922-1987;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/5956</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>