<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Kentucky Headhunters Interview by Bob Allen Side One </dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of The Kentucky Headhunters being interviewed by Bob Allen.   </dc:description>
<dc:creator>Kentucky Headhunters </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Side One - (0:24) -- Richard Young of the Kentucky Headhunters speaks about putting the band together in 1986. (1:29) -- Richard Young describes writing songs for Acuff/Rose. (2:22) -- Richard Young mentions Greg Martin playing in a band with Doug Phelps. (3:28) -- Richard Young describes the evolution of the Kentucky Headhunters' songwriting. (6:43) -- Richard Young describes the chemistry between Greg Martin and Doug Phelps. (7:54) -- Richard Young describes what makes a band work together. (8:55) -- Bob Allen asks Richard Young about The Kentucky Headhunters' first album. (9:38) -- Richard Young mentions his friend Jonathan Lyle, a man who loaned The Kentucky Headhunters the money to record their first record. (10:50) -- Richard Young describes the Kentucky Headhunters' connections to Nashville's publishers. (12:22) -- Richard Young describes pitching music to a publishing company in Nashville in competition with another group pitching the same day. (16:31) -- Richard Young describes pitching the Kentucky Headhunters to Columbia and Airborne Records. (20:22) -- Richard Young describes signing the Kentucky Headhunters' first record deal. (21:40) -- Richard Young describes the struggles of Polygram Records. (25:50) -- Richard Young describes the main goal of The Kentucky Headhunters. (27:28) -- Bob Allen asks about the Kentucky Headhunters' new album. </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>audio cassette, compact;</dc:format>
<dc:format>1.75 ips;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CAS4671_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>CAS4671</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-08-29</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>The Kentucky Headhunters (Musical group);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9449</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>