<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Fan Fair Reunion Show - Tape 1</dc:title>
<dc:description>Tape 1 of 3. Recording of the 1980 Fan Fair Reunion Show.  Featuring Hugh Cherry (host), Joe Walker (personality), Joe Allison (host), Biff Collie (host), Smokey Dawson (performer), Patsy Montana (performer), Hardrock Gunter (performer), Tom Perryman (performer), Hank "Sugarfoot" Garland (performer), Laura Lee McBride (performer), Limmy Recard (performer), Lulu Belle and Scotty (performers), Syd Heartraider (performer).</dc:description>
<dc:date>1980-06-14</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Smoky Dawson; Patsy Montana; Hardrock Gunter; Tom Perryman; Hank "Sugarfoot" Garland; Laura Lee McBride; Jimmie Revard; Lulu Belle and Scotty; Syd Heartraider</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Opening tune [Unidentified] -- (00:22)Hugh Cherry (Host) introduces Miss Joe Walker -- (01:26) Joe Walker presents fan club awards to third place: Sue May, second place: Ann Macintire, and first prize to Kent Gordon -- (04:41) Hugh Cherry discusses industry influences and introduces Joe Allison (Record Producer) -- (06:52) Joe Allison greets crowd and introduces Patsy Montana -- (09:21) Patsy Montana greets crowd -- (10:15) Patsy Montana plays medley of her various songs -- (12:15) Joe Allison introduces Biff Collie -- (14:00) Biff Collie discusses country's multinational influence Smokey Dawson -- (15:32) Johnny Come Home (Smokey Dawson) -- (18:35) Biff Collie discusses first disk jokey gig and introduces Hardrock Gunter (Sidney Louie Gunter Jr.) -- (20:04) Don't Hold No Benefits For Me (Hardrock Gunter) -- (23:09) Biff Collie and Joe Allison introduce Tom Perryman -- (24:33) Tom Perryman discusses old school disk jockey recording standup -- (28:03) Biff Collie discusses and introduces Hank Sugarfoot Garland -- (29:59) Sugarfoot Rag (Hank Sugarfoot Garland) -- (31:44) [Unidentified] (Hank Sugarfoot Garland] -- (33:24) [Unidentified] (Hank Sugarfoot Garland] -- (33:44)Joe Allison discusses Hank Garland and Willie Nelson / introduces Laura Lee McBride -- (37:30) Learn to be a Slowpoke To [Unconfirmed] (Laura Lee McBride) -- (38:55) I Betcha' My Heart I Love You (Laura Lee McBride) -- (39:50) Joe Allison discusses the Texas Swing Band and introduce Jimmie Revard -- (41:15) [Unidentified] (Jimmie Revard) -- (43:54) Biff Collie discusses National Barn Dance radio spot and introduces Lulu Belle and Scotty -- (45:08) Mountain Dew (Lulu Belle and Scotty) -- (46:58) Scotty and Lulu Belle jokes to crowd -- (49:19) Remember Me (Lulu Belle and Scotty) -- (52:10) Have I Told You Lately That I Love You (Lulu Belle and Scotty) -- (55:08) Joe Allison introduces Syd Heartraider -- (55:45) Syd jokes and invites crowd to visit home -- (57:56) Mockingbird Breakdown (Syd Heartraider)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1106_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1106</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-12-13</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Dawson, Smoky; Montana, Patsy; Gunter, Hardrock, 1925-2013; Perryman, Tom; Garland, Hank, 1930-2004; McBride, Laura Lee, 1920-1989; Revard, Jimmie; Revard, Jimmie, 1909-1991; Lulu Belle and Scotty; Heartraider, Syd</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8289</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>