<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Opryland Music Demo Recordings - Y-87</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording is of a group of demo recordings from Opryland Music. Recordings are from an unknown date and recorded by a number of unknown bands. Tape is labeled Y-87. </dc:description>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Harold Horner's Boogie (H. Horner) -- (02:46) Heartaches and Pain (C. Cole) -- (05:56) How About You (C. Cole) -- (08:02) Then I'll Never Smile Again (R. Hendon and C. Sparks) -- (11:06) That's What Friends Will Do (W. Chandler) -- (13:03) Too Soon to Tell (C. Harris and W. Fleener) -- (16:06) Two Ruby Lips (J. Kuhn and W. S. Stevenson) -- (18:19) Tell Me (C. Belew, T. Blake, and W. S. Stevenson) -- (20:30) That's What I Like About My Baby (B. Flournoy) -- (21:40) Too Many Changes (G. Lukenbill and F. Renould) -- (23:38) Two Hearts (H. Glenn and J. Bradshaw) -- (25:03) 2-Rocka (H. Glenn, F. Smith, J. Bradshaw, and W.S. Masters) -- (25:59) Triflin Kind (B. Calvin and W. S. Stevenson) -- (27:45) Twilight Isle (H. Glenn and J. Bradshaw) -- (29:43) That's When My Life Began (B. Flournoy) -- (30:57) Take Me (H. Messai and J. Miller) -- (32:53) Forked Tongue (B. Hill and W. S. Stevenson) -- (34:11) From Out of the Blue (T. Coe and B. Sharp) -- (35:50) A Friend of the Bride (P. Pike and K. Alderman) -- (37:00) A Fork in the Road (B. Flournoy) -- (38:11) Fingerprints (D. Hecht and W. Fleener) -- (40:48) Forgotten (F. Wilson and R. Baker) -- (42:16) Farther Along (W. S. Stevenson) -- (45:02) Flowers For the Master's Bouquet (W. S. Stevenson) -- (47:55) Fool I Was (O. Ervin) -- (50:42) From Day to Day (D. Rose) -- (52:35) Fe Fo Wu Ti (S. Willet) -- (55:06) Get Ready, Get Set, and Then Go ([Unidentified]) -- (57:50) Enough Sun For the Rain ([Unidentified]) -- (1:00:44) Pandora's Box ([Unidentified]) -- (1:03:23) Summer Replacement ([Unidentified]) -- (1:05:58) Bubbles and Teardrops [Incomplete] ([Unidentified])</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1283_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1283</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-03-06</dcterms:created>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8594</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>