<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Various interviews - Grand Ole Opry</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of various interview questions for various Grand Ole Opry audience members on the topics of Waylon Jennings' drug use, country artists personal private lives, the Grand Ole Opry, and Webb Pierce's swimming pool venture, conducted by an unidentified female interviewer.</dc:description>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>[Unidentified] asks about Waylon Jennings drug use and artists being entitled to their personal lives -- [Unidentified] talks about being uninterested in artists personal lives, and enjoying them for their music -- [Unidentified] talks about artists not having influence on children -- [Unidentified] talks about everyone having a right to their own opinion and their own doing, it is up to parents to guide children not music artists -- [Unidentified] says personal lives is the artists own business -- [Unidentified]  says it does affect the children -- [Unidentified] says everyone's private life is their own business -- [Unidentified] talks about the Opry making the star rather than the stars making the Opry -- [Unidentified] says it is a mixture of both, and it has changed over time -- [Unidentified] says the Opry makes the star -- [Unidentified] says the Opry makes the star -- [Unidentified] talks about some bigger artists being just as popular as the Opry as a whole -- [Unidentified] talks about artists coming and going, but the Opry is always big -- [Unidentified] speculates on where country music is headed -- [Unidentified] talks about the younger generation of country music fans -- [Unidentified] says the stars make the Opry -- [Unidentified] talks about preferring the old style of country music over the new -- [Unidentified] said if he could he would live at the Opry -- [Unidentified] talks about how they would not pay to have their name inscribed at Webb Pierce's pool -- [Unidentified] says Webb Pierce's pool is a money making venture -- [Unidentified] says they would pay to have their name inscribed on the pool -- [Unidentified] agrees</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-7-04065_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-7-04065</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-07-30</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Grand Ole Opry House (Nashville, Tenn.); Grand ole opry (Radio program);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/7953</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>