<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Eddy Arnold donation ceremony - WSM radio coverage -2003-03-06</dc:title>
<dc:description>Eddy Arnold donation ceremony.  Held on March 6, 2003 in the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum as broadcast by WSM radio.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2003-03-06</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Eddy Arnold; Eddie Stubbs; Jack Clement; Bobby Bare; Shawn Camp; Suzy Bogguss; Billy Burnette; Jim Lauderdale; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Radio annoucements by Eddie Stubbs.  Includes audio from video.  Speakers include Kyle Young, Cowboy Jack Clement, Bill Denny, Brenda Lee, John Rumble, Tammy Genovese, Bill Purcell,  Eddy Arnold.  Performances include "Anytime" Suzy Bogguss --  "I'll Hold You In My Heart" Cowboy Jack Clement -- "You Don't Know Me" Shawn Camp -- "I Really Don't Want To Know" Bobby Bare --  "Cattle Call" Suzy Bogguss -- "Make The World Go Away" Jim Lauderdale  --  "The Tip Of My Fingers" Billy Burnette -- "When I Dream" Cowboy Jack Clement --  interviews conducted by Eddie Stubbs and Bill Cody with Eddy Arnold, Bobby Bare, Harold Bradley.</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>CD-R;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>PP0033</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2015-10-22</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Arnold, Eddy, 1918-2008; Bare, Bobby; Clement, Jack; Camp, Shawn; Bogguss, Suzy; Lauderdale, Jim; Burnette, Billy; Stubbs, Eddie;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/2524</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>