<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Ralph Stanley and the Clinch Mountain Boys performances - Tokyo, Japan - 1971-05</dc:title>
<dc:description>Performances of various tunes, as performed by Ralph Stanley and the Clinch Mountain Boys in May of 1971, recorded by an audience member, live in Tokyo, Japan, according to tape case.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1971-05</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Ralph Stanley; Clinch Mountain Boys</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>[Unidentified tune] -- Ralph Stanley talks and introduces the next tune -- Baby Girl (Ralph Stanley, Clinch Mountain Boys) -- Ralph Stanley talks -- [Unidentified fiddle tune] (incomplete) -- Orange Blossom Special ([Unidentified fiddle]) -- Ralph Stanley talks and introduces the next tune -- Louisville Kentucky (Ralph Stanley, Clinch Mountain Boys) -- Ralph Stanley talks and introduces the next tune -- Lost All My Money (But A Two Dollar Bill) [Ralph Stanley, Clinch Mountain Boys] -- Ralph Stanley talks and introduces the next tune -- Pretty Polly (Ralph Stanley, Clinch Mountain Boys) -- Ralph Stanley introduces the next tune -- [Unidentified fiddle tune] -- [Unidentified tune] (Ralph Stanley, Clinch Mountain Boys) (incomplete)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>3 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-5-00418_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-5-00418</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-11-01</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Clinch Mountain Boys; Stanley, Ralph;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8215</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>