<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Songwriter Session - Shawn Camp - 2017-08-26</dc:title>
<dc:description>Performance by songwriter Shawn Camp from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on August 26, 2017.  Includes questions from the audience.  Presented in support of the exhibit Loretta Lynn: Blue Kentucky Girl. </dc:description>
<dc:date>2017-08-26</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Shawn Camp; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Walk-in music / (02:34) Opening comments and introduction by Abi Tapia / (06:23) Opening comments by Shawn / (06:33) Performs unidentified song likely titled Already Sweet On You / (08:40) Talks about writing the song with Herb McCullough / (09:10) Song introduction / (11:00) Performs Two Pi&#241;a Coladas / (14:18) Song introduction / (14:29)  Performs How Long Gone / (17:00) Song introduction / (17:58) Performs River Of Love / (20:12) Song introduction / (21:01) Performs Would You Go With Me / (24:42) Song introduction and story about first working with Loretta Lynn / (28:33) Performs I'm Dying For Someone To Live For / (31:58) Answers question about who Cowboy Jack Clement was and what he meant / (35:14) Answers question about words or music coming first and what writing songs is like / (37:15) Answers question about what makes you get better as a writer and his favorite songs / (38:16) Answers question about writing with Loretta /</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(39:08) Answers question about hearing other artists singing his songs or wishing he had kept them for himself to sing / (40:26) Talks about Guy Clark and introduces the next song / (41:30) Performs Sis Draper / (45:21) Performs Magnolia Wind / (48:40) Song introduction / (49:16) Performs Live This Long / (52:40) Closing comments / (53:00) Walk-out music / (57:14) FILE END                </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/24;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0058</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2018-08-08</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Camp, Shawn; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8054</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>