<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>This Little Light of Mine Programs: Hoss Allen: The Radio Voice of Gospel Music - William Herbert Brewster: Gospel Songwriter</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of two segments of This Little Light of Mine. This Little Light of Mine is a show that provides introspection to the main influencers of African-American gospel.  The segments are hosted by Bobby Jones (host). The first segment reflects on the life of Hoss Allen (singer/songwriter), and is called "Hoss Allen: the Radio Voice of Black Gospel." The second segment is hosted by an unidentified host and features William Brewster (songwriter). The second segment is called, "William Herbert Brewster: Gospel Songwriter" The recordings are from unidentified dates.
</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Hoss Allen; William Herbert Brewster; Bobby Jones</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) This Little Light of Mine [featuring Bobby Jones voiceover] ([Unidentified]) -- (00:47) Hoss Allen performs a commercial spot -- (00:57) Bobby Jones reflects on the radio range of Allen -- (01:21) Unidentified harmonica tune ([Unidentified]) -- (01:54) Jones reflects on Allen's time on Early Morning Gospel Time -- (02:30) Allen reflects on the white audience the gospel channels had accrued -- (03:35) Unidentified harmonica tune ([Unidentified]) -- (04:19) Hey Good Lookin' (Hank Williams) -- (04:30) Allen reflects on 'rockabilly' -- (04:54) That's Alright (Elvis Presley) -- (05:24) Allen reflects on the rarity of black musical stations -- (06:00) Please, Please, Please (James Brown) -- (06:20) Allen reflects on how his show had to feature a majority of demo recordings -- (08:48) Jones discusses cosmetics; additionally, Allen discusses his program formula -- (10:59) Jones introduces Allen's segment on the commercial value of his program -- (14:12) Allen recalls how he grew up enjoying black gospel -- (14:58) This Little Light of Mine [featuring Hoss Allen voiceover] ([Unidentified]) -- (15:52) Unidentified guitar tune ([Unidentified]) -- (16:12) Allen discusses how he picked up slang over time -- (17:43) Allen jokes about how everyone asks about Allen's skin -- (18:23) Call it Stormy Monday [featuring Allen voiceover about the blues] (T-Bone Walker) -- (21:06) Unidentified tune (T-Bone Waler) -- (21:33) Allen reads a piece of mail sent to him -- (22:41) Unidentified gospel tune [featuring Allen voiceover] ([Unidentified]) -- (23:44) Jones reflects on Allen's contribution to the nurture of black gospel music -- (24:51) Allen reflects on how studio musicians have taken over the black gospel industry -- (26:17) Allen discusses how he met his goals in life -- (27:00) This Little Light of Mine [featuring Bobby Jones  outro voiceover] ([Unidentified]) -- (28:06) This Little Light of Mine [featuring Bobby Jones voiceover] ([Unidentified]) -- (28:43) Move Up a Little Higher (Mahalia Jackson) -- (29:12) Jones reflects on how Mahalia Jackson revolutionized gospel music with the help of William Brewster -- (30:11) Brewster reflects on how he tunes had genuine meaning -- (32:40)  Move Up a Little Higher (Mahalia Jackson) -- (35:40) Jones discusses the influence Jackson had on Brewster (36:05) Just Over the Hill (Clara Ward and Mahalia Jackson) -- (38:44) Jones introduces Brewster's segment discussing "Surely God is Able" -- (40:35) Surely God is Able (Ward Singers) -- (41:56) Jones introduces "The Old Landmark" -- (42:05) The Old Landmark (Ward Singers) -- (42:54) Jones introduces Jackson's rendition of "How I Got Over" that introduced Martin Luther King Jr. -- (43:11) How I Got Over (Mahalia Jackson) -- (45:16) Jones introduces "I'm Climbing Higher and Higher" -- (45:35) I'm Climbing Higher and Higher (Ward Singers) -- (46:39) Jones introduces Queen C. Anderson's singing influence -- (47:04) Brewster comments on the awe inspiring work Anderson performed -- (48:00) Jesus, the Perfect Answer (Queen C. Anderson) -- (50:19) [The tape significantly slows down] -- (50:43) I Can Hear the Angels ([Unidentified]) -- (52:49) Jones introduces "Lord I've Tried" -- (53:23) Lord I've Tried ([Unidentified]) -- (54:47)This Little Light of Mine [featuring Bobby Jones  outro voiceover] ([Unidentified])</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1540_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1540</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-06-03</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Allen, Hoss; Brewster,Herbert; Jones, Bobby;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8975</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>