<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Lorrie Morgan Interview - Biff Collie</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of an interview with Lorrie Morgan (performer) conducted by Biff Collie. </dc:description>
<dc:date>1990-01-24</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Lorrie Morgan; Biff Collie</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Lorrie Morgan says 'Probably good place to start' -- (00:03) Morgan address the fact that Leave the Light On is her first LP, recorded by RCA -- (00:33) Biff Collie introduces "Trainwreck of Emotion" and Morgan reflects on her desire to find up-tempo tracks when she was shown "Trainwreck of Emotion" by Jon Vezner and Alan Rhody -- (02:08) Morgan discusses the relationship of Vezner and Kathy Mattea -- (03:02) Morgan's first number one record "Out of Your Shoes" is described by Morgan as a twist to a tale never sung before -- (04:01) Morgan does into depth about "Out of Your Shoes" being about friends borrowing from each other -- (04:26) Collie asks about the album order and Morgan attests to not knowing how her song order was chosen -- (05:24) Collie and Morgan discuss "I'll Take the Memories," referring to the slow ballad as a projection of Morgan's idea of divorce -- (06:25) Morgan reveals how "I'll Take the Memories" has changed in her mind -- (06:38) Collie and Morgan discuss Morgan's late husband and the idea of songs being reflections of her late husband -- (07:32) Morgan recalls doing a demo of "Far Side of the Bed" while working at Acuff Rose and Collie and Morgan discuss the process of a demo track -- (09:00) Morgan discusses her father's (George Morgan) influence on establishing herself in Nashville while Morgan fought her 'father's-daughter' image -- (10:24) Collie recaps the Music City Album Review and introduces Morgan to introduce "Dear Me" -- (10:34) Morgan describes when she worked at Acuff Rose, and her recording "Dear Me" for Carson Whitsett and Buzz Aldrich -- (11:31) Morgan tells of how each record label prior had over looked "Dear Me" -- (12:33) Morgan gives her advice to new members of the music business -- (13:13) Morgan reflects on "Dear Me," "Far Side of the Bed," and "Leave the Light On" and their ability to resonate with consumers -- (14:15) Morgan touches on constructive criticism and recalls her being known as hard to work with -- (16:02) Morgan has difficulty describing "Five Minutes" and eventually Morgan discusses the difference in styling from a typical Morgan song -- (18:50) Morgan says "He Talks to Me" is her favorite and Morgan discusses her love of Mike Reid -- (19:37) Morgan reflects on Keith Whitley's influence on "He Talks to Me" -- (21:03) Morgan and Collie discuss how Whitley would communicate with Morgan almost daily -- (22:03) Morgan discusses the past artists who recorded "It's Too Late (To Love Me Now)" and reflects on her disconnect from its message -- (23:00) Morgan reaffirms how there is not a story behind why it was recorded -- (24:04) Collie and Morgan discuss the music industries influence on Morgan's children (Morgan and Jessie) -- (26:38) "Gonna Leave the Light On" is said to be a song that Morgan initially disliked, but recorded on behalf of Barry Beckett -- (29:01) Morgan and Collie reflect on Morgan's father's wishes and how she is the only singer of five siblings, but her brother Marty's talent in music is underappreciated -- (30:31) Morgan tells about her sister Candy not enjoying singing and Morgan and Collie reflect on her sisters name -- (31:05) Collie and Morgan discuss how Morgan had recently switched management and Morgan reflects on her excitement for the future -- (32:08) Collie and Morgan joke about Morgan's disc jockey career -- (32:27) Morgan expresses the end of the album (32:32) Morgan says her goodbye</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1180_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1180</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-01-23</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Morgan, Lorrie; Collie, Biff;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8413</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>