<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Interview - Paul Hemphill - 2005-09-17</dc:title>
<dc:description>Interview with author Paul Hemphill about his biography titled Lovesick Blues: The Life of Hank Williams from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on September 17, 2005.  Moderated by Jay Orr. </dc:description>
<dc:date>2005-09-17</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Paul Hemphill;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Recording begins in progress and on one channel until 01:01.  /  (00:00) Introduction of Paul Hemphill by Jay Orr / (03:20) Paul reads the prologue to the book / (20:19) Paul talks about his inspiration for writing the Hank book / (19:58) Oscar Davis working with Hank and story about Hank's drinking / (23:27) Confirming and dispelling stories on Hank / (26:17) Inspiration for writing the book / (28:30) Information and research used for the book and Don Helms /  (33:00) Hanks relationship with Fred Rose / (38:32) Hank's relationship with his alter ego Luke the Drifter / (39:44) Talks about the song I'm So Lonesome I Could Cry / (43:14) Talks about Hank's death and the myths and circumstances surrounding it / (51:49) Question from the audience regarding Lillie Stone and the writing of the song I Saw The Light / (55:02) Hank's continuing influence on current artists and Hemphill's style in writing this book /</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(57:03) Speculation on Hank's early music influences and the scene in Georgiana Alabama / (58:30) Talks about Rufus "Tee Tot" Payne / (01:01:30) Comments about attending the Grand Ole Opry and missing Hank Williams / (01:02:54) Final comments / PROGRAM END. </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>RDAT digital tape;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RS.2014.0137</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2017-11-08</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Hemphill, Paul, 1936-2009; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/6187</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>