<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Grand Ole Opry - Prince Albert - 1943-09-04 - Part 2</dc:title>
<dc:description>Part 2 of Prince Albert tobacco sponsored Grand Ole Opry segment from September 4, 1943. Featuring Louie Buck (announcer), George D. Hay (host), and performers Pee Wee King and his Golden West Cowboys, Ernest Tubb and his Texas Troubadours, Minnie Pearl, Curley Williams and his Georgia Peach Pickers with vocalist Jimmie Selph, Mac McGar, and fiddler Hal (likely Hal Smith, unconfirmed). Held at Ryman Auditorium, Nashville, TN.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1943-09-04</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Mac McGar; Ernest Tubb; Texas Troubadours; Curley Williams; Georgia Peach Pickers; Jimmie Selph</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Trudy Brown interviews service men -- Louie Buck talks -- George D. Hay introduces Mac McGar -- Soldier's Joy (Mac McGar) -- George D. Hay introduces Ernest Tubb -- You Nearly Lose Your Mind (Ernest Tubb and his Texas Troubadours) -- Prince Albert commercial (Louie Buck, George D. Hay) -- George D. Hay introduces Curley Williams and his Georgia Peach Pickers -- When The Sun Goes Down (Curley Williams and his Georgia Peach Pickers, Jimmie Selph vocals) -- George D. Hay introduces Hal [Smith?] -- Fire On The Mountain (Hal [Smith?]) -- George D. Hay talks -- Ida Red -- Closing statement (George D. Hay)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>16 inch glass-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR000058_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>TR000058</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2006-10-12</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); National Broadcasting Company; Grand ole opry (Radio program); Ryman Auditorium (Nashville, Tenn.); Buck, Louis, 1910-1971; Hay, George D. (George Dewey), 1895-1968; King, Pee Wee, 1914-2000; Golden West Cowboys (Musical group); Minnie Pearl; McGar, Mac; Tubb, Ernest, 1914-1984; Texas Troubadours; Paige, Tommy; Williams, Curley, 1913-1970; Georgia Peach Pickers (Musical group); Fowler, Wally; Smith, Hal, 1923-2008; Selph, Jimmy; Williams, Sanford (Musician)</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/985</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>