<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Various interviews - Biff Collie - 1982-12-04</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of interviews with Charlie Louvin (performer), Hank Snow (performer), and Charlie Walker (performer), conducted by Biff Collie on December 4, 1982.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1982-12-04</dc:date>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Charlie Louvin radio spots for Biff Collie -- Biff Collie microphone check -- Collie and Hank Snow talk and joke -- Biff Collie compliments Snow's vocal control -- Snow thanks Biff and talks about wondering if fans think his vocals have changed over the years -- Snow talks about the material he chooses to sing on the Grand Ole Opry -- Snow talks about Nova Scotia being pretty -- Snow talks about sailing the Atlantic Ocean as a cabin boy and his duties -- Snow talks about when he decided to pursue music -- Snow talks about the Country Music Hall of Fame being the greatest honor one could receive as an artist -- Snow talks about how he got a contract on his first record -- Snow talks about his record Lonesome Blue Yodel and how it was inspired by Jimmie Rodgers -- Snow talks about Ace Joseph, Cecil Landry, Steve Shoals, and Ernest Tubb being very memorable people in his life, just to name a few -- Snow talks about his Child Abuse Foundation (incomplete) -- Snow talks (incomplete) -- Snow talks about the Foundation finally coming together -- Snow talks about why he feel so strongly about ending child abuse -- Snow talks about all the programs created by his foundation -- Snow talks about his recording Moving On and that Biff provided a line for the song -- Charlie Walker does an introduction for Biff Collie -- Walker talks about wanting to pursue sports but then becoming inspired to make music -- Walker talks about early performances and how he'd get paid money via tips in a hat -- Walker talks about artists really make money for their traveling rather than their short performances -- Walker talks about being from Nevada and moving to Texas -- Walker talks about his first radio job -- Walker talks about Ernest Tubb being his biggest inspiration (incomplete)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-7-04044_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-7-04044</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-07-23</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Collie, Biff; Louvin, Charlie, 1927-2011; Snow, Hank; Walker, Charlie, 1926-2008;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/7937</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>