<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Hank Thompson Show (Office of Price Stabilization) - Programs 22 &amp; 23</dc:title>
<dc:description>Multiple recordings of the Hank Thompson radio show promoted by the Office of Price Stabilization. Labeled as program 22 and program 23. Original broadcast date unknown. Backed by his Brazos Valley Boys of Amos Hendrick on fiddle (presumably, not mentioned), Harold Lee "Curly" Chalker on steel guitar (mentioned) and Billy Stewart on bass and vocals (mentioned).</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Hank Thompson</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Humpty Dumpty Heart [featuring Hank Thompson voiceover] (Hank Thompson and His Brazos Valley Boys) -- (00:43) Whoa, Sailor (Hank Thompson and His Brazos Valley Boys)  -- (02:56) Thompson performs an Office of Price Stabilization commercial break -- (03:50) Waiting in the Lobby of Your Heart (Hank Thompson and His Brazos Valley Boys) -- (06:03) Give Me More, More, More of Your Kisses [featuring "Curley" Chalker vocals] (Hank Thompson and His Brazos Valley Boys) -- (08:33) Thompson performs an Office of Price Stabilization commercial break -- (09:19) In the Mood (Hank Thompson and His Brazos Valley Boys) -- (11:20) Could You Take Me Back Again? (Hank Thompson and His Brazos Valley Boys) -- (13:48) Humpty Dumpty Heart [featuring Hank Thompson voiceover] (Hank Thompson and His Brazos Valley Boys) -- (14:42) Humpty Dumpty Heart [featuring Hank Thompson voiceover] (Hank Thompson and His Brazos Valley Boys) -- (15:22) Humpty Dumpty Boogie (Hank Thompson and His Brazos Valley Boys) -- (17:58) Thompson performs an Office of Price Stabilization commercial break -- (19:07) All Those Things Money Can't Buy (Hank Thompson and His Brazos Valley Boys) -- (21:24) Anytime [featuring Billy Stewart Vocals] (Hank Thompson and His Brazos Valley Boys) -- (23:02) Thompson performs an Office of Price Stabilization commercial break -- (23:53) Bile Dem Cabbage Down (Hank Thompson and His Brazos Valley Boys) -- (25:53) John Henry (Hank Thompson and His Brazos Valley Boys) -- (28:16) Humpty Dumpty Heart [featuring Hank Thompson voiceover] (Hank Thompson and His Brazos Valley Boys)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1221_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1221</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-02-11</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Thompson, Hank;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8479</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>