<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>The Burch Sisters &amp; Marty Stuart Interviews - Biff Collie</dc:title>
<dc:description>Tape has multiple recordings. The first recording is of an interview with the Burch Sisters (performance group) conducted by Biff Collie. The second recording is of an interview with Marty Stuart (performer) conducted by Biff Collie. </dc:description>
<dc:date>1989-10-23</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Burch Sisters; Marty Stuart; Biff Collie</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) The Burch Sisters describe a song [unidentified] to be a dedication to men they want out of their lives, and Biff Collie has the Burch Sisters reflect on how they identify with their music -- (01:38) The Burch Sisters radio spot introducing "The Only Love You Need" -- (01:50) The Burch sisters discuss the talkative nature of their family, and Collie has the Burch Sisters reflect on where the musical aspirations came from -- (03:53) Cathy and Charlene Burch discuss love, and Collie asks if any of them are in love -- (05:00) The Burch Sisters reflect on their first music video -- (06:14) The Burch Sisters discuss their system of decision making; additionally, Collie introduces "Old Flame, New Fire" -- (06:50) Charlene recalls the time she was waiting for a train (That did not exist) -- (07:40) Cathy expresses her love for a Paulie, and Collie jokingly explains the direction the show is going -- (08:15) The Burch Sisters reflect on Larry Gatlin and "Cold Day in My Heart" -- (08:51) The Burch Sisters and Collie discuss how people reacted to "What Do Lonely People Do," and Collie introduces "What Do Lonely People Do" -- (10:13) The Burch Sisters discuss how they initially met their producer Doug Johnson -- (12:48) The Burch Sisters recall how Doug Johnson had written for a multitude of artists -- (13:48) Cathy recalls how a friend of hers enjoyed "Open Arms," and Collie has the group describe how "Open Arms" was written by Journey -- (15:41) The Burch Sisters reflect on how Johnson does not want the group influenced by who wrote a song -- (16:27) Marty Stuart reflects on the advice he received, and Ernest Tubb's (among others) influence on Stuart -- (17:27) Stuart reflects on working with Lester Flatt and Johnny Cash, and Stuart recalls being kicked out of school -- (19:47) Stuart jokingly describes the advice he got from an unidentified male -- (20:40) Collie has Stuart recall the story of the Great Revelator -- (21:18) Stuart describes how he decided to use "Hillbilly Rock," and Stuart describes Paul Kennerley -- (22:10) Stuart compares "Western Girls" to his unchanging audience -- (22:51) Collie introduces "Don't Leave Her Lonely Too Long," and Stuart reflects on writing with Kostas -- (24:27) Collie has Stuart describe how Flatt and Tubb would play poker -- (26:16) Collie and Stuart discuss how Stuart is a fan of country, and Stuart describes the first time he saw Tubb -- (27:45) Stuart describes the difficulties behind creating "The Coal Mine Blues" -- (28:26) Collie and Stuart jokingly discuss Stuart's inspirations for Hillbilly Rock -- (31:10) Stuart begins to explain a story about Merle Travis [incomplete] -- (31:17) Stuart describes  "The Wild One" as a song Richard Bennett brought to him by Tillman Franks and Merle Kilgore -- (32:17) Stuart and Collie discuss why Stuart gives credit to Jack Clement in his album -- (34:06) "Me and Billy the Kid" is described by Stuart to be a product of Stuart and Clement being in Dublin, Ireland -- (35:01) Collie and Stuart discuss the remaining thanks Stuart gives on the album -- (35:45) Collie praises Stuart's promise as a disc jockey, and Stuart reflects on how Johnny Cash would perform "Cry! Cry! Cry!" -- (38:55) Collie and Stuart discuss how Stuart's life changed drastically when he began at the Grand Ole Opry -- (40:03) Stuart describes his favorite song on the album, "When the Sun Goes Down" -- (41:40) Collie introduces Stuart and Hillbilly Rock, and Collie and Stuart discuss how Stuart has to give thanks to his manager via her nickname -- (42:35) Max T. Barnes is praised by Stuart -- (43:35)  "Easy to Love (Hard to Hold)" is described by Stuart as an example of what a hillbilly is -- (43:50) Stuart reflects on W.S. 'Fluke' Holland -- (44:58) Stuart associates "Since I Don't Have You" to his divorce -- (45:56) Stuart and Collie discuss the influence Cash and Flatt had on Stuart's show career -- (47:47) Collie has Stuart reflect on how the Maddox Brothers and Rose influenced his showmanship -- (50:09) Stuart recalls the story of how the Maddox Brothers and Rose decided to be country artists, and Collie recalls taking Fred Maddox to the radio station -- (54:24) Stuart attempts to describe the Maddox Brothers and Rose, and Stuart addresses the younger generation about entertainment</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1246_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1246</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-02-18</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Burch Sisters; Stuart, Marty; Collie, Biff;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8517</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>