<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Country Music History program - Volume 1 - Recording 1 - Side 1</dc:title>
<dc:description>Various voice overs by an unidentified male narrator. Subject matter pertains to the history of country music, and recording is likely linked to a country music history radio program, exhibit, or documentary. Tape is labeled as: volume one, recording one, side one.</dc:description>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) An unidentified speaker discusses the success of Jimmie Rodgers -- (00:30) T for Texas (Jimmie Rodgers) -- (03:40) An unidentified speaker introduces Ernest Tubb to reflect on Rodgers  -- (04:04) Last Thoughts (My Blue Bonnet Dream) (Jimmie Rodgers) -- (06:53) An unidentified speaker reflects on Gene Autry's start in country music during 1931 -- (07:08) Autry reflects on his first musical experience -- (07:27) Jimmie the Kid (Gene Autry) -- (10:09) An unidentified speaker discusses Ralph Peer discovering Rodgers and the Carter Family -- (10:40) Maybelle Carter reflects on how she was asked to make her first record -- (11:15) Worried Man Blues (Carter Family) -- (13:43) An unidentified speaker reflects on the market crash of the 1930's while introducing Pee Wee King -- (14:26) Pee Wee King reflects on the difficulty of earning money in the 1930's -- (14:36) Slow Poke (Pee Wee King) -- (17:26) An unidentified speaker introduces the Sons of the Pioneers -- (18:03) Cool Water (Pioneers) -- (19:56) An unidentified speaker reflects on the disasters of 1936 and Homer and Jethro -- (20:13) Homer and Jethro joke to each other -- (20:27) How Much is That Hound Dog in the Window (Homer and Jethro) -- (23:02) The History of Country Music (Unconfirmed) ([Unidentified])</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1434_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1434</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-04-30</dcterms:created>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8861</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>