<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Larry Boone Interview - Biff Collie</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of an interview with Larry Boone (performer) conducted by Biff Collie.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1990-01-10</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Larry Boone; Biff Collie</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Larry Boone's album Down That River Road is introduced by Biff Collie and discussed between him and Boone about the number of times it had been played back before release -- (00:57) "Everybody Wants To Be Hank Williams" is introduced by Collie and Boone discusses how he wrote it for Hank Williams Jr. with Paul Nelson -- (01:45) Boone talks about how it was produced quickly and the use of the scratch vocal track -- (02:17) Collie and Boone discuss Boone's favorite Vern Gosdin song "If You're Gonna Do Me Wrong (Do It Right)" -- (02:55) "Hard Time Taking The Easy Way Out" by Boone is discussed about how it was originally on hold multiple times before being able to record it -- (03:46) Collie wants Boone to recite a story about Boone going into the studio for an album and losing a good chunk of music to artists like George Strait -- (05:48) Boone talks about "I Know Who Drove Her There" written by Verlon Thompson and Wayland Holyfield and how he felt it could have been written by himself -- (06:52) Boone talks about being raised in Florida before moving to Nashville and working with Mary Tyler Moore Productions as a song writer -- (09:00) Boone talks about Faron Young and his track "Wine Me Up" and introduces "Step Aside" -- (09:20) Collie introduces Boone and Boone talks about being a baseball player in high school and being dared to sing in a variety show -- (11:01) Boone talks about playing college baseball at Florida Atlantic University before getting injured, after which, he began performing to pay his was through college -- (12:01) "Too Blue To Be True" is introduced along with a baseball pun -- (12:22) Boone discusses "Too Blue To Be True" is talked about as a song about loss of a women -- (12:52) Collie asks about Boone's writing style to which Boone responds with the evolution of songs from being over personal to being based on word play -- (14:35) Collie and Boone talk about Boone's interest in creative writing and original journalism major career path -- (16:48) "Best Performance By A Fool" writers Gene Nelson and Robert Byrne are talked about by Boone -- (17:30) Boone talks about having a variety between serious and comical songs -- (17:47) Collie radio spot about the halfway mark and Boone introduces John Conlee's "The Old School" -- (18:39) Collie compliments Boone's disc jockey work and Boone discusses working at the Blue Plate Special and dive bars on tips alone -- (21:13) "A Quarter At A Time" is talked about by Boone as a Paul Nelson vision and writing it on the road -- (22:21) Collie and Boone discuss the process of introducing new songs in live performances to gauge the response -- (23:14) Boone introduces a Merle Haggard song -- (23:35) "Gettin' Nowhere (Gettin' Over You)" is discussed by Boone as coming about through working with Mercury -- (24:35) Boone and Collie discuss his four track machine he purchased and getting help from Kathy Mattea -- (26:13) "Down That River Road" written by Buddy Cannon is discussed as a commercial song -- (27:05) Collie introduces Boone and Boone talks about new artist Garth Brooks -- (27:49) Collie and Boone talk about his substitute teaching career and the difficulties of being a substitute -- (28:53) "The Moon Over Georgia" is discussed by Boone as Mark Narmore's first song and Boone's reaction -- (30:02) Boone introduces "Hello Darlin" -- (30:16) Collie and Boone talk about "Crow Hill Road" starting out as a concept about a dirt road where he would hangout in their youth -- (31:35) Collie asks about where generations would hangout and Boone talks about growing up and what shapes a person -- (32:49) Collie recaps Boone's life, credits him as a disc jockey and Boone says goodbye</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1125_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1125</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-12-27</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Boone, Larry; Collie, Biff;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8319</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>