<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Grand Ole Opry - Prince Albert - 1956-10-20 - Part 2</dc:title>
<dc:description>Part 2 of Prince Albert tobacco sponsored Grand Ole Opry segment from October 20, 1956. Featuring Grant Turner (announcer), Carl Smith (host/performer - although George Morgan was advertised as the host for this week on the previous show), guest performer Benny Martin, and regular performers the Jordanaires, Dale Potter, Del Wood, Minnie Pearl, and Chet Atkins. Held at Ryman Auditorium, Nashville, TN.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1956-10-20</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Minnie Pearl; Benny Martin; Chet Atkins; Carl Smith</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Carl Smith introduces Minnie Pearl -- Comedy routine (Minnie Pearl, Carl Smith) -- Carl Smith introduces Benny Martin -- Whip-poor-will (Benny Martin) -- Carl Smith introduces Chet Atkins -- Hello My Baby (Chet Atkins) -- National Safety Council P.S.A. (Carl Smith) -- Wicked Lies (Carl Smith) -- Closing theme -- Closing statement (Carl Smith) -- Cavalier Cigarettes commercial -- Station announcements</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>16 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR000204</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2006-04-26</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); National Broadcasting Company; Grand ole opry (Radio program); Ryman Auditorium (Nashville, Tenn.); Turner, Grant; Minnie Pearl; Atkins, Chet; Wood, Del; Potter, Dale; Jordanaires (Musical group); Smith, Carl, 1927-2010; Martin, Benny</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/1162</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>