<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Sunday Down South - 1945-03-11 - Part 2</dc:title>
<dc:description>WSM program Sunday Down South, sponsored by Lion Oil. Originally broadcast 1945-03-11 at 5:00 pm, part 2. Personnel include Louie Buck (host), Ott Devine (announcer), Beasley Smith (conductor), the Lion Orchestra (performer) including Harold Johnson (violin), Danny Ryan (performer), Betty (Alcyone Beasley) and the Dixie Dons (performers), and Mac McGar (performer).</dc:description>
<dc:date>1945-03-11</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Beasley Smith; Lion Orchestra; Mac McGar; Danny Ryan; Alcyone Bate Beasley; Dixie Dons</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Lion Oil commercial (Louie Buck, Ott Devine) -- Louie Buck introduces Mac McGar -- China Boy (Mac McGar mandolin) -- Louie Buck introduces Danny Ryan and Betty and the Dixie Dons -- I Surrender Dear (Danny Ryan, Betty and the Dixie Dons) -- Louie Buck introduces the next piece -- Beale Street Blues (Beasley Smith and the Lion Orchestra) -- Lion Oil commercial (Ott Devine) -- Louie Buck and Danny Ryan talk about the year 1931 -- You Call It Madness (Danny Ryan) -- Louie Buck talks about information regarding the war -- Theme (Beasley Smith and the Lion Orchestra) -- Closing statement (Louie Buck)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>16 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR001279_2</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>TR001279</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2014-11-12</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); National Life &amp; Accident Insurance Company, Inc. (Nashville, Tenn.); Sunday down south (Radio program); Buck, Louis, 1910-1971; Devine, Ott, 1910-1994; Lion Orchestra (Musical group); Smith, Beasley; Ryan, Danny (Vocalist); Beasley, Alcyone; Dixie Dons (Musical group); Johnson, Harold (Musician); McGar, Mac</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/558</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>