<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Opryland Music Demo Recordings - Y-94</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording is of a group of demo recordings from Opryland Music. Recordings are from an unknown date and recorded by a number of unknown bands. Tape is labeled Y-94. </dc:description>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Blue You Gave to Me (E. Miller and W. Wilson) -- (01:30) Be Careful With Your Heart (E. Potter) -- (05:06) Beautiful City (R. Wynn) -- (07:56) Blue Eyed Darling  (O. Pierce) -- (10:35) Bartender Polka (J. Gilbertson) -- (12:59) Blue Heart (C. Harris) -- (15:13) Boppin' and Hoppin' (R. Rix and W. S. Stevenson) -- (16:50) Blue Jean Love (J. Kuhn) -- (18:31) Bluebird Over the Mountain (J. Kuhn) -- (20:31) Blue Was the Day (G. Owens and W. S. Stevenson) -- (22:05) Broken Heart Waltz (D. Richardson) -- (24:44) You're Free to Go (W. Blevins) -- (27:36) A Yodelin' Tune (S. Lundo) -- (30:09) You Better Hold Me (J. Reed and B. Geddins) -- (32:20) You are My Love (E. Gates, M. Hurley, and G. Love) -- (35:23) You Gotta Go Down (R. Baker) -- (37:27) You Got the Devil in You (J. Wilson) -- (40:32) I Can't Tell My Heart What to Do (E. Miller) -- (41:35) You're Gonna Sign on the Dotted Line (R. Golden and J. Hobson) -- (43:36) You Walked Away (G. Ricketts and W. S. Stevenson) -- (45:35) Yes, I Understand (C. Beam, C. Jiles, and W. S. Stevenson) -- (47:46) You Can't Know (R. Blackwell) -- (50:31) You Can't Buy Love With $$ Signs (E. Miller and W. S. Stevenson) -- (53:23) I Killed Her Love (Glen Castleberry) -- (56:27) It's Over (Ray Winn) -- (59:22) Hardly Worth Livin' at All (Les Emmerson) -- (1:01:30) Border Town Clown ([Unidentified]) -- (1:04:24) Jennifer Joy (Dick Monda)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1290_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1290</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-03-08</dcterms:created>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8612</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>