<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Hank Williams: Complete Works Volume 4</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of a number of performances of Hank Williams Sr. (singer/songwriter). Tape is part of a collection labeled Hank Williams: Complete Works. Tape is labeled as part four of eight. The tapes were donated from the M.G.M. Studios collection.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Hank Williams</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) I Saw the Light (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (02:49) Calling You (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (05:47) Dear Brother (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (08:34) Wealth Won't Save Your Soul (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (11:23) I'm Gonna Sing (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (13:18) A Message to My Mother (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (16:07) How Can You Refuse Him Now (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (18:59) When God Comes and Gathers His Jewels (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (21:51) Jesus Remembered Me (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (24:46) House of Gold (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (27:16) Thank God (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (29:35) The Angel of Death (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (32:21) I Just Told Mamma Goodbye (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (35:19) Never Again (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (38:03) I Can't Get You Off My Mind (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (40:56) Fly Trouble (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (43:44) Dear John (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (46:23) Let's Turn Back the Years (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (48:54) I'm Sorry For You My Friend (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (51:41) I'll be a Bachelor 'Til I Die (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (54:20) I Can't Escape From You (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (56:47) I'd Still Want You(Hank Williams Sr.) -- (59:50) My Love For You Has Turned to Hate (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (1:02:35) My Son Calls Another Man Daddy (Hank Williams Sr.)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1455_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1455</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-05-09</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Williams, Hank, 1923-1953; Williams, Hank, 1923-1953. I saw the light;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8966</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>