<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Saturday Night Camel Caravan: 1937-07-27 to 1939-10-28</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of the Saturday Night Camel Caravan, hosted by Ted Pierson (personality). The show featurings Benny Goodman (musician), Louis Armstrong (musician), the Benny Goodman Band (musical group), and the lynn Murray Choir (musical group). The recordings are from July 27, 1937 to October 28, 1939.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1939-10-28</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Louis Armstrong; Lynn Murray Choir; Benny Goodman; Benny Goodman Band</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Ted Pierson (unconfirmed) introduces the show and Camel Cigarettes -- (00:13) Unidentified tune [featuring Ted Pierson voiceover] (Benny Goodman and the Lynn Murray Choir) -- (01:00) Benny Goodman greets the crowd -- (01:24) Pierson (unconfirmed) introduces "Pick a Riff" -- (01:33) Pick a Riff (Unconfirmed) (Benny Goodman and the Lynn Murray Choir) -- (04:22) Pierson introduces "I Didn't Know What Time it Was" -- (04:45) I Didn't Know What Time it Was (Benny Goodman and the Lynn Murray Choir) -- (08:10) Pierson introduces George Bryan to perform a Camel Cigarettes commercial break -- (09:32) Louis Armstrong is introduces as Goodman praises Armstrong -- (10:11) Pierson reads off praises of Armstrong -- (10:37) Ain't Misbehavin (Benny Goodman, Louis Armstrong, and the Lynn Murray Choir) -- (13:17) Pierson praises Goodman's band -- (13:38) Moonlight Serenade (Benny Goodman and the Benny Goodman Band) -- (17:18) Goodman reflects on coming up with the name "AC DC Current" -- (17:36) AC DC Current (Benny Goodman and the Benny Goodman Band) -- (20:10) Pierson introduces Bryan to perform a Camel Cigarettes commercial break -- (21:01) Shadrack [featuring Ted Pierson voiceover] (Benny Goodman, Louis Armstrong and the Lynn Murray Choir) -- (24:38) King Porter Stomp (Benny Goodman and the Benny Goodman Band) -- (28:17) Unidentified tune [featuring Pierson and Bryan outro comments] (Benny Goodman and the Benny Goodman Band) -- (29:45) Prince Albert commercial spot hosted by an unidentified host -- (30:36) Ted Pierson (unconfirmed) introduces the show and Camel Cigarettes -- (30:46) Unidentified tune [featuring Ted Pierson voiceover] (Benny Goodman and the Benny Goodman Band) -- (31:34) Goodman and Pierson discuss the show -- (31:56) Unidentified tune (Benny Goodman and the Benny Goodman Band)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1804_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1804</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-07-15</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Goodman, Benny; Armstrong, Louis, 1901-1971;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9256</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>