<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Various record and radio excerpts</dc:title>
<dc:description>Various recordings of performances featuring R. Thompson (performer), J.J. Garrett (performer), V. Clements (performer), and Don Thorpe (performer), according to case label. These performers are featured on a disc recorded in Germany. Tape also features Roy Acuff (performer), Roy Duke (performer), Pete Pyle (performer), Clyde Moody (performer), Eddy Arnold (performer), Ernest Tubb (performer). All of these performances are from various dates, radio programs, and records.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Roy Acuff; Roy Duke; Pete Pyle; Clyde Moody; Eddy Arnold; Ernest Tubb</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Test tones -- Stealing The Blues (various) -- Black Mountain Rag (various) -- Great Speckled Bird (Roy Acuff) (incomplete) -- There Will Be A Bright Star After Every Dark Cloud (Roy Duke) [unconfirmed] -- You Wake Up Too Late (Roy Duke) [unconfirmed] -- Pete Pyle talks -- You've Broken Your Promise (Pete Pyle) -- [Unidentified talks] -- [Unidentified audio of train imitations] -- Mississippi River Blues (Clyde Moody) -- Meeting In The Air (Roy Acuff) (incomplete) -- Call On Me And Darling I'll Be There (Eddy Arnold) (incomplete) [unconfirmed] -- Born To Lose (Ernest Tubb)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-0041_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-0041</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2017-08-16</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Acuff, Roy, 1903-1992; Duke, Roy; Pyle, Pete; Moody, Clyde, 1915-1989; Arnold, Eddy, 1918-2008; Tubb, Ernest, 1914-1984;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/5533</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>