<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Tom Paxton in Concert - Tape 1</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of Tom Paxton (musician) live in concert. The tape is persummed to be have been recorded at Penn. State. The recording is from an unidentified date. Tape is labeled one of three.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Tom Paxton</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Paxton jokes with the crowd about his flight -- (02:09) Show Me a Pretty Little Number (Natural Girl for Me) (Tom Paxton) -- (04:25) Buy a Gun for Your Son (Tom Paxton) -- (07:12) The Last Thing on My Mind (Tom Paxton) -- (11:40) Georgie on the Freeway (Tom Paxton) -- (14:42) There's a Rumblin' in the Land (Tom Paxton) -- (17:23) Can't Help but Wondering When I'm Bound (Tom Paxton) -- (21:15) Unidentified tune (Tom Paxton) -- (23:58) My Dog's Bigger Than Your Dog (Tom Paxton) -- (25:44) Goodman, Schwerner and Chaney (Tom Paxton) -- (28:38) Beau John [incomplete] (Tom Paxton)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1481_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1481</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-05-21</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Paxton, Tom;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8899</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>