<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Chuck Wagon Gang Interview - Biff Collie</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of an interview with Chuck Wagon Gang (performance group) conducted by Biff Collie.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1982-06-15</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Chuck Wagon Gang; Biff Collie</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Biff Collie introduces the Chuck Wagon Gang as "Keep On The Sunny Side" (Chuck Wagon Gang) plays -- (00:41) We Are Climbing (Chuck Wagon Gang) -- (02:57) Collie introduces the Chuck Wagon Gang, himself, and commercial sponsor (West Texas Chevrolet Dealership) -- (03:14) Collie asks the Chuck Wagon Gang to tell their story -- (03:21) Roy Carter and Anna (Fie) Carter Gordon Davis tell about how Davis fell on their first performance and how Carter caught Davis -- (04:23) Collie asks to hear "Leyland Way" -- (04:32) Leyland Way (Chuck Wagon Gang) -- (06:46) Collie talks about the track "Echoes From the Burning Bush" and Pat McKee jokes about having great difficulty waking up -- (07:41) Echoes From the Burning Bush (Chuck Wagon Gang) -- (09:56) Collie compliments the group, Betty Godwin jokes, and Collie introduces the commercial sponsor (West Texas Chevrolet Dealership) -- (10:24) Collie gives the address to write to the Chuck Wagon Gang -- (10:43) Collie tells Carter about a letter and Carter introduces McKee to play "Church in the Wildwood" (11:13) Church in the Wildwood (Chuck Wagon Gang) -- ( 13:04) Collie gives an outre, saying goodbye, as the Chuck Wagon Gang plays a melody in the background [unidentified] </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1135_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1135</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-01-03</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Chuck Wagon Gang; Collie, Biff;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8334</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>