<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Country Music Hall of Fame Medallion Ceremony - 2004-05-02</dc:title>
<dc:description>Country Music Hall of Fame medallion ceremony held on May 2, 2004 from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum.  Inductees honored were Carl Smith and Floyd Cramer. </dc:description>
<dc:date>2004-05-02</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Carl Smith; Connie Smith; Jason Coleman; Hank Locklin; Maura O'Connell; Chuck Mead; Kix Brooks; Joe Nichols; Charlie Louvin; Melba Montgomery; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Recording begins in progress -- Fire exit announcement --  Introductory comments by Kyle Young -- introduction of Connie Smith -- Wait A Little Longer Please Jesus (Connie Smith) -- Introduction of Hall Of Fame members in attendance -- Introduction of CMF Board Members -- Introductions of VIP's -- Introduction of Bud Wendell -- Remarks by Bud Wendell -- Introduction of host Michael Gray -- Introduction of Jimmy Capps as Medallion band director -- On The Rebound (Dirk Johnson - piano) -- introductions of the All-Star Medallion band -- Introduction of Jason Coleman and Hank Locklin - Please Help Me, I'm Falling (Hank Locklin with Jason Coleman on piano) -- Introduction of Maura O'Connell -- Crazy (Maura O'Connell with Jason Coleman on piano) -- Last Date (Jason Coleman) -- Introduction of Brenda Lee -- Comments and presentation of Medallion to Floyd Cramer's family (Brenda Lee) -- Comments from Mary Cramer -- Introduction of Chuck Mead (Hey Joe!) -- Introduction of Kix Brooks -- Let Old Mother Nature Have Her Way (Kix Brooks with Carl Smith) -- Introduction of Joe Nichols - (When You Feel Like You&#8217;re in Love) Don&#8217;t Just Stand There (Joe Nichols) -- Are You Teasing Me (Charlie Louvin and Melba Montgomery) -- Introduction of Little Jimmie Dickens -- Comments and presentation of Medallion to Carl Smith (Little Jimmie Dickens) -- Comments (Carl Smith) -- Closing Comments (Kyle Young) -- Will The Circle Be Unbroken (Assembled Hall of Fame members and singers).</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>RDAT digital tape;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RS.2014.0045</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>R-DAT-0012</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2017-02-01</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Johnson, Dirk; Coleman, Jason; O'Connell, Maura; Mead, Chuck; Brooks, Kix; Nichols, Joe; Montgomery, Melba; Smith, Connie, 1941-; Locklin, Hank, 1918-2009; Louvin, Charlie, 1927-2011; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/4867</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>