<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Billy Sherrill Interviewed by Bob Allen in 1981 Side Two </dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of Bob Allen interviewing Billy Sherrill. The recording takes place on 11-13-81.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1981-11-13</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Billy Sherrill</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Side Two, Tape 1 of 2 - (0:20) -- Billy Sherrill discusses marriage and his personal religious beliefs. (3:57) -- Billy Sherrill discusses his variation on recording a waltz (3/4 time). (4:58) -- Billy Sherrill mentions recording with Jack Scott. (5:12) -- Bob Allen asks Billy Sherrill about trends in country music songwriting. (7:04) -- Billy Sherrill mentions that he usually produces an album in three days time. (10:35) -- Billy Sherrill mentions working with David Allan Coe. (11:58) -- Bob Allen asks Billy Sherrill about his professional relationship with his artists. Bob mentions that he's heard that Billy Sherrill treats his artists like family. (12:40) -- Bob Allen asks Billy Sherrill about Elvis Costello. (13:23) -- Billy Sherrill speaks about Elvis Costello contacting him about recording Billy's song "Too Far Gone." (15:26) -- Billy Sherrill speaks about Elvis Costello's appreciation for older country music such as George Jones and Lefty Frizzell. (16:48) -- Bob Allen and Billy Sherrill discuss Elvis Costello's stylistic differences. (18:55) -- Bob Allen asks Billy Sherrill about Hank Williams' influence. (21:02) -- Bob Allen asks Billy Sherrill what he looks for in new talent. (23:21) -- Bob Allen asks Billy Sherrill about whether an artist's appearance plays a role with their success. (24:20) -- Billy Sherrill suggests that an artist should reach out to a publishing company when pitching their music. (25:51) -- Bob Allen asks Billy Sherrill about various musical artists and his first reaction to their names. (26:41) -- Billy Sherrill discusses his first reaction to hearing country music. (28:17) -- Billy Sherrill discusses recording a duet with Johnny Cash and Ray Charles. (30:10) -- Billy Sherrill mentions that he hates yodeling except for "Cattle Call" by Eddy Arnold. (31:12) -- Billy Sherrill shares a story about Bob Dylan. (34:03) -- Bob Allen asks Billy Sherrill if he wants to become a rock music producer. "Nope." - Billy Sherrill (35:30) -- Bob Allen asks Billy Sherrill about the future of country music. </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>audio cassette, compact;</dc:format>
<dc:format>1.75 ips;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CAS4657_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>CAS4657</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-08-26</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Sherrill, Billy;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9411</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>