<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Charlie Douglas Interview of Emmylou Harris, Charlie Louvin, and Bill Ivey</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of an interview, hosted by Charlie Douglas (host), of Emmylou Harris (entertainer), Charlie Louvin (entertainer), and Bill Ivey (entertainer). The recording is for the Country Music Radio Network. The recording is from June 18, 1987.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1987-06-18</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Charlie Douglas; Emmylou Harris; Charlie Louvin; Bill Ivey</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) (Unidentified tune) [featuring Charlie Douglas voiceover] (Judds) -- (00:11) Charlie Douglas introduces Emmylou Harris, Charlie Louvin, and Bill Ivey to discuss Harris' appreciation for the Louvin Brothers -- (02:45) Douglas asks Louvin to react to how he felt when he heard his songs were being rerecorded -- (03:55) Douglas performs a commercial break sponsored by Fruehauf Trailers -- (04:52) Kyle Cantrell radio spot featuring the historical events of the day -- (05:38) My Heart [excerpt] [featuring Kyle Cantrell voiceover] (Ronnie Milsap) -- (05:55) When I Stop Dreaming (Louvin Brothers) -- (08:12) Douglas inquires about Ivey's collection of the Louvin Brothers' material -- (09:31) Douglas radio spot -- (09:40) An unidentified voice performs a cholesterol number commercial spot -- (10:39) Phil Randolph performs a weather synopsis -- (11:40) One Promise Too Late [featuring Reba McEntire voiceover for a trucking radio spot] (Reba McEntire) -- (12:39) Unidentified WSM tune ([Unidentified]) -- (13:08) Douglas inquires about Harris' continued interest in Alabama and music -- (14:39) Douglas and Harris discuss what led to Harris' musical interests -- (15:19) Douglas asks Louvin to recall why he chose to start his musical career -- (17:56) If I Could Only Win Your Love (Emmylou Harris) -- (20:26) Jackie Robinson commercial spot for Delo -- (21:25) An unidentified voice performs a Grand Ole Opry commercial spot -- (22:25) Douglas asks Louvin to recall where the Louvin Brothers began recording gospel music -- (24:31) Douglas inquires about Harris' work in gospel -- (26:51) They've Got the Church Outnumbered (Louvin Brothers) -- (29:02) Douglas asks Ivey about where the Louvin Brothers found "They've Got the Church Outnumbered" -- (29:36) An unidentified voice performs an educational commercial radio spot -- (30:36) Phil Randolph performs a sports synopsis -- (31:37) An unidentified voice performs a musical synopsis -- (32:39)   Unidentified WSM tune [featuring unidentified voiceover] ([Unidentified]) -- (33:07) Douglas inquires about the extent at which Harris had recorded Louvin Brothers tunes -- (34:41) You're Learning (Emmylou Harris) -- (37:24) Douglas inquires about Ivey's knowledge in producing Harris' album; additionally, Douglas asks Harris to reflect on how the group is promoting her album -- (41:02) Douglas asks Louvin to recall the original recording of "You'll Forget" -- (41:51) You'll Forget (Louvin Brothers) -- (44:21) An unidentified group of voices perform an Opryland commercial radio spot -- (45:18) Every Time You Leave (Emmylou Harris) -- (48:06) Douglas asks Ivey to provide the information on how to order Harris' album; additionally, Douglas says goodbye to his guests -- (49:07) An unidentified voice hosts a Motor Vehicle Association commercial spot -- (50:08) An unidentified voice performs a WSM radio spot</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1487_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1487</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-05-22</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Douglas, Charlie; Harris, Emmylou; Louvin, Charlie; Louvin, Charlie, 1927-2011; Ivey, Bill;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8924</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>