<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Roy Acuff Grand Ole Opry Discs: Tape 6</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of Roy Acuff's Royal Crown Cola sponsored Grand Ole Opry. The tape is labeled Acuff's tape number six of an unidentified number. The tape features multiple recordings. The additional recordings are sponsored by Kahn Weatherhouse and American Ace Coffee. The recording features performances by: Roy Acuff (musician), the Smokey Mountain Boys (musical group), Oswald and Racheal (musical duo), Tommy Magness (musician), B, and Jimmie Riddle (musician). The tape is from a multitude of dates from: January 31, 1948; February 07, 1948; and February 21, 1948.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1948-02-21</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Roy Acuff; Smokey Mountain Boys; Oswald and Racheal; Tommy Magness; Jimmie Riddle</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:07) Wait For the Light to Shine (Roy Acuff and the Smokey Mountain Band) -- (02:14) Tennessee Wagner (Roy Acuff and the Smokey Mountain Band) -- (03:10) Rose of My Heart (Roy Acuff and the Smokey Mountain Band) -- (06:36) Roll on Buddy, Roll on (Oswald and Racheal) -- (07:51) Were You There When They Crucified My Lord (Roy Acuff and the Smokey Mountain Band) -- (10:59) Blackberry Blossom (Tommy Magness) -- (12:05) The Great Speckled Bird (Roy Acuff and the Smokey Mountain Band) -- (14:21) Where Could I Go, but to the Lord (Roy Acuff and the Smokey Mountain Band) -- (17:00) Twelfth Street Rag (Jimmie Riddle) -- (18:21) This World Can't Stand Long (Roy Acuff and the Smokey Mountain Band) -- (20:40) Cotton Eyed Joe (Tommy Magness) -- (21:47) The Pale Horse and His Rider (Roy Acuff and the Smokey Mountain Band) -- (24:45) Will the Circle be Unbroken (Roy Acuff and the Smokey Mountain Band) -- (27:40) Acuff reads the poem: 'I Takes a Heap of Living in a House to Make a Home' -- (29:54) Grey Eagle [drops out] (Tommy Magness)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-0986_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-0986</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-09-16</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Acuff, Roy; Smoky Mountain Boys; Oswald and Racheal; Magness, Tommy; Riddle, Jimmy, 1918-1982;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9608</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>