<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Jerry Zolten Phone Interview of Pete Seeger - 1974 - Tape 1</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of a phone interview between Pete Seeger (singer/social activist) and Jerry Zolten (host/writer/producer). The tape is the first of two from an unidentified date in 1974.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1974</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Jerry Zolten; Pete Seeger</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Pete Seeger and Jerry Zolten discuss Reprints From People's Songs; additionally, Seeger describes the type of man Irwin Silber is -- (06:46) Seeger describes how the new songs he performs are about the working-class struggles, and Seeger describes what a 'hootenanny' is -- (11:11) Zolten a Seeger describe what "Pretty Boy Floyd," among other songs, past controversies were -- (13:28) Zolten recalls the first time he heard Seeger's name associated to communism; additionally, Seeger reflects on the various communist studies he performed -- (22:45) Seeger and Zolten reflect on the amount of musicians who perform without proper musical knowledge -- (25:31) Seeger admits that his work with the Hudson River has led to health issues -- (27:13) Zolten inquires as to how he may communicate with Seeger; as well as, both reflect on the various formats of audio exchange</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1492_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1492</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-05-24</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Zolten, Jerry; Seeger, Pete, 1919-2014;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8902</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>