<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Nashville Record Review Artist Interviews 1982 - A</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recordings of phone interviews with various artists hosted by Al Rosen. Recording features: Roseanne Cash, Juice Newton, Charley Pride, T. G. Sheppard, Ed Bruce, Bill Golden, Tom Wright, and Lee Greenwood. Item is listed as part A of the 1982  Nashville Radio Review artist interviews.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1982</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Al Risen</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Al Risen and Randy Parton discuss Parton's past profession, and Parton discusses his family's influence -- (01:09) Parton discusses why he chose to record "Oh No," and Risen and Parton discuss who influenced Parton's musical career -- (02:13) Parton reflects on how he chooses his music career over a career in television -- (02:46) Risen radio spot introducing "Oh No" -- (02:51) Risen introduces Sylvia, and Sylvia discusses how he had been spending all night recording her album -- (03:28) Sylvia reflects on her upcoming ventures -- (04:32) Sylvia and Risen reflect on the writers of "Sweet Yesterday" -- (05:15) Sylvia discusses her upcoming tour with the Oak Ridge Boys -- (05:53) Risen radio spot introduction for "Drifter" -- (05:56) Risen introduces David Allen Coe, and Coe discusses what his current projects are -- (08:02) Coe and Risen reflect on why Risen chose to live in Key West, Florida instead of Nashville, Tennessee -- (08:42) Coe describes how he came to record "Now Lay Me Down to Cheat" -- (09:23) Risen radio spot introducing "Now Lay Me Down to Cheat" -- (09:30) Risen introduces T. G. Sheppard, and Sheppard reflects on his recent television work -- (10:19) Sheppard and Risen discuss Sheppard's racing interests -- (11:50) Risen and Sheppard reflect on the importance of Fan Fair -- (12:19) Sheppard and Risen reflect on the creation of "Finally," and Sheppard's new album -- (13:35) Risen radio spot introduction to "Finally" -- (13:41) Risen introduces Ronnie McDowell, and McDowell reveals that he had worked on a music video recently -- (14:48) McDowell reflects on his restaurant ventures -- (15:35) McDowell discusses how "Step Back" has been labeled under different genres -- (16:12) Risen and McDowell reflect on the number of songs Risen receives -- (17:26) McDowell's producer, Buddy Killen, is joked about -- (17:56) Risen radio spot introducing "Finally" -- (18:01) Risen introduces Sheppard, and both discuss how he had just returned from Missouri -- (18:37) Sheppard discusses his time on the Today Show -- (19:49) Sheppard reflects on talking to the writers of "War is Hell" -- (21:34) Sheppard reveals his upcoming schedule -- (22:23) Risen radio spot introducing "War is Hell" -- (22:29) Risen introduces Steve Wariner, and both discuss the delays associated with his Wariner's new album -- (23:19) Wariner discusses contributing to the new Chet Atkins album and the upcoming Christmas album -- (24:29) Risen radio spot introducing "Your Memory" -- (24:34) Risen introduces Jeff Cook who discusses Alabama's upcoming album; additionally, Cook discusses the additional staff required to screen music -- (25:28) Cook reveals Alabama's new Christmas song, and Cook and Risen discuss Cook's aspirations to be a saxophone artist -- (26:07) Risen and Cook discuss Cook's new studio aspirations -- (26:24) Risen and Cook reflect on why Alabama chose to record "Close Enough to Perfect," and Cook discusses his free time -- (27:49) Risen radio spot introducing "Close Enough to Perfect -- (27:54) Risen introduces Sylvia, and both discuss the preparation required for the Country Music Association Awards -- (29:24) Sylvia reflects on her recent scheduling issues -- (30:22) Why Sylvia chose "Like Nothing Ever Happened" is discussed -- (31:35) Risen radio spot introducing "Like Nothing Ever Happened"</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1253_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1253</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-02-20</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Risen, Al; Cash, Rosanne; Newton, Juice; Pride, Charley; Pride, Charley, 1938-; Sheppard, T. G.; Bruce, Ed; Golden, William Lee; Wright, Thomas; Greenwood, Lee;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8534</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>