<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Country Music Hall of Fame Medallion Ceremony - 2006-04-07 - DeFord Bailey, Glen Campbell, Alabama</dc:title>
<dc:description>Country Music Hall of Fame medallion ceremony as broadcast by WSM, April 7, 2006, at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum's Ford Theater. Inductees DeFord Bailey, Glen Campbell, and Alabama.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2006-04-07</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Vince Gill; Joe Filisko; DeFord Bailey Jr.; Charlie McCoy; Carlos Bailey; Jamie Hartford; Shawn Camp; John D. Loudermilk; Glen Campbell; Lonestar; Hobie Hubbard; Shane Hill; Mark Miller; Kenny Chesney</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Intro remarks by Bud Wendell  --  What Are They Doing In Heaven (Vince Gill) --  Kyle Young comments and DeFord Bailey segment  --  WSM Radio Station break and ID --  DeFord Bailey segment  --  Fox Chase (Joe Filisko harmonica)  -- Swing Low, Sweet Chariot (DeFord Bailey Jr.)  --  intro of medallion all-star band  --  Pan American Blues (Charlie McCoy)  --  The Legend Of DeFord Bailey (Carlos Bailey, DeFord Bailey Jr.)  --  WSM Radio Station break and ID  --  Bud Wendell presents medallion accepted by DeFord Bailey's daughter  --  Kyle Young intros Glen Campbell segment  --  Gentle On My Mind (Jamie Hartford) --  WSM Radio station break and ID  -- By The Time I Get To Phoenix (Shawn Camp)  --  I Wanna Live (John D. Loudermilk)  --  Brenda Lee comments  and presentation of medallion to Glen Campbell  --  Glen Campbell acceptance -- WSM  Radio station break and ID  -- Rhinestone Cowboy (Glen Campbell)  --  Kyle Young intros Alabama segment  --  Mountain Music (Lonestar) --  WSM Radio station break and ID -- Dixieland Delight (Hobie Hubbard, Shane Hill, Mark Miller) --  Lady Down On Love (Kenny Chesney) --  WSM Radio station break and ID  --  Jo Walker-Meador comments  --  Francis Preston comments and presentation of medallion to Alabama  --  Mark Herndon comments  --  Jeff Cook comments  --  Teddy Gentry comments  --  Randy Owen comments -- WSM Radio station break and ID  --  Will The Circle Be Unbroken (HOF members)  --  Eddie Stubbs closing comments</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>CD-R;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>PP0001_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2015-09-23</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); Bailey, DeFord; Campbell, Glen, 1936-; Alabama (Musical group); Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/2452</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>