<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Grand Ole Opry - Prince Albert - 1958-01-04 - Part 1</dc:title>
<dc:description>Part 1 of Prince Albert tobacco sponsored Grand Ole Opry segment from January 4, 1958. Featuring Grant Turner (announcer), Roy Acuff (host/performer) and his Smoky Mountain Boys, guest performer Johnny Cash, and regular performers Rod Brasfield, Howdy Forrester, June Webb, Jimmy Riddle, Minnie Pearl, and Bashful Brother Oswald. Held at Ryman Auditorium, Nashville, TN. It is announced that this is the 952nd broadcast.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1958-01-04</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Roy Acuff; Smoky Mountain Boys; Rod Brasfield; Johnny Cash; Howdy Forrester; June Webb</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Grant Turner introduces Roy Acuff -- Pins And Needles (In My Heart) (Roy Acuff) -- Opening statement (Grant Turner, Roy Acuff) -- Roy Acuff introduces Rod Brasfield -- Comedy routine (Rod Brasfield, Roy Acuff) -- Roy Acuff introduces Johnny Cash -- Ballad Of A Teenage Queen (Johnny Cash) -- Prince Albert commercial (Rod Brasfield, Roy Acuff) -- Roy Acuff introduces Howdy Forrester -- Golden Eagle Hornpipe (Howdy Forrester fiddle) -- Roy Acuff introduces June Webb -- I'm So Lonesome I Could Cry (June Webb) -- Roy Acuff talks -- Won't It Be Wonderful There (Roy Acuff and his Smoky Mountain Boys)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>16 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR000329</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2006-02-03</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); National Broadcasting Company; Grand ole opry (Radio program); Ryman Auditorium (Nashville, Tenn.); United States. Armed Forces Radio Service; Turner, Grant; Brasfield, Rod; Minnie Pearl; Forrester, Howdy, 1922-1987; Bashful Brother Oswald; Riddle, Jimmy, 1918-1982; Webb, June, 1934-; Acuff, Roy; Smoky Mountain Boys; Cash, Johnny</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/1270</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>