<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Hank Thompson Show 1948-04-29 Disc #3 &amp; 4</dc:title>
<dc:description>Multiple recordings of the Hank Thompson Radio Show. Original recording date is April 29, 1948. Thompson is backed by his Brazos Valley Boys. Recordings are labeled as Disc #3 and Disc #4 respectfully.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1948-04-29</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Hank Thompson</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) I Got A Letter from My Kid Today (Hank Thompson and His Brazos Valley Boys) -- (01:55) Tennessee Waltz (Hank Thompson and His Brazos Valley Boys) -- (04:08) Froggie Went A'Courtin (Hank Thompson and His Brazos Valley Boys) -- (05:56) Farther Along (Hank Thompson and His Brazos Valley Boys) -- (08:49) Miss Mollie (Hank Thompson and His Brazos Valley Boys) -- (10:04) Second Hand Gal (Hank Thompson and His Brazos Valley Boys) -- (11:37) Blue Eyes Crying in the Rain (Hank Thompson and His Brazos Valley Boys) -- (13:45) Blue Prairie (Hank Thompson and His Brazos Valley Boys) -- (16:14) Cowboy Jack (Hank Thompson and His Brazos Valley Boys) -- (19:21) Those Tears in Your Eyes (Hank Thompson and His Brazos Valley Boys) -- (21:30) I Know My Baby Loves Me (Hank Thompson and His Brazos Valley Boys) -- (23:13) The Great Judgement Morning (Hank Thompson and His Brazos Valley Boys) -- (25:42) Don't Live a Lie (Hank Thompson and His Brazos Valley Boys)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1226_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1226</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-02-12</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Thompson, Hank;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8485</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>