<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Performance - Cash on Cash with John Carter Cash - 2017-05-12</dc:title>
<dc:description>Performance by John Carter Cash honoring his father Johnny Cash from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on May 12, 2017.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2017-05-12</dc:date>
<dc:creator>John Carter Cash; Ana Christina Cash; George Daeger; Dave Daeger; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Walk-in Music / (00:12) Opening comments and introduction by Maureen Aguilar / (01:27) Opening theme and comments from John Carter Cash about the history of music in Tennessee and the Carter Family / (05:44) Performs Keep On The Sunny Side / (07:39) Talks about his father Johnny Cash listening to music in his early life, joining the U.S. Air Force and beginning to write songs / (10:21) Performs Folsom Prison Blues / (12:39)  Talks about Johnny's post military career / (13:55) Performs Big River / (16:33) Talks about his Dad meeting Luther Perkins and Marshall Grant and the importance of gospel music in their lives / (18:34) Performs I Was There When It Happened / (21:12) Introduces his band members George and Dave Daeger / (21:44) More history about the early recording and touring days of Johnny Cash / (24:12) Performs I Walk The Line / (26:43) Talks about the touring road life and the hazards of drug addiction / (27:52) Talks about Patsy Cline touring with Johnny Cash / </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(28:23) Talks about Johnny asking June Carter to join his road show / (31:21) Introduces his wife Ana Cristina Cash / (31:48) Performs Ring Of Fire (with Ana Christina Cash) / (34:47) Talks about the 1960's and his father's divorce and marriage to June / (36:24) Performs Jackson (with Ana Christina Cash) / (39:34) John Carter talks about the year surrounding his birth and  traveling around the world with his parents / (41:09) Johnny making music through the 1970's and 1980's recording with The Highwaymen / (41:46) Talks about his Dad beginning to work with Rick Rubin in the 1990's / (44:15) Talks about working with his father on the American 3 Solitary Man project and his father's failing health / (47:53) Performs Hurt / (51:21) Talks about the unbroken circle and their meaning and purpose / (52:40) Performs Will The Circle Be Unbroken / (54:26) Closing comments and theme / (55:37) Program end / (55:58) FILE END.                   </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/24;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0032</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2017-06-07</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Cash, John Carter; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/7607</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>