<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Kentucky Headhunters/Erv Woolsey Interview by Bob Allen Side Two </dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of The Kentucky Headhunters being interviewed by Bob Allen. The last five minutes of the tape consist of a phone interview with Erv Woolsey.    </dc:description>
<dc:creator>Kentucky Headhunters/Erv Woolsey </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Side Two - (0:00) -- Continuation of the Kentucky Headhunters interview with Bob Allen. (0:57) -- Richard Young describes the creativity of The Kentucky Headhunters in their practice room. (1:27) -- Richard Young mentions that the property is located on his grandparents' farmland. (2:30) -- Richard Young describes the band's different publishing companies. Doug, Greg, &amp; Ricky had a publishing company through BMI named "Three-Headed Music." Richard, Fred, Mitchell Fox have a publishing company on the ASCAP side named Head Cheese. (3:36) -- Bob Allen asks the Kentucky Headhunters about their radio show. (5:10) -- The Kentucky Headhunters held a live radio show once a month on Tuesday or Wednesday night. The radio show existed from 1986-1989. (9:44) -- the Kentucky Headhunters first played a bar named "Mr. C's." (10:36) -- Richard Young describes the Kentucky Headhunters playing a club named Picasso's. (14:21) -- Richard Young speaks about their album "Pickin' On Nashville." (15:58) -- Richard Young speaks about the owner of Exit/In. (18:30) -- Richard Young and The Kentucky Headhunters speak about playing bars like "Texarkana" and smaller clubs. (19:40) -- Richard Young describes playing a gig in Washington, D.C. (21:55) -- The Kentucky Headhunters speak about dealing with success in their personal lives and trying to preserve their privacy. (25:27) -- End of Kentucky Headhunters interview. (25:28) -- Bob Allen phone interview with Erv Woolsey. (26:10) -- Erv Woolsey speaks about travelling with his artists (George Strait). (27:23) -- Erv Woolsey says that his business is located on 18th and Grand Avenue (Nashville, TN). (28:44) -- Erv Woolsey speaks about his parents and where he grew up. </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>audio cassette, compact;</dc:format>
<dc:format>1.75 ips;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CAS4671_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>CAS4671</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-08-29</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>The Kentucky Headhunters (Musical group); Woolsey, Erv</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9452</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>