<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Discussion - Working with VIP's - 2018-09-08</dc:title>
<dc:description>Discussion regarding interacting with VIP's from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on September 8, 2018.  Participants include Chris Parr, Rebecca King, Emily Reynolds and Jake Basden.  Moderated by Lisa Purcell.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2018-09-08</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Chris Parr; Rebecca King; Emily Reynolds; Jake Basden;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Walk-in music / (12:50) Opening comments from Lisa Purcell / (16:05) Introduction of panel participants / (19:57) Chris talks about the types of clients that he works with and overview of his responsibilities with the Maverick Artist Management company / (21:55) Jake talks about the type of clients that he works with and overview of his responsibilities with Big Machine Records  / (22:59) Emily talks about the type of clients that she works with and an overview of her responsibilities working in Federal and State government / (24:29) Rebecca talks about the client's that she works with and an overview of her responsibilities with the Nashville Predators hockey team / (27:31) Jake gives advice to museum staff members about appropriate behavior when encountering VIP's / (28:59) Emily gives advice to museum staff members about being discreet when encountering VIP's / (30:06) Rebecca gives advice about appropriate behavior when encountering star athletes / (30:50) Chris gives advice about appropriate behavior when encountering VIP's in the music business / (32:37) Emily talks about discretion being the better part of valor / (33:40) Rebecca talks about being an venue employee and how VIP's expect them to act / (34:30) Chris talks about the importance of not putting his artists in the position of being the bad guy / (35:30) Jake talks about sometimes having to take on the role of the bad guy to remove their client from a situation / (36:33) Rebecca talks about helping her clients accomplish their event goals and still meeting the fans expectations / (37:36) Chris talks about helping his clients accomplish their event goals and still meeting the fans expectations / (39:30) Jake talks about helping his clients accomplish their event goals and still meeting the fans expectations / (40:16) Emily talks about helping her clients accomplish their event goals and still meeting audience expectations / (42:32) Chris talks about the things he does and the thing that a venue can do to help improve the experience with his clients / (44:48) Jake talks about the issues of when the venue staff is separate from the security staff / (46:19) Lisa talks about how important it is to know who's in charge at an event / (47:06) Emily talks about encountering a venue or security member who's steps outside the bounds of expectations and going rogue / (47:51) Rebecca talks about managing expectations of the audience or customers / (48:59) Jake gives his advice on always having a plan and not making assumptions or leaving anything to chance / (50:30) Emily gives advice about calibrating yourself and tells a story about Madison Square Garden and her first encounter with the Governor of New York State / (52:40) Rebecca talks about taking time to escort client where they want to go rather than giving them directions / (53:28) Chris talks about how important tour managers are and tells a story about an early experience that he learned from / (55:38) Chris talks about being yourself when working with VIP's / (56:36) Jake talks about how important it is for client and venue teams to get to know each other / (57:36) Emily talks about the importance of being yourself and how excited her clients can get during an event / (58:44) Rebecca talks about the importance of the venue staff knowing their roles and getting to know the VIP's staff / (59:40) Lisa thanks the participants and opens the floor to questions / (01:00:27) Chris answers question about times when a client purposely goes off script and pushes the limits during an event / (01:01:13) Jake talks about times when a client goes off script and pushes the limits / (01:02:00) Emily talks about her client pushing the limits sometimes / (01:02:24) Rebecca talks about her clients knowing the consequences of going off script and other times when they don't care / (01:03: 35) Lisa with final comments / (01:03:47) Walk-out music / (01:07:17) FILE END                                   </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0170</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2019-06-27</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Parr, Chris; King, Rebecca; Reynolds, Emily; Basden, Jake; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9321</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>