<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Roger Cook Interview by John Lomax III </dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is an interview of Roger Cook by John Lomax III. The interview takes place on 1-14-81.  </dc:description>
<dc:date>1981-01-14</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Roger Cook</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Side One - (0:01) -- Introduction by John Lomax. (0:17) -- John Lomax asks about the recordings Roger Cook made with Cowboy Jack Clement. (0:48) -- Roger Cook describes making a demo that Cowboy Jack Clement eventually heard and took interest in. This record began a dialogue between Jack Clement and Roger Cook. (2:10) -- Roger Cook describes the personnel when working with Cowboy Jack Clement. (3:16) -- Roger Cook mentions he's a fan of Allen Reynolds and Bob McDill's songwriting. (4:38) -- Roger Cook mentions cutting the Don Williams song "I Believe In You." (5:26) -- Roger Cook speaks about Cowboy Jack Clement's enthusiasm about the song "Living In These Troubled Times." (5:47) -- John Lomax asks Roger Cook to reflect on his career as a vocalist/performer. (8:00) -- Roger Cook mentions being called by Roger Greenaway, leader of a group named "The Kestrels." Roger Cook joined the group on the road for about six months. Roger Cook mentions co-writing the tune "You Got Your Troubles, I've Got Mine" with Roger Greenaway. (9:38) -- Roger Cook mentions recording with George Martin. (11:15) -- Roger Cook describes joining a band named "Blue Mink." (12:44) -- Roger Cook mentions recording the song "Today I Killed A Man I Didn't Know," with an artist named John Burgess. (13:40) -- Roger Cook speaks about leaving the UK and coming to the United States. (14:50) -- John Lomax asks Roger Cook about his sales figures. (15:28) -- Roger Cook mentions Warner Brothers declining his album "Alright." (16:46) -- Roger Cook discusses the emotional impact of his album being rejected by Warner Brothers. (18:00) -- Roger Cook mentions the thoughtfulness of songwriters in Nashville. (19:03) -- John Lomax asks Roger Cook about his additional hits as a writer. (20:25) -- John Lomax asks Roger Cook about working with The Hollies. (21:32) -- John Lomax asks Roger Cook about his songs that have charted in the top five. (25:29) -- Roger Cook mentions the despair as a songwriter of having successful hits then a dry spell. (27:31) -- John Lomax asks Roger Cook about his method of writing lyrics. (29:17) -- Roger Cook mentions that most skilled musicians in Nashville compose with the Nashville number system. </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>audio cassette, compact;</dc:format>
<dc:format>1.75 ips;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CAS4692_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>CAS4692</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-09-05</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Cook, Roger (Vocalist);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9493</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>