<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Carolina Country Style: Hosted by Doug Mayes: Tape 3</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording is of a variety of interviews performed by Doug Mayes (host/personality) for WBT's Carolina Country Style radio program. The tape features interviews of George Jones (entertainer), Mary Reeves (entertainer), Bill Anderson (entertainer), Ernie Ashworth (entertainer), Jim Reeves (entertainer),  Pearl Butler (entertainer),  Tex Ritter (entertainer), Wesley Rose (entertainer), Bill Monroe (entertainer), Norma Jean (entertainer), Hank Williams Jr. (entertainer), June Carter (entertainer), Johnny Cash (entertainer), and the McCormick Brothers (musical group). Recordings are from a variety of unknown dates. The tape is the third of six tapes.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Doug Mayes; George Jones; Mary Reeves; Bill Anderson; Ernie Ashworth; Jim Reeves; Pearl Butler; Tex Ritter; Wesley Rose; Bill Monroe; Norma Jean; Hank Williams Jr.; June Carter; Johnny Cash; The McCormick Brothers</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Doug Mayes praises George Jones, and both discuss Jones' popularity and writing -- (04:01) Mayes inquires about the future Jones envisions -- (04:31) Mayes introduces Mary Reeves, and Reeves reflects on the change in lifestyle Jim Reeve's success has created -- (07:45) Mayes reflects on his excitement to be hosting Bill Anderson; additionally, Anderson's recent achievements are reflected on -- (11:15) Mayes introduces Ernie Ashworth, and both reflect on Ashworth's awards -- (13:57) Mayes introduces Jim Reeves; additionally, Reeves reflects on what happens at a disc jockey awards show -- (17:00) Mayes discusses Pearl Butler's contribution to Carl Butler's musical career -- (22:16) Mayes introduces Tex Ritter to talk about Ritter's approach to recording -- (27:01) Mayes congratulates Wesley Rose; additionally, Rose reflects on being named: Man of the Year -- (28:40) Mayes introduces Bill Monroe, and both encapsulate what it is like to work in a bluegrass band -- (35:03) Mayes introduces Norma Jean to discuss her personal appearances with Porter Wagoner -- (39:42) Mayes introduces Hank Williams Jr.; additionally, Mayes inquires about how Williams Jr.'s work, at such a young age, will affect his future -- (43:13) Mayes introduces June Carter, and both reflect on Carter's time learning in areas such as New York -- (50:08) Mayes introduces Johnny Cash, and both reflect on appeal of recording to Cash -- (55:39) Mayes and the McCormick Brothers discuss how the McCormick Brothers' life had changed in recent years</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1472_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1472</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-05-16</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Mayes, Doug; Jones, George; Jones, George, 1931-2013; Reeves, Mary, 1929-1999; Anderson, Bill; Anderson, Bill, 1937-; Ashworth, Ernie; Reeves, Jim; Butler, Pearl; Ritter, Tex; Ritter, Tex, 1905-1974; Rose, Wesley; Monroe, Bill, 1911-1996; Jean, Norma; Williams, Hank, Jr., 1949-; Carter Cash, June; Carter, June; Cash, Johnny; McCormick Brothers;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8900</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>