<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Clint Black Interview - Biff Collie</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of an interview with Clint Black (performer) conducted by Biff Collie. Around nineteen minute mark of tape is a recording of an interview with Kathie Baillie and Michael Bonagura (performers) conducted by Biff Collie. Around forty-six minute mark of tape is a recording of an interview with Suzy Bogguss (performer) conducted by Biff Collie.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1989-08-21</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Clint Black; Biff Collie; Kathie Baillie; Michael Bonaguara; Suzy Bogguss</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Clint Black introduces himself and talks about moving to Houston, Texas -- (00:34) Biff Collie and Black talk about the sudden rise to popularity despite Black being a recording artist for twelve years -- (01:10) Black and Collie talk about down time's relation to "Killin' Time" -- (01:30) Black talks about losing inspiration for "Killin' Time" for over a month before discovering the hook -- (02:14) Black talks about "Nothing's News" and his father describing his life as too plain to be a country writer -- (02:58) Black talks about "Winding Down" as a quickly written song when we was working as a soloist -- (03:33) Collie and Black discuss winding down after a show -- (04:09) "Live and Learn" by Black is recalled as a desire to find the right guitar lick -- (04:48) Collie and Black discuss the song that took two years for Black to write -- (05:33) Collie asks black to give his personal information -- (05:47) Black recalls, in his youth, when he determined he was going to be a m</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1146_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1146</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-01-08</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Black, Clint; Collie, Biff; Baillie and the Boys; Baillie, Kathie; Bonagura, Michael; Bogguss, Suzy;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8353</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>