<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Apollo 16 - Moon travel tapes - Tape 1 Side 4 </dc:title>
<dc:description>Tape 1 (Side 4). Program sent on the Apollo 16 space mission for Charlie Duke's (astronaut) enjoyment. Originally from a cassette Tape. Tape featuring Bill Bailey (host), Chet Atkins, Jerry Reed, Floyd Cramer, and Jordanaires (Music Group).                               </dc:description>
<dc:creator>Bill Bailey; Chet Atkins; Jerry Reed; Floyd Cramer; Jordanaires</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Bill Bailey opening remarks addressing the Apollo 16 crew and introduces Chet Atkins, Jerry Reed, and Floyd Cramer -- (00:36) Chet Atkins introduce themselves and introduce Jerry Reeds first song -- (01:17) You Took All the Rambling Out of Me (Jerry Reed) -- (02:05) Chet Atkins and Jerry Reed introduce Kentucky -- (03:50) Kentucky  (Chet Atkins) -- (06:50) Chet Atkins and Jerry Reed introduce Floyd Cramer who addresses astronauts -- (07:29) It's Impossible (Floyd Cramer) -- (10:12) Chet Atkins and Jerry Reed addresses Floyd Cramer's Speech and introduces "A Thing Called Love" (11:07) A Thing Called Love (Jerry Reed)  -- (13:18) Chet Atkins and Jerry Reed introduce "The Red, White, and Blue Medley"  --  (14:15) The Red, White, and Blue Medley (Chet Atkins) -- (17:46) Chet Atkins and Jerry Reed introduce Floyd Cramer who addresses astronauts -- (18:08) The Sounds of Sunday (Floyd Cramer with The Jordanaires) -- (20:08) Chet Atkins and Jerry Reed praise Floyd and introduce "Another Puff" -- (21:07) Another Puff (Jerry Reed) -- (24:59) Chet Atkins and Jerry Reed joke about space travel and introduce "Jerry's Breakdown" -- (26:14) Jerry's Breakdown (Chet Atkins and Jerry Reed) -- (28:19) Jerry Reed and Chet Atkins closing comments -- (28:57) Floyd Cramer gives closing comments (29:06) Bill Bailey closing remarks</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1105_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1105</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-12-13</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Bailey, Bill; Bailey, Bill, 1965-; Atkins, Chet; Reed, Jerry; Cramer, Floyd; Cramer, Floyd, 1933-1997; Jordanaires (Musical group);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8285</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>