<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Grand Ole Opry - Prince Albert - 1956-05-05 - Part 2</dc:title>
<dc:description>Part 2 of Prince Albert tobacco sponsored Grand Ole Opry segment from May 5, 1956. Featuring Grant Turner (announcer), Ferlin Husky (host/performer), guest performers Bill Carlisle and the Carlisles, and regular performers Claude Sharpe and the Old Hickory Singers, Del Wood, Rod Brasfield, and Grandpa Jones. Held at Ryman Auditorium, Nashville, TN.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1956-05-05</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Rod Brasfield; Carlisles; Grandpa Jones; Ferlin Husky</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Ferlin Husky introduces Rod Brasfield -- Comedy routine (Rod Brasfield) -- Ferlin Husky introduces the Carlisles -- Little Liza Jane (Carlisles) -- Ferlin Husky introduces Grandpa Jones -- When You Wore A Tulip And I Wore A Big Red Rose (Grandpa Jones) -- Civil Defense P.S.A. (Grant Turner) -- Ferlin Husky talks -- That Big Old Moon (Ferlin Husky) -- Closing theme -- Closing statement (Ferlin Husky) -- Cavalier Cigarettes commercial -- Station announcements</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>16 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR000155_2</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>TR000155</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2005-08-17</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); National Broadcasting Company; Grand ole opry (Radio program); Ryman Auditorium (Nashville, Tenn.); Hay, George D. (George Dewey), 1895-1968; Brasfield, Rod; Wood, Del; Jones, Grandpa, 1913-1998; Old Hickory Singers; Sharpe, Claude, 1902-1969; Husky, Ferlin; Carlisle, Bill; Carlisles (Musical group)</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/1096</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>