<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Pioneer Rhythm Boys - WHFB - 1949-03-10</dc:title>
<dc:description>Pioneer Rhythm Boys radio show for station WHFB, Benton Harbor, MI. Originally broadcast Saturday March 12, 1949 at 11:30 am. Featuring Dwight Edmunds (announcer), Eddie Skates (host), and (verbally identified) band members Bud 'The Deacon' Wheeler, Ray 'The Professor' Watkins, Tiny and Earl (presumably Gulley). Sponsored by Bill's Auto Service and Super Save-Way Market.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1949</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Pioneer Rhythm Boys</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Theme -- Opening statement (Dwight Edmunds) -- Opening statement (Eddie Skates) -- There's No Room In My Heart For The Blues -- Bill's Auto Service commercial (Dwight Edmunds) -- Eddie Skates introduces the Professor -- Guitar Polka -- Eddie Skates introduces Tiny -- Milk Cow Blues -- Super Save-Way commercial (Dwight Edmunds) -- Eddie Skates talks -- Too Fat Polka -- Theme -- Closing statement (Eddie Skates) -- Closing statement (Dwight Edmunds)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>16 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR001400_2</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>TR001400</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2015-02-23</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WHFB (Radio station : Benton Harbor, Mich.); Pioneer Rhythm Boys</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/755</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>