<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Songwriters Session - Rhett Akins, Dallas Davidson - 2015-08-01</dc:title>
<dc:description>Performances by songwriters Rhett Akins and Dallas Davidson collectively known as the Peach Pickers from the CMA Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on August 1, 2015.  In support of the exhibit Luke Bryan: Dirt Road Diary</dc:description>
<dc:date>2015-08-01</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Dallas Davidson; Rhett Akins;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Performances include; Play It Again (Dallas Davidson) --  All About Tonight (Rhett Akins) -- The One That Got Away (Dallas Davidson) -- When She Says Baby (Rhett Akins) -- (Dallas Davidson) -- Huntin&#8217;, Fishin&#8217; and Lovin&#8217; Every Day (Rhett Akins) -- I Don't Want This Night To End (Dallas Davidson) -- That Ain't My Truck (Rhett Akins) -- Gimmie That Girl (Dallas Davidson and Rhett Akins) -- It Goes Like This (Rhett Akins) -- Tonight Looks Good On You (Dallas Davidson) -- Duck Blind (Dallas Davidson and Rhett Akins) -- Grandaddy's Gun (Rhett Akins) -- Boys Round Here (Dallas Davidson and Rhett Akins) -- Country Girl (Shake It For Me) (Dallas Davidson)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>CD-R;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>PP0267</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2016-07-13</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Davidson, Dallas; Akins, Rhett; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/4089</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>