<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Carolina Country Style: Hosted by Doug Mayes: Tape 5</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording is of a variety of interviews performed by Doug Mayes (host/personality) for WBT's Carolina Country Style radio program. The tape features interviews of Del Wood (entertainer), Cowboy Copas (entertainer), Patsy Cline (entertainer), the Louvin Brothers (musical group), Minnie Pearl (entertainer),  Roy Drusky (entertainer), Lester Flatt and Earl Scruggs (musical group), and Jim Reeves (entertainer). Recordings are from a variety of unknown dates. Second half of recording features a variety of classical music (most likely to be served as background pieces during discussion). The tape is the fifth of six tapes.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Doug Mayes; Del Wood; Cowboy Copas; Patsy Cline; the Louvin Brothers; Minnie Pearl; Roy Drusky; Flatt and Scruggs; Jim Reeves</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:06) An unidentified voice places vocal identification of the following recording (00:12) Doug Mayes introduces Del Wood, and both reflect on Wood's inspirations during writing for Mercury Records -- (03:00) An unidentified voice places vocal identification of the following recording -- (03:07) Mayes introduces Cowboy Copas while both reflect on the Disc Jockey Convention; additionally, Copas reflects on the evolution of country music -- (06:35) An unidentified voice places vocal identification of the following recording -- (06:42) Mayes introduces Patsy Cline, and both discuss Cline's extensive career -- (10:11) An unidentified voice places vocal identification of the following recording -- (10:22) Mayes invites Charlie Louvin to receive praise for the Louvin Brother's success -- (14:40) An unidentified voice places vocal identification of the following recording -- (14:47) Mayes introduces Minnie Pearl to reflect on her influence from the Grand Ole Opry -- (17:38) An unidentified voice places vocal identification of the following recording -- (17:48) Mayes asks Pearl to discuss the state of country music -- (20:16) An unidentified voice places vocal identification of the following recording -- (20:23) Mayes praises Roy Drusky's recent endeavors, and both reflect on the state of country music -- (24:12) An unidentified voice places vocal identification of the following recording -- (24:24) Mayes introduces Lester Flatt and Earl Scruggs to reflect on the popularity of their shows -- (28:04) Mayes, Flatt, and Scruggs discuss the articles written about Flatt and Scruggs -- (30:25) An unidentified voice places vocal identification of the following recording -- (30:30) Mayes introduces Jim Reeves to discuss the future of country music; additionally, Reeves reflects on his international success -- (33:15) Unidentified classical tune ([Unidentified]) -- (36:26) Unidentified classical tune ([Unidentified]) -- (38:01) Unidentified classical tune ([Unidentified]) -- (41:44) Unidentified classical tune ([Unidentified]) -- (42:57) Unidentified classical tune ([Unidentified]) -- (45:58) Unidentified classical tune ([Unidentified]) -- (49:24) Unidentified classical tune ([Unidentified]) -- (53:27) Unidentified classical tune ([Unidentified])</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1474_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1474</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-05-17</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Mayes, Doug; Wood, Del; Copas, Cowboy; Cline, Patsy, 1932-1963; Louvin Brothers; Pearl, Minnie; Drusky, Roy; Flatt and Scruggs and the Foggy Mountain Boys (Musical group); Flatt, Lester; Scruggs, Earl; Reeves, Jim;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8942</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>