<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Hallmarks of Country Music - Crash Craddock</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of an interview of Crash Craddock (musician). The interview is hosted by Rick Phillips (army sergeant/ radio host) for the Hallmarks of Country Music segment. The tape was recorded on an unidentified date.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Crash Craddock; Rick Phillips</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Rick Phillips introduces Crash Craddock, and both discuss the longevity of Craddock's career -- (01:51) Craddock reveals that he began working with his brother at thirteen years of age -- (02:38) Phillips inquires as to how Craddock got his nickname -- (03:41) Phillips inquires as to why Craddock chose to record ""Going to Knock on Your Door"" -- (05:25) Phillips and Craddock reflect on Stonewall Jackson's ""Don't be Angry"" -- (06:05) ""Til the Water Stops Running"" is described by Craddock as a title he did not understand prior to hearing the song; additionally, Craddock praises Elvis Presley -- (09:14) Phillips forgets his question for Craddock, and Phillips inquires about Craddock's show schedule -- (11:44) Phillips praises Craddock while asking about Craddock's favorite venues of entertainment -- (12:46) Phillips inquires as to what happens when someone rerecords a track while discussing ""Stop if You Love Me"" -- (14:47) Craddock says that ""It's Hard to Love a Hungry Worried Man"" is his favorite song off his album -- (16:30) Phillips inquires as to whether or not Presley has an influence on ""It's Hard to Love a Hungry Worried Man"" -- (18:11) Craddock reflects on the maturation process of country music -- (20:04) Phillips asks who else recorded ""Rub it In"" -- (21:57) Phillips and Craddock say their goodbyes -- (22:13) Phillips inquires about Craddock's future goals</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Insert is of program information. The insert features time stamps.</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1620_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1620</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-06-07</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Craddock, Billy; Phillips, Rick;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9061</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>