<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Hank Williams: Complete Works Volume 2</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of a number of performances of Hank Williams Sr. (singer/songwriter). Tape is part of a collection labeled Hank Williams: Complete Works. Tape is labeled as part two of eight. The tapes were donated from the M.G.M. Studios collection.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Hank Williams</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Window Shopping (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (02:35) Weavin' Out Your Walkin' Shoes (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (04:26) A Teardrop on a Rose (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (07:03) Lost on the River (Hank Williams Sr. and Audrey Williams) -- (09:41) Jesus Died For Me (Hank Williams Sr. and Audrey Williams) -- (12:18) A Home in Heaven (Hank Williams Sr. and Audrey Williams) -- (14:53) Fool About You (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (16:39) The Pale Horse and His Rider (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (19:34) If You'll be a Baby to Me (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (21:20) Mother is Gone (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (24:00) Dear Brother (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (26:49) When You're Tired of Breaking Other Hearts (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (28:25) Low Down Blues (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (31:03) Someday You'll Call My Name (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (33:18) Alone and Forsaken (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (35:21) Weary Blues From Waitin' (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (38:07) Men With Broken Hearts (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (41:21) Too Many Parties and too Many Pals (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (44:27) The Funeral (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (47:36) Beyond the Sunset (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (50:44) Everything's Okay (Hank Williams Sr.)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1453_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1453</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-05-09</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Williams, Hank, 1923-1953; Williams, Hank, 1923-1953. I saw the light;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8970</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>