<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Country Music Hall of Fame induction press conference - 2001</dc:title>
<dc:description>Press conference announcing the 2001 inductees to the Country Music Hall of Fame.  Held in the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on October 13, 2001</dc:description>
<dc:date>2001-10-13</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Ken Nelson; Bill Anderson; Gordon Stoker; Ray Walker; Sam Phillips; Bill Anderson; Phil Everly; Charlie Louvin;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Press conference announcing the 2001 inductees to the Country Music Hall of Fame.  Inductees present are Ken Nelson, Gordon Stoker and Ray Walker of the Jordanaires, Charlie Louvin of the Louvin Brothers, Phil Everly of the Everly Brothers, Sam Phillips and Bill Anderson.  Inductees also include Don Gibson, Homer and Jethro, Waylon Jennings, Don Law, Webb Pierce.</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>CD-R;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>PP0025</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2015-10-20</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.); Phillips, Sam, 1923-2003; Louvin, Charlie, 1927-2011; Everly, Phil, 1939-2014; Anderson, Bill, 1937-; Nelson, Ken, 1911-2008; Stoker, Gordon, 1924-2013; Walker, Ray, 1934-;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/2516</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>