<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Announcement - Brad Paisley Love And War video album launch - 2017-04-23.  Part one of two.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Event surrounding the launch of the 2017 Band Against Cancer initiative by Sarah Cannon, the Cancer Institute of HCA, in partnership with Brad Paisley and Sony Music Nashville.  Event held at the CMA Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on April 23, 2017.  Includes introductory remarks pertaining to the screening of the music video album for Paisley's Love And War project.  Does not include audio from the video album.  Part one of two.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2017-04-23</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Brad Paisley; Randy Goodman; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Opening comments from Sony Music Nashville CEO Randy Goodman / (06:09) Comments from the President of ETA Productions Ellen Appleton / (10:35) Comments from Sarah Cannon CEO Dee Anna Smith / (11:20) Audio from Band Against Cancer video / (13:21) More comments from Dee Anna Smith / (15:36) Introduction of Brad Paisley / (15:52) Opening comments by Brad Paisley / (17:08) More comments from Randy about the launch of Love and War and its accompanying video album / (18:39) Brad talks about the idea to create a video album after creating the music video for Today and the making of the video album / (20:35) Screening begins of the Love And War visual album /(20:52) FILE END   </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/24;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0027</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2018-05-30</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Paisley, Brad; Goodman, Randy; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/7553</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>