<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Harvey's Record Department Live From the Grand Ole Opry - 1966-01-29</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of a variety of live shows from the Grand Ole Opry. The shows include multiple sponsors including: Harvey's Record Department, Lava Hand Soap, Newport Cigarettes, Luzianne Coffee, and Martha White. The recordings feature artist performances by: the Crook Brothers (musical group), Ernest Tubb (musician), Norma Jean (musician), Lonzo and Oscar (musical duo), Sam and Kirk McGee (musical duo), Jean Shepard (musician), Curly Fox (musician), Billy Grammer (musician), Wilma Lee and Stoney Cooper (musical duo), and Grandpa Jones (musician). The Harvey's Record Department show is believed to be from January 29, 1966. The Martha White show is believed to be from January 31, 1966.The remaining recordings are from a group of unidentified dates. The tape is labeled the sixth of thirteen.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1966-01-29</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Crook Brothers; Ernest Tubb; Norma Jean; Lonzo and Oscar; Sam and Kirk McGee; Jean Shepard; Curly Fox; Billy Grammer; Wilma Lee and Stoney; Grandpa Jones</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:03) Unidentified tune [featuring unidentified host outro] ([Unidentified]) -- (00:20) Newport Cigarette commercial spot hosted by an unidentified host -- (00:47) Chicken Reel (Crook Brothers) -- (01:59) Through the Door (Ernest Tubb) -- (04:20) Walking the Floor [featuring unidentified host outro] [incomplete] (Ernest Tubb) -- (04:52) Newport Cigarette jingle (Unidentified) -- (05:01) An unidentified host provides a Coca Cola commercial spot -- (05:20_ Coca Cola jingle ([Unidentified]) -- (05:37) Then Go Home to Her (Norma Jean) -- (08:17) Lloyd ""Lonzo"" George and Oscar Sullivan joke about the amount of brothers on the show -- (09:18) Take Them Cold Feet Out of My Back (Lonzo and Oscar) -- (11:56) Banjo Instrumental (Sam and Kirk McGee) -- (13:40) Coca Cola Jingle [featuring unidentified host outro] ([Unidentified]) -- (14:16) Lava Hand Soap commercial spot hosted by an unidentified host -- (14:28) Lava Hand Soap Jingle ([Unidentified]) -- (14:40) I Love You More and More Every Day (Jean Shepard) -- (17:09) Black Mountain Rag (Curly Fox) -- (19:08) An unidentified host performs a Lava Hand Soap commercial spot -- (19:26) Lava Hand Soap Jingle [featuring unidentified host outro] ([Unidentified]) -- (19:55) Unknown Soldier (Billy Grammer) -- (23:07) An unidentified host introduces the Grand Ole Opry -- (23:31) Luzianne Coffee Jingle (Unidentified) -- (23:48) An unidentified host introduces the Grand Ole Opry and Luzianne Coffee -- (24:11) An unidentified host introduces the Grand Ole Opry and Martha White -- (24:17) Martha White Jingle (Unidentified) -- (25:32) I Want to be Loved (Wilma Lee and Stoney Cooper) -- (27:55) Solider's Joy (Crook Brothers) -- (29:52) Martha White Jingle (Wilma Lee and Stoney Cooper) -- (30:13) Fly Around My Pretty Little Miss (Grandpa Jones)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1827_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1827</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-08-19</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Crook Brothers; Tubb, Ernest; Tubb, Ernest, 1914-1984; Jean, Norma; Lonzo and Oscar; Sam &amp; Kirk McGee (Musical group); Shepard, Jean, 1933-2016; Fox, Curly; Fox, Curly, 1910-1995; Grammer, Billy; Wilma Lee and Stoney (Musical Group); Jones, Grandpa, 1913-1998;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9366</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>