<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Performance - Boppin' the Blues: A Celebration of Sam Phillips - 2016-05-28</dc:title>
<dc:description>Concert performances celebrating the music influenced by Sam Phillips from the CMA Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on May 28, 2016.  In support of the exhibit Flyin&#8217; Saucers Rock &amp; Roll: The Cosmic Genius of Sam Phillips.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2016-05-28</dc:date>
<dc:creator>the Planet Rockers; Webb Wilder; Margo Price; JD McPherson; Jerry Phillips;  </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Hosted by Michael Gray.  Performances include; I'm Burning (Webb Wilder with the Planet Rockers) -- Poolside (Webb Wilder with the Planet Rockes) -- Down The Line (Webb Wilder and the Planet Rockers) -- Ubangi Stomp (Webb Wilder and the Planet Rockers) -- Since You Put Me Down (Margo Price) -- Big River (Margo Price) -- Don't Be Cruel (Margo Price) -- Tennessee Song (Margo Price) -- Love My Baby (JD McPherson and the Planet Rockers) -- Break Up - (JD McPherson and the Planet Rockers) -- My Gal Mary Ann (JD McPherson and the Planet Rockers) -- North Side Gal (JD McPherson and the Planet Rockers) -- No More Crying The Blues (Sonny George and the Planet Rockers) -- Folsom Prison Blues (Sonny George and the Planet Rockers) -- My Babe (Jerry Phillips and the Planet Rockers) -- You're Never Too Short To Rock (Jerry Phillips and the Planet Rockers) -- Billy Thunder (Sonny George with Billy Swartz on drums with the Planet Rockers) -- Ones All The Law Will Allow (Sonny George with the Planet Rockers) -- Boppin The Blues (entire cast).</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>CD-R;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>PP0304</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2016-09-21</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Phillips, Sam, 1923-2003; Planet Rockers (Musical group); Price, Margo, 1983- ; Phillips, Jerry; McPherson, JD; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/4410</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>