<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Bob Rieley Collection - tape 7</dc:title>
<dc:description>Tape 7 of various performances featuring Chubby Wise (performer), Roy Acuff (performer), Bill Monroe (performer), Curly Fox (performer), Eddy Arnold (performer), Mac McGar (performer), Tommy Magness (performer), and Earl Scruggs (performer), in 1947 and other unidentified dates. Some recordings from an American Ace sponsored Grand Ole Opry segment on radio station WSM (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:description>
<dc:date>1947</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Chubby Wise; Roy Acuff; Bill Monroe; Curly Fox; Eddy Arnold; Mac McGar; Tommy Magness; Earl Scruggs;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Test tones -- Chicago Fire ([Unidentified]) (incomplete) -- [Unidentified tune] -- Love Somebody ([Unidentified]) -- Thess ([Unidentified]) -- Billy In The Lowground ([Unidentified]) -- Roy Acuff talks -- Closing theme -- Back Up And Push ([Unidentified]) -- Red Herron ([Unidentified]) -- Toyed Toy Heart (Bill Monroe) -- Blackberry Blossom ([Unidentified]) -- Katy Eline (Bill Monroe) -- Polk County Breakdown ([Unidentified]) -- Fire On The Mountain ([Unidentified]) -- Sugarfoot Rag ([Unidentified]) -- [Unidentified tune] -- Rocky Road Blues (Bill Monroe) -- Cotton Eyed Joe (Chubby Wise) -- Love Gone Cold (Lester Flatt) -- Devil's Dream ([Unidentified]) -- Fire On The Mountain (Curly Fox) -- [Unidentified tune] -- I'll Hold You In My Heart (Eddy Arnold) -- John Henry (Chubby Wise) -- Boil The Cabbage ([Unidentified]) -- Fire On The Mountain/Old Joe Clark (Benny Martin) -- Tennessee Wagoner (Mac McGar) -- I'm So Easy To Please ([Unidentified]) -- No One Will Ever Know (Roy Acuff) (incomplete) -- Mockingbird ([Unidentified]) -- Grey Eagle ([Unidentified]) -- Turkey In The Straw (Tommy Magness) -- Devil's Dream (Tommy Magness) -- Tennessee Wagoner ([Unidentified]) -- Mule Skinner Blues (Benny Martin) -- Polk County Breakdown (Tommy Magness) -- White House Blues (Bill Monroe, Earl Scruggs) -- Bill Monroe Stomp (Chubby Wise) -- Katy Hill (Tommy Magness) -- Lonesome Road Blues (Earl Scruggs) -- Grey Eagle ([Unidentified]) -- Going To Town (Tommy Magness) -- Up Jumped The Devil (Tommy Magness) -- Roy Acuff talks -- Theme -- Leather Breeches ([Unidentified]) -- Molly And Tenbrooks (Bill Monroe) -- Pretty Little Widow (Tommy Magness) -- [Unidentified tune]</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-0438_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-0438</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-05-03</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Wise, Chubby; Acuff, Roy, 1903-1992; Monroe, Bill, 1911-1996; Fox, Curly, 1910-1995; Arnold, Eddy, 1918-2008; McGar, Mac; Magness, Tommy; Scruggs, Earl, 1924-2012;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/7373</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>