<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Ralph Emery Interviews Ronnie McDowell - Parts 1, 2 and 3</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording is from Ralph Emery's (entertainer) interview of Ronnie McDowell (performer) for the Ralph Emery Show. Tape labeled parts 1, 2 and 3. Recording is from June 24, 1982.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1982-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Ralph Emery; Ronnie McDowell</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Ronnie McDowell radio spot for the Ralph Emery Show -- (00:13) Wings of an Eagle [excerpt] (Bobby Goldsboro) [Featuring Ralph Emery introduction voiceover] -- (00:37) Emery and McDowell greet each other, and Emery asks about his memory of the first time he was on the Ralph Emery Show -- (02:40) Emery inquires about McDowell's popularity among the older population -- (04:04)Emery jokes about the first time he saw "I Just Cut Myself" -- (04:52) Emery invites McDowell to discuss his restaurant the Good Ole Days -- (07:04) McDowell introduces "Whatever" by the Statler Brothers -- (07:34) Emery inquires about McDowell's relationship with Jamie O'Hara -- (09:09) Emery asks McDowell about how tired he is; additionally, McDowell reflects on his Elvis Presley image -- (12:37) Emery reflects on how he believes McDowell is similar to Tanya Tucker -- (13:08) McDowell introduces "Cheater's Prayer" while discussing the Kendalls' home town -- (14:15) Emery and McDowell discuss Bobby Bare's laid-back personality -- (14:45) Emery and McDowell reflect on the film career of Ferlin Husky -- (15:32) Wings of an Eagle [excerpt] (Bobby Goldsboro) [Featuring Ralph Emery and Ronnie McDowell outro voiceover] -- (16:47) Wings of an Eagle [excerpt] (Bobby Goldsboro) [Featuring Ralph Emery and Ronnie McDowell introduction voiceover] -- (17:04) Darlene Austin, McDowell, and Emery discuss what McDowell knows -- (18:40) Emery introduces Austin and asks McDowell to interview him -- (20:28) Emery questions Austin about where she grew up and what she was doing in Nashville -- (23:09) Emery inquires about David Havner and has Austin introduce "Love Busted" by Billy 'Crash' Craddock -- (24:23) Emery and McDowell joke about McDowell's nickname -- (25:15) Emery inquires about Austin and McDowell's upcoming joint ventures -- (28:00) Emery reflects on the songs that directly relate to the artists wife; additionally, McDowell enjoys being an opening act -- (30:08)  Austin discusses her enjoyment from performing Alabama's "Why Baby Why" -- (30:47) Emery inquires about Austin's discipline with her band -- (32:18) Emery asks Austin to introduce McDowell -- (32:56) Wings of an Eagle [excerpt] (Bobby Goldsboro) [Featuring  Emery, Austin and McDowell outro voiceover] -- (34:18) Wings of an Eagle [excerpt] (Bobby Goldsboro) [Featuring Ralph Emery and Ronnie McDowell introduction voiceover] -- (34:35) McDowell introduces Keren Cain's "I'll be Your Man of the House" -- (34:56) Emery asks McDowell about why he chose to record Conway Twitty's "It's Only Make Believe" -- (38:16) Emery recalls a show he did with Ann Murray while introducing a Murray segment -- (38:48) Emery plays a segment with Murray where both discuss "Please Don't Sell Nova Scotia" -- (40:22) Emery introduces Waylon Jennings' "Honky Tonk Blues" -- (41:02) McDowell discusses how Gene Watson's appearance has changed over time while introducing "This Dreams on Me" -- (41:38) "I Just Cut Myself" is introduced and Emery inquires about what McDowell believes to be a hit -- (43:22) Emery recalls a time at a hotel where a television show reminded him of "I Just Cut Myself" -- (43:58) McDowell praises Sylvia while introducing "Nobody" -- (44:28) Emery and McDowell discuss how McDowell discovered his great-grandfather was one of three McDowells to cross into the new world -- (47:24) Emery praises McDowell's "Only the Lonely" which happened to be the first record McDowell recorded -- (48:25) Wings of an Eagle [excerpt] (Bobby Goldsboro) [Featuring Emery and McDowell outro voiceover]</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1374_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1374</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-04-12</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Emery, Ralph; McDowell, Ronnie;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8786</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>