<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Kendalls Interview - Biff Collie</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of an interview with the Kendalls (performance group) conducted by Biff Collie.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1989-06-30</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Kendalls; Biff Collie Collie</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Royce and Jeannie Kendall discuss how Royce's brother got the name Floyce -- (00:33) Royce reflects on his father's passing when Royce was young -- (01:29) Royce tells of how he would listen to the Grand Ole Opry and how his mother got him a guitar -- (02:28) Collie reflects on why Bill Anderson plays right-handed guitar -- (02:54) Royce reflects on working on a cotton farm -- (03:27) Royce and Collie discuss how Royce had to charge a  battery to listen to the Grand Ole Opry -- (04:30) Royce and Jeannie reflect on how Royce and Floyce were uncommitted to music -- (05:37) Jeannie is revealed to be the only child of Royce; Jeannie grew up in St. Louis -- (07:05) Royce and Jeannie reflect on the first time they had sung together -- (08:30) Royce and Jeannie discuss the first couple tracks they had ever recorded -- (10:12) Collie has the Kendall's reflect the aspects of paying to record -- (12:01) Jeannie asserts the way they had recorded was the only way they could have -- (12:55) Leaving on a Jet Plane is discusses by the Kendalls, and Jeannie and Royce agree that it was a life-changing album -- (14:05) Jeannie and Royce tell about how they had given up their old lives to pursue their musical career -- (15:15) Collie and the Kendalls reflect on the relationship developed when working with one's child -- (17:13) Royce and Jeannie reflect on how Royce's wife had altered her life to allow the Kendalls to thrive -- (18:07) Collie has Royce discuss how he and his wife were originally beauticians together -- (19:01) Jeannie and Royce tell about how they started their careers in the studio -- (19:25) Jeannie and Royce reflect on an unidentified  person -- (20:02) Royce says country music artists, including Eddie Arnold and George Jones, were his inspiration; Jeannie boasts about a larger diversity of musical appreciation -- (21:24) Royce and Jeannie reflect on how they developed their own personal style -- (22:32) Collie and the Kendalls reflect on similar sounding acts -- (23:39) Collie and the Kendalls address the Kendalls' relationship with Pete Drake -- (25:06) Royce reflects on getting a record deal from Bryant Fisher -- (25:40) Jeannie reveals the material the Kendalls had created prior to beginning to record and Royce and Jeannie reflect on their recording -- (28:29) The Kendalls discuss their experience on a tobacco farm -- (30:22) Collie asks about the Kendalls' status as tobacco farmers -- (30:33) Jeannie reveals they only grew one crop; Royce tells Collie about their move to Hendersonville -- (30:53) Collie and the Kendalls discuss the Kendalls' road performances -- (31:59) Collie has the Kendalls discuss how they constructed a band -- (33:06) Collie and Royce discuss Royce's time in barber school -- (33:39) The Kendalls address their equipment used during recording their first record -- (35:13) Jeannie and Royce reflect on Jeannie's love of Peter, Paul, and Mary; Royce and Jeannie reflect on John Denver being the host for the Grammy's -- (36:41) Collie presses Jeannie to talk about how she never dated before she got married -- (38:15) The Kendalls address what their future goals in entertainment are -- (38:53) Collie and the Kendalls discuss how Ralph Emery and Roy Acuff had been the biggest contributors to country music -- (40:14) The Kendalls express their thanks and Collie asks Jeannie about her future aspirations -- (40:47) Collie and Royce joke about Royce's future aspirations to become a fisherman -- (41:15) Jeannie reflects on her inability to plan for retirement -- (41:30) Jeannie tells about how she would stay at home for the foreseeable future and Royce tells his favorite vacation was Hawaii</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1188_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1188</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-01-25</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Kendalls (Musical group); Kendall, Jeannie; Collie, Biff;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8428</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>