<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Lionel Cartwright - Biff Collie</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of an interview with Lionel Cartwright (performer) conducted by Biff Collie.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1989-09-27</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Lionel Cartwright; Biff Collie</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Biff Collie and Lionel Cartwright joke about his album title and Cartwright confirms his real name -- (00:23) Cartwright describes "Fallin' Again" as a minor key song in an up-tempo influenced by the Everly Brothers -- (00:53) Cartwright talks about "Like Father Like Son" and being at the Blue Bird Cafe and hearing it first performed by Don Schlitz -- (02:58) Collie and Cartwright talk about "You're Gonna Make Her Mine" being a personal ode from Cartwright -- (03:46) Cartwright talks about Doc Watson's influence on "A Little Lesser Blue" and how he doesn't do it live -- (04:32) Cartwright opens up to Collie about his first album and the long recording time required to find his variety -- (05:50) Cartwright talks about the group the stuck around him through the growth process (06:24) Cartwright discusses his new single "In My Eyes" and the influences of being on the road for work -- (07:03) Cartwright talks about growing up in Gallipolis, Ohio and moving to West Virginia to discover country music -- (08:00) Cartwright talks about the variety of artists he enjoys and being a self-taught musician playing his brother uke -- (09:03) Cartwright tells about the first time he heard country music -- (09:23) Cartwright talks about listening to WWVA and hiding a radio in his room -- (10:08) Cartwright talks about arriving in Nashville and auditioning for the I-40 Paradise -- (11:13) Cartwright talks with Collie about musical heritage in Knoxville and meeting his wife / Felice and Boudleaux Bryant -- (12:26) Collie and Cartwright converse about the Bryant's 1400 recorded tracks and what it was like to work with them -- (14:02) Collie gives the advice to find professionals to work with -- (14:25) Cartwright talks about the Bryant's influence -- (14:48) Cartwright discusses the commute and moving back to Nashville in 1986 after getting signed to MCA -- (15:45) "Give Me His Last Chance" is discussed by Cartwright as his inspiration coming through as he was down at a loading dock on Percy Priest lake -- (17:08) Collie and Cartwright talk about "That's Why They Call It Falling" and the unpredictability of falling in love -- (18:12) Cartwright's "Blue Fiddle Waltz" was inspired from a fiddler contest and an older gentlemen that blew everyone away -- (19:30) "She Never Saw Love" is described as a caring and unselfish song by Cartwright -- (20:41) "Let the Hard Times Roll" is the last tune that Cartwright uses in shows and he describes it as the hard times coming and going -- (21:30) Cartwright talks about not having a plan b after music and being a fan of the industry -- (22:12) Collie jokes about stealing money -- (22:28) Collie and Cartwright interview about a list of Cartwright's music favorite -- (23:09) Collie asks Cartwright about his love life and Cartwright talks about teaching his wife to ice skate -- (23:44) Collie and Cartwright say goodbye and thank each other </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1133_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1133</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-01-02</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Cartwright, Lionel; Collie, Biff;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8331</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>