<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Redd Harper's Hollywood Roundup - Program #258 - Part 1 + 2</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of Redd Harper's Hollywood Roundup. Listed as program number 258 parts one and two. Labeled as part of the Armed Forces Radio Series EN-81. Recording features Redd Harper (entertainer), the Ozark Mountain Boys (performance group), Hank Thompson (performer), Freddie DeVares (performer), and Frankie Messina (performer). Recording is from an unknown date.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Redd Harper; The Ozark Mountain Boys; Hank Thompson; Freddie DeVares; Frankie Messina</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Opening Theme [featuring Redd Harper voiceover] -- (01:12) Take Me Back to Tulsa (Ozark Mountain Boys) -- (02:56) Harper and Wade Ray joke about Tulsa -- (03:34) Rounded Up in glory (Redd Harper) -- (05:15) Harper introduces Hank Thompson -- (05:32) Hangover Heart (Hank Thompson) -- (07:30) Harper and Thompson discuss Thompson's goat farm -- (08:54) Are You Fer That? (Ozark Mountain Boys) -- (10:54) Harper and Thompson discuss Thompson's goat farm -- (12:17) Paradise Isle (Freddie DeVares) [unconfirmed]-- (13:49) Harper and Thompson discuss Thompson's prize goat -- (15:00) Margie (Ozark Mountain Boys) -- (17:50) -- (07:30) Harper and Thompson discuss Thompson's goats -- (18:41) Love thief (Hank Thompson) -- (21:10) Harper and Thompson discuss Thompson's goats -- (22:07) About Face [featuring Frankie Messina on the accordion] (Ozark Mountain Boys) -- (23:57) Harper and Thompson discuss Thompson's goats -- (24:15) What's Cooking on the Hollywood Range (Redd Harper) -- (25:38) That Beautiful Picture (Hank Thompson) -- (27:40) Thompson and Harper give their thanks and urge the audience to go to church -- (28:03) Closing Theme [featuring Redd Harper voiceover]</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1235_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1235</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-02-13</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Harper, Redd, 1903-1992; Thompson, Hank; Ray, Wade, 1913-1998; </dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8494</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>