<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Harlan Howard Written Song Recordings - Tape 4</dc:title>
<dc:description>The series of recordings features a variety of tracks written by Harlan Howard. The tracks are performed by a variety of artists including: Wanda Jackson, Jean Shepard, Tex Ritter, Ernest Tubb, Jimmy Newman, Roy Drusky, Jan Howard, Wynn Stewart, and Johnny Cash. The tracks are from a variety of unidentified dates. The tape is the forth in a series of eight.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Harlan Howard</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) If I Cried Every Time You Hurt Me (Wanda Jackson) -- (02:24) Lonely Little World (Jean Shepard) -- (04:39) The Gun, the Gold and the Girl (Tex Ritter) -- (07:02) I Never Could Say No (Ernest Tubb) -- (09:32) Everything (Jimmy Newman) -- (11:53) You Never Cried (When You Were Mine) (Roy Drusky) -- (13:49) Wrong Company (Jan Howard and Wynn Stewart) -- (15:59) We'll Never Love Again (Jan Howard and Wynn Stewart) -- (18:17) I've Got My Pride (Jan Howard) -- (20:25) I Wish I Was a Single Girl Again (Jan Howard) -- (22:41) Just Another Girl (Jean Shepard) -- (25:01) Still in Town (Johnny Cash)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-7-03743_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-7-03743</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-08-15</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Jackson, Wanda, 1937-; Shepard, Jean, 1933-; Shepard, Jean, 1933-2016; Ritter, Tex; Ritter, Tex, 1905-1974; Tubb, Ernest; Tubb, Ernest, 1914-1984; Newman, Jimmy C.; Drusky, Roy; Howard, Jan (Vocalist); Howard, Harlan; Stewart, Wynn; Cash, Johnny; Cash, Johnny, 1932-2003;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9348</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>