<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>UNICEF tour - New Zealand - 1972 - part 2</dc:title>
<dc:description>Part two of a 1972 UNICEF fundraiser tour performance in New Zealand. Featuring Tex Ritter (host), Freddy Weller (performer), and Connie Smith (performer).</dc:description>
<dc:date>1972</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Freddy Weller; Connie Smith</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:11) The Promised Land (Freddy Weller) (incomplete) -- (02:30) Freddy Weller talks about Merle Haggard and introduces the next tune -- (02:37) Okie From Muskogee (Freddy Weller) -- (04:59) Weller thanks Tom T. Hall's band and introduces Bob Warford and the next tune -- (05:30) Games People Play (Freddy Weller, Paul Warford guitar) -- (08:54) Tex Ritter introduces Connie Smith -- (10:05) Just One Time (Connie Smith) -- (12:32) I Never Stopped Loving You (Connie Smith) -- (15:14) Connie Smith introduces the next tune -- (15:23) Louisiana Man (Connie Smith) -- (18:15) Once A Day, Everyday, All Day Long (Connie Smith) -- (20:43) Smith thanks the audience and talks about the people of New Zealand -- Smith talks about her experiences with God -- (22:07) How Great Thou Art (Connie Smith)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-7-01975_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-7-01975</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-01-10</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Country Music Association (U.S.); Ritter, Tex, 1905-1974; Weller, Freddy, 1947-; Smith, Connie, 1941-;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8362</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>