<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Pickard Family Performance P-F R-C &amp; P-F R-D</dc:title>
<dc:description>Tape 2 of 7. Two recordings of the Pickard Family (performance group) from the thirteenth day of an unknown month in 1937. Sessions are labeled as P-F R-C side 2 and P-F R-D side 2 respectively and recorded in Mexico.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1937</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Pickard Family</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) [Unknown instrumental jew's harp song] (Pickard Family) -- (01:02) Obed Pickard, Charlie Pickard and Ruthie Pickard joke about the jew's harp -- (01:51) Abdul A-Bull-Bull-Amir (Pickard Family) -- (04:11) Charlie, Ruthie and Obed joke about yodeling -- (04:44) Sweet Fern (Pickard Family) -- (07:10) Charlie and Obed joke about a sweet girl (07:35) Commercial for Peruna performed by Dad -- (09:00) [Unidentified Harmonica Tune] (Pickard Family) -- (09:42) The Pickard Family introduces Old MacDonald Had a Farm-- (09:54) Old MacDonald Had A Farm (Pickard Family) -- (12:13) The Old Songs that Live Forever (Pickard Family) [featuring Peruna radio spot by Don] -- (13:46) [Piano Duet] (Pickard Family) -- (14:00) Charlie and Ruthie talk about a poem wrote for their father and Don gives his appreciation for his home town -- (15:23) Dad's Narrative (Pickard Family) -- (17:35) Charlie, Don, and Ruthie appreciate the poem and joke about fooling fish -- (18:22) Commercial for Peruna performed by Don -- (19:58) Corinna, Corinna [Instrumental] (Pickard Family) -- (20:21) Ruthie, Charlie, and Ruthie joke about an obituary -- (21:19) The Poor Married Man (Pickard Family) -- (24:10) Bub, Ruthie and Charlie joke about being single and pronouncing a Hawaiian Princess' name-- (25:05) Aloha Oe (Pickard Family) -- (27:02) Dad thanks Charlie and Bub for the song (27:14) It's the Old Songs that Live Forever (Pickard Family) </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1154_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1154</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-01-10</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Pickard Family (MusicalGroup)</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8367</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>