<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Oklahoma Roundup Aired Performance - 1946-11-11 - KOMA - Part 1</dc:title>
<dc:description>Part one of an aired performance from the Oklahoma Roundup radio program on November 11, 1946 on radio station KOMA (Oklahoma City, Okla). Staff includes Hiram Higsby (master of ceremonies, writer),  Allan Page (announcer, director), and Kenyon Brown (producer).</dc:description>
<dc:date>1946-11-11</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Chuck Davis; Roundup Boys; Oklahoma Songbirds; Hiram Higsby; Ann Bond; Dick Reinhart</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(0:00) Opening theme and statements / (1:30) Hiram Higsby opens the show / (1:50) Chuck Davis and the Roundup Boys perform "Dragging The Bow" / (2:54) Hiram Higsby and Allan Page tell a joke / (4:14) The Oklahoma Songbirds perform "I&#8217;ll Go Riding Down That Old Texas Trail" / (6:14) Hiram Higsby and Allan Page tell a joke / (6:45) Hiram Higsby performs "I Left Her Standing There (With A Doodad In Her Hair)" / (8:33) Hiram Higsby, Allan Page, and Ann Bond tell a joke through a skit / (9:47) Ann Bond performs "Fireball Mail" / (11:29) Hiram Higsby and Allan Page tell a joke / (12:06) Dick Reinhart performs "Don&#8217;t Fence Me In" / (14:03) Lem Hawkins and Hiram Higsby tell a joke / (16:24) Lem Hawkins performs "[Unidentified banjo tune]" [incomplete]</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>16 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR003063_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>TR003063</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:isPartOf>TRB002_1</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2017-08-04</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Oklahoma Roundup; KOMA (Radio station : Oklahoma City, Okla.); CBS Inc.; Davis, Chuck; Higsby, Hiram, 1909-1975; Bond, Ann; Reinhart, Dick;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/5475</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>