<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Various interviews - Mike Robbins Music City Breakdown - WKDA</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of interviews with Willie Nelson (performer), Don Gibson (performer), and Dolly Parton (performer), hosted by Mike Robbins for radio program Music City Breakdown on radio station WKDA (Nashville, Tenn.) Recording also contains dialogue from Larry Kingston (performer) and Allen Reynolds (producer) on the recording of Wilma Lou.</dc:description>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Willie Nelson talks about labels like hippies and rednecks, and how Austin was a place where hippies and rednecks came together -- Nelson talks about audiences being labeled in country music -- Nelson talks about Austin not attempting to become another Nashville -- Don Gibson talks about taking drugs and gaining success as a country artist -- Gibson talks about hanging around Hank Garland -- Dolly Parton talks about being a girl raised in the mountain and how her father was a hard worker -- Parton talks about giving and giving until you have no more to give and having common sense -- Mike Robbins talks for Music City Breakdown -- [Unidentified] introduces the recording Wilma Lou -- Wilma Lou (Larry Kingston) -- Allen Reynolds talks about producing Wilma Lou -- Larry Kingston talks about Bob McDill writing the song and recording Wilma Lou</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-7-04041_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-7-04041</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-07-20</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WKDA (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); Nelson, Willie, 1933-; Gibson, Don (Donald Eugene), 1928-2003; Parton, Dolly, 1946-; Kingston, Larry; Reynolds, Allen;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/7934</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>