<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Johnson Brothers Radio Show - WAVU - Tape 1</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording is of the Johnson Brothers Radio Show for the WAVU radio station of Albertville, Alabama. Tape is labeled part one of six tapes. The recording comes from January 10,1953.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1953-01-10</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Johnson Brothers String Band</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Ras Johnson opens with a guitar tune while Jesse Culp discusses the Sand Mountain Truck and Tractor Company -- (01:49) Sally Goodin' (Johnson Brothers String Band) -- (01:26) Ras introduces "Sally Goodin" -- (01:46) Sally Goodin' (Johnson Brothers String Band) -- (03:22) Fiddler's Dram (Johnson Brothers String Band) -- (04:50) Ras invites Culp to perform his commercial spot for the Sand Mountain Truck and Tractor Company -- (07:34) Where the Soul Never Dies (Johnson Brothers String Band) -- (09:43) Oh My Little Boy She's Foolin' You (Johnson Brothers String Band) -- (12:09) Silver Bells (Johnson Brothers String Band) -- (14:21)  Mollie Put the Kettle on (Johnson Brothers String Band) -- (15:05) Culp discusses the Sand Mountain Truck and Tractor Company atop of Johnson Brother's String Band backing -- (17:27)  Time (Imogene and Ella Johnson) -- (20:08) Some of Them Gals Will Do to Take Along (Johnson Brothers String Band) -- (22:56) Down Yonder (Imogene and Ella Johnson) -- (25:00) Ras invites Culp to perform his commercial spot for Sand Mountain Truck and Tractor Company -- (25:10) Culp discusses the Sand Mountain Truck and Tractor Company atop of Johnson Brother's String Band backing -- (27:21) Shall We Gather at the River (Johnson Brothers String Band) -- (28:26) Outro break tune [featuring Jesse Culp voiceover] (Johnson Brothers String Band) -- (30:18) Commercial break tune (Ras Johnson) -- (30:37) Culp and Ras joke and say their goodbyes</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:isPartOf>The tape containes the logs of all six recordings of the Johnson's String Band.</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1461_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1461</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-05-14</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Johnson Brothers String Band (Musical group);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8925</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>