<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Hallmarks of Country Music - Johnny Paycheck</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of an interview of Johnny Paycheck (musician). The interview is hosted by Rick Phillips (army sergeant/ radio host) for the Hallmarks of Country Music segment. The tape was recorded on an unidentified date.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Johnny Paycheck; Rick Phillips</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Promotion for Hallmarks of Country Music featuring Johnny Paycheck -- (00:26) Hallmarks tune [featuring Rick Phillips introduction voiceover] ([Unidentified]) -- (01:01) An unidentified host performs a Health Education commercial spot -- (01:40) Someone to Give My Lovin' to (Johnny Paycheck) -- (04:27) Phillips introduces Paycheck to reflect on his move to Nashville, and both discuss Paycheck's George Jones influence -- (07:37) Phillips and Paycheck discuss "My Part of Forever" -- (08:09) My Part of Forever (Johnny Paycheck) -- (10:55) Phillips performs a Project Ahead radio spot -- (11:51) Somebody Loves Me (Johnny Paycheck) -- (14:19) Phillips asks Paycheck to recall "Somebody Loves Me" and the accompanying book; additionally, both reflect on Paycheck's song-writing career -- (18:48) An unidentified host performs an alcoholism commercial spot -- (19:17) Mr. Lovemaker -- (21:28) Phillips asks Paycheck about "Mr. Lovemaker," and Paycheck declares a producer makes the career -- (24:21) Song and Dance Man (Johnny Paycheck) -- (26:45) Phillips performs a Recruiting Command radio spot -- (27:30) Something About You I Love (Johnny Paycheck) -- (29:55) United States Officers commercial spot hosted by an unidentified host -- (31:07) Love is a Good Thing (Johnny Paycheck) -- (33:36) Paycheck reflects on Jerry Foster and Bill Rice's song-writing; additionally, Phillips asks about the commercial aspect of country music -- (40:17) Infectious disease commercial spot hosted by an unidentified host -- (40:48) Paycheck reflects on the Country Music Association Awards -- (44:45) Keep on Lovin' Me (Johnny Paycheck) -- (47:05) Phillips inquires about "Keep on Lovin' Me," and Phillips inquires about the threat of a different type of country music -- (49:05) Voluntary Action commercial spot hosted by an unidentified host -- (49:29) She's All I Got (Johnny Paycheck) -- (52:16) Paycheck reflects on being nominated for a Grammy, and Paycheck and Phillips say goodbye -- (54:20) Hallmarks tune [featuring Rick Phillips outro voiceover] ([Unidentified])</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Insert is of program information. The insert features time stamps.</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1721_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1721</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-06-17</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Paycheck, Johnny; Phillips, Rick;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9111</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>