<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Skip Ewing Interview - Biff Collie</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of an interview with Skip Ewing (performer) conducted by Biff Collie. </dc:description>
<dc:date>1989-12-27</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Skip Ewing; Biff Collie</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Skip Ewing talks about blocking out times to write and writing "Burnin' a Hole in My Heart" in his truck -- (01:30) Ewing talks about his discussion to name the album "The Coast of Colorado" and writing "Lighter Shade of Blue" with Max T. Barnes and Troy Seals -- (04:05) Ewing comments on Seals and gaining acceptance from writers he respects -- (05:33) Ewing talks about the continental divide - (05:47) Biff Collie inquires about "I Don't Have Far to Fall," Ewing reflects on his own writings, and Ewing discusses the honor he feels to have his songs re-recorded -- (06:44) Ewing reflects on his writing friend Barnes -- (07:18) Collie and Ewing discuss the writing styles of Barnes -- (07:50) Ewing recalls his divorce coinciding with cutting Ewing's album and writing "Autumn's Not That Cold" in the IHOP with Barnes -- (10:00) Ewing talks about finishing "Autumn's Not That Cold" and staying up all night wanting to show people his track -- (10:56) Ewing talks about preferring to use his own experiences to write songs but is willing to take other's stories -- (11:50) Ewing talks about "The Coast of Colorado" and living in Colorado in junior high -- (12:34) Ewing tells how "The Coast of Colorado" was created to describe a feeling more than a literal interpretation and jabbed at Barnes -- (14:50) Ewing talks about the genius of simplicity in writing; Merle Haggard demonstrates this value for Ewing -- (15:56) Ewing and Collie joke about writers -- (16:08) Ewing talks about his song "Don't Mind If I Do" and how he found the inspiration; additionally, Ewing tells about disturbing Don Sampson to write the song -- (18:03) Ewing talks about George Strait -- (18:40) Ewing discusses Sampson's inspiration for "The Gospel According to Luke" -- (19:16) Collie and Ewing talk about growing up and diversity in Ewing's work -- (20:56) Collie and Ewing discuss Ewing's future living decisions -- (21:53) Ewing talks about making himself write and writing all night when inspiration hits -- (24:30) Ewing recalls talking with a Michael White -- (25:15) Ewing thanks Collie and vise versa -- (25:20) Ewing talks about the time required in order to record an album and the process of recording -- (26:17) Ewing says goodbye radio spot for the Music City Album Review</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1147_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1147</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-01-08</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Ewing, Skip; Collie, Biff;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8350</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>