<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Riverside Hoedown - Audition - Part 1</dc:title>
<dc:description>Audition for WSM program Riverside Hoedown, part 1. Featuring Ernie Keller (announcer), George Morgan (host, performer), Candy Kids (performers, including Dean on fiddle), Anita Kerr Singers (performer), Don Slayman (performer), Little Jimmy Dickens (performer), and Chet Atkins (performer). Sponsored by Bristol-Myers products Ipana and Sal Hepatica.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1953-02-20</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Anita Kerr Singers; Little Jimmy Dickens; George Morgan; Candy Kids; Chet Atkins</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Sal Hepatica / Ipana jingle (Anita Kerr Singers) -- Opening statement (Ernie Keller) -- Theme (Stay A Little Longer) (Anita Kerr Singers) -- Opening statement (George Morgan) -- Jambalaya (On the Bayou) (George Morgan) -- George Morgan and Little Jimmy Dickens talk -- I'm Little But I'm Loud (Little Jimmy Dickens) -- Sal Hepatica commercial (George Morgan, Ernie Keller) -- Sal Hepatica jingle (Anita Kerr Singers) -- George Morgan introduces Anita Kerr -- It's My Lazy Day (Anita Kerr Singers) -- George Morgan talks about New Orleans -- Birth Of The Blues (Chet Atkins guitar) -- (I Just Had A Date) A Lover's Quarrel (George Morgan) -- Ipana commercial (Ernie Keller, George Morgan) [continued in part 2]</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>16 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR001315_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>TR001315</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2014-12-08</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); Bristol-Myers Company; Riverside hoedown (Radio program); Keller, Ernie; Morgan, George, 1925-1975; Anita Kerr Singers; Slayman, Don (Musician); Dickens, Little Jimmy, 1920-; Atkins, Chet; Candy Kids (Musical group)</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/617</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>