<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Hank Williams Mother's Best show - #163 - WSM</dc:title>
<dc:description>First recording contains excerpts of various Aunt Jemima jingles, plugs, and performances by Tommy Sosebee (performer), the Beasley Sisters (performers), and Louis Buck (announcer). Second Recording contains various cut-ins and Mother's Best plugs by Hank Williams and Louis Buck. Third recording is of Hank Williams' Mother's Best show, featuring Louis Buck (announcer), Hank Williams (performer, host), Don Helms (performer) and Jerry Rivers (performer), listed as show #163 on radio station WSM (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Hank Williams; Jerry Rivers; Don Helms; Tommy Sosebee; The Beasley Sisters</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>[Unidentified] talks -- Aunt Jemima jingle -- Opening statement -- [Unidentified] introduces Tommy Sosebee -- Don't Forget (Tommy Sosebee) [unconfirmed] -- Aunt Jemima plug (Louis Buck) -- I Can't Help It (Beasley Sisters) -- Tommy Sosebee talks -- Aunt Jemima plug (Louis Buck) -- [Unidentified] talks -- Jealous Heart (Tommy Sosebee) -- [Unidentified] and Tommy Sosebee talk -- Aunt Jemima jingle -- Closing statement (Louis Buck) -- [Unidentified] talks -- Aunt Jemima jingle -- Opening statement -- How Can You Smile (Tommy Sosebee) (incomplete) -- [Unidentified] talks -- Aunt Jemima jingle -- Opening statement -- How Can You Smile (Tommy Sosebee) -- Tommy Sosebee talks -- Aunt Jemima plug (Louis Buck) -- Honey, Be My Honey Bee (Beasley Sisters) -- Aunt Jemima plug (Louis Buck) -- Tommy Sosebee talks -- I Come To The Garden Alone (Tommy Sosebee) -- Closing statement -- Hank Williams talks (incomplete) -- Mother's Best plug (Louis Buck) -- Mother's Best plug (Hank Williams) -- Mother's Best plug (Hank Williams and Louis Buck) -- Mother's Best plug (Hank Williams and Louis Buck) -- Hank Williams talks -- Mother's Best plug (Louis Buck) -- Mother's Best plug (Hank Williams) -- Mother's Best plug (Hank Williams and Louis Buck) -- Opening statement (Louis Buck) -- Opening theme -- Hank Williams talks and introduces the first tune -- I'll Sail My Ship Alone (Hank Williams) -- Hank Williams talks -- Mother's Best plug (Hank Williams and Louis Buck) -- Hank Williams talks and introduces the next tune -- Little Annie (Don Helms steel guitar and Jerry Rivers fiddle) -- Hank Williams talks and introduces the next tune -- I'll Have A New Body (Hank Williams) -- Mother's Best plug (Louis Buck) -- Closing statement (Hank Williams and Louis Buck) -- Closing theme</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-0173_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-0173</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2008-05-13</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); Buck, Louis, 1910-1971; Beasley Sisters; Sosebee, Tommy; Williams, Hank, 1923-1953; Helms, Don (Guitarist); Rivers, Jerry, 1928-;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/6168</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>