<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Songwriter Session - Jon Pardi - 2017-06-08</dc:title>
<dc:description>Performance by Jon Pardi from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on June 8, 2017.  Includes questions from the audience.  Presented in support of the exhibit American Currents: The Music of 2016. </dc:description>
<dc:date>2017-06-08</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Jon Pardi;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Excerpt from sound check / (03:11) Opening comments and songwriter introduction by Abi Tapia / (06:44) Opening comments by Jon Pardi / (07:37) Introduction and performance of Chasin' Them Better Days (excerpt) / (09:46) Write You A Song (excerpt) / (11:45) Love You From Here / (13:18) Talks about his first record, having long hair and wearing a cowboy hat / (15:00) Heads Over Boots / (18:14) Talks about writing Head Over Boots / (25:04) Answers question about what has he learned working with Dierks Bentley / (27:44) Answers question about feeling an obligation to keep the California music thing going / (32:05) Heartache On The Dance Floor / (35:17) Talks about the previous song and his love of Motown music / (37:09) Answers question about how he gets in a zone for songwriting / (39:19) Answers question about how hard it is to chose songs to play /(41:24) Answers question about his first guitar and if he still has it / (42:35) Answers question about his favorite songs /</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(43:59) Answers question about his marital status and how he deals with being away from his family / (46:15) Answers questions about missing In and Out Burger, real mexican food and who he would like to perform with at the Crystal Palace in Bakersfield / (48:10) Answers question about the first time he heard one of his songs on the radio / (49:29) Answers question about how he gets songs to his publisher / (50:36) Answers question about having plans to tour overseas / (52:53) Answers question about where he was brought up / (53:42) California Sunrise / (57:11) Closing comments / (58:27) Program end / (01:06:09) FILE END                            </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/24;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0042</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2018-06-27</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Pardi, Jon; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/7710</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>