<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Dottie West interview - Biff Collie - 1965</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of an interview with Dottie West (performer), conducted by Biff Collie in 1965.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1965</dc:date>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Biff Collie asks Dottie West if she is an overnight sensation -- Dottie West denies that claim -- Collie talks about her being one of the fastest growing female artists around -- Dottie Talks about her hometown -- Dottie talks about her first music job being on a radio show in Ohio -- Dottie talks about recording since 1959 -- Dottie talks about being glad she crawled before she walked in the music business so she could learn the right and the wrong way to do things -- Dottie talks about working with Connie Smith -- Dottie talks about being mainly a sad, ballad singer -- Collie says the he think West will be Ms. Country Music in 1965 -- West thanks him -- Collie talks about Dottie being a pioneer for female country artists -- Collie concludes the interview</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-7-04061_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-7-04061</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-07-26</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>West, Dottie, 1932-1991; Collie, Biff;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/7949</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>