<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Grand Ole Opry - Prince Albert - 1959-10-03 - Part 2</dc:title>
<dc:description>Part 2 of Prince Albert tobacco sponsored Grand Ole Opry segment from October 3, 1959. Featuring Grant Turner (announcer), Faron Young (host/performer) with Donny Young, guest performers the Louvin Brothers, and regular performers Archie Campbell, Tommy Jackson, the Jordanaires Chet Atkins with Buddy Harman, Minnie Pearl, and Grandpa Jones. Held at Ryman Auditorium, Nashville, TN. It is announced that this is the 1043rd broadcast.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1959-10-03</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Minnie Pearl; Archie Campbell; Faron Young; Louvin Brothers; Grandpa Jones; Faron Young; Donny Young</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Faron Young introduces Minnie Pearl -- Comedy routine (Minnie Pearl, Archie Campbell) -- The Proof Is In The Puffing (Faron Young) (recording) -- Grant Turner introduces the Louvin Brothers -- While You're Cheating On Me (Louvin Brothers) -- Grant Turner introduces Grandpa Jones -- The Baldheaded End Of The Broom (Grandpa Jones) -- Grant Turner and Faron Young announce his tour schedule -- Country Girl (Faron Young, Donny Young) -- Closing theme -- Closing statement (Faron Young) -- Camel Cigarettes jingle -- Network announcements (Grant Turner)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>16 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR000508</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2006-06-21</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); National Broadcasting Company; Grand ole opry (Radio program); Ryman Auditorium (Nashville, Tenn.); United States. Armed Forces Radio Service; Turner, Grant; Sloan, Ralph; Tennessee Travelers; Campbell, Archie; Minnie Pearl; Atkins, Chet; Jones, Grandpa, 1913-1998; Jackson, Tommy; Jordanaires (Musical group); Harman, Buddy; Paycheck, Johnny; Young, Faron; Louvin Brothers; Louvin, Charlie, 1927-2011; Louvin, Ira, 1924-1965</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/1450</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>