<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Tonight We Salute&#8230; Florence, Alabama - Part 2</dc:title>
<dc:description>Part of WSM's Tonight We Salute series, this episode salutes Florence, Alabama (part 2). Personnel include Grant Turner (host), Beasley Smith (WSM Orchestra conductor), WSM Orchestra (performer), Dutch Gordon (WSM Orchestra trombonist), Buddy Hall (performer), Dottie Dillard (performer), Rod Brasfield (performer), Mayor E. F. Martin (guest speaker, Mayor of Florence, Al.), W. H. Mitchell (guest speaker, President of the Florence Chamber of Commerce), Herman K. Longshore (guest speaker, Probate Judge), and Louis A. Eckle (Editor of the Florence Times). Part 1:</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Buddy Hall; Dottie Dillard; WSM Orchestra; Rod Brasfield</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Grant Turner introduces Dottie Dillard -- Hot Dog! That Made Him Mad (Dottie Dillard) -- Grant Turner introduces Herman K. Longshore -- Herman K. Longshore talks -- Ballin' The Jack (WSM Orchestra) -- Grant Turner introduces Louis A. Eckle -- Louis A. Eckle talks -- Stella By Starlight (Buddy Hall) -- Grant Turner introduces Mayor E. F. Martin -- Mayor E. F. Martin talks -- Grant Turner thanks the guests -- Comedy routine (Rod Brasfield) -- Theme (WSM Orchestra) -- Closing statement (Grant Turner)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>16 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR001233</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2014-10-10</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); Turner, Grant; Smith, Beasley; WSM Orchestra; Hall, Buddy (Singer); Dillard, Dottie; Brasfield, Rod; Gordon, Dutch</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/483</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>