<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Various Artist Recordings for a West-Vlaanderen, Belgium Radio Station - Tape 2</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording is of a radio station, believed to be hosted by Elsfan Herzelley, playing various country music hits . According to insert, tape originates from West-Vlannderen, Belgium. Recording is from October 5, 1972. Tape is number two of an unknown number.</dc:description>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Unidentified fiddle tune [featuring unidentified voiceover] (Unidentified) -- (00:29) An unidentified voice introduces the Country Music Month -- (00:34) Unidentified introductory tune ([Unidentified]) -- (01:31) An unidentified voice introduces Elsfan Herzelley (unconfirmed) and Eric Michael's "Crazy Banjo" -- (01:49) Crazy Banjo (Eric Michael) -- (03:48) Herzelley introduces Howard Vokes' "Break the News" -- (04:01) Break the News (Howard Vokes) -- (06:43) Herzelley introduces Dea Doll's "Mag ik U Vragen Mister" -- (07:00) Mag ik U Vragen Mister (Dea Doll) -- (08:54) An unidentified voice and Herzelley introduce Sue Thompson's "A Full Time Job" -- (09:08) A Full Time Job (Sue Thompson) -- (11:13) Unidentified introductory tune [featuring unidentified voiceover] ([Unidentified]) -- (11:58) An unidentified voice and Herzelley introduce Bobbejann's "Juul de Stier" -- (12:12) Juul de Stier (Bobbejaan) -- (14:23) An unidentified voice introduces Freddy Hart's "Got the All Overs You" -- (14:33) Got the All Overs You (Freddy Hart) -- (16:55) An unidentified voice introduces Howard Vokes' "West of the Yukon" -- (17:12) West of the Yukon (Howard Vokes) -- (19:16) An unidentified voice introduces various country artists to discuss the Country Music Month and Nelly Jane's "Nobody" -- (21:18) Nobody (Nelly Jane) -- (23:33) Unidentified outro tune [featuring unidentified voiceover] ([Unidentified]) -- (24:31) Unidentified tune [featuring unidentified and Herzelley voiceover] ([Unidentified]) -- (26:35) Unidentified fiddle tune [featuring unidentified voiceover] (Unidentified) -- (27:00) Various western soundtracks are played [featuring unidentified voiceover] -- (27:42) An unidentified voice discusses the image of American country music -- (28:21) Bonanza (Geoff Love) -- (30:15) An unidentified voice and Herzelley discuss people's idealization of cowboys -- (30:53) Wat Doet een Cowboy in Amsterdam (Bob Schoepen) -- (32:16) An unidentified voice and Herzelley discuss 'hillbilly' music -- (32:52) The Gold Rush is Over (Hank Snow) -- (35:22) An unidentified voice and Herzelley discuss western movies -- (35:55) White Man (Dennis Payne) -- (38:37) An unidentified voice and Herzelley introduce Tex Ritter's "Chuck Wagon Son of a Gun" -- (38:59) Chuck Wagon Son of a Gun (Tex Ritter) -- (41:27) An unidentified voice and Herzelley discuss Jim Reeves -- (41:47) He'll Have to go (Jim Reeves) -- (44:06) The Virginian (Geoff Love) -- (44:18) An unidentified voice and Herzelley discuss Buck Owens -- (44:44) Buck Owens radio spot -- (45:01) Buck Owens radio spot -- (45:18) Looking Back to See (Buck Owens and Susan Rays) -- (47:41) The Virginian (Geoff Love) -- (47:45) An unidentified voice and Herzelley discuss Johnny Cash -- (48:06) The Troubadour (Johnny Cash) -- (50:14)  Unidentified outro tune [featuring unidentified voiceover] ([Unidentified]) -- (51:10) Gun Law [featuring unidentified and Herzelley voiceover] (Geoff Love) -- (52:40) An unidentified voice and Herzelley radio spot listing contributing parties, and both say goodbye</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Insert is in German and a list of the used tracks. Each track has the associated artist listed.</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1448_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1448</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-05-08</dcterms:created>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8971</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>