<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Jimmie Dickens Interview - Biff Collie</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of an interview with Jimmie Dickens (performer).  Interview conducted by Biff Collie.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Jimmie Dickens; Biff Collie</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) 'Little' Jimmie Dickens and Biff Collie start by talking segregationists and the Grand Ole Opry -- (03:04) Dickens compares his own show compared to Opry experience -- (03:21) Collie describes first impressions of Dickens on the Opry -- (04:50) Dickens radio spots and excerpts -- (06:52) Dickens tells is background information until Collie interrupts with comedic relief -- (07:32) Dickens continues to list off family members -- (08:10) Dickens talks about father and family working as a miners -- (8:59) Dickens recalls going to the store and food cooked by his grandparents -- (10:03) Dickens begins to discuss the musical influences in his home -- (11:58) Dickens first performance at a talent show is discussed -- (13:41) Collie and Dickens talk about Dickens height (4'11") and being in a group -- (14:59) Dickens talks about selling Grit newspapers -- (16:08) Dickens talks about retaking semesters in high school -- (16:56) Dickens talks about Roy Acuff and singing in Indianapolis -- (19:56) Dickens talks about meeting Roy Acuff and joining the Opry -- (21:13) Dickens talks about first impressions of Nashville when he pulled up with his house trailer -- (22:03) Dicken's first experience with the Ryman Auditorium and staying with Acuff -- (23:53) Dickens speaks of starting his first band after more than a year in Nashville -- (24:30) Dickens talks about being branded a novelty singer -- (26:42) Dickens talks about his original manager -- (28:18) Dickens speaks of magnetism and drawing crowds -- (29:27) 'Take an Old Cold Tater and Wait' and other successful Dickens records are discussed -- (30:34) Dickens recording with Johnny Carson is described as instantaneous -- (31:19) "Straight-Up" recording is discussed -- (31:38) "Sleeping at the Foot of a Bed" is talked about how it stems from a poem and Boudleaux Bryant's first song was wrote for Dickens -- (33:28) Dickens novelty songs are discussed -- (34:00) Dickens speaks on Acuff's sincerity -- (34:58) Dickens answers "What kind of person is Minnie Pearl?" -- (35:55) Dickens talks about Grandpa Jones growing stories and Ferlin Husky -- (38:24) Dickens unique wardrobe is discussed -- (40:06) Art Satherley's difficulty to work with is brought up -- (41:26) Collie talks about Bob Wills experience about talking during recording -- (42:09) Dickens talks about being on tour and discovering Marty Robins -- (43:42) Dickens and Collie talk about finally getting into the Country Music Hall of Fame -- (45:26) Dickens talks about how life has changed -- (46:06) The Camel Caravan group and Phillip Morris Caravan group are reminisce about -- (48:27) Collie and Dickens discuss how Dickens views new acts as well as Conway Twitty -- (49:20) Dickens talks about opening shows for Louise Mandrell -- (50:00) Dickens endorsement of Garth Brooks and Clint Black -- (50:54) Dickens gives Acuff his selection for greatest country influence with consideration to Ernest Tubb and Hank Williams -- (52:13) Dickens contemplates who he believes should be in the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; -- (53:01) Dickens puts his lens of what he defines as an entertainer -- (54:10) Dickens reflects on what he would like to be remembered for -- (54:44) Dickens talks about a roast and a host having issues -- (56:00) Dickens jokes about being a stand-up comic </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1117_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1117</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-12-20</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Dickens, Little Jimmy, 1920-2015; Collie, Biff;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8309</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>