<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Performance - Georgette Jones - 2011-05-28</dc:title>
<dc:description>Performance and interview by Georgette Jones from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on May 28, 2011.  Companion to a Tammy Wynette exhibit.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2011-05-28</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Georgette Jones; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Performance includes; Your Good Girls Gonna Go Bad; Apartment #9; I Don't Wanna Play House; D.I.V.O.R.C.E.; Golden Ring (with Bill Yates); We're Gonna Hold On (with Bill Yates); Til' I Can Make It On My Own (with Yvonne Abdon); They Call It Making Love (with Yvonne Abdon); Amazing Grace/I'll Fly Away/Will The Circle Be Unbroken/I Saw The Light; You And Me; Womanhood; Near You (with Charlie Allen); Two Story House (with Charlie Allen); Another Chance; I Hope You Knew; Stand By Your Man. Interview conducted by Ali Tonn.  Performance of Slightly Used Woman.</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>CD-R;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>PP0141</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2016-01-07</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Jones, Georgette, 1970-; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/3001</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>