<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Minnie Pearl Comedy Routines - Disc 9,10, 11, 12, 13</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of a variety of clips featuring Minnie Pearl's comedy routines. The various stand up recordings feature: Ernest Tubb (musician), Rod Brasfield (comedian), Ray Price (musician), and George Morgan (musician). The recordings are labeled disc number nine, ten, eleven, twelve, thirteen, and fourteen. The recordings are believed to take place at the Grand Ole Opry. The first recording is from August of 1954. The remaining recordings are from a number of unidentified dates.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1954-08</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Minnie Pearl; Rod Brasfield; Ernest Tubb; Ray Price; George Morgan</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:01) Minnie Pearl reflects on her friend's jealousy when she flirts with members of the Grand Ole Opry -- (01:01) Pearl reflects on visiting New York City, New York -- (02:20) Rod Brasfield asks Pearl about her commute to New York; additionally, Brasfield reflects on his difficulties with women -- (04:55) Unidentified fiddle riff ([Unidentified]) -- (05:00) Pearl reveals that Billy Bird had been chasing her all evening to Ernest Tubb -- (06:21) Pearl reveals the demonstration she witnessed at the grocery store -- (07:19) Brasfield has Pearl read a threatening letter; additionally, Pearl reflects on how Brasfield was called a variety of terrible names -- (08:53) Unidentified fiddle riff ([Unidentified]) -- (09:03) Unidentified fiddle riff ([Unidentified]) -- (09:09) Pearl reflects on how a man got in trouble with his wife, and Pearl discusses a modern miracle -- (11:11) Pearl pokes at Brasfield for his ability to swim -- (11:56) Pearl reflects on how Brasfield missed a swimming party -- (13:32) Unidentified fiddle riff ([Unidentified]) -- (13:41) Unidentified fiddle riff ([Unidentified]) -- (13:45) Pearl contemplates the hospitality of matricide -- (14:47) Pearl and Brasfield discuss Brasfield's experience at the circus -- (17:07) Pearl reflects on helping someone above the age of one-hundred -- (17:44) Unidentified fiddle riff ([Unidentified]) -- (17:55) Unidentified fiddle riff ([Unidentified]) -- (18:03) Pearl reflects on her date with her doctor; additionally, Ray Price and Pearl discuss watching one's figure -- (19:46) Pearl reflects on the suggestions made at the city hall; additionally, Pearl reflects on her romantic partner not getting a job -- (21:55) Unidentified fiddle riff ([Unidentified]) -- (22:05) Pearl expresses her joy for the fall weather; additionally, Pearl and George Morgan reflect on her various attempts at marriage -- (25:32) Pearl calls Nashville 'one big part' -- (26:17) Unidentified fiddle riff ([Unidentified]) -- (26:28) Unidentified fiddle riff ([Unidentified]) -- (26:37) Pearl reflects on her Aunt Abby -- (27:24) Red Foley reads question and answer letters to Pearl; additionally, Pearl expresses her distain to increasing age -- (29:42) Pearl reflects on her family and the local undertaker</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-0216_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-0216</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-08-28</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Pearl, Minnie; Brasfield, Rod; Brasfield, Rod, 1910-1958; Tubb, Ernest; Tubb, Ernest, 1914-1984; Price, Ray, 1926-2013; Morgan, George, 1925-1975;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9439</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>