<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Tanya Tucker Interview - Biff Collie</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of an interview with Tanya Tucker (performer) conducted by Biff Collie. Segment features commentary from La Costa Tucker (performer). Segment is recorded on May 22, 1989.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1989-05-22</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Tanya Tucker; Biff Collie; La Costa Tucker</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Tanya Tucker and Biff Collie discuss Tucker's family dynamic and her father's work -- (02:10) Tucker reflects on her family's artistic talent and her inclination to country music -- (03:48) Tucker discusses the difficulties associated to moving to Nashville; additionally, Tucker recalls meeting Hank Williams and others while recording -- (05:28) Tucker recalls the time she went Mary Davis' home -- (06:58) Tucker describes the moves her father made to foster Tucker's musical career -- (09:02) Tucker discusses the improvisational style her family lived by -- (10:37) Collie and Tucker discuss Tucker's childhood performances, and Tucker discusses how she sent out a number of demo tapes -- (12:24) Tucker recalls how she was punished by a teacher for something her mother did -- (15:21) Tucker praises her middle school teachers -- (16:09) Tucker and La Costa discuss the time Tucker lost a talent show to La Costa -- (18:07) La Costa Tucker and Tanya joke about their sibling rivalry -- (19:33) Tanya discusses how she had to sing in order to get approval to rent a home -- (20:27) Tanya reflects on how she met Billy Sherrill -- (22:48) Tanya reveals she was twelve the first time she recorded a record -- (23:30) Collie brings back up the story of how Tanya had to sing in order to get approval to rent a home -- (25:30) Tanya discuses how Sherrill gave Tucker access to a number of great songs -- (28:24) Collie and Tanya discuss the first session Tanya had done with Sherrill -- (31:04) Tanya reflects on the interesting people in her life that influenced her -- (32:32) Tanya and Collie discusses Tanya's successful albums, and Tanya continuing to work with Sherrill -- (33:53) Tanya discusses continuing her education while being a successful artist -- (35:37) Tanya recalls moving to Nashville in 1977 -- (35:50) Tanya recalls her favorite part of moving away from Arizona, and Collie and Tanya discuss the rough parts of music -- (37:02) Tanya reflects on how she signed with MCA Records when she was sixteen -- (38:34) Tanya continues to discuss the difficulty in leaving Sherrill -- (39:23) Tanya reflects on the difficulty with her coming to terms with her new MCA producer -- (42:34) Tanya reveals her desire for a relationship, and Tanya and Collie discuss Tanya's love interests [recording skips] -- (44:17) Collie and Tanya discuss the difference of living in Hollywood and Nashville -- (46:09) Tanya and Collie discuss Tanya's past drug problems -- (51:09) Collie and Tanya discuss how Tanya almost owned a boutique -- (51:45) Tanya and Collie discuss Tanya's relationship with Glen Campbell -- (52:56) Tanya reflects on what she would be doing if she was not an artist -- (55:58) Collie inquires about Tanya's horse collection, and Tanya reveals she sold them to Loretta Lynn -- (57:00) Tanya describes how Jimmy Rogers inspires her, and Tanya reveals her part of the Superstar Salute to Jimmy Rogers -- (1:00:00) Tanya discusses how she created the video for "Daddy and Home" -- (1:02:40) Tanya recalls meeting Elvis Presley, and Tanya discusses Ernest Tubb -- (1:04:36) Tanya and La Costa joke about La Costa taking dates from Tanya, and both discuss Tanya's children -- (1:06:26) Collie and the Tuckers praise each other and say their goodbyes </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1260_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1260</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-02-22</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Tucker, Tanya; Collie, Biff;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8545</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>