<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Interview - Dave Cobb - 2017-01-28</dc:title>
<dc:description>Interview program titled Music Masters with Dave Cobb from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on January 28, 2017.  Interviewer is Peter Cooper.  Includes excerpts of recorded audio and audio from video. </dc:description>
<dc:date>2017-01-28</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Dave Cobb; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Walk-In Music / (10:07) Opening comments and introduction of Dave Cobb by Peter Cooper / (13:17) Opening comments / (13:35) Talks about his concept of the role of a music producer / (14:02) Why he brings artists through the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum for inspiration / (14:50) His thoughts on where and how the magic happens during a recording session / (14:58) Dave talks about his background and his Pentecostal preacher grandmother in the 1950's / (17:18) Story about his grandmother meeting the family of William Lee Golden / (18:06) Musical background and influences / (19:05) The influence of the Rolling Stones and Gram Parsons / (19:55) Plays excerpt of Country Honk by the Rolling Stones / (21:05) Dave comments on his musical influences and how he found country music / (21:33) Talks about the Georgia music scene that he grew up in / (22:21) Musical instrument background / (22:51) His parents recognizing his musical talent / </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(23:31) First experiences in a recording studio and the education of that / (25:43) Moving from Georgia to California / (26:40) Being introduced to and working with Shooter Jennings / (28:34) Plays excerpts of the recording of 4th Of July by Shooter Jennings / (30:06) How the production of 4th Of July came together / (32:24) Meeting Jamie Johnson at a party, deciding to move to Nashville to work with him and why he loves working in Nashville / (33:56) Meeting Sturgill Simpson and the caliber of musicians and songwriters in Nashvile / (35:01) Working with Jason Isbell and Traci Thomas and the recording of the Isbell album Southeastern / (39:03) Audio from video of the making of the song 24 Frames by Jason Isbell / (41:28) His input into the recording of 24 Frames and the input of Jason Isbell and his musicians / (42:28) His role in providing direction and chemistry in making a record / (44:43) Having fun and deciding who he wants to work with and why / </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0010</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2018-04-25</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Cobb, Dave; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/7272</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>