<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Performance - Next Women of Country - 2017-06-09</dc:title>
<dc:description>Performance along with discussion by Brandy Clark, Jillian Jacqueline, Carly Pearce, Maggie Rose, and Lucie Silvas from the CMA Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on June 9, 2017.  Hosted by CMT executive Leslie Fram.  </dc:description>
<dc:date>2017-06-09</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Brandy Clark; Jillian Jacqueline; Carly Pearce; Maggie Rose; Lucie Silvas;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Program begins in progress with comments from Lucie Silvas regarding her move to Nashville / (01:10) Performs My Old Habits (Lucie Silvas with vocal accompaniment) / (04:52) Leslie introduces Maggie Rose / (05:09) Maggie shares her story about her journey to Nashville / (06:19) Introduces the next song and performs More Dreams Than Dollars (Maggie Rose with Tom Maxwell on guitar and vocal accompaniment) / (09:57) Leslie introduces Jillian Jacqueline / (10:30) Jillian tells her story about her journey to Nashville / (11:37) Introduces the next song and performs Hate Me / (15:35) Leslie introduces Carly Pearce / (16:23) Carly shares the story about her journey to Nashville / (18:17) Introduces the next song / (19:07) Performs Ride Home (Carly Pearce with vocal accompaniment) / (22:54) Leslie introduces Brandy Clark / (24:11) Brandy shares her story about her journey to Nashville / (26:17) Introduces the next song / (26:40) Performs Daughter (Brandy Clark with vocal accompaniment) / (30:18) Lucie introduces her next song / (30:40) Performs Just For The Record / (34:25) Maggie introduces her next song / (36:27) Performs Body On Fire (Maggie with Tom Maxwell) / (40:38) Jillian introduces her next song / (42:36) Performs Sad Girls (Jillian) / (45:51) Carly introduces her next song / (47:42) Performs Every Little Thing (Carly) / (51:05) Brandy introduces her next song / (51:33) Talks with her fellow performers and they announce their upcoming appearances / (54:33) Performs Three Kids (Brandy) / (57:43) Closing comments with introduction of accompanying musicians and vocalists / (58:46) Muted audio signal / (01:05:43) FILE END                 </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 48/24;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0166</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2019-06-13</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Clark, Brandy; Jacqueline, Jillian; Pearce, Carly; Rose, Maggie; Silvas, Lucie; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9187</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>