<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>George Morgan Show - First Show - 1950-09-29 - Stereo</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of the first episode of the George Morgan radio show, featuring: Grant Turner (announcer), George Morgan (host, performer), Hank Williams (performer), Jordanaires (performers), Liza Waters (performer), and Hank Garland (performer) from September 29, 1950 on radio station WSM (Nashville, Tenn.) The recording is recorded in stereo tracking.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1950-09-29</dc:date>
<dc:creator>George Morgan; Jordanaires; Grant Turner; Hank Williams; Liza Waters; Hank Garland</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Grant Turner introduces the George Morgan Show -- (00:06) Unidentified tune [featuring Grant Turner introducing the George Morgan Show]([Unidentified]) -- (00:41) You Can't Break My Heart (It's Been Broken Before) (George Morgan) -- (01:59) Morgan greets the audience and describes the reasoning behind creating the George Morgan -- (02:40) My Dearest, My Darlin' (George Morgan) -- (05:27) Morgan introduces the Jordanaires -- (05:57) Roll on Jordan (Jordanaires) -- (08:12) Morgan introduces Hank Williams; additionally, Williams and Morgan joke about William' weight -- (09:08) They'll Never Take Her Love From Me (Hank Williams) -- (12:05) Morgan thanks Williams and performs a skit about interruptions with Liza Waters -- (14:35) Sugarfoot Rag (Hank Garland) -- (16:10) Morgan and Turner discuss how people can communicate with the show -- (17:15) I'll Sail My Ship Alone (George Morgan) -- (19:34) Morgan is told by the Jordanaires that they are performing later that night in Ashland, Tennessee -- (20:20) Swing Down Sweet Chariot (Jordanaires) -- (22:44) Morgan inquires as to why Turner is counting the empty chairs at the Grand Ole Opry -- (23:52) Long Gone Lonesome Blues (Hank Williams) -- (26:32) Morgan thanks Williams -- (26:47) Don't be Afraid to Love Me (George Morgan) -- (28:02) Unidentified tune [featuring George Morgan and Grant Turner outro statements] ([Unidentified])</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-0225_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-0225</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-08-29</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Morgan, George, 1925-1975; Jordanaires (Musical group); Turner, Grant; Williams, Hank, 1923-1953; Waters, Liza; Garland, Hank, 1930-2004;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9569</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>