<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Hank Snow Benefit at the Grand Ole Opry - 1978-08-30 - Part 1</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of the Hank Snow Benefit Concert at the Grand Ole Opry. The segment is hosted by T. Tommy Cutrer (musician) and features performances by: Opry Staff Band (musical group), Boots Randolph (musician), Dottie Rambo (musician), Bill Jones and the Promenaders (dance group), and Skeeter Davis (musician). The recording is from August 30, 1978. The tape is part one of four.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1978-08-30</dc:date>
<dc:creator>T. Tommy Cutrer; Boots Randolph; Dottie Rambo; Bill Jones and the Promenaders; Opry Staff Band; Skeeter Davis</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:06) T. Tommy Cutrer introduces reverend Jimmie Rodgers Snow to perform a prayer -- (01:46) Cutrer greets the audience and discusses the purpose of Snow's benefit shows; additionally, Cutrer introduces Boots Randolph -- (03:42) Ya'll Come (Boots Randolph) -- (06:05) Unidentified tune (Boots Randolph) -- (08:34) Randolph recalls his previous experience with the Grand Ole Opry -- (09:42) Movin' on Up (Boots Randolph) -- (12:27) You Needed Me (Boots Randolph) -- (15:56) Saxophone Medley (Boots Randolph) -- (21:40) Randolph introduces his band members: Eddie Seals, Joe Brand, Steve Slate and Jay Seals -- (22:48) Yakety Yak (Boots Randolph) -- (24:58) Unidentified tune (Boots Randolph) -- (25:30) Cutrer jokingly compares the band to Johnny Carson and addresses the important members of the audience -- (27:50) Amazing Grace (Dottie Rambo) -- (30:41) Jubilee Band (Dottie Rambo) -- (32:39) Rambo praises the members of the benefit -- (33:51) I Go to the Rock (Dottie Rambo) -- (37:38) Rambo addresses her daughter and husband -- (38:46) When Lovers Become Friends [unconfirmed] (Dottie Rambo) -- (42:46) I Will Glory in the Cross of Jesus (Dottie Rambo) -- (47:19) Cutrer praises Rambo and introduces the square dance group: Bill Jones and the Promenaders -- (48:10) Unidentified tune (Opry Staff Band) -- (51:17) Cutrer stops the program to discuss that Ralph Slone had a, presumed, heart attack -- (52:58) Your Cheating Heart (Skeeter Davis) -- (55:21) Am I That Easy to Forget (Skeeter Davis) -- (58:22) Just When I Needed You Most (Skeeter Davis) -- (1:02:36) I'll Fly Away (Skeeter Davis) -- (1:06:24) The End of the World [incomplete] (Skeeter Davis)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1062_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1062</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-07-29</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Cutrer, T. Tommy; Randolph, Boots; Randolph, Boots, 1927-2007; Rambo, Dottie, 1934-2008; Bill Jones and the Promenaders; Jones, Bill; Opry Staff Band; Davis, Skeeter;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9295</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>