<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Rick Riman tapes - tape 2 of 5 - Side two - Channel two</dc:title>
<dc:description>Bluegrass performances collected by Rick Riman.  On loan from Craig S. Wales.  Party at Dillards' house in Topanga Canyon, California on May 7 and 8, 1963.  Continued from side one.  Also includes finger style solo guitar playing from David Laibman and Paul Cadwell playing solo banjo, both credited to 1964.  Performers listed on insert include Bill Keith (banjo), Doug Dillard (banjo), Bob Yellin (banjo), Kenny Baker (fiddle), Tracy Schwartz (fiddle), Dean Webb (mandolin), Del McCoury (guitar), Clarence White (Guitar), Rodney Dillard (guitar), Skip Conover (dobro), Roger Bush (bass). </dc:description>
<dc:date>1963-05-07; 1963-05-08</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Bill Keith; Doug Dillard; Bob Baker; Tracy Schwartz; Dean Webb; Del McCoury; Clarence White; Rodney Dillard; Skip Conover; Roger Bush; David Laibman; Paul Cadwell;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Dillard's House Party -- (00:08) Rawhide (begins in progress) / (04:43) Rawhide (abrupt ending) / (07:50) Announcement made that at this point on the tape Del has replaced Rod on the guitar / (10:06) Prisoner's Song (Del McCoury and Rodney Dillard-vocals) / (13:25) Cincinnati Rag / (16:29) Smith's Rag ? (Doug Dillard-banjo and Clarence White-mandolin) / (19:10) Stoney Creek (Doug Dillard-banjo and Clarence White-mandolin) / (23:07) Salt Creek (Bill Keith-banjo) / (26:41) Dixie Hoedown (Bill Keith and Doug Dillard-banjo) / (30:53) Old Joe Clark (Bill Keith and Doug Dillard-banjo) / (33:57) Bury Me Beneath The Willow - tape starts in progress (Bill Keith and Doug Dillard-banjo, Tracy Swartz-fiddle) / (36:58) Little Darling Pal Of Mine (Bill Keith and Doug Dillard-banjo) / (39:52) Dixie Breakdown (Bill Keith) / (43:51) Santa Claus - tape starts in progress (Bill Keith) / (46:12) Signal dropout / (48:18) Possibly Dallas Rag (David Laibman-solo guitar) / </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(49:46) Maple Leaf Rag (David Laibman-solo guitar) / (52:06) Red Carpet Rag (David Laibman-solo guitar) / (56:07) Black And White Rag (David Laibman-solo guitar) / (58:58) Nutcracker Rag (David Laibman-solo guitar) / (01:00:43) Unidentified song possibly Cataracts Rag (David Laibman-solo guitar) / (01:03:42) Nola (David Laibman-solo guitar) / (01:06:51) Temptation Rag (David Laibman-solo guitar) / (01:09:54) Unidentified Song (David Laibman-solo guitar) / (01:12:12) Kitten On The Keys (David Laibman-solo guitar) / (01:15:32) Blues (David Laibman-solo guitar) / (01:16:15) Paul Cadwell with introduction to his performances of classical banjo pieces (1964?) / (01:16:49) Pearling Brook (Paul Cadwell-solo banjo) / (01:18:44) Leisure Moments (Paul Cadwell-solo banjo) / (01:22:16) Dutch Hymn of Thanksgiving (Paul Cadwell-solo banjo) / (01:24:40) Beethoven's Minuet in G - played in C (Paul Cadwell-solo banjo) / (01:26:46) Unidentified Song / (01:28:53) Unidentified Song / (01:29:44) Recording End /</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Typed content notes on notebook paper inserted in tape box.</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:format>1/4 inch audio tape - 4 quarter tracks;</dc:format>
<dc:format>3.75 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Xfer.2017.02 - side 2 channel 2</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2017-08-18</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Yellin, Bob; Schwartz, Tracy; Webb, Dean; Dilliard, Rodney; Conover, Skip; Bush, Roger; White, Clarence, 1944-1973; Dillard, Douglas Flint, 1937-2012; Keith, Bill, 1939-2015; Baker, Kenny, 1926-2011;  	McCoury, Del, 1939- ; Laibman, David; Cadwell, Paul; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8174</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>