<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Nashville Cats program - Mac McAnally - 2017-09-09</dc:title>
<dc:description>Interview program on the life and career to date of Mac McAnally from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on September 9, 2017.  Program hosted by Bill Lloyd.  Includes audio from video and selected audio excerpts.  Includes performances by McAnally.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2017-09-09</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Mac McAnally;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Walk-in music / (01:38) Opening announcements by Abi Tapia / (03:30) Opening comments, introductions of past Nashville Cats in attendance and introduction by Bill Lloyd / (05:55) Audio from video / (08:56) Mac talks about his appearance on Monday Night Concert and first time working with Ricky Skaggs on a Dolly Parton recording / (11:06) Mac talks about his family background and growing up / (13:19) Mac talks about his musical background / (13:37) Talks about his Mom playing piano in church and his first focus being on piano / (15:12) Playing piano in bands in junior high and high school / (16:08) Talks about his first band in a honky tonk / (17:56) Beginning to play in recording studios in Tupelo, playing in Tennessee state line honky tonks and meeting the Muscle Shoals musicians / (20:04) Beginning to write songs, talk about his literary influences and his first song They Call Me Jesus / (21:36) Talks about how he got signed to a record label / </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(23:58) Touring in support of Randy Newman and being a fan / (24:51) Comment on the song She's A Doll / (25:37) Talks about the music business when he first became a recording artist at a young age and his motivation or lack of / (28:49) Talks about his love of songwriting / (29:52) Talks about balancing being a songwriting, a musician and a record producer / (32:23) Plays medley of excerpted recordings featuring Mac and his guitar playing / (34:50) Talks about the song Minimum Love and Jerry Wexler / (37:30) Talks about the thrill of working with big artists, tells story about working with Hank Williams Jr. on the song Family Tradition / (38:27) Talks about Hank Jr. recording the first song Mac ever had recorded called Daddy and tells story about the recording session / (40:43) Talks about deciding to Nashville / (41:49) Talks about writing Old Flame / (42:33) Plays excerpted recording of Old Flame by Alabama / </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/24;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0060</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2018-08-10</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>McAnally, Mac; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8076</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>