<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Opryland Music Demo Recordings - Y-114</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording is of a group of demo recordings from Opryland Music. Recordings are from an unknown date and recorded by a number of unknown bands. Tape is labeled Y-114. </dc:description>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) I Want no Wills or Ways of My Own (C. W. Miller) -- (03:01) If You're Looking For a Fella (W. Blevins) -- (05:37) I'll Feel Blue Til Then (P. Blevins) -- (08:31) I Gotta Go Get My Baby (M. Rainwater and K. Adelman) -- (11:16) I'll Fear No More (R. Omans) -- (13:38) I'm Living to Live (Not Living to Die) (R. Omans) -- (15:46) I Miss Your Lovin' (H. Hart and D. Darling) -- (18:36) I Don't Believe You Now (A. Vaughn and R. Cochran) -- (21:06) I Know I'll Find Another Way (J. Jericho) -- (24:00) I'm a Hen Pecked Man (R. B. Ford) -- (26:51) I'll Try All My Life (R. B. Ford) -- (29:28) I'll Fly Away (W. S. Stevenson) -- (31:45) Come Unto Me (W. S. Stevenson) -- (34:41) Come Back to Baby (B. Flournoy) -- (36:26) Counterfeit Love (C. Sparks and W. S. Stevenson) -- (38:10) Cold Blooded Woman (O. Ervin) -- (40:34) (I Want Some) Country Lovin' (B. Bobo, C. Lewis, and W. S. Stevenson) -- (42:19) Christ Can Heal a Broken Heart (H. Vanderpool) -- (44:47) The Center Cross (H. Beaver and T. Beaver) -- (47:43) Cool Gator Shoes (T. Blake and W. S. Stevenson) -- (50:07) Cotton Pickin' Boogie (P. Freeman) -- (53:00) Checkin' Up Blues (E. White) -- (55:48) Cool Down Mama (E. J. Hunter) -- (58:12) Chicken Pickin' Boogie (P. Freeman) -- (1:00:51) Cowboy Bugle Boy (G. Bertolero) -- (1:03:11) Don't Bother Me (C. Burns) -- (1:05:56) Darling I Don't Understand (C. Hallmark and J. James) -- (1:08:44) Dream Waltz (J. De Noone) -- (1:11:42) Darkness (H. Cassity) -- (1:15:26) Doughboys in Heaven (R. Crandall, W. Ryan, and E. Hollenbeck) -- (1:18:07) Dusty Trail (D. Denning) -- (1:21:12) Double Trouble (C. Pryor and R. Bristol) -- (1:24:05) The Dying Solider on Foreign Fields (J. B. Burk) -- (1:26:32) Oh to be a Christan (S. Foster) -- (1:29:32) Waltz of San Antone (R. Tompkins) -- (1:32:35) Won't You Come on Home [Incomplete] (E. Foreman)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1310_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1310</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-03-15</dcterms:created>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8648</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>