<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Vern Gosdin Interview - Biff Collie</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of an interview with Vern Gosdin (performer) conducted by Biff Collie.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1989-05-23</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Vern Gosdin; Biff Collie</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Vern Gosdin talks about dreaming a singer -- (00:40) Gosdin talks about being one of eleven kids being raised on a rock farm and discovering his father's moon shining -- (02:17) Gosdin talks about his families musical talents and eventual professional work -- (02:53) Gosdin talks about the first time he sang in front of a crowd (a local talent contest) -- (03:38) Biff Collie and Gosdin talk about his first guitar being gifted to him and his father's disagreement with music -- (04:34) Gosdin talks about why he started writing music and his fascination with country stars -- (05:21) Collie challenges Gosdin to name all of his siblings -- (06:12) Collie and Gosdin talk about first talent show in-depth -- (07:06) Gosdin and Collie discuss emanating who they heard on the Opry and Gosdin talks about picking up various instruments -- (08:01) Gosdin talks about The Golden State Boys group he joined immediately after moving to California and how his first album was rock and roll -- (09:02) Gosdin talks about continuing to work with the Golden State Boys and his idea of the loss of bluegrass -- (10:54) Gosdin talks about being a glass maker in Atlanta Georgia and moving to Nashville to record -- (13:01) Gosdin and Collie talk about the Gosdin Family Gospel Show -- (14:32) Collie says phrases for Gosdin to reflect on starting with a bar he owned -- (15:50) Gosdin recalls his 1970 Philippine Tour and rush of the shows -- (16:58) Gosdin talks about his driver during the Philippine Tour fighting in a field to settle their differences -- (17:54) Gosdin talks about the Blue Room and seeing The Lumen Brothers -- (18:54) Gosdin talks about Christmas 1981 with George Jones and meeting him on tour in London, England -- (20:16) Gosdin says who he'd enjoy recording with -- (20:52) Collie brings up how quotable Gosdin is while reading critics reviews -- (22:06) Gosdin expresses how he does not like that people think they need to put him on a pedestal -- (22:58) "Yesterday's gone" is talked about -- (23:13) "Til the End" and Gosdin's sons are discussed -- (23:38) The recording of "Never My Love" is talked about -- (24:23) "Dream of Me" is talked about how it almost was not recorded -- (24:55) "Break My Mind" is briefly touched on -- (25:15) "If You're Gonna Do Me Wrong, Do Me Right" was wrote for Gosdin's wife </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1120_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1120</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-12-21</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Gosdin, Vern; Collie, Biff;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8314</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>