<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Performance - Next Women of Country - 2018-06-09</dc:title>
<dc:description>Performances and discussions by Ashley Campbell, Abby Anderson, Bailey Bryan, Alyssa Bonagurua and Ruby Stewart aka the Sisterhood Band and Cassadee Pope from the CMA Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum.  Program hosted by CMT executive Leslie Fram.   </dc:description>
<dc:date>2018-06-09</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Ashley Campbell; Bailey Bryan; Abby Anderson; Alyssa Bonagurua; Ruby Stewart; Cassadee Pope;  </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Walk-in music / (23:37) Opening comment from Abi Tapia and introduction of participants / (27:49) Opening comments by Leslie / (28:41) Leslie introduces Ashley Campbell / (29:19) Ashley talks about her songwriting journey and the making of her first album and music video / (31:22) Ashley talks about what she learned about touring from her father, Glen Campbell and talks about how many instruments that she plays / (32:04) Leslie introduces Bailey Bryan /(32:38) Bailey talks about her journey to Nashville, her songwriting and new music / (35:52) Leslie introduces the Sisterhood (Alyssa Bonagurua and Ruby Stewart) / (36:11) Alyssa talks about how the Sisterhood got together and Ruby talks about her journey to Nashville / (40:43) Leslie introduces Abby Anderson / (41:24) Abby talks about her journey to Nashville and her songwriting / (44:10) Leslie introduces Cassadee Pope / (44:52) Cassadee talks about the past year and her journey / (47:49) Leslie talks about Cassadee / (48:27) Ashley introduces her song / (49:53) Performs Better Boyfriend (Ashley with guitar and fiddle accompaniment by Eli Bishop) / (53:30) Bailey introduces her song / (54:55) Performs This Without Us (Bailey with guitar accompaniment) / (58:27) The Sisterhood introduce their song / (01:01:09) Performs Half Way (Alyssa and Ruby with guitar accompaniment) / (01:05:05) Abby introduces her song / (01:05:36) Performs The Naked Truth (Abby with guitar accompaniment) / (01:08:51) Cassadee introduces her song / (01:10:06) Performs Take You Home (Cassadee with accompaniment by Pat McCarthy) / (01:13:37) Leslie with comments / (01:13:47) Ashley introduces her next song / (01:14:30) Performs  Wish I Wanted To (Ashley with Eli Bishop on fiddle) / (01:18:20) Bailey introduces her next song / (01:21:10) Performs Watered Down (Bailey with guitar accompaniment) / (01:24:36) The Sisterhood introduce their next song / (01:26:01)  Performs Doors (The Sisterhood) / (01:30:43) Abby introduces her next song / (01:33:14) Performs Make Him Wait (Abby with piano and guitar accompaniment) / (01:37:07) Cassadee introduces her next song / (01:37:49) Performs Wasting All These Tears / (01:41:24) Leslie with final comments / (01:41:53) Walk-out music / (01:47:03) Walk-out music ends / (01:51:56) Audio pop (right channel only) / (02:05:08) FILE END                       </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0171</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2019-06-09</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Campbell, Ashley; Bryan, Bailey; Anderson, Abby; Bonagurua, Alyssa; Stewart, Ruby; The Sisterhood (Musical group); Pope, Cassadee; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9307</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>