<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Discussion - Springfield, Missouri - 2018-05-19</dc:title>
<dc:description>Discussion and performance celebrating Springfield, Missouri with Eric Ambel, Dave Hoekstra, Vance Powell, Scott Siman and Abbey Waterworth.  Presented in celebration of the screening of the documentary film The Center of Nowhere: The Spirit and Sounds of Springfield, MO.  Moderated by Michael McCall.  Includes performance from Eric Ambel.  Includes selected audio excerpts and audio from video. </dc:description>
<dc:date>2018-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Eric Ambel; Dave Hoekstra; Vance Powell; Scott Siman; Abbey Waterworth;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Walk-in Music / (03:20) Opening announcements by Abi Tapia / (03:52) Opening comments by Michael McCall and introduction of panel participants / (10:38) Audio from video of Red Foley on the Ozark Jubilee / (12:34) Michael talks about the importance of the Ozark Jubilee television program and it's musicians / (13:59) Eric talks about the guitar that Grady Martin is shown playing / (14:32) Scott talks about the Ozark Jubilee TV show, it's influence and how Si Siman got Red Foley to join the show / (17:47) Scott talks about the previous syndicated shows originating in Springfield, Ralph Foster and his Dad finding and booking talent including Chet Atkins / (19:53) Scott talks about his feeling on the lasting legacy of the Ozark Jubilee / (21:36) Eric talks about his musical background and his relationship to Springfield / (27:14) Eric talks about producer Lou Whitney and his influence on him / (27:57) Vance talks about his background, his relationship to Springfield and to Lou Whitney  / (33:27) Dave talks about his background and relationship to Springfield and Lou Whitney / (34:47) Abbey talks about her background and her relationship to Springfield / (38:58) Talk about Springfield being isolated from other areas of the country / (39:25) Abbey talks about her album Rose Bridge which focuses on the music of Springfield / (40:27) Excerpt of recordings from the Rose Bridge album / (42:24) Talks about the previously heard audio and story about Take My Breath Away / (44:17) Scott talks about song publishing and how his father Si Siman got into the publishing business and about songwriter Wayne Carson / (51:42) Mention of other artists with a Ozark Jubilee TV Springfield connection and Brenda Lee / (52:49) Scott talks about the Eddy Arnold song Somebody Like Me / (54:00) Scott talks about Brenda Lee / (55:30) Audio from video of Brenda on the Ozark Jubilee / (56:41) Scott talks about the hand painted set seen on the previous clip and the song Always On My Mind and Willie's version of the song / (58:50) Eric talks about recording the song Always On My Mind / (01:01:10) Scott talks about bringing Wayne Carson to Nashville / (01:04:07) Audio excerpt of the demo recordings of songs written by Wayne Carson / (01:06:03) Talks about Johnny Paycheck and then Wayne Carson's abilities at a songwriter / (01:07:22) Scott talks about Wayne Carson and Si Siman opening a recording studio in Springfield / (01:08:25) Talk about the Ozark Mountain Daredevils and the purity of the music in Springfield / (01:10:37) Abbey talks about her do-it-yourself mentality coming from her upbringing and talks about Si Siman / (01:12:12) Abbey talks about a paper she wrote for her museum studies class focusing on Si and Ralph Foster and what she learned from them / (01:13:15) Scott tells story about early issues with Springfield television transmission to the network and using the television station at the University of Missouri in Columbia for the first Ozark Jubilee shows / (01:15:19) Eric talks about when the Del-Lords first showed up in Springfield, the bands reaction to the town and tells some stories about their days there / (01:21:43) Vance talks about and tells stories about Lou Whitney / (01:25:34) Audio from video of The Skeletons / (01:26:48) Talk about the previous video clip and band members seen in the clip / (01:28:00) Michael thanks the panelists for their participation / (01:29:47) Stage gets cleared for performance / (01:30:41) Eric Ambel performance opening comments / (01:31:03) Eric introduces his first song / (01:31:48) Performs 30 Days In the Workhouse (Eric Ambel) / (01:34:32) Eric talks about Lou Whitney and introduces the next song / (01:36:02) Performs Always On My Mind (Eric Ambel) / 01:39:52) Final comments from Eric / (01:40:05) Walk-out Music / (01:41:02) FILE END                                       </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded as an mp3 file at 44.1</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0117</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2019-02-09</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Ambel, Eric; Hoekstra, Dave; Powell, Vance; Siman, Scott; Waterworth, Abbey; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8606</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>