<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Performance - Bobby Earl Smith - 2018-05-27</dc:title>
<dc:description>Musicians spotlight program featuring Bobby Earl Smith from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on May 27, 2018.  Includes appearances by Kimmie Rhodes and Marcia Ball.  Accompanied by Eric Smith.  Presented in support of the exhibit Outlaws &amp; Armadillos: Country&#8217;s Roaring &#700;70s</dc:description>
<dc:date>2018-05-27</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Bobby Earl Smith; Kimmie Rhodes; Marcia Ball;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Opening comments by Michael Gray begin in progress / (03:05) Opening comments by Bobby Earl / (03:10) Performs Mercy Me Mercy My / (05:48) Introduction of the next song / (06:51) Performs Unidentified song likely titled The Day The Fire Came / (11:26) Bobby Earl introduces Kimmie Rhodes / (11:47) Bobby Earl comments on the hospitality he's received in Nashville and thanks the folks at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum / (14:25) Performs Rear View Mirror (Bobby Earl with Kimmie) / (18:14) Bobby Earl and Kimmie talk about when they met, Kimmie's book and talk about Joe Gracey / (19:44) Intros the next song / (21:00) Performs Meet Me At The Menger (Bobby Earl and Kimmie) / (24:16) Bobby Earl brings out Jolie Goodnight Gracey and Marcia Ball / (25:18) Introduces the next song / (25:45) Performs Contrabandistas (Bobby Earl with Marcia and Kimmie) / (28:53) Introduces the next song / (30:51) Performs Muleshoe (Bobby Earl with Kimmie) / (33:48) Bobby Earl talks about the inspiration for the last song / (34:18) Bobby Earl talks about Kimmie / (34:35) Kimmie talks about meeting Joe Gracey and Bobby Earl Smith (The Jackalope Brothers) and meeting other important people in her life / (37:07) Kimmie talks about meeting and working with the Jackalope Brothers and introduces her first time / (37:58) Performs No Next Time (Kimmie Rhodes with Marcia and Bobby Earl) / (41:20) Bobby Earl talks about the previous song and talks about the next song / (42:00)  Performs Outlaws And Armadillos (Bobby Earl and Kimmie) / (45:14) Bobby Earl and Kimmie talk about Marcia Ball / (46:57) Marcia talks about meeting Bobby Earl and Kimmie talks about Marcia / (48:17) Marcia intros the next song / (48:31) Performs World Full Of Love (Marcia and Kimmie) / (52:27) Bobby Earl and Kimmie with closing comments / (53:34) Intros the next song / (54:00) May The Lord Watch Over You (Bobby Earl and Kimmie) / (56:04) Final comments / )56:14) Walk-out music / (57:45) FILE END                           </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded as an mp3 file at 44.1</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0122</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2019-02-20</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Smith, Bobby Earl; Rhodes, Kimmie; Ball, Marcia; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8605</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>