<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Merle Haggard interview - Ralph Emery</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of a phone interview with Merle Haggard (performer), as conducted by Ralph Emery on May 1, 1974.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1974-05-01</dc:date>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Ralph Emery introduces Merle Haggard -- (00:22) Merle Haggard talks about being on the cover of Time magazine -- (01:25) Haggard talks about the content in his Time magazine article, including his train -- (02:22) Haggard talks about being too busy to keep up with his train hobby -- (03:16) Haggard talks about it being a great honor to represent country music on the cover of Time -- (03:32) Haggard talks about how much time was spent on the article -- (04:25) Haggard talks about how long the interviewing process took for the article, and that he was quite pleased with the article -- (06:00) Haggard talks about why he is recording in Texas rather than Bakersfield -- (06:40) Haggard talks about making appearances around Texas while recording, and when he plans to come back to Nashville -- (07:13) Haggard talks about taking a month off each year to go fishing -- (07:55) Haggard talks about some of his other favorite fishing spots around the country -- (08:45) Haggard talks about James Franciscus -- (09:28) Haggard talks about wanting to do more television in the future -- (11:00) Haggard talks about when his next recording will be released -- (11:25) Haggard thanks Ralph and concludes the interview -- (11:42) Emery ends the segment</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-5-00506_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-5-00506</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-03-19</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Haggard, Merle, 1937-2016; Haggard, Merle; Emery, Ralph; WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8656</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>