<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Performance - Music Matters 2018-03-08</dc:title>
<dc:description>Music Matters performances celebrating the First Amendment co-hosted by the Country Music Hall of Fame and the First Amendment Center at the CMA Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on February 23, 2018.  Hosted by Ken Paulson. Features band members Joseph Wooten, Sara Beck, Dez Dickerson and Bill Lloyd.  Includes recorded audio excerpts.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2018-03-08</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Ken Paulson; Joseph Wooten; Sara Beck; Dez Dickerson; Bill Lloyd;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Opening comments by Ali Tonn in progress / (01:47) Introduction of participating musicians and artists / (03:55) Performs Revolution (Unidentified on lead vocal)  / (07:34) Ken Paulson talks about free speech and music / (08:44) Plays recording of Roar / (09:08) Plays recording of All About That Bass / (09:52) Ken talks about songs with messages in them / (10:55) Perform Yankee Doodle (Joseph Wooten on vocal and piano) / (11:28) Ken talks about the political side of Yankee Doodle / (11:50) Performs little known verse from Yankee Doodle (Joseph Wooten on vocal and piano) / (12:14) Ken talks about the end of the revolutionary war and makes compares that to the civil rights movement / (13:26) Performs This Little Light Of Mine (Sara Beck on vocal) / (14:51) Ken talks about free speech and introduces the next song / (15:51) Performs Happy Birthday (Unidentified vocalists) / (17:02) Ken talks about the activism in the 1960's and how important it is / (17:18) Blowing In The Wind (Bill Lloyd on lead vocal) / (19:58) Ken talks about songs written to promote causes / (20:58) Performs Taxi (Sara with lead vocal) / (22:47) Ken talks about offensive songs / (25:06) Performs (You're) Having My Baby (Dez and Sara on vocals) / (27:09) Ken talks about sexiest songs / (27:51) Performs I Am Woman (Sara on lead vocals) / (29:45) Ken talks about songs dealing in reality / (30:23) Performs Coal Miners Daughter (Sara on lead vocal) / (32:04) Ken talks about songs about teenagers / () Performs Fifteen (Sara of lead vocal) / (34:23) Ken talks about censorship of music / (38:09) Performs Wake Up, Little Susie (Dez and Bill on vocals) / (39:25) Ken talks about political correctness / (41:56) Performs Short People (Bill on lead vocal) / (43:28) Ken talks about popular music and performing with two turntables, the creation of hip hop music and asks the audience question regarding where the phrase hip hop originated / (45:42) Plays excerpted recorded of the song Rapper's Delight / (46:12) Ken talks about Hip Hop and sampling / (47:32) Plays excerpted recording of the song A Change Is Gonna Come by DMX / (47:52) Ken talks about Sam Cooke / (49:42) Performs A Change Is Gonna Come (Dez on lead vocal) / (50:59) Ken talks about the impact of the song and plays recorded excerpt of Barack Obama speech and back to performance of A Change Is Gonna Come / (52:37) Ken talks about patriotism / (53:13) Performs This Land Is Your Land (Lead vocals by all) / (55:54) Closing comments from Ken / (56:24) Comments from Ali Tonn and opens the floor to questions / (57:40) Sara answers question about performing together before / (58:13) Bill talks about his band The Long Players / (59:20) Ken answers question about the show traveling / (59:52) Sara talks about touring with Kevin Costner / (01:00:30) Bill talks about traveling the world with Foster and Lloyd and Cheap Trick / (01:01:02) Dez talks about touring with Prince and the Revolution / (01:01:25) Joseph talks about future tours / (01:02:10) Answers question about being winning or being nominated for Grammy's / (01:02:48) Group gets together for picture opportunity / (01:03:37) Sara answers question about her musical inspiration / (01:04:39) Bill talks about his musical inspiration / (01:05:14) Dez talks about his musical inspiration / (01:06:25) Joseph talks about his musical inspiration / (01:07:21) All performers tell where they are from and how they made it to Nashville / (01:09:24) Sara answers question about how she feels about performing music / (01:09:57) Bill talks about how he feels about performing music and hearing people singing songs that he's written / (01:10:13) Dez talks about how he used to visualize seeing himself playing music and the first time he actually performed publicly / (01:10:34) Joseph talks about how he felt performing music for the first time / (01:11:08) Ali with final comments and dismisses schools / (01:11:46) Walk-out music / (01:12:23) FILE END                                </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0173</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2019-07-05</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Paulson, Ken; Wooten, Joseph; Beck, Sara; Dickerson, Dez; Lloyd, Bill; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9455</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>