<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Discussion - Remembering Guy Clark - with Tamara Saviano, Shawn Camp, Chuck Mead, and Verlon Thompson - 2017-01-14</dc:title>
<dc:description>Interview and discussion on the life, career and music of Guy Clark with author Tamara Saviano, Shawn Camp, Chuck Mead and Verlon Thompson.  Coincides with the release of Saviano's book titled Without Getting Killed or Caught: The Life and Music of Guy Clark.  From the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on January 14, 2017.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2017-01-14</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Peter Cooper; Tamara Saviano; Shawn Camp; Chuck Mead; Verlon Thompson;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Includes audio from video.  Hosted by Peter Cooper / (00:21) Emergency exit announcement from Abi Tapia / (04:44) Program and participant introductions by Peter Cooper / (09:09) Tamara responds to question regarding Guy Clark's craftsman label / (10:27) Guy Clark identifying as a Texan while living in Nashville / (11:16) Influence of blues musicians and Guy's time in Houston / (12:41) Guy's time in Austin / (13:11) Shawn Camp and Chuck Mead comment on the blues influence on Guy's guitar playing / (14:32) Comments about visiting and working in Guy's basement workshop / (17:53) Peter tells story about the first meeting and interview with Guy / (19:50) Audio of video clip from the movie Heartworn Highways / (22:15) Saviano talks about writing her book and about Susanna Clark / (23:42) Shawn Camp talks about creating music with Guy / (24:51) Comments about the pink Shawn Camp t-shirt that Guy had / (26:30) Shawn tunes guitar and Verlon tells Guy guitar tuning story /</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(28:08) Dublin Blues (Shawn Camp) / 33:28) Comments about mad dog margaritas / (34:22) Tamara tells the story about the song Let Him Roll / (35:44) Let Him Roll (Chuck Mead) / (39:35) Verlon Thompson talks about touring and performing with Guy during his last years / (43:17) Verlon talks about playing with Guy / (44:18) Red River Valley - excerpt (Verlon Thompson) / (44:08) Desperadoes Waiting For A Train (Verlon Thompson) / (50:43) Tamara tells story about the inspiration for Desperadoes Waiting For A Train / (51:46) Tamara talks about writing her biography on Guy / (54:38) Story about the tour bus trip taken after Guy's death with his remains / (55:56) Talk about playing songs that Guy would want them to play / (57:12) Chuck Mead with story about Guy on Lower Broadway / (59:04) Lower Broad St. Blues (Chuck Mead) / (01:01:52) This Guy, Guy (Shawn Camp) / (01:07:55) Peter Cooper and Verlon with sound check stories \ (01:10:42) Story about Townes Van Zandt and his importance to both Guy and Susanna / </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>PCM</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/24;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CMHOF 1 14 2017 Guy Clark book.wav</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2018-02-02</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Clark, Guy; Cooper, Peter; Saviano, Tamara; Camp, Shawn; Mead, Chuck; Thompson, Verlon; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/6772</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>