<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Country Music Awards Highlights - Steve Snell - 1971 - KEEN</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of a 1971 Country Music Awards and 46th Anniversary of the Grand Ole Opry highlights program on radio station KEEN (San Jose, Calif.) with Steve Snell (host).</dc:description>
<dc:date>1971</dc:date>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Opening statements for highlights from Snell's trip to the 1971 CMAs and 46th anniversary of the GOO (Steve Snell) -- (00:43) I Beg Your Pardon, I Never Promised You A Rose Garden (Lynn Anderson) [recorded excerpt] -- (03:25) Snell recalls Johnny Cash taking the stage -- (03:35) Man In Black (Johnny Cash) [recorded excerpt] -- (06:23) Snell talks about Cash's record sales that year, and talks about seeing Marty Robbins -- (06:50) My Woman, My Woman, My Wife (Marty Robbins) [recorded excerpt] -- (10:15) Snell talks about Robbins, and recalls visiting the Country Music Hall of Fame while in Nashville -- (10:32) Hank Williams' Guitar (Freddie Hart) [recorded excerpt] -- (14:20) Snells talks about Freddie Hart, and various artifacts he saw at the Hall -- Snells talks about meeting Art Satherly -- (14:43) Snell talks about seeing Tammy Wynette -- (14:52) Stand By Your Man (Tammy Wynette) [recorded excerpt] -- (17:23) Snell talks about his favorite part of the convention, at the Capitol Records show, when Freddie Hart performed Easy Lovin' -- (17:53) Easy Lovin' (Freddie Hart) [recorded excerpt] -- (20:18) Snell talks about Hart receiving multiple standing ovations, openly crying on stage in appreciation -- (20:50) Closing statements (Steve Snell)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-7-02004_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-7-02004</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-01-24</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Country Music Association (U.S)--Awards; Grand Ole Opry House (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8418</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>