<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Johnny Horton interview - Bob Stoner - 1959-07 - KWKH</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of an interview with Johnny Horton (performer), as conducted by Bob Stoner on radio station KWKH (Shreveport, La.) in July of 1959.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1959-07</dc:date>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Test tone -- (00:28) Bob Stoner congratulates Johnny Horton for his recent gold record The Battle Of New Orleans -- (00:55) Horton talks about receiving a gold record, and how blessed he is -- (01:37) Horton talks about some other artists who recorded the same tune, and how good they all were -- (02:14) Horton talks about recently visiting Florida with other artists, and being intimidated by some other big artists -- (02:52) Horton talks about singing differently depending on how he feels about the song, regardless of it being pop or country -- (03:38) Horton talks about never hearing about another country artist receiving a gold record -- (04:42) Horton talks about how many sales it takes for a record to receive gold status -- (05:00) Horton talks about a new, upcoming record -- (05:50) Horton talks about also receiving a platinum record -- (06:30) Horton talks about The Battle Of New Orleans being rewritten -- (07:47) Stoner congratulates Horton again, and concludes the interview</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-7-01025_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-7-01025</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-02-01</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>KWKH (Radio station : Shreveport, La.); Horton, Johnny;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8447</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>