<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Grand Ole Opry - Prince Albert - 1956-12-15 - WSM</dc:title>
<dc:description>First part of recording contains a segment of a Prince Albert tobacco sponsored Grand Ole Opry segment from December 15, 1956. Featuring Grant Turner (announcer), Jim Reeves (performer/host), Rod Brasfield (performer), Ferlin Husky as Simon Crum (performer), Tommy Jackson (performer), Minnie Pearl (performer), and Chet Atkins (performer), held at Ryman Auditorium, Nashville, TN. Second part of recording contains a segment of a Prince Albert tobacco sponsored Grand Ole Opry segment from June 8, 1957. Featuring Grant Turner (announcer), Marty Robbins (host/performer), Lonzo &amp; Oscar (performers), Rod Brasfield (performer), the Jordanaires (performers), Chet Atkins (performer), June Carter (performer), and Del Wood (performer). Held at Ryman Auditorium, Nashville, TN. It is announced that this is the 922nd broadcast.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1956-12-15</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Jim Reeves; Rod Brasfield; Simon Crum; Tommy Jackson; Minnie Pearl; Chet Atkins; Marty Robbins; Lonzo &amp; Oscar; June Carter</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Waiting For A Train (Jim Reeves) -- (01:45) Opening statements (Grant Turner, Jim Reeves) -- (02:10) Reeves introduces Rod Brasfield -- (02:22) Comedy routine (Rod Brasfield, Jim Reeves) -- (05:33) Reeves introduces Simon Crum -- (06:30) Answer The Phone (Simon Crum, Ernest Tubb impression) -- (07:39) Crum introduces the next tune -- (07:48) More And More (Simon Crum, Webb Pierce impression -- (08:25) You And Me (Simon Crum, Red Foley and Kitty Wells impression) -- (09:20) Don't Be Cruel (Simon Crum, Elvis Presley impression) -- (10:10) Mississippi Sawyer (Tommy Jackson fiddle) -- (11:47) Reeves introduces a hymn -- (12:08) (Gimme That) Old Time Religions (Jim Reeves) -- (13:40) Reeves introduces Minnie Pearl -- (13:39) Comedy routine (Minnie Pearl) -- (15:50) Reeves introduces Simon Crum -- (16:20) Cuz You're So Sweet (Simon Crum) -- (17:45) Reeves thanks Crum and introduces Chet Atkins -- (17:55) Smiles (Chet Atkins) -- (20:19) Traffic Law commercial (Grant Turner) -- (20:40) Reeves introduces the next tune -- (20:50) Am I Losing You (Jim Reeves) -- (23:20) Closing statements and theme (Jim Reeves) -- (23:55) Grant Turner introduces Marty Robbins -- (24:03) Knee Deep In The Blues (Marty Robbins) -- (25:50) Opening statements (Marty Robbins, Grant Turner) -- (26:00) Robbins introduces Rod Brasfield -- (26:34) Comedy routine (Rod Brasfield, Marty Robbins) -- (29:37) Robbins introduces Lonzo &amp; Oscar -- (30:22) A Fallen Star No. 2 (Lonzo &amp; Oscar, Jordanaires) -- (33:17) Old Joe Clark (band) -- (34:36) Robbins introduces a hymn -- (34:49) There Is Power In The Blood (Marty Robbins, Jordanaires) -- (36:10) Robbins thanks the audience and introduces Chet Atkins -- (36:20) Sweet Georgia Brown (Chet Atkins) -- (38:47) Robbins introduces June Carter -- (39:07) Comedy routine (June Carter, Marty Robbins) -- (42:30) Robbins introduces Lonzo &amp; Oscar -- (43:00) Since You're Gone (Lonzo &amp; Oscar, Jordanaires) -- (45:20) A White Sport Coat (Marty Robbins)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-7-01009_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-7-01009</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-02-05</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Grand Ole Opry (Radio program); Ryman Auditorium (Nashville, Tenn.); WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); Turner, Grant; Reeves, Jim; Brasfield, Rod; Brasfield, Rod, 1910-1958; Husky, Ferlin; Minnie Pearl; Cannon, Sarah Ophelia, 1912-1996; Atkins, Chet; Robbins, Marty; Lonzo and Oscar; Carter, June; Jordanaires (Musical group);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8458</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>