<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Charlie Walker Interview About 1952 Material</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of an interview of Charlie Walker (musician) discussing his 1952 material such as "I'm Looking For You", "Stolen Kisses", "Two Red Lips", and "By Rights You Belong To Me", and "Tell Her Lies And Feed Her Candy"  This is side 2 of 2.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Charlie Walker</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) -- Introduction 03/28/1998 Side Two (0:25) Discusses producers' ties to publishing companies and that producers might have an interest in some of the songs presented to artists. Interviewer asks specifically about Paul Cohen and whether he had an interest in what songs were recorded. Charlie Walker responds neutrally and emphasizes that he had a great relationship with the people who he recorded with. (2:14) --- Discusses session for Decca on February 9th, 1956 at Bradley Studios. Mentions Quonset Hut (804 16th Avenue South).  "Remembering" written by Cindy Walker, "Stepping Stones" written by Leon Payne, "Stand Still" written by Bob Tanner &amp; TNT Publishing, "Cheaters Never Win" - Acuff/Rose. Charlie Walker mentions that he might have been one of the first guys to record in the Quonset Hut. (5:16) -- Discussion about switch to Mercury/Starday from Decca. Mercury was for the larger artists. (7:56) -- Interviewer mentions that he is skeptical about his 1957 date, but provides information about session in Slim Willet's garage. (9:00) -- Continues discussion about Mercury switch. (10:38) -- Charlie Walker mentions that Slim Willet was a disc jockey in Abilene, TX. They were great friends. (12:06) -- "I'll Never Let It Show" song discussion, Walker mentions that the sax player was Jim Seals. (14:07) -- Charlie Walker mentions that he did the first session in Houston. Slim Willet invited him to Abilene to record. Mentions "Don't Let Stars Get In Your Eyes", with Buck White on piano. (17:30) -- Discussion of his ten children. (20:45) -- Charlie Walker mentions working in Las Vegas, Nevada, after Hank Thompson. Hank Thompson took the gig after Bob Wills left, and then Charlie took over after Hank Thompson. </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Compact Cassette Tape</dc:format>
<dc:format>1.75 IPS</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CAS4147_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>CAS4147</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-08-14</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Walker, Charlie, 1926-2008;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9343</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>