<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Nashville Cats program - Charlie McCoy - 2006-06-17</dc:title>
<dc:description>Interview program on the life and career to date of Charlie McCoy from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on June 17, 2006.  Program moderated by Bill Lloyd.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2006-06-17</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Charlie McCoy; Bill Lloyd; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Includes selected audio excerpts and audio from video.  Includes questions from the audience.  Recording begins during audience walk in music / (03:41)  Opening comments by Jay Orr /  (07:11) Video presentation / (10:00) Fire alarm goes off with evacuation notice and cancellation of fire alarm / (11:14) Replay of video presentation /  (16:46) Introductory comments by Bill Lloyd / (18:22) Introduction of Charlie McCoy / (19:34) Charlie talks about his early years and interest in playing harmonica and guitar / (22:45) His growing interest in music and musical influences / (22:10) Meeting Mel Tillis in Florida and moving to Nashville / 23:13) Seeing his first recording session and deciding session work is what he wanted to do / (24:35) Going back to Miami to teach and leaving to come back to Nashville / (24:55) First jobs in Nashville playing drums / (26:18) Working with Jim Denny / (27:01) Plays recording of Cherry Berry Wine / (28:20) talks about the musicians on Cherry Berry Wine / </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(44:33) Dylan opening the door to other folk rock artist to record in Nashville / (45:23) Plays recording excerpts of McCoy's other session work / (47:16) Comments on the previously played recordings / (49:31) Talks about Area Code 615 and Barefoot Jerry and the recording of Hey Jude / (51:33) Video recording of Area Code 615 on the Johnny Cash show / (53:45) Area Code 615 morphing to Barefoot Jerry / (54:35) Talks about his solo career and the recording and popularity of Today I Started Loving You Again and the album The Real Charlie McCoy / (57:29) Video of the 1972 CMA Awards show where Charlie McCoy wins Instrumentalist of the year / (01:00:14) Talks about the cover art on his albums / (01:01:15) Promoting his albums doing in-store record promotions and stories about a Boston appearance / (01:02:20) Continuing to do recording sessions / (01:03:47) Plays recorded excerpts / (01:06:35) Becoming the musical director for the television program Hee Haw / </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>RDAT digital tape;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RS.2014.0145</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2017-11-30</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>McCoy, Charlie, 1941- ; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/6312</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>