<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Francis Craig's Orchestra - 1937-mm-dd - Part 1</dc:title>
<dc:description>WSM/NBC Blue program Francis Craig's Orchestra, part 1. Unknown broadcast date, performances suggest 1937 as year. Featuring Francis Craig and his Orchestra with Cecil Bailey.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1937</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Francis Craig and his Orchestra; Cecil Bailey</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>[Unidentified musical excerpt] -- Blue Hawaii (rehearsal excerpt) -- Let's Call The Whole Thing Off (rehearsal excerpt) -- Theme (Red Rose) (Francis Craig and his Orchestra) -- Opening statement -- [Unidentified orchestral piece] -- Announcer introduces Cecil Bailey -- Let's Call The Whole Thing Off (Cecil Bailey) -- Announcer introduces the next piece -- Easy On The Eyes (Francis Craig and his Orchestra) -- Announcer introduces the next piece -- Got A Need For You (Francis Craig and his Orchestra) -- Announcer introduces the next piece -- Blue Hawaii (Francis Craig and his Orchestra)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>16 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR001308_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>TR001308</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2014-12-03</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); National Life &amp; Accident Insurance Company, Inc. (Nashville, Tenn.); Francis Craig's orchestra (Radio program); Craig, Francis, 1900-1966; Bailey, Cecil (Vocalist)</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/608</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>