<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Opryland Music Demo Recordings - Y-101</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording is of a group of demo recordings from Opryland Music. Recordings are from an unknown date and recorded by a number of unknown bands. Tape is labeled Y-101. </dc:description>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) To Love is to Live (N. Oleachea and W. S. Stevenson) -- (02:45) Tell Me Why Baby (S. Martin, D. Mather, and W. S. Stevenson) -- (04:40) Thanks For Saturday Night (M. Jaffie, B. Henderson, and W. S. Stevenson) -- (05:47) Teenage Child (M. Jaffe, B. Henderson, and W. S. Stevenson) -- (07:53) Too Young to Settle Down (M. Jaffe, B. Henderson, and W. S. Stevenson) -- (09:11) Taking Chances (C. Belew and K. Sowder) -- (11:15) Tulips (Two Lips) (F. Wilson and R. Baker) -- (12:57) Toodle-oo (W. Chandler) - (14:32) Two Sided Woman (L. King and D. Wright) -- (16:30) That's What Bothers Me (C. Sparks and W. S. Stevenson) -- (19:07) There's No Work Tomorrow (Let's Have Fun Tonight) (L. B. Watts and W. S. Stevenson) -- (22:01) Tall Men (S. Willet) -- (24:51) That Just Kills Me (D. Rose and T. T. Tyler) -- (26:59) Nickels, Dimes, and Copper Pennies (F. Simon and S. Gardner) -- (29:15) Need You Like Crazy (B. Flournoy) -- (31:25) No More-No Less (W. Chandler) Nellie Bly (B. Brock and W. S. Stevenson) -- (32:56) Nellie Bly (B. Brock and W. S. Stevenson) -- (36:08) The Note Pinned on My Bed (O. Ervin) -- (39:10) New Jerusalem (T. &amp; H. Beaver) -- (41:57) Nothing But Trouble (E. Miller) -- (44:25) No Time (G. McQuaig and J. McQuaig) -- (47:25) New Muleskinner Blues (W. S. Stevenson) -- (50:23) New Baby Doll [drops out] (T. Link) -- (52:57) Puffin' on My Nickel Cigar (S. Masters and T. Atchison) -- (54:55) Pretty Lady (E. Miller and T. Colbert) -- (58:00) Playing With Fire (R. Baker) -- (1:00:05) Palsy Walsy (L. Dossey and W. S. Stevenson) -- (1:01:41) Pretty Baby of Mine (J. Walton and B. Luke) -- (1:03:55) Peace in Our Time (D. Pierce and W. S. Stevenson) -- (1:06:33) Pilot Mountain Rag (D. Stone) -- (1:09:35) Pocket Book Heart (Wallo, Ice, Mitinick, and Stevenson) -- (1:11:57) Pretty Starlight (Bradshaw and Glenn) -- (1:13:21) Paid in Full (F. Miller) -- (1:15:25) Pike's Peak (D. and B. Spielman) -- (1:17:29) Patty Cake (D. and B. Spielman) -- (1:19:22) A Permanent Friend (B. Flournoy) -- (1:20:24) Psychopathic Blues (L. Lewis and K. Adelman) -- (1:22:22) Paul's Boogie (P. Wayne and L. Miller) -- (1:24:36) Puxico Polka (F. Huskey)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1297_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1297</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-03-11</dcterms:created>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8625</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>