<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Grand Ole Opry - Prince Albert - 1940-12-28 - NBC</dc:title>
<dc:description>Prince Albert tobacco sponsored Grand Ole Opry segment from December 28, 1940. Featuring Louie Buck (announcer), George D. Hay (host), Roy Acuff and his Smoky Mountain Boys (performers), Bill Monroe and his Bluegrass Boys (performers), Paul Warmack and his Gully Jumpers (performers), Ford Rush (performer), Pap &amp; Odie (performers), and Bashful Brother Oswald (performer), broadcast on NBC.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1940-12-28</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Roy Acuff; Smoky Mountain Boys; Pap &amp; Odie; Gully Jumpers; Paul Warmack; Ford Rush; Bashful Brother Oswald; Bill Monroe; Bluegrass Boys</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Opening statement (Louie Buck) -- Opening theme -- (00:40) Louie Buck advertises Prince Albert and introduces George D. Hay -- (01:19) Hay talks and introduces Roy Acuff and his Smoky Mountain Boys -- (01:55) Old Joe Clark (Roy Acuff and his Smoky Mountain Boys) -- (03:29) George D. Hay talks and introduces Bill Monroe and his Bluegrass Boys -- (03:51) Were You There? (Bill Monroe and his Bluegrass Boys) -- (05:52) Prince Albert commercial (Louie Buck, George D. Hay, Roy Acuff, Ford Rush, Bill Monroe) -- (07:40) Hay introduces Paul Warmack and his Gully Jumpers -- (07:48) Paddy On The Turnpike (Paul Warmack and his Gully Jumpers) -- (09:00) Hay talks and introduces Ford Rush -- (09:30) When You And I Were Young, Maggie (Ford Rush) -- (11:18) Hay talks and introduces the next tune -- (11:45) Fisher's Hornpipe (opry band) -- (13:00) Hay talks and introduces Pap &amp; Odie -- (13:29) The Old Grey Goose (Pap &amp; Odie) -- (15:15) Pap &amp; Odie encore -- (15:37) Prince Albert commercial (Bashful Brother Oswald, Louie Buck) -- (16:42) That Beautiful Picture (Roy Acuff and his Smoky Mountain Boys) -- (19:21) Hay talks and introduces Paul Warmack and his Gully Jumpers -- (19:45) Roy Acuff encore -- (20:26) Hay introduces Paul Warmack again -- (21:05) Honeycut (Paul Warmack and his Gully Jumpers) -- (22:03) Hay talks and introduces Ford Rush -- (22:30) The Little Whitewashed Chimney (Ford Rush) -- (24:09) Hay talks and introduces Bill Monroe -- (24:33) Katy Hill (Bill Monroe and his Bluegrass Boys) -- (25:35) Hay talks and introduces Bashful Brother Oswald -- Bashful Brother Oswald jokes with George D. Hay -- (26:08) Whoa, Mule Whoa (Bashful Brother Oswald) -- (26:43) Prince Albert commercial (George D. Hay, Louie Buck) -- (27:30) Hay talks and introduces the last tune -- (27:39) Tennessee Breakdown (opry band) -- (28:23) Closing statement (George D. Hay) -- (28:49) Closing statement (Louie Buck) -- (29:20) NBC statement and tones</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-7-04142_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-7-04142</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-01-08</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); National Broadcasting Company; Buck, Louis, 1910-1971; Hay, George D. (George Dewey), 1895-1968; Acuff, Roy, Jr., 1943-; Smoky Mountain Boys; Monroe, Bill, 1911-1996; Bill Monroe and the Bluegrass Boys (Musical group); Warmack, Paul; Gully Jumpers (Paul Warmack); Rush, Ford, 1895-; Pap &amp; Odie; Bashful Brother Oswald; Grand Ole Opry (Radio program);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8354</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>