<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Daniele Alexander Interview - Biff Collie - Tape 2</dc:title>
<dc:description>Tape 2 of 2. Recording of an interview with Daniele Alexander (performer) conducted by Biff Collie.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1990-02-23</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Daniele Alexander; Biff Collie</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Daniele Alexander talks about writing "First Move" at five am -- (00:30) "First Move" is talked about as Alexander being one of few excited for individual recording -- (00:55) Alexander describes "Fairy tail Fools" with Lisa Graham as one of her favorites -- (01:26) Alexander talks about how she believed she was going to be a pilot -- (01:47) "Silly Me" by Alexander is joked about as it was a story about someone who walked out on her -- (02:30) Biff Collie and Alexander talk about Alexander's family structure and how Alexander didn't plan on singing but being a pilot -- (03:38) Alexander talks about how her father's aviation company went under and how it propelled her to sing -- (04:22) Alexander talks about how she would sing with her father at clubs and it inspired her to continue singing -- (04:57) "Where'd the Moon Go Wrong" by Alexander is talked about -- (5:33) Alexander talks about singing at school and girls changing voices -- (07:14) "Memories" is recalled to be a song wrote while driving in traffic and selling it to someone is Los Angelo's -- (08:18) Alexander talks about he consistent writing and fitting her sound to Nashville -- (08:44) Alexander's "Just a Little too Late" is recalled as another break-up song -- (09:17) "She's There" by Alexander is just described as a spontaneous decision -- (09:55) "I Don't Want to Know" Alexander talks about her success under a time crunch -- (10:25) Bonnie Raitt is talked about as Alexander's favorite singer -- (11:14) Alexander's height (5'9") is addressed and her troubles in youth -- (12:34) Alexander enjoys the message of her "True Heart" track -- (13:10) Collie and Alexander discuss difficulty of relationships -- (14:39) Alexander reflects on as a child hoping to help overseas as a child -- (15:18) "Goodbye to Me" is talked about as about leaving a cheater -- (15:58) Alexander try's her best disc jockey impersonation</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1121_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1121</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-12-21</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Alexander, Daniele; Collie, Biff;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8315</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>