<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Scott McQuaig Interview - Biff Collie</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of an interview with Scott McQuaig (performer) conducted by Biff Collie. </dc:description>
<dc:date>1990-04-04</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Scott McQuaig; Biff Collie</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Biff Collie jokes about Scott McQuaig's album title Scott McQuaig, and McQuaig reveals it was originally set to be based off the first track "Honky Tonk Amnesia" -- (00:32) McQuaig tells that he wrote "A Law Against Leavin'" with Louis Anderson; McQuaig reveals he was working as a tool and die maker when the song came to him -- (01:16) Collie asks about McQuaig's musical history, and McQuaig recalls learning Jimmy Rogers' "That's Why I'm Blue" at his grandfather's home -- (02:18) Collie introduces " High Friends In Places (All Over Town)," and McQuaig reveals he did not write it -- (02:52) Collie inquires about McQuaig's musical tastes, and McQuaig lists: Merle Haggard, blues, and Muddy Waters -- (03:40) McQuaig discusses being in a pre-production meeting when he was introduced to "Honky Tonk Amnesia" -- (04:12) Collie and McQuaig joke about how Whitey Shafer may be a good song-writer one day -- (04:30) Collie and McQuaig discuss how his version of "Honky Tonk Amnesia" has a different style than the original recording -- (04:55) McQuaig discusses how music videos narrow the range of interpretations for a song by giving the song a visual representation -- (05:20) Collie and McQuaig reflect on how McQuaig had no idea what he wanted to be when he was younger -- (05:34) McQuaig declares that the Andy Griffith Show is his favorite show, and Collie and McQuaig discuss their ability to re-watch an episode; Collie reflects on how people can only do a routine once but music is unending  -- (06:58) Collie remembers how a comedian will only use the same couple jokes over and over again; McQuaig reflects on how there are a couple albums that he can listen to multiple times -- (08:00) "I Will Always Wait For You" is described to be a swing song that is called the 'Hoagy Carmichael' song; McQuaig recalls working with J. Fred Knobloch at Hank Williams' home -- (09:16) Collie and McQuaig discuss how McQuaig was introduced to Tex Whitson -- (10:34) McQuaig discusses how winning the Jimmy Rogers Festival Talent Show changed McQuaig's opinion of himself from just being a song-writer -- (11:59) Collie introduces Scott McQuaig and "Johnny And The Dreamers," and McQuaig reflects on how " Johnny And The Dreamers" is about how people separate to follow their dreams -- (13:05) Collie recalls how Dizzy Dean would continuously tell different journalists different background information -- (13:57)  McQuaig reflects on a line in "Johnny And The Dreamers" that says, 'every time he swings that hammer, he bends a guitar string' -- (14:19) "Old Memory" is told by McQuaig to be a song that reminds him of a veteran returning from war -- (15:06) Collie and McQuaig discuss what it takes to create a cord that has an impact -- (15:55) Collie asks if McQuaig carries a pencil on him, and McQuaig says that he has to write down a lyric within twenty minutes of thinking of it -- (16:25) "Plans Of A Leavin' Man" is told by McQuaig to be a song that Paul Overstreet helped him on, and McQuaig tells that session musicians love recording "Plans Of A Leavin' Man" -- (16:55) McQuaig says "Plans Of A Leavin' Man" has 'Paul Overstreet magic' that you do not know why you like it -- (17:23) Collie asks about McQuaig's childhood influences, and McQuaig reveals his father drowned when McQuaig was young; McQuaig tells that his step-father had stepped into the role of father -- (18:30) Colle and McQuaig discuss McQuaig's position in his family tree -- (19:00) "Take The Smile From Your Face" is revealed by McQuaig to be a true story about a fight McQuaig can not remember -- (19:49) McQuaig recalls when he heard Quinton Powers playing a powerful melody, and McQuaig decided to record "The Little Senorita With Green Eyes"  -- (21:08) McQuaig says that the only difficulty in traveling is being away from his family, and McQuaig reveals his joy he gets when he plays Bobby Wills' songs -- (22:01) McQuaig reflects on how he wishes to continue to record, and McQuaig remembers how Haggard only wished to make a living -- (22:40) McQuaig shows his appreciation for Collie </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1200_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1200</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-01-30</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>McQuaig, Scott; Collie, Biff;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8455</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>