<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Opryland Music Demo Recordings - Y-110</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording is of a group of demo recordings from Opryland Music. Recordings are from an unknown date and recorded by a number of unknown bands. Tape is labeled Y-110. </dc:description>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) There's no Place Like Home ([Unidentified]) -- (02:32) I'll Tell the World on You (C. Beam, C. Jiles, and W. S. Stevenson) -- (03:56) I'm Ready for You Honey (C. Beam, C. Jiles, and W. S. Stevenson) -- (05:55) It's Time to Pay (P. Ware and J. Little) -- (08:39) I Kissed an Angel Last Night (E. Miller and W. S. Stevenson) -- (09:47) I Hear a Whistle (C. Belew, T. Coe, and C. Felling) -- (12:27) If I Could Only Stay Asleep (E. Bassey and W. Chandler) -- (15:07) I Like You Like That (K. Wade and D. Tilley) -- (16:26) I'm Feeling So Lonely (M. Dickey) -- (17:22) I See You Everywhere (B. Flournoy) -- (18:50) I Ain't Gonna Say Hello (J. Dunklin and W. S. Stevenson) -- (20:39) If You Ever get to Heaven (J. Dunklin, J. Rowell, and W. S. Stevenson) -- (23:44) I'd be Satisfied (M. Coursey) -- (25:13) I Gotta Have Music (V. F. Stewart) -- (28:10) I'm a Mind to Tell You (V. F. Stewart) -- (31:21) I'll be Faithful Forever -- (34:31) I'm Wise to Your Past (J. Stewart and D. Whitney) -- (37:39) You're Just What I Always Wanted -- (38:54) You are my Dream Come True (J. Bias, V. Bias, and W. S. Stevenson) -- (41:50) You've Got What it Takes (J. Bradshaw and H. Glenn) -- (44:12) You Hurt Me (J. Bradshaw and H. Glenn) -- (46:32) You're Living it Up (W. Lyons and W. S. Stevenson) -- (47:50) You Gotta Play it Cool (G. London and W. S. Stevenson) -- (50:42) You'll Have to See it in My Eyes (B. Flournoy) -- (51:58) You're no Longer Mine (J. McGraw and W. S. Stevenson) -- (54:15) Yellow Boots and a Black Bow Tie (S. Herpic and J. Ranier) -- (56:09) You Don't Know (G. Brown and W. S. Stevenson) -- (58:11) You're Counting Me Out of Your Heart (C. Kellogg) -- (1:01:06) Tattler's Wagon (T. Beaver, H. Beaver, and W. S. Stevenson) -- (1:03:54) There Goes My Heart Again ( D. Bowen and G. Bowen) -- (1:06:51) Time Marches on (G. Daniels) -- (1:09:36) Triflin' Mama (J. Perkins) -- (1:12:32) Tennessee Stomp (J. Perkins) -- (1:14:55) Tie a Little String Around Your Finger (D. Darling) -- (1:17:19) Take Your Time (P. White) -- (1:20:13) Talking Blues (W. S. Stevenson) -- (1:23:17) Thru the Garden (J. Jericho) -- (1:26:28) Taxes (J. Wise and B. Wise) -- (1:29:32) Time Will Tell (C. Gant)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1306_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1306</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-03-14</dcterms:created>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8640</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>