<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Bobby Goldsboro Interview - Biff Collie</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of an interview with the Bobby Goldsboro (performer) conducted by Biff Collie.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1990-05-22</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Bobby Goldsboro; Biff Collie</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Bobby Goldsboro wishes a Happy Holidays radio spot and talks about his bike -- (00:22) Goldsboro holiday spot about Roy Rogers -- (00:38) Goldsboro failed attempt at announcing audiobiography -- (00:49) Goldsboro successful attempt at announcing audiobiography -- (00:56) Goldsboro radio spot announcing his show with Biff Collie and his audiobiography -- (01:16) Goldsboro radio spot announcing his show with Collie and his audiobiography -- (01:27) Goldsboro radio spot announcing how music change his life with Collie and his audiobiography -- (01:42) Goldsboro radio spot announcing his show with Collie and his audiobiography -- (01:51) Goldsboro announces his two hour segment with Collie -- (02:02) Goldsboro announces his two hour segment with Collie -- (02:16) Goldsboro radio spot announcing his show with Collie and his audiobiography -- (02:30) Goldsboro announces the thirty minute mark to begin commercial break -- (02:44) Goldsboro announces the hour mark to begin commercial break -- (02:56) Goldsboro announces the ninety minute mark to begin commercial break -- (3:06) Goldsboro sign off -- (03:17) Goldsboro tells his background information and jokes about his age -- (04:00) Goldsboro talks about being a younger brother -- (04:20) Goldsboro talks about his parents flower shop and dad going off to war -- (04:48) Goldsboro talks about his athletics and his secret boxing and major league baseball -- (07:35) Goldsboro talks about his musical family and his early diversification of music -- (08:25) Goldsboro talks about how he learned songs and jokes to kill time in morning school -- (09:03) Goldsboro talks about being a self-taught guitar player and almost getting a bass by mistake -- (10:16) Goldsboro talks about The Webbs and being at their rehearsals hearing Chet Atkins styling -- (11:45) Goldsboro tells about how he played at an airbase and becoming a singer on the spot -- (13:54) Goldsboro talks about his first song he wrote "The Birmingham Bop" and writing "Wonderful Wonder" -- (14:51) Goldsboro talks about writing poems in school and ideas of major league sports -- (15:47) Goldsboro talks about being signed to a recording contract and being afraid of New York -- (16:45) "See the Funny Little Clown" is discussed as an afterthought made top ten -- (17:20) Goldsboro talks about being in the Roy Orbison band and going to Seattle -- (20:27) Goldsboro talks about Orbison and believing in chance -- (21:18) Orbison's humor is talked about -- (23:02) Goldsboro talks about Orbison's dark glasses as a method of disguise -- (24:27) Goldsboro tells leaving the band as a difficult decision supported by Orbison -- (27:08) Goldsboro talks about doing a show in Detroit and Chicago promotions -- (28:42) Goldsboro talks about his downward trend of his records and its influence of quickly releasing "Honey" -- (29:36) Goldsboro talks about "Honey"'s influence on his expanding role in television -- (30:56) Goldsboro talks about being asked to host the Michael Douglas Show with Cornel Wilde -- (34:37) Collie and Goldsboro talk about his time recording in various foreign languages and the flub in Germany by being stuck with three different ways to pronounce the opening lyric -- (36:45) Goldsboro talks about recording in Paris with no opportunity to see any sites -- (37:26) Collie and Goldsboro talk about his television experience with interviewing actors and preparing for the Tonight Show -- (40:28) Goldsboro talks about the Phil Donahue Show -- (40:45) Goldsboro talked about being on the Mike Douglas Show and their decision to make Goldsboro be known as accident prone and dealing with a peacock -- (43:25) Goldsboro talks about being on a Dick Clark tour and breaking a guitar string on stage leading to his frog voice -- (45:20) Jim Henson is discussed and Goldsboro having worked with puppets -- (46:16) The three years the Bobby Goldsboro show was on the air is discussed -- (48:03) Goldsboro talks about meeting Mac Davis and recording Davis' song -- (40:46) Goldsboro's biggest hobby, bass fishing, is discussed -- (51:12) Goldsboro reminisce about being on the road and playing for cruises -- (53:48) Goldsboro's dreams are joked about </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1119_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1119</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-12-21</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Goldsboro, Bobby; Collie, Biff;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8313</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>