<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Grand Ole Opry - Prince Albert - 1948-07-10 - Johnny Bond performance - WSM</dc:title>
<dc:description>Excerpts from a Prince Albert tobacco sponsored Grand Ole Opry segment from July 10, 1948. Featuring Red Foley (announcer) and Johnny Bond and Gene Autry on radio station WSM (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:description>
<dc:date>1948-07-10</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Johnny Bond; Gene Autry</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Red Foley introduces Johnny Bond (incomplete) -- Red Foley talks -- Johnny Bond talks -- I'll Step Aside (Johnny Bond) -- Red Foley talks -- Red Foley introduces Minnie Pearl (incomplete) -- Address Unknown (Gene Autry) (incomplete) -- [Unidentified] talks (incomplete) -- Address Unknown (Gene Autry) (incomplete)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>12 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>78 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR002994_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>TR002994</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2017-06-15</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); Grand ole opry (Radio program); Foley, Red, 1910-1968; Bond, Johnny, 1915-1978; Autry, Gene, 1907-1998; </dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/5254</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>