<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Ambrose Haley and his Ozark Ramblers performances</dc:title>
<dc:description>Various performances by Ambrose Haley and his Ozark Ramblers (performers) [according to tape case] on December 24 and February 4 from an unknown year.</dc:description>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Test tones -- We've Come A Long Way Together (Sarah and the Boys) (incomplete) -- [Unidentified] talks and introduces the next tune -- Put Your Arms Around Me Honey (Curly, Monte, Ruth, Mary) -- [Unidentified] talks and introduces the next tune -- White Christmas (Joe Ross accordion) -- [Unidentified] talks and introduces the next tune -- Mellow Mountain Moon (Ruth Nicholas) -- [Unidentified] talks and promotes future shows -- Silent Night (Mary) -- [Unidentified] talks and introduces the next tune -- Limehouse Blues (Joe Ross accordion) -- [Unidentified] talks and the cast wishes Merry Christmas -- Closing theme -- Closing statement -- I'm A Cowboy's Gal (Mary) -- [Unidentified] talks and introduces Joe Ross -- Sweet Georgia Brown (Joe Ross accordion) -- [Unidentified] talks and introduces the next tune -- Tweedle-O-Twill ([Unidentified]) -- [Unidentified] introduces Ruth -- I Know That A Light Will Be Burning (Ruth) -- [Unidentified] talks about future shows -- Mother's Prayer Guide Me ([Unidentified trio]) -- [Unidentified] introduces Nancy -- Marzy Doats(Nancy) -- Send Her Tender And Call ([Unidentified]) -- Closing theme</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-0355_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-0355</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-03-16</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Haley, Ambrose; Ozark Ramblers</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/7090</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>