<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Herman Crook interview - Biff Collie</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording contains an interview with Herman Crook, followed by the Judds, as conducted by Biff Collie. Recording also contains various news segments for Biff Collie's radio program.</dc:description>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:03) Herman Crook talks about playing on the National Barn Dance and at the Ryman Auditorium, and how that show transitioned into the Grand Ole Opry -- (01:38) Crook talks about being lucky to have been picked to stay on as a performer at the Opry, and getting paid to do so -- (02:30) Biff says hello to Ott Devine -- (03:21) Ott Devine talks (incomplete) -- (03:34) Biff Collie talks about a show being co-hosted by Roy Clark and a different star each week -- (03:48) Biff talks about wanting to get an interview with the Judds -- (04:15) The Judds talk about singing when they were young girls in order to get out of doing chores -- (04:43) The Judds talk about touring and their relationship with each other as a mother and daughter -- (05:51) Biff talks about wanting to do another interview with the Judds in the future -- (06:12) Biff talks about the Grand Ole Opry exhibit at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum -- (07:06) Biff talks about his mail contact information and Dolly Parton's book Wild Flowers -- (08:03) Biff talks about T. G. Shepard joining the car racing business and Kenny Rogers as well -- (08:30) Biff talks about Roy Clark's interest in the equine arts and Mel Tillis growing molasses -- (08:58) Biff talks about Mickey Gilley and Urban Cowboy starring John Travolta -- (09:27) Biff talks about Jerry Reed's lawsuit with AAMCO oil company -- (09:52) Biff talks about the Judds rise to fame in a short time -- (10:27) Biff talks about the the opposition of "hillbilly" music in Nashville in the 1920's and how the Grand Ole Opry got it's name, the longest running radio show in history -- (11:25) Biff does some of his mailbag entries from listeners -- (12:30) Biff talks about Willie Nelson teaching Sunday school and Waylon studying ministry -- Biff talks about Larry Gatlin's clothing designer -- Biff talks about the Ozark Jubilee in the 1950's and Ralph Foster -- (13:33) Biff talks about Hawkshaw Hawkins, Cowboy Copas, and Patsy Cline dying in a plane crash, and all the songs that have been written about the event -- (14:37) Biff talks about Hall of Famer Ralph Peer being considered the father of country music -- (15:44) Biff talks about Johnny Russell's pizza restaurant (incomplete)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-7-04115_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-7-04115</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-12-14</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Crook, Herman; Collie, Biff; Judds (Musical group); Judd, Wynonna, 1964-; Judd, Naomi; Devine, Ott, 1910-1994;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8290</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>