<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>It Pays To Be Ignorant - 1946-08-23 - Part 4 // Waltz Time - 1946-08-23 - Part 1</dc:title>
<dc:description>CBS radio program It Pays To Be Ignorant, as broadcast August 23, 1946 (part 4) by station WHIO (Dayton, OH). Featuring announcer Ken Roberts; host Tom Howard; cast members Harry McNaughton, Lulu McConnell, and George Shelton; and musicians Harry Salter and the Philip Morris Orchestra, and Ray Porter's Esquires. Recording ends with the opening of radio program Waltz Time, featuring a performance by Evelyn MacGregor.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1946-08-23</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Evelyn MacGregor</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Cast talk [continued from part 3] -- Closing statement (Ken Roberts) -- Closing statement (Tom Howard) -- Station announcement -- Waltz Time excerpt</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>8 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR002332_2</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>TR002332</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2016-06-15</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>CBS Inc.; It pays to be ignorant (Radio program); Howard, Tom, 1885 or 1886-1955; McNaughton, Harry; McConnell, Lulu; Shelton, George; Roberts, Ken (Radio announcer); Salter, Harry, 1899-1984; Philip Morris Orchestra; WHIO (Radio station : Dayton, Ohio); MacGregor, Evelyn</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/3990</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>