<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Hank Snow Interview for WTCW: Part 1</dc:title>
<dc:description>This recording features backstage interviews from the Grand Ole Opry with Hank Snow and guests. Guests include: Jim Reeves, Faron Young, Maybelle Carter, Johnny Cash, and Ray Price. Hank asks each guest where they have been on tour, where they will be going on tour next, and what new music they have released as well as offer them the opportunity to say something to the listeners. After each interview, the guests congratulates Hank Snow on 20 years with RCA Vector and also congratulate Snow and Ernest Tubb on their two radio station programs for WTCW in Whitesburg, Kentucky and WHBT in Harriman Tennessee. The guests also record snapshots announcing the different radio stations. The tape is undated. This tape is thirty-nine of an unidentified number of tapes.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Hank Snow; Jim Reeves; Faron Young; Jean Shepard; Maybelle Carter; Johnny Cash; Ray Price; Ernest Tubb; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Hank Snow introduces Jim Reeves from backstage at the Grand Ole Opry -- (00:23) The two talk about where Reeves has been -- (00:45) Snow asks how long Reeves has been with the Opry -- (01:02) The two discuss RCA Victor label and Reeves' new record -- (02:04) Reeves talks about his future overseas travel plans -- (02:47) Reeves and Snow wish each other luck-- (03:26) Jim Reeves outtake -- (03:36) Reeves wish Snow congratulations for 20 years with RCA Victor -- (03:54) Reeves wishes congratulations to Snow and Ernest Tubb for station WTCW, Whitesburg, Kentucky  -- (04:09) Reeves outtake -- (04:22) Reeves wishes congratulations Snow and Tubb for station WHBT, Harriman, Tennessee  -- (04:40) Reeves wishes congratulations to Snow and Tub for station WTCW -- (04:58) Reeves announces station WTCW  -- (05:11) Reeves announces station WHBT -- (05:26) Snow introduces Faron Young -- (05:45) Young says hello to everyone -- (05:55) Snow asks Young where he has traveled -- (06:17) Young talks about his experience with making motion pictures -- (06:52) Snow and Young talk about Young's new religious tracks -- (07:35) Snow asks Young about the future and Young talks about upcoming tours -- (08:32) Young talks about his new releases -- (09:04) Young thanks everyone -- (09:38) Young congratulates Snow on 20 years with RCA Victor -- (10:11) Young outtake -- (10:34) Young congratulates Snow and Tubb and radio station WTCW -- (10:54) Young congratulates Snow and Tubb for station WHBT -- (11:27) Young outtake -- (12:03) Young congratulates Snow and Tubb for station WTCW -- (12:48) Young announces station WTCW -- (13:04) Young outtake -- (13:18) Young announces station WTCW -- (13:31) Young announces station WHBT -- (13:41) Snow introduces Jene Shepard -- (13:57) Snow asks her were she has been and her health -- (14:22) Snow and Shepard discuss her music -- (15:02) Snow asks Shepard how long she's been with the Opry -- (15:31) Shepard thanks everyone -- (16:40) Shepard congratulates Snow on 20 years with RCA -- (17:01) Shepard congratulates Snow and Tubb on station WTCW -- (17:14) Shepard outtake -- (17:34) Shepard congratulates Snow and Tubb on station WHBT -- (18:01) Shepard outtake -- (18:10) Shepard announces station WTCW -- (18:21) Shepard announces station WHBT -- (18:46) Snow announces Mommy Maybelle Carter -- (19:06) Snow and Carter talk about Carter's traveling and family -- (20:05) The two take about the Carter Sisters and Carter's music -- (20:52) The two talk about Jimmy Rodgers -- (21:28) Snow compliments Carter -- (22:02) Carter outtake -- (22:22) Carter congratulates Snow on 20 years with RCA -- (22:32) Snow introduces Johnny Cash -- (23:02) Cash talks about what he has been up to in the past few months -- (23:49) The two talk about Cash's recent releases -- (24:17) Cash talks about upcoming travels -- (25:07) Cash thanks everyone -- (25:57) Cash congratulates Snow for 20 years with RCA -- (26:21) Cash outtake -- (26:43) Cash congratulates Snow and Tubb for station WTCW -- (26:57) Cash congratulates Snow and Tubb for WHBT -- (27:16) Cash outtake -- (27:23) Cash announces station WTCW -- (27:32) Cash announces station WHBT -- (27:40) Cash announces station WTCW -- (28:01) Snow introduces Ray Price -- (28:22) Price talks about his touring and new music -- (29:20) Snow talks about his and Tubb's radio program -- (29:40) Snow and Price talk about the future -- (29:47) Price congratulates Snow on 20 years with RCA -- (30:18) Price congratulates and thanks Snow and Tubb -- (31:16) Price announces station WTCW -- (31:29) Price announces station WHBT --- (31:40) Price congratulates Snow on 20 years with RCA -- (31:50) Price congratulates Snow and Tubb for station WTCW -- (32:30) Price congratulates Snow and Tubb for station WHBT</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-7-02569_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-7-02569</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-09-11</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Snow, Hank; Reeves, Jim; Young, Faron; Shepard, Jean, 1933-2016; Carter, Maybelle, 1909-1978; Cash, Johnny; Cash, Johnny, 1932-2003; Price, Ray, 1926-2013; Tubb, Ernest; Tubb, Ernest, 1914-1984;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9558</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>