<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Eddie Hill Show (Tape 2)</dc:title>
<dc:description>This recording features a conversation between radio host, Eddie Hill and Hank Snow. Ray Price, Hal Cook, and Don Law are also in the studio talking to Eddie Hill. The conversation is primarily about the Price and Robbins' Golden Guitar award and the new sound in country. Hill does announce songs that were played in real time but are not included on this recording. The tape is dated April of 1957. The tape is the second for the Eddie Hill Show and conversation has been carried over from the first tape. This tape is forty-nine of an unidentified number of tapes.</dc:description>
<dc:date>195704</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Eddie Hill; Hank Snow; Ernest Tubb; Ray Price; Hal Cook; Don Law; Marty Robbins; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Hank Snow and Eddie Hill come on in the middle of conversation talking about Ernest Tubb and Snow's start at the Grand Ole Opry [conversation continued from tape 1] -- (01:58) Hill announces station break for the Opry Star Spotlight -- (02:28) Hill announces next song -- (02:50) Hill thanks Snow -- (03:02) Snow suggests sharing the microphone with Ray Price -- (03:26) Hill, Snow, and Price talk about "the new sound" to country music -- (04:08) Snow talks about his last show -- (04:20) Hill suggest Snow and Price talk about the business -- (04:49) Snow and Price talk about the first time they met [Hill muttering in the background] -- (05:39) Snow and Price talk about Price being awarded the Golden Guitar -- (06:27) Hill interrupts to suggest they talk about the new sound with Hal Cook of Columbia Records -- (06:55) Snow, Price, Cook, and Don Law continue to talk about the Golden Guitar award -- (08:42) Mention that Marty Robbins will also be getting a Gold Guitar -- (08:58) The men start talking about the new sound -- (09:42) The men talk about Price and Robbins' new music -- (11:09) Finished listening to Price's new single, "Please Don't Leave Me" -- (11:32) Continue talking about Price's music and the song "I'll Be There" -- (11:51) Hill and Law talk about the new sound again ("country sound with a little pop flavor") -- (14:51) The men talk about why people are buying country records -- (16:02) Hill begins talking about records and recording --- (17:36) Hill announce the time and program -- (17:48) Snow, Price, and Hill announce upcoming shows -- (23:47) Hill announces next song, "Six White Horses" (Lester Flatt and Earl Scruggs)-- (24:45) Hill talks to Price about his new album and Robbins' new album -- (25:11) The men talk about Price's tour -- (25:47) Snow brings up Roy Acuff from the night before -- (25:47) The men talk about where to pick up the radio station WSM -- (26:33) Snow brings up Acuff and what they talked about the previous night -- (27:11) The men talk about Acuff's age -- (28:12) The men start talking about Red Foley and his age -- (29:07) Snow and Price talk about guns and pistols -- (31:10) The men talk about horses -- (32:06) Begin to talk about Snow being able to trick ride -- (32:37) Hill announces time and program [conversation and tape cut out] [conversation continues on tape 3]</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-7-02579_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-7-02579</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-09-13</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Snow, Hank; Hill, Eddie, 1921-1994; Hill, Eddie, 1921-1995; Tubb, Ernest, 1914-1984; Price, Ray, 1926-2013; Cook, Hal (music executive); Law, Don, 1902-1982; Law, Donald F., 1902-1982; Robbins, Marty;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9596</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>