<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Robin Lee Interview - Biff Collie</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of an interview with Robin Lee (performer) conducted by Biff Collie. </dc:description>
<dc:date>1990-03-26</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Robin Lee; Biff Collie</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Biff Collie directs Robin Lee for the Robin Lee radio spot on the Music City Album Review -- (00:14) Collie directs Lee to stress the ease of being a disc jockey for radio spot -- (00:34) Collie directs Lee to announce her album for the Music City Album Review radio spot -- (00:56) Collie directs Lee to announce her album for the Music City Album Review radio spot -- (01:01) Collie directs Lee to announce that she is with the 'Biffer' on the Music City Album Review -- (01:12) Collie has Lee spell out Biff  Collie and it takes Lee a couple attempts -- (01:42) Collie attempts to say his and Lee's names in a form of pig-Latin -- (02:28) Collie has Lee introduce her favorite artist, Dolly Parton, to introduce "Yellow Roses" -- (02:47) Collie has Lee reflect on Parton for a radio spot -- (03:05)  Collie directs Lee to announce the thirty-minute radio spot -- (03:11)  Collie directs Lee to announce a recap radio spot for the Music City Album Review -- (03:25) Collie helps Lee's diction for her Music City Album Review radio spot -- (03:32) Collie has Lee ask the audience if they had been paying attention -- (03:42) Collie and Lee joke about giving away lee's ear rings -- (04:07) Collie directs Lee to announce that she is with the 'Biffer' on the Music City Album Review -- (04:17) Collie has Lee announce the commercial break radio spot -- (04:30) Collie has Lee announce the return from commercial break radio spot -- (04:36) Collie directs Lee to question the show quality for radio spot -- (04:40) Collie directs Lee to tell Collie to take the week off for radio spot -- (04:50) Collie jokes about Lee's seriousness in last radio spot -- (04:55) Collie directs Lee to announce the thirty-minute remaining radio spot -- (05:00) Collie directs Lee to announce that she is with Collie on the Music City Album Review radio spot -- (05:16) Collie directs Lee to give her personal signature for radio spot -- (05:51) Collie has Lee give her leaving radio spots -- (06:16) Collie directs Lee to give the radio spot for the next week's program -- (06:38) Collie directs Lee to give her goodbye radio spot -- (07:03) Collie tells Lee about the procedures of the Music City Album Review -- (07:42) Lee introduces the album title Black Velvet and the title track "Black Velvet;" Lee discusses how "Black Velvet" had been a success in Canada for Alannah Myles -- (08:23) Lee asserts "Black Velvet" to be a recognized track; additionally, Collie and Lee compares Lee to Myles in her music video -- (09:10) Collie and Lee discuss the meaning of Myles' phrase 'When you play it, say it' -- (09:55) "How About Goodbye" is told by Lee to be a  representation of a female summizing her relationship -- (10:50) Collie recalls discussions with Vern Gosdin about Gosdin's ex-wife -- (12:01) Lee recalls how she was having issues getting songs to record when she found "He's Helping Me Get Over You" -- (13:31) Collie addresses how titles are created and recalls a friend of his that had a peculiarly way of saying known phrases -- (15:03) Collie and Lee discuss how "When the Feeling Comes Around" was a Jennifer Warnes song that she had to sell the idea to her producer -- (16:06) Lee reminisces about how "When the Feeling Comes Around" feels like a 'beach song' -- (16:22) Collie and Lee address Ron Reynolds' contribution and how he uses Nerds containers for percussion -- (18:22) Collie and Lee discuss how Pam 'Sunny' Russ has her first song cut on the Black Velvet album -- (19:36) Collie has Lee recall being in Panama City, Florida the first time she heard one of her songs being played -- (20:30) Collie and Lee attempt to express the feeling when no one is around when he has something to tell -- (21:44) Collie tells about his daughter seeing Skip Ewing downtown and wanting to address him -- (22:33) Lee recalls a time working at the bank when a country celebrity walked in -- (22:52) "Love Letter" is told by Lee to be a 'boogie song' that she had recorded after "Black Velvet" had been cut -- (23:51) Collie and Lee discuss the importance of running in Lee's life -- (25:08) Collie has Lee discuss "Something I Know I'm Gonna Love" and Lee reveals the song's tie to Deborah Allen -- (26:42) Collie has Lee reflect on Lee's favorite artists and Lee reflects on owning a variety on music -- (28:01) Lee discusses how the piano is her instrument of choice -- (28:44) Collie describes how his poodle is terrified of thunderstorms and Collie and Lee reflects on crying dogs -- (29:46) "Every Little Bit Hurts" writer Tommy Brasfield is revealed to have passed away and Lee compares it to "Midnight Hour" -- (30:43) Lee reveals how "Till I Get It Right" was almost the title track as a demonstration of people's assumptions and Lee reveals how the album was changed to be primarily male backup singers -- (32:29) Collie and Lee discuss miniature buses that they use for travel -- (33:04) Collie introduces Lee and Lee tells how "Sad Eyes" was recorded for her first album originally -- (34:33) Lee reveals her paranoia when it comes to releasing singles -- (35:27) Collie and Lee show their appreciation for each other -- (35:45) Collie brings up the format of the show and Lee discusses her assumptions made pre-interview -- (36:57) Collie has Lee discuss how she wishes to go for a run -- (37:32) Collie tells Lee he will call her parents and tell them what she wants for dinner </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1184_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1184</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-01-24</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Lee, Robin (Singer); Collie, Biff;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8421</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>