<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Interstate 7 Show - Loretta Lynn and Ernest Ray interview - Jack Reno - 1978 - WLW - part 2</dc:title>
<dc:description>Part two of a segment of the Interstate 7 Show with Jack Reno (host), featuring Loretta Lynn (performer) and Ernest Ray Lynn (performer), broadcast in 1978 on radio station WLW (Cincinnati, Ohio).</dc:description>
<dc:date>1978</dc:date>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) [Unidentified] introduces Jack Reno -- (00:15) Spring Fever (Loretta Lynn) [recorded excerpt] -- (02:50) Jack Reno introduces Loretta Lynn, and compliments her records -- (03:18) Loretta talks about living in Humphrey's county, out in the countryside -- (03:42) Loretta talks about owning the town there, and putting up a post office there -- (04:03) Loretta talks about the town being included when she bought a house there, in Hurricane Mills, Tennessee -- (04:54) Loretta talks about selling her rodeo, and having 5,000 acres -- (05:12) Loretta talks about her husband farming a lot of their land -- (05:35) Loretta talks about her duderanch -- (06:09) Loretta talks about an old bridge in her town -- (6:31) Ernest Ray talks about where he got his newest recording, from his mother -- (06:52) Ernest Ray talks about his little sisters wanting to record when they get older, and how wild they are -- (07:27) Loretta talks about taking her teen daughters on the road -- (07:45) Loretta tells a story about her daughter being caught gambling in a hotel -- (08:33) Loretta talks about the harsh winter they just had, and that it did not affect any of her shows -- (08:57) Loretta talks about her mother having a lung removed -- (09:45) Loretta talks about cutting Ernest Ray's song first, but letting her son have it first -- (10:13) True Love Needs To Keep In Touch (Ernest Ray Lynn) [recorded excerpt] -- (12:35) Weather report -- (15:13) Loretta talks about the pronunciation of Nashville -- (15:35) Loretta corrects her next tour destination -- (16:16) Your Squaw Is On The Warpath (Loretta Lynn) [recorded excerpt] -- (18:15) Loretta talks about the inspiration behind her record "Your Squaw Is On The Warpath" -- (19:17) Loretta talks about writing her own music -- (19:30) Loretta talks about doing a book about her lyrics, and that Coal Miner's Daughter is releasing later this year -- (20:41) Loretta talks about not starring in the movie, but helping with production -- (21:30) Loretta talks about why her sister's accent is different from her -- (21:42) Loretta talks about where Butcher's Holler, KY is located -- (22:00) Loretta talks about moving to Washington -- (22:15) Loretta talks about how she got her first record contract in Washington -- (24:05) Loretta and Jack talk about how newer artist's songs get into the Top 40 -- (25:15) Loretta talks about a hit only being a hit if it gets recognition -- (25:30) Loretta talks about why some hits don't get any radio play -- (27:00) Loretta talks about never changing -- (27:27) You Ain't Woman Enough To Take My Man (Loretta Lynn) [recorded excerpt] -- (29:50) Loretta and Jack conclude the interview -- (32:50) God Bless The Children (Loretta Lynn) [recorded excerpt]</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-7-04147_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-7-04147</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-01-16</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Reno, Jack; Lynn, Loretta, 1932-; Lynn, Ernest; WLW (Radio Station : Cincinnati, Ohio);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8398</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>