<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>WSM Variety Award Presentation - 1954-01-21 (copy) - Part 3</dc:title>
<dc:description>WSM program aimed at George Rosen of Variety magazine. Written by Bill Graham; engineered by Elmer Alley, Charles Bragg, Glen Snoddy, and Tom Sparkman; produced by Noel Digby. Part three of six. This disc is a duplicate of TR001249_1.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1954-01-21</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Hank Williams; Lawrence Goodman; Betty Brown; Richard Rivers; Fisk University Choir; Roy Petty; Beasley Smith; Owen Bradley Quintet; Hilltoppers; Del Wood; Jordanaires; Dottie Dillard; Marvin Hughes; Don Estes; John Gordy; Bob Lamb; Bob Johnstone</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Cold, Cold Heart (excerpt) (Hank Williams) -- David Cobb talks about Hank Williams -- Ernie Keller and David Cobb talk about Opry performances for charity and the military -- Ernie Keller and David Cobb report on an Opry survey -- David Cobb and Ernie Keller talk about 'non-hillbilly' talent -- Ernie Keller introduces Lawrence Goodman -- Fantasiest&#252;cke, Op. 12, 2. Aufschwung (excerpt) (Lawrence Goodman) -- David Cobb introduces Sidney Dalton and the program Exploring Music -- Exploring Music (excerpt) -- David Cobb introduces Betty Brown and Richard Rivers -- Song Of Love (excerpt) (Betty Brown, Richard Rivers) -- Ernie Keller introduces various vocalists -- In The River Of Jordan (excerpt) (Fisk University Choir) -- Ernie Keller talks about the Fisk University Choir -- Ernie Keller introduces Roy Petty -- On The Road To Mandalay (excerpt) (Roy Petty) -- Ernie Keller talks about popular music -- [Unidentified musical excerpt] (Beasley Smith) -- Ernie Keller talks about Beasley Smith and the program Eight O'Clock Time -- David Cobb talks about the WSM Orchestra -- Ernie Keller introduces WSM conductors Francis Craig and Owen Bradley -- [Unidentified musical excerpt] (Owen Bradley Quintet) -- David Cobb talks about Beasley Smith -- Ernie Keller talks about Owen Bradley -- Ernie Keller and David Cobb talk about artists to record with Owen Bradley and the WSM Orchestra -- Trying (excerpt) (The Hilltoppers) -- David Cobb talks about The Hilltoppers -- David Cobb introduces Del Wood -- Down Yonder (excerpt) (Del Wood) -- Ernie Keller introduces various groups -- Dig A Little Deeper (excerpt) (The Jordanaires) -- Ernie Keller introduces Dottie Dillard -- I've Got A Right To Cry (excerpt) (Dottie Dillard) -- Ernie Keller introduces Marvin 'Friday' Hughes -- Beale Street Blues (excerpt) (Marvin Hughes) -- David Cobb introduces Don Estes -- All Day Singin' And Dinner On The Ground (excerpt) (Don Estes) -- Ernie Keller introduces John Gordy -- Panama (excerpt) (John Gordy) -- David Cobb introduces Bob Lamb -- I Still Get A Thrill (excerpt) (Bob Lamb) -- Ernie Keller introduces Bob Johnstone -- Alone Together (excerpt) (Bob Johnstone)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>16 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR001251_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>TR001251</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2014-10-22</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); Cobb, David (Announcer); Keller, Ernie; Williams, Hank, 1923-1953; Goodman, Lawrence (Pianist); Bradley, Owen; Owen Bradley Quintet; Craig, Francis, 1900-1966; Wood, Del; WSM Orchestra; Jordanaires (Musical group); Hilltoppers (Musical group); Dillard, Dottie; Exploring music (Radio program); Fisk University. Choir; Smith, Beasley; Eight o'clock time (Radio program); Hughes, Marvin; Estes, Don (Vocalist); Gordy, John (Pianist);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/504</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>