<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Chet Atkins Interviewed by Bob Allen in 1985 Side Two</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of Bob Allen interviewing Chet Atkins. The recording takes place on 03-04-85.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1985-03-04</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Chet Atkins</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Side Two - (0:04) -- Chet Atkins continues discussion about overdubbing. (0:59) -- Chet Atkins mentions that he often records 8 bars of music at a time. (2:08) -- "I tend to play something a lot better the first time I play it anyway. The longer I play it, the worse I get." - Chet Atkins about recording. (2:34) -- Bob Allen asks Chet Atkins about whether his friends use his personal home studio. (3:22) -- Chet Atkins discusses rehearsing for shows and preparing for recording sessions. (3:45) -- Chet Atkins mentions that he does about 30-40 shows a year. (4:24) -- Bob Allen asks Chet Atkins what music he listens to in his spare time. Chet mentions Art Tatum (jazz piano player). (6:14) -- Bob Allen asks Chet Atkins about his consulting work with guitar companies (Gibson). (9:11) -- Bob Allen asks Chet Atkins about his future projects. (9:57) -- Bob Allen asks Chet Atkins if he is currently designing a new guitar. (12:02) -- Bob Allen asks Chet Atkins about sessions with George Benson. (13:14) -- Chet Atkins describes his road band. (14:55) -- Chet Atkins describes promotion plans for the album "Stay Tuned." (15:53) -- Bob Allen asks about how Chet Atkins get his signature sound when recording. "Nah, there's nothing special I do, I'm always searching..and trying to find a better sound." - Chet Atkins (19:59) -- Bob Allen asks about Chet Atkins' piano player's equipment. (20:39) -- Chet Atkins discusses his home instrument collection. (21:54) -- Chet Atkins mentions Rick Blackburn's interest in "Stay Tuned." (24:10) -- Bob Allen asks Chet Atkins about his producing work. Chet Atkins says he's working with Roger Whittaker. (25:10) -- Chet Atkins discusses the difficulties of producing. Chet briefly mentions dealing with managers who tried to interfere with his creative process. (27:45) -- Bob Allen asks Chet Atkins about the changes in the Nashville music scene. </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>audio cassette, compact;</dc:format>
<dc:format>1.75 ips;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CAS4656_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>CAS4656</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-08-26</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Atkins, Chet;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9406</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>