<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>UNICEF tour - New Zealand - 1972 - part 7</dc:title>
<dc:description>Part seven of a 1972 UNICEF fundraiser tour performance in New Zealand. Featuring Tex Ritter (host/performer), Rusty Greaves (performer), Ray Sanders (performer), and Tom T. Hall (performer).</dc:description>
<dc:date>1972</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Rusty Greaves; Ray Sanders; Tom T. Hall</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Tex Ritter talks and introduces Rusty Graves -- (01:30) Rusty Greaves talks and introduces the first tune -- (02:06) She Taught Me How To Yodel (Rusty Greaves) -- (03:55) Greaves thanks the audience and introduces the next tune -- (04:45) A Pub With No Beer (Rusty Greaves) -- (07:03) Greaves talks about his family and New Zealand and introduces the next tune -- (08:35) There's A Gold Mine In The Sky (Rusty Greaves) -- (10:52) Ritter thanks Greaves and introduces Ray Sanders -- (12:18) Let's Blame It On Rosie (Ray Sanders) -- (14:19) Sanders talks about playing in Australia and introduces the next tune -- (14:38) Beer Drinkin' Music (Ray Sanders) -- (17:12) Sanders talks and introduces the next tune -- (17:33) All I Ever Need Is You (Ray Sanders) -- (19:40) Ritter thanks Sanders and introduces Tom T. Hall -- (22:24) Tom T. Hall thanks the audience -- (22:53) Ballad Of Forty Dollars (Tom T. Hall)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-7-01980_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-7-01980</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-01-14</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Greaves, Rusty (Entertainer); Ritter, Tex, 1905-1974; Sanders, Ray (Vocalist); Hall, Tom T.;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8377</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>