<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Kris Kristofferson interview - Ralph Emery - Part 2 - 1980-02-26</dc:title>
<dc:description>Part 2 of an interview with Kris Kristofferson conducted by Ralph Emery on February 26, 1980.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1980-02-26</dc:date>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Kristofferson talks about his first television appearance -- Kristofferson talks about appearing on the Grammys -- Emery checks the interview length -- Kristofferson talks about rumors -- Kristofferson talks about quitting drinking for the past 3 years and quitting to watch his daughter grow up and because he didn't like the way he looked on interviews while drunk -- Kristofferson says that at the height of his drinking he'd drink a bottle and a half of whiskey a day along with beer -- Kristofferson says he thought he had to be drunk to perform to prevent stage-fright -- Kristofferson talks about still being scared when acting and performing -- Kristofferson recalls Johnny Cash being scared before a performance just weeks before the interview -- Emery says veteran entertainers are more fearful of their peers rather than audiences -- Kristofferson talks about writing "For The Good Times" -- Kristofferson talks about his favorite recording of his songs by another artist and how he likes them all for different reasons -- Kristofferson talks about his huge respect for Waylon Jennings -- Kristofferson talks about "Why Me, Lord?" and how he had a religious experience during the writing -- Kristofferson feels embarrassed talking about religion -- Emery thanks Kristofferson for being on the show</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1078_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1078.1.1</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2017-07-19</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Emery, Ralph; Kristofferson, Kris, 1936-;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/5385</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>