<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>All Star Western Theatre - 1947-04-22 - Part 2</dc:title>
<dc:description>Part 2 of All Star Western Theatre radio program from April 22, 1947. Featuring Foy Willing and the Riders Of The Purple Sage, with announcer Cottonseed Clark, and guest Jimmy Wakely.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1947-04-22</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Foy Willing; Riders Of The Purple Sage; Jimmy Wakely</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Radio play 'The Lone Bandit' (Jimmy Wakely, cast) [continued from part 1] -- Cottonseed Clark announces the cast -- Cottonseed Clark introduces Foy Willing and Jimmy Wakely -- Foy Willing and Jimmy Wakely talk -- A Melody From The Sky (Jimmy Wakely) -- Drifting Along, Singing A Song (instrumental) -- Cottonseed Clark introduces Foy Willing -- Foy Willing talks -- I Wonder Who's Kissing Her Now (Foy Willing and the Riders Of The Purple Sage) -- Closing statement (Foy Willing) -- Theme (Drifting Along, Singing A Song) -- Closing statement (Cottonseed Clark)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>16 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR000716</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2007-01-24</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>All star western theatre (Radio program); Clark, Cottonseed; Willing, Foy, 1914-1978; Riders of the Purple Sage; Forte, Joe, 1893-1967; Wakely, Jimmy, 1914-1982; Murphy, Horace, 1880-1975</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/1906</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>