<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Artist in Residence - Jerry Douglas - 2008-08-27</dc:title>
<dc:description>Performance by Jerry Douglas and others in the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame on August 27, 2008.  Band includes Luke Bulla; Bryan Sutton; Bela Fleck; Sam Bush; Edgar Meyer; John Douglas; The Whites; </dc:description>
<dc:date>2008-08-27</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Jerry Douglas; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Performance includes; Another Morning (with Bela Fleck); Bounce (with Sam Bush and Edgar Meyer); Spanish Point (with Bryan Sutton and Luke Bulla); Green Slime; When You're Lonely (with John Douglas); This Morning At Nine (with John Douglas); Who's Your Uncle?; The Lochs Of Dread; The Lights Of Home; White House Blues (with Sam Bush);  Intermission; Hanging Around (with the Whites); You Put The Blue In Me (with the Whites); If It Ain't Love (Let's Leave It Alone) (with the Whites); Give Me Back That Old Familiar Feeling (with the Whites); Lonesome Wind (with the Whites); Making Believe (with the Whites); Fancy Dance (with the Whites); Tumbling Tumbleweeds (with the Whites); Abilene Gal (with the Whites); Swing Down Sweet Chariot (with the Whites);</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>CD-R;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>PP0107</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2015-12-03</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Douglas, Jerry, 1956-; Bush, Sam; Bulla, Luke; Sutton, Bryan; Fleck, Bela; Meyer, Edgar; Douglas, John; the Whites (Musical group); Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/2745</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>