<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Songwriter Session - Kelly Archer - 2017-10-28</dc:title>
<dc:description>Performance by singer songwriter Kelly Archer from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on October 28, 2017.  Includes questions from the audience. </dc:description>
<dc:date>2017-10-28</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Kelly Archer; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Introductory comments by Abi Tapia begin in progress / (01:20) Opening comments by Kelly and talks about her background / (04:18) Introduces the next song / (04:56) Performs Somebody Else Will / (07:55) Welcomes audience members / (08:48)  Talks about story songs in country music and introduces the next song / (10:14) Performs Something Borrowed / (14:28) Talks about Justin Moore and co-writing songs with Justin Weaver and tells story of being let go from her publishing deal / (17:49)  Performs On My Highway / (21:54) Introduces the next song / (25:30) Performs For Her / (29:25) Talks about writing the next song / (33:) Performs Love Like Mine / (36:17) Talks about the next song / (36:59) Performs unidentified song probably titled I'm Gonna Love You / (39:56) Answers question from the audience about co-writing and the ideas for songs / (43:05) Performs Sleep Without You / (46:07) Final comments / (46:31) Walk-our music / (49:40) FILE END           </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/24;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0074</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2018-09-13</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Archer, Kelly; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8153</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>