<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Ralph Emery Interviews Merle Haggard [Unedited]</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording is from Ralph Emery's (entertainer) interview of Merle Haggard (performer) for the Ralph Emery Show. Recording is unedited and from July of 1987.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1987-07</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Ralph Emery; Merle Haggard</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Merle Haggard addresses his concerns with Russia and praises Oliver North -- (01:00) Haggard compares his family to the one from the Grapes of Wrath while discussing "Mama's Hungry Eyes" -- (01:31) Haggard describes the marriage that inspired "My Favorite Memory" -- (02:02) Ralph Emery inquires about the change of age effecting Haggard when he wrote "Are the Good Times Really Over" -- (03:38) Emery inquires is Haggard believes his title of the Poet of the Common Man -- (05:02) Emery questions whether or not there will be a Merle Haggard movie -- (06:53) Emery praises Haggard for the large number of awards he had been nominated for -- (07:51) Emery and Haggard discuss a show Haggard did with Marty Robbins -- (09:13) Emery and Haggard discuss Haggard's second wife Bonnie Owens -- (10:45) Emery introduces Haggard's band, and Haggard reveals the band had been together since 1965</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1377_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1377</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-04-12</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Emery, Ralph; Haggard, Merle; Haggard, Merle, 1937-2016;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8787</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>