<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Interview - Wanda Jackson - 2017-12-02</dc:title>
<dc:description>Interview with Wanda Jackson from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on December 2, 2017.  Interview moderated by Scott Bomar.  In conjunction with the release of the book Every Night Is Saturday Night: A Country Girl's Journey to the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame.  Includes selected audio excerpts and audio from video. </dc:description>
<dc:date>2017-12-02</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Wanda Jackson; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Walk-in music / (01:32) Opening announcements by Sara Lederach / (02:46) Walk-in music continues / (05:18) Opening comments and introduction of Scott Bomar and Wanda Jackson by Michael Gray / (10:21) Opening comments from Scott and Wanda / (10:29) Wanda introduces her granddaughter to the crowd / (11:30) Scott thanks the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum for hosting this event / (12:45) Introduces and plays video of Wanda performing the song Mean, Mean Man / (16:28) Scott introduces attendees Randy Fox and Becky Riser / (18:05) Wanda talks about her move from Oklahoma to California and what she heard in California that influenced her / (19:56) Wanda talks about her Father and her first guitar / (22:02) Talks about returning to Oklahoma from California and ending up as a KLPR radio personality at age 14 / (23:56) Talks about getting a phone call from Hank Thompson  after one of her radio performances /                     </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(25:43) Talks about her first professional public performance appearing with Hank Thompson / (27:08) Talks about being a teenager and beginning to date Leonard Sipes aka Tommy Collins / (28:25) Taking Tommy Collins to California with them on a trip and him staying / (29:14) Talk about Tommy Collins, Ferlin Husky and Merle Haggard / (30:01) Talk about Capitol Records and the first time Hank Thompson attempted to get Wanda signed to Capitol / (31:19) Talks about signing with Decca Records / (31:56) Plays recording of You Can't Have My Love by Wanda and Billy Gray / (33:15) Talks about the success of, and recording of that song / (34:48) Talks about appearing the first time on the Grand Ole Opry in Nashville / (37:20) Talks about Elvis Presley / (40:07) Talks about performing on a show in Cape Girardeau, Missouri with Elvis and him talking her into performing Rock-a-Billy music / (43:23) Wanda talks about being on Capitol Records and her first recording of Rock-a-Billy music /                   </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/24;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0094</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2018-11-08</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Jackson, Wanda, 1937-; Presley, Elvis, 1935-1977; Thompson, Hank, 1925-2007; </dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8253</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>