<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Leroy Smith demo performances - 1980-03-18</dc:title>
<dc:description>Various demo performances, as performed by Leroy Smith (performer) and recorded on March 18, 1980 and sent to Cedarwood Publishing Company.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1980-03-18</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Leroy Smith</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Forever's Not As Long As I Once Thought (Leroy Smith) -- (01:48) I'm Gonna Be A Pro Wrestler (Leroy Smith) -- (03:33) If I Had My Life To Live Over Again (Leroy Smith) -- (06:18) You Don't Have To Be Crazy, But It Helps (Leroy Smith) -- (08:13) Dancing Lady (Leroy Smith) -- (10:54) Love Don't Come As Easy For Some As It Does For Others (Leroy Smith) -- (14:09) Life Begins At 40 (Leroy Smith) -- (18:52) I Wonder What I Would Be Doing Tonight (Leroy Smith) -- (22:15) Sad Little Angel (Leroy Smith)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 quarter tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-7-06487_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-7-06487</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-05-30</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Cedarwood Publishing Company; Smith, Leroy</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9029</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>