<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Performance and Interview - Mable John - 2006-07-08 - Tape one of two.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Interview with and performance by Mable John from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on July 8, 2006.  Tape one of two.  In support of the exhibit I Can&#8217;t Stop Loving You: Ray Charles and Country Music.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2006-07-08</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Mable John;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Recording begins in progress.  Opening comments by Michael Gray.  Includes questions by the audience.  Subjects include; Her background and working with the Barry Gordy family -- Meeting Barry Gordy through Gordy's mother -- Gordy founding Motown Records at John's and Smokey Robinson's suggestion -- Story about opening for Billie Holiday -- Holiday's teachings -- Her time in Nashville -- Working with the Nashville group the Imperials -- Leaving Motown Records -- Joining Ray Charles' band -- Working the Johnny Cash television show -- WLAC Radio and John "R" Richbourg -- Talks about her brother Little Willie John and his advice -- Her decision not to sing after her brother's death -- Ray Charles talking her back in to singing with him -- Story about Al Bell and signing with Stax Records --  Story about songwriter Deanie Parker -- Ray Charles teaching her a new singing style -- Screening of Shake performance on television -- Story about the dresses -- </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Setting guidelines for the Raelettes -- Working for Ray Charles -- Leaving Ray Charles -- Continuing her friendship with Charles -- Charles' last days and his personality -- John's recent book -- Excerpt from book regarding expressions from the soul and making a happy noise --  WSM Radio break-in including Eddie Stubbs intimate evening with Vince Gill (Unknown date) -- End of tape one.</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>RDAT digital tape;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RS.2014.0148</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2017-05-05</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>John, Mable; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/5169</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>