<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Chet Atkins Interview/Performance at Blair School of Music Side Two  </dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of Chet Atkins being interviewed and performing at The Blair School Of Music. </dc:description>
<dc:creator>Chet Atkins </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Side Two - (0:00) -- Chet Atkins begins performing an instrumental piece by Jerry Reed. (1:51) -- Chet Atkins begins playing part of a tune named "Scarecrow." (2:32) -- John Johns asks Chet Atkins when he first became interested in playing 'classical guitar', or nylon string guitar. (4:45) -- Chet Atkins discusses playing guitar for Segovia. The first five minutes of this tape can also be found at the end of side one. (8:30) -- John Johns asks Chet Atkins how many classical guitars he currently owns. (9:36) -- Chet Atkins discusses recording with Mark Knopfler. (11:00) -- John Johns tells a story about Chet Atkins. (12:28) -- Chet Atkins speaks about his recent album sales. (17:02) -- Chet Atkins mentions practicing behind stage at the Grand Ole Opry. (17:42) -- Chet Atkins speaks on his relationship and advice received from Byron Nelson (golfer). "You can get so from instructors and teachers and then you've got to dig it up yourself." - Chet Atkins. (19:22) -- John Johns asks Chet Atkins about how he first met Steve Sholes. (22:57) -- Chet Atkins discusses working with George Barnes. (23:17) -- "The chair would squeak and he would say, F#!" - Chet Atkins telling a joke about George Barnes. (23:35) -- Chet Atkins mentions learning and playing with George Barnes in a hotel room. (24:58) -- John Johns telling a story about interviewing Steve Sholes about who made the most money for RCA. (26:14) -- Chet Atkins playing a snippet of "Let It Be Me." (27:49) -- Chet Atkins speaks about Charley Pride. (31:22) -- Chet Atkins speaks about his first guitar methodology book through RCA. (33:08) -- Someone from the audience asks Chet Atkins about whether he listens to his own recordings. (34:20) -- Member of audience questions Chet Atkins about when he almost quit playing music in 1946. (38:39) -- Chet Atkins describes meeting and working with The Carter Sisters. (41:22) -- Member of audience asks about how Chet Atkins began working with Mark Knopfler. </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>audio cassette, compact;</dc:format>
<dc:format>1.75 ips;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CAS4670_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>CAS4670</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-08-28</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Atkins, Chet;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9448</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>