<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Discussion - Woman Enough: Loretta Lynn's Legacy - 2018-08-04</dc:title>
<dc:description>Panel discussion on Loretta Lynn and Lynn&#8217;s enduring impact and the adversities she and other women have faced and continue to face in the country music world.  Held in the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on August 4, 2018. Participants include Holly Gleason, Aubrie Sellers and Brenda Lee.  Discussion moderated by Abi Tapia.  Includes audio from video screening. </dc:description>
<dc:date>2018-08-04</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Holly Gleason; Aubrie Sellers; Brenda Lee;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Walk-in music / (02:17) Opening comments and introductions by Abi Tapia / (07:22) Opening comments by Brenda Lee (08:14)  Holly talks about her first memory of loving a song / (08:43) Brenda talks about hearing her Mother singing to her, how it affected her and tells story about meeting Hank Williams / (10:08) Aubrie talks about her first memory of loving songs / (10:43) Brenda talks about when she discovered that she loved to sing and tells story about advise she got from Judy Garland / (12:02) Brenda talks about her perception of the music world, working with Owen Bradley and tells story about Owen, Loretta Lynn, Doyle Wilburn and the finding the song Fool #1 / (13:54) Brenda asked about being underestimated early in her career due to her age / (14:25) Plays video of Brenda Lee performing the song Dynamite / (16:42) Aubrie talks about her thoughts about the music business / (17:26) Holly talks about the music she listened to and how she discovered country music / (18:03) Brenda talks about Owen's success with female singers / (19:35) Holly comments about Owen Bradley / (19:46) Brenda with more on Owen and tells story about the song I'm Sorry / (22:17) Talk about how hard it is for a female artist being on the charts today / (23:12) Holly talks about how Loretta Lynn affected her / (23:58) Aubrie talks about her favorite music moment of Loretta's being the Van Lear Rose album / (24:31) Brenda talks about loving Loretta for who she is / (27:06) Brenda talks about Dottie West and her relationship with her / (29:15) Holly talks about the importance of having other women in the industry to mentor her / (30:05) Aubrie talks about being a woman on the road with mostly men / (30:32) Brenda talks about the problem of newer artists knowing little about the pioneers of the industry / (31:00) Holly talks about the history of the music and industry being lost / (31:48) Brenda talks about when she was a popular artist and knowing how knocked the doors down for her / (33:05) Aubrie talks about her contemporaries not knowing music knowledge past the last 20 years / (33:24) Brenda tells story about being at the Grand Ole Opry and seeing who see considered a little girl backstage / (34:38) Holly talks about her book Woman Walk The Line and her inspiration for putting it together / (37:10) Holly talks about Tanya Tucker and reads a portion of her essay on Tanya / (44:40) Brenda talks about her relationship with Tanya Tucker, being child stars and tells story about appearing on the Crook and Chase TV show with her / (47:52) Brenda tells story about her daughter first going to College and Tanya offering to give her housing in California / (46:09) Brenda compares Tanya to Loretta and talks about working with Tanya recently on a cruise ship and her tribute to Glen Campbell / (50:05) Holly talks about her book and Tanya / (50:24) Brenda talks about Holly's book / (50:57) Aubrie reads an essay excerpt she wrote in Woman Walk The Line on Alison Krauss / (55:16) Plays excerpt of Aubrie Sellers Sit Here and Cry / (57:09) Discussion about Loretta's song The Pill / (58:12) Plays video of documentary segment on the song The Pill / (01:00:39) Brenda talks about the time period when the song The Pill came out / (01:01:07) Holly and Brenda talk about the effect that the song The Pill had / (01:01:50) Holly talks about the segment on The Pill in her book Woman Walk The Line / (01:02:43) Aubrie talks about her reaction to the song The Pill / (01:04:28) Holly talks about the changing meanings of songs over time and experience / (01:05:52) Holly talks about Taylor Swift and her contributions to the book Woman Walk The Line / (01:07:22) Holly reads essay excerpt on Brenda Lee from her book written by Taylor Swift / (01:10:23) Brenda talks about what it means to her to have young artists like Taylor Swift look up to her / (01:13:50) Aubrie talks about her Mom and what she learned from her being in the music business / (01:15:15) Brenda talks about Patsy Cline being a woman in country music that changed her life and tells a Patsy story / (01:19:19) Final comments / (01:19:31) Walk-out music / (01:19:49) FILE END                                             </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 48/24</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0140</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2019-04-03</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Lynn, Loretta; Gleason, Holly; Lee, Brenda; Sellers, Aubrie; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8874</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>