<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Wild Rose Interview - Biff Collie - Tape 2</dc:title>
<dc:description>Tape 2 of 2. Recording of an interview with Wild Rose (performance group) conducted by Biff Collie. </dc:description>
<dc:creator>Wild Rose; Biff Collie</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Wild Rose members describe why they chose "Breaking New Ground" to be the title track; Nancy Given jokes how "Breaking New Ground" caused trouble with her husband -- (01:13) Given gives praise to Carl Jackson -- (01:44) "I Can't Lose What I Never Had" writer Jim Rushing is reflected on by the Wild Rose members -- (02:58) "Go Down Swingin'" is described as a fun song, and the process of choosing songs for an album is discussed -- (03:37) Collie has the members of Wild Rose introduce themselves -- (04:59) Pamela Gadd describes growing up in Hammansburg, Ohio -- (05:38) "Where Did We Go Wrong" is joked about being a 'happy song' -- (05:58) Kathy Mac describes how she got her stage name -- (07:03) "Lonesome Highway (To the End of the Rainbow)" is described as a song about perusing from your dreams -- (07:31) Given describes how "On the Bayou" is known in the group under a different name; the Wild Rose band members joke about Louisiana -- (08:28) Collie has Pam Gadd joke, about knowing herself, while describing "Home Sweet Highway" -- (10:14) Gadd touches on how "Home Sweet Highway" is a tribute to those who had helped them; the Wild Rose members describe a incident with their Bus getting stuck -- (11:56) Collie has the Wild Rose band members touch on how they had changed bus drivers and the change in their careers -- (13:55) Pam Perry reveals that "Teach Me to Say Goodbye" is a tribute to her mother -- (15:47) "Who Needs You" is described as a negative song about people who will not change -- (18:07) Collie and the Wild Rose band members joke about Wanda Vick's background -- (19:58) "Easy to Say/Hard to Prove" is discussed, and the Wild Rose band members discuss their relationship with Beth Nielsen Chapman -- (21:08) Collie has the Wild Rose members reflect on the instances where songs are introduced near the end of the album cutting process; Gadd describes radio's influence on Wild Rose's success  -- (23:08) Gadd remembers a time when she was encouraged to pursue music by her father; additionally, Gadd recalls how she discovered her comfort on stage  -- (25:43) "Wild Rose" and the banjo are joked about by the Wild Rose band members -- (26:13) Wild Rose and Biff Collie say their thanks and goodbyes</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1241_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1241</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-02-15</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Wild Rose (Musical group); Collie, Biff;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8508</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>