<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Words and Music Night - 2012-04-24</dc:title>
<dc:description>Words and Music Night program held in the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on April 24, 2012.  Professional songwriters with student co-writers performing songs they have written together during the course of the school year. Hosted by</dc:description>
<dc:date>2012-04-24</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Diamond Rio;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>"Performances include; When I Go To Middle School (Bob Spanburgh with Taylor Griggs); Leaving London (Sandy Ramos with Gaby Viner); Pretzel Pete (Mark Johnson with Amalia Estrada); Strong (Jason Duke with Sophie Bailey); I&#8217;m A Boy (Joel Atkins with Sims Lance); You And Me (Tim Buppert with Engy Aziz); Island Time (Christy McDonald and Erick Hedrick with Emma Farley); Dreams (Tammy Vice with Gracie Fleser, Addy Mitchell, and Kaitlyn Sneed); Thankful (Les Kerr with Jenna DeRivera); That&#8217;s A Noun (Simon McCain with Ladarionta Burnley); Barn Rat (Jerry Vandiver with Zoe Smith); I Love Food (Bob Howard with Gisele Campos and Isabella Nunez); Can&#8217;t Stop Loving You (Misty Rae with Whitney Brown and Anna Wright); A Baker&#8217;s Gift (Gary Michael Smith with Lily Unick); I Hate Homework (Shane Adams with Austin Ayres); One More Day (Diamond Rio);
</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>CD-R;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>PP0162</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2015-01-21</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Diamond Rio (Musical group); Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/3136</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>