<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Saturday Social - Unknown date - Part 1</dc:title>
<dc:description>WSM program Saturday Social, unknown broadcast date, part 1. Personnel include Grant Turner (announcer), George Morgan (host, performer), the Village Four (performers), Little Jimmy Dickens (performer), Dale Potter (performer), Judy Martin (performer), and Jamup &amp; Honey (performers). Also mentioned as being on the program but not featured in this part is Zeb Turner.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>George Morgan; Village Four; Little Jimmy Dickens; Dale Potter; Judy Martin; Jamup &amp; Honey</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Theme -- Opening statement (Grant Turner) -- I Hung My Head And Cried (George Morgan) -- Opening statement (George Morgan) -- Camptown Races (Village Four) -- George Morgan introduces Little Jimmy Dickens -- Take An Old Cold Tater (And Wait) (Little Jimmy Dickens) -- George Morgan introduces Dale Potter -- Arkansas Traveler (Dale Potter fiddle) -- George Morgan introduces Judy Martin -- Jealous Heart (Judy Martin) -- George Morgan introduces Jamup &amp; Honey -- Comedy routine (Jamup &amp; Honey) (incomplete)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>16 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR001334</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2014-12-18</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); Saturday social (Radio program); Turner, Grant; Morgan, George, 1925-1975; Village Four (Musical group); Dickens, Little Jimmy, 1920-; Potter, Dale; Martin, Judy, 1918-1951; Jamup &amp; Honey; Wilds, Lee Davis, 1902-1982; Turner, Zeb, 1915-1978</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/641</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>