<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Interview and performance - Old Crow Medicine Show - 2017-04-28</dc:title>
<dc:description>Interview with Ketch Secor and Chris "Critter" Fuqua and performance by Old Crow Medicine Show celebrating the release of their album 50 Years of Blonde on Blonde from the CMA Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on April 28, 2017.  Includes audio from video.  Interview segment hosted by Peter Cooper.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2017-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Ketch Secor; Chris "Critter" Fugua; Old Crow Medicine Show; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00 Walk-in music / (19:41) Plays recording of Old Crow Medicine Show's Rainy Day Woman #12 and #35 / (23:31) Peter Cooper introduces Ketch Secor and Critter Fuqua and talks about last years concert performance of the album 50 Years of Blonde On Blonde by Old Crow Medicine Show / (25:15) Ketch and Critter talk about how the idea for recording the album honoring the 50th anniversary of Blonde On Blonde came about / (28:32) Talk about getting on board with the project and thinking about rocking it out at first / (30:41) Talk about deciding on the arrangements for each of the songs and how to perform them live / (33:26) Talk about the musicians that played on the Dylan album and Old Crow's arrangement of the song One Of Us Must Know (Sooner Or Later) / (35:39) Introduction of and plays recording of One Of Us Must Know (Sooner Or Later) / (40:55) Talk about the performance and performance of the live album, the difficulties and excitement in pulling it off / (43:57) Talk about Columbia Records being interested in signing them and releasing the live album / (48:50) Talk about how they felt signing with Columbia Records / (50:53) Talk about the influence that Bob Dylan had on them / (51:22) Talk about their arrangement of the song Leopard Skin Pill Box Hat / (53:41) Plays recording of Leopard Skin Pill Box Hat / (57:16) Final comments from Peter and introduction of Old Crow Medicine Show / (58:34) Band comments / (59:15) Performance of Obviously 5 Believers / (01:02:02) Talk about the previous song and introduces the next song / (01:02:52) Performs I Want You / (01:06:19) Comments from the band about Blonde on Blonde / (01:07:42) Performs Just Like A Woman / (01:11:58) Introduction of the band / (01:14:08) Performs Most Likely You Go Your Way And I'll Go Mine / (01:17:26) Final applause / (01:18:05) Walk-out music / (01:19:27) Walk-out music end / (01:19:30) FILE END                              </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 48/24;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0165</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2019-06-13</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Secor, Ketch; Fugua, Chris; Old Crow Medicine Show (Musical group); Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9185</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>