<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Ronnie McDowell Interview - Biff Collie</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of an interview with Ronnie McDowell (performer) conducted by Biff Collie. </dc:description>
<dc:date>1990-02-28</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Ronnie McDowell; Biff Collie</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Ronnie McDowell radio spot for Biff Collie and the Music City Album Review -- (00:09) Collie softly describes the structure of the radio spots -- (00:20) McDowell says "Hey, couldn't be any better" -- (00:26) McDowell says "Goes together like Gene Autry, Champion, and Back in the Saddle Again" -- (00:33) McDowell radio spot introducing the break for the Music City Album Review -- (00:42) McDowell radio spot for the Music City Album Review -- (00:54) McDowell radio spot declaring that they are having fun for the Music City Album Review -- (01:05) McDowell radio spot declaring the audience does not put off listening to the Music City Album Review -- (01:17) McDowell radio spot declaring "You can't lose if you listen to Biff Collie and the Music City Album Review" -- (01:28) McDowell radio spot addressing that he is hosting the Music City Album Review with Collie -- (01:38) McDowell thirty-minute break radio spot for the Music City Album Review -- (01:48) McDowell hour break radio spot for the Music City Album Review -- (01:58)  McDowell return-from-break radio spot for the Music City Album Review -- (02:08) McDowell ninety-minute break radio spot for the Music City Album Review -- (02:16) McDowell says his goodbyes for the Music City Album Review radio spot -- (02:28) McDowell discusses how "The King is Gone" was put on his greatest hits because of its overall popularity -- (03:07) "It's Only Make Believe" is told by McDowell to be a song he had to entice Conway Twitty to sing on -- (04:18) McDowell recalls being in Charlotte and listening to his son, Tyler D. McDowell, be born over the phone -- (04:53) Collie and McDowell discuss McDowell's children's weight and age [incomplete] -- (05:18) "I Love You, I Love You, I Love You" is said to be a good album for McDowell, and McDowell says his producer did not McDowell to sing like McDowell -- (06:39) "Sheet Music" is recalled by McDowell to be a song by Joe Metter; McDowell says this is his first 'gut-feeling' song -- (07:58) "I'm Still Missing You" is told by McDowell to be his attempt to create a song similar to Elvis Presley's style; McDowell recalls calling Gordon Stoker for assistance -- (08:49) Collie has McDowell recall his feelings when The King is Gone was released; McDowell was broke at the time The King is Gone was released -- (11:20) McDowell recalls working in Mitchellville, Tennessee on a snowy night when he wrote "All Tied Up" -- (12:37) McDowell reflects on the nature of working in music -- (13:17) McDowell tells about how Troy Seals convinced him to record "Since I Don't Have You;" McDowell had difficulty changing the track into country -- (14:20) McDowell associates "She's a Little Past Forty" to the Calgary Stampede and McDowell's trust in radio -- (15:19) McDowell discusses the demographic that relates to "She's a Little Past Forty" -- (15:38) Collie has McDowell discuss how McDowell is releasing a greatest hits album of Curb Records recordings because he had already done one for CBS Records -- (17:02) Collie and McDowell converse about the association people make for McDowell and Presley; Collie points out how he did not have pictures with Hank Williams, despite the fact Collie had helped Williams -- (18:16) McDowell speaks about the pride he has to be associated with Presley, and Collie and McDowell express how they believe people are jealous of McDowell's ability -- (19:23) McDowell talks about writing "American Music" with Seals, and McDowell praises Seals while talking about his unique music video associated with "American Music" -- (20:31) McDowell speaks on the difficulty on hand-painting each frame for a two-minute music video -- (21:36) McDowell tells how he took a line, from another song, to create "Watching the Girls Go By," and McDowell says it's a follow-up to "Wandering Eyes" -- (23:04) Collie and McDowell reflect on how McDowell will be sent scripts and McDowell will go in the studio with little guidance -- (24:01) McDowell recalls all the Presley songs he recorded, and McDowell and Collie reflect on how people lost interest in Presley -- (24:50) McDowell says, "It's either that Biff, or it doesn't have enough dirt to it. It's too clean"</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1199_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1199</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-01-30</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>McDowell, Ronnie; Collie, Biff;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8453</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>