<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Girls Next Door Interview - Biff Collie</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of an interview with Girls Next Door (performance group) conducted by Biff Collie.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1990-01-16</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Girls Next Door; Biff Collie</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Biff Collie introduces the Girls Next Door album "How 'Bout Us" and first track "He's Gotta Have Me" -- (00:06) "He's Gotta Have Me" is talked about by Tammy Stephens as an aggressive representation of someone who left and came back -- (00:48) The Girls Next Door joke with Collie and introduce Ricky Van Shelton's "I'll Leave This World Loving You" -- (01:12) "I Called It Love Once" is introduced by Collie and reflected on by Stephens as a representation of changing perspective through education and music -- (02:04) Stephens talks about growing up singing gospel music and being in various different vocal groups through school -- (03:00) An Stephens and Diane Williams talk about performing at the Grand Ole Opry and joining MTM a management company -- (04:21) The album title "How 'Bout Us" is said to be a statement about the various issues the group had beginning their music careers -- (05:02) "One of the Boys" is talked about by Williams as how growing older changed how girls are perceived by their male counter parts -- (05:42) Doris King talks about getting familiar with songs while being on the road -- (06:22) "Maybe You Wouldn't Be Miss'" is talked about by Cindy Nixon and King about how they perceived it to be a single soon and the upcoming video -- (08:14) Williams introduces K.T. Oslin's "I'll Always Come Back" -- (08:23) Collie introduces the group and Williams talks about being a part of an air force family and moving around from Belgium, Germany to Denver, Colorado and eventually moving to Nashville, Tennessee -- (09:00) Nixon talks about how she's one of the few artists born in Nashville and having a great deal of country music influencing her youth -- (09:48) King talks about growing up in Nashville and her exposure to music and love of horses -- (10:35) "Few Good Men" is described by King as a song for a women that needs multiple good men to heal her -- (11:01) "How Can They Call This Cheating" is told by Williams as a song by a female artist in a male dominated field -- (12:14) Williams says "Here's my favorite Steve Wariner song" -- (12:18) "It's Too Late" is told as by King that their engineer (Nelson Larken) does not tell them who writes the song to avoid bias -- (13:21) "Last Goodbye" and the Girls Next Door are introduced by Collie -- (13:33) Williams explains "Last Goodbye" as a 'honky tonk' type song -- (14:02) Stephens talks about a time where they traveled in a van and being confronted by a man about not having a fiddle -- (14:52) Nixon talks about a fan who bought five copies of their album -- (15:29) Nixon thinks about a song to play and "Restless Heart" by Wheels is introduced -- (15:50) Collie and Girls Next Door talk about the ease of having a three word named band -- (16:25) "Wasn't It You" is discussed by King as the most traditional song about mistreatment -- (16:55) Nixon describes "Wasn't It You" as a song about someone who left that comes back -- (17:22) Collie and Girls Next Door discuss that this is the first show they have ever done their entire album and been a performing disc jockey -- (18:10) Girls Next Door thank Collie for being there and talk about purchasing their album -- (19:13) Girls Next Door Say Goodbye</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1131_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1131</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-01-02</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Girls Next Door (Musical group); Collie, Biff;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8329</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>