<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Music &amp; the Spoken Word - Mormon Tabernacle Choir radio program - Episode 707 Part 2 - 1943-01-31 - KSL - WLAC</dc:title>
<dc:description>Syndicated radio broadcast of the Music &amp; the Spoken Word radio program, originally broadcast from KSL (Salt Lake City, Utah). Recorded from Temple Square in Salt Lake City, Utah, the program is narrated by Richard L. Evans, conducted by J. Spencer Cornwall, and performed by the Mormon Tabernacle Choir with Alexander Schreiner on organ. This is the second part of the 707th airing, recorded on January 31, 1943. Part one: TR004038_2</dc:description>
<dc:date>1943-01-31</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Mormon Tabernacle Choir; Alexander Schreiner</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(0:00) [Blank] / (0:29) Richard L. Evans introduces the next performance / (0:47) The Mormon Tabernacle Choir performs a largetto composed by George Frideric Handel / (4:05) Richard L. Evans reads a passage / (6:58) Alexander Schreiner performs "[Unconfirmed piece]" / (7:52) Richard L. Evans introduces the next performance / (8:25) The Mormon Tabernacle Choir performs a hymn composed by Charles Gounod / (12:35) Richard L. Evans announces the closing statements</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>16 inch glass-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR004035_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>TR004035</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:isPartOf>TRB014_1</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-05-26</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>CBS Inc.; Mormon Tabernacle Choir; Music and the spoken word (Radio program); KSL (Radio station : Salt Lake City, Utah); WLAC (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/7522</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>