<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Old Timers Quartet - 1949-06-11</dc:title>
<dc:description>WSM program featuring the Old Timers Quartet (also styled as Old-Timers' Quartet and Ol' Timers' Quartet), originally broadcast 1949-06-11. Personnel include David Cobb (announcer), Frank Marlowe (host), and Joseph MacPherson (performer).</dc:description>
<dc:date>1949-06-11</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Old Timers Quartet; Joseph MacPherson</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Grand Ole Opry commercial (David Cobb) -- Theme (Long, Long Ago) (Old Timers Quartet) -- Opening statement (David Cobb) -- Opening statement (Frank Marlowe) -- Tie Me To Your Apron Strings Again (Old Timers Quartet) -- Frank Marlowe talks -- I'll Take You Home Again, Kathleen (Old Timers Quartet) -- Frank Marlowe talks -- Great Day (Joseph MacPherson) -- Frank Marlowe talks -- In The Chapel In The Moonlight (Old Timers Quartet) -- Frank Marlowe talks -- Precious Memories (Old Timers Quartet) -- Theme (Long, Long Ago) (Old Timers Quartet) -- Closing statement (David Cobb)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>16 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR001305_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>TR001305</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2014-12-01</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); Old-timers' quartet (Radio program); Old Timers Quartet; McPherson, Joseph (Musician); Cobb, David (Announcer); National Life &amp; Accident Insurance Company, Inc. (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/601</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>