<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Various record and radio excerpts</dc:title>
<dc:description>Various recordings of performances featuring various performers and other unidentified performers.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Sons Of The Pioneers; Curt Massey; Georgia Wildcats; Texas Troubadours; Golden West Cowboys; Shorty Boyd</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Test tones -- I Belong To The Range (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- Cowboys And Indians (Sons Of The Pioneers) [unconfirmed] -- Happy Roving Cowboy (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- Nelly Bly (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- The Man On The Flying Trapeze (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- Outlaw Rag (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- Wild Cat (Curt Massey) [unconfirmed] -- [Unidentified tune] (Georgia Wildcats) -- Sally Goodin (Georgia Wildcats) -- Whispering Wind (Texas Troubadours) -- Cajun Stomp ([Unidentified]) -- Waiting For The Robert E. Lee ([Unidentified]) -- [Unidentified fiddle tune] (Shorty Boyd fiddle) -- Mama Don't Allow It (incomplete) (Golden West Cowboys) -- How Was I To Know (Sons Of The Pioneers) (incomplete) -- When The Prairie Sun Climbs Out Of The Hay (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- The Timber Trail (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- The Yellow Rose Of Texas (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- Hillbilly Wedding In June (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- Nelly Bly (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- Cherokee Strip (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- I'm A Cowboy Rockefeller (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- (Down The Trail) To San Antone (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- Good Mornin' (Sons Of The Pioneers) [unconfirmed] -- Old Black Mountain Trail (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- Jubilation Jamboree (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- Where The Rio Rolls Along (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- No Good Son Of A Gun (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- Rocky Roads (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- [Unidentified tune] (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- Its A Lie (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- Ridin' Home (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- South Of Santa Fe (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- Under The Stars Over Texas (Sons Of The Pioneers) [unconfirmed] -- Moonlight Melody (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- [Unidentified tune] -- I Ain't Worried (Sons Of The Pioneers) [unconfirmed] -- Lazy (Sons Of The Pioneers) [unconfirmed] -- Oompah Rag (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- [Unidentified guitar tune] (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- Give Me A Home On The Pains (Sons Of The Pioneers) [unconfirmed] -- Lone Coyote (Sons Of The Pioneers) [unconfirmed] -- Cowboys And Indians (Sons Of The Pioneers) -- I'll Be Switched (Sons Of The Pioneers) [unconfirmed]</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-0064_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-0064</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2017-09-20</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Sons of the Pioneers; Golden West Cowboys (Musical group); Boyd, Shorty; </dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/5817</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>