<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Hank Williams: Complete Works Volume 6</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of a number of performances of Hank Williams Sr. (singer/songwriter). Tape is part of a collection labeled Hank Williams: Complete Works. Tape is labeled as part six of eight. The tapes were donated from the M.G.M. Studios collection.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Hank Williams</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Kaw-Liga (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (02:39) My Bucket Got a Hole in it (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (05:16) Cold, Cold Heart (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (08:03) I Won't be Home No More (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (10:52) My Heart Would Know (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (13:18) Honky Tonk Blues (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (15:32) Your Cheatin' Heart (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (18:18) Settin' the Woods on Fire (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (20:56) I Saw the Light (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (23:42) How Can You Refuse Him Now (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (26:32) Calling You (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (29:28) When God Comes and Gathers His Jewels (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (32:21) There's No Room in My Heart (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (34:40) The Waltz of the Wind (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (36:53) Pan American (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (39:46) With Tears in My Eyes (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (42:02) I Wish I Had a Nickel (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (43:49) Fly Trouble (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (46:37) Please Don't Let Me Love You (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (48:58) I'm Satisfied With You (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (51:35) No One Will Ever Know (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (53:57) Faded Love and Winter Roses (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (56:00) The First Fall of Snow (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (59:18) California Zephyr (Hank Williams Sr.)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1457_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1457</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-05-10</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Williams, Hank, 1923-1953; Williams, Hank, 1923-1953. I saw the light;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8964</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>