<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Garth Brooks Interview - Biff Collie</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of an interview with Garth Brooks (performer) conducted by Biff Collie.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1989-05-30</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Garth Brooks; Biff Collie</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Garth talks about "Not Counting You" being a 'tongue in cheek' type song and the expediency of how he wrote it why selling boots -- (01:03) Brooks talks about going up in Oklahoma, performing with Santa Fe and eventually moving to Nashville to sign a publishing deal / recording -- (02:01) Biff Collie and Brooks talk about "I've Got a Good Thing Going" and how its about someone losing their love -- (02:52) Brooks and Collie talk about having to experience a song before being able to sing believably -- (03:52) Collie and Brooks joke about his album title Garth Brooks and its originality -- (04:27) "If Tomorrow Never Comes" by Brooks is compared to "Tomorrow Never Comes" by Collie and Brooks describes it as a question to whether or not someone loved their wife as much as the could -- (06:10) Brooks tell "Everytime That It Rains" was written for a women, before he knew his wife, as a memory -- (07:04) Brooks talks about "Alabama Clay" drawing effect to Brooks about a boy who never knew he had a kid -- (08:26) "Much Too Young (To Feel This Damn Old)" by Brooks is reflected on its popularity -- (09:43) Brooks tells about how his song [possibly Cowboy Bill] floors his every time after -- (10:44) Brooks talks about "Nobody Gets Off in This Town" and figuring out the jabs it took to the places he was playing -- (11:56) Brooks says his wish for every artist is to work with Allen Reynolds -- (12:41) "I Know One" is talked about with Brooks meeting John Peel and being terrified to perform "I Know One" -- (14:06) Collie recaps the "I Know One" components and Brooks reflects on its importance -- (14:44) Brooks talks about "The Dance" and his immediate want to work with Tony Arata -- (16:41) Brooks thanks Collie and Collie returns the remarks -- (17:12) Collie tells why he remembers Brooks birthday and the outro is cut off </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1130_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1130</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-01-02</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Brooks, Garth; Collie, Biff;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8327</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>