<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Songwriter Session - Steve Dean and Bill Whyte - 2018-08-11</dc:title>
<dc:description>Performance by songwriters Steve Dean and Bill Whyte from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on August 11, 2018.  Includes questions from the audience.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2018-08-11</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Steve Dean; Bill Whyte; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Walk-in Music / (03:53) Opening comments and songwriter introductions by Abbie / (07:53) Opening comments by Steve and Bill / () Steve introduction the first song / (09:41) Performs Round About Way (Steve with Bill) / (12:48) Bill plays song excerpt and asks the audience where they're from / (14:25) Bill introduces the next song and talks about being inducted into the Country Radio Hall of Fame / (15:59) Performs Unidentified song probably titled A Face For Radio (Bill) / (19:51) Introduces the next song / (24:22) Performs Southern Star (Steve with Bill) / (27:30) Bill introduces of the next song / (29:06) Performs R And S Wood Flooring commercial (Bill with Steve) / (29:55) Bill introduces the next song / (31:53) Performs Safe Haven (Bill with Steve) / (35:55) Answers question about how they met each other / (37:58) Answers question about songwriting / (38:30) Answers question about songwriting royalties / (39:42) Answers question about the quality of songwriting today as compared to the past / (40:27) Steve introduces the next song / (41:32) Performs Watching You (Steve with Bill) / (45:30) Closing comments and introduction of the last song / (46:36) Performs I'm Going Ugly Early Tonight (Bill) / (49:58) Final comments / (50:02) Walk-out Music / (01:04:20) FILE END                       </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 48/24</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0138</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2019-03-29</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Dean, Steve; Whyte, Bill; Country Radio Hall of Fame; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8873</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>