<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Songwriter Session - Kyshona Armstrong, David Bingaman, Jennie Hayes Kurtz, Kelsey Burkhart, Tammy Rogers King and Alex Seier - 2018-01-27</dc:title>
<dc:description>Performance by participants in the acoustic guitar project including singer songwriters Kyshona Armstrong, David Bingaman and Jennie Hayes Kurtz (of Brother and the Hayes), Kelsey Burkhart, Tammy Rogers King (of the SteelDrivers) and Alex Seier.  Performances from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on January 27, 2018.  </dc:description>
<dc:date>2018-01-27</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Kyshona Armstrong; David Bingaman; Jennie Hayes Kurtz; Kelsey Burkhart; Tammy Rogers King; Alex Seier; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Walk-In Music / () Opening comments from Abi Tapia and introduction of Jennie Hays Kurtz / (03:22) Jennie introduces Tammy Rogers King / (04:03) Tammy intros the next song / (05:06) Performs Live More And Fear Less (Tammy Rogers King) / (08:11) Tammy intros the next song / (09:12) Performs unidentified song likely titled Family Reunion Minus One / (12:20) Jennie introduces Alex Seier / (13:14) Alex introduces the next song / (13L47) Performs unidentified song likely titled Unrepeatable (Alex Seier) / (17:23) Alex introduces the next song / (18:05) Performs Love You Anyway (Alex) / (21:41) Jennie introduces Kelsey Burkhart / (22:25) Kelsey intros the next song / (22:54) Performs Free (Kelsey) / (25:43) Kelsey introduces the next song / (26:05) Performs unidentified song likely titled The City That Never Sleeps / (29:47) Jennie introduces Kyshona Armstrong / (30:55) Kyshona introduces the next song / (31:08) Kyshona performs My Own Grave / </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(35:33) Kyshona introduces the next song / (35:40) Kyshona performs Same Blood / (39:52) Abi Tapia introduces Brother and the Hayes (David Bingaman and Jennie Hayes Kurtz) / (40:49) David and Jennie introduce the next song / (42:00) Something Beautiful (David and Jennie) / (45:15) David introduces the next song / (45:51) Performs Give In To The Day (David and Jennie) / 50:18 Final comments from David and Jennie / (50:31) Walk-out Music / (53:41) Walk-out Music end / (53:45) Open mic conversations and songwriter demos / (58:01) Microphone check / (58:58) Room conversation / (01:10:41) Walk-in Music and more room conversation / (01:13:35) FILE END            </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/24;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0090</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2018-10-31</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Armstrong, Kyshona; Bingaman, Davie; Kurtz, Jennie Hayes; Burkhart, Kelsey; King, Tammy Rogers; Seier, Alex; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8218</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>