<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Ralph Emery's Interview of Kris Kristofferson - 1980-02-26: Reel # 2</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of Ralph Emery (entertainer) interviewing Kris Kristofferson (musician) for the Ralph Emery Show. The interview takes place on February 26, 1980. The tape is part two of two.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1980-02-26</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Kris Kristofferson; Ralph Emery</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Ralph Emery and Kris Kristofferson discuss how Kristofferson feels about his wild success -- (01:01) Emery and Kristofferson recall Kristofferson's first interview with Emery, and Emery sites that people believe Kristofferson to be quiet -- (03:26) Kristofferson reflects on his sobriety -- (06:30) Emery asks Kristofferson if he ever gets scared of recording, and Kristofferson likens his experience to a Johnny Cash story -- (09:01) Emery asks Kristofferson to recall writing "For the Good Times" in the car -- (11:42) Emery asks to reflect on his favorite recording that he wrote -- (13:28) Kristofferson praises Waylon Jennings for his dedication to song-writers; additionally, Emery inquires about the religious implications of "Why Me Lord" -- (16:19) Emery expresses his praises of Kristofferson, and both say their goodbyes</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1078_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1078</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-08-12</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Emery, Ralph; Kristofferson, Kris; Kristofferson, Kris, 1936-;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9328</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>