<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Country Artists From Around The World - Nashville television program</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of a live taping in Nashville for television program Country Artists From Around The World, featuring Larry Cunningham (performer), Gordie Tapp (host/performer), Gary Buck (performer), Pat Campbell (host), and Rick McKenna (performer).</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Gordie Tapp; Gary Buck; Larry Cunningham</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) [Unidentified] introduces some notable audience members in attendance -- (00:30) [Unidentified] introduces Pat Campbell -- (00:50) Pat Campbell addresses audience members from England, and introduces some of the cast members and performers -- (04:00) [Unidentified] talks about this show being televised, and it being the first CMA sponsored show featuring various artists from around the world -- (04:40) Campbell introduces Bill Walker and his guests -- (05:40) Campbell introduces Rick McKenna -- (06:36) [Unidentified tune] (Rick McKenna) -- (09:18) Pat Campbell talks with McKenna about recording, and thanks the producers and workers who put on the program -- (10:30) Campbell introduces Jim Weir -- (12:18) [Unidentified] introduces Gordie Tapp -- (13:00) Tapp talks and introduces the program -- (14:00) Many Others (Gordie Tapp) -- (16:40) Tapp talks about the various nationalities present at the show -- (17:20) Many Others (Gordie Tapp) (incomplete) -- (17:45) Tapp introduces Gary Buck -- (18:18) It Takes Time (Gary Buck) -- (20:47) Gary Buck thanks the audience and introduces the next tune -- (21:05) Saunders' Ferry Lane (Gary Buck) -- (24:23) Tapp thanks Buck and introduces Larry Cunningham -- (24:58) I Guess I Better Go (Larry Cunningham) -- (27:47) (That's How I Learned To Love) That Good Old Country Music (Larry Cunningham) (incomplete)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-7-02060_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-7-02060</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-01-24</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Cunningham, Larry (Vocalist); Tapp, Gordie, 1922-2016;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8422</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>