<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Martha White Show - Lester Flatt and the Nashville Grass - 1977-05-03 - WSM</dc:title>
<dc:description>Multiple recordings of Martha White Shows, featuring Grant Turner (host),  Lester Flatt (host/performer), Kenny Ingram (performer), Benny Martin (performer), Marty Stuart (performer), the Nashville Grass (performers), and special guest John Hartford (performer) on radio station WSM (Nashville, Tenn.) First recording is from May 2-6, 1977 and second recording is from May 3, 1977.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1977-05-03</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Nashville Grass; Kenny Ingram; Lester Flatt; John Hartford; Benny Martin; Marty Stuart; Grandpa Jones</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Test tones -- Opening theme -- Opening statement (Grant Turner) -- Lester Flatt talks about special guest John Hartford -- Lester Flatt introduces Kenny Ingram -- Flint Hill Special (Kenny Ingram banjo) -- Martha White commercial (Grant Turner and Lester Flatt) -- John Hartford talks -- Gentle On My Mind (John Hartford) -- Lester Flatt talks about Hartford and his recordings -- He Didn't Stop At Calvary (Lester Flatt) -- Martha White commercial (Grant Turner) -- Back Up And Push (Benny Martin fiddle) (incomplete) -- Opening theme -- Opening statement (Grant Turner) -- Lester Flatt talks about special guest John Hartford -- Skipping In The Mississippi Dew (John Hartford) -- Lester Flatt talks about Benny Martin's playing -- Martha White commercial (Grant Turner) -- Milwaukee Here I Come (Benny Martin) -- Lester Flatt talks -- Turn Your Radio On (Lester Flatt) -- Trailblazer dog food commercial (Grant Turner and Grandpa Jones) -- I Don't Care Anymore (Kenny Ingram and Marty Stuart) [unconfirmed] -- Billy In The Lowground (Marty Stuart mandolin) -- Lester Flatt talks about Stuart's playing -- Closing theme -- Closing statement (Grant Turner]</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-0001_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-0001</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2017-07-13</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); Flatt, Lester, 1914-1979; Nashville Grass (Musical group); Turner, Grant; Ingram, Kenny; Martin, Benny; Hartford, John; Jones, Grandpa, 1913-1998; Stuart, Marty;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/5340</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>