<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>McCarters Interview - Biff Collie</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of an interview with the McCarters (performance group) conducted by Biff Collie.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1989-12-18</dc:date>
<dc:creator>McCarters; Biff Collie</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Jennifer, Lisa, and Teresa McCarter iterate how Better Be Home Soon has a different feeling from The Gift -- (00:34) Biff Collie and the McCarters discuss how they used their own band member to record a guitar track for "Up and Gone" -- (01:11) "I Haven't Got a Prayer" is discussed by the McCarters as a song they brought to Warner Brothers as the only song on the album with a orchestra in the back ground -- (02:07) The McCarters tell of how the group got their first opportunity to sing for Capitol Records and Warner Brothers though Randy Travis' producer -- (02:47) Jennifer reveals that the group had originally clog danced before they began their singing career when Jennifer was fourteen -- (03:30) Lisa discusses the structure of a show and how it is detrimental to an entertainers growth -- (04:05) The McCarters discuss Teresa's mole and how people believe Jennifer is Lisa and Teresa's mother -- (05:01) Collie and the McCarters discuss how Lisa and Teresa are twins and that Lisa is the 'runt' -- (05:20) Collie and the McCarters discuss how "Shot Full of Love" is an expression and Jennifer reflects on how they had not originally released the song on the first album -- (06:05) Collie and the McCarters discuss how the McCarters have tracks that they have not released because of their belief in timing and changing attitudes -- (07:08) Collie and the McCarters discuss how they were able to perform on Dolly Parton's show, and the McCarters reflect on their love of an unidentified tune (08:15) "Where Have You Been" is reflected upon as a wonderful song -- (08:51) "Quit While I'm Behind" is discussed as a track by Bill Casual; additionally, Casual's character is discussed by the McCarters -- (09:48) Collie inquires about writers and the McCarters vocalize how they are approached by writers -- (10:26) "If Tomorrow Never Comes" by Garth Brooks is described by the McCarters as a beautiful song that has significant pull on the McCarters -- (11:30) Collie tells a tale about Brooks desire to release "If Tomorrow Never Comes" above any other track he had done -- (11:54) The McCarters and Collie discuss Kim Patton making "Mountain Memories" specifically for the McCarters -- (13:31) Lisa reflects on her love for "Beneth Still Waters" and its writer Emmylou Harris -- (14:15) Collie and the McCarters reflect on Dolly Parton and Harris being role models while reflecting on Parton being on the Porter Wagoner Show -- (15:30) The McCarters recall traveling to California to perform on Parton's show -- (16:01) The McCarters recall working at Dollywood -- (16:19) "Better Be Home Soon" is the favorite track by each member of the McCarters and Teresa recalls hearing the song for the first time while eating lunch -- (18:57) Collie and the McCarters discuss how to pronounce "Papa Sita" and the McCarters reveal the inspiration for the song named "Mama Sita" -- (19:30) The McCarters reveal the Mexican influence on "Papa Sita" while discussing the up-tempo styling of the album -- (20:42) "Stay Within the Sound of My Voice" is described by Jennifer as a song that has a lot of meaning to her that she wants to translate a message -- (21:35) Jennifer introduces Cambell's "Stay Within the Sound of My Voice" -- (21:40) Collie and the McCarters discuss the seven siblings they all share and their father's musical contributions -- (23:00) The McCarters review their family's musical background -- (23:33) Collie tells of how Roni Stoneman would create jello in a washer and Collie and the McCarters discuss large family living -- (24:59) The process behind the demo recording of "Betcha Gonna Love Me" is described by Jennifer -- (25:56) Collie jokes about getting a reaction and has the McCarters introduce John Denver's "Back Home Again" -- (26:40) "Slow Country Dance" is reflected on by Jennifer as a waltz that they waited awhile to release -- (27:27) "Mama Knows" by Shenandoah is reflected on by Lisa as her mother's fear of losing her children -- (28:39) "I Don't Want to Cry Anymore" is joked about by Collie and the McCarters describe the feeling of hearing it live at the Blue Bird -- (29:49) The McCarters discuss their performance on the Music City Album Review away from the mic -- (29:57) The McCarters joke about becoming disc jockeys -- (30:01) Lisa McCarter radio spot for the Music City Album Review -- (30:08) Teresa McCarter radio spot for the Music City Album Review -- (30:17) Jennifer McCarter radio spot for the Music City Album Review</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1181_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1181</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-01-23</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>McCarter, Jennifer; the McCarters (Musical group)</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8416</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>