<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Various Song Excerpts - Old museum music row location - Artist Gallery exhibition</dc:title>
<dc:description> Various recording excerpts of performances featuring Roy Acuff (performer)' Bill Anderson (performer), Eddy Arnold (performer), Gene Autry (performer), Johnny Bond (performer), Elton Britt (performer), Jimmie Rodgers (performer), The Carter Family (performer), Johnny Cash (performer), Patsy Cline (performer), Cowboy Copas (performer), Vernon Dalhart (performer), Skeeter Davis (performer), Jimmy Dean (performer), Bing Crosby (performer), Ernest Tubb (performer), Jim Reeves (performer), Tennessee Ernie Ford (performer), Lefty Frizzell (performer), Roy Orbison (performer), Homer and Jethro (performance group), Johnny Horton (performer), Ferlin Husky (performer), Sonny James (performer), Bill Monroe (performer), George Jones (performer), Hank Thompson (performer), Pee Wee King (performer), Hank Locklin (performer), Roger Miller (performer), Vince Gill (performer), Wilf Carter (performer), Buck Owens (performer), Webb Pierce (performer), Ray Price (performer), Jim Reeves (performer), Tex Ritter (performer), Guy Mitchell (performer), Walter Brennan (performer), Jimmie Rodgers (performer), Porter Wagoner (performer), Carl Smith (performer), Roy Rogers (performer), Bill Monroe (performer), Jim Reeves (performer), Kitty Wells (performer), Slim Whitman (performer), The Wilburn Brothers (performance group), Hank Williams Sr. (performer), Merle Haggard (performer), Faron Young (performer) and other unidentified performers.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1976-07-05</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Roy Acuff; Bill Anderson; Eddy Arnold; Gene Autry; Johnny Bond; Elton Britt; Jimmie Rodgers; The Carter Family; Johnny Cash; Patsy Cline; Cowboy Copas; Vernon Dalhart; Skeeter Davis; Jimmy Dean; Bing Crosby; Ernest Tubb; Jim Reeves; Tennessee Ernie Ford; Lefty Frizzell; Roy Orbison; Homer and Jethro; Johnny Horton; Ferlin Husky; Sonny James; Bill Monroe; George Jones; Hank Thompson; Pee Wee King; Hank Locklin; Roger Miller; Vince Gill; Wilf Carter; Buck Owens; Webb Pierce; Ray Price; Jim Reeves; Tex Ritter; Guy Mitchell; Walter Brennan; Porter Wagoner; Carl Smith; Roy Rogers; Bill Monroe; Kitty Wells; Slim Whitman; The Wilburn Brothers; Hank Williams Sr.; Merle Haggard; Faron Young</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Wabash Cannonball [excerpt] (Roy Acuff) -- (00:37) Still [excerpt] (Bill Anderson) -- (00:58) Bouquet of Roses (Eddy Arnold) -- (01:41) (Unidentified) [excerpt] ([Unidentified]) -- (02:06) (Unidentified) [excerpt] ([Unidentified]) -- (02:34) That Silver Haired Daddy of Mine [excerpt] (Gene Autry) -- (03:08) 10 Little Bottles [excerpt] (Johnny Bond) -- (03:38) There's a Star Spangled Banner Waving Somewhere [excerpt] (Elton Britt) -- (04:03) My Blue Eyed Jane [excerpt] (Jimmie Rodgers) -- (04:36) Keep on the Sunny Side [excerpt] (The Carter Family) -- (05:01) I Walk the Line [excerpt] (Johnny Cash) -- (05:39) I Fall to Pieces [excerpt] (Patsy Cline) -- (06:18) I'm Goin' Back to Alabam [excerpt] (Cowboy Copas) -- (06:41) Wreck of the Old 97 [excerpt] (Vernon Dalhart) -- (07:08) You Are My Sunshine [excerpt] ([Unidentified]) -- (07:34) I Forgot More Than You'll Ever Know (Skeeter Davis) -- (08:01) Big Bad John [excerpt] (Jimmy Dean) -- (08:33) Pistol Packin' Mama [excerpt] (Bing Crosby) -- (09:00) May the Bird of Paradise Fly Up Your Nose [excerpt] (Ernest Tubb) -- (09:22) (Unidentified Banjo Tune] [excerpt] ([Unidentified]) -- (09:43) Peace in the Valley [excerpt] (Jim Reeves) -- (10:24) 16 Tons [excerpt] (Tennessee Ernie Ford) -- (10:53) If You Got the Money I've Got the Time [excerpt] (Lefty Frizzell) -- (11:19) Oh Lonesome Me (Roy Orbison) -- (11:51) How Much is That Hound Dog in the Window [excerpt] (Homer and Jethro) -- (12:17) Battle of New Orleans, In 1814 [excerpt] (Johnny Horton) -- (12:49) Gone [excerpt] (Ferlin Husky) -- (13:25) Young Love [excerpt] (Sonny James) -- (13:55) Poison Love [excerpt] (Bill Monroe) -- (14:31) White Lightning [excerpt] (George Jones) -- (15:07) (Unidentified) [excerpt] ([Unidentified]) -- (15:34) Letter Edged in Black [excerpt] (Hank Thompson) -- (16:21) Tennessee Waltz [excerpt] (Pee Wee King) -- (17:00) Please Help Me I'm Falling (In Love With You) [excerpt] (Hank Locklin) -- (17:43) (Unidentified) [excerpt] ([Unidentified]) -- (18:18) King of the Road [excerpt] (Roger Miller) -- (19:01) Blue Moon of Kentucky [excerpt] (Vince Gill) -- (19:41) My Swiss Moonlight Lullaby [excerpt] (Wilf Carter) -- (20:08) Act Naturally (Buck Owens) -- (20:36) An unidentified woman jokes about a dress she bought -- (21:11) Back Street Affair [excerpt] (Webb Pierce) -- (21:53) Crazy Arms [excerpt] (Ray Price) -- (22:29) Put Your Sweet Lips a Little Closer (He'll Have to Go) [excerpt] (Jim Reeves) -- (23:14) Do Not Forsake Me, My Darling [excerpt] (Tex Ritter) -- (23:47) Singing the Blues [excerpt] (Guy Mitchell) -- (24:08) Life Gets Tee-Jus, Don't it [excerpt] (Walter Brennan) -- (24:39) T"" For Texas [excerpt] (Jimmie Rodgers) -- (25:11) Satisfied Mind [excerpt] (Porter Wagoner) -- (25:51) Hey Joe! [excerpt] (Carl Smith) -- (26:17) I'm Movin' On [excerpt] (Ernest Tubb) -- (26:53) Cool Water [excerpt] (Roy Rogers) -- (27:25) Nine Pound Hammer [excerpt] (Bill Monroe) -- (28:01) I'm Walking the Floor Over You [excerpt] (Ernest Tubb) -- (28:43) Just Walk on By [excerpt] (Jim Reeves) -- (29:24) It Wasn't God Who Made Honky Tonk Angels [excerpt] (Kitty Wells) -- (29:55) Indian Love Call [excerpt] (Slim Whitman) -- (30:30) Troubles Back in Town [excerpt] (The Wilburn Brothers) -- (31:10) Your Cheatin' Heart [excerpt] (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (31:50) San Antonio Rose [excerpt] (Merle Haggard) -- (32:41) Hello Walls [excerpt] (Faron Young)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1420_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1420</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-03-29</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Acuff, Roy; Anderson, Bill, 1937-; Anderson, Bill; Arnold, Eddy, 1918-2008; Autry, Gene, 1907-1998; Bond, Johnny; Bond, Johnny, 1915-1978; Britt, Elton, 1917-1972; Rodgers, Jimmie, 1897-1933; Rodgers, Jimmie, 1933-; The Carter Family; Cash, Johnny; Cline, Patsy, 1932-1963; Copas, Cowboy; Dalhart, Vernon; Davis, Skeeter; Dean, Jimmy; Dean, Jimmy, 1928-2010; Crosby, Bing, 1903-1977; Tubb, Ernest; Tubb, Ernest, 1914-1984; Reeves, Jim; Ford, Ernie; Frizzell, Lefty, 1928-1975; Orbison, Roy; Homer and Jethro; Horton, Johnny; Husky, Ferlin; James, Sonny; Monroe, Bill, 1911-1996; Jones, George; Jones, George, 1931-2013; Thompson, Hank; King, Pee Wee, 1914-2000; Locklin, Hank; Locklin, Hank, 1918-2009; Miller, Roger, 1936-1992; Gill, Vince; Carter, Wilf, 1904-1996; Owens, Buck, 1929-2006; Pierce, Webb; Pierce, Webb, 1921-1991; Price, Ray, 1926-2013; Reeves, Jim; Ritter, Tex; Ritter, Tex, 1905-1974; Mitchell, Guy; Brennan, Walter, 1894-1974; Wagoner, Porter; Smith, Carl, 1927-2010; Rogers, Roy, 1911-1998; Monroe, Bill, 1911-1996; Wells, Kitty; Whitman, Slim; Whitman, Slim, 1924-2013; The Wilburn Brothers; Williams, Hank, 1923-1953; Williams, Hank, 1923-1953. I saw the light; Haggard, Merle; Haggard, Merle, 1937-2016; Young, Faron;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8725</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>