<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Nashville Record Review Artist Interviews # 1</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recordings of phone interviews with various artists hosted by Al Rosen and Skip Woolwine. Recording features: Louise Mandrell, John Conlee, Jim Ed Brown, Ronnie McDowell, George Strait, Bill Anderson, David Wills, Sylvia, Randy Owen, and Ricky Skaggs. Item is listed as part 1 of the Nashville Radio Review artist interviews.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Al Risen</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Conversation between Louise Mandrell and Skip Woolwine discussing the structure of the show -- (00:19) Woolwine introduces Mandrell who speaks about her new record and book -- (01:06) Mandrell and Woolwine discuss the importance of drums while discussing "Too Hot to Sleep" -- (02:46) Woolwine has Mandrell address her upcoming schedule -- (03:21) Woolwine radio spot introducing "Too Hot to Sleep" -- (03:28) Mandrell says 'Thank You' -- (03:32) Woolwine performs vocal test -- (03:42) Woolwine introduces John Conlee, and both discuss "I'm Only in it For the Love" -- (04:42) Woolwine introduces "Rose Colored Glasses," and Brown reflects on when he wrote the track while watching television -- (06:02) Woolwine radio spot introducing "Rose Colored Glasses" -- (06:08) Woolwine and Brown joke away from the microphone -- (06:12) Tape skip introduces Woolwine radio spot for "Rose Colored Glasses" -- (06:21) Woolwine and Brown discuss away from microphone -- (06:30) Al Risen introduces Jim Ed Brown, and Brown discusses his current business ventures [including: You Could Be a Star] -- (08:17) Risen and Brown discuss Brown's absence from the recording industry -- (08:48) Risen introduces "Pop A Top," and Brown tells that he was not the one to originally record it -- (09:37) Risen radio spot introduction of "Pop A Top" -- (09:44) Risen talks about the number of times he has recorded with Ronnie McDowell -- (09:51) Risen introduces McDowell, and both discuss McDowell's strawberry crop -- (10:35) McDowell reveals his work with Conway Twitty and addresses his upcoming work -- (11:26) McDowell recalls the first time he heard "You're Gonna Ruin My Bad Reputation," and McDowell and Risen discuss the changes made to "You're Gonna Ruin My Bad Reputation" from the album cut -- (12:47) Risen radio spot introduction "You're Gonna Ruin My Bad Reputation" -- (12:53) Risen asks George Strait if he is ready to begin -- (12:58) Risen introduces Strait, and Strait discusses his upcoming aspirations -- (13:37) Risen and Strait discuss 'turkey open' -- (13:51) Strait discusses how he met "A Fire I Can't Put Out" writer Darrell Statler -- (15:11) Risen radio spot introducing "A Fire I Can't Put Out" -- (15:16) Risen thanks Strait [incomplete] -- (15:22) Risen asks Bill Anderson where he is currently -- (15:29) Risen introduces Anderson, and both talk about Anderson hosting Fandango -- (16:34) Anderson reflects on the direction his career has taken -- (17:22) Anderson "Son of the South" is revealed to be Anderson's brain child -- (18:11) Risen radio spot introduction of "Son of the South" -- (18:15) Risen introduces David Wills, and both discuss Wills' memorable songs -- (18:52) Wills reflects on the effect Charlie Rich has had on his life, as well as, Charlie Pride -- (19:41) Risen inquires about Wills' relationship with Blake Nevis and Will's upcoming career moves -- (20:54) Risen and Wills discuss Ronnie Rogers and "Those Nights , These Days" -- (21:33) Risen radio spot introduction of "Those Nights, These Days" -- (21:38) Risen introduces Sylvia, and Sylvia discusses how she can visualize "Like Nothing Ever Happened" -- (22:21) Sylvia's success with "Nobody" is praised -- (22:46) Sylvia discusses her upcoming changes to the Sylvia Show -- (24:01) Risen has Sylvia recall how she had two separate bands for a time -- (24:33) Sylvia's appearance on James Galway's record is discussed -- (25:24) Risen radio spot introducing "Like Nothing Ever Happened" -- (25:29) Risen introduces Randy Owen who discusses Alabama's upcoming live album -- (26:02) Owen and Risen discuss the June Jam charitable show -- (27:08) Risen and Owen address how listeners can get a ticket to the June Jam -- (28:29) Risen and Owen discuss how Roger wrote "Dixieland Delight" -- (29:35) Risen radio spot introducing "Dixieland Delight" -- (29:41) Risen introduces Ricky Skaggs, and both discuss how Skaggs wound up calling from a phone booth -- (30:35) Risen has Skaggs discuss the Whites' upcoming album -- (31:40) "Highway 40 Blues" is told by Skaggs to be part of an album Skaggs produced for Larry Cordle -- (33:04) Risen radio spot introducing "Highway 40 Blues"</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1257_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1257</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-02-21</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Risen, Al; Woolwine, Skip; Mandrell, Louise; Conlee, John; Brown, Jim Ed; Brown, Jim Ed, 1934-2015; McDowell, Ronnie; Strait, George, 1952-; Anderson, Bill; Anderson, Bill, 1937-; Wills, David; Sylvia, 1956-; Owen, Randy, 1949-; Skaggs, Ricky;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8537</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>