<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Discussion -  Outlaws on Film - 2018-05-25</dc:title>
<dc:description>Discussion about an upcoming documentary film on the Austin Texas music scene in the 1970's.  Filmmakers Eric Geadlemann and Kelly Magelky are joined by Texas singer-songwriter Jack Ingram.  Presented in support of the exhibit Outlaws &amp; Armadillos: Country&#8217;s Roaring &#8217;70s.  Includes audio from selected video excerpts and live performance from Jack Ingram.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2018-05-25</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Eric Geadlemann; Kelly Magelky; Jack Ingram; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Walk-in Music / (07:03) Opening comments by Michael Gray / (09:25) Audio from film excerpt / (15:47) Michael introduces the panel participants including Eric Geadlemann family in attendance / (19:11) Opening comments / (19:42) Eric talks about the inspiration for his film project / (21:23) Kelly talks about his connection to the music in this story / (22:40) Eric talks about his musical influences / (23:24) Jack tells story about meeting Eric / (26:06) Eric talks about his experience in researching for a project like this / (28:07) Kelly talks about his background in film and attending film school / (29:57) Eric talks about the film, the six segments of the film and what the first segment is roughly about / (33:22) Audio from film excerpt / (35:18) Eric talks about the effect of Kristofferson and Johnny Cash's recording of Sunday Morning, Coming Down / (35:45) Audio from film excerpt / (37:04) Eric talks about what the second segment is roughly about / (38:12) Audio from film excerpt / (40:41) Eric talks about what the third segment is roughly about / (43:33) Kelly talks about the first meeting Mike Tolleson / (44:32) Eric continues talking about the third segment / (44:26) Audio from film excerpt / (48:07) Eric and Kelly talks about what the fourth segment of the film is roughly about / (51:53) Audio from film excerpt / (52:19) Eric talks about what the fifth segment is roughly about / (54:21) Audio from film excerpt / (56:03) Eric talks about what the sixth segment is roughly about / (56:38) Audio from film excerpt / (57:51) Eric talks about Kris Kristofferson and why he's important to the story / (59:56) Kelly talks about a Kristofferson interview videotaping setting the tone for the rest of film / (01:00:59) Jack talks about interviewing Kristofferson and how Kris changed music / (01:04:38) Eric tells the story about Kris asking for Jack Ingram to do the interview and Jack's importance to the film / (01:06:50) Jack talks about what he learned from doing these interviews with the subjects of the film / (01:08:19) Jack tell story about going to Guy Clark's workshop and working on songs and being told to make a choice to either be an artist or a star / (01:11:05) Audio from film excerpt / (01:13:06) Kelly talks about the interview style they use / (01:14:44) Audio from film excerpt / (01:15:44) Kelly talks about Jeff Hanna and the song Mr. Bojangles / (01:16:10) Eric talks about the importance of having Jesse Colter's input on the film / (01:17:15) Audio from film excerpt / (01:17:44) Eric and Kelly tells story about losing money playing poker with Willie Nelson / (01:19:22) Kelly and Eric tell story about filming Willie doing a speed bag workout / (01:21:50) Eric talks about commerce versus artistic vision and funding for the film and challenges they faced being similar to what songwriters go through / (01:28:06) Eric talks about the final clip to be shown / (01:29:39) Jack Ingram introduces song / (01:30:00) Performs Sunday Morning, Coming Down (Jack Ingram) / (01:35:11) Eric talks about the timeline for release of the film / (01:36:02) Michael with closing comments / (01:36:25) Eric compliments Michael Gray and his work on the exhibit / (01:37:15) Final comments / (01:37:22) Walk-out Music / (01:40:26) FILE END                                             </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded as an mp3 file at 44.1</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0120</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2019-02-13</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Geadlemann, Eric; Magelky, Kelly; Ingram, Jack; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8568</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>