<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Judy Baker Interviews at Corpus Christi</dc:title>
<dc:description>This recording is for Hank Snow from Judy Baker and features interviews with Billy Walker, Lefty Frizzell, and Frances Whitfield. The recording is from an unidentified date. This tape is a two sided tape and this is tape 1 of 2. Tape is the twelfth of an unidentified number of tapes.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Hank Snow; Judy Baker; Billy Walker; Lefty Frizzell; Frances Whitfield;  </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Judy Baker's personal message to Hank Snow (who the tape was intended for) -- (03:01) Set up noises for Billy Walker interview -- (03:39) Back Street Affair (Billy Walker) -- (06:12) Baker and Walker discuss where Walker is traveling from and to -- (06:50) The two talk about Walker's friend  -- (08:03) Baker talks about her favorite song of Walker's, "You Have My Heart Now" -- (08:12) Walker talks about his cold -- (08:25) Baker asks what is Walker's favorite song -- (08:32) What Makes Me Love You Like I Do (Billy Walker) -- (10:20) Baker asks about Walker's newest song -- (10:46) I'm Looking For Love (Billy Walker) -- (12:02) Song is interrupted by a separate recording -- (12:19) Back to the original recording with Baker and Walker discussing Walker's newest songs -- (13:19) Anything Your Heart Desires (Billy Walker) -- (14:58) Baker asks Walker who's style he likes the best -- (16:10) Baker talking to Snow again about the text tape she is recording with Lefty Frizzell and Frances Whitfield -- (16:52) Beginning of interview where everyone is trying to figure out where to sit -- (17:44) The three start talking about spaghetti and meatballs -- (18:34) Baker mentions a man named Leo -- (19:17) They start talking about the show the previous night -- (20:37) Baker asks Frizzell to name everyone in his band and their instruments -- (21:01) Al Florist talks about the band that is touring with Frizzell -- (22:37) Baker asks Frizzell where he's been and where he is going -- (24:02) Frizzell says thank you to Baker -- (24:31) Baker tries to tune Frizzell's guitar -- (24:55) California Blues (Lefty Frizzell) -- (27:10) Baker asks for another song -- (28:01) Frizzell strums on the guitar while having an undistinguishable conversation with Baker -- (28:19) I Love You A Thousand Ways (Lefty Frizzell) -- (30:27) Pistol Packing Papa (Lefty Frizzell) -- (31:46) Song cuts out</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1/2 track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-7-02542_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-7-02542</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-08-29</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Snow, Hank; Walker, Billy, 1929-2006; Walker, Billie (Vocalist); Frizzell, Lefty; Frizzell, Lefty, 1928-1975; </dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9462</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>