<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Grand Ole Opry - Prince Albert - 1939-11-04 - Part 2</dc:title>
<dc:description>Part 2 of Prince Albert tobacco sponsored Grand Ole Opry segment from November 4, 1939. Featuring David Stone (announcer), George D. Hay (host), and performers Roy Acuff and his Smoky Mountain Boys, Uncle Dave Macon and son Dorris Macon, Pee Wee King and his Golden West Cowboys with vocalists Little Texas Daisy and Lost John, and Ford Rush. Held at War Memorial Auditorium, Nashville, TN.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1939-11-04</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Roy Acuff; Smoky Mountain Boys; Uncle Dave Macon; Dorris Macon; Pee Wee King; Golden West Cowboys; Ford Rush; Lost John</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>My Old Pal Of Yesterday (Roy Acuff and his Smoky Mountain Boys) [continued from part 1] -- George D. Hay talks -- Prince Albert commercial (David Stone) -- George D. Hay introduces Uncle Dave Macon and Dorris Macon -- I Intend To Make Heaven My Home (Uncle Dave Macon, Dorris Macon) -- George D. Hay introduces the Golden West Cowboys trio -- Just One More Kiss (Golden West Cowboys trio) -- George D. Hay introduces Ford Rush -- When You And I Were Young, Maggie (Ford Rush) -- George D. Hay introduces Lost John and the Golden West Cowboys -- When It's Peach Picking Time In Georgia (Lost John, Golden West Cowboys) -- Prince Albert commercial (David Stone) -- Closing theme -- Closing statement (George D. Hay) -- Closing statement (David Stone)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>16 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR000008</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2005-04-21</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); National Broadcasting Company; Grand ole opry (Radio program); Hay, George D. (George Dewey), 1895-1968; Stone, David P., 1901-1995; Acuff, Roy; Smoky Mountain Boys; Rush, Ford, 1895-; Wilkerson, George W., 1895-1954; Fruit Jar Drinkers (Musical group); Macon, Uncle Dave, 1870-1952; King, Pee Wee, 1914-2000; Golden West Cowboys (Musical group); Little Texas Daisy; Lost John Miller</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/924</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>