<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Brown County Jamboree - Bill Monroe and his Bluegrass Boys - 1966-10-31</dc:title>
<dc:description>Various performances from the Brown County Jamboree Bluegrass Festival, located in Bean Blossom, Indiana, featuring Bill Monroe (performer) and his Bluegrass Boys, Pete Rowan, Richard Greene, Jim Monroe, and Lamar Grier. Recorded on October 31, 1966.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1966-10-31</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Bill Monroe; Bluegrass Boys</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) [Unidentified] talks about upcoming performances in Beanblossom, and introduces Bill Monroe -- (01:51) When The Watermelons Are Smiling On The Vine (Bill Monroe and his Bluegrass Boys) -- (02:24) Monroe talks about playing in Beanblossom in the past, and introduces the band -- (03:43) Panhandle Country (Bill Monroe and his Bluegrass Boys) -- (06:05) Sunny Side Of the Mountain (Bill Monroe and his Bluegrass Boys) -- (09:05) Monroe introduces the next tune - (09:14) Walls Of Time (Bill Monroe and his Bluegrass Boys) -- (13:10) Monroe introduces the next tune -- (13:29) Bluegrass Breakdown (Bill Monroe and his Bluegrass Boys) -- (16:38) Monroe introduces the next tune -- (16:48) Molly And Tenbrooks (Bill Monroe and his Bluegrass Boys) -- (19:09) Monroe introduces the next tune -- (19:15) You'll Find Her Name Written There (Bill Monroe and his Bluegrass Boys) -- (22:42) Monroe takes requests from the audience -- (22:51) Breakin' In A Brand New Pair Of Shoes (Bill Monroe and his Bluegrass Boys) -- (25:50) Monroe introduces the next tune -- (26:00) Blue Moon Of Kentucky (Bill Monroe and his Bluegrass Boys) -- (28:05) Monroe thanks the audience and introduces the next tune -- (26:26) Roanoke (Bill Monroe and his Bluegrass Boys) -- (30:53) Toy Heart (Bill Monroe and his Bluegrass Boys) -- (33:33) Bluegrass Special (Bill Monroe and his Bluegrass Boys) -- (37:05) Monroe introduces the next tune -- California Blues (Bill Monroe and his Bluegrass Boys) -- (39:32) Monroe introduces the next tune -- (40:49) Uncle Pen (Bill Monroe and his Bluegrass Boys) -- (43:37) A Beautiful Life (Bill Monroe and his Bluegrass Boys)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-7-01055_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-7-01055</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-02-06</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Monroe, Bill, 1911-1996; Bill Monroe and the Bluegrass Boys (Musical group); Brown County Jamboree; Bean Blossom (Brown County, Ind.); </dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8464</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>