<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Poets and Prophets program - Jerry Chesnut - 2009-09-26</dc:title>
<dc:description>Poets and Prophets interview program and performance with singer/songwriter Jerry Chesnut from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on September 26, 2009.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2009-09-26</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Jerry Chesnut;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Program begins in progress.  Hosted by Michael Gray.  Includes performances.  Includes selected audio excerpts and audio from video.  Subjects include; Inspiration for the song They Don't Make  'em Like My Daddy -- Childhood days in Harlan County, Kentucky -- Musical inspirations and listening to the radio -- Joining the Air Force -- Playing music in the Air Force -- Beginnings of his songwriting career -- Discharge from the Air Force and moving to Florida -- Inspiration for writing the song Oney -- Moving to Nashville --  First time hearing a song of his being sung by Arthur Alexander in a recording session -- Being laid up for 6 months in bed and spending his time listening to country songs to help improve his craft -- Writing the song A Dime At A Time -- Writing the song Another Place, Another Time and how it got to Jerry Lee Lewis -- Writing the song Holding On To Nothing -- Writing the song A Good Year For The Roses and how it got to George Jones --  </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Writing the song The Wonders You Perform and how it got to Tammy Wynette -- Talks about Elvis Costello's recording of A Good Year For The Roses -- Writing the song It's Four In The Morning and playing it for Faron Young --  Talks about the craft of songwriting -- Hiring Lamar Fike and meeting Elvis Presley --  Writing the song Trouble -- Little David Wilkins -- Performances includes; It's Four In The Morning -- A Good Day For The Roses -- Closing comments.</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>CD-R;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>PP0337</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2017-08-17</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Chesnut, Jerry; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.); </dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/5537</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>