<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Nashville Record Review Artist Interviews 1982 - E</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recordings of phone interviews with various artists hosted by Al Risen. Recording features: T. G. Sheppard, Leon Everette, Ronnie Milsap, Richard Sterban, and Ricky Skaggs. Item is listed as part E of the 1982 Nashville Radio Review artist interviews.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1982</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Al Risen</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Al Risen introduces T. G. Sheppard who discusses his excitement with the success of his records -- (00:51) Risen and Sheppard discuss "War is Hell" and compared it to the Summer of 1942 -- (01:53) Sheppard discusses his upcoming touring -- (02:53)  Risen radio spot introduction for "War is Hell" -- (02:59) Al Risen introduces Leon Everette, and both discuss the creation of Orlando Records -- (04:04) "Giving Up Easy" is revealed to be Everette's first record with RCA -- (05:15) Everette discusses his successful records -- (05:46) Everette reveals he is about to go on tour with Hank Williams Jr. -- (06:14) Everette discusses the inspiration for "Shadows of My Mind" -- (06:54) Risen radio spot introduction for "Shadows of My Mind" -- (06:59) Al Risen introduces Ronnie Milsap; additionally Milsap demonstrates his 'talking watch' -- (08:27) Risen and Milsap discuss the Glen Campbell Music Show -- (10:15) The horn structure of "He Got You" is discussed by Milsap -- (11:27) Risen radio spot introduction for "He Got You" -- (11:32) Risen introduces Richard Sterban of the Oak Ridge Boys, and Sterban discusses the Oak Ridge Boys' first Christmas album -- (12:47) Eddie Raven is reflected on by Risen and Sterban -- (14:09) Sterban discusses how William Lee sings lead on the new album -- (15:09) Risen radio spot introduction of "Thank God for Kids" -- (15:17) Risen introduces Ricky Skaggs, and "You Put the Blue in Me" is discussed -- (16:06) Risen has Skaggs discuss how he is producing the Whites -- (18:01) Risen and Skaggs discuss how he discovered "I Wouldn't Change You" -- (18:34) Risen radio spot introduction of "I Wouldn't Change You" -- (18:42) Risen introduces Chuck Glaser, and both discuss how the Glaser Brothers discovered their distinctive style -- (21:17) Risen has Glaser discuss the time where the brothers where broken up -- (22:19) Glaser reflects on the first time he heard "Maria Consuela" -- (24:19) Risen radio spot introduction of "Maria Consuela"</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1249_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1249</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-02-21</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Shepherd, T. G.; Sheppard, T. G.; Everette, Leon; Milsap, Ronnie; Milsap, Ronnie, 1943-; Sterban, Richard, 1943-; Skaggs, Ricky; Glaser, Chuck;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8526</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>