<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Sweethearts of the Rodeo Interview - Biff Collie</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of an interview with Sweethearts of the Rodeo (performance group) conducted by Biff Collie. </dc:description>
<dc:date>1989-12-14</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Sweethearts of the Rodeo; Biff Collie</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Janis Oliver discusses her and Kristine Arnold's first experiences singing together in Manhattan Beach, California -- (00:44) Oliver recalls her first memory; Arnold says her first memory was of a party for United Nations Day -- (01:59) Biff Collie inquires and Arnold states that Pearl Hinforth (unconfirmed) was her and Oliver's biggest influence; Oliver reflects on Hinforth's artistic influences -- (03:55) Arnold reveals that, while in church, "Trust and Obey" was the first song she and Oliver ever performed -- (05:14) Collie and the Sweethearts of the Rodeo discuss the girls' love of performing from a young age -- (05:57) Oliver discusses the various attempts the girls had, at a young age, to shape their performing careers; Arnold discusses her and Oliver's age difference affecting their relationship -- (08:59) Collie has Oliver and Arnold recall their reactions to each other bringing home dates -- (09:57) Collie and the Sweethearts of the Rodeo reflect on how working at the Pizza Palace led to Emmylou Harris and others coming to watch them perform -- (11:16) Arnold reveals her and Oliver's first studio experience came from being background vocalists in high school; Oliver reveals some of her and Arnold's first experiences came from working with Cliffie Stone -- (13:34) Collie and the Sweethearts of the Rodeo discuss how winning the Wrangler Country Showdown gained them popularity -- (14:56) Oliver discusses how she met her husband, Vince Gill -- (16:00) Arnold discusses the difficulty of starting a career in Nashville, and how if she and Oliver didn't have the connections they did it would have been a lot more difficult -- (18:00) Arnold suggests aspiring artists should do talent shows -- (18:41) Collie and the Sweethearts of the Rodeo discuss how they had signed with CBS while touring with Willie Nelson -- (19:31) Oliver and Arnold discuss their personal lives -- (20:48) Arnold and Oliver attribute their success to Hinforth and their ballet instructor -- (22:04) Collie has Arnold and Oliver recall the Wrangler Country Showdown -- (23:44) Oliver recalls the first song she ever wrote ("Gotta Get Away") was written for the Wrangler Country Showdown -- (24:22) Oliver and Arnold recall "Wolverton Mountain" by Claude King was the first record they ever owned -- (25:09) "Since I Found you" is revealed to be the first top-ten record the Sweethearts of the Rodeo created, and it is revealed that they have yet to reach number one -- (25:26) Arnold and Oliver believe that Hank Williams Sr. is the most influential country artist -- (26:10) Arnold and Oliver reflect on their favorite time to think and who they believe should be in the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1240_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1240</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-02-15</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Sweethearts of the Rodeo (Musical group); Collie, Biff;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8505</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>