<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Songwriter Session - Maggie Rose and Lucie Silvas - 2018-03-03</dc:title>
<dc:description>Performances by singer songwriters Maggie Rose and Lucie Silvas from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame on March 3, 2018.  Accompanied by Jon Green and Tom Maxwell.  Includes questions from the audience.  </dc:description>
<dc:date>2018-03-03</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Maggie Rose; Lucie Silvas; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Walk-in music / (05:14) Opening comments and introduction of performer by Abi Tapia / (09:02) Opening comment from Maggie and Lucie / (09:45) Maggie introduces her first song / (11:21) Performs Hey Blondie (Maggie Rose) / (14:02) Lucie talks about Maggie and tells story about performing with Gabe Dixon / (14:48) Lucie introduces Jon Green on guitar and introduces the next song / (15:52) Performs Black Jeans (Lucie Silva and Jon Green) / (20:14) Maggie talks about Lucie / (21:21) Maggie introduces the next song / (22:06) Performs Change The Whole Thing (Maggie with Tom Maxwell) / (26:39) Maggie and Lucie talk about Tom Maxwell / (28:17) Lucie and Maggie answer question about the craft of songwriting and having your own voice / (31:13) Lucie introduces the next song / Performs Letters To Ghosts (Lucie and Jon) / (34:50) Maggie introduces the next song / (38:55) Performs Just Getting By (Maggie and Tom) / (40:18) Lucie talks about co-writing /   </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(41:20) Lucie introduces the next song / (42:05) Performs Everything Looks Beautiful (Lucie with Jon, Tom and Maggie) / (47:22) Maggie introduces the next song / (48:47) Performs Pull You Through (Maggie and Tom) / (52:28) Lucie talks about Maggie's song and their Grand Ole Opry appearance / (54:02) Lucie introduces the next song / (54:28) Performs Change My Mind (Lucie and Jon) / (57:53) Final comments from Maggie and Lucie / (58:41) Walk-out music / (01:00:25) FILE END                        </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/24;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0104</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2019-01-10</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Rose, Maggie; Silvas, Lucie; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8439</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>