<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Ozarkana Corners - Part 2</dc:title>
<dc:description>Ozarkana Corners radio show (sometimes spelled 'Ozarkanna'), part 2. Likely broadcast by KWTO, Springfield, MO, circa late 1930s (by 1940 the show had been renamed The Little Crossroads Store). Featuring announcer Bill Ring, host Squint Thompson (played by George Earle Wilson), co-host Chuck Wagner (played by Al Stone), Slim Pickens Wilson, Penny Nichols, Flash &amp; Whistler, the Matthews Quartet, Chuck Bowers, the Tall Timber Boys, Lou Black, Zed Tennis, and 'Midnight' (character possibly played by George Earle Wilson).</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Tall Timber Boys; Squint Thompson; Chuck Wagner; Flash &amp; Whistler; Chuck Bowers; Zed Tennis</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Spanish Two Step (Tall Timber Boys) -- Comedy routine (Squint Thompson, Chuck Wagner, Slim Pickens Wilson) -- Squint Thompson introduces Flash &amp; Whistler -- With The Wind And The Rain In Your Hair (Flash &amp; Whistler) -- Comedy routine (Squint Thompson, Chuck Wagner) -- Squint Thompson introduces Chuck Bowers -- Four Or Five Time (Chuck Bowers) -- Squint Thompson introduces Lou Black -- Lou Black's 'Hillosophy' -- Comedy routine (Squint Thompson, Chuck Wagner, Slim Pickens Wilson, 'Midnight') -- Squint Thompson introduces Zed Tennis -- Soldier's Joy (Zed Tennis fiddle) -- Closing statement (Squint Thompson) -- Closing theme -- Closing statement (Bill Ring)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>16 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR000837_2</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>TR000837</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2007-06-12</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>KWTO (Radio station : Springfield, Mo.); Ozarkana corners (Radio program); Ring, Bill, 1913-1991; Wilson, George Earle, 1904-2001; Wilson, Slim; Nichols, Penny; Flash and Whistler (Musical group); Rutledge, Floyd, 1906-1970; Matthews Quartet (Musical group); Bowers, Chuck, 1921-; Tall Timber Boys (Musical group); Black, Lou, 1906; Tennis, Zed</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/2209</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>