<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Discussion - Bob Dylan: Blonde On Blonde recording sessions in Nashville - 2017-07-15</dc:title>
<dc:description>Panel discussion titled &#8220;Is It Rolling, Bob?&#8221;: Bob Dylan&#8217;s Nashville Recordings Revisited.  Moderated by Pete Finney.  Participants are author and Princeton University history professor Sean Wilentz, guitarist Wayne Moss, multi-instrumentalist Charlie McCoy and songwriter Robyn Hancock.  In support of the exhibition titled Dylan, Cash, and the Nashville Cats: A New Music City. </dc:description>
<dc:date>2017-07-15</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Pete Finney; Sean Wilentz; Wayne Moss; Charlie McCoy; Robyn Hancock; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Opening comments by Michael Gray begin in progress / (00:55) Introduction of Sean Wilentz / (03:40) Sean's opening comments / (04:09) Sean talks about the year 1966, Bob Dylan's influences and why he went to Nashville / (07:03) Dylan trying to follow up the success of the recording of Like A Rolling Stone and his unhappiness with recording in New York with The Hawks / (08:44) Producer Bob Johnston brings Dylan to Nashville and the influence of Charlie McCoy on that decision / (09:24) Manager Albert Grossman's hesitation to let Dylan come to Nashville / (09:48) Bringing Al Kooper to Nashville and his background / (10:53) Dylan's first recordings in Nashville / (11:20) Stories about Dylan finishing song lyrics while the musicians wait and other recording stories / (14:27) Other artists coming to Nashville because of Dylan's success / (15:07) Makes supposition about the arch of the Nashville recordings in Dylan's mind by talking about the song Leopard Skin Pillbox Hat /</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(16:26) Plays recording of Lightning Hopkins' Automobile Blues / (17:33) Plays recording of the first takes of Leopard Skin Pillbox Hat by Dylan / (18:59) Sean comments on the comparisons of the two songs / (19:24) Plays the Nashville third take of Leopard Skin Pillbox Hat / (20:55) Sean talks about this Nashville take leading into takes four and five and plays recording of takes four and five of the Nashville version of Leopard Skin Pillbox Hat / (22:51) Talks about coming back to the song Leopard Skin Pillbox Hat on the last day of recording / (23:11) Plays recording of the final take of Leopard Skin Pillbox Hat / (26:25) Other participants join Sean on stage introduced by Michael Gray / (28:06) Introduction of moderator Pete Finney / (29:23) Opening comments from Pete / (30:25) Pete talks about the importance of Dylan's Blonde On Blonde album to the Nashville recording scene to both Dylan and Nashville / </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/24;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0052</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2018-07-27</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Wilentz, Sean; Finney, Pete; McCoy, Charlie, 1941-; Moss, Wayne; Hancock, Robyn; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/7964</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>