<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Brand on My Heart by Willie Nelson and Hank Snow</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of the album Brand on My Heart, performed by Willie Nelson (musician) and Hank Snow (musician). The recordings are from an unidentified date. The album is produced by Chips Moman and engineered by David Cherry.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Willie Nelson; Hank Snow</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) The Caribbean (Willie Nelson and Hank Snow) -- (03:32) Trouble in Mind (Willie Nelson and Hank Snow) -- (07:00) Brand on My Heart (Willie Nelson and Hank Snow) -- (10:15) A Fool Such As I (Willie Nelson and Hank Snow) -- (13:25) Send Me the Pillow That You Dream on (Willie Nelson and Hank Snow) -- (16:48) I Don't Hurt Anymore (Willie Nelson and Hank Snow) -- (19:57) The Golden Rocket (Willie Nelson and Hank Snow) -- (23:03) I've Been Everywhere (Willie Nelson and Hank Snow) -- (25:58) When I Lost My Baby (Willie Nelson and Hank Snow) -- (29:44) I'm Movin' on (Willie Nelson and Hank Snow) -- (32:56) It Makes No Difference Now (Willie Nelson and Hank Snow)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half track</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1066_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1066</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-07-31</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Nelson, Willie, 1933-; Snow, Hank;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9299</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>