<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Grand Ole Opry - Martha White - 195y-mm-dd - Part 1</dc:title>
<dc:description>Part 1 of Martha White sponsored Grand Ole Opry segment, date unknown, circa early 1950s. Featuring Jud Collins (announcer), Ernest Tubb (host/performer), and performers Johnnie &amp; Jack, the Crook Brothers, Hank Snow, Martha Carson, and the Blue Grass Boys (not present on this part). Held at Ryman Auditorium, Nashville, TN.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Ernest Tubb; Johnnie &amp; Jack; Crook Brothers; Hank Snow; Martha Carson</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>"Opening theme -- Opening statement (Jud Collins) -- Fortunes In Memories (Ernest Tubb) -- Opening statement (Ernest Tubb)
Ernest Tubb introduces Johnnie &amp; Jack -- Poison Love (Johnnie &amp; Jack) -- Martha White jingle -- Martha White commercial (Jud Collins) -- Martha White jingle -- Ernest Tubb introduces the Crook Brothers -- Boil Them Cabbage Down (Crook Brothers) -- Ernest Tubb introduces Hank Snow -- The Golden Rocket (Hank Snow) -- Martha White commercial (Jud Collins) -- Ernest Tubb introduces Martha Carson -- Rock-A My Soul (Martha Carson) -- Ernest Tubb talks -- I Will Miss You When You Go (Ernest Tubb)"</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>16 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR000937</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2007-12-03</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); Grand ole opry (Radio program); Martha White Foods; Ryman Auditorium (Nashville, Tenn.); Collins, Jud; Tubb, Ernest, 1914-1984; Johnnie &amp; Jack; Byrd, Billy; Carson, Martha; Blue Grass Boys; Crook Brothers; Snow, Hank</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/1836</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>