<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Hallmarks of Country Music - Tom T. Hall</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of an interview of Tom T. Hall (musician). The interview is hosted by Rick Phillips (army sergeant/ radio host) for the Hallmarks of Country Music segment. The tape was recorded on an unidentified date. Tape features a segment at the end called Five Minutes With Johnny Rodriguez. The segment features Johnny Rodriguez (musician) discussion with Phillips.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Tom T. Hall; Rick Phillips; Johnny Rodriguez</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Country is [featuring Phillips commercial spot for the Hallmarks of Country Music program] (Tom. T. Hall) -- (00:18) Unidentified tune (Tom T. Hall) -- (00:38) Hallmarks tune [featuring Rick Phillips introduction voiceover] ([Unidentified]) -- (01:10) Yogurt commercial spot hosted by unidentified voice -- (01:42) Salute to a Switchblade Knife (Tom T. Hall) -- (05:04) Hall reflects on his time in Germany while recalling "Salute to a Switchblade Knife;" additionally, Hall reflects on working as a song-writer -- (07:04) That Song is Driving Me Crazy (Tom T. Hall) -- (10:00) Feron Young radio spot about his military service -- (11:02) Reenlistment commercial spot hosted by Hall -- (12:19) Home Coming (Tom T. Hall) -- (15:31) Hall discusses the statement "Home Coming" makes, and Phillips asks as to why Hall left the Grand Ole Opry -- (18:50) That's How I Got to Memphis (Tom T. Hall) -- (21:35) Carpool commercial spot hosted by an unidentified voice -- (22:38) Country is (Tom T. Hall) -- (24:38) Phillips hosts a military housing commercial spot -- (25:12) One-Hundred Children (Tom T. Hall) -- (27:35) Hall reflects on his dream of a perfect world -- (30:07) The Promise and the Dream (Tom T. Hall) -- (32:50) Phillips radio spot for the Veteran's Office -- (33:03) A Week in Country Jail (Tom T. Hall) -- (35:58) Phillips inquires about how genuine "A Week in Country Jail" is; additionally, Hall and Phillips discuss the story of "Old Dogs, Children and Watermelon Wine" -- (37:50) Old Dogs, Children and Watermelon Wine (Tom T. Hall) -- (41:41) Military medical insurance commercial spot hosted by an unidentified voice -- (42:13) Shoe Shine Man (Tom T. Hall) -- (44:57) Phillips and Hall discuss how one draws inspiration for a story like "Shoe Shine Man" -- (46:53) I Love (Tom T. Hall) -- (48:53) Phillips performs a reenlistment commercial spot -- (49:30) The Year Clayton Delaney Died (Tom T. Hall) -- (52:06) Hall reveals the man who inspired "The Year Clayton Delaney Died," and both Hall and Phillips say goodbye -- (52:58) Hallmarks outro tune [featuring Phillips outro voiceover] ([Unidentified]) -- (55:16) Ridin' My Thumb to Mexico (Johnny Rodriguez) -- (57:18) Rodriguez recalls stealing goats to feed himself and being brought before officers to perform -- (59:18) Unidentified outro tune </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Insert is of program information. The insert features time stamps.</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1618_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1618</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-06-07</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Rodriguez, Johnny, 1951-; Rodriguez, Johnny; Hall, Tom T.; Phillips, Rick;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9059</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>