<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Discussion - The Armadillo World Headquarters - 2018-05-25</dc:title>
<dc:description>Panel discussion titled Home with the Armadillo on the Armadillo World Headquarters from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on May 25, 2018.  Participants include Armadillo World Headquarters co-founders Jim Franklin (the club&#8217;s artistic director and frequent emcee), attorney Mike Tolleson, and Eddie Wilson.  Rounding out the panel will be Gary P. Nunn.  Texas music journalist Joe Nick Patoski is the moderator.  Includes audio from video excerpts and performance by Gary P. Nunn.  Presented in support of the exhibit Outlaws &amp; Armadillos: Country&#8217;s Roaring &#700;70s</dc:description>
<dc:date>2018-05-26</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Eddie Wilson; Jim Franklin; Mike Tolleson; Gary P. Nunn; Joe Nick Patoski; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Walk-in Music / (04:20) Opening comments and introductions by Michael Gray / (09:00) Audio from video excerpt / (11:55) Joe Nick with opening comments and introduction of the discussion participants / (15:23) Eddie talks about how the he found the location for what became the Armadillo World Headquarters and how it started / (19:44) Talks about how the beer garden of Eden was created in a fenced-off area of the parking lot / (22:05) Jim Franklin talks about how he ended up in Austin from Galveston and how the Armadillo became metaphor and mascot for the Austin scene and in his drawings / (29:18) Gary P. Nunn tells a story about the first time seeing a Franklin painting of an armadillo on the side of a van, asking about it and it leading him to Austin / (30:25) Mike Tolleson talks about how he ended up in Austin and the grand opening of the Armadillo World Headquartes venue / (35:00) Gary P. Nunn talks about his background and the writing of the song London Homesick Blues / (40:38) Gary tells about recording the song London Homesick Blues / (41:38) Talk about the album Viva Terlingua and it's importance / (42:30) Joe Nick talks about country music coming to the Armadillo World Headquarters / (42:39) Eddie talks about Willie Nelson coming to the beer garden and meeting him for the first time / (45:19) Jim Franklin talks about broaching the idea of booking country acts in his club while rock acts were booked in the Austin coliseum and the resistance to that since psychedelic music halls didn't book country acts then / (46:37) Mike tells a story about Willie Nelson and discovering that he would be perfect act to expose country music to their audience through their venue / (48:55) Eddie talks about Willie's first appearance at the venue and what was going on at the time / (51:10) Eddie talks more about the armadillo and its use as the logo / (52:25) Eddie talks about Willie calling Waylon and Waylon's reaction at his first appearance there / (53:22) More talk about the Armadillo World Headquarters logo and the work of their art squad / (54:53) Jim Franklin talks about being inundated with requests to draw armadillos and his drawings bringing graphic artists to Austin to assist him / (56:10) Eddie and Gary talk about the first Willie Nelson 4th of July picnic / (58:02) Group talk about the Armadillo Country Music review tour and Willie Nelson story / (01:01:05) Story about taking the Armadillo World Headquarters concept to Victoria Texas / (01:02:52) Joe Nick talks about Chet Flippo / ()01:04:19) Jim Franklin talks about Lone Star Beer wanting to eliminate the long neck bottle and his efforts to combat that / (01:05:44) Eddie talks about using a song written by the Lost Gonzo Band for radio commercials / (01:08:14) Gary tells story about writing portions of the radio commercial / (01:09:33) Eddie talks about Chet Flippo's reluctance to read the radio copy if it mentioned beer and his feelings about working with the Lone Star beer company / (01:11:31) Jim talks about bringing Leon Russell to the Armadillo World Headquarters, painting his swimming pool in Oklahoma and introducing him to Willie Nelson / (01:14:57) Jim, Joe Nick and the group talk about a Thanksgiving jam session with members of the Grateful Dead and Doug Sahm / (01:18:30) Gary talks about the Armadillo World Headquarters as a venue and how it compared to other venues / (01:19:24) Story about Willie Nelson hearing B. W. Stevenson's harmonica player Mickey Raphael for the first time at another club in Austin / (01:19:46) Gary continues with his comments about the venue and the bridge between country and rock as shown by the Lost Gonzo Band / (01:21:54) Gary talks about country and rock cultures coming together at the Armadillo in Austin / (01:24:00) Eddie tells story about Bruce Springsteen, Kenneth Threadgill and Alvin Crow at the Armadillo the same night as Roy Acuff showed President Nixon how to yo-yo in Nashville / (01:28:04) Joe Nick talks about the glory days of the Armadillo World Headquarters, how it fell victim to real estate pressures and it's legacy / (01:29:02) Recognition of audience members tied to the World Headquarters story / (01:29:36) Closing comments by Joe Nick / (01:30:21) Closing comments from Gary P. Nunn / (01:31:29) Performance of Standing On A Piece Of The Ryman (Gary P. Nunn) / (01:34:44) Performs London Homesick Blues (Gary P. Nunn) / (01:38:49) Final comments / (01:39:28) Walk-out Music / (01:40:02) FILE END                                                    </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded as an mp3 file at 44.1</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0121</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2019-02-15</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Armadillo World Headquarters; Wilson, Eddie; Tolleson, Mike; Franklin, Jim, 1943-; Patoski, Joe Nick, 1951-; Nunn, Gary P.; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.); Austin city limits (Television program);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8569</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>