<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Buddy Killen Interview Side Two - Tree International</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of Bob Allen interviewing Buddy Killen of Tree International. The recording takes place on 8-31-79.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1979-08-31</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Buddy Killen</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Side Two - (0:04) -- Buddy Killen continues discusses his goals for Tree Publishing Company's growth. (1:01) -- Bob Allen asks about Don Gant's role at Tree Publishing Company and Don's history at Acuff/Rose. (2:10) -- Bob Allen changes the subject back to the purchase of the Pamper catalog. (3:22) -- Buddy Killen discusses purchasing conditions for Tree Publishing Company when Tree purchases a catalog. (4:12) -- Bob Allen asks Buddy Killen how many writers are currently signed to Tree Publishing Company. Bob goes on to ask about whether certain writers are jealous of each other. (5:07) -- Buddy Killen describes how writers will pitch each other's songs. (6:31) -- Buddy Killen discusses Curly Putnam's guidance to other songwriters. (7:25) -- Buddy Killen describes his relationship with Sonny Throckmorton. (9:11) -- Buddy Killen mentions that he keeps a low profile as a songwriter/"songcraftsman." (9:55) -- Bob Allen asks Buddy Killen about who he considers his competitors. (12:01) -- Buddy Killen describes his personal motivation to continue to grow. (13:06) -- Bob Allen compares Acuff/Rose to Tree Publishing Company. (14:42) -- "I compete with myself. I'm not really trying to knock anybody out but me." - Buddy Killen. (15:54) -- Bob Allen asks about Rafe Van Hoy and how he joined Tree Publishing Company. (17:39) -- Bob Allen asks about the group Equinox. (18:51) -- Bob Allen asks about what studios Buddy Killen produces in. Buddy Killen personally owns two studios. (20:52) -- Bob Allen asks Buddy Killen about whether his divorce changed his professional life. (23:23) -- Bob Allen asks about the total value of all publishing businesses in Nashville. (25:56) -- Bob Allen asks Buddy Killen about his personal background as a musician and when he first came to Nashville. (27:51) -- Buddy Killen tells a story about being behind on car payments and having his car towed. (30:28) -- Buddy Killen describes becoming a session musician, songwriter, singer, and publisher. "Through the years doing that has given me a tremendous overview of the business." (33:14) -- "Without pain you can't have depth." - Buddy Killen. (35:16) -- "When you are swimming in self-pity, people let you drown." - Buddy Killen. </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>audio cassette, compact;</dc:format>
<dc:format>1.75 ips;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CAS4652_2</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>CAS4652</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-08-23</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Killen, Buddy;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9400</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>