<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Words and Music Night - 2016-05-18</dc:title>
<dc:description>Words and Music Night program held in the CMA Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on May 18, 2016.  Hosted by Gary Allan.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2016-05-16</dc:date>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Performances include;  My Favorite Song (Bob Spanburgh with Jack Clouse and Rovarro Sanders) -- I&#8217;ll Stand by You (Misty Rae and Jason Carson with McKenna Rhinehart) -- Which Truck to Choose (Lacey Williams with Hayden Griggs) -- Black and White Towns (Caroline Spence with Skylar Parks) -- Sweet Tennessee (Christy McDonald and Kyle Jones with Hayden Mckee) -- Fall, Fall Down on Me (Trisha Leone with Diego Paz) -- Hey Legs (Shane Adams with Rachel Bowling) -- Stay Strong (Sandy Ramos with AJ Dale) -- Over the Mountains (Kathy Hussey with Nicole Caruso) -- The Music&#8217;s Beat (RaShelle Myra with Samantha Jennings) -- I&#8217;m Playing Basketball (Deanna Brown with Caleb Justice) -- See the World (Jerry Vandiver with Rory White) -- Nasty Locker Room (Emily Shackelton and Phil Barton with Bailey Brumit and Autumn Burgess) -- Always Headed Your Way (Matt Vrba with Rickia Mitchell) - Lil&#8217; Tennessee Country Boy (Gary Culley with Shaun Groves) -- Another Lover (Tim Buppert with Jeralyn Johnson) -- Her Man ( Gary Allan).</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>CD-R;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>PP0299</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2016-09-14</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/4371</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>