<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Louise Scruggs Memorial Forum -Traci Thomas - 2017-02-15</dc:title>
<dc:description>The 10th Annual Louise Scruggs Memorial Forum honoring Traci Thomas from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on February 15, 2017.  Includes audio from video and excerpts of recorded audio.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2017-02-15</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Traci Thomas; Peter Cooper;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Walk-in music / (04:45) Opening comments by Abi Tapia / (05:24) More walk-in music / (12:58) Opening comments and background on Louise Scruggs by Peter Cooper / (20:00) Recognition of past Memorial Forum honorees in attendance / (21:41) Comments from Gibson Guitars president Dave Berryman / (24:36) Introduction of Traci Thomas / (47:27) Traci talks about the difference between being a publicist and a manager / (27:25) What makes a good manager / (28:33) Working with artists that she respects / (28:50) Her background and first interest in the music business / (30:18) First jobs in the music business / (32:25) Working at Meyers Media and Bluegrass music / (33:00) Meeting Buddy Miller / (33:41) Working with Chris Thile early in his career / (34:54) Working on the Tulare Dust project / (36:51) Stepping out and forming her own public relations company / (37:43) Working on the Guy Clark album Keeper and learning from that / </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(38:41) Working on such an important project as the Keeper album and what working with Guy Clark did for her / (39:43) Choosing the Crittenton building for her office and working with Steve Earle / (41:18) Working on the Steve Earle and Del McCoury band partnership and the breakup / (43:23) Dealing with the conflict during the breakup / (44:12) Video presentation from the David Letterman Show of Steve Earle and the Del McCoury band / (46:15) Working to reconciling the McCoury manager request for more airtime on the Letterman show / (47:27) Perception of her personality / (47:43) Beginnings of the Americana Music Association / (50:01) Working with Drive-By Truckers / (50:54) Her thoughts on what Americana music is / (51:39) Working on the Drive-By Truckers Southern Rock Opera album / (53:10) Audio of the Drive-by Truckers recording The Southern Thing / (54:52) What rock and roll means to her career / (55:50) Moving to management from publicity and starting Justin Townes Earle career / </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/24</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0003</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2018-04-11</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Thomas, Traci; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/7200</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>