<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Lecture - Peter Cooper - 2017-04-11</dc:title>
<dc:description>Lecture to the Sony Music Nashville records staff about the history of their label by Peter Cooper from the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on April 11, 2017.  Includes audio from video. </dc:description>
<dc:date>2017-04-11</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Peter Cooper; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Opening comments from Randy Goodman and introduction of Kyle Young / (01:52) Comments from Kyle Young / (02:51) More comments and introduction of Peter Cooper from Randy Goodman / (04:36) Opening comments from Peter / (05:20) Peter talks about Bill Anderson and attending the Atlanta Braves spring training camp with him to make a correlation between that spring training and this lecture / (11:14) Peter talks about the first time he addressed this group and the differences between that time and this meeting /(12:38) Peter talks about Sony  Music Nashville record artists from the past currently in the Country Music Hall of Fame / (13:43)  Talks about the most recent HOF class and Don Schlitz's relationship to the Sony music label / (16:41) Talks about Alan Jackson and his relationship to the Sony music label / (18:07) Talks about Jerry Reed and his relationship to the Sony music label / </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(18:57) Talks about the roots of RCA records and the famous Bristol sessions including the history of the Carter Family and their first recordings / (23:32) Plays excerpt recording of Bury Me Under The Weeping Willow Tree by the Carter Family / (24:14) Peter continues talking about the Carter Family's Bristol sessions and the success of those recordings / (25:47) Talks about the importance Maybelle Carter guitar playing style, her needing a high quality guitar and the guitar's importance and influence on the future of country music / (27:21) Talks about Chet Atkins and Jerry Reed / (28:45) Plays excerpt recording of Jerry Reed's The Claw / (29:15) Continues talk about Jerry Reed and the other two members going into the HOF / (29:38) Tells the audience that the past is their present / (30:17) Talks about Sony's history of artists and recording studios in Nashville /  </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/24;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0026</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2018-05-24</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Cooper, Peter; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/7521</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>