<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Johnny Cash - Live in The Annex NCO Club - Tape 1</dc:title>
<dc:description>Tape 1 of 3. Recording from tape features Carl Perkins (performer) and June Carter (performer) performing on the Johnny Cash Show on an unknown date. Segment was recorded at the Annex 14 NCO Club in Long Binh, Vietnam.
</dc:description>
<dc:creator>June Cash; Carl Perkins</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Walk the Line (Johnny Cash) -- (00:43) [Unidentified] greets the crowd and introduces Carl Perkins -- (01:41) Freeborn Man (Carl Perkins) -- (04:43) Carl Perkins talks about Jackson, Tennessee and thanks the soldiers for their service -- (05:31) Mean Woman Blues (Carl Perkins) -- (08:12) Carl Perkins introduces "I Can't Help It (If I'm Still In Love With You)" -- (08:30) I Can't Help It (If I'm Still In Love With You) (Carl Perkins) -- (11:09) Jambalaya (On The Bayou) (Carl Perkins) -- (13:13) Perkins introduces "Restless" (13:39) Restless (Carl Perkins) -- (16:29) Carl Perkins expresses his respect for the Tennessee Three, and Perkins talks about Johnny Cash -- (17:09) Blue Suede Shoes (Carl Perkins) -- (18:58) [Unidentified] Expresses their thanks for Perkins and Perkins introduces June Carter Cash -- (20:16) June Carter talks to the audience -- (22:27) June Carter recites a poem -- (24:13) The Last Thing On My Mind (June Carter) -- (26:25) June talks about the Carter Family and introduces the next tune -- (26:53) I Never Will Marry (June Carter) [incomplete]</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1202_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1202</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-02-06</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Perkins, Carl; Perkins, Carl, 1932-1998; Cash, June Carter, 1929-2003;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8459</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>