<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Old Dominion Barn Dance - Osborne Brothers - WRVA Part 1</dc:title>
<dc:description>Part 1 of an Old Dominion Barn Dance segment featuring the Osborne Brothers (performer), Benny Birchfield (performer), and Roberta Osborne (performer) on radio station WRVA (Radio Station : Richmond, Va.)</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Osborne Brothers; Benny Birchfield; Roberta Osborne</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Test tones -- [Unidentified] introduces the Osborne Brothers -- My Saro Jane (Osborne Brothers) -- Bobby Osborne talks about the band and introduces members of the band -- Fair And Tender Ladies (Osborne Brothers) -- Bobby Osborne introduces Benny Birchfield to sing -- Head Over Heels In Love With You (Osborne Brothers) -- Bobby Osborne talks about Paul Craft and introduces the next song -- Bugle Call Rag (Osborne Brothers) -- Bobby Osborne introduces the next song -- Take This Hammer (Osborne Brothers) -- Bobby Osborne talks about past performances and record label changes -- Worried Man Blues (Osborne Brothers) -- Bobby Osborne talks about Virginia -- Give This Message To Your Heart (Osborne Brothers) -- Bobby Osborne introduces the next song -- Each Season Changes You (Osborne Brothers) -- Bobby Osborne introduces the next song -- Is This How A Broken Heart Dies (Osborne Brothers) (incomplete)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-0029_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-0029</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2017-08-07</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WRVA (Radio station : Richmond, Va.); Osborne Brothers; Osborne, Bobby; Osborne, Sonny; Osborne, Roberta;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/5495</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>