<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Truth Or Consequences - 1943-04-17 - Part 2</dc:title>
<dc:description>Truth Or Consequences game show from April 17, 1943, part 2. Hosted by Ralph Edwards with announcer Cliff Engle and contestants Pvt. Bernard Litt, Pvt. Collins Weehunt, Bill Dague, Maurice Hook, Kansas Governor Andrew Schoeppel, and Betty Wright (contestant names unconfirmed). Features a performance by the Kansas City Symphony conducted by Dr. N. De Rubertis, with guest vocalist Betty Wright. Sponsored by Duz Soap.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1943-04-17</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Kansas City Symphony; Betty Wright</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Game show competition [continued from part 1] -- Ralph Edwards introduces the Kansas City Symphony Orchestra and conductor Dr. N. De Rubertis -- Seguidilla (Betty Wright, Kansas City Symphony) -- Duz Soap commercial (Ralph Edwards, Cliff Engel, Mrs Harry K. Allen) -- Announcement of grand prize winner -- Closing statement (Ralph Edwards)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>16 inch glass-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR000056_2</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>TR000056</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2006-10-11</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>National Broadcasting Company; Truth or consequences (Radio program); Engle, Cliff; Edwards, Ralph, 1913-2005; Schoeppel, Andrew Frank, 1894-1962; Kansas City Symphony; Rubertis, N. de</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/982</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>