<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Discussion - Banjoman film featuring Earl Scruggs - 2006-05-21</dc:title>
<dc:description>Panel discussion following the screening of the film "Banjoman" from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on May 21, 2006.  In support of the exhibit Banjo Man: The Musical Journey of Earl Scruggs.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2006-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Steve Hermes; Tracy Nelson; Earl Scruggs; Michael Varhol; Randy Scruggs; Gary Scruggs; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Recording begins in progress.  Opening comments by Jay Orr.  Discussion moderated by Jay Orr.  Introduction of panelists.  Subjects include; 1973 Kansas State University concert by the Earl Scruggs Review being filmed -- Steve Hermes with the background of the concert -- Film director Michael Varhol remembers the events leading up to and the day of the concert -- Tracy Nelson reminiscences  -- Rambling Jack Elliott story -- Randy Scruggs reminiscences -- Gary Scruggs reminiscences -- Earl Scruggs reminiscences -- Airplane stories --  Tracy Nelson first memories of meeting Earl and the boys -- Performance of the song Freight Train -- Campus response -- Technical issues with the sound and production crew -- Budget for the film -- Interviews filmed after the concert -- Earl Scruggs talks about learning to play banjo -- Joan Baez -- Hanging out backstage -- Clarence White and his B bender telecaster --  Camera shot choices -- Josh Graves -- </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Impact of the concert on the Kansas State community -- Final thoughts by each of the panelists.</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>RDAT digital tape;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RS.2014.0083</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2017-04-07</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Hermes, Steve; Nelson, Tracy; Scruggs, Earl; Varhol, Michael; Scruggs, Gary; Scruggs, Randy; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/5137</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>