<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Poets and Prophets program - Sharon Vaughn - 2017-08-05</dc:title>
<dc:description>A program on the career and life to date of songwriter Sharon Vaughn from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on August 5, 2017. Includes selected audio excerpts, audio from video and musical performances.  Hosted by Michael Gray.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2017-08-05</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Sharon Vaughn; John Rich; Tim Ryan; Melissa Manchester; Al Anderson;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Blank audio signal / (05:48) Walk-in music / (12:08) Opening comments and introduction by Michael Gray / (18:00) Opening comments by Sharon / (18:20) Performs My Heroes Have Always Been Cowboys / (22:00) Michael asks about the inspiration for writing My Heroes Have Always Been Cowboys and Sharon talks about her background / (23:59) Talks about meeting Roy Rogers / (25:30) Talks about writing the song and getting it to Waylon Jennings / (29:20) Sharon talks about Willie's version of the song / (29:56) Plays audio from video of the film Electric Horseman / (31:22) Sharon talks about her childhood growing up in Florida and when she started singing / (34:28) Recognizes audience member Ed Cargill and talks about entering a talent contest with him as a child / (35:33) Talks about working on radio, being discovered by Mel Tillis and meeting Chuck Glaser in 1969 / (40:19) Talks about beginning to write songs / </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(41:09) Talks about moving to Nashville, working at WSM, singing with Boyce Hawkins' jazz band and working at a dress shop / (42:37) Talks about beginning work in recording sessions as a background singer / (43:56) Tells story about working with Porter Wagoner and Dolly Parton, talks about the recording session scene, people she worked for and recordings she sang on / (46:40) Plays recorded excerpt of From Boulder To Birmingham by Dolly Parton / (47:43) Talks about the Lea Jane Singers and what she learned about songs from being a background vocalist / (49:33) Talks about writing Ya'll Come Back Saloon and the Oak Ridge Boys / (53:15) Performs Ya'll Come Back Saloon / (56:23) Talks about beginning to co-write / (57:49) Working with Bill Rice / (58:35) Plays audio from video of the Bobby Bare and Friends TV show / (01:01:21) Talks about writing the song 'Til A Tear Becomes A Rose / (01:03:27) Performs 'Til A Tear Becomes A Rose (Sharon with John Rich and Tim Ryan) / </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/24;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0056</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>Poets and Prophets program - Sharon Vaughn - 2017-08-05</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Vaughn, Sharon; Rich, John; Ryan, Tim; Manchester, Melissa; Anderson, Al; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8052</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>