<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Discussion - Jimi Hendrix in Nashville - 2004-07-24</dc:title>
<dc:description>Panel discussion about time spent in Nashville by Jimi Hendrix from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on July 24, 2004.  In support of the exhibit "Night Train to Nashville: Music City Rhythm and Blues".</dc:description>
<dc:date>2004-07024</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Ed Salamon; Johnny Jones; George Yates; Billy Cox; Marion James; Frank Howard; Teddy Acklen Jr; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Recording begins in progress.  Opening comments by Michael Gray.  Includes questions by the audience.  Moderated by Ed Salamon.  Introduction of panelists.  Subjects include; Del Morocco club -- Little Richard's appearances -- George Yates remembrances of the club scene -- Frank Howard's remembrances of the scene -- Billy Cox's first time meeting Jimi -- Playing in Clarksville, TN -- WLAC radio's impact on Jimi and Billy --  Impact of Nashville on Jimi -- Marion James' role in the Nashville scene and her reminiscences of playing engagements with Jimi -- Jimi's playing being outside of what was considered normal playing -- Marion's dream about a park dedicated to Jimi in Nashville -- Johnny Jones reminiscences of meeting Jimi the first time -- Why Jimi was drawn to Johnny and what Jimi learned from him -- Johnny's guitar shoot out with Jimi at the Baron club --  Jimi carrying his guitar with him everywhere -- Jimi's proper talking style -- Jimi's left handed playing style --</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Comparison of various blues guitar players -- Jimi wanting a long guitar cord so he could walk around --  Jimi's living conditions -- Frank Howard's friendship with Bill "Hoss" Allen of WLAC radio and his influence -- Hoss Allen's recording session with Jimi -- Frank's reminiscences of Jimi and his playing -- George Yates's reminiscences of Jimi and his guitar strap -- Marion's remembrances of Jimi at the New Era Club and his leaving Nashville to go to Atlanta -- Billy's comments about Jimi's moving on -- Little Richard story -- George Yates's story about the Baron club shoot out with Johnny -- Billy's contribution to the museum exhibition -- Recognition of Dave Pearcy in the audience -- Billy's story about working with Jimi in later years -- Appearing at the Woodstock festival -- Band of Gypsys album and Jimi's obligation to record it --  Thoughts about what if Jimi had lived -- Video screening -- Johnny's comments about Jimi's performance -- Question about Miles Davis and Jimi -- </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>RDAT digital tape;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RS.2014.0139</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2017-05-04</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Salamon, Ed; Jones, Johnny; Yates, George; Cox, Billy; James, Marion; Howard, Frank; Acklen Jr., Theodore; </dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/5168</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>