<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Songwriter Session - Bobby Bare, Max T. Barnes, Mary Gauthier - 2017-10-14</dc:title>
<dc:description>Performance by singer songwriters Bobby Bare, Max T. Barnes and Mary Gauthier from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on October 14, 2017.  </dc:description>
<dc:date>2017-10-14</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Bobby Bare; Max T. Barnes; Mary Gauthier;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Opening comments in progress by Ali Tonn and introduction of participants / (5:00) Opening comments by Bobby Bare / (06:45) Bobby and Mary introduce the song Mercy Now / (07:56) Performs the song Mercy Now (Mary Gauthier) / (13:43) Bobby and Mary talk about the previous song and the inspiration / (17:07) Bobby introduces next song / (18:49) Performs I Drink (Bobby Bare) / (23:19) Mary and Bobby talk about the previous song / (24:32) Max T. Barnes talks about Max D. Barnes, working in Bare's band and encouragement he got from Bare / (26:04) Max introduces the next song / (26:35) Performs Love, Me (Max T. Barnes) / (30:28) Performs brief excerpt of Look At Us (Max T. Barnes) / (31:06) Talks about the Songwriting with Soldiers program / 3(1:37) Performs Bullet Holes In The Sky (Mary Gauthier) / (35:45) Bare talks about his song God Bless America Again / (36:20) Bare talks about the song 500 Miles Away From Home / (37:27)  Performs 500 Miles Away From Home (Bobby Bare) /         </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(41:06) Max talks about the next song / (42:12) Performs How Your Love Makes Me Feel (Max T. Barnes) / (45:15) Talk about the previous song / (45:40) Bare talks about the next song / (46:30) Performs Things Change (Bobby Bare) / (48:14) Final comments / (48:47) Walk-out music - (53:05) FILE END              </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/24;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0071</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2018-09-06</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Bare, Bobby; Barnes, Max T.; Gauthier, Mary; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8136</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>