<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Aunt Jemima jingles - Ernest Tubb - show #5</dc:title>
<dc:description>Various Aunt Jemima jingles, plugs, and performances by Ernest Tubb (performer), the Beasley Sisters (performers), and Louis Buck (announcer)</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Ernest Tubb; Beasley Sisters</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Louis Buck talks -- Aunt Jemima jingle -- Aunt Jemima commercial -- Ernest Tubb introduces the first tune -- Walking The Floor Over You (Ernest Tubb) -- Ernest Tubb talks about his songs -- Aunt Jemima commercial (Louis Buck) -- Columbus Stockade Blues (Beasley Sisters) -- Aunt Jemima commercial (Ernest Tubb) -- Ernest Tubb introduces the next tune -- Till The End Of The World (Ernest Tubb) -- Ernest Tubb talks about next weeks guest -- Aunt Jemima jingle -- Closing statement (Louis Buck)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-0213_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-0213</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2017-11-29</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Buck, Louis, 1910-1971; Tubb, Ernest, 1914-1984; Beasley Sisters;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/6308</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>