<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Sunday Down South - 1954-03-28 - Part 1</dc:title>
<dc:description>WSM program Sunday Down South, sponsored by Lion Oil. Originally broadcast 1954-03-28, part 1. Personnel include Buddy Hall (host, performer), David Cobb (announcer), Owen Bradley (conductor) and the Lion Orchestra (performer), the Anita Kerr Singers (performers), Dolores Watson (performer), and Helen Traubel (performer). Hosted at the Ryman Auditorium.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1954-03-28</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Buddy Hall; Anita Kerr Singers; Owen Bradley; Lion Orchestra; Helen Traubel; Dolores Watson</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Opening statement (David Cobb) -- Theme (Got The South In My Soul) (Buddy Hall) -- Opening statement (Buddy Hall) -- Hillbilly Fever (Buddy Hall, Anita Kerr Singers) -- Buddy Hall introduces Helen Traubel -- Buddy Hall, Helen Traubel and David Cobb talk -- No Other Love (Helen Traubel) -- Lion Oil commercial -- Lion Oil jingle (Dolores Watson) -- Buddy Hall introduces Dolores Watson -- Half As Much (Dolores Watson)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>16 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR001284_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>TR001284</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2014-11-14</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); Sunday down south (Radio program); Ryman Auditorium (Nashville, Tenn.); Cobb, David (Announcer); Hall, Buddy (Singer); Traubel, Helen; Watson, Dolores; Anita Kerr Singers; Bradley, Owen; Lion Orchestra (Musical group)</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/566</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>