<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Lone Star Cafe Show - Storytellers and Tom T. Hall</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is from the Lone Star Cafe live show. The tape features live performances from: the Storytellers (musical group) and Tom T. Hall (musician). The Lone Star Cafe show is presented by Mort Cooperman, Bill McGivney and the WHN radio network. The recording of Tom T. Hall is from April 27, 1979.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1979-04-27</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Storytellers; Tom T. Hall</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) An unidentified host introduces the Lone Star Cafe and the Storytellers -- (01:07) Damn Good Band [poor recording] (Storytellers) -- (04:16) Nervous Pool Crawl [unconfirmed] (Storytellers) -- (06:40) An unidentified host introduces Tom T. Hall -- (07:20) Country Is (Tom T. Hall) -- (09:24) Hall looks for his friends in the crowd, and Hall reflects on working in a cemetery -- (11:09) Ballad of Forty Dollars (Tom T. Hall) -- (14:07) Hall reflects on a Penthouse Magazine article while listing his friends in the audience -- (15:56) The Year That Clayton Delaney Died (Tom T. Hall) -- (18:50) Hall reflects on growing up in Kentucky -- (20:02) Unidentified banjo tune (Tom T. Hall) -- (23:42) I Know You're Married (But I Love You Still) (Tom T. Hall) -- (26:11) Hall pays tribute to the various artists that recorded his songs -- (27:29) Unidentified tune (Tom T. Hall) -- (31:21) I Can't Stop Loving You (Tom T. Hall) -- (35:00) Hall addresses more guests in the crowd -- (36:15) I Like Beer (Tom T. Hall) -- (39:11) Hall addresses the crowd and WHN -- (40:52) I Love (Tom T. Hall) -- (44:03) Mr. Bojangles (Tom T. Hall) -- (49:01) Old Dogs, Children, and Watermelon Wine (Tom T. Hall) -- (53:39) Hall introduces a member of the crowd, and Hall brings multiple members of the crowd on to the stage -- (55:54) Amazing Grace (Tom T. Hall) -- (59:18) Unidentified tune (Tom T. Hall) -- (1:01:53) Down on the Rio Grande [featuring unidentified host] [incomplete] (Johnny Rodriguez) </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1567_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1567</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-06-21</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Storytellers (musical group); Hall, Tom T.;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9145</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>