<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Don Williams Interview - Biff Collie</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of an interview with Don Williams (performer) conducted by Biff Collie. </dc:description>
<dc:date>1989-05-15</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Don Williams; Biff Collie</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Don Williams describes the lessons "Learn to Let It Go" teaches about mental health -- (00:34) Biff Collie and Williams discuss the various interpretations of "One Good Well" -- (02:05) "Cryin' Eyes" is associated to a time Williams toured with Emmylou Harris and Waylon Jennings -- (03:30) Collie has Williams discuss the song-writing process while being a traveling musician -- (05:00) Williams tells that he most often is alone -- (05:09) "I've Been Loved By The Best" writer Bob McDill is discussed for his relationship to Williams -- (06:21) Williams and Collie reflect on why Williams chooses not to listen to a song in front of a writer -- (07:59) Williams recalls the first song of McDill's he recorded -- (09:12) Williams states that the most important part of his career has been to stay true to himself -- (11:04) Williams recalls how he feared recording "Broken Heartland" -- (13:03) Williams praises "Just As Long As I Have You" as an encapsulation of his feelings for his wife -- (13:59) Williams recalls meeting his wife at a department store -- (15:03) Collie inquires about what Williams enjoys doing in Hawaii -- (15:43) Williams describes how he discovered "Why Get Up" via his son -- (17:11) Williams touches on his children's musical inclinations -- (18:45) Williams identifies with the message of "Maybe That's All It Takes" -- (20:41) Williams reveals that "We're All the Way" was originally recorded by Eric Clapton; additionally, Collie and Williams discuss how Garth Fundis has been Williams producer for awhile -- (21:41) Collie has Williams describe what a Garden of Stone is from "Flowers Don't Grow (In Gardens of Stone)" -- (22:15) Williams reflects on his relationship with his wife -- (23:48) The inspiration for "If You Love Me, Won't You Love Me Like You Love Me" writer McDill is discussed; Collie and Williams say their goodbyes </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1250_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1250</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-02-20</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Williams, Don, 1939-; Williams, Don, 1939-2017; Collie, Biff;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8521</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>