<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Ralph Emery Interviews Charley Pride, Wayne Kemp and Mack Vickery</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording is from Ralph Emery's (entertainer) interviews of Charley Pride (performer), Wayne Kemp (performer), and Mack Vickery (perfromer) for the Ralph Emery Show. Recordings are from November 18, 1970.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Ralph Emery; Charley Pride; Wayne Kemp; Mack Vickery</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Keep on Walking (Brian Collins) -- (01:42) Ralph Emery radio spot commercial for Roadway Center Truck Stop -- (02:40) Emery and Charley Pride discuss Pride's international tour possibilities -- (03:35) Emery invites Pride to retell a story about when he met Webb Pierce -- (08:59) Pride discusses his leg getting run over during a time where he was auditioning for the Major League; additionally Pride reflects on attempting to meet Casey Stengel at three in the morning -- (13:44) Emery inquires about if joining the Mets was the last attempt Pride made to make the Major League -- (17:47) Come on Home and Sing the Blues to Daddy (Charley Pride) -- (20:05) Mr. D. C. radio spot commercial hosted by an unknown voice -- (21:09) Emery introduces Johnny Cash -- (21:17) Come Along and Ride This Train (Johnny Cash) -- (21:59) Unidentified announcer announces Cash's Come Along and Ride This Train: Live at the Grand Ole Opry -- (22:14) Emery introduces Wayne Kemp, and both discuss the characters that emerged from the Badlands of Oklahoma -- (24:00) Who'll Turn Out the Lights (Wayne Kemp) -- (26:42) WSM commercial break hosted by an unidentified voice -- (27:03) Emery invites Pride and Kemp to discuss their time together at the Panther Hall while recording "Image of Me" -- (29:36) Image of Me (Charley Pride) -- (32:11) Emery reflects on Tommy Collins influence on an episode of the Porter Wagoner Show -- (32:27) Emery introduces Pride's Christmas album, and both discuss their ability to get into the Christmas spirit -- (34:32) Emery inquires about the difference in African-American's perception of Christmas; additionally, Emery inquires about Pride's children's reaction to see their father dressed up as Christmas -- (36:57) Emery and Pride discuss Pride's father, Mach Pride, and Pride getting honored in Jackson, Mississippi -- (39:41) Santa and the Kids [featuring Emery voiceover] (Charley Pride) -- (41:39) WSM radio spot commercial for the Grand Ole Opry hosted by an unidentified voice -- (41:52) Emery introduces Mack Vickery, and invites him to do a John Wayne impression -- (43:46) Emery inquires as to how Vickery gained his Wayne impression -- (44:43) Emery invites Vickery to discuss his live album at an Alabama women's prison -- (47:46) Life Turned Her That Way (Mack Vickery) -- (50:39) Emery invites Vickery to discuss the subject of live albums -- (52:57) Cummins radio spot commercial hosted by Linda Gill -- (53:54) I Can't Believe That You Stopped Loving Me [featuring Ralph Emery voiceover] (Charley Pride)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1380_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1380</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-04-16</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Emery, Ralph; Kemp, Wayne, 1941-; Pride, Charley; Pride, Charley, 1938-; Vickery, Mack;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8798</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>