<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Nashville Record Review Artist Interviews 1982 - C</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recordings of phone interviews with various artists hosted by Al Rosen. Recording features: Mel Tillis, Teddy Gentry, Parker Milsap, George Strait, Ricky Skaggs, Don Williams, and the Flying Burrito Brothers. Item is listed as part C of the 1982  Nashville Radio Review artist interviews.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1982</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Al Risen; Skip Woolwine</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Al Risen introduces Mel Tillis, and Tillis reflects on his extended touring -- (02:03) Tillis tells about how he received "The One That Got Away" via the mail -- (02:55) Risen radio spot introduction of "The One That Got Away" -- (02:59) Skip Woolwine greets Teddy Gentry, and Gentry discusses his upcoming tour starting in Baltimore, Maryland -- (03:27) Woolwine and Gentry discuss the difficulty Alabama might have when addressing free time -- (04:48) Gentry reflects on the music they chose for the Mountain Music album; additionally, Woolwine and Gentry discuss how "Mountain Music" was written -- (05:54) Woolwine radio spot introduction of "Mountain Music" -- (06:00) Risen introduces Ronnie Milsap, and Milsap addresses where he had been touring to this point -- (07:31) Risen and Milsap discuss the influence of originality in Milsap's live shows -- (08:26) Milsap and Risen discuss "Any Day Now" -- (09:45) Risen radio spot introducing "Any Day Now" -- (09:49) Risen introduces George Strait, and both address how Strait became a country music artist -- (11:43) Strait describes performing "Fool Hearted Memory" for a movie -- (12:16) Risen inquires about Strait's desire to teach -- (13:15) Risen radio spot introducing "Fool Hearted Memory" -- (13:21) Risen introduces Ricky Skaggs, and both discuss Skaggs becoming a member of the Grand Ole Opry -- (14:48) Skaggs and Risen address Skaggs' family, and "Cryin Over You" is praised -- (15:42) Skaggs reflects on being his own producer -- (16:12) The release of Highways and Heartaches is discussed -- (16:49) Skaggs addresses how he was presented a number of Webb Pierce songs when he chose "I Don't Care" -- (17:38) Risen radio spot introduction of "I Don't Care" -- (17:44) Risen introduces Don Williams who describes his working career and home -- (18:24) Risen and Williams discuss William's European tour -- (19:30) Risen and Williams reflect on Danny Flowers and the Scratch Band -- (20:50) "Listen to the Radio" is revealed to have been sent to Williams via the mail -- (21:34) Risen radio spot introducing "Listen to the Radio" -- (21:41) Risen introduces Milsap, and both address the success of "Any Day Now" -- (22:23) Risen has Milsap reflect on the feeling of having successful albums -- (23:07) Milsap reveals that he is about to begin a new tour -- (23:57) Risen praises "Carolina Dreams," and Milsap reveals it's a reflection of his hometown -- (25:41) Risen and Milsap discuss the loose nature associated with "Any Day Now" -- (26:39) Risen radio spot introducing "Any Day Now" -- (26:44) Risen introduces the Flying Burrito Brothers , and Gib Buillbeau describes how he first started working with John Beland -- (27:55) Risen has Beland describe the hectic schedule the band has faced -- (28:38) Beland and Buillbeau describe their contribution to getting Lefty Frizzell into the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum -- (29:47) "Drinkin' Canada Dry" is described as a fun song -- (30:59) Risen radio spot introducing "Drinkin' Canada Dry"</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1256_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1256</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-02-21</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Risen, Al; Woolwine, Skip; Tillis, Mel; Gentry, Teddy; Milsap, Ronnie; Milsap, Ronnie, 1943-; Strait, George, 1952-; Skaggs, Ricky; Williams, Don, 1939-; Williams, Don, 1939-2017; Flying Burrito Bros.;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8536</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>