<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>T. G. Sheppard and Susie Allanson Live at the Lone Star Cafe Show -- 1978-08-02</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is from the Lonestar Cafe live show. The tape features a live performance of T. G. Sheppard (musician) and Susie Allanson (musician). T. G. Sheppard is accompanied by the Palomino Road.The Lonestar Cafe show is presented by Mort Cooperman, Bill McGivney and the WHN radio network. The recording is from August 02, 1978.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1978-08-02</dc:date>
<dc:creator>T. G. Sheppard; Susie Allanson; Palomino Road</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Lee Arnold introduces the Lone Star Cafe and Susie Allanson -- (01:33) One Fine Day (Susie Allanson) -- (04:27) Baby, Last Night Made My Day (Susie Allanson) -- (06:55) Allanson reveals 'We Belong Together' was just released -- (07:13) Starting Tonight [Unconfirmed] (Susie Allanson) -- (11:15) Love's Made a Fool of You (Susie Allanson) -- (14:01) Look Who's Lovin' You Now (Susie Allanson) -- (16:44) Maybe Baby (Susie Allanson) -- (19:34) Desperado (Susie Allanson) -- (23:02) The Cowgirl and the Dandy [unconfirmed] (Susie Allanson) -- (25:41) Allanson introduces "We Belong Together" -- (25:56) We Belong Together [featuring Allanson thanking the crowd] (Susie Allanson) -- (28:27) Back to the Love (Susie Allanson) -- (31:09) Arnold praises Allanson and introduces the Palomino Road and T. G. Sheppard -- (32:52) Show Me a Man (T. G. Sheppard and the Palomino Road) -- (37:35) Rollin' With the Flow (T. G. Sheppard and the Palomino Road) -- (40:38) Another Woman (T. G. Sheppard and the Palomino Road) -- (43:39) Devil in the Bottle (T. G. Sheppard and the Palomino Road) -- (49:15) Sheppard reflects on the long nights on the road -- (50:03) Motels and Memories (T. G. Sheppard and the Palomino Road) -- (53:30) Mr. D. J. (T. G. Sheppard and the Palomino Road) -- (56:31) Sheppard reflects on having pneumonia -- (56:52) When Can We Do This Again (T. G. Sheppard and the Palomino Road) -- (1:00:05) When Can We Do This Again (T. G. Sheppard and the Palomino Road) -- (1:00:51) Sheppard praises his bandmates -- (1:01:38) Are You Sure Hank Done it This Way (T. G. Sheppard and the Palomino Road) -- (1:07:22) Sheppard addresses the radio audience to discuss meeting Elvis Presley -- (1:09:00) C. C. Rider (T. G. Sheppard and the Palomino Road) -- (1:12:30) Arnold praises T. G. Sheppard and the Palomino Road and says goodbye </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1560_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1560</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-06-25</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Sheppard, T. G.; Sheppard, T.G.; Allanson, Susie, 1952-; Palomino Road (Musical group);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9165</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>