<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Pioneer Rhythm Boys - WHFB - 1949-mm-dd</dc:title>
<dc:description>Pioneer Rhythm Boys radio show for station WHFB, Benton Harbor, MI. Original broadcast date unknown, possibly early December 1949 (unconfirmed). Featuring Mel Irving (announcer), Eddie Skates (host), and (verbally identified) band members Ray 'The Professor' Watkins, Rex Watkins, and Butch. Bud 'The Deacon' Wheeler is identified as not being present. Sponsored by Bill's Auto Service and Al's Grocery.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1949</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Pioneer Rhythm Boys</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Theme -- Opening statement (Mel Irving) -- Opening statement (Eddie Skates) -- Candy Kisses -- Bill's Auto Service commercial (Mel Irving) -- Eddie Skates introduces Rex -- Galway Bay -- Eddie Skates introduces the Professor -- Wildwood Flower -- Al's Grocery Store commercial (Mel Irving) -- Eddie Skates introduces Rex -- Someday You'll Call My Name -- Eddie Skates introduces Butch -- I'm Throwing Rice (At The Girl That I Love) -- Theme -- Closing statement (Eddie Skates) -- Closing statement (Mel Irving)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>16 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR001405_2</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>TR001405</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2015-02-25</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WHFB (Radio station : Benton Harbor, Mich.); Pioneer Rhythm Boys</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/763</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>