<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Grand Ole Opry - Prince Albert - 1939-10-21 - Part 1</dc:title>
<dc:description>Part 1 of Prince Albert tobacco sponsored Grand Ole Opry segment from October 21, 1939. Featuring David Stone (announcer), George D. Hay (host), and performers Roy Acuff and his Smoky Mountain Boys, Uncle Dave Macon and son Dorris Macon, George Wilkerson and his Fruit Jar Drinkers, the Possum Hunters, Ford Rush, and Rachel Veach. Held at War Memorial Auditorium, Nashville, TN. Recording begins with the end of the previous Opry segment.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1939-10-21</dc:date>
<dc:creator>George Wilkerson; Fruit Jar Drinkers; Roy Acuff; Smoky Mountain Boys; Uncle Dave Macon; Dorris Macon; Possum Hunters; Ford Rush</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(0:00) George Wilkerson and his Fruit Jar Drinkers perform "[Unidentified instrumental]" / (0:29) Announcer closing statement / (1:02) Opening theme to the Prince Albert portion of the Grand Ole Opry / (1:39) David Stone announces the opening statement and introduces George D. Hay / (2:19) George D. Hay announces his opening statements and introduces Roy Acuff and his Smoky Mountain Boys / (2:37) Roy Acuff and his Smoky Mountain Boys perform "I'll Be All Smiles Tonight" / (3:50) David Stone announces a Prince Albert commercial / (4:37) George D. Hay introduces Uncle Dave Macon and Dorris Macon / (4:55) Uncle Dave Macon and Dorris Macon perform "Keep My Skillet Good And Greasy" / (7:00) George D. Hay introduces the Possum Hunters / (7:14) Possum Hunters perform "Take Your Foot Out Of The Mud And Put It In The Sand" / (9:08) George D. Hay introduces Ford Rush / (9:24) Ford Rush performs "Carry Me Back To The Lone Prairie" / (11:07) George D. Hay introduces Roy Acuff / (11:19) Roy Acuff performs "Wabash Cannonball" / (14:29) David Stone announces a Prince Albert commercial / (15:15) George D. Hay introduces Uncle Dave Macon [incomplete]</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>16 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR000003_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>TR000003</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2005-04-21</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); National Broadcasting Company; Grand ole opry (Radio program); Hay, George D. (George Dewey), 1895-1968; Stone, David P., 1901-1995; Acuff, Roy; Smoky Mountain Boys; Rush, Ford, 1895-; Wilkerson, George W., 1895-1954; Fruit Jar Drinkers (Musical group); Macon, Uncle Dave, 1870-1952; Macon, Dorris; Veach, Rachel; Stone, Oscar, 1881-; Possum Hunters (Musical group); King, Pee Wee, 1914-2000; Golden West Cowboys (Musical group)</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/917</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>