<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Earl Thomas Conley Interview - Biff Collie</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of an interview with Earl Thomas Conley (performer) conducted by Biff Collie.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1989-06-08</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Earl Thomas Conley; Biff Collie</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Earl Thomas Conley talks about being born in Portsmith, Ohio and being the third child of eight -- (00:35) Conley talks about his father working on steam engines and losing his job for fifteen years causing his alcoholism -- (01:10) Conley talks about the lack of money in his home and his families ability to repurpose -- (03:05) Conley talks about Hank Williams and his father's musical talents -- (03:40) Conley talks about listening to the Opry while his family drank -- (04:39) Conley talks about Elvis, among others, and following the progression of popular music -- (05:51) Conley talks about his record collection and his Victrola -- (06:27) Conley talks about his uncle and how he taught Conley music before being disfigured -- (07:20) Conley talks about joining the military and the fellow soldiers he would listen to George Jones music with -- (08:16) Collie and Conley talk about his inability to play and his high school popular music influences -- (09:24) Conley talks about seeing Earnest Tubb and Jan Howard while in Germany and his fellow solider introducing him to new music -- (10:09) Conley reflects on imitating styles and how influences hurt recording work -- (10:39) Conley talks about artistic inclinations before song writing -- (11:26) Conley talks about working in a steel mill, listening to Charlie Pride, and beginning to song write -- (12:20) Conley speaks on getting introduced to a recording studio through his uncle -- (13:05) Conley's studio development and work history is discussed -- (13:56) Conley talks about Meryl Streep and the process of "Smokey Mountain Memories" is discussed -- (15:00) Conley talks about attempting to avoid melody plagiarism by using minor cords -- (15:54) Conley talks about his growing popularity as a song writer and how his personal artistic success progressed -- (17:20) Conley talks about how he battled between being unique and playable -- (18:05) Collie and Conley discuss the use of studios with recording -- (19:13) Conley talks about meeting up with Tommy Brassfield -- (19:41) Conley talks about moving to Nashville in 1974 and recording in bunches -- (20:20) Conley talks about the importance of timing -- (21:36) Conley and Collie discuss Conley's ascension to popularity and being turned down by Warner Brothers for an entire album -- (22:55) "Middle Age Madness" and "Middle Age Crazy" are discussed based on a similarity of thought process -- (24:01) Conley talks about working on a Freddie Hart album and releasing "Silent Treatment" in the midst of other works and how it lead to a Sunburnt Records deal - (25:29) Collie and Conley talks about his growing career and his ideas on being a mainstream artist -- (28:55) Collie and Conley discuss the unique niche that describes Conley's fan group -- (29:35) Conley reiterates his success confirming his career path -- (30:35) Conley talks about how his beard was a way of hiding himself for over ten years -- (31:29) Conley tells Collie about his greatest satisfaction coming from his artistic achievements and having a grand-daughter</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1136_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1136</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-01-03</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Conley, Earl Thomas; Collie, Biff;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8336</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>