<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>1975 Reunion Show - Jordanaires and Rex and Eleanor Parker performances</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is from a number of snippets from the 1975 Reunion Show in Nashville, Tennessee. The recording displays a number of hosts that includes Pee Wee King. The tape features performances by the Jordanaires (musical group), and Rex and Eleanor Parker (performing group). The tape is from an unidentified date in 1975.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1975</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Jordanaires; Pee Wee King; Rex and Eleanor Parker;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Background noise featuring the Jordanaires tuning up -- (03:13) Pee Wee King indicates that the Suburban Transit Company bus is about to leave -- (05:46) Orange Blossom Special [featuring T. Tommy Cutrer voiceover] (Jordanaires) -- (08:03) King praises the Jordanaires; additionally, the host attempts to introduce a female musician [incomplete] -- (09:12) The unidentified host introduces Joe and Rose Maphis -- (10:00) Joe Maphis expresses his appreciation and begins to play "Hot Time in Nashville" -- (10:23) The unidentified host introduces Ethel Delaney, Buddy Durham, Jim Ense [unconfirmed] and Danny Dill -- (11:26) The unidentified host discusses Rex Parker and Eleanor Parker -- (11:58) I Care Not (Rex and Eleanor Parker) -- (15:40) The unidentified host introduces "San Antonio Rose;" additionally, a member of the band introduces his bandmates</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1616_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1616</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-06-06</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Jordanaires (Musical group); King, Pee Wee, 1914-2000; Parker, Rex; Parker, Eleanor;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9057</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>