<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Nashville Record Review Artist Interviews 1982 - D</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recordings of phone interviews with various artists hosted by Al Risen. Recording features: Richard Sterban, Charley Pride, John Hartford, Ronnie Rogers, Michael Murphey, Joe Thrasher, Earl Thomas Conley, and Sylvia. Item is listed as part D of the 1982 Nashville Radio Review artist interviews.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1982</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Al Risen</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Al Risen introduces Richard Sterban who discusses the success of Bobby Sue and Elvira -- (01:32) Risen and Sterban discuss the inspiration for "I Wish You Could Have Turned My Head" -- (02:49) Risen radio spot introduction for "I Wish You Could Have Turned My Head" -- (02:58) Risen introduces Charley Pride who discusses his upcoming schedule of shows; additionally, Risen and Pride discuss the Texas Vocal Company -- (04:29) "You're so Good (When You're Bad)" is discussed by Pride to be a memorable song, and Pride reflects on what he looks for in a song -- (05:48) Risen radio spot introduction for "You're So Good (When You're Bad)" -- (05:53) Risen introduces John Hartford who discusses with Risen how he is a steam boat pilot -- (07:15) Hartford reflects on being on the Glen Campbell Show -- (07:53) Hartford reflects on when Campbell had heard Hartford's "Gentle on My Mind;" additionally Risen and Hartford discuss what difficulties "Gentle on My Mind" faced -- (10:45) Risen radio spot introduction for "Gentle on My Mind" -- (10:55) Risen introduces Ronnie Rogers who discusses his Nashville upbringing; additionally, Rogers discusses his relationship with Ed Bruce -- (12:28) Tommy West is discussed by Rogers and Risen -- (13:01) Risen and Rogers discuss "Gonna Take My Angel Out Tonight; additionally Rogers reflects on the comparisons the record faces -- (14:35) Rogers reflects on why he wrote "Happy Country Birthday" for his wife -- (15:23) Risen radio spot introduction for "Happy Country Birthday" -- (15:28) Risen introduces Michael Murphey who discusses a bit of his musical career -- (17:09) Murphey's next single is discussed; additionally, Murphey reflects on the after-hours session that led to "What's Forever For" -- (19:07) Risen radio spot introduction for "What's Forever For" -- (19:17) Risen introduces Joe Thrasher who discusses a bit of the Thrasher Brothers' musical career -- (20:25) Risen invites the comparison of the Thrasher Brothers to the Oak Ridge Boys -- (21:03) Thrasher discusses where he and the band members live -- (21:40) "One Day at a Time" is told by Thrasher to be the biggest gospel song the Thrasher Brothers had released; additionally, the Thrasher Brothers' television show is discussed -- (22:45) "Still the One" is told by Thrasher to be one of his favorites -- (23:26) Risen radio spot introduction for "Still the One" -- (23:31) Risen introduces Earl Thomas Conley who discusses a bit of his touring schedule -- (24:06) Risen addresses the success of "Somewhere Between Right and Wrong," and Conley addresses the writers on his track -- (24:51) Conley discusses "I Have Loved You Girl," among others, from his new album -- (25:35) Conley reflects on his families current successes -- (26:27) Conley discusses the woman's perspective of "Somewhere Between Right and Wrong" -- (26:53) Risen radio spot introduction for "Somewhere Between Right and Wrong" -- (26:59) Risen introduces Sylvia who discusses living in Kokomo, Indiana -- (27:58) Sylvia and Risen discuss how Sylvia's parents' lives had changed -- (28:34) Sylvia discusses her upcoming projects including: Country Jamboree, and creating her new house -- (29:50) Risen reflects on how "Nobody" was created -- (31:00) Risen radio spot introduction for "Nobody"</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1248_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1248</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-02-20</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Sterban, Richard, 1943-; Pride, Charley; Pride, Charley, 1938-; Hartford, John; Rogers, Ronnie; Murphey, Michael, 1945-; Thrasher Brothers; Conley, Earl Thomas; Sylvia, 1956-;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8525</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>