<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Jim Bulleit face-to-face Interview Tape 1 of 2 </dc:title>
<dc:description>Record industry pioneer Jim Bulleit talks about his career in the music business, focusing on his WSM days, his record label Bullet Records, and his work as a booking agent. Discussion includes various artists from the Bullet catalogue; the contract arrangement for Bullet artists; WSM programming and personalities; Bullet distribution and promotion; opening the first record processing plant in Nashville; the end of Bullet Records; the Village and Delta record labels; his publishing interests; Lefty Frizzell and Don Law; overseeing the booking and the artists for the Louisiana Hayride; his work at Sun Records; the attempt to revive Bullet Records; and memories of Fred Rose.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1983-05-09</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Jim Bulleit</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Side One, Tape 1 of 2 -- (00:00) -- Introduction by John Rumble. 2nd Interview about Bullet Records and the beginning of the Nashville music industry. (1:05) -- John Rumble citing a clipping from the 1948 Indianapolis Times about Bullet Records. (3:10) -- John Rumble asks about The Rangers Quartet, a gospel quartet. (5:45) -- Jim Bulleit remembers Seegar Ellis, the manager of the Mills Brothers. (6:34) -- Discussing Bob Lamb, a blind vocalist for Francis Craig. (7:55) -- Jim Bulleit discusses recording The Big Three Trio, a group from Chicago. Bullet Records recorded the group in Chicago. (9:48) -- John Rumble asks about Milton Estes and the Musical Millers, a group recorded by Bullet Records. Milton Estes was a singer for the Opry. (10:30) -- Jim Bulleit describes that Bullet Records had low country sales except for Zeb Turner. (11:04) -- Jim Bullet describes that a decent country sale was between 25,000 and 50,000 records. (15:12) -- John Rumble asks about Noontime Neighbors, a show run by Pee Wee King. Jim Bulleit describes that the show was eventually run by John McDonald. (17:45) -- John Rumble begins discussion about record distribution and asks which distributors Bullet Records used. Jim Bulleit mentions that he used independent distributors that would take care of every release from Bullet Records. (21:43) -- John Rumble asks about a New York distributor Ed Levee. (23:44) -- Jim Bulleit elaborates on the record distribution process. (25:10) -- Jim Bulleit elaborates on how jukeboxes were incredibly important for popularizing records. (28:30) Jim Bulleit recalls how Bullet Records in September of 1947 sold $25,000 of records per day. (30:13) John Rumble inquires about the pressing plants used by Bullet Records. </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Compact Cassette Tape</dc:format>
<dc:format>1.75 IPS</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>OH.C047_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>OH.C047</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-08-16</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Bulleit, Jim;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9358</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>