<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Interview - Robert Earl Keen - 2018-09-12</dc:title>
<dc:description>Interview with Robert Earl Keen from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on September 12, 2018.  Conducted by Michael McCall.  Includes selected audio recording excerpts and audio from video and performance.  Presented in partnership with the Americana Music Association. </dc:description>
<dc:date>2018-09-12</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Robert Earl Keen;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Walk-in music / (05:59) Opening comments by Michael McCall / () Introduction of Americana director of education and programs Dana Strong / (06:56) Comments from Danna Strong / (07:50) Michael introduces Robert Earl Keen / (10:00) Opening comments from Robert Earl / (10:45) Talks about the influence of Houston Texas on his music and the music scene there / (13:17) Talks about the venues and songwriting culture in Houston / (14:17) Talks about his sisters impact on him and going to clubs in the early days / (16:08) Talks about how he started playing and performing / (18:02) Talks about beginning to write songs / (20:02) Talks about finding his voice and style / (21:42) Talks about attending Texas A&amp;M University and getting to know Lyle Lovett / (26:19) Talks about the album Happy Prisoner: The Bluegrass Sessions / (27:42) Talks about making the album No Kinda Dancer / (32:05) Talks about moving to Nashville from Austin Texas / (35:12) Talks about Hatch Show Print manager Jim Sherraden offering him lodging / (37:16) Talks about moving from Nashville back to Texas / (43:11) Talks about his friendship with Jim Rooney and making a live album / (45:28) Talks about his career arch, how it happened and tells story about playing a show in San Antonio which drew a large crowd / (48:34) Talks about making the album A Bigger Piece Of The Sky / (49:39) Talks about being ready at that time to change his sound / (50:57) Talks about producer Gary Velletri input on this album / (51:40) Talks about making the album Gringo Honeymoon / (54:01) Talks about the Song Merry Christmas From The Family / (56:17) Talks about making the following albums Walking Distance, Farm Fresh Onions and how he feels about making studio albums / (58:56)  Talks about providing benefits for his band / (01:01:42) Closing interview comments / (01:02:25) Introduces his performance / (01:03:25) Performs unidentified song likely titled Will You Go When She's Gone / (01:06:30) Performs Merry Christmas From The Family / (01:10:54) Final comments / (01:11:18) Walk-out music / (01:12:34) FILE END                           </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 48/24</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0148</dc:identifier>
<dc:subject>Keen, Robert Earl; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8885</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>