<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Ralph Emery On The Record with Lorrie Morgan - Part 2</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording from Ralph Emery's (entertainer) interview of Lorrie Morgan (performer) for Ralph Emery: On the Record With Lorrie Morgan.  The recording is performed in front of a live audience. The recording is from January 13, 1995. The tape is labeled part 2.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1995-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Ralph Emery; Lorrie Morgan</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Lorrie Morgan discusses how it hurt when she and Troy Aikman broke up, and Ralph Emery and Morgan discuss the beginning of their relationship -- (01:59) Emery addresses a tabloid article that accuses Morgan of not liking country music, and Morgan denies any allegations -- (05:33) Emery recalls a story about when Morgan fell and revealed herself to the crowd -- (10:05) Emery asks Morgan to reflect on the comedic genes she received from George Morgan -- (12:11) Emery inquires about Morgan's theatric performances, and Morgan reflects on not allowing television to come between her and music -- (14:49) Emery plays a clip of Morgan acting for Proud Heart -- (15:50) Emery inquires about how Morgan was paired with Collin Wilcox-Paxton to perform for Proud Heart, and Emery stops for a break while Morgan praised Wilcox-Paxton -- (18:48) Emery and Morgan reflect on Wilcox-Paxton and how she was in: To Kill a Mockingbird -- (19:33) Emery and Morgan discuss how Morgan played Kris Kristofferson a number of her songs -- (21:34) Emery and Morgan joke about Morgan having a kiss with Kris Kristofferson -- (22:10) Emery praises "Merry Christmas from London," and Morgan excites from discussing the number of featured artists she had on the album -- (24:57) My Favorite Things [excerpt] (Lorrie Morgan) -- (25:49) Emery asks Morgan to reflect on where Morgan recorded her video for "My Favorite Things" -- (27:00) Emery praises Morgan's work with Frank Sinatra on "How Do You Keep the Music Playing?/My Funny Valentine" -- (29:10) Emery questions Morgan about her smoking issues, and Morgan reflects on her prayers -- (31:56) Emery asks Morgan to reflect on her upcoming projects -- (33:35) Emery dons his "War Paint" jacket, and Morgan discusses her pursuit of movie roles -- (35:25) Indistinguishable chatter in the background -- (36:19) Lorrie Morgan radio spot for the 22nd American Music Awards on ABC -- (36:38) Lorrie Morgan radio spot for the 22nd American Music Awards on ABC -- (36:56) Lorrie Morgan radio spot for the 22nd American Music Awards on ABC -- (37:47) Morgan chats with Emery -- (38:05) Morgan radio spot recording of key words -- (39:53) Lorrie Morgan radio spot for the 22nd American Music Awards on ABC -- (40:43) Lorrie Morgan radio spot for the 22nd American Music Awards on ABC -- (41:05) Lorrie Morgan radio spot for the 22nd American Music Awards on ABC -- (42:31) Lorrie Morgan radio spot for the 22nd American Music Awards on ABC -- (43:04) Lorrie Morgan radio spot for the 22nd American Music Awards on ABC -- (43:17) Lorrie Morgan radio spot for the 22nd American Music Awards on ABC </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1400_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1400</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-04-24</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Emery, Ralph; Morgan, Lorrie;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8831</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>