<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Country Music Association Awards - 1987</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of the 1987 Country Music Association Awards hosted by Kenny Rogers. The Country Music Awards is presented by the Country Music Association and Kraft.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1987-10-12</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Various Artists</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Kenny Rogers introduces a group on nominees before getting cut off -- (00:07) Musical Introduction of the twenty-first Country Music Awards featuring Hummingbird (Restless Heart) [recorded excerpt] -- (00:35) Kenny Rogers introduces the nominees for the Country Music Awards -- (00:40) Hummingbird (Restless Heart) [recorded excerpt] -- (00:45) Oh Darlin' (The O'Kanes) [recorded excerpt] -- (00:50) Give Me One More Chance (Exile) [recorded excerpt] -- (00:55) Rockin' With the Rhythm of the Rain (The Judds) [recorded excerpt] -- (01:01) Too Many Times (Earl Thomas Conley &amp; Anita Pointer) [recorded excerpt] -- (01:09) Those Memories of You (Linda Ronstadt, Emmylou Harris and Dolly Parton) [recorded excerpt] -- (01:22) Daddy's Hands (Holly Dunn) [recorded excerpt] -- (01:29) Making Up for Lost Times (Gary Morris &amp; Crystal Gayle) [recorded excerpt] -- (01:35) Walk the Way the Wind Blows (Kathy Mattea) [recorded excerpt] -- (01:42) Hold On (Rosanne Cash) [recorded excerpt] -- (01:49) Midnight Girl/Sunset Town (Sweethearts of the Radio) [recorded excerpt] -- (01:54) Wine Colored Roses (George Jones) [recorded excerpt] -- (02:02) You've Got the Touch (Alabama) [recorded excerpt] -- (02:09) Forever and Ever, Amen (Randy Travis) [recorded excerpt] -- (02:17) A Long Line of Love (Michael Martin Murphey) [recorded excerpt] -- (2:23) Love Can't Ever Get Better Than This (Sharon White &amp; Ricky Skaggs) [recorded excerpt] -- (02:29) All My Ex's Live in Texas (George Strait) [recorded excerpt] -- (02:35) Meet Me in Montana (Marie Osmond &amp; Dan Seals) [recorded excerpt] -- (02:42) House of Blue Lights (Asleep at the Wheel) [recorded excerpt] -- (02:48) Brilliant Conversationalist (T. Graham Brown) [recorded excerpt] -- (02:58) Born to Boogie (Hank Williams, Jr.) [recorded excerpt] -- (03:04) Let the Music Lift You Up (Reba McEntire) [recorded excerpt] -- (03:18) Let the Music Lift You Up (Various Artists) [incomplete] -- (03:44) Rogers introduces nominees and commercial break -- (04:06) Kraft commercial playing quietly in the background as crowd converses amongst themselves -- (04:58) Various instruments prepare to play -- (06:04) Rogers introduces the Country Music Association Awards and the various performing acts; Rogers jokes about not being nominated -- (06:59) Rogers tells of how the five nominees for Entertainer of the Year will perform and introduces Randy Travis -- (07:15) Forever and Ever, Amen (Randy Travis) -- (10:57) Rogers introduces Dan Seals and Kathy Mattea -- (11:28) Seals and Mattea introduces the nominees for Vocal Group of the Year; the nominees are: Alabama, Asleep at the Wheel, Exile, The Judds, and Restless Heart -- (12:05) Mattea reveals the winner to be the Judds -- (12:28) Naomi Judd reflects on the importance of music in communication and Wynonna Judd shows her appreciation to each member of their success -- (14:09) Rogers introduces Rosanne Cash to announce the nominees for Single of the Year -- (14:32) Cash calls music miracles and introduces the nominees for Single of the Year; the nominees are: All My Ex's Live in Texas (George Strait), Can't Stop My Heart from Loving You (O'Kanes), Forever and Ever, Amen (Randy Travis), The Right Left Hand (George Jones), and Walk the Way the Wind Blows (Kathy Mattea) -- (15:20) Cash announces the winner: Forever and Ever, Amen (Randy Travis) -- (15:40) Travis thanks the lord amongst others and reflects on wanting to be apart of the Country Music Association Awards -- (16:33) Rogers introduces The Judds -- (16:46) Turn it Loose (The Judds) -- (20:32) Rogers introduces the commercial break -- (20:42) Low chatter can be heard -- (22:17) Rogers mentions how people are nominated and introduces Patty Loveless and Dwight Yoakam -- (23:18) Loveless announces the nominees for the Vocal Duo of the Year; the nominees are: Earl Thomas Conley and Anita Pointer, Crystal Gayle and Gary Morris, Michael Martin Murphey and Holly Dunn, Marie Osmond and Dan Seals, and Ricky Skaggs and Sharon White -- (23:56) Loveless and Yoakam announces the winner: Ricky Skaggs and Sharon White -- (24:34) Skaggs talks about having to practice, along with how he met White, and White breaks down in tears while thanking god and family -- (26:37) An unknown voice introduces the Oak Ridge Boys -- (27:00) The Oak Ridge Boys introduce the nominees for Album of the Year; the nominees are: Always &amp; Forever (Randy Travis), Ocean Front Property (George Strait), Trio (Linda Ronstadt, Emmylou Harris and Dolly Parton), What am I Going to Do (Reba McEntire), Wine Colored Roses (George Jones) -- (20:12) The Oak Ridge Boys announce the winner: Always &amp; Forever (Randy Travis) -- (28:34) Travis reaffirms his appreciation for family, song writers and the fans -- (29:28) Skaggs present the Horizon Award nominations; Skaggs starts by introducing Jamie O'Hara, Karen Kane -- (30:10) Can't Stop My Heart From Loving You (O'Kanes) -- (31:16) Skaggs introduces Holly Dunn -- (31:30) Daddy's Hands (Holly Dunn) -- (32:40) Skaggs introduces T. Graham Brown -- (32:57) She Couldn't Love Me Anymore (T. Graham Brown) -- (33:46) Skaggs introduces Kristine Arnold and Janis Oliver -- (34:00) Midnight Girl in a Sunset Town (Sweethearts of the Radio) -- (35:00) Skaggs introduces the last nominee Restless Heart-- (35:19) Why Does It Have to Be (Wrong or Right) (Restless Heart) -- (36:20) Skaggs reflects on winning the Horizon Award and introduces the winner: Holly Dunn -- (36:58) Dunn reflects on being unprepared and thanks who she considers family -- (38:22) An unknown voice tells of the upcoming acts -- (38:30) Indistinguishable chatter -- (41:18) Charley Pride introduces the nominees for Female Vocalist of the Year; the nominees are: Emmylou Harris, Kathy Mattea, Reba McEntire, Rosanne Cash, and Dolly Parton -- (42:08) Pride announces the winner: Reba McEntire -- (42:29) McEntire expresses her appreciation and reflects on her mother's support -- (43:46) Rogers reflects on what it takes to be Entertainer of the Year and introduces George Strait and his return to the University of Texas -- (44:26) All My Ex's Live in Texas (George Strait) -- (47:52) Rogers introduces Emmylou Harris (48:17) Harris introduces the nominees for Male Vocal Artist of the Year; the nominees are: George Jones, Ricky Skaggs, George Strait, Randy Travis, and Hank Williams Jr. -- (48:53) The winner is: Randy Travis -- (49:19) Travis says thanks and quickly recaps his other nominees -- (50:16) Rogers touches on the wardrobe of Ray Stevens and introduces Ray Stevens -- (50:51) Stevens reflects on song writing and jokes about his commercial songs -- (53:02) Stevens introduces the nominees for Song of the Year: All My Ex's Live in Texas (George Strait), Can't Stop My Heart From Loving You (O'Kanes), Daddy's Hands (Holly Dunn), Forever and Ever, Amen (Paul Overstreet and Don Schlitz), On the Other Hand (Don Schlitz) -- (53:59) The winner is: Forever and Ever, Amen (Paul Overstreet and Don Schlitz) -- (54:34) Schlitz expresses his surprise and next steps and Overstreet talks about his mother before addressing their song 'Forever and Ever, Amen' -- (56:53) An unknown voice introduces the upcoming acts -- (57:02) Indistinguishable chatter -- (59:03) Rogers introduces Reba McEntire -- (59:15) The Last One to Know (Reba McEntire) -- (1:02:36) Rogers discusses and introduces Anne Murray -- (1:03:16) Murray reflects on the Irving Waugh Award by speaking on Waugh's influence -- (1:05:09) Murray introduces the winner of the Irving Waugh Award: Frances Preston -- (1:05:30) Preston reflects on the Irving Waugh Award and shares the success with the industry members that helped her -- (1:06:55) Make No Mistake (She's Mine)" (Kenny Rogers &amp; Ronnie Milsap) -- (1:10:38) An unknown voice introduces the upcoming acts -- (1:10:52) Indistinguishable chatter -- (1:12:19) Rogers reveals Johnny Gimble won the Instrumentalist of the Year Award at the Grand Ole Opry and announces the nominees for the Music Video of the Year; the nominees are: A Long Line of Love (Michael Martin Murphey), Forever and Ever, Amen (Randy Travis), My Name is Bocephus (Hank Williams Jr.), Oh Darlin (O'Kanes), and What Am I Gonna Do About You (Reba McEntire) -- (1:13:03) The winner is: My Name is Bocephus (Hank Williams Jr.) -- (1:13:31) Williams Jr. jokes about quitting singing and thanks Van Halen while touching on expanding country music -- (1:14:24) Rogers tells a story and introduces Minnie Pearl -- (1:15:03) Pearl reflects on Rod Brasfield and recalls working with Brasfield -- (1:15:55) A comedy segment featuring Brasfield and Pearl is played -- (1:16:40) Pearl calls Brasfield kind and unselfish -- (1:17:50) Rogers introduces Disc Jockey of the Year winners: Rhubarb Jones, Eddie Edwards, and Gary Walker -- (1:18:28) Rogers introduces Hank Williams Jr. -- (1:18:36) Born to Boogie (Hank Williams Jr.) -- (1:20:05) Williams address country -- (1:20:16) Young Country (Various Artists) -- (1:23:27) Unknown voice introduces commercial break -- (1:23:39) Indistinguishable chatter -- (1:25:06) Rogers introduces Barbara Mandrell -- (1:25:31) Mandrell reflects on the performers for Entertainer of the Year and talks of the country music roots -- (1:25:45) Mandrell introduces the nominees for Artist of the Year; the nominees are: The Judds, Reba McEntire, George Strait, Randy Travis, and Hank Williams Jr. -- (1:26:55) Mandrell shrieks and announces the winner: Hank Williams Jr. -- (1:27:43) Williams jokes about the award, reflects on all the influence people in his life, and thanks the crowd -- (1:29:21) Rogers thanks Kraft and CBS and says goodnight -- (1:30:10) Young Country (Various Artists) </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>3.75 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1151_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1151</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-01-09</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Rogers, Kenny; Restless Heart (Musical group); O'Kanes (Musical group); Exile (Musical group); Judds (Musical group); Conley, Earl Thomas; Pointer, Anita; Ronstadt, Linda; Ronstadt, Linda, 1946-; Harris, Emmylou; Parton, Dolly; Parton, Dolly, 1946-; Dunn, Holly; Morris, Gary; Gayle, Crystal; Gayle, Crystal, 1951-; Mattea, Kathy; Cash, RosAnne; Sweethearts of the Rodeo (Musical group); Jones, George; Jones, George, 1931-2013; Alabama (Musical group); White, Sharon; White, Sharon, 1953 December 17-; Skaggs, Ricky; Murphey, Michael, 1945-; Osmond, Marie, 1959-; Seals, Dan; Strait, George, 1952-; McEntire, Reba; McEntire, Reba, 1955-; Murray, Anne; Murray, Anne, 1945-; Pearl, Minnie;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8361</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>