<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Ralph Emery Interviews Randy Travis</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording is from Ralph Emery's (entertainer) interview of Randy Travis (performer). Segment taped at the request of Warner Brothers and Warner West. Recording is from May 21, 1993.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1993-05-21</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Ralph Emery; Randy Travis</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Ralph Emery and Randy Travis discuss Wind in the Wire and Chuck Norris' helpful nature -- (05:39) Travis discusses his co-stars on Wind in the Wire -- (06:43) Emery discusses the program with his engineer -- (07:09) ""The Cowboy Boogie"" is told by Travis to be a song for the dance craze -- (08:45) Emery and Travis double back to Western music in Wind in the Wire -- (11:14) Travis and Emery reflect on the current 'Cowboy Singers' -- (11:44) ""Memories of Old Santa Fe"" is told, by Travis, to not be a part of the movie it was written for -- (12:30) Emery inquires about Travis' experience with 'Mexican cowboys' and the 'Tex Mex' sound  -- (13:28) Travis recalls a story about how ""Blue Mesa"" was going to be used for the movie -- (15:43) Travis discusses his Western upbringing and Roy Rogers -- (17:21) Travis' ""Too Gone Too Long"" is discussed -- (18:00) Burt Reynolds vocal performance on ""Down at the Old Corral"" is reflected on -- (19:40) ""Roamin' Wyoming"" is told by Travis to be used for the footage from South Dakota, and Emery and Travis discuss Travis' live performances -- (20:49) ""Wind in the Wire"" is told by Travis to be a song brought to the film from a Canadian recording group -- (22:58) Travis and Emery discuss the Western influence on children -- (23:32) ""Paniolo Country"" is told by Travis to be about the Hawaiian Cowboy -- (27:03) Marty Robbins and his influence are discussed in the decision to use ""Hula Hands"" -- (28:57) Emery inquires about Travis' decision to record ""Beyond the Reef"" and ""Hula Hands"" -- (29:54) Emery and Travis recall working at the Cayman Islands -- (31:44) Travis discusses the Pahinui Brothers with Emery, Kapena, and Willie K. -- (33:29) Emery inquires about the difference between country and western music -- (34:09) Emery and Travis reflect on Travis' first interests in country music -- (34:52) Travis and Emery discuss why Americans have an interest in cowboys -- (38:35) Travis recalls what Rogers had gifted him -- (39:27) Travis lists his favorite cowboys -- (40:30) Travis reveals he had been meeting with directors in California </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1348_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1348</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-04-03</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Emery, Ralph; Travis, Randy;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8743</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>