<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Ralph Emery On The Record with Brooks and Dunn - Part 1</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording from Ralph Emery's (entertainer) interview of Brooks and Dunn (performance group) for Ralph Emery: On the Record With Brooks and Dunn. Recording is performed in front of a live audience. Interview features a segment featuring Merle Haggard (performer). Recording is from May 02, 1995. Tape is labeled part 1.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1995-05-02</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Ralph Emery; Brooks and Dunn</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:35) Ralph Emery introduces Ronnie Dunn and Kix Brooks by listing their accolades -- (01:33) Emery inquires about where the idea for "Boot Scootin' Boogie," and Dunn attributes it to his time in Texas -- (03:34) Emery, Brooks, and Dunn discuss how "Boot Scootin' Boogie" was originally pitched to Asleep at the Wheel -- (04:17) Emery praises "Brand New Man;" additionally, Dunn reflects on the creative process behind "Brand New Man" -- (06:03) Emery inquires about the bet associated with "Brand New Man" -- (08:00) Brooks and Dunn discuss how they had first met at a lunch set up by Tim DuBois -- (11:01) Emery reads an interview stating that Brooks and Dunn were close to giving up -- (13:05) Emery inquires on how the personalities of Brooks and Dunn manifested during early shows -- (15:15) Emery inquires about how Brooks jumped off the stage at West Fest -- (16:37) Emery recalls a time where he skied with Reba McEntire wearing a Brooks and Dunn hat -- (19:00) Emery recants how Brooks and Dunn were unsure of the duration of their partnership -- (21:00) Emery plays a clip of DuBois talking about how Brooks and Dunn built their chemistry -- (21:50) Emery, Brooks, and Dunn joke about the intelligence of DuBois and 'Okies;' additionally, the chemistry behind Brooks  and Dunn is questioned by Emery -- (25:16) Emery asks about the special concerts Brooks and Dunn performs -- (29:11) Emery questions where Brooks and Dunn came across the expressions behind "Little Miss Honky Tonk" -- (30:00) Emery inquires about the injuries Brooks had inquired whilst moving around on stage; additionally, Emery asks about the multilingual expressions of "Rock My World" -- (33:01) Emery asks about Brooks' childhood background -- (35:19) Emery presents a couple pictures of Brooks on a horse as a child, and asks Brooks why he was named Kix -- (39:02) Emery has Brooks discuss Leon Brooks and Brooks and Dunn's similar interest in the oil business -- (41:03) Emery inquires about how Dunn's father performed with Sonny James; additionally, Emery asks Dunn to reflect on his father's definition of country music -- (44:56) Emery readdresses why Dunn had received a girl's bicycle for Christmas -- (47:44) Emery inquires about Brooks and Dunn's colligate performance -- (53:46) Emery and Brooks discuss the clothing store Brooks worked at -- (55:48) Emery inquires about Brooks' immediate family -- (58:25) Brooks reflects on how Leon Brooks would not see Brooks for quite some time -- (1:01:46) Emery invites Brooks to discuss Merle Haggard and if he would like to meet Haggard -- (1:02:23) Emery introduces Haggard, and Haggard expresses how he enjoys Brooks and Dunn's efforts -- (1:04:40) Haggard recalls how he was intimidated when he met Lefty Frizzell -- (1:05:59) Haggard recalls a time Elvis Presley wished to meet Haggard and Bonnie Owens</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1393_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1393</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-04-22</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Emery, Ralph; Brooks &amp; Dunn (Musical group); Haggard, Merle; Haggard, Merle, 1937-2016; Brooks, Kix; Dunn, Ronnie;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8820</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>