<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Hank Snow Benefit at the Grand Ole Opry - 1978-08-31 - Part 4</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of the Hank Snow Benefit Concert at the Grand Ole Opry. The segment is hosted by T. Tommy Cutrer (musician) and features performances by: Ralph Sloan and the Tennessee Travelers (musical group), Conway Twitty (musician), Loretta Lynn (musician) and Hank Snow (musician). The recording is from August 31, 1978. The tape is part four of four.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1978-08-31</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Ralph Sloan and the Tennessee Travelers; Loretta Lynn; Conway Twitty; Hank Snow</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Loretta Lynn reflects on beginning her musical career -- (01:35) Don't Come Home A-Drinkin' (Loretta Lynn) -- (03:51) Unidentified tune (Ralph Sloan and the Tennessee Travelers) -- (04:26) From Seven 'til Ten (Loretta Lynn and Conway Twitty) -- (07:04) Louisiana Woman, Mississippi Man (Loretta Lynn and Conway Twitty) -- (09:10) You're the Reason Our Kids are Ugly (Loretta Lynn and Conway Twitty) -- (11:49) God Bless American, Again (Loretta Lynn and Conway Twitty) -- (15:31) Unidentified tune (Ralph Sloan and the Tennessee Travelers) -- (16:15) T. Tommy Cutrer thanks Owen Bradley for Conway Twitty and Lynn's relationship; additionally, Cutrer compares the show's schedule to the Grand Ole Opry -- (20:40) I'm Movin' on (Hank Snow) -- (23:19) Hank Snow reflects on being nervous to perform -- (24:25) Paper Roses (Hank Snow) -- (27:35) Snow reflects on judging music -- (28:12) Hello Love (Hank Snow) -- (31:38) Ramblin' Road (Hank Snow) -- (34:05) Snow apologizes for his voice -- (34:52) I've Done at Least One Thing (Hank Snow) -- (38:10) Little Children are the Hope of the World (Hank Snow) -- (41:22) Cutrer expresses his thanks to everyone involved in the event -- (42:00) Unidentified tune (Ralph Sloan and the Tennessee Travelers) -- (43:29) Unidentified tune ([Unidentified]) -- (46:54) Unidentified tune ([Unidentified]) -- (47:50) Indistinguishable reversed audio</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1053_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1053</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-07-25</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Sloan, Ralph; Tennessee Travelers; Lynn, Loretta; Lynn, Loretta, 1932-; Twitty, Conway; Snow, Hank;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9283</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>