<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Mickey Gilley and Johnny Lee Live at the Ritz Theatre - 1981-01-24</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is from Ritz Theatre live show. The tape features a live performance of Mickey Gilley (musician) and Johnny Lee (musician). The Ritz Theatre live show is presented by Mort Cooperman, Bill McGivney and the WHN radio network. The recording of Mickey Gilley and Johnny Lee is from January 24, 1981.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1981-01-24</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Mickey Gilley; Johnny Lee</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Lee Arnold greets the crowd and introduces Mickey Gilley -- (01:28) Me and Bobby McGee (Mickey Gilley) -- (05:38) Gilley introduces his band -- (11:17) Bring Me Sunshine (Mickey Gilley) -- (13:15) Gilley introduces ""A Heartache Tomorrow (Or a Heartache Tonight)"" -- (14:17) A Heartache Tomorrow (Or a Heartache Tonight) (Mickey Gilley) -- (17:25) Gilley reflets on ""Lying Again"" -- (18:20) Lying Again (Mickey Gilley) -- (20:51) Gilley jokes about the neccessity of drinking songs -- (21:52) The More I Turn the Bottle Up, the Further Down I Go (Mickey Gilley) -- (25:12) The Power of Positive Drinkin' (Mickey Gilley) -- (27:17) True Love Ways (Mickey Gilley) -- (30:08) Gilley thanks the crowd -- (30:27) That's All That Matters to Me (Mickey Gilley) -- (33:11) Don't the Girls All Get Prettier at Closing Time (Mickey Gilley) -- (35:47) Gilley praises working with an unidentified artist -- (36:26) Stand by Me (Mickey Gilley) -- (39:42) Mamma's Don't Let Your Babies Grow Up to be Cowboys (Mickey Gilley) -- (43:09) Gilley praises WHN, and Johnny Lee jokes about a 'three bagger' -- (47:05) Lookin' for Love (Mickey Gilley) -- (50:58) illey reflects on 'cajan music' -- (51:43) Diggy Liggy Lo (Mickey Gilley) -- (54:28) Unidentified tune [feautring Mickey Gilley and Lee Arnold outro voiceover] (Mickey Gilley)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1558_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1558</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-07-03</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Lee, Johnny, 1946-; Gilley, Mickey;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9216</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>