<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Frances W. Preston Interviewed by John Lomax III  </dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of Frances W. Preston being interviewed by John Lomax III. The interview takes place on 1-19-1983          </dc:description>
<dc:date>1983-01-19</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Frances W. Preston</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Side One (0:00) -- Introduction by John Lomax, interview being conducted at the BMI offices. (1:10) -- John Lomax asks Frances W. Preston why Nashville is the world capital of music. (1:43) -- Frances W. Preston discusses why songwriters come to Nashville. (2:00) -- Frances W. Preston mentions Harlan Howard's generosity and desire to help newer songwriters. (4:22) -- Frances Preston discusses what the big appeal was for new songwriters coming to Nashville before the Grand Ole Opry. WSM provided several shows per week for NBC. Songwriters came to Nashville for radio performances due to decent pay. The larger orchestra leaders controlled a good bit of radio play and hiring - Beasley Smith &amp; Francis Craig. (7:19) -- Frances Preston discusses the musical origins of BMI. BMI first aimed for country music due to the lack of a collection agency in country music. (7:58) -- Frances Preston discusses Bob Burton's love for country music and his partnership with Frank Clement. (9:42) -- Frances Preston discusses meeting contacts from BMI when working at WSM. It was her idea to separate writers and artist awards. She convinced BMI to give their awards at a breakfast. The house band for these events consisted of Grady Martin, Owen Bradley, Chet Atkins, Bob Moore, Buddy Harman. Through these events, Frances Preston was asked to work for BMI. (16:24) -- Frances Preston mentions ASCAP's negative opinion of Elvis Presley's music. (17:50) -- Frances Preston speaks about the future of country music in Nashville and music industry. (19:38) -- Frances Preston speaks on the closeness of the Nashville music community. (20:30) -- Frances Preston speaks on the hard work of the Nashville music business community. (22:15) -- Frances Preston speaks on the rise of the singer/songwriter combination. (25:16) -- John Lomax asks about the growth of country music beginning in 1968. Frances Preston explains that it helped enormously when people and businesses stopped fighting about what is 'country.' (27:48) -- John Lomax asks about the competition between BMI and ASCAP. (28:38) -- Frances Preston discusses that BMI's policy is to not solicit an ASCAP writer to join BMI. However, when ASCAP first came to Nashville, they tried to poach BMI's writers. (28:57) -- "Quite different from what our policy is, which is to not go after the ASCAP writer, but to keep our own writers happy" - Frances Preston.</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>audio cassette, compact;</dc:format>
<dc:format>1.75 ips;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CAS4682_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>CAS4682</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-09-03</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Preston, Frances Williams, 1928-2012;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9477</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>