<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Ralph Emery Interviews Irlene Mandrell and Louise Mandrell - Parts 4 and 5</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording is from Ralph Emery's (entertainer) interview of Louise Mandrell (performer) and Irlene Mandrell (performer) for the Ralph Emery Show. Tape labeled parts 4 and 5. Recording is from April 10, 1984.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1984-04-10</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Ralph Emery; Irlene Mandrell; Louise Mandrell</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:02) Ralph Emery introduces Louise Mandrell and Irlene Mandrell, and Emery inquires about any upcoming projects -- (04:33) Emery inquires about which instruments Louise plays and if she continues to perform White Rain commercials -- (06:38) Emery invites Irlene and Louise to discuss "Fire in His Eyes" -- (08:02) Emery inquires if the sisters had heard of Bill Medley and "I Still Do" -- (08:32) Emery reveals that Willie Nelson was about to dub over some Hank Williams recordings -- (09:29) Emery inquires whether or not Louise had performed the fiddle on one of her tracks -- (10:51) Emery inquires about the sister's family dynamic -- (11:50) Emery encourages Irlene to talk about her struggle to stop smoking and Louise's attempt to quit chocolate -- (14:00) Emery inquires about the endeavors of Mary Mandrell -- (14:45) Louise praises the efforts of Buddy Killen "Reunited" -- (15:39) Emery says goodbye to the Mandrell sisters and the audience -- (16:15) Emery introduces Louise and Irlene -- (16:43) Emery invites Louise to discuss "This Beds Not Big Enough -- (18:12) Emery questions why Louise chose to enter the game market with The Louise Mandrell Trivia game -- (20:32) Emery tells Irlene that he often has his guest talk about their childhood and asks Irlene to recall one -- (23:39) Irlene recalls working for Waylon Jennings for the Waylon Jennings Greatest Hits album -- (25:03) Emery has Louise and Irlene recall how they would go along with Barbara Mandrell on her dates -- (27:29) Louise shy's away from Emery's introduction of "Goodbye Heartache" -- (28:03) Emery inquires about Louise's modeling career and Louise's high energy -- (30:11) Emery inquires Irlene about her modeling career -- (31:05) Emery, Louise, and Irlene discuss if they have ever been asked to pose in risque scenes -- (31:55) Emery inquires whether or not the Mandrell Show was still in circulation -- (32:54) Emery expresses his thanks and gives his guarantee of future endeavors; Irlene inquires about whether or not she was invited to go to Aspen -- (34:12) Emery, Irlene, and Louise say their goodbyes</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1366_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1366</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-04-09</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Emery, Ralph; Mandrell, Irlene; Mandrell, Louise;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8769</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>