<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Renfro Valley Gatherin' - 1954-02-07</dc:title>
<dc:description>Renfro Valley Gatherin' program, 1954-02-07, parts 1 and 2, as recorded by WLAC (Nashville, Tenn.) Featuring announcer Ken Meeker, host John Lair, and performers Rural and Flossie [unconfirmed], as well as other unidentified performers. A CBS syndication originating at WHAS (Louisville, Ky.)</dc:description>
<dc:date>1954-02-07</dc:date>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Test tones -- Opening statement (Ken Meeker) -- Opening theme [Take Me Back To Renfro Valley] -- Opening statement (John Lair) -- John Lair dedicates the program to Abraham Lincoln and introduces the next tune  -- How Tedious And Tasteless The Hours (all) -- Postum commercial (John Lair) -- I'm A Pilgrim (Rural and Flossie) [unconfirmed] -- John Lair reads off the list of birthdays -- Lair talks about the Renfro Valley Bugle, his book, and some history about Abraham Lincoln -- Rock Me To Sleep Mother ([Unidentified]) -- John Lair talks more about Lincoln and introduces the next tune -- Twenty Years Ago ([Unidentified]) -- Skip To My Lou (incomplete) -- Skip To My Lou (incomplete) -- Oh Sister Phoebe (all) -- John Lair talks -- When Adam Was Created ([Unidentified]) (incomplete) -- Lair talks -- Gentle Annie ([Unidentified]) -- Lair talks -- [Unidentified tune] -- Lair talks -- [Unidentified tune] -- Lair talks more about Lincoln -- Rock Me To Sleep Mother ([Unidentified]) -- Bran Flakes commercial (Lair)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-0309_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-0309</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-02-27</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WLAC (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); Renfro Valley Gathering (Radio program); WHAS (Radio station : Louisville, Ky.); Meeker, Ken (Announcer); Lair, John;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/6905</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>