<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Louisiana Hayride - 1958-09-27 - KWKH</dc:title>
<dc:description>Excerpt from a Louisiana Hayride radio program segment, featuring Norm Bale (announcer), Frank Page (announcer, host), Ferlin Husky (performer), Margie Singleton (performer), Charlie Walker (performer), Tony Douglas (performer), and Dobber Johnson (performer) on September 27, 1958 on radio station KWKH (Shreveport, La.)</dc:description>
<dc:date>1958-09-27</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Ferlin Husky; Margie Singleton; Charlie Walker; Tony Douglas; Dobber Johnson; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Test tones -- Opening theme -- Opening statement (Norm Bale) -- Opening statement (Frank Page) -- Frank Page introduces Ferlin Husky -- I Will (Ferlin Husky) -- Husky and Page talk -- I Feel Better All Over (Ferlin Husky) -- Page introduces Margie Singleton -- I Can't Help Wondering (Margie Singleton) -- Page introduces Charlie Walker -- Charlie Walker talks -- Pick Me Up On Your Way Down (Charlie Walker) -- Tell Her Lies And Feed Her Candy (Charlie Walker) -- Page introduces Tony Douglas -- World In My Arms (Tony Douglas) -- Page introduces Simon Crum (Ferlin Husky) -- Cuzz Yore So Sweet (Ferlin Husky as Simon Crum) -- Country Music Is Here To Stay (Ferlin Husky as Simon Crum) -- Bill Cheatham (Dobber Johnson fiddle)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-0049_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-0049</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2017-08-24</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Louisiana hayride (Radio program); KWKH (Radio station : Shreveport, La.); Page, Frank; Bale, Norm; Husky, Ferlin; Singleton, Margie; Walker, Charlie, 1926-2008; Douglas, Tony;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/5609</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>