<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Tandy Rice Interviewed by Bob Allen in 1978 Side One</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of Bob Allen interviewing Tandy Rice. The recording takes place on 8-18-78.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1978-08-18</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Tandy Rice</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Side One - (0:04) -- Bob Allen introduction about his article on Top Billing. (0:46) -- Bob Allen asks about the first agencies Tandy Rice worked for. (2:40) -- Tandy Rice discusses starting out working as a publicist. (4:23) -- Tandy Rice about the relationship between agents and artists. (5:17) -- Tandy Rice on the "agency explosion." (6:59) -- Tandy Rice describes that a publicity department of a company reflects the company's character. (9:02) -- Tandy Rice mentions that he went into business for himself as a publicist for five years. (9:19) -- Tandy Rice was offered a job by Showbiz Incorporated, Bill Graham. (10:30) -- Tandy Rice describes being trained by Bill Graham. (12:41) -- Tandy Rice speaks about Showbiz Incorporated growing into a "General Motors of the TV industry." (13:12) -- Tandy Rice speaks about Bill Graham starting Top Billing incorporated. His first client was Porter Wagoner. (16:07) -- Tandy Rice tells the story of how he bought Top Billing. (18:00) -- Tandy Rice introduces his nephew to Bob Allen. (20:18) -- Interview continues, Tandy Rice tells a story about going into debt for the first time. (22:45) -- Tandy Rice speaks about the beginnings of the Top Billing offices. (23:20) -- Bob Allen asks how Tandy Rice maintained Top Billing's clientele. (26:41) -- Bob Allen asks how many people Tandy Rice currently represents. (26:55) -- Bob Allen asks Tandy Rice what the future of Top Billing looks like. (28:30) -- Tandy Rice wants his own building for Top Billing and a west coast specialist. (29:36) -- Bob Allen asks Tandy Rice to define management. (32:52) -- Bob Allen asks Tandy Rice about the importance of artist management. (34:56) -- Tandy Rice speaks about an artist managing themselves. (36:26) -- Tandy Rice explains his opinion on a story written by Bob Allen. (37:28) -- Tandy Rice speaks about the Nashville agency scene. (39:30) -- Bob Allen asks Tandy Rice about the technology used in his business. (40:33) -- Bob Allen asks Tandy Rice about the Philadelphia marketplace. (41:51) -- Bob Allen asks Tandy Rice to describe the international marketplace. (43:30) -- Bob Allen asks Tandy Rice about whether the national market's potential has been fully unlocked. (44:27) -- Bob Allen asks Tandy Rice about the business factor and relevance of television. </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>audio cassette, compact;</dc:format>
<dc:format>1.75 ips;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CAS4664_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>CAS4664</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-08-27</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Rice, Tandy;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9423</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>