<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Mississippi Minstrels - 1949-06-10 - Part 3</dc:title>
<dc:description>CBS syndication of KMOX (St. Louis, IL) radio program Mississippi Minstrels, originally broadcast June 10, 1949, part 3. Featuring 'interlocutor' Lambert Kaiman; the Mississippi Minstrel Band directed by Professor Stanley Daugherty; comedians Harry Fender, and Mose (played by Al Bland); and musicians Charlie Ackerson, Jerry Whittington (name unconfirmed), and the Magnolia Quartet. Written and produced by Al Bland.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1949-06-10</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Magnolia Quartet</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(0:00) The Magnolia Quartet [unconfirmed] performs "There'll Be A Hot Time In The Old Town Tonight" [incomplete] / (1:07) [Unidentified announcer] performs the closing statements with the closing theme playing underneath</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>16 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR000804_2</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>TR000804</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2007-04-23</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>CBS Inc.; KMOX (Radio station : Saint Louis, Mo.); Mississippi Minstrels (Radio program); Kaiman, Lambert; Ackerson, Charlie; Magnolia Quartet; Daugherty, Stanley; Mississippi Minstrel Band; Fender, Harry; Bland, Al</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/2107</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>