<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Cowboy Slim Rinehart radio show - Programs 10, 11, 12 - XEG</dc:title>
<dc:description>Cowboy Slim Rinehart radio show, featuring Cowboy Slim Rinehart (host, performer) listed as programs #10, #11, and #12, broadcast on radio station XEG (Monterrey, Mexico.)</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Cowboy Slim Rinehart</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Roaming Cowboy (Cowboy Slim Rinehart) -- (01:12) Cowboy Slim Rinehart expresses his thanks to the audience -- (01:34) You Are My Sunshine (Cowboy Slim Rinehart) -- (03:33) Pay Me No Mind (Cowboy Slim Rinehart) -- (05:29) Rinehart thanks the audience and asks the audience to write-in song requests -- (06:03) Punchin' the Dough (Cowboy Slim Rinehart) -- (08:54) Carry Me Back to the Lone Prairie [featuring Cowboy Slim Rinehart outro] (Cowboy Slim Reinhart) -- (09:48) Roaming Cowboy (Cowboy Slim Rinehart) -- (10:54) Cowboy Slim Rinehart expresses his thanks to the audience -- (11:30) I Hang My Head and Cry (Cowboy Slim Rinehart) -- (13:24) You Were My Sunshine (Cowboy Slim Rinehart) -- (15:44) Rinehart expresses his thanks to the audience -- (16:03) I Ain't Gonna Love Anymore (Cowboy Slim Rinehart) -- (17:49) Carry Me Back to the Lone Prairie [featuring Cowboy Slim Rinehart outro] (Cowboy Slim Reinhart) -- (19:01) Roaming Cowboy (Cowboy Slim Rinehart) -- (20:07) Cowboy Slim Rinehart expresses his thanks to the audience and asks the audience to write in song requests -- (20:35) There's a Range Way Up Yonder in the Sky (Cowboy Slim Rinehart) -- (22:16) Letter From Home Sweet Home (Cowboy Slim Rinehart) -- (24:32) Rinehart thanks the requests from the audience -- (24:56) Blue Ridge Mountain Blues (Cowboy Slim Rinehart) -- (27:36) Carry Me Back to the Lone Prairie [featuring Cowboy Slim Rinehart outro] (Cowboy Slim Reinhart)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-0231_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-0231</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-09-03</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Rinehart, Cowboy Slim, 1911-1948;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/6338</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>