<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Various interviews - Biff Collie - Nashville DJ Convention - 1962-11-08</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of interviews with Hank Locklin (performer), Tim Spencer (performer), Ira Louvin (performer), Jimmy C. Newman (performer), Leroy Van Dyke (performer), Brenda Lee (performer), Jean Shepard (performer), Hawkshaw Hawkins (performer), Speedy West (performer), Bill Carlisle (performer), Carl Butler (performer), Sonny James (performer), and Bobby Lord (performer), conducted by Biff Collie at the Nashville DJ Convention on November 8, 1962.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1962-11-08</dc:date>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Biff Collie talks about working at KLEE as a disc jockey -- Hank Locklin talks about his home being in Florida -- Locklin talks about playing on the Grand Ole Opry and collecting phonographs -- Locklin talks about building a cattle ranch in Florida -- Collie concludes the interview -- Collie introduces Tim Spencer -- Tim Spencer talks about being a founding member of the Sons Of The Pioneers and now working for RCA Victor -- Collie introduces Ira Louvin -- Ira Louvin talks about an upcoming record release -- Jimmy C. Newman talks about the convention -- Collie talks about how exhausting the convention can be -- Newman talks about some of his new records -- Collie concludes the interview -- Collie introduces Leroy Van Dyke -- Leroy Van Dyke talks about the convention and how big it is -- Van Dyke talks about touring schedules -- Van Dyke talks about finally being successful from selling records and touring -- Van Dyke talks about Shelby Singleton at Mercury Records -- Collie concludes the interview -- Collie introduces Brenda Lee -- Brenda Lee talks about being on vacation and visiting the convention -- Collie introduces Jean Shepard -- Jean Shepard talks about her son and his love for the guitar -- Hawkshaw Hawkins talks about his records -- Collie introduces Speedy West -- Speedy West talks about working for Fender and recording with Capitol Records -- Collie concludes the interview -- Collie introduces Bill Carlisle -- Carlisle talks about being a joker and trying to act serious -- Carlisle talks about winning an award at the convention -- Carlisle talks about being in the business for 25 years -- Carlisle talks about recording with Cliff for Brunswick Records -- Collie introduces Carl Butler -- Carl Butler talks about his new records -- Butler talks about being at the convention -- Collie introduces Sonny James -- Sonny James talks about being on the road and how good an idea it is for Biff to carry around his recorder -- Sonny James talks about going to record with some other convention attendees -- James talks about a new album -- Collie introduces Bobby Lord -- Lord talks about touring for five weeks at a time -- Collie concludes the interview</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-7-03989_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-7-03989</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-07-03</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Disc jockey festival; Collie, Biff; Locklin, Hank, 1918-2009; Spencer, Tim, 1908-1974; Louvin, Ira, 1924-1965; Newman, Jimmy C.; Van Dyke, Leroy, 1929-; Lee, Brenda, 1944-; Shepard, Jean, 1933-2016; Hawkins, Hawkshaw, 1921-1963; West, Speedy; Carlisle, Bill; Butler, Carl; James, Sonny; Lord, Bobby;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/7752</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>