<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Performance - Shetland Island country music - 2004-05-27</dc:title>
<dc:description>Performances by artists from the Shetland Islands from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on May 27, 2004.  Performers include Arthur Pottinger, Jordy Pottinger, May Fraser, Mackie Sutherland. </dc:description>
<dc:date>2004-05-27</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Arthur Pottinger; Jordy Pottinger; Mackie Sutherland; May Fraser; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Recording begins in progress.  Professor James Akenson from Tennessee Tech introduces Danny Allen.  Introduction of Arthur Pottinger.  It Don't Hurt Anymore (Arthur Pottinger) -- Waiting For A Train (Arthur Pottinger) -- A Message From The Tradewinds (Arthur Pottinger) -- Hey, Good Lookin' (Arthur Pottinger) -- Promises (Arthur Pottinger) -- Never Knew Lonely (Arthur Pottinger) -- Crazy (Arthur Pottinger) -- Put Me On The Trail To Carolina (Jordy Pottinger) -- Butter On The Bow (Jordy Pottinger) -- Unidentified Scottish Hornpipe (Mackie Sutherland-mandolin) -- Comments from Carl Fraser -- Forever Has Come To An End (May Fraser) -- Low And Lonely (Mackie Sutherland) -- The Pathway Of Teardrops (May Fraser) -- You'll Never Be The Sun (May Fraser) -- Miss the Mississippi And You (May Fraser).</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>RDAT digital tape;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RS.2014.051</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RDAT-0018</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2017-02-08</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Pottinger, Arthur; Pottinger, Jordy; Sutherland, Mackie; Fraser, May; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);  Shetland Islands Area (Scotland);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/4895</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>