<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>WHN Guest Disc Jockey - Olivia Newton-John - 1977-11-18</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is from Olivia Newton-John's (musician) performance as disc jockey for WHN Studios. The performance was on November 18, 1977. The tape was created by the WHN radio network.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1977-11-18</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Olivia Newton-John</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Unidentified intro jingle [featuring unidentified voiceover] ([Unidentified]) -- (00:09) Olivia Newton-John introduces the WHN radio show -- (00:17) Long Way From Memphis (Merle Haggard) -- (02:38) Newton-John introduces "Please Mr. Please" -- (02:52) Please Mr. Please (Olivia Newton-John) -- (06:10) Newton-John performs a weather report -- (06:34) Wool Bureau commercial spot hosted by an unidentified host -- (07:02) Iberia Airlines commercial spot hosted by an unidentified host -- (08:05) Derio Oldsmobile commercial spot hosted by Newton-John -- (09:00) Savings Banks commercial spot hosted by an unidentified host -- (09:30) Newton-John introduces Larry Gatlin -- (09:36) Love is Just a Game (Larry Gatlin) -- (13:06) Don't Stop Believin' (Olivia Newton-John) -- (16:15) Newton-John invites the audience to call in; additionally, Newton-John performs a He-Man commercial spot -- (17:10) Metropolitan Life tune [featuring voiceover] ([Unidentified]) -- (18:11) I'm Knee Deep in Lovin' You (Dave and Sugar) -- (20:42) Newton-John praises Dave and Sugar and reflects on her promotional trip -- (21:18) Have You Ever Been Mellow (Olivia Newton-John) -- (24:33) Newton-John performs a Goods Super Sale [unconfirmed] commercial spot -- (25:33) Hankel commercial spot hosted by Otto Hankel -- (26:32) How Can I Leave You Again [excerpt] [featuring Newton-John and unidentified voiceover] (John Denver) -- (27:37) WHN commercial spot hosted by an unidentified host -- (28:11) Newton-John -- (28:21) Don't Let Me Touch You (Marty Robbins) -- (31:07) Newton-John invites people to phone in -- (31:36) If You Love Me Let Me Know (Olivia Newton-John) -- (34:37) Gimble's Warehouse commercial spot hosted by Newton-John -- (35:25) Park's Sausage commercial spot hosted by an unidentified host -- (35:35) Heineken jingle [featuring unidentified voiceover] ([unidentified]) -- (36:05) Banker's Trust commercial spot hosted by an unidentified host -- (37:05) Newton-John and an unidentified voice talk via the phone -- (37:30) Come a Little Bit Closer (Johnny Duncan and Janie Fricke) -- (40:45) Let it Shine (Olivia Newton-John) -- (43:05) Newton-John reflects on being in Nashville recently and Christmas -- (43:47) Ford commercial spot hosted by an unidentified host -- (44:47) Generic Prescription Drug commercial spot hosted by Newton-John -- (45:37) Castro commercial spot hosted by an unidentified host -- (46:46) I Got the Hoss (Mel Tillis) -- (49:36) Wilabee's [unconfirmed] commercial spot hosted by an unidentified host -- (50:35) John Conlee performs a radio spot of the current state of the Middle East -- (52:10) Lem Stone reflects on the state of Israel -- (53:12) Conlee finishes the international report -- (53:26) Ann Compton discusses the state of the White House's relationship with Israel -- (54:05) American Airlines commercial spot hosted by Conlee -- (55:11) Conlee performs a current state of the nation report -- (55:57) Patricia Harris reflects on the Urban Response policies, and Conlee performs a weather report -- (57:28) Newton-John says goodbye to the audience -- (57:46) I Honestly Love You (Olivia Newton-John)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1571_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1571</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-06-26</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Newton-John, Olivia;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9174</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>