<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Ralph Emery Interviews Chet Atkins - Parts 1, 2 and 3</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording is from Ralph Emery's (entertainer) interview of Chet Atkins (performer) for the Ralph Emery Show. Tape labeled parts 1, 2 and 3. Recording is from May 03, 1983.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1983-05-03</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Ralph Emery; Chet Atkins</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Chet Atkins radio spot for the Ralph Emery Show -- (00:10) Atkins radio spot for the Ralph Emery Show -- (00:24) Wings of an Eagle [excerpt] (Bobby Goldsboro) [Featuring Ralph Emery introduction voiceover] -- (01:02) Emery inquires about Atkins' health, and Atkins possibly touring -- (01:54) Emery and Atkins introduce "Yakety Axe" -- (02:23) Atkins says praise of Janie Fricke while introducing "He's a Heartache (Looking For a Place to Happen)" -- (02:53) Emery invites Atkins to reflect on the idea of being a 'star;' additionally, Emery inquires about the tag CGP Atkins places on his album -- (04:37) Emery invites Atkins to reflect on his first album with RCA: Work it Out With Chet Atkins -- (06:40) Emery questions Atkins about his ability to play duel tracks -- (08:03) Emery invites Atkins to recall talking to Leona Williams and Merle Haggard while introducing "We're Strangers Again" -- (08:39) Emery asks Atkins about the first time he met Dolly Parton -- (09:21) Emery questions the process Atkins took for transferring from RCA to CBS, and Atkins leaving his guitar company -- (11:41) Emery chooses to bring up Working it Out With Chet Atkins again; additionally, Atkins' health is discussed -- (14:20) Emery and Atkins discuss the need for walking -- (15:31) Emery inquires about the first group to release "Oh Baby Mine" -- (16:08) Emery inquires about the background vocalists for "Freight Train" -- (17:05) Wings of an Eagle [excerpt] (Bobby Goldsboro) [Featuring Ralph Emery and Chet Atkins outro voiceover] -- (18:17) Wings of an Eagle [excerpt] (Bobby Goldsboro) [Featuring Ralph Emery and Chet Atkins introduction voiceover] -- (18:52) Emery and Atkins discuss Atkins' discomfort to being a member of the Country Music Hall of Fame -- (19:59) Emery introduces Atkins' CBS album -- (21:11) Emery has Atkins' discuss the various ways one can cause an instrument to 'talk' -- (23:20) Emery and Atkins describe the 'Chase' and "The Streakin' Melody" -- (23:55) Emery reads a verse of Atkins to him, and Atkins remembers Parton -- (27:19) Emery inquires about the amount of Willie Nelson's songs that Atkins produced; additionally, Emery dives into the contents of Atkins' album -- (29:05) Emery inquires about where Atkins grew up, and if Atkins almost died as a child -- (30:58) Emery inquires about the peculiarities of musicians -- (33:03) Emery asks about Atkins about his greatest thrills -- (35:01) Emery praises Atkins' version of "Snow Bird" -- (35:57) Wings of an Eagle [excerpt] (Bobby Goldsboro) [Featuring Ralph Emery and Chet Atkins outro voiceover] -- (37:13) Wings of an Eagle [excerpt] (Bobby Goldsboro) [Featuring Ralph Emery and Chet Atkins introduction voiceover] -- (37:40) Emery and Atkins discuss Jim Glaser and Atkins' "Frog Kissing" -- (41:09) Emery and Atkins reflect on the first time Atkins was asked to perform on Garrison Keillor's radio show; additionally, both introduce "Country Gentleman" -- (42:57) Emery inquires about the possibility of Atkins working on albums, including Work It Out With Chet Atkins -- (44:56) Emery inquires about the words "I Can't Sleep" on the back of his album, and how writers sensationalize topics when talking about Elvis Presley -- (47:30) Emery inquires about if Atkins knows about Michael Murphey -- (48:11) Emery praises Atkins when discussing "Cascade" -- (49:09) Wings of an Eagle [excerpt] (Bobby Goldsboro) [Featuring Ralph Emery and Chet Atkins outro voiceover]</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1373_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1373</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-04-11</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Emery, Ralph; Atkins, Chet;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8785</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>