<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Magnolia Blossoms - 1940-04-28 - Part 3</dc:title>
<dc:description>NBC syndication Magnolia Blossoms, originating from WSM. Originally broadcast 1940-04-28, part 3. End of program that featured performances by the Fisk Jubilee Singers led by Mrs James Myers (Henrietta Myers), contralto soloist Emma Cornelia Pitt (spelling unconfirmed), and an orchestra led by Pietro Brescia.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1940-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Fisk Jubilee Singers; Pietro Brescia Orchestra</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(0:00) [Blank] / (0:38) Announcer performs the closing statements and credits over the closing theme song</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>16 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR001271_2</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>TR001271</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2014-11-05</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); National Broadcasting Company; Magnolia blossoms (Radio program); Jubilee Singers; Brescia, Pietro; Myers, Henrietta Helena Crawley, 1878-1968</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/547</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>