<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Ray Whitley home recordings - 1941</dc:title>
<dc:description>Various home recordings from Ray Whitley, including messages to his wife Kay Whitley, his daughter Judy Kay, and Fred and Lorene Rose. Recordings are from the years 1941, 1942, 1943, 1945, and 1949</dc:description>
<dc:date>1941</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Ray Whitley; Fred Rose; Oklahoma Wranglers</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Ray Whitley gives a message of well-wishes to Kay Whitley, along with Fred Rose, Lorene Rose, Ken Card, Jesse Ashlock, and other friends and family members, during Thanksgiving of 1942 -- (02:49) Fred and Lorene Rose give a message of well-wishes to Ray and Kay Whitley, during late-1943 -- (05:45) Fred and Lorene Rose gives a message of well-wishes to the Whitleys -- (08:40) Ray Whitley introduces the tune -- Old MacDonald Had A Farm (Ray Whitley, various) (incomplete) -- (10:32) Ray Whitley, Fred Rose, and members of the Oklahoma Wranglers give a message of well-wishes to Kay and Judy Kay Whitley, in late 1945 -- (13:20) Roundup In The Sky (Ray Whitley, Fred Rose, Oklahoma Wranglers) [unconfirmed] -- (15:15) Lee "Lasses" White gives Ray and Kay Whitley a message of well-wishes and sings an unidentified tune, in 1941 when Kay was expecting the birth of their daughter Judy Kay</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 quarter track</dc:format>
<dc:format>3 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-7-00800_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-7-00800</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-02-07</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Whitley, Ray; Whitley, Kay; Rose, Fred; Rose, Fred, 1897-1954; Card, Ken, 1912-1990; Oklahoma Wranglers (Musical group); Ashlock, Jesse, 1915-1976; Ashlock, Jesse;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8469</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>