<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>WNOX news report -- Art Linkletter's House Party (opening)</dc:title>
<dc:description>WNOX news broadcast with commercials. End of disc contains the beginning of Art Linkletter's House Party, with guest Pierre J. Huss (chief of the Hearst Headline Service Bureau at the United Nations). Circa March 1962.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1962-03</dc:date>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Mentholatum commercial -- International news report -- Ex-Lax commercial -- International and Washington news report -- Ammens Medicated Powder commercial -- Good Housekeeping Magazine commercial -- Local news report -- Weather report -- WNOX Station ID -- Opening statement (Art Linkletter) -- Mum Deodorant commercial -- Art Linkletter interviews Pierre J. Huss (incomplete)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>10 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR000783_2</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>TR000783</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2007-03-27</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WNOX (Radio station : Knoxville, Tenn.); CBS Inc.; House party (Radio program); Linkletter, Art, 1912-2010; Huss, Pierre J. (Pierre John), 1903-</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/2168</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>