<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Various interviews - Biff Collie</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of interviews with Grandpa Jones (performer), George Jones (performer), Cindy Walker (performer), Claude Gray (performer), Archie Campbell (performer), Flatt &amp; Scruggs (performer), Harlan Howard (songwriter), and George Hamilton IV (performer), conducted by Biff Collie.</dc:description>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Biff Collie introduces Grandpa Jones -- Grandpa Jones talks about all the records he has out - Jones talks about his yodeling -- Jones talks about being from Niagara, KY -- Jones talks about a time he was in the hospital at the same time as Stoney Cooper, because of a gull bladder removal -- Jones jokes about still buying his groceries on credit -- Jones talks about the year that he sold the most records, from 1949 to 1953 -- Collie concludes the interview -- Collie introduces George Jones -- George Jones talks about being from Beaumont, TX -- Jones talks about singing for as far back as he can remember -- Jones talks about picking up the guitar as a young child -- Jones talks about when he decided to make a career out of music -- Jones talks about his first recording coming out in 1954 -- Jones talks about preferring to sing country ballads -- Jones talks about singing duets with female vocalists -- Jones talks about a restaurant he owns -- Collie concludes the interview -- Collie introduces Cindy Walker -- Cindy Walker talks about knowing Biff for a long while -- Walker talks about Collie being a wonderful person and a great disc jockey -- Walker talks about some hit songs she has written -- Walker talks about randomly running into Biff and recording this interview -- Collie concludes the interview -- Collie introduces Claude Gray -- Claude Gray talks about thinking that Collie was a middle aged person based off his voice, but he is really younger -- Collie says he has always gotten that -- Gray talks about being taller than he looks in photos -- Collie concludes the interview -- Collie concludes the interview -- Collie introduces Archie Campbell -- Campbell talks about still playing on the Grand Ole Opry and working for a publishing company -- Collie concludes the interview -- Collie introduces Flatt &amp; Scruggs -- Flatt talks about playing for various age groups and their reactions -- Flatt talks about the content of their music (incomplete) -- Biff Collie introduces George Hamilton IV and Harlan Howard -- Howard talks about playing with George Hamilton IV -- Hamilton talks about his touring and traveling through Canada -- Hamilton talks about Biff inspiring him to keep certain records -- Hamilton talks about his family and having a George Hamilton V at home -- Hamilton talks about his family name being passed down, ever since the 1800s -- Collie concludes the interview</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-7-03986_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-7-03986</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-06-29</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Collie, Biff; Jones, Grandpa, 1913-1998; Jones, George, 1931-2013; Walker, Cindy, 1918-2006; Gray, Claude; Campbell, Archie, 1914-1987; Flatt, Lester, 1914-1979; Scruggs, Earl, 1924-2012; Hamilton, George, IV, 1937-;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/7749</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>