<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Songwriter Session - Tony Arata - 2017-04-08</dc:title>
<dc:description>Performance by Tony Arata from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on April 8, 2017.  Includes questions from the audience. </dc:description>
<dc:date>2017-04-08</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Tony Arata; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Walk-in Music  / (02:44) Opening comments and introduction of Tony Arata by Abi Tapia / 05:43) Opening comments by Tony (05:45) Performs Night By Night / (06:06) Tony talks about his arriving in Nashville / (09:19) Here I Am / (12:23) Tony talks about meeting Pat Alger and Trisha Yearwood / (14:32) Performs Sing You Back To Me / (17:36) Tony talks about Suzy Bogguss / (18:40) Performs Love Every Time / (20:55) Tony tells Chet Atkins story / (21:34) Tony talks about how he got to Nashville and first meeting with Garth Brooks / (26:15) Performs The Dance / (29:33) Answers question about lyrics and how his background in journalism inform his lyric writing / 32:39)  Answers question and changing and/or adding lyrics for recordings / (35:33) Hardest lesson learned when he moved to Nashville / (36:43) Talks about Pat Alger and performs My Mother's Son / (39:27) Talks about his parents and his wife / (41:08) Performs unidentified song likely titled She's The Difference / </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(43:35) Tony talks about his first experience at an open mic night in Nashville and moving to Nashville  / (46:11) Performs Hand Full Of Dust / 48:46 Closing comments by Tony Arata / (48:59) Walk-out Music / (51:24) FILE END</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/24;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0020</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2018-05-17</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Arata, Tony; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/7454</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>