<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Velvo cough syrup - Webb Pierce advertisement - 1957-08</dc:title>
<dc:description>Radio advertisements for Velvo cough syrup voiced by Webb Pierce and Dave Overton in August of 1957.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1957-08</dc:date>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Dave Overton talks -- Dave Overton introduces Webb Pierce -- Webb Pierce talks -- Webb Pierce advertises Velvo cough syrup -- Dave Overton advertises Velvo cough syrup -- Webb Pierce talks -- Webb Pierce advertises Velvo cough syrup -- Dave Overton advertises Velvo cough syrup</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>12 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR002989_2</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>TR002989</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2017-06-13</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Noble-Dury &amp; Associates, Inc.; Pierce, Webb, 1921-1991; Overton, Dave;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/5247</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>