<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Bobby Bare phone interview - 1975-01-24</dc:title>
<dc:description>Phone interview with Bobby Bare (performer) conducted by Joe Suglia, with an unidentified radio station in Kalamazoo, Michigan.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1975-01-24</dc:date>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Magnavox television set commercial (incomplete) -- Arby's commercial -- weather report ([Unidentified]) -- Joe Suglia introduces Bobby Bare -- Bare talks about this being his first time in Kalamazoo with Tom T. Hall and Jeannie C. Riley -- Bare talks about taking December off and talks about his family album -- Bare talks about touring with family -- Bare talks about setting up for the nights show and other future shows -- Bare talks about premiering the a new record at the nights show -- Bare talks about recording Detroit City  -- Bare talks about his new album the Hard Time Hungrys -- Joe thanks Bobby and signs off -- Detroit City (Bobby Bare) (incomplete recording)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- quarter track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-5-00015_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-5-00015</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-06-12</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Bare, Bobby; Riley, Jeannie C.; Hall, Tom T.;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/7616</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>