<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Interview and Performance - Dierks Bentley - 2016-03-12</dc:title>
<dc:description>Interview with and performance by Dierks Bentley from the CMA Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on March 12, 2016.  In support of the exhibit Dierks Bentley: Every Mile A Memory.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2016-03-12</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Dierks Bentley;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Interview conducted by Peter Cooper.  Performances include; What Was I Thinkin' -- Come A Little Closer -- Free And Easy Down The Road I Go -- Up On The Ridge -- Am I The Only One -- I Hold On -- Drunk On A Plane -- Freedom -- Somewhere On A Beach.  Accompanied by Jon Randall Stewart.</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>CD-R;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>PP0295</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2016-09-07</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Bentley, Dierks;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/4321</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>