<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Jimmy Bowen Interview by John Lomax III   </dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is an interview of Jimmy Bowen. The interview takes place on 11-18-86.  </dc:description>
<dc:date>1986-11-18</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Jimmy Bowen</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Side One - (0:21) -- Jimmy Bowen describes a lawyer that he knows. (0:38) -- Conversation shifts to discussion about music business lawyers. (1:55) -- Jimmy Bowen story about Jerry Lee Lewis. (2:20) -- John Lomax tells story about story about Hazel Smith and Steve Scruggs. (3:58) -- Jimmy Bowen describes the recent changes of Music Row. (4:37) -- John Lomax asks Jimmy Bowen about his corporate history and why he switched from certain companies. (5:47) -- Jimmy Bowen discusses moving from California to Tennessee. (7:34) -- Jimmy Bowen discusses leaving MGM with several contracts. (9:57) -- Jimmy Bowen discusses his previous production company, Amos Productions Inc. (10:37) -- Jimmy Bowen reorganized the Polydor A&amp;R department in New York between 1974 and 1975. (12:25) -- Jimmy Bowen speaks about learning about country consumers. (13:47) -- Jimmy Bowen first came to Nashville in September 1976. (15:27) -- Jimmy Bowen speaks about music as an artform. (17:36) -- Jimmy Bowen speaks about Nashville's wonderful collection of songwriters. (18:26) -- Jimmy Bowen speaks about finding a great engineer to work with, but ended up deciding to engineer music himself. (19:49) -- Jimmy Bowen speaks about working at the Glaser Brothers studio. (25:20) -- Jimmy Bowen speaks about setting Jim Foglesong up to take over MCA. Foglesong backed out and Jimmy Bowen took over MCA. (28:07) -- Jimmy Bowen speaks about dealing with the press.  (30:15) -- Jimmy Bowen speaks about meeting and hiring Nick Hunter. (32:33) -- Jimmy Bowen speaks about caring for his wife in the hospital while running a company. (34:15) -- Jimmy Bowen speaks about Tanya Tucker playing rock n' roll music for a crowd of country &amp; western fans. (35:09) -- Jimmy Bowen speaks about meeting Bill Monroe at a festival. (36:45) -- Jimmy Bowen tells a story about Jim Foglesong trying to frame him for ripping MCA off.  Jim Foglesong believed that Jimmy Bowen spent thousands of dollars on luggage with MCA's money, but in reality Bowen purchased hang-up bags for musicians. (43:32) -- Jimmy Bowen speaks about leaving MCA for Elektra Records. (45:00) -- Jimmy Bowen speaks about building Elektra Records. (46:23) -- Jimmy Bowen speaks about the staff at Elektra Records. </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>audio cassette, compact;</dc:format>
<dc:format>1.75 ips;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CAS4689_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>CAS4689</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-09-05</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Bowen, Jimmy;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9487</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>