<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Ray Stevens interview - Joe Suglia - 1977-07-01 - WBUK</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of an interview with Ray Stevens (performer), conducted by Joe Suglia from July 1, 1977 on radio station WBUK.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1977-07-01</dc:date>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Ray Stevens promotes radio station WBUK -- Joe Suglia introduces Ray Stevens -- Ray Stevens talks about his new single Dixie Hummingbird -- Stevens says he likes the song -- Stevens says he doesn't know what his favorite song of his is -- Stevens messes with Suglia -- Stevens talks about interviewing with Ralph Emery -- Stevens introduces Sonny James -- Stevens tells a story about flying in a plane with a chicken -- Stevens does a Jimmy Stewart impersonation -- Stevens promotes Joe Suglia and WBUK</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-5-00019_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-5-00019</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-08-15</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Stevens, Ray, 1939-;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8071</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>