<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Pulsebeat Radio Show: Dean Dillon - Part 1</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of Kim Spangler (host) dictating the Pulsebeat section of the Voice of the Heartland Radio Show. The episode interviews Dean Dillon (musician). The episode was set to air for the week of October 03, 1988. The episode is part 1 of 2.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1988-10-03</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Kim Spangler; Dean Dillon</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:01) Kim Spangler introduces the upcoming Dean Dillon Pulsebeat show -- (00:35) Hey Heart (Dean Dillon) -- (03:32) Spangler introduces the commercial break -- (03:41) Dial 901 [unconfirmed] ([Unidentified]) -- (04:49) Spangler reveals Dean Dillon was performing on a television show by age fifteen; additionally, Dillon reflects on how his recording initially failed -- (06:03) Spangler and Dillon discuss how Dillon's party lifestyle had abruptly changed -- (07:34) Spangler reveals that Merle Haggard and being an extra at Opryland influenced Dillon -- (08:52) Go to Pieces (Dean Dillon) -- (12:12) Spangler introduces the commercial break -- (12:26) Spangler asks Dillon where the name 'Slick Nickel' came from -- (13:34) Father, Son and Holy Ghost (Dean Dillon) -- (17:25) Spangler and Dillon reflect on the difficulties of succeeding in music -- (18:18) Appalachia Got to Have You Feelin' in My Bones (Dean Dillon) -- (20:29) Spangler introduces the commercial break -- (20:49) Spangler asks Dillon what song he wished to hear -- (21:02) Baby Blue (George Strait) -- (24:14) Unidentified tune [featuring Kim Spangler outro discussion] ([Unidentified])</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-0973_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-0973</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-09-10</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Spangler, Kim; Dillon, Dean;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9549</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>