<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Forester Sisters Interview - Biff Collie - Tape 1</dc:title>
<dc:description>Tape 1 of 2. Recording of an interview with Forester Sisters (performance group) conducted by Biff Collie.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1989-07-17</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Forester Sisters; Biff Collie</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) The Forester Sisters talk about the first snowfall on Christmas in their life -- (01:08) The Forester Sisters talk about always wanting to be at their mother's and their mother's sickness -- (02:39) Kim Forester tells where she lived and almost electing herself -- (03:14) Chris Forester jokes about dropping Kim on her head -- (03:31) Kim and Chris talk about Chris' hair embarrassing her as a child -- (04:13) June, Chris, and Kim Forester talk about seeing children for the first time and Chris' pregnancy -- (05:20) Chris, Kim, and June talk about Kathy having to practice instrumentation constantly -- (06:25) Kim talks about June's experimentations with food -- (06:48) June talks about Kim and Christy trying to get her to stand up only to go limp -- (07:29) Biff Collie attempts to figure out the sibling role -- (07:37) Kathy talks about singing while working and June recalls having the role as the house keeper -- (08:40) Kathy recalls a time from her youth, making gravy, and her dad calling her food oatmeal -- (09:16) Collie jokes with all the Forester Sisters' about their role in the family -- (10:40) The Forester Sisters recall a time where they tied Kim to a tree -- (11:34) Kim talks about her domestic roles -- (11:56) Christy and the Forester Sisters joke about her baby sitting role and her having money -- (14:13) Collie and the Forester talk about Christy's nickname Ivana Trump -- (15:01) The Forester Sisters talk about how Christy's frugality comes forth -- (17:06) Collie and The Forester Sisters talk about how they first started singing together in church -- (18:02) The Forester Sisters and Collie talk about 'Singing Schools' as a form of recreation -- (20:28) The Forester Sisters talk about the vast amount of musicians from their home town and the 'All Day Singin' event -- (21:24) The Forester Sisters discuss their grandma as a large women who couldn't walk in heels -- (22:01) Kathy talk about the Bradford family and her friend Louise -- (22:55) The Forester Sisters joke about a third grade love named John -- (24:12) Kim talks about Kathy receiving a bracelet from a guy who liked her -- (24:39) Kathy talks about the eventual change of life because of dating -- (25:43) Kathy talks about a poorly dressed date -- (26:03) Kim talks about being in multiple extra-curricular activities and her sisters messing up -- (27:09) The Forester Sisters joke about June hitting her head and crashing driving to church -- (29:05) Collie and the Forester Sisters discuss the artistic side of their hometown -- (31:12) Kathy talks about Plum Nelly -- (31:40) Kim and Kathy tells about decorating cakes as children and Kim tells about getting her tongue stuck -- (33:41) Kathy talks about singing at their first festival and singing at ceremonies -- (34:48) Collie talks to the Forester Sisters practicing music despite life pulling them further apart -- (36:39) Kim and Christy talk about their college majors -- (37:06) Collie and the Forester Sisters joke about Kim and Christy's career choices; then, talked about deciding to do a demo tape -- (38:54) Kim talks about the difficulty in getting interested parties to come see a performance -- (39:59) Kim talks about their first producer and performing for twenty Warner Brothers executives -- (41:30) Kathy talks about the process of celebrating their first deal -- (42:31) The Forester Sisters talk about quitting their jobs to work in the studio and the struggles their first year -- (43:51) Kathy talks about the changing life style and her / Kristy's love life while touring with the Oak Ridge Boys -- (45:01) Collie and Kristy talk about Ricky Skaggs  and Kristy's husband -- (45:33) The Forester Sisters and Collie talk about their entire entourage -- (46:10) Kathy talks about the Forester Sisters' aunt and their extended family -- (47:32) The Forester Sisters talk about what happens when they get off the road -- (48:50) Kristy talks about how she's in the process of becoming a farm owner -- (49:28) The Forester Sisters talk about being nominated for awards and only winning an ACM award in 1987 -- (50:07) The Forester Sisters talk about how the couldn't contain their excitement when they won their award -- (51:03) The Forester Sisters talks about the Forester Sisters' shows and what they want to be remembered as after the show -- (52:40) The Forester Sisters talk about establishing their own individual identities -- (53:15) The Forester Sisters' influences are discussed -- (53:51) June talks about getting tired and all their musical tastes -- (54:24) The Forester Sisters and Collie discuss whether they have considered being a solo act -- (54:55) June talks about her professional goals of owning a business and having a family -- (55:25) Kim talks about wanting children and not wanting a road life for them -- (56:15) Kristy talks about wanting to improve her writing skills and family values -- (56:45) Kathy talks about honing her skills -- (57:30) The Forester Sisters talk about their grandmother as the most unforgettable character -- (58:48) Collie and the Forester Sisters talk about their parents </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1140_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1140</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-01-04</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Forester Sisters; Collie, Biff;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8342</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>