<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Songwriter Session - Steve Dean and Bill Whyte - 2017-05-06</dc:title>
<dc:description>Performance by Steve Dean and Bill Whyte from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on May 6, 2017.  Includes questions from the audience. </dc:description>
<dc:date>2017-05-06</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Steve Dean; Bill Whyte; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Walk-in Music / (02:08)Opening comments by Abigail St. Pierre and introduction of Steve and Bill / (06:04) Opening comments from songwriters / (08:11) Round About Way (Steve Dean) / (11:40) Excerpted Comedy Song (Bill Whyte) / (13:37) Unidentified Song likely titled A Face For Radio (Bill Whyte) / (21:06) Southern Star (Steve Dean with harmony by Bill Whyte) / (26:52) Safe Haven (Bill Whyte) / ()  (Steve Dean) / (32:11) Answers question from audience about advice for budding songwriters / (33:54) Answers question about the strangest things that has happened to them as songwriters / (36:00) Answers question about the first funny songs written / 37:47) Answers question about the influences on country songwriters / (40:17) Watching You (Steve Dean) / (45:11) Goin' Ugly Early (Bill Whyte) / (48:36) Closing Comments / (53:59) Recording Ends/ (56:49) FILE END.</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/24;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0031</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2018-06-07</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Dean, Steve; Whyte, Bill; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/7606</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>