<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>WCKY Hayride - 1949-01-19 - Part 1</dc:title>
<dc:description>1949-01-19 broadcast of WCKY's Hayride program, part 1. Featuring pre-recorded music, hosted by Don Davis, sponsored by Mason's Chicks.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1949-01-19</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Texas Jim Lewis; Lone Star Cowboys; Rudy Sooter; Mountain Boys; Spade Cooley; Montana Slim</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Theme (Wait For The Wagon) -- Opening statement (Don Davis) -- Rolling Along (Texas Jim Lewis and his Lone Star Cowboys) -- Mason's Chicks commercial (Don Davis) -- Hear Dem Bells (Rudy Sooter and his Mountain Boys) -- Mason's Chicks commercial (Don Davis) -- Hollywood Hoedown (Spade Cooley) -- Don Davis introduces Montana Slim -- Cowboy's Airplane Ride (Montana Slim)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>16 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR001266</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2014-11-03</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WCKY (Radio station : Cincinnati, Ohio); Hayride (Radio program); Davis, Don (WCKY radio station); Lewis, Texas Jim; Lone Star Cowboys (Musical group); Sooter, Rudy; Mountain Boys (Musical group : Rudy Sooter); Cooley, Spade, 1910-1969; Montana Slim, 1904-1996</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/539</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>