<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Let's Think Forum - 1952-02 - WMAK</dc:title>
<dc:description>First recording is part 2 of various performances by Uncle Dave Macon (performer) and other unidentified performers, recorded in May of 1950 in Kittrell, Tennessee by Charles F. Bryan [according to tape case]. Second recording is a ""Let's Think"" forum held at Vanderbilt University in February of 1952, featuring Will R. Manier Jr. (moderator), Charles F. Bryan (panelist), Guy Taylor (panelist), Bill McDaniel (panelist), Beasley Smith (panelist), Eddy Arnold (panelist), and Hugh Cherry (panelist) on radio station WMAK (Nashville, Tenn.) Forum topics included opinions on the best and most interesting type of music, an extensive breakdown of folk music, and the future of country music.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1952-02</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Charles F. Bryan; Eddy Arnold; Guy Taylor; Beasley Smith; Hugh Cherry; Bill McDaniel; Uncle Dave Macon</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Test tones -- All Go Hungry Hash House (Uncle Dave Macon) (incomplete) -- [Unidentified talking] -- All Go Hungry Hash House (Uncle Dave Macon) (incomplete) -- Whoa Mule (Uncle Dave Macon) -- Uncle Dave Macon and [Unidentified] talk and introduces the next tune -- No One To Welcome Me Home (Uncle Dave Macon) -- [Unidentified banjo tune] (Uncle Dave Macon) -- Jenny Put The Kettle On (Uncle Dave Macon) -- [Unidentified] talks -- Kissing On The Sly (Uncle Dave Macon) -- [break] -- Will R. Manier Jr. opens the discussion -- Charles F. Bryan talks about different types of music and that if you only listen to one type you are ignorant -- Beasley Smith talks about his likes and dislikes among different genres -- Eddy Arnold says he likes his type of music the best and admits to liking tunes from all genres -- Guy Taylor says he likes his music the best and agrees there are good and bad aspects of any given genre and he likes the good in all of them -- Bill McDaniel says the best music is whatever music an individual likes the best -- Hugh Cherry talks about making a living playing all different types of music -- Cherry talks about jazz music and thinks the best music is that which most people understand and relate to -- Will R. Manier Jr. says there is good and bad in all types of music -- Beasley Smith talks about folk music and how it passes down through the generations -- Hugh Cherry talks about record sales among different genres and pseudo-folk from the perspective of a disc jockey -- Eddy Arnold talks about all the different terms and monikers people have given western music and tells a joke about him being a cowboy -- Bill McDaniel talks about his dislike of the classification of pseudo-folk and says folk music is any music that is an expression of the people -- Beasley Smith says how the link between popular music and folk music is getting smaller and asks Eddy Arnold a question -- Eddy Arnold distinguishes the different subgenres within country music -- Guy Taylor says how he knows too little about folk music to comment -- Will R. Manier Jr. asks another question -- Bill McDaniel talks about varying audiences of different genres of music across different parts of the country -- Hugh Cherry talks about selling sponsors for different genres of music and how readily available they are -- Eddy Arnold agrees with the other panelists -- Will R. Manier Jr. presents another topic regarding musical audiences -- Charles F. Bryan remarks on the topic and points to record sales -- Beasley Smith talks about the complexities of different genres -- Guy Taylor disagrees with Smith's point and remarks audiences should expose themselves to all types before making judgements (incomplete)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-0291_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-0291</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-02-06</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Macon, Uncle Dave, 1870-1952; Manier, Will R., Jr.; Vanderbilt University; WMAK (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); Bryan, Charles Faulkner; Taylor, Guy; McDaniel, Bill; Smith, Beasley; Arnold, Eddy, 1918-2008; Cherry, Hugh;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/6770</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>