<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Opryland Music Demo Recordings - Y-113</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording is of a group of demo recordings from Opryland Music. Recordings are from an unknown date and recorded by a number of unknown bands. Tape is labeled Y-113. </dc:description>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Don't Let Your Pride (Keep Our Hearts Apart) (C. Huff and B. Gifford) -- (01:51) Don't Cry in My Beer (I Want to Drink it) (H. Burton, B. Deihl, and W. S. Stevenson) -- (04:25) Death Valley (D. Carson and W. S. Stevenson) -- (06:44) Dark Eyes (W. S. Stevenson) -- (09:17) Devil in Your Heart (B. Maxwell) -- (11:56) Desert Sands (K. Adelman, L. Mestesky) -- (14:13) Dr. Brown (J. Reed and B. Geddins) -- (17:45) Do You Love Me? (E. Gates and M. Hurley) -- (20:41) The Drifter (S. Masters) -- (22:43) A Dream (Chas. Ryan) -- (25:38) Darling Don't Go (P. Williams and L. Miller) -- (28:17) Don't Tell Me How (Tell Me When) (E. Miller and W. S. Stevenson) -- (30:22) Don't Cry When I Told You So (C. Beam, C. Jiles, and W. S. Stevenson) -- (32:28) Davey Lee (G. J. Drexler) -- (34:58) Drinking House Over the Way (V. F. Stewart) -- (38:04) Don't Push Me too Far (E. Miller and W. S. Stevenson) -- (39:29) Down the Road (E. Miller and W. McWain) -- (42:08) Double Trouble (T. Linn and C. Linn) -- (44:03) Don't Look Back (G. Brown and W. S. Stevenson) -- (45:18) The Day That I Found You (K. Adelman and J. Williams) -- (46:26) Don't Make a Fool Out of Me (C. Reid and J. Hobson) -- (49:06) Do You Wish to be Free (C. Belew) -- (50:47) Do You Know What I Mean (R. Jones) -- (52:18) Don't Look Back (G. Brown and W. S. Stevenson) -- (54:58) Don't Wait for the Hearse (To Take You to Church) (H. Vanderpool) -- (57:31) Evening Blues (Ed White) -- (1:00:14) Electric Guitar Blues (P. Freeman) -- (1:02:38) Everybody Loves That Boogie (P. Freeman) -- (1:05:17) Echoes of the Trail (B. Cooper) -- (1:07:17) Empty Arms (P. Kilpatrick and R. McCallon) -- (1:10:01) E. Ramble (J. De Noone) -- (1:12:30) Empty Dreams (K. Sowder, H. Mays, and C. Felling) -- (1:14:36) Every Time I'm Kissing You (C. Belew) -- (1:16:40) Echoing Bells (S. Foster) -- (1:19:53) Every Time They Have a War (C. Harless) -- (1:22:46) Too Many Tears (O. Gunn) -- (1:25:57) Two Guitars in Chime (O. Gunn) -- (1:28:43) Trouble of the World (R. Duchett)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1309_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1309</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-03-15</dcterms:created>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8649</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>