<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Hallmarks of Country Music - Joe Stampley</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of an interview of Joe Stampley (musician). The interview is hosted by Rick Phillips (army sergeant/ radio host) for the Hallmarks of Country Music segment. The tape was recorded on an unidentified date.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Joe Stampley; Rick Phillips</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) I'm Still Loving You [excerpt] [featuring Joe Stampley radio spot for the Hallmarks of Country Music] (Joe Stampley) -- (00:20) How Lucky Can One Man be? [excerpt] (Joe Stampley) -- (00:32) Hallmarks tune [featuring Rick Phillips introduction voiceover] -- (01:14) The Army New Year's Resolution radio spot hosted by Rick Phillips -- (02:00) United States Customs commercial spot hosted by an unidentified voice -- (02:32) Too Far Gone (Joe Stampley) -- (05:10) Phillips introduces Stampley who reflects on his traveling work -- (06:57) All These Things (Joe Stampley) -- (11:03) Drug commercial spot hosted by an unidentified host -- (12:04) Phillips hosts a commercial break about military personal movements -- (12:42) Sometime (Joe Stampley) -- (15:52) Phillips and Stampley reflect on the time Stampley met Hank Williams; additionally, ""Take Time to Know Her"" is said to be telling a country message -- (17:47) Take Time to Know Her (Joe Stampley) -- (20:52) Airborne and Special Forces' openings radio spot hosted by Phillips -- (21:30) I'm Still Loving You (Joe Stampley) -- (24:23) Stampley expresses his appreciation to ""I'm Still Loving You,"" and Stampley and Phillips discusses Stampley's time with Paula Records -- (28:19) If You Touch Me (You've Got to Love Me) (Joe Stampley) -- (30:36) Feron Young reflects on his time in the military -- (31:43) Phillips hosts a radio spot about reenlistment in the military -- (32:16) How Lucky Can One Man be? (Joe Stampley) -- (34:27) ""How Lucky Can One Man be?"" is told by Stampley to have been recorded with the Uniques, and ""Not to Long Ago"" writer Merle Kilgore is reflected on by Stampley -- (35:47) Stampley reflects on his band and family -- (37:56) U.S.O. commercial spot hosted by an unidentified host -- (38:55) Bring it on Home to Your Woman (Joe Stampley) -- (40:52) P. X. check verification radio spot hosted by Phillips -- (41:30) Soul Song (Joe Stampley) -- (43:53) Stampley and Phillips discuss Stampley's first impression of ""Soul Song,"" and Stampley reflects on what he believes to be a hit -- (48:58) Take Me Home to Somewhere (Joe Stampley) -- (51:23) Dishonorable discharge radio spot hosted by an unidentified voice -- (52:00) Phillips asks Stampley to reflect on ""Most Beautiful Girl,"" and both say their goodbyes -- (53:19) Phillips performs a PX Money Saver program radio spot -- (53:47) Phillips performs his outro statement -- (54:10) Hallmarks outro tune ([Unidentified]) -- (55:36) Phillips introduces Ronnie Milsap -- (55:43) I'd be a Legend in My Time (Ronnie Milsap) -- (58:30) Milsap reflects on his time in college where he discovered his passion for music; additionally, Phillips questions Milsap's limitations based on his sight -- (1:00:00) Hallmarks outro tune ([Unidentified])</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Insert is of program information. The insert features time stamps.</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1622_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1622</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-06-10</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Stampley, Joe; Phillips, Rick;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9069</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>