<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Various record and radio excerpts</dc:title>
<dc:description>Various recordings of performances featuring Virgil Simmons (performer), Paul Byrd (performers), Curly Fox (performer), Roy Acuff (performer), John Daniel Quartet (performers) and other unidentified performers, some on radio station WROV (Roanoke, VA.) and some on radio station WSM (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Paul Byrd; Virgil Simmons; Roy Acuff; Curly Fox; John Daniel Quartet</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Test tones -- [Unidentified] -- introduces the Paul Byrd -- The Girl I Left Behind (Paul Byrd) -- [Unidentified] introduces Virgil Simmons -- Bill Cheatham (Paul Byrd) -- Devil's Dream (Virgin Simmons fiddle) -- Buffalo Gals (Virgil Simmons fiddle) -- Five Foot Two (Virgil Simmons fiddle) -- Fisher's Hornpipe (Virgil Simmons fiddle) -- Beer Barrel Polka (Paul Byrd) -- [Unidentified tune] -- [Unidentified tune] -- [Unidentified tune] -- [Unidentified tune] -- [Unidentified tune] -- Liza Jane (Paul Byrd) -- Tennessee Wagoner (Paul Byrd) -- Bye Bye Blues (Paul Byrd) -- Fisher's Hornpipe (Paul Byrd) -- Going Back To Georgia (Virgil Simmons fiddle) -- Orange Blossom Special (Virgil Simmons fiddle) -- Twelfth Street Rag (Paul Byrd) -- Who's Sorry Now? (Paul Byrd) -- Beer Barrel Polka (Paul Byrd) -- Tiger Rag (Paul Byrd) -- Under The Double Eagle (Virgil Simmons fiddle) -- Mississippi Sawyer (Virgil Simmons fiddle) -- Darktown Strutter's Ball (Paul Byrd) -- Goodbye Little Darlin' ([Unidentified]) -- [Unidentified tune] -- [Unidentified tune] -- [Unidentified] talks -- Mockingbird (Curly Fox) -- I Read It In The Book Of Revelations (John Daniel Quartet) [unconfirmed] -- [Unidentified tune] -- [Unidentified] talks -- Wait For The Light To Shine (Roy Acuff) -- [Unidentified] talks -- [break] -- John Henry ([Unidentified]) -- Away Out There ([Unidentified]) -- Where Is My Wondering Boy Tonight ([Unidentified]) -- [Unidentified tune] -- Boil Them Cabbage Down ([Unidentified]) -- Time Changes Everything ([Unidentified])</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-0058_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-0058</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2017-09-12</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>John Daniel Quartet; Fox, Curly, 1910-1995; Acuff, Roy, 1903-1992;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/5740</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>