<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Ralph Emery Interview of George Jones and Waylon Jennings - 1979-05-02</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of an interview of George Jones (musician) and Waylon Jennings (musician). The interview is hosted by Ralph Emery. The tape is the unedited recording. The tape was recorded May 02, 1979. This is the first tape of two.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1979-05-02</dc:date>
<dc:creator>George Jones; Waylon Jennings; Ralph Emery</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) George Jones and Waylon Jennings joke while Ralph Emery explains the structure of the show -- (02:10) Jones performs a radio spot for the Ralph Emery Show -- (02:21) Emery introduces Jones and Jennings; additionally, the three discuss how Jones drove Jennings to the show -- (04:11) Emery asks Jennings to reflect on "Amanda," and Jennings associates it to Jessi Colter -- (05:52) Emery and Jennings associate Don Williams to "Amanda," and Jones discusses living with Johnny Cash -- (08:33) Emery asks Jennings to introduce Glen Campbell -- (10:15) Jones reveals how he worked on Star Routes -- (11:29) Emery, Jones and Jennings reflect on the best songs they had written -- (13:38) Emery asks the two to bring on Cash -- (14:04) Emery asks why Jennings was recruited by Cash -- (14:42) Emery inquires about what Jones has been up to since moving to Nashville, Tennessee -- (17:45) Emery has Jones and Jennings introduce the next track -- (19:35) Emery, Jones, and Jennings say goodbye for their first segment -- (19:52) Jones introduces the Ralph Emery Show, and Emery inquires about Jones' radio name -- (20:57) Emery recalls how he saw Jennings at the Kentucky Derby where they discuss the word outlaw -- (23:27) Emery invites Jones to play a record, and Emery inquires to Jones and Jennings' impersonations of each other -- (25:24) A Picture From Life's Other Side (Waylon Jennings and George Jones) -- (28:34) Emery inquires about the prospect of a live album for Jennings and Jones -- (29:30) Emery asks about Jennings' rare recording of Hank Williams Sr. -- (32:13) Emery asks about the live shows coming up for Jennings and Jones -- (34:52) Jennings recalls a story about Billie Jo Spears' husband -- (35:23) Emery inquires about Jennings' relationship to Willie Nelson; additionally, Jennings recalls how he cussed in-front of Emery -- (36:54) Emery inquires about Jones' work with Johnny Paycheck, and Emery introduces "You Can Have Her" -- (39:19) Emery, Jones, and Jennings say goodbye for their segment -- (39:37) Emery and Jennings greet the audience, and Emery inquires about Jones' song-writing -- (43:01) Jennings discusses the water fountain -- (44:23) Jennings reflects on the country style of Loretta Lynn -- (45:25) Emery asks Jones to reflect on "We Ought to be Ashamed"</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1541_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1541</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-06-05</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Jones, George; Jones, George, 1931-2013; Jennings, Waylon; Emery, Ralph;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8974</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>