<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Interview and performance - Neil Rosenberg - tape one of two -  2006-09-28</dc:title>
<dc:description>Interview with and performance by Neil Rosenberg from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on September 28, 2006.  Tape one of two.  Audio portion of video interview.  In partnership with the International Bluegrass Music Association.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2006-09-28</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Neil Rosenberg; Fred Bartenstein; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Program begins in progress. Opening comments by Ali Tonn.  Introduction of Gabrielle Gray.  Introduction of Fred Bartenstein.  Introduction and interview of Neil Rosenberg by Fred Bartenstein.  Subjects include: Birth and early days -- First exposure to music and beginning violin lessons -- Watching cowboy movies growing up and remembering a Tex Ritter personal appearance -- Moving to Los Alamos with his parents and their musical and life inspiration -- Education and interest in folk music at Berklee -- The 1950's folk revival -- Political overtones of folk music -- Meeting Mayne Smith -- First exposure to bluegrass music -- Attending Oberlin College -- Freshman year at Oberlin and meeting Eric Weissberg -- First exposure to country music -- Syd Nathan of King Records controlling juke boxes in Ohio -- Mike Seeger -- Antioch College and the Lorain County string band -- Commentary on photographs being shown -- prerecorded music played during break for video tape change --</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Hearing Jimmy Martin for the first time and meeting Shorty and Juanita Shehan -- Seeing the Country Gentlemen and hiring them for the first festival at Oberlin -- Starting at Indiana University and people he knew them from Bloomington Indiana -- Going to his first Bean Blossom festival and seeing Bill Monroe and his Bluegrass Boys for the first time -- Playing at Bean Blossom -- The route to becoming an academian -- Doing a masters thesis on Parrot jokes instead of the song White House Blues -- Monroe wanting Neil to play banjo with him at the next years Bean Blossom festival -- Forming the Pigeon Hill Boys -- Being hired to be the manager of Brown County Jamboree while a graduate student -- Bridging the gap between his Jewish urban background and the rural background -- The cultural environment of Bloomington and Brown County -- Writing first academic paper titled From Sound to Style -- Commentary on photographs being shown -- Continues on tape two.</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>RDAT digital tape;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RS.2014.0110</dc:identifier>
<dc:subject>Rosenberg, Neil V.; Bartenstein, Fred, 1950-; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/5287</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>