<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Excerpt from Plantation Party</dc:title>
<dc:description>Excerpt from a broadcast of the Plantation Party, with performances by Louise Massey &amp; The Westerners, the Duke Of Paducah, Curt Massey, Michael Stewart, and the Plantation Choir.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Duke Of Paducah; George Barnes; Curt Massey; Louise Massey &amp; The Westerners; Michael Stewart; Plantation Choir</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(0:00) Duke Of Paducah performs a comedy routine about joining the army / (4:20) George Barnes performs "Melody In F" / (5:22) Charlie Lyon introduces the next performance / (5:37) Curt Massey introduces the next song then performs "Whoopie Ti Yi Yo" / (7:53) Duke Of Paducah and Michael Stewart introduce the next performance / (8:10) Michael Stewart and the Plantation Choir perform "The Glendy Burk"</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>10 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR003808_2</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>TR003808</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:isPartOf>TRB010_1</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-03-20</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Duke of Paducah, 1901-1986; Plantation party (Radio program); Massey, Louise, 1902-1983; The Westerners (Musical group); Massey, Curt, 1910-1991</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/7119</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>