<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Interview - Peter Guralnick - 2005-11-12</dc:title>
<dc:description>Interview with author Peter Guralnick about his biography on Sam Cooke titled Dream Boogie: The Triumph of Sam Cooke from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on November 12, 2005.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2005-11-12</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Peter Guralnick; Jay Orr; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Includes questions from the audience.  Recording begins in progress / (00:00) Opening comments by Jay Orr / (00:37) Introduction of Peter / (01:17) Peter talks about his inspiration for writing his Sam Cooke biography and reads segments from his book / (16:28) Peter talks about continuity from previous book research to this book / (19:52) Comments about Elvis Presley and Sam Cooke / (21:31) Talks about Sam Cooke, Nashville, Gorgeous George and Jimi Hendrix / (24:23) Talks about Sam making the transition from gospel music to secular music and the effect of Ray Charles' recording of I Got A Woman on music / (29:00) Influence of behind the scenes people like Art Rupe, Bumps Blackwell and Barbara Cooke on Sam and music and the attempt to present and honest picture of Sam / (33:41) Answers question from the audience regarding Allen Klein in regards to Sam and removing preconceptions from his writing /</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(37:10) Answers question from audience regarding Sam's social life and the manner or his death / record signal break / (42:07) Peter talks about meeting and interviewing Barbara Cooke and his thoughts about her /  (45:14) Peter talks about his feelings about Sam Cooke, his songwriting and his music / (48:15) Answers question from audience regarding Sam's early song writing and Sam working with Ren&#233; Hall / (53:12) Answers question about Sam and Bobby Womack and the Womack brothers / (55:08) Answers question about Sam working with Billie Holiday / (57:39) Answers questions about Sam reaching out to white audiences while never losing the black audience and his trying to conquer that divide / (01:01:24) Question about Elvis Presley, his instincts and the civil rights movement / PROGRAM ENDS ABRUPTLY /</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>RDAT digital tape;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RS.2014.0134</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2017-11-08</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Guralnick, Peter; Orr, Jay; Cooke, Sam; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/6170</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>