<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Performance - Blue Mafia and the Irene Kelly band - 2017-11-11</dc:title>
<dc:description>Performance by Blue Mafia and the Irene Kelly band as part of the Bluegrass and Beyond series from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on November 11, 2017.   Part 1 of 3.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2017-11-11</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Blue Mafia (Musical group); Gregg Welty; Mike Gregory; Tony Wray; Dara Wray; Kent Todd; Irene Kelly band (musical group);  Mark Fain, Wayne Southards, Matt Menefee, Justyna Kelly; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Walk-in music / (02:24) Opening comments and introduction by Ben Hall / (05:33) Opening comments from Jim Hurst and introduction of Blue Mafia / (07:03) Performs My Cold Heart/Down The Road / (12:35) Performs I'm Lonesome Without You / (16:31) Introduces band members Gregg Welty, Mike Gregory, Tony Wray, Dara Wray, Kent Todd / (19:10) Introduction of the next song / (19:52) Performs Pray For Rain/Pretty Polly / (26:08) Introduces the next song / (27:07) Performs Midnight Rain / (31:25) Introduces the next song / (33:13) Performs He's Waiting To Hear / (37:03) Gives shout out to sound crew / (37:37) Performs He's In Control / (43:10) Answers question about how long ago and how they got together / (44:36) Answers question about music they listened to growing up / (48:10) Performs Can't You Hear Me Calling / (51:37) Introduction of next song / (52:05) Performs All I Ever Loved Was You / (55:02) Walk-out music / (01:05:29) Jim Hurst with introduction of the Irene Kelly band /            </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(01:07:35) Performs You Don't Run Across My Mind / (01:10:35) Introduces the next song / (01:11:16) Performs Up In Those Blue Ridge Mountains / (01:14:15) Talks about her background / 01:15:12) Performs Coal Train / (01:18:34) Introduces band members Mark Fain, Wayne Southards, Matt Menefee, Justyna Kelly  / (01:20:10) Introduces next song / (01:20:39) Performs These Hills / (01:24:39) Answers questions about what got her started playing music and her songwriting / (01:27:19) Introduces next song / (01:27:41) Performs Can't You Hear Me Callin' (Wayne - vocal) / (01:30:18) Introduces next song / (01:31:18) Performs My Flower / (01:34:41) Introduces the next song / (01:35:01) Performs Quelqu'un m'a dit (Someone Told Me) (Justyna - vocal) / (01:39:12) Introduces the next song / (01:39:40) Performs Groundspeed / 01:42:28) Introduces the next song / (01:42:32) Performs Leaning On the Good Times / (01:45:02) Talks about Claire Lynch and introduces next song / (01:46:15) Performs Jealousy / </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/24;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0078</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2017-09-20</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Blue Mafia (Musical group); Irene Kelly band; Hurst, Jim; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8163</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>