<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Larry Gatlin Interview by Bob Battle 8-1-1978</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is an interview of Larry Gatlin by Bob Battle. The interview takes place on 8-1-78.   </dc:description>
<dc:date>1978-08-01</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Larry Gatlin;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Side One - (0:02) -- Bob Battle introduction of himself and mentions that he's writing for Country Style Magazine. Bob Battle also wrote for The Nashville Banner. (0:39) -- Bob Battle asks Larry Gatlin about his possible upcoming roles in movies and television shows. (1:13) -- Larry Gatlin mentions that he's written a soundtrack for his upcoming movie, "Penny Annie." (1:44) -- Larry Gatlin mentions that he's filming the movie with Silo Productions. (2:15) -- Larry Gatlin speaks about the meaning of "Penny Annie." (3:04) -- Bob Battle asks about how Larry Gatlin's career is going so far. (4:38) -- Bob Battle asks Larry Gatlin about his recent material with The Gatlin Brothers. Larry Gatlin mentions the record "Do It Again Tonight" and The Gatlin Brothers' current album "Love Is Just A Game." (4:58) -- Bob Battle asks Larry Gatlin about his plans for a new album. (5:34) -- Bob Battle asks Larry Gatlin about his recent success. (7:02) -- Bob Battle asks whether the stories in Larry Gatlin's music have helped sell his music. (7:49) -- Bob Battle asks Larry Gatlin's about his involvement with The Grand Ole Opry. (8:13) -- Bob Battle mentions his column "Country Cookin'" for Country Style Magazine. (8:41) -- Bob Battle asks Larry Gatlin whether he wishes to add anything else to his article in Country Style Magazine. Larry Gatlin speaks about his relationship with his fans. </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>audio cassette, compact;</dc:format>
<dc:format>1.75 ips;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CAS4736_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>CAS4736</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-09-16</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Gatlin, Larry;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of th+V2e Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9614</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>