<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Roy Acuff Grand Ole Opry Discs: Tape 2</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of Roy Acuff's American Ace Coffee sponsored Grand Ole Opry. The tape is labeled Acuff's tape number two of an unidentified number. The tape features multiple recordings. The recording features Grant Turner (host) and features performances by: Tommy Jackson (musician), Rod Brasfield (comedian), Roy Acuff (musician/host), Smokey Mountain Boys (musical group), Ernest Tubb (musician), Oswald and Joe (musicial duo), Pap and his Jug Band (musical group), Texas Ruby (musician), and Brothers Oswald (musicial duo). The tape is from a multitude of dates from: November 15, 1947; and November 22, 1947.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1947-11-22</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Jug Band; Roy Acuff; Tommy Jackson; Smokey Mountain Belles; Sonny Day; Oswald and Joe; Grant Turner; Ernest Tubb; Rod Brasfield; Texas Ruby;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:16) Souix City Sue (Pap and his Jug Band) -- (02:20) I'm Waiting for My Call to Glory (Roy Acuff) -- (04:09) Grant Turner performs an American Ace commercial spot -- (04:51) The Boatman's Hornpipe (Tommy Jackson) -- (06:20) Cool Water (Smokey Mountain Belles) -- (08:41) Sonnay Day and his accordian are introduced -- (08:54) Accordian tune (Sonny Day) -- (09:47) Lonesome Road Blues (Oswald and Joe) -- (11:22) When the Saints Go Marching in (Roy Acuff) -- (13:10) Ricketts Hornpipe (Tommy Jackson) -- (14:20) Turner performs an American Ace commercial spot -- (14:35) Ida Red (Roy Acuff) -- (15:27) Minnie Pearl performs a closing statement -- (15:36) Glorybound Train [drops out and speed influxes] (Roy Acuff) -- (17:57) Square Dance (Tommy Jackson) -- (19:01) Ida Red [Featuring Roy Acuff outro statements] (Roy Acuff) -- (20:00) Red Foley and Ernest Tubb introduce ""I'll Step Aside"" -- (20:24) I'll Step Aside (Ernest Tubb) -- (23:15) Rod Brasfield performs comedy about his cousin -- (26:53) Foley talks about Prince Albert [incomplete] -- (27:11) A Meeting in the Sky [incomplete] (Roy Acuff) -- (28:33) Columbus Stockade Blues [repeats] (Texas Ruby) -- (31:15) The Girl I Love Don't Pay Me No Mind (Oswald)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-0982_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-0982</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-09-13</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Pap's Jug Band; Acuff, Roy; Jackson, Tommy; Smoky Mountain Belles; Smoky Mountain Boys; Day, Sonny (Accordionist); Oswald and Joe; Turner, Grant; Tubb, Ernest, 1914-1984; Brasfield, Rod; Brasfield, Rod, 1910-1958; Texas Ruby;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9604</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>