<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>I Heard My Name On The Radio - King's Sacred Quartet performance</dc:title>
<dc:description>Performance of I Heard My Name On The Radio, written by Albert Brumley, performed by the King's Sacred Quartet [unconfirmed] which consisted of Johnnie Wright, Jack Anglin, Ray Atkins, and Clyde Moody. Mention of a previous performance with Harmie Smith in Warren, Tex., mention of an upcoming performance with Johnnie &amp; Jack and the Tennessee Mountain Boys and Harmie Smith on at a high school auditorium, and mention of upcoming performance on Friday, January 7th (most likely either 1944 or 1949).</dc:description>
<dc:creator>King's Sacred Quartet</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(0:00) The King's Sacred Quartet [unconfirmed] performs "I Heard My Name On The Radio" [incomplete] / (1:57) [Unidentified radio announcer] and [Unidentified musician] discuss previous and upcoming performances / (3:16) [Unidentified] performs "[Unidentified song]" [incomplete]</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>8 inch fibre-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>78 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR003720_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>TR003720</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:isPartOf>TRB001_4</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-02-20</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Brumley, Albert E., 1905-1977; Wright, Johnnie, 1914-2011; Atkins, Ray, 1927-1997; Anglin, Jack, 1916-1963; Moody, Clyde, 1915-1989; Smith, Harmie; Tennessee Mountain Boys</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/6884</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>