<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Opryland Music Demo Recordings - Y-141</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording is of a group of demo recordings from Opryland Music. Recordings are from an unknown date and recorded by a number of unknown bands. Tape is labeled Y-141. </dc:description>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Schottische Mixer (W. S. Stevenson) -- (04:43) Such is Life (Bill Brock, Carl Belew, and W. S. Stevenson) -- (07:08) Stop, Look and Listen (Geo. L. London and W. S. Stevenson) -- (10:00) This is the Last Time (Eddie Miller and W. S. Stevenson) -- (12:44) That's What I Get For Loving You (C. C. Beam, C. L. Jiles, and W. S. Stevenson) -- (14:44) There's Good Rockin' Tonight (W. S. Stevenson) -- (17:44) This Train is Heaven Bound (Flora Miller and W. S. Stevenson) -- (19:37) Three Cigarettes in an Ashtray (E. Miller and W. S. Stevenson) -- (22:05) Tell His Love Today (W. S. Stevenson) -- (24:42) Teen Hoppers Ball (Oscar H. Harris and W. S. Stevenson) -- (27:02) Thru the Mill (Charley Ryan and W. S. Stevenson) -- (29:58) Voice of the Drums (Jim Holiday and W. S. Stevenson) -- (32:42) Gonna Lay My Burden Down (W. S. Stevenson) -- (35:04) I Really Don't Want to Know (W. S. Stevenson) -- (37:25) I'm Going to Live My Life Alone (W. S. Stevenson) -- (40:55) Little Community Church (W. S. Stevenson) -- (43:56) Over the Waves (W. S. Stevenson) -- (46:15) Poor Ichabod Crane (Dusty Rose and T. Texas Tyler) -- (48:15) Tiptoe to My Teepee (Joe Lane and W. S. Stevenson) -- (51:10) Too Many Lies (Chuck Harless and W. S. Stevenson) -- (54:16) You Are Mine (Daniel Goros) -- (57:22) An Alaskan Christmas (Bud Allen) -- (1:00:19) Arkansas Special (W. S. Stevenson)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1337_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1337</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-03-26</dcterms:created>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8699</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>