<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Hank Snow Benefit at the Grand Ole Opry - 1978-08-31 - Part 1</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of the Hank Snow Benefit Concert at the Grand Ole Opry. The segment is hosted by T. Tommy Cutrer (musician) and features performances by: Ralph Sloan and the Tennessee Travelers (musical group), Boots Randolph (musician), Skeeter Davis (musician) and Ernest Tubb (musician). The recording is from August 31, 1978. The tape is part one of four.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1978-08-31</dc:date>
<dc:creator>T. Tommy Cutrer; Ralph Sloan and the Tennessee Travelers; Boots Randolph; Skeeter Davis; Ernest Tubb</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:10) T. Tommy Cutrer greets the crowd by asking their demographic background; additionally, Cutrer addresses the new declaration of Child Abuse Prevention Week -- (07:07) Unidentified fiddle tune (Ralph Sloan and the Tennessee Travelers) -- (09:23) Cutrer reflects on the Grand Ole Opry and being a Master of Ceremonies -- (10:55) Unidentified saxophone tune (Boots Randolph) -- (14:00) Southern Nights (Boots Randolph) -- (16:58) Unidentified saxophone tune (Boots Randolph) -- (20:24) Randolph greets the crowd and introduces "Big Daddy's Alabama Bound" -- (21:15) Big Daddy's Alabama Bound (Boots Randolph) -- (23:59) Randolph introduces his band -- (24:50) Tumbling Tumbleweeds (Boots Randolph) -- (26:56) Yakety Sax (Boots Randolph) -- (29:30) Movin' on Up (Boots Randolph) -- (32:35) Cutrer praises Randolph and introduces Skeeter Davis -- (33:40) Silver Threads and Golden Needles (Skeeter Davis) -- (36:08) It Wasn't God Who Made Honky Tonk Angels (Skeeter Davis) -- (39:46) Only Mama That'll Walk the Line (Skeeter Davis) -- (42:36) Davis praises her accompanying band, comparing them to the Seven Dwarfs -- (44:49) Bridge Over Troubled Water (Skeeter Davis) -- (49:20) He Will be There [unconfirmed] (Skeeter Davis) -- (52:03) Davis jokes about looking like Dolly Parton -- (53:11) The End of the World (Skeeter Davis) -- (55:48) Outro tune (Tennessee Travelers) -- (56:10) Cutrer asks Davis to show her shoes and discusses how everyone imitates Ernest Tubb -- (58:20)  Thanks a Lot (Ernest Tubb) -- (1:00:45) Tubb expresses his thanks for the program</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1050_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1050</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-07-23</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Cutrer, T. Tommy; Sloan, Ralph; Tennessee Travelers; Randolph, Boots; Randolph, Boots, 1927-2007; Davis, Skeeter; Tubb, Ernest; Tubb, Ernest, 1914-1984;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9280</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>