<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Interview - Kris Kristofferson - 1995-mm-dd</dc:title>
<dc:description>Interview with Kris Kristofferson by an unidentified host interviewer.  Includes answering questions from the internet while streaming.  circa 1995.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1995-mm-dd</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Kris Kristofferson; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Comment about interview being captured on audio / (00:54) Kris talks about previous interviews done during the day / (01:09) Kris talks about what he's currently listening to and how he appreciates Bob Dylan's guitar playing  / (02:39) His current ties to the Rio Grande Valley / (03:54) Writing with the other Highwaymen and each of them being individual loner types / (05:24) Asked about new film that he's been working on and talks about filming Lone Star / (06:19) Working on his latest album with Don Was and being asked to write extra verses on songs for the album / (08:24) Where the inspiration for the song Worth Fighting For came from / (10:30) Talks about the recording of Me And Bobby McGee by the Grateful Dead and his reaction to Jerry Garcia's death / (12:50) Kris asked about his most prized possessions / (13:36) First recorded song / (15:51) Talks about Janis Joplin / (18:23) Where he's going after this interview and show in Memphis tomorrow / </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(18:55) Talks about his friendship with B.B. King / (19:41) Talks about his show business career / (20:12) Comparing songwriting to acting, getting offers to do films and always wanting to be a songwriter  / (22:20) The story of landing a helicopter on Johnny Cash's house / (23:52) Former jobs he's had and ending up in Nashville and never having to work a regular job again / (25:59) Talks about The Johnny Cash Show television show and it's importance to his career /  (27:23) Where he thinks country music is heading and where it is now / (28:10) Songwriting and what he hoped would happen when he first came to Nashville / (29:34) More comments about Jerry Garcia and the Grateful Dead's influence on music / (32:02) Kris asked his age (59) / (32:37) Why he did new arrangements of older songs on the new album / (34:22) Considering himself a folk singer and not a country singer / (36:01) Where the inspiration for How Under The Gun came from / </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>RDAT digital tape;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RS.2017.0001</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2018-03-07</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Kristofferson, Kris; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/6980</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>