<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>My Greatest Friend - Grant Turner performances - WSM</dc:title>
<dc:description>First recording contains multiple performances by Grant Turner and an unidentified performer. Second recording contains interviews conducted by Grant Turner at the Dot Records Luncheon for the Grand Ole Opry's 46th Birthday Celebration at Nashville's Municipal Auditorium.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Grant Turner</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Test tones -- My Greatest Friend (Grant Turner) -- Uncle Jimmy Lee (Grant Turner) -- I'm Glad ([Unidentified]) [unconfirmed] -- Grant Turner introduces himself at the Municipal Auditorium in Nashville for the Dot Records Luncheon for the Grand Ole Opry's 46th birthday celebration -- Grant Turner boasts about the sound system at the function -- Grant Turner introduces Bud Ross -- Bud Ross talks about his company Kustom Electronics and his staff -- Bud Ross talks about how the sound is set up at the function and the acoustics in the building -- Bud Ross talks about all the services his company provides -- Grant Turner talks about the mixing boards used for this function -- Bud Ross describes the set up and the idea behind why the boards are placed as such -- Grant Turner talks about first timers at this gathering -- [Unidentified] talks about this being his first time at a gathering like this -- Grant Turner describes the events that took place at this function -- [Unidentified] talk about their love for country music and Nashville -- Grant Turner talks about Patsy Montana -- Patsy Montana talks about coming to Nashville -- Grant Turner talks about them working together on the Grand Ole Opry -- Patsy Montana talks about the art of yodeling and performing with her family -- Grant Turner talks about her stage name -- Patsy Montana talks about keeping the classics alive and choosing songs she will perform live -- Grant Turner talks about the time Montana came into the industry -- Patsy Montana talks about WSM and it's impact on country music and the year she's had -- Patsy Montana talks about how earlier in her career WLS artists wouldn't dare come to Nashville and how that's not the case anymore -- Grant Turner talks about the original Opry at the Ryman closing down and opening the Opryland -- Patsy Montana talks about growing along with the industry -- Grant Turner signs off</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-0004_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-0004</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2017-07-17</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); Turner, Grant; Dot Records; Montana, Patsy;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/5359</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>