<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Songwriter Session - Pat Alger - 2017-03-11</dc:title>
<dc:description>Performance by Pat Alger from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on March 11, 2017.  Includes questions from the audience and guest appearance by Tony Arata. </dc:description>
<dc:date>2017-03-11</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Pat Alger; Tony Arata;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Walk-in Music / (00:13) Opening  comments and songwriter introduction by Abi Tapia / (03:28) Opening comments from Pat Alger / (05:45) Pat performs True Love on guitar / (10:12) Pat performs the song Unanswered Prayer / () Answers question about the writing of the song Unanswered Prayers / (15:41) Answers question about writing by himself or co-writing / (17:15) Answers question about how to get songs to artists / (20:12) Pat performs the song Small Town Saturday Night / (25:36) Answers question about writing songs with musical accompaniment or without / (26:42) Answers question about how many songs he's had recorded / (27:36) Pat invites audience member Tony Arata to come up on stage / (28:08) Tony Arata tells about meeting Pat Alger at the Bluebird Cafe / (29:20) Tony Arata performs the song The Dance on guitar / (32:44) Pat tells story about meeting Garth Brooks for the first time and writing songs with him / </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(34:02) Pat performs excerpt of the song Like A Hurricane and tells the story of writing the song The Thunder Rolls with Garth Brooks / (35:30) Pat performs the song The Thunder Rolls with story about Tanya Tucker and the writing of the last verse of the song / (42:00) Pat performs the song Seeds / (4516) Walk-out music / (49:31) FILE END</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/24;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0013</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2018-05-02</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Alger, Pat; Arata, Tony; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/7323</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>