<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Performance and discussion - Salute to pedal steel guitarist Buddy Emmons - 2013-09-21</dc:title>
<dc:description>Performances and discussion on the Big E; Salute to pedal steel guitarist Buddy Emmons from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on September 21, 2013.  Presented in Partnership with the Americana Music Association in celebration of the album release The Big E: Salute to Steel Guitarist Buddy Emmons.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2013-09-21</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Duane Eddy; Dan Dugmore; Hargus "Pig" Robbins; Dean Miller; Buck Reid; Tommy White; Steve Fishell; Buddy Emmons;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Program hosted by Bill Lloyd.  Participants include Duane Eddy; Dan Dugmore; Hargus "Pig" Robbins; Dean Miller; Buck Reid; Tommy White; Steve Fishell; Buddy Emmons.  Includes audio from video.  Performances include; Night Life (Band)  --  Demonstration of split pedal innovation  and diatonic strings (Steve Fishell and Buck Reid) --  Half A Mind (Dean Miller with Buck Reid)  --  Blue Jade (Duane Eddy and Dan Dugmore) --  Interview with Buddy Emmons  --  Mansion On The Hill (Band).</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>CD-R;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>PP0215</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2016-03-03</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Emmons, Buddy; Eddy, Duane; Dugmore, Dan; Robbins, Hargus "Pig"; Miller, Dean; Reid, Buck; White, Tommy; Fishell, Steve; </dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/3409</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>