<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Opry Star Spotlight - Roy Acuff, Shot Jackson, and Robert Lunn - WSM</dc:title>
<dc:description>Excerpts from an Opry Star Spotlight radio program featuring interviews with Roy Acuff, Shot Jackson, and Robert Lunn on radio station WSM (Nashville, Tenn.) Interviews conducted by Bill Clayborne.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Charlie Louvin; Joe Maphis; Merle Travis</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Test tones -- Weather report (Bill Clayborne) -- Opening theme -- Bill Clayborne introduces Roy Acuff -- Roy Acuff talks about being busy since visiting Germany and his respect for Bill Clayborne within the country music community -- Roy Acuff talks about Shot Jackson and Robert Lunn and their comedic qualities -- Bill Clayborne talks about Acuff's exhibit opening -- Roy Acuff talks about his exhibit opening -- Bill Clayborne talks about Jimmy Thompson's fiddle, the first fiddle on the Opry -- Roy Acuff talks about the fiddle going in the exhibit and sun bonnets in the exhibit -- Roy Acuff talks about his process for finding artifacts for his exhibit -- Roy Acuff tells a story about his tour in Germany, seeing the courts of justice, and stealing a drinking glass and an ashtray from the court room -- Bill Clayborne talks about the dolls in Acuff's exhibit -- Roy Acuff talks about collecting dolls from different countries and that he has lost count of all the countries he's visited -- Roy Acuff talks about doing Christmas shows overseas -- Roy Acuff talks about finding artifacts in Dunbar cave (Clarksville, Tenn.) and its opening -- Bill Clayborne introduces Charlie Louvin -- See The Big Man Cry (Charlie Louvin) [record excerpt] (incomplete) -- Harvey's Record department commercial (Bill Clayborne) -- Bill Clayborne talks about Acuff, Jackson, and Lunn -- Robert Lunn talks about practical jokes -- Roy Acuff talks about his early career and tells a story about Robert Lunn -- Robert Lunn tells a story from visiting Italy -- Roy Acuff talks about how to communicate with local people in foreign countries -- Roy Acuff talks about meeting Robert Lunn -- Shot Jackson talks about working with Roy Acuff -- Roy Acuff talks about meeting Shot Jackson -- Roy Acuff talks about Jackson's abilities -- Roy Acuff talks about Jimmy Williams -- Bill Clayborne plugs Opry Star Spotlight -- Roy Acuff tells a story about naming his group (Crazy Tennesseans) and tells a story about playing a show early in his career -- Bill Clayborne talks about selling his families piano to Roy Acuff -- Bill Clayborne introduces Merle Travis and Joe Maphis -- [Unidentified guitar tune] (Merle Travis and Joe Maphis) [record excerpt] (incomplete) -- Bill Clayborne talks (incomplete)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-0006_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-0006</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2017-07-19</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); Acuff, Roy, 1903-1992; Jackson, Shot; Lunn, Robert; </dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/5365</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>