<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>This Little Light of Mine Program: Black Gospel on Record and Radio</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of one segment of This Little Light of Mine. This Little Light of Mine is a show that provides introspection to the main influencers of African-American gospel.  The segment hosted by an unidentified voice. The first segment  is called "Sweet Honey in the Rock: New Songs From An Old Tradition." The recordings are from unidentified dates.
</dc:description>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) This Little Light of Mine [featuring an unidentified voiceover] ([Unidentified]) -- (00:36) The unidentified host discusses the creation of gospel music -- (00:58) The unidentified host introduces how Thomas A. Dorsey would introduce his music to new audiences -- (01:24) Oh Precious Lord [featuring the unidentified host describing sheet music influence] (Thomas A. Dorsey) -- (02:29) Fred Mendelsohn (unconfirmed) reflects on the traditionalist styling that guided Dorsey -- (03:23) The unidentified host reflects on Mendelsohn starting the idea of recording live church performances -- (03:39) Peace be Still (James Cleveland) -- (06:53) Mendelsohn reflects on the practices of recording in gospel music -- (08:13) Peace be Still (James Cleveland) -- (09:28) The unidentified host introduces Mendelsohn's take on the predominantly white-owned recording studios -- (11:02) The unidentified host introduces Moses Dillard's take on white people in gospel music -- (12:55) The unidentified host introduces Bill "Hoss" Allen to reflect on the  white movement to gospel -- (14:02) The Lord Will Make a Way Somehow (Al Green) -- (15:46) The unidentified host introduces "Rough Side of the Mountain" -- (15:58) Rough Side of the Mountain (F. C. Barnes) -- (18:29) An unidentified voice reflects on the purity of Barnes and Ron Freeman -- (20:04) Mendelsohn discusses how he did not approve of the Grammy's choices -- (21:02) The unidentified host reflects on the popularity of Allen -- (21:18) Allen recalls his process of producing a show -- (22:08) Strange Things Happening Everyday [featuring Hoss Allen voiceover] (Sister Rosetta Tharpe) -- (22:38) Mendelsohn praises Allen -- (24:01) The unidentified voice discusses Bobby Jones; additionally, Jones reflects on his viewing audience -- (24:47) The unidentified voice calls Emmylou Harris an exception, and Harris reflects on singing in church -- (26:18) Dillard reflects on the power of Barnes and the sincerity of church-goers -- (26:45) This Little Light of Mine [featuring outro voiceover] (Unidentified)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1498_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1498</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-05-28</dcterms:created>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8912</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>