<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>WSM Radio delayed broadcast of the Country Music Hall of Fame medallion ceremony - 2007-11-05.  Tape one of three.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Delayed broadcast by WSM radio of the HOF medallion ceremony tributes and performances of the 2007 Country Music Hall of Fame Medallion ceremony honoring Ralph Emery from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on November 5, 2007.  Delayed broadcast on WSM Radio.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2001-11-05</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Kyle Young; Bud Wendell; Tammy Genovese; Eddie Stubbs; Raul Malo; the Gaither Vocal Band; Con Hunley; Ray Stevens; Ralph Emery;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Recording begins in progress.  Radio broadcast hosted by Eddie Stubbs.  (00:00) WSM top of the hour coverage / (02:43) Comments from Kyle Young about Mel Tillis / (05:00) Bud Wendell introduces Randy Scruggs who plays the song Amazing Grace / (07:10) Bud Wendell introduces the Medallion ceremony event / (08:05) Introduction of CMA COO Tammy Genovese and her  comments / (11:26) Comments from Kyle Young / (18:59) Eddie Stubbs break in with WSM promotions / (27:03)  Kyle Young introduces Ralph Emery segment / (34:40) Raul Malo is introduced and performs the song You Gave Me A Mountain / (40:03) Eddie Stubbs break in with WSM break / (46:44) Kyle Young continues with Ralph Emery segment / (47:46) Introduction of the Gaither Vocal Band who perform the song Yes, I Know / (53:20) Eddie Stubbs break in with WSM break including news break / (01:03:08) Kyle Koung continues with Ralph Emery segment / (01:06:20) Introduction of Con Hunley and performance of the song Since I Fell For You /</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(01:13:46) Eddie Stubbs break in with WSM break / (01:15: 33) Eddie Stubbs interviews Ralph Emery during pre-ceremony festivities and WSM break / (01:30:15) Kyle Young continues with Ralph Emery segment / (01:30:17) Introduction of Ray Stevens who performs the song Everything Is Beautiful / (01:38:24) Eddie Stubbs break in with WSM break / (01:43:47) Kyle Young continues with Ralph Emery segment / (01:47:55)  Bud Wendell conducts induction of Ralph Emery / (01:49:47) Ralph Emery's acceptance speech / (01:53:53) Emery segment closing comments by Kyle Young and Eddie Stubbs with WSM break / END OF TAPE ONE OF THREE. </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>RDAT digital tape;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RS.2014.0121</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2017-09-22</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Emery, Ralph; Young, Kyle; Wendell, Bud; Genovese, Tammy; Stubbs, Eddie; Malo, Raul; Gaither Vocal Group (Musical group); Hunley, Con; Stevens, Ray; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/5904</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>