<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Becky Hobbs Interview - Biff Collie</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of an interview with Becky Hobbs (performer) conducted by Biff Collie. </dc:description>
<dc:date>1990-05-14</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Becky Hobbs; Biff Collie</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Becky Hobbs radio spot for her audiobiography -- (00:06) Hobbs radio spot introducing Biff Collie and the Music City Album Review -- (00:16) Hobbs radio spot for her audiobiography -- (00:26) Hobbs radio spot for her audiobiography -- (00:34) Hobbs radio spot congratulating the listener for her audiobiography -- (00:46) Hobbs radio spot declaring she reveals almost everything she knows -- (00:55) Hobbs radio spot for her audiobiography -- (01:02) Hobbs thirty-minute radio spot [incomplete] -- (01:09) Hobbs asks how long she had been doing radio spots -- (01:17) Hobbs thirty-minute radio spot for her audiobiography -- (01:27)  Hobbs hour radio spot addressing Collie for her audiobiography -- (01:42) Hobbs return-from-commercial radio spot for her audiobiography -- (01:49) Hobbs ninety-minute radio spot for her audiobiography -- (02:00) Hobbs commercial-break radio spot fro her audiobiography -- (02:08) Hobbs radio spot for her audiobiography -- (02:16) Hobbs radio spot asking Collie for feedback -- (02:21) Hobbs goodbye radio spot -- (02:29) Hobbs and Collie radio spot joking about who Collie performs with -- (02:45) Hobbs tells about how she grew up in Bartlesville, Oklahoma and Hobbs reflects on how she, and her sister, would play piano when they were young -- (04:14) Hobbs reflects on being a part of a number of groups in junior high school, and Hobbs talks about performing for a Rouge's Five's show -- (05:00) Hobbs discusses how she would create her own costumes -- (05:16) Hobb's first girl group, The Four Faces of Eve, is reflected on -- (06:07) Hobbs reflects on the life of a Beth Morrison -- (06:32) Hobbs recalls the first songs she ever wrote with the all-girl band -- (07:48) Hobbs reflects on her dedication to music -- (09:05) Hobbs recalls working on Dance Party where she started performing with The Sir Prize Package -- (10:52) Collie asks Hobbs to reflect on her influences and Hobbs describes her country and rock influences -- (12:03) Hobbs describes her rockabilly tunes "I'm in the Mood for Love" and expresses her desire to record a great old country song -- (12:40) Hobbs describes going to Tulsa University and how she constantly would be locked out of her dorm -- (14:09) Hobbs describes how she left her all-girl band and joined Swamp Fox -- (15:11) Hobbs describes her southern rock career moving her in Los Angeles -- (15:42) Hobbs recalls signing with Al Gallico and how she visited Nashville to perform for Billy Sherrill -- (17:16) Hobbs reflects on her song "The More I Get (The More I Want)," as well as, "I Can't Say Goodbye to You" opening doors for Hobbs -- (18:03) Hobbs discusses that, while she lived in Los Angeles, she was infatuated with Nashville -- (19:05) Hobbs describes how she performed for wet t-shirt contests -- (19:49) Hobbs describes how she prospered with "I'll Be Your Audience" writer Helen Reddy, and Hobbs recalls her first country cut "Feedin' the Fire" -- (21:16) Collie has Hobbs reflect on Loretta Lynn and Hobbs also includes George Jones -- (21:59) Hobbs discusses George Jones inspiration for "Jones on the Jukebox" -- (22:24) Hobbs discusses Moe Bandy being at one of her concerts and how they had recorded "Let's Get Over Them Together" -- (23:17) Hobbs describes the difficulty in being able to record with Bandy -- (23:53) Hobbs tells of how her song, "You Are," was recorded by Earl Campbell and Emmylou Harris -- (24:15) Hobbs describes her desire for "I Want to Know You Before We Make Love" to be a single and how eventually Conway Twitty recorded it -- (25:00) Collie and Hobbs discuss when Hobbs would open for Conway -- (25:39) Hobbs recalls when she moved to Nashville after being overwhelmed in Los Angeles -- (26:45) Hobbs describes her last thoughts on Los Angeles -- (27:20) Hobbs first thoughts on moving to Nashville are revealed -- (29:09) Hobbs reflects meeting Bandy and having interest from EMI Records -- (29:40) Hobbs recalls a story of when a bartender put a man's feet on fire -- (31:17) Hobbs recalls a humorous time she met a fan -- (31:42) Collie introduces a word game, and Collie and Hobb's discuss Bobby Orman -- (32:36) Collie and Hobbs discuss a flattering article -- (33:50) Hobbs recaps the time when she had signed with EMI Records, and Hobb's reflects on the new president of EMI Records firing her -- (36:05) Hobbs tells of how she had to perform on stage for a chance at a MTM Records contract -- (37:39) Hobbs tells about the mental games affecting her personal growth -- (40:17) Hobbs and Collie joke about people's inability to read a map -- (42:10) Hobbs discusses working for Curb Records,"A Little Hunk of Heaven," and her difficulty with doubts -- (44:12) Hobbs says she would love to do the score for a movie -- (44:43) Hobbs describes playing at the her piano the most relaxing feeling, and Hobbs tells about a time performing with Twitty -- (45:35) Collie and Hobbs discuss how Hobbs would love to be stuck on an island with Willie Nelson -- (46:08) Hobbs laughs</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1189_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1189</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-01-28</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Hobbs, Becky; Collie, Biff;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8430</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>