<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Curly Putman Interview by John Lomax III Side Two </dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is an interview of Curly Putman by John Lomax III. The interview takes place on 10-26-1981. </dc:description>
<dc:date>1981-10-26</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Curly Putman; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Side Two - (0:03) -- Curly Putman continues discussion of his co-writing and learning from other songwriters. (0:33) -- Curly Putman describes the type of person he prefers to write with. (1:34) -- Curly Putman speaks about Bobby Braddock's preference for songwriting. (1:50) -- Curly Putman mentions that he often co-writes when he is in a hurry to get a song out. (2:07) -- John Lomax asks Curly Putman about his sons' interest in writing and playing music. (2:40) -- Curly Putman mentions playing steel guitar in a band in Alabama before he got into songwriting. This background helped his transition from performer to songwriter. (3:22) -- John Lomax asks Curly Putman about his marriage. (4:18) -- John Lomax asks Curly Putman about his long history with BMI. Curly Putman compliments Frances W. Preston. (5:08) -- John Lomax asks Curly Putman about his songwriting schedule with Bobby Braddock. (6:10) -- John Lomax asks Curly Putman about his interest in the evolving types of country music. (7:53) -- John Lomax asks Curly Putman how a young writer may begin working with a respected publishing company such as Tree Publishing Company. (9:04) -- John Lomax asks Curly Putman about winning 'Song Of The Year' two years in a row. (10:07) -- John Lomax asks Curly Putman about whether he stills pitches his own tunes. Curly Putman mentions that he still pitches tunes occasionally. (10:52) -- John Lomax asks Curly Putman about whether he thinks he has songs that have been overlooked compared to his other popular compositions. (11:58) -- John Lomax asks Curly Putman about a songwriter's presence at a recording session. (13:22) -- John Lomax asks Curly Putman about what makes a great country song compared to other genres. Curly Putman mentions that a great country song has superb longevity.</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>audio cassette, compact;</dc:format>
<dc:format>1.75 ips;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CAS4694_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>CAS4694</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-09-09</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Putman, Curly;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9508</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>