<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Songwriter Session - Adam Hambrick and Justin Wilson - 2017-08-19</dc:title>
<dc:description>Performance by songwriters Adam Hambrick and Justin Wilson from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on August 19, 2017.  Includes questions from the audience.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2017-08-10</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Adam Hambrick; Justin Wilson;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Opening comments and songwriters introductions by Abi Tapia begin in progress / (02:55) Opening comments / (03:15) Song introduction / (04:26) Performs We Went (Justin Wilson) / (07:08) Song introduction / (08:46) Performs How Not To (Adam Hambrick) / (12:23) Song introduction / (14:14) Performs Life Ain't Fair (Justin Wilson) / (18:32) They answer question about favorite songs they wish they'd written / (20:24) Answers question about how songs are monetized and getting songs to artists / (23:15) Answers question about writing lyrics or music first / (25:18) Answers question about inspiration for song writing and the transition from writing by yourself to co-writing / (28:25) Answers question about artists changing the lyrics to their songs / (30:56) Performs unidentified song likely titled One Of Those Country Stars (Adam Hambrick) / (35:04) Song introduction / (36:17) Performs Later On (Justin Wilson) / (39:26) Song introduction /</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(41:12) Performs Somebody Else Will (Adam Hambrick) / (43:57) Closing comments / (44:23) Walk-out music / (45:06) FILE END   </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/24;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0057</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2018-08-08</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Hambrick, Adam; Wilson, Justin; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8053</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>