<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Pulsebeat Radio Show: Johnny Rodriguez</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of Kim Spangler (host) dictating the Pulsebeat section of the Voice of the Heartland Radio Show. The episode interviews Johnny Rodriguez (musician). The episode was set to air for the week of August 15, 1988.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1988-08-15</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Kim Spangler; Johnny Rodriguez</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:01) Kim Spangler introduces the upcoming Pulsebeat show with Johnny Rodriguez -- (00:44) Spangler praises the album: Gracias; additionally, Rodriguez reveals what caused a delay in its production -- (01:20) I Wanna Wake Up With You (Johnny Rodriguez) -- (04:32) Spangler reflects on Rodriguez's three year hiatus -- (04:43) Rodriguez reflects on recording "Deportee" with Johnny Cash and Willie Nelson -- (05:52) Deportee (Johnny Rodriguez, Willie Nelson, Johnny Cash) -- (09:18) Spangler introduces WWYN and others to the broadcast -- (09:42) Ronald Olson and David Page perform a Hot Stuff Show break about Joe Episcopo and Elvis Presley -- (11:00) Spangler introduces how Rodriguez started his career -- (11:12) Rodriguez reflects on how he had been caught stealing goats -- (12:52) Spangler welcomes back the audience and begins the discussion of where Rodriguez was in his life -- (13:22) Rodriguez reveals how he began his career with Tom T. Hall -- (14:15) I Didn't (Every Chance I Had) (Johnny Rodriguez) -- (17:21) Rodriguez says his biggest regrets was the goat situation -- (17:29) Pass Me By (Johnny Rodriguez) -- (19:45) Spangler introduces the commercial break -- (19:59) Spangler asks Rodriguez what song he would like to hear -- (20:17) Sunday Morning Coming Down (Johnny Cash) -- (24:16) Unidentified tune [featuring Kim Spangler outro discussion] ([Unidentified])</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-0962_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-0962</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-09-09</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Spangler, Kin; Rodriguez, Johnny;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9526</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>