<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>John Conlee Interview - Biff Collie</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of an interview with John Conlee (performer) conducted by Biff Collie.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1989-03-28</dc:date>
<dc:creator>John Conlee; Biff Collie</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Biff Collie introduces himself as John Conlee and Conlee introduces himself as Collie -- (00:15) Conlee talks about "Where Are The Pieces Of My Heart" and it's writer Huge Prestwood -- (00:46) Conlee talks about changing labels and "River Of Time" which he believes to be a song about age -- (02:06) Collie and Conlee talks about how a song "clicks" and listening to fifty or more tracks and narrowing his selections -- (03:08) Collie and Conlee talk about the artists that inspire his music and making sure to listen to as much as he possibly can -- (04:20) Collie talks about a story he heard about Conway (Twitty) listening to the sounds of his publishing office which leads to Conlee to talk about how they discovered a track on the album -- (05:13) Conlee describes an unidentified song as having a "cajun feel" -- (05:38) Conlee talks about love for blues listing Ray Charles, Aretha Franklin, and B.B.King as examples -- (06:07) Conlee talks about a song (I Had The Time And Money Too) that's based around people with oil money -- (06:54) Conlee talks about "Fellow Travelers" as a message of unity in the human race -- (07:28) Conlee talks about a song he enjoys, about how he avoids labels, and instead searches for quality music -- (08:58) Conlee talks about "Knowin' You Were Leavin'" as a breakup tune -- (09:26) "Don't Get Me Started" is discussed as a new song that has had great response despite have not being released yet -- (10:15) Conlee describes "Almost Free" as a story about a person having almost left their spouse but turning around at the last second -- (10:48) Conlee thanks Collie for his time on -- (10:55) Conlee confirms his bus type -- (11:03) Conlee says "Alright, hope so"</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1126_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1126</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-12-27</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Conlee, John; Collie, Biff;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8320</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>