<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Elizabeth Schlappi Roy Acuff collection audio tapes</dc:title>
<dc:description>Radio and television programs recorded off air in 1956 by Roy Acuff biographer Elizabeth Schlappi.  </dc:description>
<dc:date>1956mmdd</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Roy Acuff; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Recorded from television Opry TV Film -- Down South In New Orleans (Johnnie and Jack) excerpt -- Making Believe (Kitty Wells) -- Eight More Miles To Louisville (Grandpa Jones) excerpt -- Cotton-Eyed Joe (Cast) -- Grand Ole Opry from unknown date -- On And On (Bill Monroe and his Bluegrass Boys) -- Opry TV Film -- How To Catch A Man (Minnie Pearl) -- Knock It Off (Eddie Hill) excerpt -- No Help Wanted (Lonzo and Oscar with Cousin Jody) -- Remember Me (Commercial recording by Lee Moore and Juanita) -- Goodbye Mr. Brown (Commercial recording by Roy Acuff and Kitty Wells) -- Orange Blossom Special (Commercial recording by the Stanley Brothers) -- When They Cut Down The Old Pine Tree (Commercial recording by unidentified vocal group) -- You And Me (Commercial recording by Red Foley and Kitty Wells) -- Put My LIttle Shoes Away (Commercial recording by Bill Monroe and his Bluegrass Boys) -- Folsom Prison Blues (Commercial recording by Johnny Cash) -- I'd Rather Stay Home (Commercial recording by Kitty Wells) -- Rock Island Line (Comercial recording by Lonnnie Donegan) -- I Wish I Had A Nickle (Commercial recording by Hank Williams) excerpted -- Opry TV Film - Close By (Bill Monroe and his Bluegrass Boys) -- Moving On #2 (Lonzo and Oscar with Cousin Jody) -- Bald Headed End Of A Broom (Grandpa Jones) -- Crazy 'Bout You Baby (Lonzo and Oscar with Cousin Jody) -- Boil The Cabbage Down (Grandpa Jones and Ramona Jones) low level at beginning -- Bringing In The Sheaves (Credited on tape box as a commercial recording by the Jordanaires) -- Unidentified Television program -- Political Ballads and talk -- OPRY TV Film -- Charming Betsy (Lonzo and Oscar with Cousin Jody) -- The Cat Came Back (Commercial recording by Sonny James) Low level --  Play The Music Louder (Commercial recording by Curtis Gordon) excerpt and Low level -- Wildwood Flower (Commercial recording by unidentified artist)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4" analogue tape;</dc:format>
<dc:format>3.75 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-7-03132 side two</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2016-10-28</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Acuff, Roy; Johnnie and Jack (Musical group); Wells, Kitty; Jones, Grandpa, 1913-1998; Jones, Ramona; Minnie Pearl; Hill, Eddie, 1921-1994; Lonzo and Oscar; Monroe, Bill; Moore, Lee; Stanley brothers (Musical group); Foley, Red, 1910-1968; Cash, Johnny; Donegan, Lonnie; Jones, Ramona; Jordanaires (Musical group); James, Sonny; Gordon, Curtis; Williams, Hank, 1923-1953;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/4638</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>