<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Hank Snow's Canadian Show (Tape 2)</dc:title>
<dc:description>This recording features short snippets of songs by Hank Snow from his Canada tour. The recording also includes parts of the radio program Way Down East Music with Don Messer and his Islanders. The box includes a handwritten song list of what is included on this recording, written on Hank Snow letterhead. This is tape two of an unidentified number of tapes related to Hank Snow's Canada Show. This tape is thirty-three of an unidentified number of tapes.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Hank Snow; Don Messer; Margaret Osborn; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00 Wabash Cannonball [Fades out] (Hank Snow) -- (00:52) When My Blue Moon Turns Gold Again [Fades out] (Hanks Snow) -- (01:47) Who's Been Here Since I've Been Gone [Fades out] (Hank Snow) -- (02:34) To the End of the World [Fades out] (Hank Snow) -- (03:14) To the End of the World (Hank Snow) -- (03:56) Sing Me a Song of the Islands (Hank Snow) -- (04:33) No One Will Ever Know (Hank Snow) -- (05:26) Sorrow Struck Me One Morning (Hank Snow) -- (06:06) Unidentified tune (Unidentified) -- (06:22) Next song announced -- (06:30) The Old Homestead (Don Messer) -- (08:14) Next song announced -- (08:29) Along the Road to Boston (Unidentified) -- (10:14) Next song announced -- (10:21) The White Cockade (Unidentified) -- (11:20) Closing of the Way Down East Music with Don Messer and his Islanders -- (11:48) Rockin' to the Rockies [Fades out] (Hank Snow) -- (13:07) Unidentified tune (Don Messer and the Islanders) -- (13:58) Unidentified tune (Don Messer and the Islanders) -- (15:27) Announcer</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-7-02563_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-7-02563</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-09-09</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Snow, Hank; </dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9537</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>