<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Hank Williams: Beyond the Legend Part 1</dc:title>
<dc:description>Part 1 of 3. Recording is of the documentary Hank Williams: Beyond the Legend. Documentary is hosted by Kyle Cantrell and includes commentary Roy Acuff (performer), Minnie Pearl (performer), and Lycrecia Williams (daughter). </dc:description>
<dc:creator>Hank Williams Sr.; Minnie Pearl; Roy Acuff; Lycrecia Williams; Kyle Cantrell</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) An unknown duo hosts a commercial about checking one's cholesterol -- (00:59) Kyle Cantrell discusses New Year's Day in Nashville -- (03:09) Cantrell reveals that Hank Williams Sr. had died that day -- (03:56) Cantrell discusses Hank Williams Sr.'s influence thirty-five years later -- (4:24) I'll Never Get Out of This World Alive (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (06:47) Cantrell introduces the show title: Hank Williams, Beyond the Legend -- (07:11) Fruehauf Trailer commercial presented by an unknown voice -- (08:11) An unknown host delivers an eulogy for Hank Williams Sr. -- (09:24) Cantrell discusses the funeral of Williams Sr. -- (10:14) Roy Acuff performs his eulogy -- (12:06) I Saw the Light (Roy Acuff) -- (13:14) Cantrell reflects on who Williams was while introducing the commercial break -- (14:00) UNICEF commercial presented by an unknown voice -- (15:01) The National Automobile Dealers Association commercial presented by a duo of unknown voices -- (16:00)  Music Country Radio Network commercial presented by an unknown voice -- (16:30) Jambalaya (On the Bayou) [featuring Cantrell voice over] (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (19:19) Cantrell reflects on William's writing career and the mysteries behind his death -- (21:04) An unknown voice describes the circumstances leading up to Williams Sr.'s death; including how Williams Sr. was given medicine due to his intoxication -- (24:24) Cantrell reflects on how he was given medicine, and how Williams was not as the media portrayed him as -- (25:14) Whistler Truckers Move America (Unconfirmed) [featuring an unknown voiceover] ([Unidentified])-- (26:15) The Nashville Network commercial introducing their upcoming events on New Country -- (27:15) Cantrell reflects on what makes Williams Sr. an interesting character -- (28:35) Cherokee Boogie (recorded for WSM) (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (31:25) Cantrell discusses why people were attracted to Williams Sr.'s singing style -- (32:50) Cantrell introduces the commercial break -- (33:00) Public service announcement about proper driving practices presented by Tom Bodett -- (34:02) The Boy Scouts of America commercial break presented by an Ben Love -- (35:02) Music Country Radio Network commercial presented by an unknown voice -- (35:31) Cantrell introduces Williams young life [featuring Williams Sr. background music] -- (36:54) Minnie Pearl reflects on the time Williams Sr. received a large scar from a fight -- (37:17) Cantrell reflects on Williams Sr.'s parents (specifically Lillie Williams) -- (37:54) The Old Log Train (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (40:14) Goodies Headache Powder commercial presented by Reba McEntire [featuring "How Blue"] -- (41:13) Dello commercial presented by Jackie Robinson -- (42:13) Cantrell discusses when Williams Sr. first tried alcohol and his association with country music -- (45:35) Don Helms jokes about the requirements Williams Sr. required for Helms to join his band -- (46:10) Cantrell discusses how Lillian's relationship with Williams Sr. changed when he met Audrey Williams -- (47:40) Baby, We're Really in Love (Hank Williams) -- (50:11) Cantrell introduces Audrey's daughter (50:26) Lycrecia Williams reflects on Williams Sr.'s alcoholism -- (51:21) Cantrell introduces the commercial break -- (51:32) Co-op Education commercial presented by an unknown voice -- (52:34) [Unknown jingle] -- (53:02) Lycrecia continues to speak on Williams Sr.'s alcoholism -- (53:15) Cantrell introduces the upcoming schedule of the show -- (53:29) The National Cholesterol Education Program commercial presented by an unknown voice -- (54:29) [Unknown Jingle] -- (54:56) Remainder of tape is reversed and includes a rendition of "Blue Christmas;" segment is unrelated to tape</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1421_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1421</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-03-29</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Williams, Hank, 1923-1953; Williams, Hank, 1923-1953. I saw the light; Williams, Lycrecia, 1941-; Pearl, Minnie; McEntire, Reba; McEntire, Reba, 1955-; Acuff, Roy; Acuff, Roy, Jr., 1943-; Cantrell, Kyle;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8727</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>