<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Tom T. Hall Interview by Bob Allen 1-15-82 - Tape Two, Side One</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is an interview of Tom T. Hall by Bob Allen. The interview takes place on 1-15-82.   </dc:description>
<dc:date>1982-01-15</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Tom T. Hall;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Tape Two, Side One - (0:00) -- Bob Allen asks Tom T. Hall about a particularly tumultuous period of his life. (0:45) -- Tom T. Hall discusses his family's lineage. (2:14) -- Tom T. Hall speaks of his anger about his mother's passing. (5:10) -- Bob Allen speaks about walking to the school bus each morning. Bob Allen and Tom T. Hall discuss whether privileged children will reflect about their past the same as those who didn't have heat, air, or carpeting growing up. (7:00) -- Bob Allen asks Tom T. Hall about his song "The Hitchhiker." (8:08) -- Tom T. Hall tells a story about picking up a hitchhiker in his jeep. (11:15) -- Bob Allen asks Tom T. Hall if he identifies with his characters' lives from his music. Tom T. Hall responds that he tries to keep his ego away from his songwriting and only tell the story from an objectively neutral perspective. (15:21) -- Bob Allen asks Tom T. Hall about his songs "Turn It On, Turn It On, Turn It On" and "The Man Who Shot Himself." (18:24) -- Continued discussion about the song "The Man Who Shot Himself." (19:45) -- Bob Allen asks Tom T. Hall to compare his current songwriting to his older songwriting. Bob Allen mentions that critics are saying that his newer songwriting lacks the same amount of "substance." Tom T. Hall responds that he believes that to be true, but only because he's changed drastically and aged. Tom T. Hall compares this situation to football (Joe Namath). (25:23) -- Tom T. Hall speaks about how his success bars him from entering smaller songwriting circles. (29:59) -- Tom T. Hall speaks about the large percentage of those who lack heat &amp; basic comfort in an incredibly rich nation. (31:28) -- Tom T. Hall speaks about taxes and his political views. (34:46) -- Tom T. Hall speaks about the corruption of the distribution of wealth in America. (35:08) -- Bob Allen asks how many political songwriters were around when Tom T. Hall first came to Nashville. (36:36) -- Tom T. Hall speaks about his childhood poverty. (40:02) -- Bob Allen asks Tom T. Hall about the wandering years of his life after he left the army. "I knew I was too young to die, and not old enough to accept any responsibility" - Tom T. Hall. (43:54) -- Bob Allen asks Tom T. Hall about performing while in the army. </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>audio cassette, compact;</dc:format>
<dc:format>1.75 ips;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CAS4732_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>CAS4732</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-09-13</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Hall, Tom T.;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9597</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>