<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Hallmarks of Country Music - Marty Robbins</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of an interview of Marty Robbins (musician). The interview is hosted by Rick Phillips (army sergeant/ radio host) for the Hallmarks of Country Music segment. The tape was recorded on an unidentified date.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Marty Robbins; Rick Phillips</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) El Paso [featuring Marty Robbins and Rick Phillips voiceover] (Marty Robbins) -- (00:45) El Paso [featuring Marty Robbins and Rick Phillips voiceover] (Marty Robbins) -- (01:28) Hallmarks tune [featuring Rick Phillips introduction voiceover] ([Unidentified]) -- (02:03) U.S. Customs commercial spot hosted by an unidentified host -- (02:58) Devil Woman (Marty Robbins) -- (04:32) Rick Phillips introduces Marty Robbins, and both discuss Robbins' racing career -- (06:43) Ribbon of Darkness (Marty Robbins) -- (08:59) Rick Phillips radio spot for the Fort Lee meal card tests -- (09:43) Singing the Blues (Marty Robbins) -- (10:45) Phillips inquires as to what inspired "Singing the Blues;" additionally, Robbins' association to the Grand Ole Opry is discussed -- (13:17) I Walk Alone (Marty Robbins) -- (15:10) Phillips radio spot for the Minnesota National Guard recruiting jobs -- (15:43) Don't Worry (Marty Robbins) -- (18:41) Phillips introduces "Don't Worry" and Robbins associates it to a memory from the Grand Ole Opry -- (20:49) Phillips and Robbins reflect on the change of Robbins' career when songs like "White Sport Coat" hit the charts -- (21:27) White Sport Coat (Marty Robbins) -- (23:52) Safety radio spot hosted by Phillips -- (24:21) Story of My Life (Marty Robbins) -- (26:47) Lonesome Blues [featuring Retention radio spot hosted by Faron Young] (Faron Young) -- (29:19) Big Iron (Marty Robbins) -- (33:08) Feron Young reflects on his time in the military -- (34:22) My Woman, My Woman, My Wife (Marty Robbins) -- (37:42) Robbins reflect on his heart attack when recalling "My Woman, My Woman, My Wife" -- (39:33) Love Me (Marty Robbins) -- (42:07) United States Environmental Protection Agency commercial spot hosted by an unidentified voice -- (43:06) Tonight Carman (Marty Robbins) -- (45:49) Phillips asks Robbins how he became the host of Midnight Special; additionally, the timing of "El Paso" is discussed -- (49:45) El Paso (Marty Robbins) -- (53:57) Phillips praises Robbins and performs an Exchange Travel Information commercial spot -- (54:55) Hallmarks outro tune ([Unidentified]) -- (56:29) Phillips introduces guest disc jockey: Mark Edwards -- (57:41) Phillips and Edwards discuss the instrumentation George Jones had started performing; additionally, Phillips inquires about the acceptance of country music in Chicago -- (59:31) The hype behind Don Drum is reflected on, and Edwards declares that "Who Am I," by Charley Pride, is the focus of the week -- (1:01:05) Phillips and Edwards say their goodbyes</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Insert is of program information. The insert features time stamps.</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1621_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1621</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-06-10</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Robbins, Marty; Phillips, Rick;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9068</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>