<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Chet Atkins Interviewed by Bob Allen Side One</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of Bob Allen interviewing Chet Atkins. The recording takes place on 10-31-78.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1978-10-31</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Chet Atkins</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Side One - (0:24) -- Bob Allen asks Chet Atkins how much time he spends in his office as of late. (0:51) -- Bob Allen asks Chet Atkins what his daily schedule is like. (2:05) -- Chet Atkins describes his home studio. (2:17) -- Bob Allen asks about what it's like for Chet to appear in public at restaurants or clubs. (4:44) -- Chet Atkins describes his typical day and morning routine. (6:50) -- Bob Allen asks Chet Atkins how many hours a day he practices. Chet Atkins describes that he most often practices material and tunes from upcoming shows. (9:18) -- Chet Atkins describes that he listens to other instruments more than guitar players. Chet Atkins explains that guitar is a limited instrument compared to piano. (10:42) -- Bob Allen asks Chet what music he most often listens to. "I like to hear people improvise&#8230;subsitution chords/ideas&#8230;Bill Evans type piano player." (12:55) -- Bob Allen asks Chet Atkins how many shows he plays each year. (15:41) -- Bob Allen mentions that Larrie Londin thanks Chet Atkins and Jerry Reed for giving him work. "For me, he's my favorite drummer." - Chet Atkins. (17:06) -- Bob Allen asks about Chet Atkins traveling on tour. Chet goes on to describe his distaste with flying. (20:21) -- Bob Allen asks about Chet's personal outside habits. Chet Atkins mentions his love for golf. (21:18) -- Tape cuts to Bob Allen and Chet Atkins at a benefit. (23:07) -- Chet Atkins mentions his distaste for train rides. (24:30) -- Bob Allen asks Chet Atkins about his mail. (26:50) -- Bob Allen asks about Chet Atkins' transition between recording and being an A&amp;R man. (27:55) -- Chet Atkins speaks about Steve Sholes. (29:22) -- Chet Atkins speaks about Owen Bradley. Owen Bradley was an assistant to Paul Cohen for years. Chet mentions that he was working as an A&amp;R man before Owen. (31:41) -- Chet Atkins describes Owen Bradley starting a film studio for commercials. Owen ended up recording more than he worked with film. (33:08) -- Chet Atkins mentions the RCA 1525 McGavock studio with a curved roof. (33:49) -- Chet Atkins mentions recording on homemade tape machines running at 30 ips. (34:24) -- Chet describes Jim Reeves' desire to have a closer sound. (35:37) -- Bob Allen asks Chet Atkins how producing has changed over the years. Chet mentions that Steve Sholes was the first one to put "produced by" on a record. (36:48) -- Chet Atkins discusses how Steve Sholes influenced him. (38:00) -- Bob Allen asks about the costs of running a session in 1978. (41:12) -- Chet Atkins discusses how Nashville has changed since he arrived.</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>audio cassette, compact;</dc:format>
<dc:format>1.75 ips;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CAS4654_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>CAS4654</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-08-23</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Atkins, Chet;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9402</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>