<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Grand Ole Opry - Prince Albert - 1955-08-20 - Part 2</dc:title>
<dc:description>Part 2 of Prince Albert tobacco sponsored Grand Ole Opry segment from August 20, 1955. Featuring Grant Turner (announcer), Cowboy Copas (host/performer), guest performer Jim Wilson with his daughter June, and regular performers Rod Brasfield, Moon Mullican, Minnie Pearl, and Grandpa Jones. Held at Ryman Auditorium, Nashville, TN.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1955-08-20</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Minnie Pearl; Jim Wilson; Grandpa Jones; Cowboy Copas</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Cowboy Copas introduces Minnie Pearl -- Comedy routine (Minnie Pearl, Cowboy Copas) -- Cowboy Copas introduces Jim Wilson -- The Farmer And The Lord (Jim Wilson) -- Cowboy Copas introduces Grandpa Jones -- Are You From Dixie (Grandpa Jones) -- Cowboy Copas talks -- Tragic Romance (Cowboy Copas) -- Closing theme -- Closing statement (Cowboy Copas) -- Cavalier Cigarettes commercial -- Station announcements</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>16 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR000082</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2005-06-08</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); National Broadcasting Company; Grand ole opry (Radio program); Ryman Auditorium (Nashville, Tenn.); Turner, Grant; Copas, Cowboy; Brasfield, Rod; Minnie Pearl; Mullican, Moon, 1909-1967; Jones, Grandpa, 1913-1998; Wilson, Jim (Musician)</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/1011</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>