<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Grand Ole Opry - Prince Albert - 1957-07-13 - Part 1</dc:title>
<dc:description>Part 1 of Prince Albert tobacco sponsored Grand Ole Opry segment from July 13, 1957. Featuring Grant Turner (announcer), Hawkshaw Hawkins (host/performer), guest performers the Everly Brothers, and regular performers Rod Brasfield, Tommy Jackson, Chet Atkins, June Carter, and Stringbean. Held at Ryman Auditorium, Nashville, TN. On this show Archie Bleyer, president of Cadence Records, presents the Everly Brothers with a gold record for 'Bye Bye Love', for surpassing 1,000,000 sales. It is announced that this is the 927th broadcast.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1957-07-13</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Hawkshaw Hawkins; Rod Brasfield; Everly Brothers; Tommy Jackson; Chet Atkins</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Grant Turner introduces Hawkshaw Hawkins -- I'll Be Gone (Hawkshaw Hawkins) -- Opening statement (Grant Turner, Hawkshaw Hawkins) -- Hawkshaw Hawkins introduces Rod Brasfield -- Comedy routine (Rod Brasfield, Hawkshaw Hawkins) -- Hawkshaw Hawkins introduces the Everly Brothers -- Bye Bye Love (Everly Brothers) -- Prince Albert commercial (Rod Brasfield, Hawkshaw Hawkins) -- Hawkshaw Hawkins introduces Tommy Jackson -- Old Joe Clark (Tommy Jackson fiddle) -- Hawkshaw Hawkins talks -- Just A Closer Walk With Thee (Hawkshaw Hawkins) -- Hawkshaw Hawkins introduces Chet Atkins -- Oh By Jingo! (Chet Atkins)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>16 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR000279</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2005-11-21</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); National Broadcasting Company; United States. Armed Forces Radio Service; Grand ole opry (Radio program); Ryman Auditorium (Nashville, Tenn.); Turner, Grant; Brasfield, Rod; Atkins, Chet; Stringbean, 1915-1973; Cash, June Carter, 1929-2003; Jackson, Tommy; Bleyer, Archie; Hawkins, Hawkshaw, 1921-1963; Everly Brothers; Everly, Don, 1937-; Everly, Phil, 1939-2014</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/1220</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>