<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Ernest Ridgeway and Roy Harper performances - Columbia State Community College - 1982-08-24</dc:title>
<dc:description>Performances of various tunes by the Ernest Ridgeway String Band (performers), Roy Harper (performer), Frazier Moss (performer), Kris Allen (performer) and dancing performed by Robert Spicer and Judy Shaver on August 24, 1982 at Columbia State Community College in Columbia, Tennessee.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1982-08-24</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Ernest Ridgeway String Band; Robert Spicer; Judy Shaver; Roy Harper; Frazier Moss; Kris Allen</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>[Unidentified tune] -- [Unidentified] talks -- [Unidentified tune] (Ernest Ridgeway String Band) -- Ernest Ridgeway talks -- Robert Spicer talks about his dancing background and the different types of dances that match different styles of music and their histories -- Spicer talks about flat foot dancing and its history -- [Unidentified tune] (Ernest Ridgeway String Band, Robert Spicer vocals) -- [Unidentified tune] (Ernest Ridgeway String Band) -- [Unidentified] asks about Ridgeway's style of playing -- Ridgeway says how his sound embodies both old and new styles of string music -- [Unidentified tune] (Ernest Ridgeway String Band) -- [Unidentified] asks about the dancing -- Judy Shaver explains the differences between styles of dancing -- Shaver demonstrates a few of the moves -- Robert Spicer introduces the dancers -- Shaver talks about how long she has been dancing -- [Unidentified tune] (Ernest Ridgeway String Band) -- Ernest Ridgeway talks about future performances -- [Unidentified tune] (Ernest Ridgeway String Band) -- Walkin' In My Sleep (Roy Harper) -- Harper talks about Arthur Smith -- Cotton Mill Blues (Roy Harper) -- Harper talks about how much he enjoys playing  and introduces the next tune -- Tell It To Me (Roy Harper) -- Harper talks about his musical background and introduces the next tune -- When The Roses Bloom Again (Roy Harper) -- Roy Harper introduces the next tune -- Over The River Again (Roy Harper) -- Harper talks about old styles of song writing -- Child Of Fighting (Roy Harper) [unconfirmed] -- Harper introduces the next tune -- Hangman Slack The Rope (Roy Harper) -- Harper introduces the next tune -- Letter Edged In Black (Roy Harper) -- Harper thanks the audience for listening and introduces the next tune -- There My Poor Darling Lies (Roy Harper) -- [Unidentified] talks (incomplete) -- Frazier Moss talks about Kris Allen playing with him and she responds -- Moss talks about the some of the history of the fiddle -- Whiskey Before Breakfast (Frazier Moss fiddle, Kris Allen guitar) -- Moss talks about the different types of fiddle music and talks about spreading folk music -- Sharon's Waltz (Frazier Moss fiddle, Kris Allen guitar) -- Moss says polka is his favorite fiddle music -- Jesse Polka (Frazier Moss fiddle, Kris Allen guitar) -- [Unidentified] talks -- Moss talks about why he wanted to learn to play the fiddle and how he is self taught -- Red Wing (Frazier Moss fiddle, Kris Allen vocals, guitar) -- Moss invites Kris Allen to play a fiddle duet -- What A Friend We Have In Jesus (Frazier Moss fiddle, Kris Allen fiddle) -- Moss talks about the difference between a fiddle and a violin -- [Unidentified tune] (Frazier Moss fiddle, Kris Allen guitar) -- Moss invites a dancer to perform to the next tune -- Lost Indian (Frazier Moss fiddle, Kris Allen guitar) -- Moss introduces the next tune as a hornpipe -- Fisher's Hornpipe (Frazier Moss fiddle, Kris Allen guitar) -- Moss introduces the next tune -- [Unidentified tune] (Frazier Moss fiddle, Kris Allen guitar) -- Moss talks about how much he loves playing and introduces the next tune -- Grey Eagle (Frazier Moss fiddle, Kris Allen guitar) -- Moss talks about Thomas Jefferson playing the fiddle -- Rachel's Hornpipe (Frazier Moss fiddle, Kris Allen guitar) -- Moss thanks the audience for listening -- Orange Blossom Special (Frazier Moss fiddle, Kris Allen guitar) -- Moss talks about his new album -- Boil Them Cabbage Down ([Unidentified] fiddle, Kris Allen guitar) -- Moss talks about why he reaches out to the youth about folk music and praises the young girl for playing -- [Unidentified] talks about the CMF's initiative to preserve folk music</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 4 quarter tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-0295_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-0295</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-02-08</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Spicer, Robert; Harper, Roy; Moss, Frazier; Allen, Kris;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/6852</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>