<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Studio Recordings - Merle Haggard - 1966 - 1972</dc:title>
<dc:description>Capitol records unreleased masters of Merle Haggard.  Also includes dubs from released masters later in Haggard's career at end of tape.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1966; 1967; 1968; 1969; 1970; 1971; 1972</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Merle Haggard; The Strangers; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) White Line Fever (master number 77204 recorded on 1969-04-09) / (02:56) Hang Up My Gloves (master number 56059 recorded on 1966-06-02) / (05:40) Jimmie The Kid (master number 71717 recorded on 1969-01-22 and released by Bear Family) / (07:48) Trouble In Mind (master number 74246 recorded on 1970-04-06) / (11:10) I'll Be A Hero When I Strike (74246 on 1970-03-25) / (13:20) You Don't Need To Love Me (But I'll Always Care) (master number 77664 recorded on 1971-09-11) / (16:53) When My Conscience Takes Over - Possibly not Haggard  (master number 80770 recorded on 1972-10-17) / (19:11) There You Go Again - Possibly not Haggard (master number 80774 recorded on 1972-10-18) / (21:47) News Break (master number 58692 recorded on 1967-11-17 and released by Bear Family) / (23:15) California On My Mind (master number 72200 recorded on 1969-04-08) / (25:59) Lookin' For My Mind (master number 59749 on 1968-05-09 and released by Bear Family) / (28:17) I Ain't Got Nobody (master number 74206 recorded on 1970-03-23) / </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(30:28) excerpt of New Spanish Two Step (info not listed) / (30:56) That's The Way Love Goes (info not listed) / </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>RDAT digital tape;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RS.2014.0161</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2018-01-18</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Haggard, Merle; Capitol Records, Inc; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/6615</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>