<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Willie Nelson interview part 3 - Biff Collie Inside Nashville</dc:title>
<dc:description>Part three of a recording of an interview with Willie Nelson (performer), conducted by Biff Collie (host) for his radio program Inside Nashville.</dc:description>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Biff Collie asks about Willie Nelson's athletic interests -- Willie Nelson talks about playing golf (incomplete) -- Nelson talks about the people he goes on tour with -- Nelson talks about how Elvis popularized security traveling with music stars -- Nelson talks about how many of his old friends go on tour with him -- Nelson talks about Chet Atkins and a new guitar he made -- Nelson talks about Jimmy Carter being a friend of his and him being a great man -- Nelson talk about being hesitant to take Charlie Pride to Texas because of his ethnicity, but doing it anyway -- Nelson talks about not wanting to follow Pride because of how much the crowd loved him -- Nelson talks about Leon Russell being the greatest entertainer he knows -- Nelson talks about Paul English being his oldest, closest friend, and being his drummer -- Nelson talks about Kris Kristofferson being the finest writer around in the country music scene -- Nelson talks about Tom Paul Glaser being one of the original Outlaws -- Nelson talks about what it means to be an Outlaw, which is to go against the norm -- Nelson talks about Darryl Roy being the greatest country music fan in the world -- Nelson talks about needed a lot of time to talk about Hank Cochran, he is a friend and a great songwriter -- Nelson talks about some times he got fired from jobs -- Nelson talks about being a disc jockey -- Nelson talks about Ray Price being one of his first bosses and playing bass for him -- Nelson talks about being in favor of religion and that he used to teach Sunday school -- Nelson talks about religious people getting carried away with their own importance -- Nelson talks about believing in reincarnation and heaven and hell being within our own minds -- Nelson says eternity is now, and it is impossible for energy to die -- Nelson says his favorite hymn is Precious Memories -- Nelson talks about telling a story in his songs over the course of his life -- Nelson talks about Charlie Daniels being a great friend and a great musician -- Nelson talks about Johnny Cash in the same way -- Nelson talks about Larry Gatlin being a great songwriter and singer (incomplete)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-7-03968_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-7-03968</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-06-27</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Collie, Biff; Nelson, Willie, 1933-;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/7706</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>