<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Ralph Emery Show: Oak Ridge Boys - 1984-06-27  Parts 4-5</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recordings are of the Ralph Emery Show. The show is hosted by Ralph Emery (entertainer), and features Emery in discussion with his guest: the Oak Ridge Boys (musical group). The Oak Ridge Boys members featured are Richard Sterban, William Lee, Duane Allen and Joe Bonsall. The show was recorded on June 27, 1984. The recordings are for parts four and five, of five parts, of Emery's interview of the Oak Ridge Boys.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1984-06-27</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Oak Ridge Boys; Ralph Emery</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Ralph Emery introduces Oak Ridge Boys members: Richard Sterban, William Lee, Duane Allen, and Joe Bonsall; additionally, Emery asks Allen to introduce Hank Williams Jr.'s "Attitude Adjustment" -- (01:08) Emery has the Oak Ridge Boys reflect on how "Thank God for Kids" is associated with Christmas, and how the Oak Ridge Boys have had disagreements -- (06:38) Emery has Sterban introduce Barbara Mandrell -- (07:07) Emery has Sterban reflect on how he was beat by Mandrell in a foot race and "Come on in" -- (09:45) Emery and the Oak Ridge Boys praise T. G. Sheppard -- (11:31) Emery inquires about tee pee etiquette -- (19:21) Emery says goodbye to the Oak Ridge Boys -- (19:51) The Oak Ridge Boys joke about feeling ill -- (20:55) Emery introduces the Oak Ridge Boys -- (21:17) Emery asks Bonsall to recall how they had their names enshrined in the Walkway of Stars, and Emery asks about D-Day -- (24:45) Emery invites the Oak Ridge Boys to discuss "Leaving Louisiana in the Broad Daylight," and all reflect on the overuse of "Elvira" -- (30:58) Lee introduces "Heart of Mine" -- (32:15) Emery inquires to the musical connections of "Loves Me Like a Rock" -- (34:39) The Oak Ridge Boys harmonize and praise Paul Simon -- (36:00) "Heaven Bound" is praised, for its message, by Emery; additionally, Emery has the Oak Ridge Boys reflect on their gospel recordings -- (38:23) Emery inquires as to where the Oak Ridge Boys' members were born and the status of "Lonely Heart" -- (40:52) Emery and the Oak Ridge Boys say goodbye</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1465_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1465</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-07-15</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Emery, Ralph; Oak Ridge Boys;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9262</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>