<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>NBC Bandstand - 1958-12-05 - Part 4</dc:title>
<dc:description>Part 4 of NBC Bandstand radio show hosted by Bert Parks, with Skitch Henderson and Dody Goodman. Originally broadcast December 5, 1958, and featuring WSM and Grand Ole Opry musicians to celebrate the 1000th Opry broadcast including announcer Dave Overton, Marvin Hughes and the WSM Orchestra, the Anita Kerr Quartet, Don Gibson, Dottie Dillard, Minnie Pearl, Faron Young, Hank Garland, and the Jordanaires. It is mentioned (in part 2) that KSTP of Minneapolis, MN is celebrating its thirtieth year as an NBC affiliate, and David Stone (former WSM announcer) is noted as the MC of KSTP's Sunset Valley Barn Dance.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1958-12-05</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Marvin Hughes; WSM Orchestra; Faron Young; Don Gibson; Jordanaires; Anita Kerr Quartet</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Bert Parks introduces Marvin Hughes and the WSM Orchestra -- Jingle Bells (excerpt) (Marvin Hughes and the WSM Orchestra) -- Wrigley's Spearmint Gum commercial -- Bert Parks announces the history of the Grand Ole Opry -- Alone With You (Faron Young) -- Hand lotion commercial (Madeleine Carroll) -- Bert Parks and Skitch Henderson tell how the Opry got its name -- Bert Parks and Don Gibson talk -- Give Myself A Party (Don Gibson, Jordanaires) -- Vicks VapoRub commercial (Bert Parks) -- Bert Parks and Skitch Henderson thank the Nashville crew -- Q-tips commercial (Bert Parks, Skitch Henderson) -- Bert Parks introduces the Anita Kerr Quartet -- Mama's Gone, Goodbye (Anita Kerr Quartet) -- Closing theme -- Closing statement (Bert Parks, Dave Overton)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>16 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR000638_2</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>TR000638</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2006-09-13</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>National Broadcasting Company; WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); Parks, Bert; Henderson, Skitch, 1918-2005; Goodman, Dody; Overton, Dave; Anita Kerr Quartet; Minnie Pearl; Young, Faron; Jordanaires (Musical group); Gibson, Don (Donald Eugene), 1928-2003; Dillard, Dottie; Hughes, Marvin; WSM Orchestra; Devine, Ott, 1910-1994; Stone, David P., 1901-1995; Carroll, Madeleine, 1906-1987</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/2063</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>