<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Performance - Mac Gayden - 2018-02-12</dc:title>
<dc:description>Performance by Mac Gayden from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on February 12, 2018.  In support of the exhibition Dylan, Cash and the Nashville Cats.  </dc:description>
<dc:date>2018-02-12</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Mac Gayden; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Unidentified song begins in progress (Mickey Raphael on harmonica) / (01:53) Mac talks about Mickey Raphael / (02:16) Introduction of the band by Oceana Gayden.  Band members include Chuck Foster-keyboards, Billy Mercer-bass, Mac Gayden Jr-guitar, Dave Scalia-drums, Alex Libre (sic) -guitar, Vicki Caraco and Etta Britt-vocalists along with Oceana Gayden / (03:27) Performs Come To Me Tonight / (08:21) Introduction of Diane Davidson / (08:35) Comments from Diane / (09:19) Performs Ain't Gonna Be Treated This Way / (14:25) Introduces the next song / (14:51) Performs Blood Is Not The Answer / (19:07) Performs 12 O'Clock High / (23:40) Introduces the next song / (24:15) Performs Back Fencing / (29:46)  Introduces the next song and acknowledgements from Oceana / (31:48) Performs Crazy Mama / (35:37) Intros the next song / (36:27) Performs The Minstrel Is Free At Last / (45:56) Show end comments / (45:03) Introduces the next song / (46:07) Performs She Shot A Hole In My Soul /           </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents> (49:39) Abrupt END            </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/24;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0096</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2018-11-15</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Gayden, Mac; Davidson, Dianne; Raphael, Mickey; </dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8251</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>