<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Pulsebeat Radio Show: David Lynn Jones - Part 1</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of Kim Spangler (host) dictating the Pulsebeat section of the Voice of the Heartland Radio Show. The episode interviews David Lynn Jones (musician). The episode was set to air for the week of July 25, 1988. The episode is part 1 of 2.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1988-07-25</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Kim Spangler; David Lynn Jones</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:01) Kim Spangler introduces the upcoming David Lynn Jones Pulsebeat show -- (00:50) Spangler reveals how she visited Jones at his small home in Arkansas -- (01:46) Jones reflects on how surprised he was that Willie Nelson chose his song to record -- (02:22) Living in the Promised Land (Willie Nelson) -- (05:20) Spangler introduces the commercial break -- (05:35) Spangler introduces Jones who reflects on experiencing large cities -- (06:18) The Rouge (David Lynn Jones) -- (09:56) Spangler greets the new networks -- (10:14) Ron Olson and David Page discuss the news of the week including: Gilley's court battle and a Michigan-based concert -- (11:30) Jones is introduced by Spangler to discuss how "Bonnie Jean" was written for his daughter -- (12:15) Bonnie Jean (David Lynn Jones) -- (15:28) Spangler and Jones discuss Jones' Mother's reaction to the album -- (16:31) Home of My Heart (David Lynn Jones) -- (19:52) Spangler introduces the commercial break -- (20:11) Spangler reveals that Charlie Daniels was one of the first people who took a chance on Jones -- (20:50) Stay All Night (Stay a Little Longer) (Charlie Daniels) -- (24:25) Unidentified tune [featuring Kim Spangler outro discussion] ([Unidentified])</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-0966_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-0966</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-09-09</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Spangler, Kim; Jones, David Lynn;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9520</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>