<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Grand Ole Opry Network Broadcast</dc:title>
<dc:description>This recording is of the Grand Ole Opry radio program, sponsored by Prince Albert tobacco. The recording is from November 20, 1954. This tape features Hank Snow, Carl Smith, Gene Autry, Minnie Pearl, Rodney Brasfield, the Carlisles, and Webb Pierce. Tape is the fourth of an unidentified number of tapes.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1954-11-20</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Carl Smith; Gene Autry; Hank Snow ; Webb Pierce; Carlisles; Minnie Pearl; Rod Brasfield; Grant Turner; Grandpa Jones</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Adjusting of the channel between football game and Martha White's flour commercial -- (00:57) Commercial for Harvey's (01:27) Beginning of the Grand Ole Opry program -- (02:14) Loose Talk (Carl Smith) -- (04:48) Host, Grant Turner, welcomes disc jockeys for convention -- (05:04) No Help Wanted (Carlisles) -- (06:29) Prince Albert (P.A.) tobacco commercial -- (07:38) Grant Turner introduces and talks to Gene Autry -- (09:18) Gene Autry introduces song write Johnny Marks and the song he composed "Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer" -- (09:44) Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer (Gene Autry) -- (11:42) Grant Turner introduces Hank Snow -- (11:56) Hank Snow thanks disc jockeys -- (12:24) I Don't Hurt Anymore (Hank Snow) -- (15:17) Commercial for PA tobacco with Grant Turner and Hank Snow -- (16:29) Square dancing with Dale Potter -- (17:28) Gene Autry introduces Minnie Pearl and Rod Brasfield -- (18:18) Minnie Pearl talks to the audience and Gene Autry -- (18:56) Minnie Pearl and Rodney Brasfield talk and joke -- (21:40) Grant Turner reintroduces and talks to Gene Autry -- (22:31) Gene Autry introduces Merle Travis and Johnny Bond -- (23:34) Tweedle-O-Twill (Gene Autry) -- (25:05) Mountain Dew (Grandpa Jones) -- (26:19) Grant Turner introduces Webb Pierce --  (26:33) Webb Pierce thanks disc jockeys -- (26:50) More and More (Webb Pierce) -- (29:06) Honoring the third annual convention of the country music disc jockeys of America and the 29th anniversary of the Grand Ole Opry -- (29:28) Preview of next weeks show and good bye</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-7-02534_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-7-02534</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-08-28</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Smith, Carl; Smith, Carl, 1927-2010; Autry, Gene, 1907-1998; Snow, Hank; Pierce, Webb, 1921-1991; Carlisles (Musical group); Pearl, Minnie; Brasfield, Rod; Brasfield, Rod, 1910-1958; Turner, Grant; Grandpa Jones; Grandpa Jones, 1913-1998; Grand Ole Opry (Radio program);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9428</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>