<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Various interviews - Keith Bilbrey - WSM</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of interviews and phone conversations with Randy Travis (performer), George Jones (performer), Charlie Daniels (performer), Keith Whitley (performer), Lorrie Morgan (performer), Holly Dunn (performer), Mickey Gilley (performer), Vanna White, and Hoyt Axton (performer), conducted by Keith Bilbrey (DJ) on radio station WSM (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:description>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Keith Bilbrey introduces Randy Travis -- Randy Travis talks about taking a break from touring and stopping in Nashville -- Travis talks about playing at the Opry when he stops into town -- Travis talks about being inducted into the Opry -- Travis talks about rarely having time to relax with all his success -- Travis talks about working at the Palace before his career took off -- Travis talks about not being treated differently after gaining success in his hometown -- Keith Bilbrey introduces George Jones -- George Jones talks about how great he thinks Randy Travis is -- Bilbrey forces a commercial break -- Jones talks about Randy Travis' new album and says that its the greatest country album he has heard in decades -- Randy Travis thanks Jones and talks about working with him for the first time -- Jones talks about it being the other way around next time -- Keith Bilbrey talks about it being Charlie Daniels birthday -- Bilbrey introduces Brent Stoker, Kyle Cantrell, and other female office workers -- the staff sings acapella to Charlie Daniels over the phone -- Charlie Daniels thanks the staff -- Bilbrey introduces Keith Whitley and Lorrie Morgan -- Whitley and Morgan talk about just getting married and going on their honeymoon -- Whitley does a Lester Flatt impersonation -- Whitley talks about covering various songs with his Lester Flatt impersonation -- Whitley sings a little Rub It In as Lester Flatt -- Whitley talks about his songwriters -- Whitley talks about performing Farewell Party -- Bilbrey introduces Holly Dunn -- Dunn talks -- Yvonne Dunn talks about Holly having a song on the top 10 -- Yvonne Dunn talks about Holly's father and friends being so excited for Holly -- Frank Dunn talks about being the subject of Daddy's Hands by Holly Dunn -- Frank Dunn talks about not being ashamed to share this with others and how surprised they were when Holly left home for Nashville -- Bilbrey talks about it being Mickey Gilley's birthday -- Gilley thanks Bilbrey -- the staff sings happy birthday for Mickey Gilley -- Vanna White talks about the weather in California -- White talks about visiting Nashville -- Bilbrey talks about it being Hoyt Axton's birthday -- Axton talks about being 49 -- Bilbrey puts Axton's mother on the line to wish him a happy birthday (incomplete)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-7-04026_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-7-04026</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-07-12</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); Bilbrey, Keith; Travis, Randy; Jones, George, 1931-2013; Daniels, Charlie, 1936-; Whitley, Keith; Morgan, Lorrie; Dunn, Holly; Gilley, Mickey; Axton, Hoyt;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/7818</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>