<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Words and Music Night - RaeLynn -2018-05-16</dc:title>
<dc:description>39th Annual Words and Music Night program held in the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on May 16, 2018.  Hosted by RaeLynn.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2018-05-16</dc:date>
<dc:creator>RaeLynn; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Walk-in Music / (08:05) Opening comments and host introduction by Ali Tonn / (15:16) Opening comments by RaeLynn / (15:51) Dreaming (Mason Lee with Emily Midkiff) / (19:19) Chicken Nuggets (Chris Moyse with Bo Schlosser) / (23:10) Miss You Every Hour (Michelle Pereira with Addison Evans) / (27:42) Who's Keeping Score (Raquel Cole with Sammy Webster Jr.) / (32:34) Ghost (Bob Spanburgh with Imalay Aquino Torres) / (36:27) Living It Up In Tennessee (Claire Wyndham with Anna Swaby) / (39:34) I Went To Space (Christy McDonald and Kyle Jones with Landon Hindman) / (44:43) I Wanna Be (Anne Buckle with Ansley Baker) / (48:23) Talking 'Bout My Mama (Anthony Snape with Marcel Thompson) / (52:04) I'll Listen (Misty Rae Carson with Ava Calhoun) / (56:10) Nashville (Mia Rose Lynne with Le'Jai Gaines) / (58:30) Wrong Generation (Dawn Landes with Cameron Darks) / (01:01:59) Veterans (Tim Buppert with Walker Latham) / (01:05:52) Flying Pineapple (Shane Adams with Lucie Hart and Holly Carpenter) / (01:11:00) Going, Going, Gone (Deanna Brown with Rhett Shaw) / (01:14:41) Singing Your Song (Jennie Hayes Kurtz with John Cox) / (01:18:34) Crab Mentality (James Farrell with Kenneth Owens) / (01:24:25) Queens Don't (RaeLynn) / (01:28:42) Final comments from RaeLynn and Ali Tonn / (01:29:21) Walk-out Music / (01:29:53) FILE END           </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded as an mp3 file at 44.1</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0115</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2019-02-06</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>RaeLynn; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8531</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>