<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Hank Snow Benefit at the Grand Ole Opry - 1978-08-30 - Part 2</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of the Hank Snow Benefit Concert at the Grand Ole Opry. The segment is hosted by T. Tommy Cutrer (musician) and features performances by: the Opry Staff Band (musical group), Skeeter Davis (musician), the Four Guys (musical group), Hank Snow (musician), and Kelly Foxton (musician). The recording is from August 30, 1978. The tape is part two of four.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1978-08-30</dc:date>
<dc:creator>T. Tommy Cutrer; Skeeter Davis; Opry Staff Band; Bill Jones and the Promenaders; Four Guys; Hank Snow; Kelly Foxton</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) The End of the World (Skeeter Davis) -- (02:41) Skeeter Davis gushes over Dottie Rambo, introduces the accompanying band, and reflects on her faith -- (05:34) The Old Rugged Cross (Skeeter Davis) -- (09:05) T. Tommy Cutrer praises Davis and attempts to kill time by describing the show structure; additionally, Cutrer tells a joke about a game warden -- (12:00) Cutrer reflects on his time with the Grand Ole Opry and politics -- (13:15) (There'll be) Peace in the Valley (For Me) (T. Tommy Cutrer) -- (16:34) Cutrer praises the Opry Staff Band -- (17:33) I Can't Help it if I'm Still in Love With You (Opry Staff Band) -- (20:28) Cutrer reintroduces Bill Jones and the Promenaders to perform a dance -- (21:51) Unidentified tune (Opry Staff Band) -- (23:24) Unidentified tune (Opry Staff Band) -- (26:28) Cutrer introduces the Four Guys while reflects on his long career -- (27:18) Cotton Fields and Maria Medley (Four Guys) -- (30:29) Forever in Blue Jeans (Four Guys) -- (34:24) Y'all Come Back Saloon (Four Guys) -- (36:25) Door is Always Open (Four Guys) -- (38:13) I'll Go to My Grave Loving You (Four Guys) -- (41:05) Fire (Four Guys) -- (45:39) Unidentified tune (Opry Staff Band) -- (46:02) Cutrer jokes about the Four Guys and introduces Horace Bass; additionally Bass discusses the purpose of the benefit: child abuse prevention -- (49:49) Cutrer puts Hank Snow on the pinnacle of friendship -- (51:07) I'm Moving on (Hank Snow) -- (53:44) Snow praises the various performers who assisted the benefit -- (55:52) I've Cried a Mile (Hank Snow) -- (59:38) Snow recalls being able to record with Chet Atkins -- (59:04) Tammy (Hank Snow) -- (1:02:27) Snow reflects on the skills of Kelly Foxton -- (1:04:00) Lay a Little Lovin' on Me (Hank Snow and Kelly Foxton) -- (1:06:41) Cry [incomplete] (Hank Snow and Kelly Foxton)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1063_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1063</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-07-29</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Cutrer, T. Tommy; Davis, Skeeter; Opry Staff Band; Bill Jones and the Promenaders; Jones, Bill; Four Guys (Musical group); Snow, Hank; Foxton, Kelly;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9294</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>