<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Herrington Sisters performances - tape 1</dc:title>
<dc:description>Tape 1 of various performances featuring the Herrington Sisters (performers).</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Herrington Sisters</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Test tones -- Sittin' On Top Of The World (Herrington Sisters) -- I'm Alone Because Of You (Herrington Sisters) -- The Convict And The Rose (Herrington Sisters) -- Put On Your Old Grey Bonnet (Herrington Sisters) -- Rockin' Alone In An Old Rockin' Chair (Herrington Sisters) -- Ol' Faithful (Herrington Sisters) -- My Melancholy Baby (Herrington Sisters) -- A Golden Tomorrow Ahead (Herrington Sisters) -- When I Yoo Hoo In The Valley (Herrington Sisters) -- The Dipsy Doodle (Herrington Sisters) -- Carry Me Back To The Lone Prairie (Herrington Sisters) -- The Hills Of Old Wyoming (Herrington Sisters) -- Timber (Herrington Sisters) -- I'm Thinking Tonight Of My Blue Eyes (Herrington Sisters)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-0416_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-0416</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-04-18</dcterms:created>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/7218</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>