<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Ralph Emery Show: Moe Bandy - 1982-05-18 - Reel 1</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recordings are of the Ralph Emery Show. The show is hosted by Ralph Emery (entertainer), and features Emery in discussion with his guest: Moe Bandy (musician). The show was recorded on May 18, 1982.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1982-05-18</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Moe Bandy; Ralph Emery</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Moe Bandy performs a radio spot for the Ralph Emery Show -- (00:13) Ralph Emery introduces Bandy -- (01:01) Bandy praises Johnny Gimble's humor while discussing ""Home in San Antone"" -- (02:12) Emery asserts that Bandy should record with the Kendalls; additionally, the subject of 'cheating songs' are discussed -- (03:19) Bandy reflects on the inspiration for ""She's Not Really Cheatin', She's Gettin' Even"" -- (04:07) Emery discusses Bandy's provocative album cover, and both Emery and Bandy discuss Bandy's conservatism -- (07:46) Emery asks Bandy to reflect on ""Someday Soon"" as a departure, and Bandy's connection to the rodeo -- (12:59) Bandy recalls working a show with Janie Fricke while discussing ""Don't Worry About Me Baby"" -- (14:53) Emery has Bandy reflect on the General Lee -- (15:30) Bandy reflects on his favorite line from ""Rodeo Romeo"" -- (16:32) Emery and Bandy say their goodbyes -- (16:54) Emery introduces Bandy to discuss Dolly Parton's ""Heartbreak Express"" -- (17:29) Emery asks Bandy to reflect on his working career for Braniff International Airways and Mel Tillis -- (19:33) Emery inquires as to what Bandy begins his shows with -- (19:58) Emery discusses the accolades of Ricky Skaggs -- (20:39) Emery inquires about the whereabouts of Joe Stampley -- (22:53) Emery asks Bandy to reflect on being named Country Music Duo of the Year, and Bandy's involvement with a club -- (25:28) Emery inquires to what Bandy would do if he met a man from Mars; additionally, Bandy's pronunciation of ""My Woman Loves the Devil Out of Me"" is discussed -- (28:35) Lacy J. Dalton is praised by Bandy and Emery -- (29:00) Emery inquires as to Bandy's work with Conway Twitty, and Emery asks Bandy how he can contact him -- (31:24) Emery asks Bandy about his plans with his beard -- (32:32) Emery and Bandy say their goodbyes -- (32:51) Emery introduces Bandy -- (33:26) Emery recalls doing an episode of Alabama and Friends while discussing Alabama -- (34:53) Emery asks Bandy to discuss ""The Champ,"" and his drinking habits -- (35:36) Emery and Bandy discuss Bandy's first appearance on the Ralph Emery Show -- (38:15) Emery and Bandy discuss the misconception of ""Jesus in a Nashville Jail"" -- (40:30) Bandy performs a disc jockey role when he introduces ""Dreamin'"" -- (42:00) Emery recalls how Minnie Pearl was told how to change country music -- (42:22) Bandy introduces ""She's Not Really Cheatin', She's Gettin' Even"" -- (43:15) Emery recalls how the first interview of Bandy featured his father's rodeo -- (45:30) Emery and Bandy reflect on the power of Willie Nelson while discussing ""Old Friends"" -- (46:48) Emery and Bandy discuss performing at a drive-in theatre -- (48:38) Bandy and Emery say their goodbyes</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1466_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1466</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-07-31</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Emery, Ralph; Bandy, Moe;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9300</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>