<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Moe Bandy Live at the Lone Star Caf&#233; - 1978-09-06</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is from the Lone Star Caf&#233; live show. The tape features a live performance of Moe Bandy. (musician). The Lone Star Caf&#233; show is presented by Mort Cooperman, Bill McGivney and the WHN radio network. The recording of Moe Bandy is from September 06, 1978.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1978-09-06</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Moe Bandy</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Del DeMontreux thanks the members of WHN and introduces Moe Bandy -- (00:55) Bandy the Rodeo Clown (Moe Bandy) -- (04:00) Soft Lights and Hard Country Music (Moe Bandy) -- (06:41) Bandy thanks the crowd -- (07:25) Here I Am Drunk Again (Moe Bandy) -- (09:54) Bandy reflects on cowboys and rodeos -- (10:11) She's Got That Oklahoma Look (Moe Bandy) -- (11:49) Bandy reflects on ""I Just Started Hating Cheating Songs Today"" -- (12:11) I Just Started Hating Cheating Songs Today (Moe Bandy) -- (18:21) Bandy reflects on his bus driver and introduces his band -- (20:03) Unidentified tune (Moe Bandy) -- (21:49) Bandy jokes about the pronunciation of woman -- (22:17) She Just Loved the Cheatin' Out of Me (Moe Bandy) -- (24:58) Bandy jokes about playing the guitar -- (25:27) Bandy Medley (Another Day, Another Dollar; Oh, Lonesome Me) (Moe Bandy) -- (29:40) Bandy reflects on Hank Williams -- (30:06) Hank Williams You Wrote My Life (Moe Bandy) -- (33:18) Williams Medley (Your Cheatin' Heart; Kaw-Liga; I'm So Lonesome I Could Cry; Why Don't You Love Me) (Moe Bandy) -- (38:10) Bandy discusses being personally close to rodeos -- (38:32) Cowboys Ain't Supposed to Cry (Moe Bandy) -- (41:31) Two Lonely People (Moe Bandy) -- (44:19) Biggest Airport in the World (Moe Bandy) -- (47:13) Mind Your Own Business (Moe Bandy) -- (49:41) Sing a Sad Song (Moe Bandy) -- (52:35) Bandy recites his thanks to WHN -- (52:57) That's What Make the Jukebox Play (Moe Bandy) -- (55:20) Unidentified Tune ([Unidentified]) -- (55:39) Bandy reveals his upcoming schedule -- (56:02) She Took More Than Her Share (Moe Bandy) -- (58:20) Unidentified Tune [featuring Del DeMontreux voiceover] ([Unidentified])</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1545_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1545</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-07-01</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Bandy, Moe;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9201</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>