<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Martha White Biscuit Time - Milton Estes and his Musical Millers - 1947-02-22 - WSM</dc:title>
<dc:description>WSM program Martha White Biscuit time, originally broadcast on February 22, 1947 at 7:30 pm. Personnel include Louis Buck (announcer), Milton Estes (host, performer), Lew Childre (performer), and the Musical Millers (performers). Sponsored by Martha White. Opening theme music, 'How Many Biscuits Can You Eat'; closing theme music, 'How Many Biscuits Can You Eat'.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1947-02-22</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Milton Estes; Musical Millers; Lew Childre</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Opening statement (Louis Buck) (incomplete) -- Opening theme -- Louis Buck advertises Martha White flour -- Louis Buck introduces Milton Estes -- Milton Estes talks -- Jealous Heart (Milton Estes) -- Milton Estes talks -- Milton Estes introduces Lew Childre -- Lew Childre talks -- Truck Driver's Blues (Lew Childre) -- Milton Estes Talks -- Milton Estes and Louis Buck advertise Martha White flour -- Milton Estes talks -- A-Sleepin' At The Foot Of The Bed (Milton Estes) -- Milton Estes talks -- Jimmie Selph talks -- Midnight Flower (Milton Estes) [unconfirmed] -- Louis Buck advertises Martha White flour -- Closing statement (Milton Estes) -- Closing theme -- Closing statement (Louis Buck) (incomplete)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>12 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR002996_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>TR002996</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2017-06-16</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); Martha White biscuit time (Radio program); Estes, Milton, 1914-1963; Musical Millers (Musical group); Buck, Louis, 1910-1971; Childre, Lew, 1901-1961; </dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/5258</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>