<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Selections from Eddy Arnold's Thereby Hangs A Tale album - 1959-07</dc:title>
<dc:description>Selected performances from Eddy Arnold's Thereby Hangs A Tale album. Tom Dooley and Nellie Sits A-Waitin' were recorded on July 13, 1959 at RCA Victor Studio in Nashville, Tenn., produced by Chet Atkins, and performed by Eddy Arnold (vocals), Chet Atkins (guitar), John D. Loudermilk (guitar), Velma Smith (guitar), Bob Moore (bass), and Buddy Harman (drums). Tennessee Stud was recorded on April 27, 1959 at RCA Victor Studio in Nashville, Tenn., produced by Chet Atkins, and performed by Eddy Arnold (vocals), Chet Atkins (guitar), John D. Loudermilk (guitar), Ray Edenton (guitar), Jerry Byrd (bass), and Buddy Harman and Douglas Kirkham (drums). The Battle Of Little Big Horn and The Red Headed Stranger were recorded on July 24, 1959 at RCA Victor Studio in Nashville, Tenn., produced by Chet Atkins, and performed by Eddy Arnold (vocals), Chet Atkins (guitar), Velma Smith (guitar), Bob Moore (bass), Buddy Harman (drums), and the Anita Kerr Singers (background vocals). The Wreck Of The Old 97 was recorded on July 21, 1959 at RCA Victor Studio in Nashville, Tenn., produced by Chet Atkins, and performed by Eddy Arnold (vocals), Chet Atkins (guitar), Velma Smith (guitar), Bob Moore (bass), Buddy Harman (drums), John D. Loudermilk (harmonica), and the Anita Kerr Singers (background vocals).</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Eddy Arnold</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(0:00) Eddy Arnold performs "Tom Dooley" / (2:15) Eddy Arnold performs "Nellie Sits A-Waitin'," written by Jan Crutchfield and Gerald Nelson / (4:53) Eddy Arnold performs "Tennessse Stud," written by Jimmie Driftwood / (8:02) Eddy Arnold performs "The Battle Of Little Big Horn," written by Nancy Chase / (10:21) Eddy Arnold performs "The Wreck Of The Old 97" / (12:25) Eddy Arnold performs "Red Headed Stranger," written by Edith Linderman and Carl Stutz</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>12 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR003865_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>TR003865</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:isPartOf>TRB012_2</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-04-04</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Arnold, Eddy, 1918-2008; Driftwood, Jimmie; Stutz, Carl, 1915-1986; Atkins, Chet, 1924-2001; Loudermilk, John D.; Smith, Velma; Moore, Bob, 1932-; Harman, Buddy; Edenton, Ray; Byrd, Jerry (Guitarist); Kirkham, Douglas; Anita Kerr Singers</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/7212</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>