<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Songwriter Session - Laura Veltz - 2018-03-25</dc:title>
<dc:description>Performance by Laura Veltz from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on March 25, 2017.  Includes questions from the audience.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2017-03-25</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Laura Veltz;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Opening comments and introduction of Laura Veltz by Abi Tapia / (02:28) Opening comments by Laura Veltz / (03:10) Drunk Last Night / (09:08) Rich / (16:05) We Went To The Beach / (19:22) Answers question about why she isn't an recording/touring artist / (20:50) Answers question about being left-handed / (21:21) Answers question about if artists ask her to write songs for them / Answers question about how long she's been writing and her writing history / (24:11) Answers question about how songwriters make money / (29:34) The Listener / (33:51) Answers question about how many songs she's working on at one time and how many pitches artists are getting from songwriters / (37:16) Answers question about The Listener being available or not / (37:55) Answers question about music or lyrics coming first / (39:04) Answers question about her influences / (42:03) Answers question about if she's thought about what she would say when she wins song of the year / </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(42:55) Answers question about different songwriters process of writing and the craft of country songwriting / (47:22) Lonely Eyes / (50:54) Closing comments / (51:17) Walk-out music / (52:28) FILE END        </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/24;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0017</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2018-05-09</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Veltz, Laura; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/7382</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>