<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Hallmarks of Country Music - Merle Haggard</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of an interview of Merle Haggard (musician). The interview is hosted by Rick Phillips (army sergeant/ radio host) for the Hallmarks of Country Music segment. The tape was recorded on an unidentified date.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Merle Haggard; Rick Phillips</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Promotion for Hallmarks of Country Music featuring Merle Haggard [unedited] -- (00:42)  I Take a Lot of Pride in What I am [featuring Merle Haggard and Rick Phillips introduction voiceover] (Merle Haggard) -- (01:54) Daddy Frank [featuring Merle Haggard and Rick Phillips introduction voiceover] (Merle Haggard) -- (02:50) Hallmarks tune [featuring Rick Phillips introduction voiceover] ([Unidentified]) -- (03:17) Old Man From the Mountain Hallmarks tune [featuring Rick Phillips introduction voiceover] ([Unidentified]) -- (03:45) Haggard reveals he had dropped out of school in his youth -- (05:00) Daddy Frank (Merle Haggard) -- (08:04) Phillips provides information about the Bootstrap program closing -- (08:35) Red Cross commercial spot hosted by an unidentified host -- (09:06) Swingin' Doors (Merle Haggard) -- (11:43) Phillips introduces Haggard to reflect on his troubled youth -- (13:38) Mama Tried (Merle Haggard) -- (15:43) Army commercial spot hosted by Tom T. Hall -- (16:32) It's Not Love (But It's Not Bad) (Merle Haggard) -- (19:50) Phillips invites Haggard to reflect on the importance of Fuzzy Owens on his career; additionally, the roots of Haggard are discussed -- (21:39) I'll Break Out Again Tonight (Merle Haggard) -- (24:23) Physical Fitness commercial spot hosted by Lee Sorvino (Unconfirmed) -- (24:53) Everybody's Had the Blues (Merle Haggard) -- (27:29) Phillips introduces Haggard to reflect on outside influences in his music -- (31:16) Take Me Back to Tulsa (Merle Haggard) -- (33:38) Phillips performs a Serviceman's Opportunity College radio spot -- (34:18) Fightin' Side of Me (Merle Haggard) -- (36:57) Phillips and Haggard reflect on whether or not Haggard was looking to perform a film role for Jimmie Rodgers, and Haggard reflects on " I Take a Lot of Pride in What I am" -- (39:26) I Take a Lot of Pride in What I am (Merle Haggard) -- (41:12) Conservation commercial spot hosted by an unidentified host -- (41:45) If We Make it Through December (Merle Haggard) -- (44:15) Phillips asks Haggard about where country music is headed -- (45:49) Okie From Muskogee (Merle Haggard) -- (48:37) commercial spot hosted by pair of unidentified hosts -- (49:39) Early Release Program commercial spot hosted by Phillips -- (50:34) Every Fool Has a Rainbow (Merle Haggard) -- (52:53) Phillips asks about Haggards future goals and both say their goodbyes -- (54:46) Unidentified tune [featuring Rick Phillips voiceover]  -- (55:53) Hallmarks outro tune [featuring Rick Phillips outro voiceover] ([Unidentified]) -- (57:55) News feed concerning the formation of the Association of Country Entertainers hosted by Steve Dickert of WKDA.</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Insert is of program information. The insert features time stamps.</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1719_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1719</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-06-17</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Haggard, Merle; Haggard, Merle, 1937-2016; Phillips, Rick;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9102</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>