<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Ralph Emery interviews Mel Tillis and Terry Bradshaw - Live</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording is from Ralph Emery's (entertainer) interview of Mel Tillis (performer) and Terry Bradshaw (personality) for Ralph Emery: On the Record With Mel Tillis. Recording is performed in front of a live audience. Recording is from April of 1989.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1989-04</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Ralph Emery; Mel Tillis</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Mel Tillis and Terry Bradshaw joke about their work in the Cannonball Run -- (02:53) Ralph Emery asks Bradshaw where he lived, and Bradshaw and Tillis joke about Bradshaw's football career -- (04:46) Bradshaw credits Albert Ruddy for casting him and Tillis for their charisma -- (06:37) Emery asks Bradshaw about who he believes will perform well in the NFL; additionally, Emery and Tillis say goodbye to Bradshaw -- (09:19) Emery discusses the upcoming schedule -- (10:09) Emery invites Tillis to discuss when he was hired to work for Minnie Pearl -- (13:52) Tillis discusses his time with the Duke of Paducah, and Pearl allowing him to perform on stage -- (15:41) Emery inquires about how Pearl discovered Tillis' humorous personality -- (18:27) Emery and Tillis discuss how Tillis stutters -- (22:52) Tillis reflects on his time at Decca Records, and how Red Foley led to Tillis' release -- (24:33) Tillis discusses his time with Cap Records and the number of records he had recorded -- (25:52) Emery invites Tillis to discuss how he meet Danny Dill and the story of "Detroit City" -- (29:48) Tillis recalls that  he discovered "Who's Julie" during the Disc Jockey's Convention for MGM Records -- (32:11) Emery inquires about the story of Tillis and Wayne Walker at the Disc Jockey's Convention -- (35:36) Emery speaks of Tillis' accolades, and how Tillis was on the Grand Ole Opry with a pipe -- (37:31) Emery plays a clip from the Country Music Association Awards Show when Tillis won Entertainer of the Year -- (39:23) Tillis recalls how Jimmy Dean had given him a line for his speech when they were out to eat together; additionally, Emery attempts to have Tillis discuss where his career went after he won Entertainer of the Year -- (41:23) Tillis credits Dean for getting Tillis on the Glen Campbell Goodtime Hour -- (42:25) Emery plays multiple clips from Tillis' performances on the Glen Campbell Goodtime Hour -- (43:35) Emery has Tillis address his growing family -- (44:45) Emery plays a clip from a session where Carrie April Tillis played "Mary Had a Little Lamb" for Emery's show -- (45:20) Tillis describes how Carrie became an opera singer -- (46:01) Emery asks Tillis to describe why he adopted Hannah Tillis when he was fifty years old -- (46:58) Emery inquires about one of Tillis' mother's sayings; additionally, Emery praises Tillis' work ethic -- (48:25) Tillis reflects on the difficulties in gaining his father's approval -- (50:45) Tillis praises Pam Tillis' work ethic despite her lack of recognition -- (52:52) Emery and Tillis discuss how Tillis was left a sail boat from Burl Ives -- (55:08) Emery says goodbye to Tillis, and both joke away from the microphone</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1384_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1384</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-04-17</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Emery, Ralph; Tillis, Mel;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8804</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>