<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Hank Williams: Beyond the Legend Part 3</dc:title>
<dc:description>Part 3 of 3. Recording is of the documentary Hank Williams: Beyond the Legend. Documentary is hosted by Kyle Cantrell and includes commentary from Biff Collie (personality), Justin Tubb (personality), Vic Willis (entertainer), Merle Kilgore (entertainer), Little Jimmy Dickens (performer), Grant Turner, (performer), Jerry Rivers (performer) and Lycrecia Williams (daughter). </dc:description>
<dc:creator>Hank Williams Sr.; Kyle Cantrell; Biff Collie ; Justin Tubb; Vic Willis; Merle Kilgore; Little Jimmy Dickens; Grant Turner; Jerry Rivers; Lycrecia Williams</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Commercial mash-up presented by an unknown voice -- (01:01) Kyle Cantrell introduces Hank Williams, Beyond the Legend -- (01:03) Unidentified harmonica tune [featuring Cantrell voiceover] -- (02:42) Cantrell reflects on Hank Williams Sr.'s growing success -- (03:26) Love Sick Blues [featuring Mother's Best Flour voiceover](Hank Williams Sr.) -- (04:45) There's Nothing as Sweet as My Baby (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (07:28) Louie Buck and Williams Sr. perform in banter -- (07:38) Cantrell discusses the significance of radio shows for performer's careers -- (08:05) Fruehauf Trailer commercial presented by an unknown voice -- (09:03) Cantrell introduces Biff Collie, Justin Tubb, Vic Willis, and Merle Kilgore -- (09:18) Collie, Tubb, Willis, and Kilgore discusses the ability of Williams Sr. to create a personal atmosphere in his shows -- (10:29) Blue Eyes Crying (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (13:14) Cantrell reveals that Williams Sr. frequently played other artists' songs -- (14:00) Franciscan commercial presented by an unknown voice -- (15:05) National Committee for the Prevention of Child Abuse commercial presented by an unknown voice -- (16:05) Country Music Radio commercial presented by an unknown voice -- (16:44) Hank Williams Sr. says goodbye and Cantrell discusses how Williams Sr. closed his shows -- (17:51) Lycrecia Williams reflects on the misconceptions about Williams Sr. -- (18:45) Cantrell reveals Williams Sr.'s favorite practices -- (19:17) Johnny Wright and Kitty Wright reflect on fishing with Williams Sr. -- (20:14) Don Helms jokes about Williams Sr. humor -- (20:34) Cantrell normalizes Williams Sr.'s behavior -- (21:22) Long Gone (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (23:58) Whistler Truckers Move America (Unconfirmed) [featuring an unknown voiceover] -- (24:59) TNN commercial performed by an unknown voice -- (25:57) Cantrell discusses Williams Sr.'s generosity -- (26:22) Little Jimmy Dickens discusses a memory he had with Williams Sr. and his generosity -- (27:16) Lycrecia reflects on her father's desire to be good and his religious tendencies -- (30:22) Where He Leads Me (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (32:39) Cantrell notes Williams Sr.'s sincerity and introduces the commercial break -- (33:05) Food Bank commercial presented by a number of unknown voices -- (34:09) American Humane Association commercial presented by an unknown voice -- (35:09) Country Music Radio commercial presented by an unidentified host -- (35:44) An unknown voice introduces Hank Williams -- (36:25) Moanin' the Blues (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (39:03) Cantrell reflects on William's Grand Ole Opry performances -- (40:10) Jerry Rivers and Cantrell reflect on Williams Sr.'s pride in his show -- (41:25) Grant Turner and Johnny Wright discuss Williams Sr.'s showmanship -- (42:23) Minnie Pearl reflects on the female's reaction to Williams Sr. -- (43:06) Goodies commercial presented by Reba McEntire [featuring "How Blue"] -- (44:06) Dello commercial presented by Jackie Robinson -- (45:08) Cantrell reflects on Williams Sr.'s professionalism -- (45:51) Rivers tells about Williams Sr.'s disposition to playing his guitar -- (46:04) Hey, Good Lookin' (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (49:02) Cantrell discusses the novelty of having a piano in country -- (49:34) Rivers reflects on how pianos became the norm for Williams Sr. -- (51:40) The National Institute of Drug Abuse commercial presented by an unidentified voice -- (52:40) [Unidentified jingle] -- (53:09) American Humane Association commercial presented by an unidentified voice -- (53:43) Unidentified tune -- (54:12) Unidentified tune [incomplete]</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1423_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1423</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-04-01</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Williams, Hank, 1923-1953; Williams, Hank, 1923-1953. I saw the light; Cantrell, Kyle; Collie, Biff; Tubb, Justin; Willis, Vic, -1995; Kilgore, Merle; Dickens, Little Jimmy, 1920-2015; Turner, Grant; Rivers, Jerry, 1928-; Williams, Lycrecia, 1941-; </dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8729</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>