<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Grand Ole Opry - Prince Albert - 1940-03-16 - Part 2</dc:title>
<dc:description>Part 2 of Prince Albert tobacco sponsored Grand Ole Opry segment from March 16, 1940. Featuring David Stone (announcer), George D. Hay (host), and performers George Wilkerson and his Fruit Jar Drinkers, Pee Wee King and his Golden West Cowboys with vocalists Little Texas Daisy and Lost John, Ford Rush, Ford Rush Jr., and Roy Acuff. Held at War Memorial Auditorium, Nashville, TN.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1940-03-16</dc:date>
<dc:creator>George Wilkerson; Fruit Jar Drinkers; Ford Rush; Ford Rush Jr.; Golden West Cowboys; Little Texas Daisy; Lost John; Pee Wee King; Roy Acuff</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>George D. Hay introduces George Wilkerson and his Fruit Jar Drinkers -- Don't Let Your Deal Go Down (George Wilkerson and his Fruit Jar Drinkers) -- Prince Albert commercial (David Stone) -- George D. Hay introduces Ford Rush and Ford Rush Jr. -- I'm Looking Over A Four Leaf Clover (Ford Rush, Ford Rush Jr.) -- George D. Hay introduces the Golden West Cowboys -- Saddle Your Worries To The Wind (Golden West Cowboys trio) -- George D. Hay introduces George Wilkerson and his Fruit Jar Drinkers -- Roll Down The Line (George Wilkerson and his Fruit Jar Drinkers) -- George D. Hay introduces Texas Daisy, Lost John, and the Golden West Cowboys -- Paper Of Pins (Little Texas Daisy, Lost John, Golden West Cowboys) -- George D. Hay introduces Pee Wee King -- St. Louis Blues (Pee Wee King and his Golden West Cowboys) -- Prince Albert commercial (David Stone) -- George D. Hay introduces Roy Acuff -- Sally Ann (Roy Acuff) -- Closing statement (George D. Hay) -- Closing statement (David Stone) -- Network announcements</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>16 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR000639</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2006-09-14</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); National Broadcasting Company; Grand ole opry (Radio program); Stone, David P., 1901-1995; Hay, George D. (George Dewey), 1895-1968; Wilkerson, George W., 1895-1954; Fruit Jar Drinkers (Musical group); Rush, Ford, 1895-; Rush, Ford Jr.; King, Pee Wee, 1914-2000; Golden West Cowboys (Musical group); Little Texas Daisy; Lost John Miller; Acuff, Roy</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/1817</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>