<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Opryland Music Demo Recordings - Y-102</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording is of a group of demo recordings from Opryland Music. Recordings are from an unknown date and recorded by a number of unknown bands. Tape is labeled Y-102. </dc:description>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Silence and Tears (C. Belew and K. Sowder) -- (02:01) Stop Cheatin' on Your Heart (G. Morris and W. S. Stevenson) -- (06:19) Snake in the Grass (O. Ervin) -- (09:00) This is a Bad, Bad Woman (O. Ervin) -- (11:22) She Broke My Heart (And I Broke Her Jaw) (J. Byrd and T. T. Tyler) -- (12:28) Shy Madonna (L. Dorsey) -- (14:51) Shut Up Nosey (T. Anthony) -- (17:36) Send Me the Pillow (H. Locklin) -- (20:21) Shattered Dreams (D. Rule and M. Okon) -- (22:32) Somebody Done Goofed (Que Martin) -- (26:07) Show Me the Way (M. L. Gaches) -- (27:53) Can't Stop Loving You (Eddie Miller and W. S. Stevenson) -- (28:45) A Chapel Without a Steeple (C. Japhet) -- (30:52) Colorado (J. Clay, B. Spielman, and D. Spielman) -- (34:11) Cold, Cold Grave (W. Chandler) -- (36:24) Come on In (W. Chandler) -- (38:15) Copyright Your Love (K. Wade and D. Tilley) -- (40:15) A Child Left to Stray (E. Vandergriff) -- (42:43) Carefree and Lazy (M. F. Palmer and W. S. Stevenson) -- (45:02) Crazy Dreams (Beam, Jiles, and Stevenson) -- (47:37) Chain of Broken Hearts [Unconfirmed] ([Unidentified]) -- (51:54) From the Alter to the Courtroom [Unconfirmed] ([Unidentified]) -- (55:12) At the Alter (E. Downs) -- (57:01) All By Myself (J. Kuhn) -- (59:15) Another Heart to Break (Tex Tyler, Jeans, and White) -- (1:00:55) At Mother's Knee (Ray Baker) -- (1:03:07) An Orchid and a Note (L. Montgomery and W. S. Stevenson) -- (1:05:38) Anna May (Cecil Gant) -- (1:08:17) As Long as I Live (E. Miller and T. Colbert) -- (1:10:54) All Night Long I Worried (B. Flournoy) -- (1:11:59) At the End of My Rainbow (A. Tarvin) -- (1:14:15) Aw C'mon (B. Gardner, M. Dysinger, and W. Binkley) -- (1:15:36) Afraid (M. Coursey and M. Coursey) -- (1:18:18) As You Were Standing By My Side (Miller, Ingram, and Jourdan) -- (1:20:47) I'm So Tired I Could Cry (W. S. Stevenson) -- (1:23:56) I'm Just a Stranger Here (B. Geddins) -- (1:27:17) I'm Lonely and Blue (C. Harless)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1298_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1298</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-03-11</dcterms:created>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8628</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>