<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>WSM Radio delayed broadcast of the Country Music Hall of Fame medallion ceremony - 2007-11-05.  Tape three of three.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Delayed broadcast by WSM radio of the Country Music Hall of Fame medallion ceremony with tributes and performances of the 2007 ceremony honoring Mel Tillis from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on November 5, 2007.  Delayed broadcast on WSM Radio.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2007-11-05</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Kyle Young; Kenny Rogers; Eddie Stubbs; Pam Tillis; Dierks Bentley; Mel Tillis: Porter Wagoner; Penny DeHaven; Bill Anderson; The Osborne Brothers; Vince Gill; Harold Hensley; Jimmy C. Newman; The Whites; Dan Seals; Little Jimmie Dickens; Connie Smith; Craig Morgan; Seals, Dan; Rhonda Vincent; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Recording begins in progress.  (00:00) WSM radio news and weather break / (02:23) Kyle Young continues with the Mel Tillis segment / (03:20) Introduction of Kenny Rogers who performs Ruby, Don't Take Your Love To Town / (10:34) Eddie Stubbs with WSM break in with announcements / (17:30) Kyle Young continues with the Mel Tillis segment [some repeated audio here] / (22:18) Introduction of Pam Tillis who performs Coca-Cola Cowboy /  (30:18) Kyle Young continues Mel Tillis segment / (31:31) Introduction of Dierks Bentley who performs I Ain't Never / (36:47) Eddie Stubbs with WSM break in / (39:54) Kyle Young continues Mel Tillis segment / (41:40) Introduction of the State Siders band, family members and friends / (43:14) Introduction of Little Jimmie Dickens to present medallion to Mel Tillis / (47:21) Mel Tillis accepts medallion and gives acceptance speech / (58:50) Eddie Stubbs with WSM break in / Previously recorded Friday Night Grand Old Opry 78th Birthday celebration air check /</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(01:00:27 If Teardrops Were Pennies (Porter Wagoner with Penny DeHaven) / (01:02:42)  40 Miles From Poplar Bluff (Porter Wagoner and Penny DeHaven) / 01:04:10) WSM commercials / 01:05:14) Johnny Walker Tours segment of the Grand Ole Opry / (01:05:30) Introduction of Bill Anderson / Walk Out Backwards (Bill Anderson) / Harold Hensley with Johnny Walker Tours commercial / (01:10:08) High On A Hilltop (The Osborne Brothers) / (01:15:03) Rocky Top (The Osborne Brothers) / 01:18:42) Harold Hensley with Fiddlers Inn commercial / (01:20:19) True Love (Vince Gill) / (01:24:34) Vince tells Chet Atkins guitar story / 01:29:31) This Old Guitar And Me (Vince Gill) / (01:33:45) Harold Hensley with Johnny Walker Tours commercial / (01:35:40) Still (Bill Anderson with the Carol Lee Singers) / (01:38:17) Happy Birthday (Cast) / (01:38:50) Closing song with Voice Over by Harold Hensley / (01:39:24) WSM commercial break / 01:39:50 Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum segment / </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>RDAT digital tape;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RS.2014.0123</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2017-09-28</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Young, Kyle; Stubbs, Eddie; Rogers, Kenny; Tillis, Pam; Bentley, Dierks; Tillis, Mel; Wagoner, Porter; DeHaven, Penny; Anderson, Bill; The Osborne Brothers (Musical group); Gill, Vince; Hensley, Harold; the Whites (Musical group); Seals, Dan; Dickens, Little Jimmy, 1920-; Smith, Connie; Morgan, Craig; Vincent, Rhonda; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/5906</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>