<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Grand Ole Opry - American Ace - 1947-12-06 - Part 1</dc:title>
<dc:description>Part 1 of excerpts from an American Ace sponsored Grand Ole Opry segment (7:30-8:00 pm) from December 6, 1947. Featuring Grant Turner (announcer), and performers Roy Acuff and his Smoky Mountain Boys, the Tennessee Belles, Tommy Jackson, Uncle Dave Macon, Pap's Jug Band, Sonny Day, and Bashful Brother Oswald. Held at Ryman Auditorium, Nashville, TN.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1947-12-06</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Roy Acuff; Smoky Mountain Boys; Tennessee Belles; Tommy Jackson</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Opening theme -- Opening statement (Grant Turner) -- Jealous Heart (Roy Acuff and his Smoky Mountain Boys) -- Roy Acuff introduces the Tennessee Belles -- My Love Turned Me Down In The Hills (Tennessee Belles) -- American Ace Coffee commercial (Grant Turner) -- Roy Acuff introduces Tommy Jackson -- Soldier's Joy (Tommy Jackson fiddle) -- Roy Acuff talks -- Heart That Was Broken For Me (Roy Acuff and his Smoky Mountain Boys)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>10 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR002227_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>TR002227</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2016-05-03</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); Grand ole opry (Radio program); Acuff, Roy; Smoky Mountain Boys; Tennessee Belles; Wilson, Lonnie; Pap's Jug Band; Jackson, Tommy; Macon, Uncle Dave, 1870-1952; Day, Sonny (Accordionist); Bashful Brother Oswald; Turner, Grant;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/3813</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>