<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Johnny Lee Interview - Biff Collie</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of an interview with Johnny Lee (performer) conducted by Biff Collie. </dc:description>
<dc:date>1990-03-23</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Johnny Lee; Biff Collie</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Johnny Lee reveals his original name was Johnny Lee Ham and that his father had left his family -- (01:22) Lee reflects on the directions to Alta Loma, Texas and Lee discusses living on his whole family living on a single road -- (02:33) Biff Collie has Lee remember the difficulties of working on a dairy farm and Lee reflects on cleaning cows -- (03:50) Lee discusses being around his cousins and how they would get him in trouble -- (04:37) Lee reflects on his desire to be a singer, but Lee was always worried to tell anyone -- (05:50) Lee tells Collie about his desire to be a singer and how he did not initially decide to be a singer, but a police officer, after his military service -- (07:33) Lee reflects on the time he had been a car racer and his time in construction -- (08:28) Lee discusses how his grandfather had influenced his desire to create something lasting -- (08:54) Lee's high school baseball career is discussed -- (10:13) Lee reflects on how he learned to play the guitar after his cousin had been given a guitar -- (10:56) Lee reflects on how his step-father refused to allow Lee to play sports -- (11:50) Lee remembers using his trumpet and playing in high school -- (12:57) Lee remembers attempting to play high school football, but Lee's band teacher did not allow it -- (14:16) Lee recalls breaking his leg working on the dairy farm -- (14:46) Collie and Lee reflect on Lee's time with Johnny Lee and the Roadrunners -- (15:40) Lee tells about his roadrunner tattoo -- (15:57) Lee discusses how he worked in the boiler room while being in the military and how he requested a transfer -- (18:37) Lee reflects on how he had engaged Vietnamese water crafts -- (19:20) Collie has Lee reflect on why he moved back to Texas -- (19:52) Lee recalls forming a band and working at Cedar Oaks -- (21:05) Collie reads a quote to Lee, and Lee recalls having his grandfather with him when Lee went through negotiations -- (22:44) Lee recalls the first time he heard himself on the radio -- (23:37) Collie and Lee discuss Lee going up to Mickey Gilley and Gilley having Lee perform at his club -- (26:10) Lee tells about how he had misled Gilley -- (26:36) Lee reflects on how he was the vocalist, drummer, and trumpeter for Gilley -- (28:12) Collie and Lee reflect on how John Travolta met with Lee and Gilley -- (29:28) Collie has Lee recall how there was notions of an upcoming movie while Lee worked at Gilley's -- (29:58) Lee asserts that he was asked to perform on a movie after being heard in Gilley's -- (31:02) Lee attests the nature of personalities, that come into Gilley's, as dishonest -- (31:30) Collie and Lee discuss how Gilley's had grown exponentially -- (32:11)  Lee discusses the television show he started with Gilley, named Gilley's, sponsored by Utah Carl -- (33:29) Lee discusses how Aaron Latham came to Texas to observe the country lifestyle -- (34:11) Lee tells about how Urban Cowboy got its script -- (35:32) Lee reflects on his ability to go on the road -- (35:57) Lee recalls how his popularity was starting to increase, and how Gilley convinced Lee to put his money into the bank -- (38:26) Lee recalls meeting Charlene Tilton at the 20 Year Bandstand Special -- (39:38) Lee describes courting Tilton and his comfortability with popularity -- (40:48) Lee and Collie discuss a tabloid article about him abusing a dog -- (44:46) Lee recalls being in the Dallas Fort Worth Airport when he met a beautiful women (Lee's eventual wife) -- (48:06) Lee tells of a time he used a orangutan to mess with Gilley on stage -- (50:21) Lee reflects on his bus driver usually getting the band lost -- (53:08) Lee reflects on his new opportunity to record while expressing his displeasure with a previous member of management -- (55:05) Lee discusses how he pays out his expenses -- (55:19) Lee discusses his son's name Johnny Lee the 2nd -- (56:07) Lee expresses his idea of what lies ahead for himself</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1186_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1186</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-01-25</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Lee, Johnny, 1946-; Collie, Biff;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8424</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>