<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Grand Ole Opry  - 1973-09 - WSM</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording begins with the end of an excerpt of the Johnny Cash Show, featuring Johnny Cash (host, performer.) as well as radio bumpers and advertisements. Followed by a Grand Ole Opry segment from featuring Grant Turner (announcer), Charlie Louvin (performer), Melba Montgomery (performer), Del Reeves (performer), Statler Brothers (performer), Billy Walker (performer), Ernie Ashworth (performer), Hank Locklin (performer), Bob Luman (performer), The Four Guys (performers), Archie Campbell (performer), Tommy Jones (performer), Crook Brothers (performers), Bill Monroe (performer), Bluegrass Boys (performers), Stu Phillips (performer), Marion Worth (performer), Bob Bradford (performer) [unconfirmed], Hank Snow (performer), Jeanne Pruett (performer), George Morgan (performer), Lonzo &amp; Oscar (performers) in September of 1973 on radio station WSM (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:description>
<dc:date>1973-09</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Johnny Cash; Charlie Louvin; Melba Montgomery; Del Reeves; Statler Brothers; Billy Walker; Ernie Ashworth; Hank Locklin; Bob Luman; The Four Guys; Archie Campbell; Tommy Jones; Crook Brothers; Bill Monroe; Bluegrass Boys; Stu Phillips; Marion Worth; Bob Bradford; Hank Snow; Jeanne Pruett; George Morgan; Lonzo &amp; Oscar</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>The Fourth Man In The Fire (Johnny Cash) (incomplete) -- Johnny Cash talks -- MFA Insurance commercial (Joe Swatterly) [unconfirmed] -- Closing statement (Johnny Cash) -- Closing theme -- WSM radio bumper -- NBC news report (Mark Henry) -- Penzoil commercial -- Mark Henry talks about current events, gas prices, Chrysler union workers, direct flight patterns on airlines, wanted criminals, and Vice President Agnew -- WSM radio bumper -- Opening theme -- Opening statement (Grant Turner) -- Vietti commercial -- Grant Turner introduces Charlie Louvin and Melba Montgomery -- A Man Likes Things Like That (Charlie Louvin, Melba Montgomery) -- Grant Turner talks -- Vietti commercial -- Grant Turner talks about country music birthdays and introduces Del Reeves -- Lay A Little Lovin' On Me (Del Reeves) -- Grant Turner and Jan Garret [unconfirmed] talks about a future Opry fashion show featuring various artists [1973-10-02] -- Vietti commercial -- Carry Me Back (Statler Brothers) -- Grant Turner talks -- Vietti commercial -- Grant Turner talks about where members of the audience are from and future Opry shows -- [Unidentified fiddle tune] -- Opry warm up closing statement (Grant Turner) -- Cooper Martin and Big Star commercial -- [Unidentified] talks and mentions that this is the 2,489th Opry -- Opening statement -- Mrs. Grissom's commercial -- [Unidentified fiddle tune] -- Grant Turner introduces Billy Walker -- Billy Walker talks -- Things (Billy Walker) -- Mrs. Grissom's commercial -- Billy Walker introduces Ernie Ashworth -- Ernie Ashworth talks and introduces the next tune -- Each Moment (Spent With You) (Ernie Ashworth) -- Billy Walker talks and introduces the next tune -- Behind Closed Doors (Billy Walker) -- Charlie's Shoes (Billy Walker) -- Mrs. Grissom's plug (Grant Turner) -- Grand Ole Gospel commercial -- Tony Lama boots commercial -- Grant Turner introduces Hank Locklin -- Send Me The Pillow That You Dream On (Hank Locklin) -- Grant Turner talks and plugs Rudy Farms -- Hank Locklin talks -- Movin' (Hank Locklin) [unconfirmed] -- Rudy Farms plug (Grant Turner) -- Wild Side Of Life (Hank Locklin) -- Rudy Farms plug (Grant Turner) -- BC powder commercial -- Lonely Women Make Good Lover's ([Unidentified]) -- Come On Home And Sing The Blues To Daddy (Bob Luman) -- Bob Luman talks -- She's All I Got (Bob Luman, The Four Guys) -- Shoney's plug -- Bob Luman talks and introduces the next tune -- When You Say Love (Bob Luman) -- [Unidentified] talks -- Shoney's plug -- Bob Luman talks about The Four Guys -- Sing Me Back Home, I'll Fly Away, [unidentified tune], She'll Be Coming Around The Mountain, You Are My Sunshine, and Shutters And Boards mash up (The Four Guys) -- Bob Luman talks and introduces the next tune -- Down By The Lazy River (The Four Guys) -- Shoney's plug (Grant Turner) -- I Got A Woman (Bob Luman) -- Bob Luman introduces The Four Guys, Buddy Cannon, Joey Halterman, Gene Dunlap, and Steve Smith -- Shoney's plug -- BC power commercial -- Goo Goo candy plug -- Grant Turner introduces Archie Campbell -- Make Friends (Archie Campbell) -- Archie Campbell talks and acknowledges the audience and other performers -- [Unidentified tune] (Archie Campbell) -- Goo Goo candy plug -- Archie Campbell introduces Tommy Jones -- Dueling Banjos (Tommy Jones guitar) -- Archie Campbell introduces the Crook Brothers -- Tennessee Traveler (Crook Brothers) -- Goo Goo candy plug -- Comedy routine (Grant Turner and Archie Campbell) -- Ghost Riders In The Sky (Crook Brothers) -- King Leo Candy plug (Grant Turner) -- Archie Campbell talks -- Sixteen Tons ([Unidentified]) -- Closing statement (Archie Campbell) -- SSS Tonic commercial -- Martha White jingle -- Opening statement (Grant Turner) -- Grant Turner introduces Bill Monroe and the Bluegrass Boys -- Bill Monroe introduces the first tune -- Uncle Pen (Bill Monroe) -- Grant Turner and Bill Monroe talk -- Martha White plug (Grant Turner) -- Bill Monroe introduces Stu Phillips -- Everybody's Had The Blues (Stu Phillips) -- Delta Dawn (Marion Worth) -- Bill Monroe introduces Bob Bradford [unconfirmed] -- Depending On Which Side Of Love You're On (Bob Bradford) [unconfirmed] -- Martha White plug (Grant Turner) -- Bill Monroe introduces the next tune -- Use To Be (Bill Monroe) -- Bill Monroe introduces Stu Phillips -- Another Way To Say Goodbye (Stu Phillips) -- Martha White plug (Grant Turner) -- Bill Monroe talks about a future show -- [Unidentified tune] (Marion Worth) -- Bill Monroe introduces the next tune -- Kentucky Man (Bill Monroe and the Bluegrass Boys) [unconfirmed instrumental] -- Closing statement (Grant Turner) -- Martha White jingle -- Anacin commercial -- Opening statement -- I'm Moving On (Hank Snow) -- Hank Snow talks and introduces Jeanne Pruett -- Satin Sheets (Jeanne Pruett) -- Steven's Jeans commercial [unconfirmed name] -- Hank Snow introduces George Morgan -- For The Good Times (George Morgan) -- Hank Snow talks and introduces Lonzo and Oscar -- Comedy routine (Lonzo and Oscar) -- Lonesome Road Blues (Lonzo and Oscar) -- Steven's Jeans commercial [unconfirmed name] -- [Unidentified fiddle tune]</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>3 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-0248_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-0248</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2017-12-18</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Johnny Cash Show (Television series); Cash, Johnny, 1932-2003; WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); Turner, Grant; Louvin, Charlie, 1927-2011; Montgomery, Melba; Reeves, Del; Statler Brothers (musical group); Walker, Billy, 1929-2006; Ashworth, Ernie; Locklin, Hank, 1918-2009; Luman, Bob, 1937-1978; Four Guys (Musical group); Campbell, Archie, 1914-1987; Crook Brothers; Monroe, Bill, 1911-1996; Blue Grass Boys; Phillips, Stu; Worth, Marion; Snow, Hank; Pruett, Jeanne; Morgan, George, 1925-1975; Lonzo and Oscar;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/6461</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>