<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Camel Rock &amp; Roll Dance Party - 1956-07-31 - Part 1</dc:title>
<dc:description>CBS Rock 'N' Roll Dance Party program sponsored by Camel cigarettes, 1956-07-31 part 1. Hosted by Alan Freed with announcer Bern Bennett, starring Sam ""The Man"" Taylor and his orchestra, and featuring Gloria Mann, the Jayhawks, and the Three Chuckles. Produced and directed by Lou Melamed.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1956-07-31</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Sam "The Man" Taylor; Gloria Mann</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Opening theme (Alan Freed) -- Opening theme -- Opening statement (Bern Bennett) -- Alan Freed introduces Sam ""The Man"" Taylor and the orchestra -- Cloudburst (Sam ""The Man"" Taylor and orchestra) -- Camel Cigarettes commercial (Alan Freed) -- Camel Cigarettes jingle -- Alan Freed introduces Gloria Mann -- Razzle Dazzle (Gloria Mann) -- Alan Freed introduces Gloria Mann -- A Teenage Prayer (Gloria Mann) -- Camel Cigarettes commercial (Alan Freed) -- Alan Freed introduces Sam ""The Man"" Taylor and the orchestra -- The Camel Rock (Sam ""The Man"" Taylor and orchestra) -- Alan Freed introduces the Jayhawks</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>16 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR000929_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>TR000929</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2007-11-13</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>CBS Inc.; R.J. Reynolds Tobacco Company; Camel rock 'n roll dance party (Radio program); Freed, Alan; Bennett, Bern, 1921-2014; Taylor, Sam; Mann, Gloria (Singer); Three Chuckles (Musical group); Henry, Haywood; Melamed, Louis</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/886</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>