<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Kye Fleming &amp; Dennis L. Morgan Interview by John Lomax III.   </dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is an interview of Kye Fleming &amp; Dennis L. Morgan. The interview takes place on 1-15-82. </dc:description>
<dc:date>1982-01-15</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Kye Fleming; Dennis L. Morgan</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Side One - (0:03) -- Introduction by John Lomax III. John Lomax asks about the song "I Was Country When Country Wasn't Cool," written by Kye Fleming. (1:14) -- Kye Fleming further explains that she wrote the song after she came up with the title. (2:10) -- Dennis L. Morgan and Kye Fleming explain the form of "I Was Country When Country Wasn't Cool." (4:03) -- Kye Fleming explains the joy of writing "I Was Country When Country Wasn't Cool." (7:53) -- Kye Fleming speaks on working with Barbara Mandrell. (10:23) -- John Lomax asks about the song "I Wouldn't Have Missed It For The World." (14:24) -- Dennis L. Morgan mentions that they wrote "I Wouldn't Have Missed It For The World," in an hour. (15:08) -- Dennis L. Morgan and Kye Fleming discuss "Sweet Yesterday" written for Sylvia. (15:45) -- Kye Fleming and Dennis L. Morgan discuss running into writer's block. (18:45) -- Dennis L. Morgan discusses writing with Kye Fleming for James Galway (flute player).  The duo wrote "Memories On A Backroad" and "Dreams." (21:16) -- John Lomax asks Dennis L. Morgan and Kye Fleming how many successful #1 records they've had. (22:50) -- John Lomax asks about 1981 as a year compared to 1980 for the duo. </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>audio cassette, compact;</dc:format>
<dc:format>1.75 ips;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CAS4686_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>CAS4686</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-09-04</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Fleming, Kye; Morgan, Dennis</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9482</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>