<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Opryland Music Demo Recordings - Y-115</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording is of a group of demo recordings from Opryland Music. Recordings are from an unknown date and recorded by a number of unknown bands. Tape is labeled Y-115. </dc:description>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Living on the G. I. Bill (S. Willet) -- (02:37) A Letter From the Kids (E. Miller) -- (04:43) Little Bit (B. Lile) -- (06:40) Let's Paint the Town Red (Al Sweatt and W. S. Stevenson) -- (08:53) Looking For My Baby (B. Hill and W. S. Stevenson) -- (10:14) Letta Polka (J. Gilbertson) -- (13:00) Living it Again (L. Jimerson and M. Holcomb) -- (14:00) Love Struck (T. Coe and B. Sharp) -- (15:52) Lightening Blues (W. S. Stevenson) -- (18:26) Little Baby You're Running Wild (W. S. Stevenson) -- (21:10) Love Me Darlin' (K. Adelman and J. Williams) -- (22:44) Let it Grow (W. Miller) -- (23:54) The Last Rose (E. Miller) -- (25:06) When I Wanted You (C. Gant) -- (27:28) Who's the Lucky One? (T. B. Strength) -- (30:17) When You Reach the Bottom [Distorts] (D. Evans) -- (33:05) When We All Get Together With the Lord (H. Bethea) -- (36:20) Wild Love (J. Dethless and C. Klemer) -- (39:01) Wonder Why I'm Leavin' (L. Ceaser) -- (41:54) Willamette Rose (J. Smith) -- (44:38) Why Don't Somebody Love Me (T. Knitsen and T. Kelbourne) -- (47:17) A Woman Gets Tired (W. S. Stevenson) -- (50:21) What's Left of a Broken Heart (D. Denning) -- (53:38) Woman Trouble (D. Ames) -- (56:30) Who is There to Blame (G. Smith) -- (59:30) I'll Walk With You (Don Whitney) -- (1:02:47) I Want to Love You All the Time (E. Gray and W. S. Stevenson) -- (1:05:21) I'm Goin' Down (For the 3rd Time) (Pete Graves) -- (1:08:00) I've Loved and Lost Again (E. Miller) -- (1:10:41) I Hear a Sweet Voice Calling (Al Clauser) -- (1:13:25) I'll Cry at Anniversary Time (M. Weber) -- (1:15:57) I'm Asking You (B. Easley) -- (1:17:48) I'm Not Any Good Anymore (S. Willet) -- (1:20:32) I'm Not Gonna Beg You (C. Belew and W. S. Stevenson) -- (1:22:09) I'm Lonely (Pete Graves) -- (1:23:33) I'm Missing You More Than I Should (F. Wilson and W. S. Stevenson) -- (1:26:42) I Like it, I Like it, I Like it (E. Miller and B. Hughes)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1311_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1311</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-03-18</dcterms:created>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8650</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>