<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Curly Putman &amp; Bobby Braddock Interview by John Lomax III   </dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is an interview of Curly Putman and Bobby Braddock by John Lomax III. The interview takes place on 10-26-81.  </dc:description>
<dc:date>1981-10-26</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Curly Putman; Bobby Braddock;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Side One - (0:00) -- Bobby Braddock describes his personal writing style and co-writing with others. (0:40) -- John Lomax asks Bobby Braddock about the loneliness of writing music by yourself. (1:17) -- Bobby Braddock mentions his fondness of co-writing with Curly Putman. (1:37) -- John Lomax asks Bobbby Braddock about dealing with songwriting dry spells. (2:30) -- John Lomax asks Bobby Braddock about his past BMI awards and worst years for songwriting. (3:02) -- John Lomax asks Bobby Braddock about struggling with songwriting and getting his music on the market. (4:20) -- John Lomax asks Bobby Braddock about his ability to create songs from a woman's perspective. (6:17) -- John Lomax asks about Bobby Braddock's song, "Hard Times." (7:00) -- Bobby Braddock mentions that he wrote "Golden Ring" for George Jones and Tammy Wynette with Rafe Van Hoy. (7:35) -- John Lomax asks Bobby Braddock about his preferred instrument to write songs on. Bobby mentions that he prefers piano over guitar. (8:58) -- John Lomax asks Bobby Braddock how a newer writer could gain access to a publisher. (9:30) -- Bobby Braddock speaks positively about the work environment of Tree Publishing Company. (10:44) -- John Lomax asks Bobby Braddock about the potential of songs he has planned for release. (11:36) -- John Lomax asks Bobby Braddock about his association with BMI. Bobby Braddock mentions that he feels neutrally about BMI and ASCAP as a writer. (12:16) -- John Lomax asks Bobby Braddock whether his personal turmoil has helped his songwriting. (13:42) -- Curly Putman describes co-writing with Bobby Braddock. </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>audio cassette, compact;</dc:format>
<dc:format>1.75 ips;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CAS4690_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>CAS4690</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-09-05</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Putman, Curly; Braddock, Bobby;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9490</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>