<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Discussion: Memories and Music of Ralph Stanley - 2018-09-08</dc:title>
<dc:description>Discussion on the life and musical career of Ralph Stanley from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on September 8, 2018.  Participants include Jim Lauderdale, Larry Sparks and Ralph Stanley II.  Moderated by Michael Gray. Includes performances. Presented in support of the exhibition Ralph Stanley: Voice from on High.  </dc:description>
<dc:date>2018-09-08</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Larry Sparks; Jim Lauderdale; Ralph Stanley II;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Abrupt start and opening comments and introduction of host Michael Gray / (01:07) Opening comments and panelists introduction by Michael Gray / (09:36) Larry Sparks talks about how he came to play guitar with the Stanley Brothers and how he heard about them / (13:07) Larry talks about what drew him to the Stanley Brothers / (13:40) Larry talks about the shows that he performed with the group / (14:07) Michael talks about the 1965 University of Chicago Stanley Brothers recording / (14:35) Plays excerpt of the recording of When You And I Were Young Maggie / (15:50) Larry and Michael talk about the recording / (16:19) Larry talks about singing with the Carters and beginning to sing full-time with Ralph after Carter's death in 1966 / (19:15) Michael reads excerpt from Ralph Stanley's autobiography about Larry / (20:20) Larry talks about the sound Ralph was looking for after Carter died / (20:56) Larry talks about moving to Virginia and what living there was like / (22:31) Plays excerpted medley of Ralph Stanley and Larry Sparks singing together / (25:53) Larry talks about the type of venues he played with the Clinch Mountain Boys / (28:56) Larry talks about why he left the Clinch Mountain Boys and beginning his solo career / (31:14) Ralph II talks about going on-stage with his father for the first time and the influence Ralph's music had on him / (32:20) Ralph II talks about when he wanted to start working professionally with his father and his first gig as an official member of the Clinch Mountain Boys / (34:12) Ralph II talks about almost giving up music as a career, advice that he got from his father at that time and a vision he had of Keith Whitley in a dream / (38:32) Ralph II talks about Keith Whitley and influences on his singing / (39:45) Michael introduces a excerpt of a video documentary with Ralph singing with Keith Whitley / (40:10) Plays video / (42:55) Michael reads excerpt from Ralph Stanley's autobiography about Ralph II / (43:52) Ralph II talks about the good and bad side of being the child of a famous singer and starting his solo career / (48:03) Ralph II talks about his annual Hills Of Home Memorial Day festival / (51:17) Jim Lauderdale talks about first discovering the music of the Stanley Brothers / (52:52) Jim talks about coming to Nashville and working with Roland White, Ricky Skaggs and writing a tribute song to Bill Monroe for Ralph Stanley / (56:19) Jim tells story about Ralph having a stroke two weeks before a scheduled show and working other times with Ralph / (58:06) Talks about filling in for Ralph II on at MerleFest / (58:59) Talks about asking Ralph and the Clinch Mountain Boys to do a record with him / (01:00:47) Jim tells story about writing the song She's Looking At Me for Ralph and Ralph II / (01:01:33) Michael introduces an excerpt of the song If I Lose You from a video from the Hills of Home Memorial festival / (01:02:04) Plays video / (01:03:40) Jim talks about Ralph II / (01:05:50) Michael asks Ralph II what he learned from Ralph / (01:06:40) Michael asked Larry what he learned from Ralph / (01:07:23) Michael asks Larry what Carter Stanley was like / (01:08:12) Larry talks about using Carter's guitar while working with Ralph, the circumstances around playing it and wearing Carter's boots / (01:10:48) Michael asks Ralph II about his father's work ethic and working in his later years / (01:12:45) Ralph II talks about his father's singing and the movie Oh Brother, Where Art Thou / 01:13:40) Ralph II tells a story about the Stanley autobiographer Eddie Dean and Ralph taking a trip to the Stanley's birthplace / (01:14:48) Michael with comments and introduction of a live performance of Rank Stranger / (01:15:26) Performs Rank Stranger (Ralph II and Jim) / (01:19:12) Michael introduces Larry's performance / (01:19:54) Michael thanks the panelists for their participation in the discussion / (01:20:41) Performs medley of Don't Step Over An Old Love/Stone Walls And Steel Bars (Larry) / (01: 24:13) Introduces the next song / (01:23:45) Performs excerpt of I Only Exist (Larry) / (01:25:04) Introduces the next song / (01:25:51) Performs excerpt of I Am The Man, Thomas (Larry) / (01:26:40) Michael with final comments off-mic / (01:26:58) Walk-out music / (01:35:25) FILE END                                       </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 48/24</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0144</dc:identifier>
<dc:subject>Sparks, Larry; Lauderdale, Jim; Stanley II, Ralph; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8880</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>