<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Stars For Defense program - Eddy Arnold - 1958-03-07</dc:title>
<dc:description>Transcription of the Stars For Defense radio program recorded on March 7, 1958 with featured guest Eddy Arnold and with narration by Jay Jackson and musical accompaniment by Ray Bloch and His Orchestra.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1958-03-07</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Ray Bloch and His Orchestra; Eddy Arnold; Jay Jackson</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(0:00) Eddy Arnold announces the opening statements / (0:16) Ray Bloch and His Orchestra perform the opening theme / (0:26) Jay Jackson introduces Eddy Arnold / (1:00) Eddy Arnold performs "Wagon Wheels" / (2:54) Jay Jackson and Eddy Arnold talk about the next performance / (3:17) Eddy Arnold performs "You've Made Up For Everything," written by Cindy Walker / (6:09) Jay Jackson and Eddy Arnold announce information regarding the United States Defense program, NORAD / (8:41) Ray Bloch and His Orchestra perform "Blue Room," written by Richard Rodgers / (11:21) Jay Jackson and Eddy Arnold introduces the next performance / (11:33) Eddy Arnold performs "When He Was Young," written by Fred Ebb and Eddy Manson / (13:40) Ray Bloch and His Orchestra perform the closing theme and Jay Jackson announces the closing statements</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>12 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR003855_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>TR003855</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:isPartOf>TRB012_1</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-04-02</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Arnold, Eddy, 1918-2008; Bloch, Ray; Jackson, Jay</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/7189</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>