<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Performance - Dave Pomeroy - 2018-09-09</dc:title>
<dc:description>Musicians spotlight program featuring Dave Pomeroy from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on September 9, 2018.  Includes questions from the audience.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2018-09-09</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Dave Pomeroy;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Walk-in music / (00:55) Opening comments and introduction by Kayleigh Shoemaker / (04:35) Opening comments from Dave / (05:14) Talks about his background and musical influences / (06:17) Introduces the first song / (06:44) Performs Date With A Bass / (09:18) Talks about the acoustic bass and the electric bass and plays a bass riff that changed his life / (10:34) Takes about the influence of bassist Jack Bruce on him / (11:50) Talks about his first professional engagements and moving to London England / (13:12) Talks about moving to Nashville and his first gig in town / (15:06) Talks about starting to work with Guy Clark / (16:03) Introduces the next song / (16:28) Talks about his bass and German bassist Eberhard Weber / (17:20) Talks more about Guy Clark and about Emmylou Harris / (17:59) Talks about the effects he will use on the next song / (18:54) Performs Old Friends / (22:04) Talks about getting to know Don Williams' band and beginning to work with Don / (24:30) Introduces the next song / (25:28) Performs 'Til The Rivers All Run Dry / (27:30) Talks about Don Williams / (28:25) Introduces the next song / (30:26) Performs The Day Bass Players Took Over The World / (33:32) Introduces Garth Fundis in the audience and intros the next song / (36:52) Performs Tomorrow Never Knows / (41:11) Talks about what he's learned from the Beatles / (41:48) Introduces the next song / (43:27) Performs There's A Healing Comin' / (47:15) Talks about Nashville, the local music scene and the American Federation of Musicians / (48:57) Introduces the next song / (51:26) Performs Pendulum / (56:16) Closing comments / (56:36) Walk-out music / (57:06) FILE END               </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 48/24</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0147</dc:identifier>
<dc:subject>Pomeroy, Dave; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8884</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>