<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Hallmarks of Country Music - Lynn Anderson</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of an interview of Lynn Anderson (musician). The interview is hosted by Rick Phillips (army sergeant/ radio host) for the Hallmarks of Country Music segment. The tape was recorded on an unidentified date.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Lynn Anderson; Rick Phillips</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Promotion for Hallmarks of Country Music featuring Rick Phillips introducing Lynn Anderson -- (01:26) Hallmarks tune [featuring Rick Phillips introduction voiceover] ([Unidentified]) -- (02:06) V. A. tax information commercial spot hosted by Rick Phillips -- (02:39) Listen to a Country Song (Lynn Anderson) -- (05:16) Phillips inquires how Anderson discovered ""Listen to a Country Song,"" and Phillips inquires about Anderson's road work -- (08:38) Flattery Will Get You Everywhere (Lynn Anderson) -- (10:52) Phillips performs a state tax information radio spot -- (11:22) Ride, Ride, Ride (Lynn Anderson) -- (13:07) Anderson reflects on how she got her first recording contract, and Anderson discusses her time on the Lawrence Welk Show -- (15:19) Fool Me (Lynn Anderson) -- (17:25) Postal commercial spot hosted by an unidentified host -- (17:54) Keep Me in Mind (Lynn Anderson) -- (20:34) Veteran's Benefits commercial radio spot hosted by Phillips -- (21:06) Smile For Me (Lynn Anderson) -- (23:43) Anderson discusses how more types of songs are being accepted as country, and Phillips inquires how she recorded ""Ride, Ride, Ride"" -- (26:46) If I Kiss You (Lynn Anderson) -- (28:59) Stoux Indian Project commercial spot hosted by Phillips -- (29:48) Crib death commercial spot hosted by an unidentified host -- (30:28) Top of the World (Lynn Anderson) -- (33:12) Phillips inquires as to the story of how Anderson had ""Top of the World"" recorded before the Carpenters, and Anderson praises horses -- (37:03) You're My Man (Lynn Anderson) -- (39:37) Planned Parenthood commercial spot hosted by an unidentified host -- (40:04) Sing About Love (Lynn Anderson) -- (42:15) Project Ahead commercial spot hosted by Phillips -- (43:10) Talkin' to the Wall (Lynn Anderson) -- (45:48) Anderson reflects on working with Warner and the success she received with ""Rose Garden"" -- (47:50) Rose Garden (Lynn Anderson) -- (50:34) Love commercial spot hosted by an unidentified man and child -- (51:25) What a Man, My Man is (Lynn Anderson) -- (53:34) Hallmarks outro tune [featuring Phillips outro voiceover] ([Unidentified]) -- (55:38) Phillips introduces next week's guest: Seldom Scene -- (55:54) The Tie That Bonds (Seldom Scene) -- (56:41) Mike Auldridge and John Duffey reflect on how the band had evolved based on older bands -- (58:38) Everybody Slide [featuring Rick Phillips outro voiceover] (Seldom Scene)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Insert is of program information. The insert features time stamps.</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1629_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1629</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-06-12</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Anderson, Lynn, 1947-2015; Phillips, Rick;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9086</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>