<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Hank Snow Benefit at the Grand Ole Opry - Year 5 - Part 3</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of the Hank Snow Benefit Concert at the Grand Ole Opry. The segment is hosted by T. Tommy Cutrer (musician) and features performances by:  Hank Williams Jr. (musician) and Willie Nelson (musician). The recording is from an unidentified date. The tape is identified as the fifth year of the program. The tape is part three of three.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Hank Williams Jr.; T. Tommy Cutrer; Willie Nelson; Bobbie Nelson</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) The Blues Man (Hank Williams Jr.) -- (03:16) All in Alabama (Hank Williams Jr.) -- (07:38) A Country Boy Can Survive (Hank Williams Jr.) -- (12:30) All My Rowdy Friends (Have Settled Down) (Hank Williams Jr.) -- (16:16) If You Don't Like Hank Williams (Hank Williams Jr.) -- (20:00) Family Tradition (Hank Williams Jr.) -- (22:48) Kaw-Liga (Hank Williams Jr.) -- (36:34) T. Tommy Cutrer says goodnight to the audience; additionally, Cutrer introduces Duane Allen and Hank Snow -- (31:39) Cutrer reveals how a person is able to get a piece of the Grand Ole Opry -- (35:29) Melody [feautring: Funny How Time Slips Away and Night life] (Willie Nelson) -- (43:08) Down Yonder (Bobbie Nelson) -- (44:44) Willie Nelson introduces his band -- (45:07) If You've Got the Money I've Got the Time (Willie Nelson) -- (46:41) Sweet Memories (Willie Nelson)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1073_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1073</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-08-05</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Williams, Hank, Jr., 1949-; Cutrer, T. Tommy; Nelson, Bobbie; Nelson, Willie, 1933-;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9310</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>