<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Words and Music Night - 2001-05-03</dc:title>
<dc:description>Words and Music Night program held in the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on May 3, 2001.  Hosted by Steve Wariner.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2001-05-03</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Steve Wariner;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Program begins in progress.  Opening comments by Kyle Young.  Introduction of Steve Wariner and comments by John Knowles.  Performances include: Bossy Joe (Taylor Pie with Siobhan Hickerson and Courtney Waller) --  The Perfect Friend (Bob Spanburgh with Leah Blowes) -- We Like School (Steven Farmer with Kindergarten Club from Children's House) -- Shortness (Carol Ann Etheridge-Ford with David Crosby) -- Part Of My Heart Is Gone (Carol Ann Etheridge-Ford with Kelsey Horrick) -- Jerusalem (Kim Patton-Johnston with Danielle Dishy) -- The Beat (Kim Patton-Johnston with Ashley Whitacre) -- You Can't Change Me (James Nihand with Kyle Foresman) -- I Love You (James Nihand with Chelsey Hamm) -- When I Get Old (Dwight Liles with Sean McDonnell and Steven Pingle) -- Introduction of Justine Gregory -- About Words and Music -- The Dumb Song (Brian Hedges with Emily Perkins, Richard Percy and Jordan Jackson) -- My New Bike (Gregory Delang with Ashley Finch) -- A Family (Jeff Pearson with Julie Nabors) -- Snow Days (Taylor Pie with Lindsey Breedlove and Sammie Miller) -- My Angel (Simon McCain with Amy Millwood) -- Tornado (Clay Keith with Matt Grimes, Hiro Ichikawa and Jordan Caruthers) -- Scuba Steve (Kathy Hussey and Jason White with Anna Ezell and Lauren Gustafson) -- Searching For Her (Richard Fagan with Jordan Vandiver) -- Hey You (Richard Fagan with Natalie Phillips) -- Two Teardrops (Steve Wariner).</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>RDAT digital tape;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RS.2014.0047</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>R-DAT-0014</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2017-02-02</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Wariner, Steve; education; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/4869</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>