<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Discussion - Segregation and the Music Business - 2004-11-06</dc:title>
<dc:description>Panel discussion about how segregation determined practices in the music business, how musicians circumvented those practices and how they changed society from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on November 6, 2004.  Moderated by Michael Gray.  In support of the exhibit  "Night Train to Nashville: Music City Rhythm and Blues".</dc:description>
<dc:date>2004-11-06</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Larry Taylor; Thomas Cain; Big Al Downing; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Program begins in progress.  Recording begins in progress - Includes unheard questions from the audience -- Opening comments by Michael Gray -- Introduction of participants -- Big Al Downing tells of his early influences and how he became a member of Bobby Poe and the Poe Kat band, an all-white band -- Playing for segregated audiences -- Downing's love for country music and playing in Wanda Jackson's band -- White musicians reactions to black musicians -- Country radio and Nashville record company reactions to Downing's recordings as a black artist -- Larry Taylor talks about his early influences and how he started in the music business and as a musician -- Being a white musician in the black music scene -- Other musicians feelings toward Taylor and black musicians -- Skippy Brooks' influence on Taylor -- Thomas Cain tells about Bob Beckham's influence on him -- Cain's early days at Combine Music publishing company and starting to work for Broadcast Music Incorporated --</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Cain facing bigotry -- The marketing strategy behind Charley Pride's success -- Comparing Barry Gordy and Motown records marketing strategy to Nashville and the marketing behind Charley Pride -- Facing the factors behind the scenes in the Nashville music industry -- Cain coming to Nashville at the suggestion of Fred Wesley and attending Tennessee State University -- How his college music education helped him -- Downing tells story about his first piano lesson -- Thomas Cain tells story about agreeing to play recording session for Arthur Alexander for no pay and how it helped his career --  Downing tells story about playing in a Washington DC band when the Beatles first became popular and his band letting him go because of his race -- Thomas Cain talks about ownership and being used by people -- Discussion about age discrimination in the music industry -- </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>RDAT digital tape;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RS.2014.0106</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2017-06-21</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Taylor, Larry; Cain, Thomas; Downing, Big Al, 1940-2005; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/5274</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>