<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Grand Ole Opry - Royal Crown Cola - 1946-02-16 - Part 1</dc:title>
<dc:description>Part 1 of Royal Crown Cola sponsored Grand Ole Opry segment from February 16, 1946. Featuring Ernie Keller (announcer), Louie Buck (host) and performers Pee Wee King and his Golden West Cowboys with vocalists Cowboy Copas and Becky Barfield, George Wilkerson and his Fruit Jar Drinkers, Ernest Tubb and his Texas Troubadours, the Short Brothers of Jimmy Short and Leon Short (members of the Texas Troubadours), Wally Fowler and his Oak Ridge Quartet, and Bradley Kincaid. Held at Ryman Auditorium, Nashville, TN.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1946-02-16</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Pee Wee King; Golden West Cowboys; George Wilkerson; Fruit Jar Drinkers; Ernest Tubb; Texas Troubadours; Short Brothers; Cowboy Copas</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Oxydol commercial -- Opening statement (Ernie Keller) -- Opening theme -- Ernie Keller introduces Louie Buck -- Louie Buck introduces Pee Wee King and his Golden West Cowboys -- Columbus Stockade Blues (Pee Wee King and his Golden West Cowboys) -- Louie Buck introduces George Wilkerson and his Fruit Jar Drinkers -- Sally Gooden (George Wilkerson and his Fruit Jar Drinkers, Pee Wee King) -- Louie Buck introduces Ernest Tubb -- When Love Turns To Hate (Ernest Tubb and his Texas Troubadours) -- Royal Crown Cola commercial (Louie Buck, Pee Wee King, Ernie Keller) -- Louie Buck introduces Jimmy Short and Leon Short -- Blue Kimono Blues (Short Brothers) -- Louie Buck introduces Cowboy Copas and the Golden West Cowboys -- Filipino Baby (Cowboy Copas, Golden West Cowboys)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>16 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR000061_2</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>TR000061</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2005-05-29</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); Grand ole opry (Radio program); Ryman Auditorium (Nashville, Tenn.); Keller, Ernie; Buck, Louis, 1910-1971; King, Pee Wee, 1914-2000; Golden West Cowboys (Musical group); Copas, Cowboy; Barfield, Becky; Fowler, Wally; Oak Ridge Quartet; Oak Ridge Boys; Wilkerson, George W., 1895-1954; Fruit Jar Drinkers (Musical group); Tubb, Ernest, 1914-1984; Texas Troubadours; Short Brothers (Musical group); Short, Jimmie; Short, Leon; Kincaid, Bradley; Stewart, Redd; Boyd, Shorty</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/1003</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>