<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Interview - Little Big Town - 2018-06-27</dc:title>
<dc:description>Interview with Karen Fairchild, Kimberly Schlapman, Phillip Sweet, and Jimi Westbrook collectively known as Little Big Town from the CMA Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on June 27, 2018.  Moderated by Michael McCall.  Includes audio from video presentations.  Presented in support of the exhibit Little Big Town: The Power of Four. </dc:description>
<dc:date>2018-06-27</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Little Big Town; Karen Fairchild; Kimberly Schlapman; Phillip Sweet; Jimi Westbrook;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Walk-in music / (18:26) Opening announcements by Abi Tapia / (19:22) Opening comments from Michael McCall and introduction of Little Big Town / (20:30) Opening comments from the group and Michael thanks the group and their team for the cooperation during the exhibit planning / (21:04) Michael introduces a music video / (21:22) Audio from the music video for Summer Fever / (22:33) Comments from the band about the music video and the making of the video / (23:58) Talk about the writing and recording of Summer Fever / (27:00) Talk about working with Shane McAnally and Jesse Frasure / (28:14) Talk about the evolution of the sound of the band and taking risks / (29:39) Band comments on photos being shown / (29:52) Karen talks about her childhood and growing up / (34:36) Kimberly comments on photos being shown and talks about her childhood and growing up / (38:58) Jimi comments on photos being shown and talks about his childhood and grown growing up / (41:34) Phillip comments on photos being shown and talks about his childhood and growing up / (44:08) Band talks about photo of Karen that's being shown being confused with Jimi / (45:52) More comments from Phillip about photos being shown / (46:59) Phillip and Kimberly talk about the importance of music in church being influential on them / (48:35) Phillip talks about his mother being a performer and her influence on him / (49:21) Kimberly talks about how she and Karen met at College and began singing with each other / (50:50) Karen tells about how she and Kimberly came to Nashville and deciding to sing together / (53:59) Karen tells about bring Jimi on board and Jimi talks about coming to Nashville and meeting Kimberly / (56:46) Kimberly and Karen talk about concerns about adding a 4th member / (57:59) Phillip talks about moving to Nashville and meeting Karen and Kimberly / (58:59) Kimberly and Karen picks up the story about meeting Phillip / (59:39) Tells story about sleeping through the next meeting / (01:00:06) Talk about the voice blend happening right away / (01:00:45) Karen talks about the first song they sang together being Love Profound and how their first record deal came to happen / (01:02:46) Talk about their first public performance being on the Grand Ole Opry / (01:04:27) Michael introduces a backstage video made after their second appearance on a Dwight Yoakam show / (01:05:59) Band talks about the previous video and working with Dwight / (01:07:44) Band talks about a early appearance ticket referring to them as Little Big Foot and other mispronouncements of their band name / (01:10:27) Band talks about leaving Mercury Records / (01:11:19) Talks about business relationships and leading to their second record deal with Mercury records / (01:13:12) Karen talks about critical reviews of their first Mercury album being a learning experience / (01:14:01) Phillip and Jimi talk about decisions and learning from them / (01:14:46) Talk about their being dropped for a second time by a record label and deciding that they would make the decisions about when and if they quit the business / (01:15:34) Talk about beginning to work with Wayne Kirkpatrick and playing the CMA fest right before being dropped from Sony / (01:17:06) Talk about going off on their own and finding their own sound working with Wayne Kirkpatrick / (01:18:33) Talk about working with Mike Kraski and his independent record label / (01:19:29) Talk about some of the songs on The Road To Here project and having their attorney play it for record people / (01:20:) Talk about the song Boondocks becoming a hit / (01:21:36) Tells story about USO appearances in Afghanistan / (01:23:10) Talk about a fan named Taylor Swift writing an high school essay about Little Big Town and sending it to them with a letter and their friendship / (01:24:29) Phillip tells story about how they got the song Better Man / (01:25:25) Talk about signing with Capitol Records / (01:2:54) Talk about changing producers and leaving Wayne Kirkpatrick / (01:29:00) Kimberly talks about Wayne's success with a Tony nominated Broadway show / (01:29:19) Talks about taking chances with songs the songs they've recorded and believing in taking risks / (01:30:22) Karen talks about the music community and their management team / (01:30:55) Kimberly talks about always having faith in the music and in themselves / (0131:35) Closing comments / (01:32:09) Walk-out music / (01:32:28) Abrupt signal end / (01:32:50) Walk-out music continues / (01:34:50) Walk-out music ends / (01:49:44) Wireless mic picks up conversations during photoshoot and media interview / (01:56:20) Answers question about what they see for the future of Little Big Town since they've done almost everything that they can do / (01:56:55) Answers question about pre-show rituals / (01:57:41) Answers question about things that fans might not know about them / (02:00:15) Answers question about their performance of Wichita Lineman on the CMA award show and what Glen Campbell means to them / (02:01:54) Gives liners wishing everyone a happy holiday and a merry Christmas / (02:02:50) Gives liner inviting visitors to the museum exhibit / (02:03:10) Audio feed ends / (02:21:14) FILE END         </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0175</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2019-07-18</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Little Big Town (Musical group); Fairchild, Karen; Sweet, Phillip; Westbrook, Jimi; Schlapman, Kimberly; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9456</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>