<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Discussion - Hitmaker's Workshop - RCA Studio B - 2007-03-10</dc:title>
<dc:description>Discussion on the importance of RCA Studio B with professionals that worked there from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on March 10, 2007.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2007-03-10</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Harold Bradley; Jerry Bradley; Jim Ed Brown; Bill Harris; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Moderated by John Rumble.   Includes questions from the audience.  Opening comments by Ali Tonn.  Subjects include; (03:25) Plays recording of Don Gibson's recording of Oh Lonesome Me / (05:54) Introduction to Studio B and introduction of panelists by John Rumble / (12:55) Harold Bradley on why he and his brother Owen decided on build a studio and locate in the Music Row area / (15:58) Jerry Bradley comments on real estate brokers comments about the Music Row area / (17:14) Harold talks about RCA committing to opening a studio in Nashville shortly after he and Owen opened their studio (16:10) / (19:15) The ease of recording at Studio B /  (19:50) Why RCA didn't just use the Bradley studio instead of opening their own / (20:20) Jim Ed Brown talks about the differences between the TRAFCO studios and RCA Nashville studio / (21:20) Harold talks about Brown Brothers studio and Steve Sholes starting to use Chet Atkins / (22:20) Jerry Bradley talks about the sound of RCA studio Nashville /</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(23:55) Steve Sholes signing Elvis Presley to the RCA record label and him having the clout to open a studio in Nashville / (26:10) Jim Ed Brown talks about his and the Browns career and the recording of The Three Bells / (32:02) Jim Ed talks about preferring to record on one microphone / (33:28) Jim Ed talks about Chet Atkins and engineer Bill Porter's contributions / (35:50) Jim Ed and Harold talk about the Anita Kerr Singers / (36:52) Jim Ed talks about mono mix downs and record production techniques /  (38:55) Jim Ed talks about hearing and recording the song Pop A Top / (42:19) Plays recording of Jim Ed Brown's Pop A Top / (43:46)  Harold talks about Roy Orbison working at RCA Studio and recording Only The Lonely / (45:00) Harold talks about and plays his guitar part on Orbison's Running Scared / (46:37) Plays recording of Orbison's Running Scared / (48:25) Harold talks about recording Indescribably Blue with Elvis Presley /</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>RDAT digital tape;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RS.2014.0119</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2017-09-97</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Bradley, Jerry; Harris, Bill; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.); Bradley, Harold (Guitarist); Brown, Jim Ed, 1934-2015;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/5681</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>