<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>The history of country music - Volume 1 - Recording 2 - Side 2</dc:title>
<dc:description>Country music history program with voice overs and commercial recordings likely for radio broadcast.  Internet sources say the producer and narrator is Lee Cash.  Subject matter pertains to the history of country music and recording is likely a syndicated radio show. Tape is labeled as: volume one, recording two, side two.</dc:description>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) The History of Country Music (Unconfirmed) ([Unidentified]) -- (00:05) An unidentified speaker introduces Tennessee Ernie Ford -- (00:14) Ford asks his crowd if anyone had been born in February -- (00:44) An unidentified voice introduces "Cry of the Wild Goose" -- (00:51) Cry of the Wild Goose (Tennessee Ernie Ford) -- (03:49) An unidentified speaker introduces Patti Page to reflect on the success of "The Tennessee Waltz" -- (04:38) The Tennessee Waltz (Patti Page) -- (07:23) An unidentified speaker reflects on the activity of the Grand Ole Opry in 1952 -- (07:33) No Help Wanted (The Carlises) -- (09:41) An unidentified speaker reflects on Hank Thompson's formation -- (10:04) Hank Thompson reflects on his upcoming schedule in Waco Texas -- (10:32) Humpty Dumpty Heart (Hank Thompson) -- (12:33) An unidentified speaker introduces Tex Ritter -- (12:51) High Noon (Tex Ritter) -- (15:41) Ritter reflects on what inspired him -- (15:59) An unidentified speaker introduces Merle Travis to reflect on coal mines -- (16:30) Sixteen Tons (Merle Travis) -- (18:54) An unidentified speaker praises "Hey Porter" -- (19:14) Johnny Cash reflects on recording "Hey Porter" -- (19:56) Hey Porter (Johnny Cash) -- (21:55) An unidentified speaker introduces George Jones who reflects on his early career -- (22:25) Why Baby Why (George Jones) -- (24:30) The History of Country Music (Unconfirmed) ([Unidentified])</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1433_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1433</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-04-30</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Cash, Lee; Radio programs; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8858</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>