<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Harlan Howard Interviewed by Bob Allen in 1988 Side One</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of Bob Allen interviewing Harlan Howard. The recording takes place on 06-17-1988.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1988-06-17</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Harlan Howard</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Side One - (0:12) -- Bob Allen begins interview by asking Harlan Howard if he writes music at home. (0:34) -- Harlan Howard describes writing songs in the morning at Music Row. (1:35) -- Harlan Howard describes the process of receiving feedback on your own songwriting. (3:06) -- Harlan Howard describes his relationship with other songwriters in Nashville, TN. Harlan describes his respect for other songwriter's material and the difficulty of finding an original idea for a song. (5:19) -- Bob Allen asks Harlan Howard about a resurgence of his songwriting. Harlan describes going through a divorce and how that can mentally block songwriting. (7:02) -- Harlan Howard describes his competitive nature when songwriting. (8:44) -- Harlan Howard describes the need for having fun while trying for commercial songs. (9:17) -- Bob Allen asks Harlan Howard when he first began writing. Harlan Howard cites Ernest Tubb and Floyd Tillman as some of his influences. (11:43) -- Harlan Howard discusses being in the army and learning guitar from a fellow trooper from Oklahoma. Harlan left the army at the age of 21. (12:27) -- Harlan Howard describes moving to L.A. and pitching songs to publishers in Hollywood, CA. (13:25) -- Harlan Howard describes pitching a song to Johnny Bond and Tex Ritter. (14:05) -- Harlan Howard mentions writing songs with Buck Owens. (14:51) -- Harlan Howard describes being well acquainted with Bobby Bare. (15:35) -- Harlan Howard mentions why he moved out to the coast [California]. (16:07) -- Harlan Howard discusses the birth of Tin Pan Alley, Nashville. Mentions Hank Cochran, Roger Miller, Bill Anderson, Mel Tillis, Wayne Walker, Boudleaux Bryant. (17:18) -- Harlan Howard mentions his fondness for K.T. Oslin. (18:29) -- Harlan Howard describes pitching songs for Chet Atkins and Owen Bradley. (19:49) -- Harlan Howard describes his fondness for Owen Bradley and Chet Atkins. (20:31) -- Harlan Howard mentions his own publishing company "Wilderness Music." (21:59) -- Harlan Howard mentions that he wrote most of the music for "Wilderness Music." (23:35) -- Harlan Howard describes the challenge of pitching songs to artists. (26:19) -- Harlan Howard speaks about Nanci Griffith's method of songwriting. (29:50) -- Harlan Howard mentions that he loves to write songs for women. (31:08) -- Harlan Howard speaks about Waylon Jennings recording 74 of his songs. (32:00) -- Harlan Howard mentions that he is currently writing for Tree Publishing as a staff writer. </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>audio cassette, compact;</dc:format>
<dc:format>1.75 ips;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CAS4668_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>CAS4668</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-08-28</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Howard, Harlan;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9433</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>