<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Grand Ole Opry - Prince Albert - 1958-06-14 - Part 2</dc:title>
<dc:description>Part 2 of Prince Albert tobacco sponsored Grand Ole Opry segment from June 14, 1958. Featuring Grant Turner (announcer), Marty Robbins (host/performer) with Tompall and the Glaser Brothers, guest performers Lonzo &amp; Oscar, and regular performers Rod Brasfield, Tommy Jackson, Chet Atkins, Minnie Pearl, and Del Wood. Held at Ryman Auditorium, Nashville, TN. It is announced that this is the 975th broadcast.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1958-06-14</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Minnie Pearl; Lonzo &amp; Oscar; Del Wood; Marty Robbins; Glaser Brothers</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Marty Robbins introduces Minnie Pearl -- Comedy routine (Minnie Pearl) -- Prince Albert commercial (Grant Turner, Marty Robbins) -- Prince Albert jingle -- Marty Robbins introduces Lonzo &amp; Oscar -- Things Look Silly (Lonzo &amp; Oscar) -- Marty Robbins introduces Del Wood -- Chinese Breakdown (Del Wood) -- Grant Turner and Marty Robbins announce his tour schedule -- Just Married (Marty Robbins, Glaser Brothers) -- Closing theme -- Closing statement (Marty Robbins) -- Camel Cigarettes commercial -- Station announcements (Grant Turner)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>16 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR000376</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2006-03-08</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); National Broadcasting Company; Grand ole opry (Radio program); Ryman Auditorium (Nashville, Tenn.); Turner, Grant; United States. Armed Forces Radio Service; Brasfield, Rod; Minnie Pearl; Atkins, Chet; Wood, Del; Jackson, Tommy; Robbins, Marty; Tompall &amp; the Glaser Brothers; Lonzo and Oscar</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/1318</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>