<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Hank Williams: Complete Works Volume 5</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of a number of performances of Hank Williams Sr. (singer/songwriter). Tape is part of a collection labeled Hank Williams: Complete Works. Tape is labeled as part five of eight. The tapes were donated from the M.G.M. Studios collection.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Hank Williams</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Wait For the Light to Shine (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (02:51) Jesus is Calling (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (04:36) Ready to Go Home (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (06:33) Last Night I Dreamed of Heaven (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (08:03) When the Book of Life is Read (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (09:30) Devil's Train (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (12:33) Thy Burdens are Greater Than Mine (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (16:11) Are You Building a Temple in Heaven (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (18:29) The Prodigal Son (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (20:54) Are You Walkin' and Talkin' with the Lord (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (23:47) The Bottle of Armageddon (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (26:25) Going Home (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (28:23) Roving Cowboy (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (29:52) Wedding Bells (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (33:39) Lovesick Blues (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (36:56) I'll Have a New Body (I'll Have a New Life) (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (39:14) Lost Highway (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (42:21) Old Joe Clark (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (43:24) Where the Soul of Men Never Dies (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (45:08) Roving Cowboy (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (46:40) I'm a Long Gone Daddy (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (49:31) I'm Telling You (Hank Williams Sr. and Audrey Williams) -- (51:28) Bill Cheatham (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (52:51) When God Comes to Gather His Jewels (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (55:26) When the Blues Come Around (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (58:30) I Want to Live and Love (Hank Williams Sr.)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1456_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1456</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-05-10</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Williams, Hank, 1923-1953; Williams, Hank, 1923-1953. I saw the light;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8967</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>