<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Apollo 16 - Moon travel tapes - Tape 1 Side 1 </dc:title>
<dc:description>Tape 1 (Side 1). Program sent on the Apollo 16 space mission for Charlie Duke's (astronaut) enjoyment. Originally from a cassette Tape. Featuring Bill Bailey (host), Porter Wagoner, Dolly Parton, Wagon Masters, and Speck Rhodes.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Bill Bailey; Porter Wagoner; Dolly Parton; Wagonmasters; Speck Rhodes</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Opening announcer ([Unknown]) introduces Bill Bailey -- (00:07) Bill Bailey opening remarks addressing the Apollo 16 crew and introduces the Porter Wagoner Show -- (00:51) Companies Comin' (Porter Wagoner) -- (02:09) Porter Wagoner addresses Apollo 16 crew and introduces Dolly Parton -- (03:15) Joshua (Dolly Parton) -- (05:50) Porter Wagoner and Dolly Parton address Charlie Duke by reading a letter from his wife (Dorothy Meade Claiborne) and additional comments -- (07:18) Stampeding the Orange Blossom Special (Wagonmasters) -- (09:08) Porter Wagoner introduces Speck Rhodes -- (09:45) Speck Rhodes performs comedy with Porter Wagoner -- (11:20) Shindig in The Barn (Speck Rhodes) -- (12:46) Porter Wagoner speaks of inspiration for "The Right Combination" -- (13:48) The Right Combination (Porter Wagoner &amp; Dolly Parton) -- (16:10) Porter Wagoner introduces "Run That By Me One More Time" -- (16:27) Run That By Me One More Time(Porter Wagoner &amp; Dolly Parton) -- (19:05)Porter Wagoner comments on how a pole cat inspired "Wake Up Jacob" -- (19:29) Wake Up Jacob (Porter Wagoner) -- (21:08) Porter Wagoner addresses astronauts upcoming mission -- (21:46) How Great Thou Art (Dolly Parton) -- (24:55) Bill Bailey closing statement</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1102_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1102</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-12-12</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Bailey, Bill; Wagoner, Porter; Parton, Dolly; Parton, Dolly, 1946-; Wagonmasters (Musical group); Rhodes, Speck;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8282</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>