<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Opryland Music Demo Recordings - Y-106</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording is of a group of demo recordings from Opryland Music. Recordings are from an unknown date and recorded by a number of unknown bands. Tape is labeled Y-106. </dc:description>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Shimmy Shakin' Daddy (M. Lindsey) -- (02:18) Sally Let Your Bangs Hang Down (W. S. Stevenson) -- (04:45) Sooner or Later (C. Gant) -- (07:45) A Story Book Affair (V. Orr) -- (10:30) Shake 'Em Up Rock (T. T. Tyler) -- (12:38) Service Station Blues (J. Smith) -- (15:16) Shiftless Skonk (W. S. Stevenson) -- (18:19) Susie Was too Subtle For Seattle (J. Statham and D. James) -- (21:04) Solider and Mercy (D. Gray and C. Cole) -- (23:44) Smokey (W. S. Stevenson) -- (26:54) Stop, Look and Listen (E. Foreman) -- (30:05) Johnny Calypso (S. Masters) -- (31:56) Just One More (K. Wade and T. Tilley) -- (33:40) Juke Box Jamboree (T. Blake) -- (35:26) Jr. Blues (N. Espositio and M. Howard) -- (38:06) Jennie My Love (C. Harris and W. Fleener) -- (40:26) Jam Jam Blues (Stevenson) -- (42:58) Just in Time (B. Flournoy) -- (44:34) Julia (M. Jaffe, B. Henderson, and Stevenson) -- (46:18) Just Thinking (B. Flournoy) -- (47:23) Juvenile Delinquency (T. Beaver and H. Beaver) -- (50:01) Jesse James Boogie (C. Pryor, E. Nothington, and R. Lipscomb) -- (52:44) Just a Closer Walk With Thee (Stevenson) -- (55:34) Jump Jack Jump (C. Gant) -- (57:49) Just Out of Reach (V. F. Stewart) -- (1:00:18) Juvenile Love (T. Colbert and E. Miller) -- (1:02:28) Won't Be Around (E. Oleachea and Stevenson) -- (1:04:50) Welcome (C. Bartmess) -- (1:07:43) Wolf Pack Shuffle (L. Dossey) -- (1:09:37) Wounded Heart (L. Dossey) -- (1:12:33) What Does it Take? (B. Flournoy) -- (1:14:05) Whatcha Gonna Do Tonight (G. London and Stevenson) -- (1:16:11) Why Must it Be? (J. McGraw and T. Smith) -- (1:18:30) Winkin', Blinkin' and Thinkin'  (J. Reagan and Stevenson) -- (1:19:40) What's the Use of Worryin'? (Regan and Stevenson) -- (1:20:57) What's the Matter With Me? (Regan and Stevenson) -- (1:22:22) When God Moves man (D. Rose and B. Rose) -- (1:24:45) Wise Talk (B. Flournoy) -- (1:26:01) Will You Wed Me (When the Ice Worms Nest Again) -- (1:28:36) Wasted Steps to the Altar (C. Klemer and Stevenson) -- (1:31:30) Write Me in Care of the Blues (E. Miller and Stevenson) </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1302_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1302</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-03-13</dcterms:created>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8636</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>