<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Opryland Music Demo Recordings - Y-95</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording is of a group of demo recordings from Opryland Music. Recordings are from an unknown date and recorded by a number of unknown bands. Tape is labeled Y-95. </dc:description>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) I Play (Ruby Allmond) -- (02:32) If You Should See Mary (Ruby Allmond) -- (05:15) I Can't Let My Hand Throw the First Stone (Ruby Allmond) -- (07:24) I Just Learned to Rock (J. Kuhn and W. S. Stevenson) -- (10:02) Irma (F. Huskey) -- (12:27) I Might Have Known (F. Oleachea and W. S. Stevenson) -- (14:47) I'm So Blue (Missing You) (C. C. Beam, C. L. Jiles, and W. S. Stevenson) -- (16:39) I Feel It (W. S. Stevenson) -- (19:13) I Was Kissing You Goodnight (J. F. Kibler, J. Williams, and K. Adelman) -- (20:17) If I Had (A Love That Used to Be) (K. Adelman and J. Williams) -- (21:40) I Never Wanted to Be Free (B. Flournoy) -- (23:43) I've Been Cheating All Along (B. Flournoy) -- (25:43) It's Your Turn to Cry (R. Dant) -- (27:41) I Was the Last to Know (B. Flournoy) -- (30:03) I Found Paradise (G. Lukenbill and F. Ronaud) -- (32:48) I Wish I Knew (T. Farr) -- (35:10) If (T. Farr and J. Gaither) -- (37:16) I've Found My Love (L. Newman and J. Hobson) -- (39:07) I Would Never Grow Tired of Loving You (W. Wolfe) -- (41:45) I'm Going Home (L. Dossey and W. S. Stevenson) -- (43:47) I Wish I Knew the World (L. Newman and J. Hobson) -- (46:10) It's a Wonderful Feeling (L. Newman and J. Hobson) -- (47:15) I'm Just a Stand-in (B. Maxwell) -- (49:04) I'll Pretend (M. and M. Coursey) -- (51:06) It Takes a New Love (W. Daniels) -- (53:37) I Live For You (W. Chandler and W. S. Stevenson) -- (56:29) I Threw My Heart Away (C. and M. Wright, M. Davis, and W. S. Stevenson) -- (58:46) I'd Hate to be in Your Shoes (V. Orr) -- (1:00:46) I Hold Your Picture (M. Coursey)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1291_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1291</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-03-08</dcterms:created>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8613</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>