<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Pulsebeat Radio Show: Charlie Daniels - Part 2</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of Kim Spangler (host) dictating the Pulsebeat section of the Voice of the Heartland Radio Show. The episode interviews Charlie Daniels (musician). The episode was set to air for the week of December 05, 1988. The episode is part 2 of 2.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1988-12-05</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Kim Spangler; Charlie Daniels</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:01) Kim Spangler introduces the upcoming Charlie Daniels Pulsebeat show -- (00:50) Boogie Woogie Country Blues (Charlie Daniels) -- (03:56) Spangler introduces the break -- (04:10) Spangler and Daniels discuss the country roots of "Homesick Heroes" -- (04:45) Spangler introduces Daniels to recall how he treats negative reviews -- (06:03) The mistaken nature of "The South's Gonna do it Again" is discussed, and Spangler and Daniels discuss what in the South inspires artists -- (08:51) The South's Gonna do it Again (Charlie Daniels) -- (12:42) Dial 901 [unconfirmed] ([Unidentified]) -- (13:40) Danny Thomas performs a St. Jude's commercial spot -- (14:20) Spangler asks Daniels to make a song request -- (15:48) Statesboro Blues (Allman Brothers Band) -- (19:59) Spangler asks Daniels is he is tired of "The Devil Went Down to Georgia" -- (21:10) The Devil Went Down to Georgia (Charlie Daniels) --(24:28) Unidentified tune [featuring Kim Spangler outro discussion] ([Unidentified])</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-0969_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-0969</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-09-09</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Spangler, Kim; Daniels, Charlie; Daniels, Charlie, 1936-;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9521</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>