<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Becky Hobbs Interview - Biff Collie</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of an interview with Becky Hobbs (performer) conducted by Biff Collie. </dc:description>
<dc:date>1989-07-17</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Becky Hobbs; Biff Collie</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Becky Hobbs radio spot for the Music City Album Review (featuring Biff Collie harmony and piano rift) -- (00:08) Hobbs radio spot for the Music City Album Review (featuring Collie harmony and piano rift) -- (00:19) Hobbs radio spot about Collie and the Music City Album Review -- (00:33) Hobbs radio spot with Collie (featuring piano backing) -- (00:42) Hobbs discusses how the title of her album, All Keyed Up, got its name from a shirt -- (01:50) "They Always Look Better When They're Leavin'" is discussed by Hobbs to be a song featuring a past love of Hobbs -- (02:26) They Always Look Better When They're Leavin' (Becky Hobbs) [excerpt] -- (02:34) Hobbs discusses how she attempted to produce harmonies; the harmony part of "They Always Look Better When They're Leavin'" was completed by Larry Gadler -- (03:18) " Mama Was A Working Man" is joked about by Hobbs and Collie and Hobbs recalls Mike Darwin sending her "Mama Was A Working Man" before Don London reworked it -- (04:57) Collie has Hobbs discuss: Bartlesville, Oklahoma, her sister getting a piano, and Hobbs fighting her sister for playing time -- (06:49) Collie and Hobbs discuss how Hobbs played during Sunday School -- (07:20) [Unidentified Piano Tune] (Becky Hobbs) -- (07:38) Collie compliments Hobbs -- (07:46) Hobbs believes "She Broke Her Promise "is her favorite song, and Hobbs tells about how her father made her mother promise him she would remarry -- (09:26) Collie and Hobbs discuss how Hobbs in not a cowgirl, and Hobbs reflects on how Oklahoma inspired " Cowgirl's Heart"  -- (10:39) Cowgirls Heart (Becky Hobbs) [excerpt] -- (10:45) Hobbs claims the tune to be an "Indian  Type" -- (11:15) Do You Feel The Same Way Too? (Becky Hobbs) [excerpt] -- (11:34) Hobbs describes the tune "Do You Feel The Same Way Too?" to be a 1950s dance tune -- (11:44) Collie and Hobbs discuss what equipment Hobbs brings with her on tour -- (12:29) Collie and Hobbs reflect on the disorganization before introducing "I'm-A-Gonna Get You;" Hobbs tells about the first time Richard Bennett came to visit -- (13:41)  I'm-A-Gonna Get You (Becky Hobbs) [excerpt] -- (13:52) Hobbs tells how Bennett's visit was what led to "I'm-A-Gonna Get You" -- (14:06) Collie and Hobbs harmonize to reintroduce the Music City Album Review (featuring piano rift) -- (14:11) Collie and Hobbs reflect on how Hobbs had better success writing song and Hobbs reveals her first unknown album -- (15:00) I'll be Your Audience (Becky Hobbs) [excerpt] -- (15:30) Hobbs tells how her song "I'll be Your Audience" was on Helen Reddy's record -- (16:06) Hobbs discusses Reddy's helpfulness to female artists and how she had a change of record management -- (17:43) Collie inquires and Hobbs tells that she does not have a tattoo -- (18:05) Collie and Hobbs discuss the royalties associated with her songs -- (19:07) "Jones On The Jukebox" is praised by Collie -- (19:35) Jones On The Jukebox (Becky Hobbs) [excerpt] -- (19:43) Hobbs tells how Don Goodman sang " Jones On The Jukebox" -- (20:12) Collie inquires about Hobbs' reaction to Goodman and Hobbs tells what a "hook" is -- (21:49) Collie and Hobbs discuss how Hobbs and Goodman were in discussion when they came up with "Old Flame Burns Blue" -- (22:45) "A Woman Needs" is recalled by Hobbs to be memorable song she wrote in the back of her bus -- (23:15) A Woman Needs (Becky Hobbs) [excerpt] -- (23:26) Hobbs discusses how some of the best tunes might not make sense -- (23:56) Collie and Hobbs discuss the hooks Hobbs has on her album and in "A Woman Needs" -- (24:43) Collie discusses how the "Are There Any More Like You (Where You Came From)" video had been lasting and Collie and Hobbs talk about the power of video -- (26:51) Collie praises Hobbs' charm and both say their goodbye thoughts </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1190_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1190</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-01-28</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Hobbs, Becky; Collie, Biff;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8433</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>