<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Bob McDill Interviewed by Bob Allen in 1977 Side One</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of Bob Allen interviewing Bob McDill. The recording takes place on 11-17-77.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1977-11-17</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Bob McDill</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Side One - (0:07) -- Bob Allen mentions an article written about Bob McDill's writing habits. Bob Allen asks about Bob McDill's transition from writing rock n' roll to country music. (2:01) -- Bob Allen asks Bob McDill whether he took other jobs early on in Memphis when songwriting. (2:58) -- Bob Allen asks Bob McDill when he first decided to write music full time. (4:48) -- Bob Allen asks Bob McDill about coming to Nashville with Jack Clement. (6:41) -- Bob Allen asks whether Bob McDill got discouraged when first beginning songwriting. (8:55) -- Bob Allen asks Bob McDill about his daytime songwriting habits. (12:00) -- Bob Allen discusses with Bob McDill about the "Kristofferson Myth" and Hank Williams give songwriting a false, reckless romantic image. (12:35) -- Bob Allen asks Bob McDill about his personal listening habits. Bob McDill says he doesn't listen to country stations so he doesn't compete mentally with other great songwriters. (16:10) -- Bob Allen asks Bob McDill about his daily writing quota. (17:46) -- Bob Allen asks Bob McDill about the evolution of writing a song. (19:52) -- Bob Allen asks Bob McDill about his ability to gauge whether a song will become a hit or an average album cut. (21:17) -- Bob McDill discusses pitching his own songs. (22:01) -- Bob Allen asks Bob McDill whether he has ambitions to write prose. (Referencing Bob McDill's liner notes on a Bobby Bare album). (24:15) -- Bob McDill discusses that he believes lyricism is an underappreciated artform. (25:45) -- Bob Allen asks Bob McDill about how he personally integrates melodies and lyrics. (28:04) -- Bob Allen asks whether Bob McDill ever writes music at home. (28:56) -- Bob Allen asks why Bob McDill turned down recording contracts in the past. (30:32) -- Bob Allen asks Bob McDill how many years he's lived in Nashville. (30:55) -- Bob McDill discusses being chosen as 'Songwriter of the Year'. </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>audio cassette, compact;</dc:format>
<dc:format>1.75 ips;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CAS4660_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>CAS4660</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-08-27</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>McDill, Bob;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9416</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>