<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Billy Sherrill  Interviewed by Bob Allen in 1982 Side Two </dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of Billy Sherrill being interviewed by Bob Allen. The interview takes place on 12-22-82.           </dc:description>
<dc:date>1982-12-22</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Billy Sherrill </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Side Two - (0:15) -- Billy Sherrill discusses working with Peanutt Montgomery. (1:28) -- Bob Allen asks about recording with only 8 tracks. Billy Sherrill speaks about recording drums before anything else. (2:38) -- Billy Sherrill discusses scratching a vinyl record to produce a homemade metronome/drummer. He calculated the scratches with a compass. "It's called survival, not being able to pay a drummer." - Billy Sherrill. (4:25) -- Billy Sherrill speaks about almost getting fired over EQ'ing a song. (6:12) -- Bob Allen asks Billy Sherrill about his new producing techniques. Bob Allen mentions the complexity of Billy Sherrill's string recording. (7:16) -- Billy Sherrill mentions the influence of Johann Strauss on his string arrangements. (7:58) -- Billy Sherrill speaks about altering the waltz beat on the song "Almost Persuaded." (9:43) -- Billy Sherrill speaks about asking the musicians to physically change their instrument dynamics when recording. (12:30) -- Bob Allen asks about Billy Sherrill's use of steel guitar. Billy Sherrill mentions pop stations giving him feedback to replace steel guitar with a horn section. (16:50) -- "I can go back and listen to a record I did ten years ago and I'm ashamed of it. I can see things I'd wish I had done." - Billy Sherrill discusses the advancements in recording technologies in the past ten years. Billy Sherrill mentions that this newer recording technology creates a desire to go back and change records he made in the past. (18:35) -- Billy Sherrill speaks about the release of 16-track recording. He mentions that producers were eager to fill up more than 8 tracks just because they had the new ability to do so. (21:14) -- "A lot of times less is best." - Billy Sherrill. Billy Sherrill goes on to describe Merle Haggard's minimalistic approach to recording. (22:35) -- Billy Sherrill speaks about regretting the mix on Charlie Rich's "The Most Beautiful Girl." (24:46) -- Billy Sherrill discusses the negative recording impact of using over 24-tracks. (26:11) -- Billy Sherrill speaks about Floyd Cramer's piano lick on "Last Date." Billy Sherrill used this pedal effect on the song "Behind Closed Doors" by Charlie Rich. (28:45) -- Billy Sherrill speaks about his recording work with Tammy Wynette. (29:49) -- Bob Allen asks about the arrangement of "Stand By Your Man" by Tammy Wynette. (35:52) -- Billy Sherrill speaks about receiving feedback from the Epic/CBS New York A&amp;R Department. (37:00) -- Billy Sherrill speaks about using a two octave gliss, "Yeah but that was all the way from Nashville to Heaven, see, it had to be a long gliss" - Billy Sherrill. (37:19) -- Billy Sherrill speaks about how the use of strings can be abused. (40:12) -- Billy Sherrill speaks about the gospel roots of the Statler Brothers and The Oak Ridge Boys. (40:58) -- Billy Sherrill speaks about his budget when producing for CBS. (41:41) -- Billy Sherrill speaks about recording Barbara Mandrell's "The Midnight Oil." Billy Sherrill slowed a track down to 7 1/2 inches per second and recorded a tack piano. Sherrill then increased the speed back to 15 IPS in order to achieve the sound of a mandolin on the recording.</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>audio cassette, compact;</dc:format>
<dc:format>1.75 ips;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CAS4680_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>CAS4680</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-09-03</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Sherrill, Billy;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9474</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>