<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>David Allan Coe - Penitentiary Blues outtakes and trims</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recordings of various trims and outtakes from the documentary Penitentiary Blues, featuring David Allan Coe (performer).</dc:description>
<dc:creator>David Allan Coe</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>[Unidentified guitar riff] -- David Allan Coe talks about songwriting and it's therapeutic quality -- Penitentiary Blues (David Allan Coe) (incomplete) -- [Unidentified] introduces Coe and talks about his criminal past -- [break] -- Oh Warden (David Allan Coe) -- [Unidentified] talks about Coe's past and his current musical endeavors -- [break] -- [Unidentified] introduces Coe and talks about comparisons between Coe's past and his current situation -- One Way Ticket To No Where (David Allan Coe) -- [Unidentified] continues talking about Coe's criminal past and current musical success</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-7-03881_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-7-03881</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-05-10</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Coe, David Allan;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/7379</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>