<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Artist in Residence - Tom T. Hall - 2005-08-17. Set one of two.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Third of three Artist in Residency appearances by Tom T. Hall at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on August 17, 2005.  Set one of two.  Hosted by Eddie Stubbs.  Special guests include; Terry Eldridge; Larry Stephenson; Chris Jones; Sally Jones; Becky Isaacs; Sonya Isaacs; Larry McPeak; Darren Beachley; Alicia Nugent; Carl Jackson; John Prine; Carlene Carter; Lorrie Davis Bennett; Heather Berry; Bobby Osborne; David Talbert; Jeannette and Johnny Williams; Joe Isaacs Family; Mark Newton;</dc:description>
<dc:date>2005-08-17</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Tom T. Hall; Eddie Stubbs; Terry Eldridge; Larry Stephenson; Chris Jones; Sally Jones; Becky Isaacs; Sonya Isaacs; Larry McPeak; Darren Beachley; Alicia Nugent; Carl Jackson; John Prine; Carlene Carter; Lorrie Davis Bennett; Heather Berry; Bobby Osborne; David Talbert; Johnny Williams; Jeanette Williams; Joe Isaacs Family; Mark Newton; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Recording begins in progress.  Opening comments by Kyle Young. Introduction of Eddie Stubbs.  Introduction of band members.  Instrumental Medley Of Tom T. Hall Songs -- Introduction of Tom T. and Dixie Hall -- Bill Monroe For Breakfast (Tom T. Hall and Terry Eldridge) -- Interview -- The Pretty Blue Dress (Larry Stephenson) -- Clinch Mountain Mystery (Larry Stephenson) -- Little White Lies (In A Little White Church) (Chris and Sally Jones) -- The Man On The Side Of The Road (Chris and Sally Jones with Tom T. Hall) -- Bluebird In The Rain (Sally Jones with Becky and Sonya Isaacs) -- I Love You To The Moon And Back (Larry McPeak and Darren Beachley) -- Coal Miner's Dream (Darren Beachley) --  I Cried All The Way To Kentucky (Alecia Nugent with Carl Jackson and Sonya Isaacs) -- Paradise (John Prine) -- Comedy (Carlene Carter and Lorrie Davis Bennett) -- Local Flowers (Heather Berry with Carlene Carter and Lorrie Davis Bennett) --</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>I Washed My Face In The Morning Dew (Bobby Osborne with Terry Eldridge and David Talbert) -- Get In The Boat (Jeanette and Johnny Williams) -- 1-800-Lonesome (Jeanette Williams) -- You're With Us, Ain't You Lord (Tom T. Hall with the Joe Isaacs Family) -- Family Reunion, Amen (Joe Isaacs Family with Tom T. Hall) -- A Beautiful Home (Mark Newton with Alicia Nugent and Carl Jackson) -- Follow Me Back To The Fold (Mark Newton with guests) -- Intermission.</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>RDAT digital tape;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RS.2014.0073</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2017-03-23</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Hall, Tom T.; Stubbs, Eddie; Eldridge, Terry; Stephenson, Larry; Jones, Chris; Jones, Sally; Isaacs, Becky; Isaacs, Sonya; McPeak, Larry; Beachley, Darren; Nugent, Alicia; Jackson, Carl; Prine, John; Carter, Carlene; Bennett, Lorrie Davis; Berry, Heather; Osborne, Bobby; Talbert, David; Williams, Jeanette; Williams, Johnny; Joe Isaacs Family (Musical group); Newton, Mark; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/5043</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>