<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Interview with T-Bone Burnett - 2000-12-15</dc:title>
<dc:description>Interview with T-Bone Burnett with Chris Deritis on December 12, 2000.  Engineered by Matt Marrin.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2000-12-15</dc:date>
<dc:creator>T-Bone Burnett; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Interview with T-Bone Burnett conducted by Chris Deritis for Ground Zero.  Subject matter includes; Oh Brother, Where Art Thou project-- Coen brothers -- Man Of Constant Sorrow -- Record production work -- Elvis Costello's King Of America album and the song Indoor Fireworks -- August and Everything After album by Counting Crows -- Influence of Hip Hop on production -- Meeting Gillian Welch and making the Revival album -- Gillian's help during the Oh Brother, Where Art Thou project -- Ralph Stanley and the Stanley Brothers -- Evolution of bluegrass music -- Oh, Death -- Researching music for the Oh Brother project -- You Are My Sunshine and the 4th verse of same -- Recording techniques used in the Oh Brother project -- Recording and filming at the Ryman Auditorium -- Chris Thomas King project -- Latest album project with Gillian Welch -- The current state of music -- Film soundtrack and stage play work.</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>RDAT digital tape;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RS.2014.0043</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Tbone interview - J538-2; T-Bone on left channel - Chris on right channel</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2017-01-25</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Burnett, T-Bone; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/4857</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>