<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Grand Ole Opry - Martha White - 1952-11-22 - Part 1</dc:title>
<dc:description>Part 1 of Martha White sponsored Grand Ole Opry show from November 22, 1952. Hosted by Ernest Tubb.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1952-11-22</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Ernest Tubb; Ray Price; June Carter; Chet Atkins; Carter Sisters; Maybelle Carter; Bill Monroe; Blue Grass Boys</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Walking The Floor Over You (excerpt) (Ernest Tubb) -- Opening statement (Jud Collins) -- Somebody Loves You (Ernest Tubb) -- Don't Let The Stars Get In Your Eyes (Ray Price) -- Martha White jingle (A Good Man Is Hard To Find) (June Carter, Chet Atkins) -- Martha White commercial (Jud Collins) -- Martha White jingle (A Good Man Is Hard To Find) (June Carter, Chet Atkins) -- Little Liza Jane (Chet Atkins) -- A Picture, A Ring And A Curl (The Carter Sisters, Maybelle Carter) -- Goodbye Old Pal (Bill Monroe and His Blue Grass Boys)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>16 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR001053</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2014-06-27</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); Grand ole opry (Radio program); Ryman Auditorium (Nashville, Tenn.); Martha White Foods; Collins, Jud; Tubb, Ernest, 1914-1984; Byrd, Billy; Price, Ray, 1926-2013; Cash, June Carter, 1929-2003; Atkins, Chet; Carter Sisters; Carter, Maybelle, 1909-1978; Carter, Anita; Carter, Helen, 1927-1998; Monroe, Bill, 1911-1996; Blue Grass Boys</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/148</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>