<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Artist in Residence - Tom T. Hall - 2005-08-17.  Set two of two.</dc:title>
<dc:description>Third of three Artist in Residency appearances by Tom T. Hall from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on August 17, 2005.  Set two of two.  Hosted by Eddie Stubbs.  Special guests include; Ryan Holladay; Lisa Martin; Ray Martin; Michelle Nixon; The VW Boys; Paul Williams; David Peterson; Larry Sparks; James King; Josh Williams; Gary Brewer; Don Rigsby; Carl Jackson; Sonya Isaacs; </dc:description>
<dc:date>2005-08-17</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Tom T. Hall; Eddie Stubbs; Ryan Holladay; Lisa Martin; Ray Martin; Michelle Nixon; The VW Boys; Paul Williams; David Peterson; Larry Sparks; James King; Josh Williams; Gary Brewer; Don Rigsby; Carl Jackson; Sonya Isaacs; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Recording begins in progress.  Comments from Eddie Stubbs and introduction of Ryan Holladay -- Girls Are Looking Better Everyday (Ryan Holladay) -- Jimmy Martin Songs For Dinner (Ryan Holladay) -- Unidentified Instrumental (Ryan Holladay) -- Mr. Engineer (Lisa Martin with Ray Martin) -- Harlan (Michelle Nixon) -- I Know Rain (Michelle Nixon) -- Ole Billy Ray's Chickens (The VW Boys) -- Do Something For Jesus Today (Paul Williams) -- New Pair Of Glasses (David Peterson) -- I Want You To Meet My Friend (Tom T. Hall with Larry Sparks) -- The Water Lily (Tom T. Hall with ???) -- Whatever Happened To Julie? (James King) -- Killer On The Loose (Josh Williams) -- Elvis On Velvet And Monroe On Grass (Gary Brewer) -- Empty Old Mailbox (Don Rigsby with Carl Jackson and Sonya Isaacs) --  The Midnight Call (Don Rigsby) -- Me And Jesus (Don Rigsby with all) -- Closing comments by Eddie Stubbs over band.</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>RDAT digital tape;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source was 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RS.2014.0074</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2017-03-28</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Hall, Tom T.; Stubbs, Eddie; Holladay, Ryan; Martin, Lisa; Martin, Ray; Nixon, Michelle; The VW Boys (Musical group); Williams, Paul; Peterson, David; Sparks, Larry; King, James; Williams, Josh; Brewer, Gary; Rigsby, Don; Jackson, Carl; Isaacs, Sonya; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/5044</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>