<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Hank Snow Interview for WTCW: Part 2</dc:title>
<dc:description>This recording features backstage interviews from the Grand Ole Opry with Hank Snow and guests. Guests include: Justin Tubb, June Carter, Del Wood, Porter Wagoner, Chester Atkins, and Little Jimmy Dickens. Hank asks each guest where they have been on tour, where they will be going on tour next, and what new music they have released as well as offer them the opportunity to say something to the listeners. After each interview, the guests congratulates Hank Snow on 20 years with RCA Vector and also congratulate Snow and Ernest Tubb on their two radio station programs for WTCW in Whitesburg, Kentucky and WHBT in Harriman, Tennessee. The guests also record snapshots announcing the different radio stations. The tape is undated. This tape is forty of an unidentified number of tapes. This tape is forty of an unidentified number of tapes.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Hank Snow; Justin Tubb; June Carter; Del Wood; Porter Wagoner; Chester Atkins; Little Jimmy Dickens; Ernest Tubb</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Hank Snow introduces Justin Tubb, son of Ernest Tubb -- (00:22) Tubb thanks and congratulates Snow -- (00:43) Snow asks how long Tubb has been with the Grand Ole Opry -- (01:07) Tubb discuses where he's been traveling and where he will be going next -- (02:03) The two talk about Tubb's new music -- (02:51) Tubb thanks everyone -- (03:38) Tubb congratulates Snow for 20 years at RCA Victor -- (04:03) Tubb congratulates Snow and Ernest Tubb for station WTCW, Whitesburg, Kentucky -- (-4:21) Tubb congratulates Snow and E. Tubb for station WHBT, Harriman, Tennessee -- (04:44) Tubb announces WTCW -- (04:54) Tubb announces WHBT -- (05:10) Snow introduces Little June Carter -- (05:33) Carter discusses what she has been doing with movies -- (07:05) Snow discusses the stations -- (07:22) Snow asks Carter if she's been recording -- (08:00) Snow asks Carter about her plans for the future -- (08:57) The two talk about Carter's daughter -- (10:32) Carter thanks everyone -- (11:00) Carter congratulates Snow for 20 years at RCA  -- (11:20) Carter congratulates Snow and Ernest Tubb for station WTCW -- (11:40) Carter congratulates Snow and Tubb for station WHBT -- (12:04) Carter announces station WTCW -- (12:17) Carter announces station WHBT -- (12:32) Snow introduces Del Wood -- (13:03) Snow and Wood discuss where she's been traveling and where she's going -- (14:04) Wood congratulates Snow on 20 years with RCA -- (14:23) Wood discusses her new music -- (17:15) Wood thanks Snow and everyone -- (17:54) Wood congratulates Snow on 20 years with RCA -- (18:18) Wood congratulates Snow and Tubb for station WTCW -- (18:36) Wood congratulates Snow and Tubb for station WHBT -- (19:29) Wood announces station WTCW -- (19:40) Wood announces station WHBT -- (19:54) Snow outtake -- (20:05) Snow introduces Porter Wagoner -- (20:35) Snow asks where Wagoner has been -- (20:56) Wagoner discusses his future plans -- (21:15) Wagoner discusses his new music -- (21:55) Wagoner thanks Snow and everyone -- (24:09) Wagoner congratulates Snow for 20 years with RCA -- (24:32) Wagoner congratulates Snow and Tubb for station WTCW -- (24:48) Wagoner congratulates Snow and Tubb for station WHBT -- (25:07) Wagoner outtake -- (25:21) Wagoner announces WTCW -- (25:30) Wagoner announces WHBT -- (25:43) Snow introduces Chester Atkins -- (26:18) Snow asks where Atkins has been -- (26:58) Atkins and Snow talk about fellow musicians -- (28:33) Atkins thanks everyone -- (29:08) Atkins congratulates Snow for 20 years with RCA -- (29:20) Atkins congratulates Snow and Tubb for station WTCW -- (29:30) Atkins congratulates Snow and Tubb for station WHBT -- (29:44) Atkins outtake -- (29:52) Atkins announces station WTCW -- (30:02) Atkins announces station WHBT -- (30:13) Little Jimmy Dickens congratulates Snow on 20 years with RCA -- (30:26) Dickens congratulates Snow and Tubb for station WTCW -- (30:49) Dickens congratulates Snow and Tubb for station WHBT -- (31:34) Dickens announces WTCW -- (31:45) Dickens announces WHBT </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-7-02570_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-7-02570</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-09-10</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Snow, Hank; Tubb, Justin; Carter, June; Wood, Del; Wagoner, Porter; Atkins, Chet; Dickens, Little Jimmy, 1920-2015; Tubb, Ernest, 1914-1984;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9559</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>