<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Hallmarks of Country Music - Charley Pride - Part 2</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of an interview of Charley Pride (musician). The interview is hosted by Rick Phillips (army sergeant/ radio host) for the Hallmarks of Country Music segment. The tape was recorded on an unidentified date. Tape is labeled part two of two.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Charley Pride; Rick Phillips</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Mississippi Cotton Picking Delta Town [featuring Charley Pride and Rick Phillips voiceover] (Charley Pride) -- (00:37) Amazing Love [featuring Rick Phillips voiceover] (Charley Pride) -- (00:00) Hallmarks of Country Music introduction tune [featuring Rick Phillips voiceover] ([Unidentified]) -- (01:46) Pure Love [featuring Ronnie Milsap blind peoples radio spot] (Ronnie Milsap) -- (02:39) Rick Phillips and Charley Pride discuss Pride's time performing in Germany for the troops -- (03:57) Phillips inquires about people's initial reaction to Pride's appearance -- (05:35) For the Good Times (Charley Pride) -- (09:00) Unidentified tune [featuring Dean Jones commercial spot] ([Unidentified]) -- (10:00) I'd Rather Love You (Charley Pride) -- (12:44) Phillips asks Pride to reflect on the predominantly southern-white roots -- (16:30) She's Too Good to be True (Charley Pride) -- (19:16) Police commercial radio spot hosted by an unidentified voice -- (20:14) Oklahoma Morning (Charley Pride) -- (23:21) Phillips inquires as to how Pride discovered "Amazing Love;" additionally, Pride comments on his inability to meet with his fans -- (26:58) A Shoulder to Cry On (Charley Pride) -- (29:58) A Volunteer commercial radio spot featuring an unidentified voice -- (30:33) Crystal Chandeliers (Charley Pride) -- (33:20) Military commercial radio spot featuring an unidentified host -- (34:31) Don't Fight the Feelings of Love (Charley Pride) -- (36:29) Phillips inquires about the differences Pride experiences from large to small shows -- (38:52) It's Gonna Take a Little Bit Longer (Charley Pride) -- (41:25) U. S. Customs commercial radio spot featuring an unidentified host -- (42:00) Then Who Am I (Charley Pride) -- (44:07) International Guild for Infant Survival commercial radio spot featuring an unidentified host -- (44:45) Standing in My Way (Charley Pride) -- (47:31) Phillips inquires as to what goals Pride has at this point in his life -- (49:03) Oklahoma Morning (Charley Pride) -- (51:47) Phillips introduces "We Could" -- (51:54) We Could (Charley Pride) -- (54:18) Hallmarks outro tune [featuring Phillips voiceover] ([Unidentified])</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Insert is of program information. The insert features time stamps.</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1544_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1544</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-06-06</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Pride, Charley; Pride, Charley, 1938-; Phillips, Rick;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8977</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>