<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>This Little Light of Mine Programs: C. J. Johnson and the Down-Home Tradition - Shirley Caesar: The Singing Evangelist</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of two segments of This Little Light of Mine. This Little Light of Mine is a show that provides introspection to the main influencers of African-American gospel.  The segments are hosted by Bobby Jones (host). The first segment reflects on the life of Claude Joseph Johnson (singer/songwriter), and is called, "C. J. Johnson and the Down-Home Tradition." The second segment reflects on the life of Shirley Caesar (singer/songwriter), and is called, "Shirley Caesar: the Singing Evangelist." The recordings are from unidentified dates.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Bobby Jones; C. J. Johnson; Shirley Caesar</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) This Little Light of Mine [featuring Bobby Jones voiceover] ([Unidentified]) -- (00:33) Bobby Jones introduces the audience to Claude Joseph Johnson -- (01:45) Jones reflects on how Johnson gained respect through the new pride in classical sermon styles -- (02:15) You Better Run (C. J. Johnson) -- (02:48) Jones defines "shape-note" songs -- (03:08) Johnson reflects on the styling of "shape-note" songs -- (04:38) Jones introduces Johnson to reflect on how his first live performance was at five years old -- (05:47) Jones introduces Johnson's segment where he reflects on performing his first sermon at eight years of age -- (06:53) Johnson reveals his mother prayed for Johnson to become a preacher -- (07:52) A segment of Johnson's sermon is played -- (08:30) I Will Trust in the Lord (C. J. Johnson) -- (10:08) Johnson reflects on the power of music to a sermon -- (11:04) Johnson recalls listening to a time he heard Dave Fuller preach -- (12:18) Johnson discusses how he was converted -- (14:04) (Unidentified gospel tune) (C. J. Johnson) -- (16:35) Jones discusses Johnson's musical choices; additionally, Johnson reflects on how his calling is to Jesus -- (17:26) (Unidentified gospel tune) (C. J. Johnson) -- (18:16) Johnson discusses how gospel songs were from slavery roots -- (20:06) So Good to See (C. J. Johnson) -- (21:24) Johnson recalls performing country revival -- (22:47) (Unidentified gospel tune) (C. J. Johnson) -- (23:42) Jones introduces Johnson's recollection of a Brooklyn drug-dealer -- (25:18) You Better Run (C. J. Johnson) -- (26:11) Jones talks about the interactions between congregation and pastor -- (27:12) This Little Light of Mine [featuring Bobby Jones outro voiceover] ([Unidentified]) -- (28:12) This Little Light of Mine [featuring Bobby Jones voiceover] ([Unidentified]) -- (28:48) This Joy I Have (Shirley Caesar) -- (29:11) Jones describes the power of Shirley Caesar's vocal techniques -- (29:52) Caesar reflects on the need of music for gospel -- (30:25) (Unidentified gospel tune) (Shirley Caesar) -- (31:12) Jones introduces Caesar's accomplishments and family -- (31:52) No Charge (Shirley Caesar) -- (35:04) Caesar reflects on when she incorporated God into her life -- (36:54) Get Up My Brother (Shirley Caesar) -- (37:36) Caesar discusses the duties of singer and evangelist -- (38:34) Caesar discusses her presentation style -- (30:01) I'll Fly Away (Shirley Caesar) -- (41:43) Caesar reflects on "No Charge" -- (42:09) Be Careful of the Stones That You Throw (Shirley Caesar) -- (45:10) Caesar praises songs that have a positive dialog -- (46:17) Don't Drive Your Momma Away (Shirley Caesar) -- (47:56) Jones introduces how Caesar turned down an offer to perform "rock" music -- (51:38) Caesar reflects on her early inspirations -- (52:43) Caesar discusses why she prefers to perform live to studio recordings -- (53:19) Sailing on the Sea of Your Love (Shirley Caesar) -- (54:48) Jones introduces Caesar's crusades -- (56:36) A Man Called King Heroin (Shirley Caesar) -- (57:18) Jones introduces Caesar to discuss her motivations -- (58:37) Nobody but Jesus [featuring Bobby Jones outro voiceover] (Shirley Caesar)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1490_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1490</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-05-23</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Jones, Bobby; Johnson, C. J. (Claude Joseph), 1913-1990; Caesar, Shirley;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8932</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>