<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>This Little Light of Mine Programs: C. L. Franklin: Gospel Preacher - Sweet Honey in the Rock: New Songs From An Old Tradition</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of two segments of This Little Light of Mine. This Little Light of Mine is a show that provides introspection to the main influencers of African-American gospel.  The first segment is hosted by Bobby Jones (host). The first segment reflects on the life of C. L. Franklin (singer/songwriter), and is called "C. L. Franklin: Gospel Preacher." The second segment is hosted by an unidentified host and features testimony by Sweet Honey in the Rock member, Bernice Johnson-Reagon. The second segment is called, "Sweet Honey in the Rock: New Songs From An Old Tradition." The recordings are from unidentified dates.
</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Bobby Jones; C. L. Franklin; Sweet Honey in the Rock</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) This Little Light of Mine [featuring Bobby Jones voiceover] ([Unidentified]) -- (00:31) C. L. Franklin performs for his congregation as Bobby Jones describes Reverend Franklin's story -- (03:29) Jones introduces Reverend Franklin and Jeff Titan -- (03:39) Franklin reflects on how his father was unable to read while purchasing groceries -- (05:41) Jones introduces Racheal Franklin's take on Franklin's different nature -- (06:49) Franklin reflects on being converted -- (07:44) Jones reflects on how Franklin molded Aretha Franklin  -- (08:09) I Love the Lord (He Heard My Cry) (C. L. Franklin) -- (09:41) Jones introduces Racheal Franklin's recollection of how C. L. Franklin came to the understanding that he would become a preacher -- (10:57) Jones discusses Franklin's prodigy status and Franklin's family -- (12:31) C. L. Franklin discusses his understanding of preaching -- (14:33) Franklin performs a sermon about Saint Mary -- (15:38) Jones addresses how C. L. Franklin was signed to Battle Records to record his live sermons -- (16:11) C. L. Franklin recalls the financial stress of performing with the Clara Ward singers -- (20:25) Jones reflects on Franklin's celebrity status and Aretha Franklin's first national exposure -- (21:28) Jeff Titan discusses meeting Franklin and the interview he performed -- (22:18) C. L. Franklin performs a sermon -- (23:08) This Little Light of Mine [featuring Bobby Jones outro voiceover] ([Unidentified]) -- (24:32) This Little Light of Mine [featuring unidentified host introduction voiceover] ([Unidentified]) -- (25:10) Sweet Honey in the Rock (Unconfirmed) [featuring unidentified host voiceover] (Sweet Honey in the Rock) -- (25:56) The unidentified voice introduces Sweet Honey in the Rock; additionally, Bernice Johnson-Reagon reflects on how sacred songs keep the group alive -- (27:41) What is a Babylon (Sweet Honey in the Rock) -- (31:29) Johnson-Reagon reflects on the contributions of the various members of Sweet Honey in the Rock -- (33:25) Jesus is My Only Friend (Unconfirmed)(Sweet Honey in the Rock) -- (35:12) Johnson-Reagon reflects on the traditions of the church at which Sweet Honey in the Rock performed -- (35:56) They Are Falling All Around Me (Sweet Honey in the Rock) -- (38:12) Johnson-Reagon reflects on how Aisha Kahlil has progressed over time -- (38:48) Unidentified tune (Sweet Honey in the Rock) -- (39:35) Johnson Reagon praises Kahlil's versatility -- (39:49) Feel Something Drawing Me on (Sweet Honey in the Rock) -- (42:47) Johnson-Reagon praises Yasmeen Williams -- (43:39) In the Upper Room [featuring Johnson-Reagon discussion of Ysaye Barnwell] (Sweet Honey in the Rock) -- (45:46) Father I Stretch My Hands to Thee (Sweet Honey in the Rock) -- (46:44) Johnson-Reagon reflects on the wide range of 'song forms' Sweet Honey in the Rock perform -- (49:50) This Little Light of Mine [featuring unidentified host outro voiceover] ([Unidentified])</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1497_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1497</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-05-28</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Jones, Bobby; Franklin, C. L. (Clarence LaVaughn), 1915-1984; Sweet Honey in the Rock (Musical group);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8956</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>