<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Conway Twitty interview - Joe Suglia WBUK - 1976-08-08</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of an interview with Conway Twitty (performer) conducted by Joe Suglia on August 8, 1976 for radio station WBUK. Aired on August 21, 1976.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1976-08-08</dc:date>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Conway Twitty does an introduction for this interview to be broadcast on WBUK -- Twitty says Joe Suglia is is favorite disc jockey -- Suglia talks about the last time they spoke -- Twitty talks about writing most of his songs but not This Time I've Hurt Her More Than She Loves Me -- Twitty talks about his new album and recording it -- Twitty talks about his voice changing throughout his career -- Twitty talks about his recording It's Only Make Believe and how it was re-recording -- Twitty talks about his recording The Letter and how it came to be -- Twitty talks about the simplicity in most of his recordings -- Twitty talks about releasing a single around the same time each year -- Twitty talks about singing duet with Loretta Lynn -- Twitty talks about his recording The Games That Daddy's Play -- Twitty talks about an upcoming greatest hits album -- Twitty talks about his recording After All The Good Is Gone and how it has a 1950's feel with a modern country melody -- Twitty talks about his daughters Joni Lee's and Jessica James's music careers -- Twitty talks about his recording Hello Darlin' -- Twitty talks about his recording You've Never Been This Far Before -- Joe Suglia concludes the interview</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- quarter track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-5-00025_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-5-00025</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-06-14</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Twitty, Conway;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/7627</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>