<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Roger Cook Interview by John Lomax III Side Two </dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is an interview of Roger Cook by John Lomax III. The interview takes place on 1-14-81.  </dc:description>
<dc:date>1981-01-14</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Roger Cook</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Side Two - (0:04) -- Continued discussion about the film "Honky Tonk Freeway." John Lomax asks Roger Cook about why George Martin came to Nashville to produce the music for the film. (2:55) -- Roger Cook describes the personnel for the soundtrack of "Honky Tonk Freeway." (4:12) -- Roger Cook describes his hesitations about singing other artists' music. (6:09) -- Roger Cook mentions that he'd love to cut the song "I'll Cross Over Jordan Someday." Roger Cook also mentions that he'd love to record a John Prine song, and a tune entitled "Only Love." (7:36) -- John Lomax asks Roger Cook about the song "I Believe In You." (9:05) -- John Lomax asks Roger Cook about his song "Years From Now." (10:33) -- Roger Cook explains Don Williams' mentality behind choosing songs to record. </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>audio cassette, compact;</dc:format>
<dc:format>1.75 ips;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CAS4692_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>CAS4692</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-09-05</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Cook, Roger (Vocalist);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9494</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>