<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Grand Ole Opry  - 1958-07-26 - WSM</dc:title>
<dc:description>Excerpt from Grand Ole Opry Show from July 26, 1958. Featuring Grant Turner (announcer), Cowboy Copas (host, performer), Rod Brasfield (performer), Minnie Pearl (performer), Tommy Jackson (performer), Justin Tubb (performer), Chet Atkins (performer), and Stringbean (performer) on radio station WSM (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:description>
<dc:date>1958-07-26</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Cowboy Copas; Rod Brasfield; Minnie Pearl; Chet Atkins; Stringbean; Tommy Jackson; Justin Tubb</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Test tones -- Opening statement (Grant Turner) -- Down In Nashville Tennessee (Cowboy Copas) -- Cowboy Copas and Grant Turner introduce the line up -- Cowboy Copas introduces Rod Brasfield -- Comedy routine (Rod Brasfield and Cowboy Copas) -- Cowboy Copas introduces Justin Tubb -- Justin Tubb talks about his new album -- Into Each Life Some Rain Must Fall (Justin Tubb) -- Liberty (Tommy Jackson fiddle) -- Cowboy Copas and Grant Turner talks -- Don't Shake Hands With The Devil (Cowboy Copas) -- Grant Turner and Cowboy Copas talk and introduce Chet Atkins -- Tiger Rag (Chet Atkins) -- Cowboy Copas introduces Minnie Pearl -- Minnie Pearl talks -- Comedy routine (Minnie Pearl) -- I'd Trade All Of My Tomorrows (Justin Tubb) -- Cowboy Copas talks about introduces Stringbean -- Goodbye Liza Jane (Stringbean) -- Cowboy Copas talks about touring -- Won't You Ride In My Little Red Wagon (Cowboy Copas) -- Closing theme -- Closing statement (Cowboy Copas)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-0051_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-0051</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2017-08-28</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); Grand ole opry (Radio program); Turner, Grant; Copas, Cowboy; Brasfield, Rod, 1910-1958; Minnie Pearl; Cannon, Sarah Ophelia, 1912-1996; Atkins, Chet, 1924-2001; Stringbean, 1915-1973; Jackson, Tommy; Tubb, Justin; </dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/5617</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>