<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Overdubbed Hank Williams Mother's Best #1</dc:title>
<dc:description>Unreleased edited excerpts of overdubbed recordings of performances from Hank Williams Mother's Best Flour Shows.  Original recordings made in 1951.</dc:description>
<dc:date>20yy-mm-dd</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Hank Williams </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Cherokee Boogie -- If I Didn't Love You -- Next Sunday Darling Is My Birthday -- Blue Eyes Crying In The Rain -- Where The Old Red River Flows -- Alabama Waltz -- Just When I Needed You -- I'll Sail My Ship Alone -- Deck Of Cards -- There's Nothing As Sweet As My Baby -- Mothers Best Flour Commercial -- Lonely Tomb -- Steal Away (The Funeral) --  Softly And Tenderly -- Lord Build Me A Cabin In The Corner Of Gloryland -- I Heard My Savior Calling Me -- Where He Leads Me (I Can Hear My Savior Calling) -- On Top Of Old Smokey -- I Can't Tell My Heart That -- Tennessee Border -- Gathering Flowers For The Masters Bouquet -- All I Do Is Hang My Head And Cry -- Low And Lonely -- Seaman's Blues -- Pins And Needles (In My Heart) -- Thirty Pieces Of Silver -- The Blind Child -- Farther Along -- When God Dips His Love In My Heart -- Previously Recorded Content -- The Prodigal Son -- Take My Hand Precious Lord -- I'll Fly Away -- A Beautiful Home -- I Dreamed That The Great Judgement Morning -- From Jerusalem To Jericho -- I've Got My One Way Ticket To The Sky -- Searching For A Soldiers Grave.</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>RDAT digital tape</dc:format>
<dc:format>original recorded at 48 kHz</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RDAT-0004</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2016-11-17</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject> Williams, Hank, 1923-1953;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/4658</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>