<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Country Music Month promos - 1972-08-10</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of various country music month promos featuring Tompall Glaser (performer), Charley Pride (performer), Mayf Mutter (performer), Susan Raye (performer), Ray Price (performer), Jody Miller (performer), and Hank Williams Jr. (performer), recorded on August 10, 1972.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1972-08-10</dc:date>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00 )Test tone --(00:20) Country Music Month radio spot (Tompall Glaser) -- (00:50) Country Music Month radio spot (Charley Pride) -- (01:16) Country Music Month radio spot (Mayf Nutter) -- (01:35) Country Music Month radio spot (Susan Raye) -- (01:54) Country Music Month radio spot (Ray Price) -- (02:17) Country Music Month radio spot (Jody Miller) -- (02:38) Country Music Month radio spot (Hank Williams Jr.)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-7-01835_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-7-01835</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-11-27</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Country Music Association (U.S.); Glaser, Tompall; Pride, Charley, 1938-; Nutter, Mayf; Raye, Susan; Price, Ray, 1926-2013; Miller, Jody; Williams, Hank, Jr., 1949-;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8248</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>