<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Shelby Lynne Interview (featuring Bob Montgomery) - Biff Collie </dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of an interview with Shelby Lynn (performer) and Bob Montgomery (producer) conducted by Biff Collie. </dc:description>
<dc:date>1989-11-27</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Shelby Lynne; Bob Montgomery;  Biff Collie</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Biff Collie, Bob Montgomery and Shelby Lynne discuss Lynne's vast musical knowledge and the changing audio formats -- (00:47) Collie reveals he was a member of a band named the Three B's; the members were Collie, William Stubblefield, and Hugh Lee Bosman -- (01:10) Lynne discusses her desire to continue the Mills Brothers legacy and Collie reveals from recalling a line spoken to him by Bob Tubert -- (02:28) Montgomery reflects on the structure of the music industry forcing artists to create inorganic music -- (04:53) Montgomery discusses the first time Lynne was offered a deal, under a development contract, from Billy Sherrill -- (05:31) Lynne reveals how she had trusted Montgomery even though they had only recently met and Montgomery reveals what he knows of development contracts -- (07:40) Lynne discusses the non-issue associated with money -- (08:08) Lynne radio spot for Biff Collie and the Music City Album Review -- (08:16) Lynne radio spot with the Biffer -- (08:21) Lynne, disc jockey, radio spot for Biff Collie and the Music City Album Review -- (08:31) Lynne radio spot for her audiobiography and the Music City Album Review -- (08:44) Lynne, thirty minute, radio spot for the Music City Album Review -- (08:52) Lynne, hour, radio spot for the Music City Album Review -- (09:01) Lynne thanking radio spot -- (09:07) Lynne radio spot for her audiobiography and the Music City Album Review -- (09:17) Lynne listening radio spot -- (09:19) Lynne winning radio spot -- (09:26) Collie directs Lynne to say "Oh really?" -- (09:29)  Collie directs Lynne to say "Oh yeah?" -- (09:34)  Collie directs Lynne to say "Wonderful" -- (09:36) Lynne says she hates the word wonderful -- (09:43)  Collie directs Lynne to say "Now you're going" -- (09:46)  Collie directs Lynne to say "You bet" -- (09:48)  Collie directs Lynne to say "Would you repeat that please?" -- (09:51)  Collie directs Lynne to say "Yes sir" -- (09:54) Collie directs Lynne to say "Sure" -- (09:57) Collie directs Lynne to say "That's what I like to hear" -- (10:01) Collie directs Lynne to say "That's nice" -- (10:03) Collie asks Lynne to perform her own catch-phrases and Montgomery, Lynne and Collie discuss Collie's editing process -- (11:20) Collie and Lynne discuss Lynne's album title Sunrise -- (11:49) Collie addresses Montgomery's value as a conversation driver -- (12:24) Collie and Lynne discuss how Lynne had got a contract with CBS through an appearance on Nashville Now -- (13:21) 'The Hurtin' Side' and its writers, Mike Reid and Michael Bourke, are discussed as "career boosters" -- (14:20) Montgomery discusses the hits he produced, and Montgomery reflects on understanding Lynne's potential; Montgomery compares Lynne to Red Foley -- (16:05) Collie introduces 'Little Bits and Pieces' and Lynne reflects on her luck of having song writers such as Billy Sherrill -- (16:52) Collie and Lynne reflect on the duration of the recording process and Lynne tells of Sherrill's temper associated with him having to wait for new songs -- (18:02) Montgomery tells of how 'Thinking About You Again' came off the streets of Nashville and Lynne reflects on a night working at Blue Bird; while at the Blue Bird, Lynne unknowingly met Smith -- (19:01) Montgomery and Lynne express their appreciation for Smith's help at the Blue Bird and assert their recording of Smith had been purely based on merit -- (19:56) Collie and Lynne discuss how Shelby is a man's name and Lynne and Montgomery reflect on how she was being pressured to change her name -- (20:46) 'This Time I Almost Made it' is discussed as an homage to Barbara Mandrell from Lynne that had been produced with some internal conflict -- (22:40) Lynne tells of her life growing up in Alabama and her father's military career -- (23:10) Lynne addresses living in Alabama and Texas -- (23:30) Lynne and Collie address Lynne's sister and Lynne's physical characteristics -- (23:51) Lynne tells of how she had always been a performer and Lynne recalls her first public performance at Shakey's Pizza Parlor in Mobile, Alabama -- (24:28) 'What About This Girl' is reflected on as an up-tempo song created to address the popularity of the album -- (25:13) 'Til You Were Gone' writers Reid and Bourke are reflected on as positives -- (25:55) Collie brings up how Reid is a former football player and how Bourke was head of promotions for Mercury Records -- (26:28) 'I Love You So Much It Hurts' is reflected on by Collie reminiscing on the first time he played it in 1947; additionally, Lynne and Montgomery address the slump the album was in when they decided to record 'I Love You So Much It Hurts' -- (28:23) Montgomery tells of when Lynne performed 'I Love You So Much It Hurts' on Nashville now and the complement she received from Bill Monroe -- (29:33) 'That's Where It Hurts' is reflected on by Lynne and Montgomery as a song that Montgomery hates because he believes its another version of 'I've Been Everywhere' -- (30:55) Collie and Lynne discuss Lynne's traveling band, Lynne opening for Randy Travis, and Lynne's bus -- (31:47) Montgomery and Lynne address working with Travis as a great opportunity, and Montgomery and Lynne reflect on their initial fears of performing before Travis -- (33:48) Collie addresses the number of new tracks on the Sunrise album -- (34:29) Lynne reflects on her classical inspirations behind 'I'm Confessin'' -- (35:35) 'Your Love Stays with Me' is discussed by Lynne, Collie, and Montgomery as a gospel song that Lynne had difficulties recording -- (36:35) Collie, Lynne, and Montgomery address how Lynne's album Sunrise was named as such without there being a track names 'Sunrise' on the album -- (37:55) Collie has Lynne reflect on who Lynne believes she is as a writer -- (38:53) Lynne says her closing thought</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1177_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1177</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-01-22</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Lynne, Shelby; Montgomery, Bob, 1919-1998; Collie, Biff;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8405</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>