<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>James House and Janie Fricke Interview - Biff Collie</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of an interview with Janie Fricke (performer), conducted by Biff Collie.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1989-10-12</dc:date>
<dc:creator>James House; Biff Collie; Janie Fricke</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) James House 'Don't Quit Me Now' radio spot -- (00:14) 'Its Cruel' by House is discussed -- (00:48) House recalls how he began recording in his room and being self taught -- (01:25)' Hard Times for a Honest Man,' House's new single is discussed -- (02:04) The history of House growing up is told and being underage playing in clubs -- (02:55) 'Under the Harvest Moon' is compared to poem inspiration -- (03:48) House retells how he broke his arm and switched to left handed guitars -- (04:12) 'Never Until now' is briefly discussed -- (4:43) House retells how he came to being signed under MCA Records -- (05:47) 'Oh What A Thrill' style selection is discussed -- (06:19) Biff Collie asks what advice House has had in Nashville and House refers to Don Schlitz -- (06:58) House refers to 'Lucinda' cord structure and screening material -- House describes giving up on a song previous to starting 'That'll Be the Last Thang' -- (08:30) Hose speaks of the exhaustive schedule -- (08:51) House speaks of radio appreciation dates and going to England -- (09:30) House's families musical connections are addressed -- (10:09) House speaks of cooperation with Walt Aldridge on 'Call It in the Air' -- (10:39) House's 'Born Ready' is discussed -- (11:15) House's exciting experience of signing with a label -- (11:48) House discusses favorite singers -- (12:10) House addresses his handling of recognition and profitability of music -- (13:34) Closing Remarks between Collie and House -- (13:47) 'Love is One of Those Words' is discussed between Collie and Janie Fricke -- (14:13) Fricke touches on 'Give Em My Number' and the multiple songs brought into pre-production -- (15:41) Fricke discusses the pageantry of being a show person -- (16:12) Fricke discusses how her husband wrote 'The Last Thing That I Didn't Do' while in the car -- (16:55) Collie discusses with Fricke where she lived -- (17:15) 'Walking on the Moon' is briefly discussed -- (17:45) Fricke discusses the origin of her beginning work in Nashville -- (18:40) 'Feeling is Believing' by House is described as "against her style" -- (19:00) 'I Can't Help the Way I Don't Feel' is described as sad and repetitive -- (19:19) Fricke talks about hand-painted clothing line -- (20:42) 'No Ordinary Memory' and what songs Fricke brought to her producer -- 'One of Those Things' is described as a strong delivery -- (21:58) Fricke's dreams as a child and teaching is discussed -- (23:28) How  'My Old Friend the Blues' by Fricke was found and the album release process -- (24:44) Fricke discusses growing up on a farm and learning to love singing through church services -- (25:52) Collie asks about Fricke's experience with fear -- (27:40) Fricke's siblings are discussed -- (28:03) Fricke's musical knowledge is discussed -- (28:32) Fricke discusses dropping out of school for music and her learning process -- (32:04) Fricke's musical inspiration and sheet music is discussed -- (33:02) Fricke describes her musical history with her sister -- (33:30) Where Fricke's love of music is talked about through a story of her youth and her parents -- (35:58) Fricke discusses the uncertainty of children -- (37:32) Fricke says that she never thought she would become a recording artist -- (39:16) Fricke recalls seeing going on the road as a foreign concept -- (40:00) Fricke discusses meeting and dating and being proposed to by Randy Jackson -- (42:10) Fricke speaks about how she toured in Europe with Randy Jackson -- (43:02) Fricke speaks about her first producer and records -- (43:47) 'Always Have, Always Will" is briefly discussed -- (44:06) 'Love Me' is briefly discussed -- (44:22) Fricke brings up her time in Memphis -- (45:20) Fricke and Charley Pride's relationship is discussed -- (45:47) 'He's a Heartache' is described as "high energy" -- (46:10) 'Let's Stop Talkin' Bout It' is briefly addressed -- 'Please Help Me I'm Fallin'' is described as Fricke's favorite -- (46:38) 'She's Single Again' called a "story telling song" -- (46:58) 'Tell Me A Lie' by Fricke is describe -- (47:25) Fricke describes not having her own band -- (47:40) Fricke describes her band and how the came to be -- (48:11) Fricke's hobbies are discusses as well as pets -- (49:05) Collie inquires about Fricke's value of home -- (50:01) Fricke addresses what relationship she has with her parents -- (51:07) Fricke addresses her thoughts on the future</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1113_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1113</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-12-19</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>House, James; Collie, Biff; Fricke, Janie;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8303</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>