<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Hank Williams: Complete Works Volume 3</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of a number of performances of Hank Williams Sr. (singer/songwriter). Tape is part of a collection labeled Hank Williams: Complete Works. Tape is labeled as part three of eight. The tapes were donated from the M.G.M. Studios collection.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Hank Williams</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Baby We're Really in Love (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (02:35) Lost Highway (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (05:19) I Just Don't Like This Kind of Living (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (08:12) May You Never be Alone (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (11:02) Crazy Heart (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (13:31) I Can't Help it (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (15:59) I'm a Long Gone Daddy (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (18:50) They'll Never Take Her Love From Me (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (21:38) Why Should We Try Anymore (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (24:17) Rootie Tootie (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (27:07) A House Without Love (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (30:03) The Blues Come Around (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (32:53) Dear Brother (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (35:42) Lost on the River (Hank Williams Sr. and Audrey Williams) -- (38:20) Be Careful of Stones That You Throw (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (41:24) Why Don't You Make Up Your Mind (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (44:17) Pictures From Life's Other Side (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (47:12) I Dreamed About Mama (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (50:21) I've Been Down That Road Before (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (53:21) Just Waitin' (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (56:05) I'm Gonna Sing (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (57:58) Mother is Gone (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (1:00:39) The Angel of Death (Hank Williams Sr.) -- (1:03:15) Ready to go Home (Hank Williams Sr.)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1454_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1454</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-05-09</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Williams, Hank, 1923-1953; Williams, Hank, 1923-1953. I saw the light;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8968</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>