<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Opryland Music Demo Recordings - Y-98</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording is of a group of demo recordings from Opryland Music. Recordings are from an unknown date and recorded by a number of unknown bands. Tape is labeled Y-98. </dc:description>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) One of the Two ([Unidentified]) -- (03:07) At a Girl [False Start] ([Unidentified]) -- (03:29) At a Girl ([Unidentified]) -- (06:49) I've Tried (D. Tharp and J. O'Neal) -- (09:11) If You Fortune Should Be Told (H. Cassity) -- (12:51) I Wish I Had a Picture of Last Night's Dream (J. Smith) -- (15:16) I'm Too Lonely to Smile (H. Smith) -- (18:20) I'll Not be Around (H. Smith) -- (20:58) I Should Have Known (M. Denning) -- (23:53) I'm Hungry, Hungry for Your Love (E. Bienek) -- (26:40) I'll Follow Jesus All the Way (J. Cole) -- (29:38) I'll Be Watching and Waiting (W. Reeves) -- (32:13) I'll Take the Bible (H. Hicks and J. Cole) -- (35:11) Is Anyone Waiting for Me (R. Duckett) -- (38:02) I Know in My Heart (P. Hunter) -- (40:23) Love's Expression (T. Linn and C. Linn) -- (42:42) Love at First Sight (B. Flournoy) -- (44:26) Lonely Days (J. Regan and W. S. Stevenson) -- (45:39) The Legend of the Lovers (J. Regan and W. S. Stevenson) -- (47:08) The Last Outlaw (M. Holcomb and P. Graves) -- (48:55) Lost (G. Brown and W. S. Stevenson) -- (51:57) The Legend of Paul Bunyon (B. Sloan) -- (54:38) Life in the Finnish Woods (W. S. Stevenson) -- (56:44) The Letter You Promised to Write (T. Preston and J. Perkins) -- (59:30) Let 'Er Go (E. Miller and W. S. Stevenson) -- (1:00:39) Love Me Baby (S. Willet) -- (1:03:29) Let's Be Sweethearts Again (P. Grave) -- (1:05:16) A Life of Sin Won't Pay (Sin Can't Win) (Lee Surratt)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1294_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1294</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-03-11</dcterms:created>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8621</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>