<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Bluebird 78's - tape 5</dc:title>
<dc:description>Tape 5 of recordings of Bluebird 78 discs, featuring Joe's Acadians (performers), The Four Aces (performers), Happy Fats and his Rayne-Bo Ramblers (performers), Jean Fuselier (performer), and the Hackberry Ramblers (performers), performing Creole tunes from the 1930's.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Joe's Acadians; The Four Aces;  Happy Fats and his Rayne-Bo Ramblers; Jean Fuselier; Hackberry Ramblers</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Test tones -- La Two Step A Chachin (Joe's Acadians) -- Vous Avez Quitte Avec Que Une Dotre (The Four Aces) -- Lake Charles Waltz (The Four Aces) -- Chan Se Tige (Happy Fats and his Rayne-Bo Ramblers) -- La Robe Barre (Jean Fuselier) -- Chere Te Te (Jean Fuselier) -- Les Pauls Paus Pas (Joe's Acadians) -- [Unidentified] talks to Joe -- La Valse An Oncle Knute (Joe's Acadians) -- La Valse Du Veux Temps (Hackberry Ramblers)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-0268_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-0268</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-01-22</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Joe's Acadians (Musical group); Four Aces (Cajun Group); Happy Fats; Rayne-Bo Ramblers; Hackberry Ramblers;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/6640</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>