<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Pulsebeat Radio Show: Donna Meade - Part 2</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of Kim Spangler (host) dictating the Pulsebeat section of the Voice of the Heartland Radio Show. The episode interviews Donna Meade (musician). The episode was set to air for the week of September 12, 1988. The episode is part 2 of 2.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1988-09-12</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Kim Spangler; Donna Meade</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:01) Kim Spangler introduces the upcoming Donna  Meade Pulsebeat show -- (00:49) Spangler reflects on why Meade won Miss Congeniality; additionally, Meade reflects on her first experience on stage -- (01:56) Spangler has Meade reflect on her musical family roots -- (02:53) Spangler and Meade reflect on Meade's family's pride -- (03:54) Love's Last Stand (Donna Meade) -- (07:12) Spangler greets the various hosting stations -- (07:42) Spangler and Meade reflect on how long it took Meade to become successful in music -- (08:47) Lay Around and Love on You (Donna Meade) -- (11:21) Spangler introduces the commercial break -- (11:40) Spangler and Meade reflect on working for Boots Randolph -- (12:27) Congratulations (Donna Meade) -- (15:16) Meade reflects on how she wishes to be perceived in her vocals -- (16:03) Slow Fire (Donna Meade) -- (19:28) Spangler introduces the commercial break -- (19:43) Spangler asks Meade what song she wished to hear -- (19:56) Drift Away (Dobie Gray) -- (23:36) Unidentified tune [featuring Kim Spangler outro discussion] ([Unidentified])</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-0978_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-0978</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-09-12</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Spangler, Kim; Meade, Donna;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9588</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>