<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Roy Acuff and Wesley Rose Interview by Chet Hagan in 1980</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is an interview of Roy Acuff and Wesley Rose by Chet Hagan. The recording takes place on November 14th, 1980.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1980-11-14</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Roy Acuff; Wesley Rose; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Side One - (0:01) -- Chet Hagan introduction. (0:14) -- Chet Hagan mentions that he would like to ask Roy Acuff about the Dr. Hauer's Medicine Show days.  (0:32) -- Chet Hagan asks about the Dr. Hauer's Medicine Show performances. (1:50) -- Roy Acuff mentions that they would start the show for crowds with fiddle, then go into a song. (3:22) -- Roy Acuff remembers material performed on the medicine show such as "Get Along Home Cindy." (3:48) -- Chet Hagan asks about Jake Tindall, Roy Acuff's comedic co-performer on Dr. Hauer's Medicine Show. Roy Acuff mentions that he took Jake Tindall's material to the Grand Ole Opry. (4:50) -- Chet Hagan asks Roy Acuff about the type of medicine sold by Dr. Hauer. Roy Acuff clarifies that the 'medicine' sold was named Moc-coton. (6:35) -- Roy Acuff discusses Dr. Hauer's "corn remedy." (7:06) -- Roy Acuff discusses the stage setup of Dr. Hauer's Medicine Show. The stage would be tall enough so children could not climb on. (7:40) -- Roy Acuff mentions that Dr. Hauer's Medicine Show would setup in a town for ten days to perform every night. (8:35) -- Roy Acuff mentions the name of the plays performed during the Medicine Show, such as "Over The River, Charlie," "Goin' Upstairs." (8:52) -- Roy Acuff clarifies that the plays would often run for thirty minutes. (10:15) -- Chet Hagan asks Roy Acuff whether Dr. Hauer's Medicine Show was his first professional job. Roy Acuff goes on to describe his interest in sports (baseball, basketball, football). (12:18) -- Roy Acuff describes his high-school play experience. (12:44) -- Roy Acuff describes his high-school sports experience (football, baseball). (13:37) -- Roy Acuff describes getting a sun stroke from playing baseball. (14:58) -- Chet Hagan asks Roy Acuff whether he tried out for professional baseball. (15:48) -- Roy Acuff describes his friends in professional baseball. (16:38) -- Chet Hagan asks Roy Acuff whether the sun stroke was an omen to start working in the show business. (17:16) -- Roy Acuff mentions that he liked to fight (box) when he was younger. (19:24) -- Roy Acuff mentions that he used to get into conflicts with the Knoxville Police. (20:11) -- Roy Acuff mentions that he's been shot before. (20:53) -- Chet Hagan asks Roy Acuff about when he first came to the Grand Ole Opry. (22:17) -- Roy Acuff describes singing "Great Speckled Bird." (23:14) -- Roy Acuff describes David Stone asking him to be a regular performer on the Grand Ole Opry. (24:08) -- Roy Acuff describes the reaction to his performance through radio. (24:45) -- Roy Acuff describes learning from his sister to sing from his chest. (25:19) -- Roy Acuff mentions that he used to sing on Knoxville Radio imitating Bing Crosby before developing his vocal style. (27:17) -- Chet Hagan asks Roy Acuff about whether he brought a band from Knoxville when coming to the Grand Ole Opry. Roy Acuff goes on to describe his personnel at the time. (28:42) -- Chet Hagan asks Roy Acuff about the future of The Grand Ole Opry. (30:08) -- Roy Acuff mentions his fondness for Red Foley and Tennessee Ernie. (31:15) -- Roy Acuff speaks on the effect of Uncle Dave Macon's passing on the Grand Ole Opry (1952). (31:37) -- Chet Hagan asks Roy Acuff what he thinks of himself as. (32:54) -- Chet Hagan asks Roy Acuff about the Japanese soldier story. (34:04) -- Roy Acuff discusses visiting Ernie Pyle's grave in Hawaii. Roy Acuff mentions that Ernie Pyle requested the tune "Great Speckled Bird" to be played at his funeral. (34:39) -- Roy Acuff mentions sending records to American soldiers during WWII onboard ships and in foxholes. (37:57) -- Chet Hagan asks Roy Acuff when he first started performing overseas. (39:24) -- Roy Acuff speaks on his touring habits. (40:16) -- Chet Hagan asks whether Roy Acuff performed with Minnie Pearl (tent show). (40:30) -- Roy Acuff clarifies that the tent show was not The Grand Ole Opry. (41:26) -- Roy Acuff describes a situation in Panama where he was shot at. (42:58) -- Chet Hagan asks Roy Acuff whether he felt frightened in Korea or Vietnam. (44:24) -- Roy Acuff describes going into the trenches at Korea.
</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>audio cassette, compact;</dc:format>
<dc:format>1.75 ips;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CAS4702_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>CAS4702</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-09-09</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Acuff, Roy; Rose, Wesley;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9531</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>