<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Johnson Brothers Radio Show - WAVU - Tape 4</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording is of the Johnson Brothers Radio Show for the WAVU radio station of Albertville, Alabama. Tape is labeled part four of an unidentified number of tapes.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Johnson Brothers String Band</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Snowbird in the Ashbank (Johnson Brothers String Band) -- (00:00) Rass Johnson (unconfirmed) introduces Jesse Johnson (unconfirmed) to perform a commercial spot for Hunter's Food Store and J. B. Roberts and Son -- (02:41) Time (Johnson Brothers String Band) -- (05:13) Jesse performs a commercial spot for J. B. Roberts and Son -- (06:06) Rass introduces "Who at My Door" -- (06:41) Who at My Door (Johnson Brothers String Band) -- (09:15) Rass introduces "Marilla's Lesson" (unconfirmed) -- (09:44) Marilla's Lesson [unconfirmed] (Johnson Brothers String Band) -- (11:22) Rass invites Jesse to perform a commercial spot for J. B. Roberts and Son -- (12:31) Rass introduces "Oh, You Beautiful Doll" -- (13:01) Oh, You Beautiful Doll  (Johnson Brothers String Band) -- (15:09) Rass attempts to introduce "Cripple Creek" -- (15:55) Cripple Creek (Johnson Brothers String Band) -- (16:53) Cripple Creek [featuring Jesse Johnson outro] (Johnson Brothers String Band) -- (17:39) Jesse commercial spot for the National Safety Council -- (17:57) Jesse states the time -- (18:07) An unidentified voice briefly addresses a woman named Caroline -- (18:10) (Unidentified fiddle tune) (Johnson Brothers String Band) -- (19:37) Rass reflects on square-dancing, and Jesse performs a commercial spot for J. B. Roberts and Son -- (21:14) I Feel Like Traveling on (Johnson Brothers String Band) -- (23:06) Burt Johnson (unconfirmed) and Rass joke about Rass's vocals -- (23:29) Little Brown Jug (Johnson Brothers String Band) -- (25:00) Rass introduces "Mockin' Bird Hill" -- (25:59) Mockin' Bird Hill (Johnson Brothers String Band) -- (27:43) Rass jokes about waiting - -(27:53) Jesse performs a commercial spot for J. B. Roberts and Son -- (28:23) Coconut Grove (Johnson Brothers String Band) -- (30:01) Rass introduces "In the Mood" -- (30:19) In the Mood (Johnson Brothers String Band) -- (31:39) Rass says goodbye to the audience -- (31:49) (Unidentified fiddle tune) [featuring Jesse Johnson outro] (Johnson Brothers String Band)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1442_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1442</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-05-03</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Johnson Brothers String Band (Musical group);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8895</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>