<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Opryland Music Demo Recordings - Y-138</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording is of a group of demo recordings from Opryland Music. Recordings are from an unknown date and recorded by a number of unknown bands. Tape is labeled Y-138. </dc:description>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) A Cottage Quaint and Small (Allen King and W. S. Stevenson) -- (01:25) Crazy in Love Again (C. C. Beam, C. L. Jiles, and W. S. Stevenson) -- (02:34) Christine (Eddie Miller) -- (04:57) Christmas (E. Miller) -- (07:17) Counterfeit Love (Cecil Sparks and W. S. Stevenson) -- (09:11) Candle Glow (Wayland Chandler and W. S. Stevenson) -- (11:48) Counting on Courtin' (W. Chandler and W. S. Stevenson) -- (14:20) Don't Cry When I Say I Told You So (C. C. Beam, C. L. Jiles, and W. S. Stevenson) -- (16:36) Davy Lee (Gloria Jay Drexler) -- (19:16) Don't Look Back (Gene Brown) -- (20:41) Do You Wish to be Free (Carl Belew) -- (22:34) Don't Do it to Me Now (Hollis Manley) -- (24:08) Rocking Pied Piper (Max Jaffe, Ben Henderson, and W. S. Stevenson) -- (25:45) Saturday Night on the Manatee (Chet Weldon and W. S. Stevenson) -- (27:18) Someone Stole You From Me (E. Miller and W. S. Stevenson) -- (28:44) Slow Down Blues (C. Belew) -- (30:57) She's Mine, All Mine (C. C. Beam, C. L. Jiles, and W. S. Stevenson) -- (31:48) Someday You'll Call (Ruby Smith and W. S. Stevenson) -- (35:03) Silence and Tears (Kenny Sowder and C. Belew) -- (37:13) Secret Hiding Place (E. Miller and W. S. Stevenson) -- (38:38) Sweet Lyin' Lips (Thomas Howard and W. S. Stevenson) -- (41:07) Swanee River Boogie (Gene Brown and W. S. Stevenson) -- (43:41) Stand Up and Take a Bow (Jay Mathis) -- (45:46) Sitting Up With the Blues (W. Chandler and W. S. Stevenson) -- (47:34) Strangers Waltz (G. Brown and W. S. Stevenson) -- (49:34) Sweet Sweet Lips (W. Chandler and W. S. Stevenson) -- (52:13) Sad Daddy (Bobbie Flournoy and W. S. Stevenson) -- (54:01) Shawnee Moon (Joe Reagan and W. S. Stevenson) -- (55:34) A Secret (Jim McGraw and W. S. Stevenson) -- (57:55) A Stranger to You (E. Miller) -- (1:01:16) Those Dirty Blues (W. Chandler) -- (1:03:48) Trying to Forget (W. Chandler)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1334_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1334</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-03-25</dcterms:created>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8693</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>