<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Interstate 7 Show - Loretta Lynn and Ernest Ray interview - Jack Reno - 1978 - WLW - part 1</dc:title>
<dc:description>Part one of a segment of the Interstate 7 Show with Jack Reno (host), featuring Loretta Lynn (performer) and Ernest Ray Lynn (performer), broadcast in 1978 on radio station WLW (Cincinnati, Ohio).</dc:description>
<dc:date>1978</dc:date>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Opening statement ([Unidentified]) -- Opening theme -- (00:53) Jack Reno introduces Loretta Lynn -- (01:05) Loretta talks about going to a baseball game in Cincinnati and how cold it was -- (01:55) Loretta talks about playing a show in town and other venues in Ohio -- (02:15) Loretta talks about her son Ernest appearing on a television show in town -- (02:40) Loretta talks about visiting the White House the previous week -- (03:00) Loretta talks about appearing on the Muppets television show in England -- (05:30) Loretta talks about the producer of the Muppets -- (06:49) Loretta talks about picking new songs for an album with Conway Twitty which they recently finished recording -- (08:30) Loretta talks about a new solo single releasing soon -- (09:40) Loretta talks about her recording "Spring Fever" -- (10:00) Loretta talks about being the first girl to do her own harmonies on her recordings -- (10:45) Loretta talks about the majority of her family recording music, including her son Ernest Ray -- (11:28) Loretta talks about her younger sister Crystal doing really well as a recording artist -- (11:53) Loretta talks about her upcoming television appearances and touring destinations -- (12:50) Loretta talks about touring with Ernest Tubb -- (13:03) Loretta talks about Ernest Tubb recording with a new label -- (13:25) Loretta talks about how rapidly the music business is changing, especially country -- (14:15) Loretta and Jack talk about Mel Tillis recording pop-country music -- (14:44) Loretta talks about refusing to record pop music, she says "you're looking at country" -- (15:27) Jack talks about promoters saying how much money they make when Conway and Loretta perform for them -- (15:40) Loretta talks about not understanding pop music -- (16:25) Loretta gives her opinion on why country music is so good -- radio commercial -- (18:25) Loretta talks about the last festival she performed at -- (19:00) Loretta talks about the festival being wild -- (19:30) Loretta talks about country shows being well attended across the nation -- (20:30) Loretta talks about her western wear stores -- (20:45) Loretta talks about her husband and his farming, and how he does not like to travel with her -- (21:05) Loretta talks about preferring to ride in her bus rather than fly -- (21:25) Loretta talks about traveling to Hollywood, and hating to fly -- (21:55) Loretta talks about her religious recordings -- (22:30) Loretta talks about how just about every one of her records going number one -- (23:15) Loretta talks about her most requested songs -- (23:48) Loretta talks about her country records doing better than most pop records -- (24:37) Loretta talks about performing for President Nixon and President Carter -- (25:33) Loretta talks about her biggest thrill being recording with Ernest Tubb -- (26:00) Loretta talks about wanting to, but never recording with her family members -- (26:52) Loretta talks about how good Crystals music career has been going -- (27:02) Loretta talks about back when she got her break in her career -- (28:11) Loretta talks about getting on with Decca and MCA -- (29:00) Loretta talks about her first few records -- (29:50) Loretta talks about having knives pulled on her by jealous women -- (30:15) Loretta talks about working clubs early on in her career -- (30:58) Loretta and Jack talk about ticket prices going up over time -- (32:25) Loretta and Jack talks about doing a split-record -- (33:20) Loretta talks about only being as good as your song -- (33:55) Ernest Ray talks about his new record -- (34:11) Loretta and Jack talk about new artists breaking into the industry -- (34:50) Ernest Ray talks about his siblings and traveling with Loretta -- (35:10) Ernest Ray talks about his second record release with MCA -- (35:48) Loretta talks about never changing her name -- (36:30) Ernest Ray talks about traveling with Loretta and hoping his record does well -- (37:00) Loretta talks about Owen Bradley always being her producer -- (37:50) Ernest Ray talks about Loretta's new recording -- (38:15) Loretta talks about some older songs that would be big if they were brought back -- [unidentifiable audio]</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-7-04146_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-7-04146</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-01-16</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WLW (Radio Station : Cincinnati, Ohio); Reno, Jack; Lynn, Loretta, 1932-; Lynn, Ernest</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8396</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>