<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Interview and performance - Mike Judge and various artists - 2017-09-14</dc:title>
<dc:description>Interview with Mike Judge and performances after a premiere showing of animated television series Mike Judge Presents: Tales from the Tour Bus from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on September 14, 2017.  Includes performances of Johnny Paycheck songs by various artists. Presented by the Americana Music Association.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2017-09-14</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Mike Judge; Chuck Mead; Jack Ingram; Jerry Pentecost; Bruce Robison; Brent Cobb; Joshua Hedley; Jim Lauderdale; Elizabeth Cook; Brandy Clark; Jed Hilly; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Program begins in progress with question (possibly from Michelle Aquilato) about how Mike Judge became interested in country music / (00:09) Talks about his background in New Mexico and being influenced by George Jones / (01:32) Talks about his musical background / (01:49) Talks about the animated tv series / (02:35) Final interview comments / (02:52) Introduction of performers Chuck Mead / (03:25)  It's Motel Time Again (Chuck Mead) / (05:40) Colorado Kool-Aid (Jack Ingram) / (10:17) Band introduction by Jerry Pentecost / (11:07) Slide Off Of Your Satin Sheets (Bruce Robison) / (14:38) Someone To Give My Love To (Brent Cobb) / (18:06) Final thanks by Jerry Pentecost / (18:28) The Only Hell My Mama Ever Raised (Joshua Hedley) / (22:15) Take This Job And Shove It (Joshua Hedley, Chuck Mead, Jim Lauderdale, Elizabeth Cook, Jack Ingram, Brandy Clark) / (25:45) Closing comments by Jed Hilly / (27:11) Walk-out music / (52:44) FILE END  </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/24;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0061</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2018-08-15</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Judge, Mike; Mead, Chuck; Ingram, Jack; Pentecost, Jerry; Robinson, Bruce; Cobb, Brent; Hedley, Joshua; Lauderdale, Jim; Cook, Elizabeth; Clark, Brady; Hilly, Jed; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8073</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>