<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Merle Travis interview - Biff Collie - KFOX</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of an interview with Merle Travis (performer), conducted by Biff Collie for KFOX (Long Beach, Calif.), sometime in the 1960's.</dc:description>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Biff Collie mentions how multi-faceted Merle Travis' career is -- Merle Travis talks about being from Mulenburg County, Kentucky -- Merle Travis talks about where his creative ideas for songwriting comes from -- Travis talks about being raised in a coal mining county -- Travis talks about recording No Vacancy on Capitol Records -- Travis talks about learning his guitar style from Mose Rager -- Travis talks about some of the more popular songs he has written, including Smoke Smoke Smoke That Cigarette for Tex Williams -- Travis talks about how popular his style of guitar playing has become among his peers -- Biff Collie wishes Merle Travis good luck and concludes the interview</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-7-03960_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-7-03960</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-06-22</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Travis, Merle, 1917-1983; Collie, Biff;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/7698</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>