<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Artist in Residence - Jason Isbell - 2017-12-19</dc:title>
<dc:description>Third of three Artist in Residence performances by Jason Isbell from the CMA Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on December 19, 2017.  Accompanied by Amanda Shires.  Special guests include Mac McAnally, Jerry Douglas, Buddy Miller, Emmylou Harris, Gillian Welch and David Rawlings.  Audio restricted.  Contact for access.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2017-12-19</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Jason Isbell; Amanda Shires; Mac McAnally; Jerry Douglas; Buddy Miller; Emmylou Harris; Gillian Welch; David Rawlings;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Walk-in music / (10:50) Pre-recorded announcement / (11:46) Walk-in music continues / (16:35) Opening comments and introduction of Jason Isbell by Peter Cooper / (22:02) Opening comments from Jason / (22:34) Introduction of Amanda Shires / (22:50) Performs Live Oak (Jason with Amanda) / (27:07) Talks about the previous song and Jason's acknowledgements / (28:08) Performs 24 Frames (Jason and Amanda) / (31:20) Introduces Mac McAnally / (31:59) Introduces the next song / (32:14) Performs Outfit (Jason and Mac with Amanda) / (37:22) Mac introduces the next song / (38:20) Performs All These Years (Mac with Jason and Amanda) / (42:00) Amanda and Jason talk and banter with the audience / (42:46) Performs White Man's World (Jason and Amanda) / (47:00) Amanda and Jason talk / (47:30) Tells story about his friend singing the song Falling at a high school talent show while his microphone slowly fell / (48:32) Performs Chaos And Clothes (Jason and Amanda) / (53:30) Introduces Jerry Douglas / (54:20) Comments from Jerry / (55:16) Performs Children Of Children (Jason with Jerry and Amanda) / (01:00:57) Jason comments on Jerry's playing / (01:01:49) Performs Something More Than Free (Jason with Jerry and Amanda) / (01:06:19) Jason acknowledges his guitar tech / (01:06:37) Introduction of the next song / (01:08:) Performs Cover Me Up (Jason with Amanda) / (01:15:12) Performs Tour Of Duty (Jason and Amanda) / (01:18:37) Introduces Buddy Miller / (01:19:15) Buddy talks to Jason / (01:19:35) Performs Traveling Alone (Jason with Buddy and Amanda) / (01:24:46) Buddy talks to Jason and introduces the next song / (01:25:13) Performs Wide River To Cross (Buddy with Jason and Amanda) / (01:28:33) Jason introduces Emmylou Harris / (01:29:33) Emmylou with comments and introduction of the next song / (01:30:40) Performs Love Hurts (Emmylou with Buddy) / (01:34:37) Emmylou and Jason compliment each other / (01:35:00) Performs Tupelo (Jason and Emmylou with Amanda) / (01:39:30) Jason introduces Gillian Welch and David Rawlings / (01:40:25) Gillian comments and discussion about the song key / (01:41:31) Performs Something To Love (Jason, Gillian, Dave and Amanda) / (01:46:03) Introduction of the next song with some discussion as to which song / (01:47:00) Performs Midnight Train (Dave and Gillian with Jason and Amanda) / (01:51:38) Gillian introduces the next song / (01:52:11) Performs Look At Miss Ohio (Gillian and David with Amanda and Jason) / (01:57:08) closing comments from Jason / (01:57:26) Audience applause / (01:59:47) Acknowledgements from Jason / (02:00:32) Performs If We Were Vampires (Jason and Amanda) / (02:03:20) Jason brings out all the guests for the last song and introduces the last song / (02:04:18) Performs Unknown Legend (Jason with everyone) / (02:08:20) Final comments / (02:08:41) Audience applause / (02:09:35) Recording signal ends / (02:10:20) FILE END                   </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0169</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2019-06-20</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Isbell, Jason; Shires, Amanda; McAnally, Mac; Douglas, Jerry; Miller, Buddy; Harris, Emmylou; Welch, Gillian; Rawlings, David; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9289</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>