<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Billy Sherrill Interviewed by Bob Allen in 1981 Tape Two, Side One  </dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of Bob Allen interviewing Billy Sherrill. The recording takes place on 11-13-81.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1981-11-13</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Billy Sherrill</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Side One, Tape 2 of 2 - (0:13) -- Bob Allen asks Billy Sherrill about the Grand Ole Opry. (1:28) -- Bob Allen asks Billy Sherrill what he personally listens to in the car and at home. "I've got one cassette in my car, and it's Johann Strauss' greatest hits." - Billy Sherrill. (2:35) -- "I don't think I've ever seen any artist I've ever cut in concert." - Billy Sherrill. (3:42) -- Bob Allen asks Billy Sherrill of his opinion about using strings in country music. (4:30) -- Billy Sherrill discusses using strings on a George Jones record. (5:49) -- Billy Sherrill discusses using strings on Elvis Costello's albums. (6:50) "I like pretty music. I've stolen a lot from Johann Strauss." - Billy Sherrill. (7:08) -- Bob Allen asks Billy Sherrill if bad reviews bother him. (7:41) -- Billy Sherrill shares his view on reviewer's writing strategies. (10:14) -- Billy Sherrill shares his personal views on Christianity. (11:03) -- Bob Allen asks Billy Sherrill about his historical interests. (14:28) -- Billy Sherrill discusses Buddy Killen recording Roger Miller. (15:14) -- Billy Sherrill discusses going to Las Vegas. (17:21) -- Billy Sherrill tells the story of winning 14 grand at Les Vegas. (22:08) -- Billy Sherrill discusses a story about the odds of an unknown person making it in the music business. Billy goes on to describe that you are more likely to be hit by lightning than make it in the music industry. (24:56) -- Billy Sherrill discusses the difference between Nashville and other cities. (26:09) -- Billy Sherrill discusses the temptation of marketing and promotion plans. (28:44) -- Bob Allen asks Billy Sherrill why he thinks he's successful. (29:22) -- "I'm in total awe of Owen Bradley and Chet Atkins." - Billy Sherrill. (31:29) -- Billy Sherrill goes on to describe his personal awards (BMI). (32:14) -- Billy Sherrill mentions that he doesn't pay attention to other contemporary producers. (33:08) -- Billy Sherrill mentions Phil Spector. (36:04) -- Billy Sherrill describes making instrumental recordings to survive. Billy would play each instrument on the tracks (against overdub union laws). (38:46) -- Billy Sherrill discusses his love for playing saxophone. (41:11) -- Bob Allen asks Billy Sherrill what his professional future goals are. Billy Sherrill mentions that he'd love to direct/produce a movie. (43:12) -- Bob Allen asks Billy Sherrill about working on the film soundtrack "Take This Job And Shove It."</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>audio cassette, compact;</dc:format>
<dc:format>1.75 ips;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CAS4658_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>CAS4658</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-08-26</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Sherrill, Billy;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9413</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>