<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Harlan Howard Interviewed by Bob Allen in 1988 Side Two</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of Bob Allen interviewing Harlan Howard. The recording takes place on 06-17-1988.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1988-06-17</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Harlan Howard</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Side Two - (0:30) -- Harlan Howard discusses making demos for Tree International. (1:14) -- Harlan Howard describes writing a song on a legal pad. "I'm a lyricist. And the melodies, I wish we didn't have to write them." - Harlan Howard. (2:20) -- Harlan Howard discusses how he wrote "Life Turned Her That Way." (4:37) -- Harlan Howard discusses when in the songwriting process he finds the melody for a song. (6:14) -- Bob Allen asks Harlan Howard whether he has a favorite key to sing/write in. Harlan Howard mentions that he loves the key of 'D', also mentions the keys of 'G' and 'A'. Harlan Howard mentions that he often wrote songs for Buck Owens and Ray Price in the key of 'D'. (7:23) -- Bob Allen asks whether Harlan Howard ever pulls out older songwriting ideas to finish them. (8:30) -- Harlan Howard describes his songwriting method. (11:15) -- Harlan Howard mentions why he loves hanging around songwriters and musicians. (13:12) -- Harlan Howard speaks about his personal life goals related to wellness and songwriting. (14:22) -- Harlan Howard describes his desire for happiness. (17:01) -- Bob Allen asks Harlan Howard about his personal albums that he's made. (19:00) -- "But In my mind, I never got over being a songwriter. But in my mind, they were paid-for demos." - Harlan Howard. (21:13) -- Bob Allen asks Harlan Howard whether he thought of himself as an influence to Kris Kristofferson. (24:04) -- Harlan Howard discusses his song "Pick Me Up On Your Way Down." (25:14) -- Bob Allen asks Harlan Howard whether he believes in the idea of suffering for the production of great art in relation to Kris Kristofferson. "I don't think I suffered, and I don't think he suffered." - Harlan Howard. (31:08) -- Harlan Howard discusses the musical consistencies of a shuffle. Harlan mentions that mixing has a lot to do with what genre the public perceives a record to belong to. </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>audio cassette, compact;</dc:format>
<dc:format>1.75 ips;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CAS4668_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>CAS4668</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-08-28</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Howard, Harlan;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9442</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>