<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Fan Fair radio spots - CMA various artists - 1972-01-28</dc:title>
<dc:description>Various Country Music Fan Fair promotional radio spots from 1972, featuring Buck Owens, Roy Clark, Lynn Anderson, Chet Atkins, Glen Sherley, Stonewall Jackson, Hank Snow, Jan Howard, Bill Anderson, Danny Davis, Tommy Overstreet, Porter Wagoner, Waylon Jennings, Dickey Lee, and Darryl Reeves.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1972-01-28</dc:date>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) CMA 1972 Fan Fair commercial radio spot (Buck Owens, Roy Clark) -- (00:39) CMA 1972 Fan Fair commercial radio spot (Lynn Anderson) -- (01:41) CMA 1972 Fan Fair commercial radio spot (Chet Atkins) -- (02:29) CMA 1972 Fan Fair commercial radio spot (Glen Sherley) -- (03:28) CMA 1972 Fan Fair commercial radio spot (Roy Clark) -- (04:32) CMA 1972 Fan Fair commercial radio spot (Stonewall Jackson) -- (05:31) CMA 1972 Fan Fair commercial radio spot (Hank Snow) -- (06:33) CMA 1972 Fan Fair commercial radio spot (Jan Howard, Bill Anderson) -- (07:14) CMA 1972 Fan Fair commercial radio spot (Danny Davis) -- (08:06) CMA 1972 Fan Fair commercial radio spot (Tommy Overstreet) -- (08:54) CMA 1972 Fan Fair commercial radio spot (Porter Wagoner) -- (09:56) CMA 1972 Fan Fair commercial radio spot (Waylon Jennings) -- (10:49) CMA 1972 Fan Fair commercial radio spot (Dickey Lee) -- (11:53) CMA 1972 Fan Fair commercial radio spot (Darryl Reeves) </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-7-02010_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-7-02010</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-12-03</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Country Music Association (U.S.); Fan Fair; Owens, Buck, 1929-2006; Clark, Roy, 1933-; Anderson, Lynn, 1947-2015; Atkins, Chet; Sherley, Glen; Jackson, Stonewall; Snow, Hank; Howard, Jan (Vocalist); Anderson, Bill, 1937-; Davis, Danny; Overstreet, Tommy; Wagoner, Porter; Jennings, Waylon; Lee, Dickey; Reeves, Darryl;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8258</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>