<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Pet Milk Grand Ole Opry -- 1966-01-29</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of a variety of live shows from the Grand Ole Opry. The shows include multiple sponsors including: Pet Milk, Kellog, Schick, Pure Oil, and the Harvey Record Department. The recordings feature artist performances by: Jean Shepard (musician), Lonzo and Oscar (musical duo), Stringbean (musician), Bobby Bare (musician), Jimmy C. Newman (musician), Bill Anderson (musician), Bill Carlise (musician), Del Wood (musician), Roy Acuff (musician), and Grandpa Jones (musician). The Pet Milk show is from January 29, 1966. The remaining recordings are from a group of unidentified dates. The tape is labeled the fifth of thirteen.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1966-01-29</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Jean Shepard; Lonzo and Oscar; Stringbean; Bobby Bare; Jimmy C. Newman; Bill Anderson; Bill Carlisle; Del Wood; Roy Acuff; Grandpa Jones</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:02) Jean Shepard jokes about the origin of ""Many Happy Hangovers to You"" -- (00:12) Many Happy Hangovers to You (Jean Shepard) -- (02:40) An unidentified host performs a Pet Milk commercial spot -- (03:08) Unidentified tune [featuring unidentified host performing a Kellogg's commercial spot] ([Unidentified]) -- (03:52) Lonzo and Oscar joke about the cold weather -- (04:58) Waltz Me Around Again Willie (Lonzo and Oscar) -- (08:12) Kellogg's Song (Crawdad Song) (Lonzo and Oscar) -- (09:21) Mountain Dew (Lonzo and Oscar) -- (10:45) Unidentified tune [featuring unidentified host Kellogg outro] ([Unidentified]) -- (11:16) Schick Jingle ([Unidentified]) -- (11:56) Cumberland Gap (Stringbean) -- (13:39) The Deepening Snow (Bobby Bare) -- (16:36) Jambalaya (Jimmy C. Newman) -- (17:48) Schick Jingle ([Unidentified]) -- (18:02) Unidentified tune [featuring unidentified host performing a Pure Oil commercial spot] ([Unidentified]) -- (18:39) Walk Out Backwards (Bill Anderson) -- (20:56) No Help Wanted (Bill Carlisle) -- (22:56) Alone With You (Del Wood) -- (23:45) In Case You Ever Change Your Mind (Bill Anderson) -- (26:00) Unidentified tune [featuring an unidentified host performing a Pure Oil commercial spot] ([Unidentified]) -- (26:33) Unidentified tune [featuring an unidentified host performing a Harvey Record Department commercial spot] ([Unidentified]) -- (26:57) Fireball Mail (Roy Acuff) -- (29:13) Little Home Down in New Orleans (Grandpa Jones)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1826_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1826</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-08-19</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Shepard, Jean, 1933-2016; Lonzo and Oscar; Stringbean, 1915-1973; Bare, Bobby; Newman, Jimmy C.; Anderson, Bill, 1937-; Carlisle, Bill; Wood, Del; Acuff, Roy; Jones, Grandpa, 1913-1998;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9368</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>