<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Performance and interview - Sam Bush - 2005-07-23</dc:title>
<dc:description>Performance by and interview with Sam Bush from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on July 23, 2005.  In support of the exhibition Banjo Man: The Musical Journey of Earl Scruggs.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2005-07-23</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Sam Bush; Keith Sewell;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Recording begins in progress.  (00:00) Opening comments by Jay Orr / (05:15) Introduction of Sam Bush and Keith Sewell / (06:02) Plays the song Eight More Miles To Louisville with Keith Sewell on guitar/ (10:25) Plays the song Puppies 'n Knapsacks / (15:24) Plays the song Whayasay / (23:46) Sam talks about his early childhood, musical influences and playing history / (29:04) Sam talks about Bill Monroe's influence and demonstrates his style of playing / (33:17) Sam talks about Jethro Burns and his playing / (36:20) Demonstrates contrasting styles of old style and Jethro Burns style of mandolin playing / (38:25) More talk about Jethro Burns / (39:30)  Sam talks about Jesse McReynolds and his style of mandolin cross picking playing and give demonstration / (41:50) Sam talks about learning to play banjo / (44:00) Sam plays John Henry on banjo / (46:50) Sam talks about New Grass Revival / (50:49) Plays the song Broadway / (56:45) Plays the song Sapporo / END</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>RDAT digital tape;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RS2014.0127</dc:identifier>
<dc:subject>Bush, Sam, 1952-; Sewell, Keith; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/5852</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>