<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Live from the Pet Milk Grand Ole Opry - 1965-11-27</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of a variety of live shows from the Grand Ole Opry. The recordings feature artist performances by: Roy Drusky (musician), Roy Acuff (musician), Crook Brothers (musicial group), Herman Crook (musician), Jimmie Riddle (musician), Onie Wheeler (musician), Hank Snow (musician), and the Browns (musicial group). The first show is from November 27, 1965. The remaining recordings are from a group of unidentified dates. The tape is labeled the second of thirteen.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1965-11-27</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Roy Drusky; Roy Acuff; Crook Brothers; Herman Crook; Jimmie Riddle; Onie Wheeler; Hank Snow; Browns</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) White Lightning Express (Roy Drusky) -- (02:00) Freight Train Blues (Roy Acuff) -- (04:00) Sally Goodin (Crook Brothers) -- (05:38) An unidentified host requests Crook to play a tune -- (06:51) What a Friend We Have in Jesus (Herman Crook, Jimmie Riddle, Onie Wheeler) -- (08:50) An unidentified host performs a Newport Menthal Cigarettes radio spot -- (09:00) An unidentified host performs a Coca Cola radio spot -- (09:08) Coca Cola Jingle ([Unidentified]) -- (09:45) Texas Plains (Hank Snow) -- (12:07) One Take Away One (The Browns)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1829_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1829</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-08-22</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Drusky, Roy; Acuff, Roy; Crook Brothers; Crook, Herman; Riddle, Jimmy, 1918-1982; Wheeler, Onie, 1921-1984; Snow, Hank; Browns (Musical group);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9396</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>