<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Pickard Family Performance Dec. 7, 9:00 &amp; Dec. 8, 6:45</dc:title>
<dc:description>Tape 7 of 7. Two recordings of the Pickard Family (performance group) from December 7, of an unknown year, and December 8, of an unknown year, respectively. Sessions are recorded in Mexico.</dc:description>
<dc:date>2019-07-12</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Pickard Family</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) All Aboard for Tennessee (Pickard Family) [Featuring a voice over] -- (00:51) Ruthie laughs and Obed plus Peruna while thanking the public -- (01:28) Will the Angels Play Their Harps For Me (Pickard Family) [Featuring Charlie vocals] -- (03:38) Obed greets the crowd and Charlie introduces the next song while twisting Bud about payment -- (04:30) When It's Roundup Time in Heaven (Pickard Family) -- (07:12) Obed thanks the family and Bub and Ruthie talk about writing for cowboys -- (07:48) Kolorbak commercial break performed by Bub Pickard -- (09:34) Dill Pickle Rag (Pickard Family) -- (10:26) Ruthie introduces Bub and Charlie's next song -- (11:04) Granddad Song (Pickard Family) [Featuring Charlie vocals] -- (12:31) Obed, Bub and Ruthie joke outro -- (12:53) All Aboard for Tennessee (Pickard Family) [Featuring a voice over] -- (13:22) Obed greets the audience and introduces the first track -- (14:10) Oh Dem Golden Slippers (Pickard Family) [Featuring Obed vocal] -- (16:30) Obed introduces the crowd and Ruthie asks to hear the next track -- (17:25) Blind Boy's Lament (Pickard Family) -- (20:04) Obed challenges Ruthie to a contest and Charlie and Ruthie talk about being blind -- (20:45) Kolorbak commercial break performed by Obed Pickard -- (22:17) Piano Duet (Pickard Family) [Featuring Obed and Mom] -- (23:23) Just an Echo in the Valley (Pickard Family) [Featuring Charlie vocals] -- (24:53) Obed thanks Charlie</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 1 full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1159_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1159</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-01-14</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Pickard Family (Musical group);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8375</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>