<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Tandy Rice Interviewed by Bob Allen in 1990 Side One </dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of Bob Allen interviewing Tandy Rice. The recording takes place on 9-19-90.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1990-09-19</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Tandy Rice</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Side One - (0:06) -- Tandy Rice discusses returning home from the armed services. Tandy discusses the origin of the eagle symbol. (1:10) -- Tandy Rice brought the same eagle from his old church to Top Billing. (1:52) -- Bob Allen asks Tandy Rice about his connection to Franklin. (4:50) -- Tandy Rice discusses his relationship with Sam Fleming. (6:45) -- Bob Allen asks Tandy Rice about his salesman work. (10:28) -- Tandy Rice describes the business and assets of Top Billing. (14:30) -- Continuation of office tours. (18:26) -- Continuation of interview. (20:00) -- Tandy Rice discusses the environment of his business. (23:33) -- Tandy Rice describes receiving a call from Steve Mayer on behalf of Fred Sullivan. </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>audio cassette, compact;</dc:format>
<dc:format>1.75 ips;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CAS4663_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>CAS4663</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-08-27</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Rice, Tandy;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9419</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>