<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Discussion - Gender and Country Music - 2005-05-30</dc:title>
<dc:description>Panel discussion surrounding the release of the book of essays titled &#8220;A Boy Named Sue: Gender and Country Music&#8221; from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on May 30, 2005. </dc:description>
<dc:date>2005-05-30</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Kris McCusker; Diane Pecknold; Beverly Keel; Michael Bertrand; Jocelyn Neal; Barbara Ching; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Recording begins in progress.  Includes comments and questions from audience (off mic).  Opening comments by Michael Gray (off mic).  Introduction of panelists.  Introduction of moderator Diane Pecknold.  Subjects include; Conservative values in country music --  Comparisons between rock and roll music and country music -- Elvis Presley's influence and his outlook -- Images of women in music -- Continuum of women singing in the home, in church and on records -- Women as taste makers -- Radio play aimed at women who run households -- Nashville Sound rhetoric -- Masculinity in country music -- Themes in country music appealing to women -- Elvis being representative of an entire generation of people and creating an identity -- Women's projection of escapist fantasy by Conway Twitty --  Comparing Girls Night Out songs with Honky Tonk Angels and Couples Out To Dance songs -- Shania Twain watershed impact and comparisons between her and Kathy Mattea -- </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Perceived country audience lack of acceptance of Gay and Lesbian lifestyle -- Observed response to two women dancing in a bar -- Dixie Chicks -- Gretchen Wilson -- Loretta Lynn -- The songs Redneck Woman and You're Looking At Country -- Shifts in country music and it's reaction to those shifts -- Songwriter Erin Enderlin and her attempts to understand her audience and who she's writing to -- Country music expanding beyond it's middle class roots -- K. D. Lang impact -- Visibility of women in the country music industry -- Lily May Ledford story -- Cyclical nature of pop culture and country music -- closing comments -- Recording continues after discussion is concluded.</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>RDAT digital tape;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/16;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RS.2014.0101</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Tape labeled as Sex, Lies and Country Music by AV staff.  Program title assigned by cataloger taken from comments.</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2017-06-07</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>McClusker, Kris; Pecknold, Diane; Keel, Beverly; Bertrand, Michael; Ching, Barbara; Neal, Jocelyn; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/5237</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>