<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Shelly West &amp; Earl Thomas Conley Interviews - Biff Collie</dc:title>
<dc:description>Tape has multiple recordings. The first recording is of an interview with the Shelby West (performer) conducted by Biff Collie. The second recording is of an interview with Earl Thomas Conley (performer) conducted by Biff Collie. </dc:description>
<dc:date>1989-09-25</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Shelly West; Biff Collie; Earl Thomas Conley</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Shelly West reveals she was born in Cleveland, Ohio -- (00:17) West addresses her parent's musical backgrounds; additionally, West names her three brothers -- (01:00) West reflects on the presence of music in her childhood home -- (01:37) West remembers meeting Glen Campbell -- (02:26) West discusses how her mother had created a rehearsal space in her childhood home -- (02:52) West discusses the first time she sang for the Bobby Lord Show; additionally, West reflects on Dottie West's influence on West's musical career -- (04:27) West recalls when Dottie came to school to talk to her class and its effect on her formative years -- (07:38) Biff Collie and West discuss West's kitchen work -- (08:21) Moe West and Bill West's electrical and musical work is discussed -- (10:01) West reflects on a time where she was working with David Frizzell in California -- (12:39) West reflects on being compared to Dottie West -- (14:32) West discusses the ability to live comfortably in the music i</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1251_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1251</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-02-20</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>West, Shelly; Conley, Earl Thomas; Collie, Biff;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8522</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>