<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Jimmy Bowen Interview by John Lomax III.   </dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is an interview of Jimmy Bowen with John Lomax III. The interview takes place on 2-18-83. </dc:description>
<dc:date>1983-02-18</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Jimmy Bowen</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Side One - (0:04) -- John Lomax III introduction. Interview with Jimmy Bowen at Warner Brothers Records. (0:23) -- John Lomax asks Jimmy Bowen where he was born. (1:20) -- Jimmy Bowen describes his educational background. Jimmy Bowen met Buddy Knox in 1955-56 at West Texas State. (2:18) -- Jimmy Bowen describes his high school/college group, "The Orchids." (3:40) -- Jimmy Bowen describes recording in New Mexico and meeting Norman Petty's drummer (Dave Aldridge). (4:25) -- Jimmy Bowen mentions the first time he came to Nashville (1957) and playing the Grand Ole Opry. (5:59) -- Jimmy Bowen describes being intrigued by Nashville songwriting. (6:33) -- Jimmy Bowen mentions that the first artist he produced was Judy Canova. (6:59) -- Jimmy Bowen describes being hired by Frank Sinatra. (7:24) -- Jimmy Bowen mentions meeting Roger Miller. (8:16) -- Jimmy Bowen describes running MGM in 1974 and Nashville's potential. (10:00) -- Jimmy Bowen speaks about the characteristics of the adult country music listener. (11:45) -- John Lomax asks about the musical differences between recording in Los Angeles vs. Nashville. Jimmy Bowen mentions that the Nashville number system allows for great recording efficiency. (14:05) -- Jimmy Bowen speaks about the limitations when creating music in a strict period of time. (18:50) -- Jimmy Bowen speaks about the future of country music's industry establishment. (21:52) -- Jimmy Bowen speaks about the future of the music industry. "I think we're going to have to get the quality of our product up over the next few years, and that will only come digitally and with new technology." - Jimmy Bowen (1983). (22:40) -- Jimmy Bowen speaks about the importance of owning vinyl records. (25:52) -- John Lomax asks Jimmy Bowen about whether using an excess of technology creates a bad record. (28:02) -- Jimmy Bowen describes the danger of overproducing a record. (29:14) -- John Lomax asks Jimmy Bowen about how he continues his administrative duties while also producing for artists. </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>audio cassette, compact;</dc:format>
<dc:format>1.75 ips;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CAS4687_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>CAS4687</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-09-04</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Bowen, Jimmy;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9483</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>