<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Ralph Emery On The Record with Brooks and Dunn - Part 2</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording from Ralph Emery's (entertainer) interview of Brooks and Dunn (performance group) for Ralph Emery: On the Record With Brooks and Dunn. Recording is performed in front of a live audience. Interview features a segment featuring Merle Haggard (performer). Recording is from May 02, 1995. Tape is labeled part 2.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1995-05-02</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Ralph Emery; Brooks and Dunn</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Ralph Emery inquires as to why Ronnie Dunn was opposed to a meeting with Merle Haggard, and Haggard recalls when he met Lefty Frizzell -- (01:50) Haggard recalls a time Elvis Presley wished to meet Haggard and Bonnie Owens -- (03:07) Emery and Haggard joke and say goodbye -- (04:10) Emery reflects on how Garth Brooks was intimidated to meet George Jones; additionally Dunn and Kix Brooks talk about wanting to get Haggard to sign Dunn's guitar -- (06:27) Emery invites Dunn to reflect on his family -- (08:39) Emery invites Brooks and Dunn to reflect on song-writing successes before the duo formed -- (10:16) I'm Only in it For the Love [excerpt] (John Conlee) -- (11:00) Emery recalls Dunn's successful writing career, and Dunn discusses winning the Marlboro Country Showdown -- (13:32) Holed Up in Some Honky Tonk [excerpt] (Ronnie Dunn) -- (14:25) Emery addresses the crowd during the commercial break -- (16:03) Emery, Brooks and Dunn discuss how "Holed Up in Some Honky Tonk" helped Dunn's career; additionally, Brooks and Dunn's susceptibility to criticism is discussed -- (18:58) Brooks and Dunn reflect on difficulties of unfair criticism and cancelling a show -- (21:19) Emery inquires about the amount of staffing needed to produce a Brooks and Dunn show -- (22:34) Emery questions what the 'Metal Rodeo' is -- (24:09) Emery plays a video of Brooks and Dunn practicing for the 'Metal Rodeo' -- (25:56) Emery, Dunn and Brooks joke about Dunn hitting Brooks with his vehicle -- (29:01) Emery inquires about, Brooks and Dunn's other interest, shirts -- (29:50) Emery asks about the touring schedule of Brooks and Dunn; additionally, Emery inquires about the similarities of Brooks and Dunn to different genre artists -- (30:46) Emery, Brooks, and Dunn complement each other and say their goodbyes</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1394_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1394</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-04-22</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Emery, Ralph; Brooks &amp; Dunn (Musical group); Brooks, Kix; Dunn, Ronnie; Haggard, Merle; Haggard, Merle, 1937-2016;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8818</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>