<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Various record and radio excerpts</dc:title>
<dc:description>Various recordings of performances featuring various performers, mostly pertaining to the Paul Byrd and Virgil Simmons and other unidentified performers.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Paul Byrd; Virgil Simmons; Texas Troubadours;</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Test tones -- Yellow Rose Of Santa Fe (Texas Troubadours) -- I Knew It All The Time (Texas Troubadours) -- Cowboys And Indians (Texas Troubadours) -- Farewell Blues (Paul Byrd) -- Katy Hill (Virgil Simmons) -- Sally Goodwin (Texas Troubadours) -- Cotton Eyed Joe (Virgil Simmons) [unconfirmed] -- Death Of Kilroy (Virgil Simmons) -- Eighth Of January (Virgil Simmons) -- Twinkle Twinkle Little Star (Virgil Simmons) -- Old Joe Clark (Virgil Simmons) -- Arkansas Traveler (Paul Byrd and Virgil Simmons) -- Death Of Kilroy (Virgil Simmons) -- Smokey Mountain Rag (Virgil Simmons) -- Sally Goodwin (Virgil Simmons) -- Boil Them Cabbage Down (Virgil Simmons) -- Durang's Hornpipe (Virgil Simmons) -- Alexander's Ragtime Band (Paul Byrd) -- Mockingbird (Virgil Simmons) -- Beautiful Ohio (Paul Byrd) -- Twelfth Street Rag (Paul Byrd) -- Four Leaf Clover (Paul Byrd) -- [Unidentified tune] -- Tiptoe Through The Tulips (Paul Byrd) -- Please Don't Talk About Me When I'm Gone (Paul Byrd) -- Simmon's Special ([Unidentified]) -- Some Of These Days (Paul Byrd) -- Darktown Strutters Ball ([Unidentified]) -- Stay A Little Longer (Virgil Simmons) -- Sally Goodwin (Virgil Simmons) -- China Boy (Paul Byrd) -- Alexander's Ragtime Band (Paul Byrd) -- Fisher's Hornpipe (Paul Byrd) -- Flop Eared Mule (Virgil Simmons) -- Chinatown (Paul Byrd) -- Old Joe Clark (Virgil Simmons) -- Shine On, Harvest Moon (Paul Byrd) -- The Girl I Left Behind (Virgil Simmons) -- Dill Pickle Rag (Virgil Simmons) -- Flop Eared Mule (Virgil Simmons) -- Durang's Hornpipe (Virgil Simmons) -- Painting The Clouds With Sunshine (Paul Byrd) -- Fire On The Mountain (Virgil Simmons) -- Tiger Rag (Paul Byrd) -- Miss Sawyer (Virgil Simmons)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-0070_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-0070</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2017-09-27</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Texas Troubadours;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/5876</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>