<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Grand Ole Opry - Prince Albert - 1957-09-21 - Part 2</dc:title>
<dc:description>Part 2 of Prince Albert tobacco sponsored Grand Ole Opry segment from September 21, 1957. Featuring Grant Turner (announcer), Porter Wagoner (host/performer), guest performer Dave Rich, and regular performers the Jordanaires, Chet Atkins, Rod Brasfield, and Del Wood. Held at Ryman Auditorium, Nashville, TN. It is announced that this is the 937th broadcast.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1957-09-21</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Rod Brasfield; Dave Rich; Del Wood; Porter Wagoner</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Porter Wagoner introduces Rod Brasfield -- Comedy routine (Rod Brasfield, Porter Wagoner) -- Prince Albert commercial (Porter Wagoner, Grant Turner) -- Prince Albert jingle -- Porter Wagoner introduces Dave Rich -- Chicken House (Dave Rich) -- Porter Wagoner introduces Del Wood -- Rainbow (Del Wood) -- Porter Wagoner talks -- I Thought I Heard You Calling My Name (Porter Wagoner) -- Closing theme -- Closing statement (Porter Wagoner) -- Camel Cigarettes commercial -- Station announcements -- Noel Hotel commercial (Grant Turner) (incomplete)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>16 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR000300</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2005-12-16</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); National Broadcasting Company; Grand ole opry (Radio program); United States. Armed Forces Radio Service; Ryman Auditorium (Nashville, Tenn.); Turner, Grant; Brasfield, Rod; Atkins, Chet; Wood, Del; Jordanaires (Musical group); Hayes, Red; Wagoner, Porter; Rich, Dave, 1936-</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/1240</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>