<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Various telephone interviews - Biff Collie</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of various telephone interviews with Jim Reeves (performer), Johnny Cash (performer), Tennessee Ernie Ford (performer), Freddie Hart (performer, songwriter), Webb Pierce (performer), Sheb Wooley (performer, actor), Charlie Walker (performer), and Marty Robbins (performer), as conducted by Biff Collie. Beginning of tape also contains a recording of Eddy Arnold, talking about the site of Jim Reeves plane crash.</dc:description>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Eddy Arnold talks about having just come from the  site of Jim Reeves plane crash -- Arnold praises the patrol teams -- (01:31) Jim Reeves talks about being in the music business for eleven years -- (02:10) Reeves talks about cutting his first record and not making any money -- (02:50) Reeves talks about his second record going number one -- (03:00) Reeves talks about wanting to be a baseball player as a child, playing in college, and playing pro ball for three years for the St. Louis Cardinals -- (03:54) Reeves talks about wanting to get back into the radio business, recently having purchased a station -- (04:35) Reeves tells Biff a fishing story -- (05:05) Biff concludes the interview -- (05:40) Biff introduces Johnny Cash -- (05:48) Cash talks about how he got his start in the music industry -- (06:40) Cash talks about how his band and his sound was new -- (07:10) Cash talks about his inspiration for Folsom Prison Blues, and other forms of inspiration -- (08:15) Cash talks about having an interest in acting, and that he just wrote a pilot for a western -- (09:10) Cash talks about Merle Travis being a very memorable person -- (09:55) Cash talks about mimics -- (10:40) Biff thanks Cash and concludes the interview -- (11:34) Collie introduces Jimmy Dean -- (11:50) Dean thanks Biff for having him on recently -- (12:09) Dean talks about being from Texas and migrating to New York -- (12:30) Dean talks about having more work lined up and being a great cook on the grill -- (13:41) Dean talks about Art Carnie -- Biff concludes the interview -- (15:10) Biff introduces Tennessee Ernie Ford -- (15:18) Ford talks about wanting to be a farmer as a child, and having no idea what to do before becoming a performer -- (15:50) Ford talks about studying vocal performance for some time before running out of money -- (16:45) Ford talks about how often he works, and talks about some great people he has worked with on and off stage and concludes the interview -- (17:40) Biff introduces Freddie Hart -- (18:00) Hart talks about where he is from and some of the work he had to do as a child -- (19:20) Ford talks about serving in the military -- (19:40) Ford talks about the inspiration behind his music, and always loving to sing -- (20:45) Ford talks about teaching Judo -- (21:20) Hart thanks Biff and concludes the interview -- (21:37) Biff introduces Webb Pierce -- (21:50) Pierce thanks Biff for having him on and talks about how he got his start in music, at the Louisiana Hayride -- (22:40) Pierce talks about wanting to be a singer as a child -- (23:10) Pierce talks about paying attention to trends in the music industry -- (23:53) Pierce talks about having plans for a new television show -- (24:35) Pierce thanks Biff and concludes the interview -- (24:55) Biff introduces Sheb Wooley -- (25:05) Wooley talks about acting in Rawhide -- (25:55) Wooley talks about living in California, and acting in his first show -- (26:40) Wooley talks about having success early on and having to follow it up -- (27:20) Wooley talks about liking to record music, and act in both television and film -- Biff thanks Wooley and concludes the interview -- (28:03) Biff introduces Charlie Walker -- (28:16) Walker talks about recording songs with Columbia -- (28:35) Walker talks about getting his start in the country music field, and where he is now -- (29:25) Walker talks about being inspired by Jimmie Rodgers and Ernest Tubb early on -- (30:00) Walker talks about being a disc jockey as well, and does and example of talking like one on air -- Biff concludes the interview -- (31:10) Biff introduces Marty Robbins -- (21:20) Robbins does an impression of a English speaker with a Mexican accent -- (31:50) Robbins talks about how he got his start in music, and getting on the Grand Ole Opry -- (33:33) Robbins talks about not knowing what he wanted to be as a child, and while in the military, he wanted to be a civilian -- (34:15) Robbins talks about liking his recording of White Sport Coat the best -- (34:30) Robbins talks about some of his all time favorite performers -- (34:55) Robbins talks about Hawaiian music being his favorite kind of music -- (35:27) Robbins tells a story about a Greek friend of his -- Robbins does another Mexican accent impression and the interview concludes</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-7-04150_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-7-04150</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-01-22</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Arnold, Eddy, 1918-2008; Collie, Biff; Reeves, Jim; Dean, Jimmy, 1928-2010; Cash, Johnny; Ford, Tennessee Ernie, 1919-1991; Hart, Freddie; Pierce, Webb, 1921-1991; Wooley, Sheb, 1921-2003; Walker, Charlie, 1926-2008; Robbins, Marty;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8404</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>