<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Songwriter Session - Deric Ruttan - 2017-06-24</dc:title>
<dc:description>Performance by Deric Ruttan from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on June 24, 2017.  Includes questions from the audience. </dc:description>
<dc:date>2017-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Deric Ruttan; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Walk-in music / (01:22) Opening comments and performer introduction by Abi Tapia / (05:28) Opening comments from Deric / (06:58) His history as a songwriter / (07:30) Story about writing for Dierks Bentley / (10:02) Performs Lot Of Leavin&#8217; Left To Do / (13:57) Comments on the next song / (15:26) Performs Came Here To Forget / (18:57) Answers question about deciding to become a songwriter instead of a performer / (20:55) Answers question about lyrics or music coming first / (21:55) Answers question about how he got to Nashville / (23:33) Comments about next song / (25:44)  Performs Any Ol&#8217; Barstool / (29:38) Answers question about getting songs to artists for them to record / (31:02) Answers question about changes from the demo to an artist's master recording / (31:43) Answers question about his thoughts / (33:00) Comments on the next song / (35:31) Performs Mine Would Be You / (39:38) Answers question about his songs as an artist /           </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(41:04) Answers question about the demo recording of Mine Would Be You and having a male or female vocalist do the singing / (42:05) Answers question about how he got a publishing deal and Don Schlitz story / (43:31) Performs What Was I Thinkin&#8217; / (48:00) Final comments / (48:13) Walk-out music / (50:01) FILE END          </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded at 44.1/24;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0048</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2018-07-12</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Ruttan, Deric; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/7821</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>