<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Various interviews - Biff Collie - 1974-09-12</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of interviews with Jimmy C. Newman (performer), Clyde Moody (performer/songwriter), Bill Carlisle (performer), and Jimmy Riddle (performer), conducted by Biff Collie on September 12, 1974.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1974-09-12</dc:date>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Biff Collie asks Jimmy C. Newman about quitting the Grand Ole Opry -- Jimmy C. Newman talks about traveling -- Newman talks about the town he was born and raised -- Newman talks about going to conventions -- Newman talks about what got him into playing country music -- Newman talks about his ambitions -- Newman talks about the saying ""with a bullet"" in terms to record sales -- Collie concludes the interview -- Clyde Moody talks about his lyrical content being conservative -- Moody talks about the lyrical content of country music -- Moody talks about how country music has evolved since he started -- Moody thanks Collie for the work he does -- Moody talks about his early life and leaving his family at a young age -- Moody talks about his first job making money as a performer -- Moody talks about writing Six White Horses -- Moody talks about playing with Bill Monroe -- Moody talks about conventions and what he's contributed to country music (incomplete) -- Collie introduces Bill Carlisle -- Bill Carlisle talks about being born in Kentucky and being one of the Carlisle Brothers -- Carlisle talks about how Cliff and himself started out playing in Louisville, Kentucky -- Carlisle talks about being discovered unexpectedly by Columbia Records -- Carlisle talks about the lyrical content of modern music and that it should not have to use profanity -- Carlisle talks about performing with Stringbean -- Carlisle talks about Stringbean's attitude -- Collie tells a story about Stringbean and concludes the interview -- Jimmy Riddle talks about working on Hee Haw -- Riddle talks about being born in Dyersburg, Tennessee -- Riddle talks about the first time he made money performing music -- Riddle talks about Borrah Minevitch influencing him to play the harmonica -- [Unidentified harmonica tune] (Jimmy Riddle) (incomplete)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-7-03988_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-7-03988</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2018-07-02</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Collie, Biff; Newman, Jimmy C.; Moody, Clyde, 1915-1989; Carlisle, Bill; Riddle, Jimmy, 1918-1982;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/7751</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>