<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>The Eddy Arnold Show - #033</dc:title>
<dc:description>The Eddy Arnold Show #33, produced and transcribed in Nashville, TN. by Brown Radio Productions. Featuring Eddy Arnold and the Tennessee Plowboys, the Willis Brothers, Roy Wiggins, and host Jud Collins. Opening theme music, 'Cattle Call'; closing theme music, 'Boil Them Cabbage Down'.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Eddy Arnold; Willis Brothers; Tennessee Plowboys; Roy Wiggins</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Opening statement (Jud Collins) -- Opening theme -- Opening statement (Eddy Arnold) -- Easy Rockin' Chair (Eddy Arnold) -- Eddy Arnold talks -- Eddy Arnold talks -- Trouble Keeps Hanging Around My Door (Eddy Arnold) -- Jud Collins talks -- Jud Collins introduces the the Oklahoma Wranglers -- Old Indians Never Die (Oklahoma Wranglers) -- Eddy Arnold talks -- Rubber Dolly (Roy Wiggins steel guitar) -- Jud Collins talks -- Eddy Arnold talks -- When Jesus Beckons Me Home (Eddy Arnold) -- Closing statement (Eddy Arnold) -- Closing theme</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>16 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR002960_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>TR002960</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2017-05-17</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Eddy Arnold Show (Radio program); Collins, Jud; Arnold, Eddy, 1918-2008; Oklahoma Wranglers (Musical group); Willis Brothers; Tennessee Plowboys; Wiggins, Roy; Wright, Chuck;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/5187</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>