<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Minnie Pearl Comedy Routines - Disc 4, 5, 6, 7, 8</dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of a variety of clips featuring Minnie Pearl's comedy routines. The various stand up recordings feature Ray Price (musician), Rod Brasfield (comedian), Faron Young (musician), Cowboy Copas (musician), and Red Foley (musician). The recordings are labeled disc number four, five, six, seven, and eight. The recordings are believed to take place at the Grand Ole Opry. The recordings are from a number of unidentified dates.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Minnie Pearl; Ray Price; Rod Brasfield; Faron Young; Cowboy Copas; Red Foley</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Unidentified fiddle riff ([Unidentified]) -- (00:07) Minnie Pearl reveals a truth about kissing to Ray Price; additionally, Pearl and Rodney Brasfield joke about a three-point landing and a 'willie wagon' -- (03:27) Pearl jokes about her friend's new home and her brother's new invention -- (05:01) Unidentified fiddle riff ([Unidentified]) -- (05:13) Unidentified fiddle riff ([Unidentified]) -- (05:18) Pearl reveals to Faron Young that she fancies Young; additionally, Pearl jokes about thinking about Clark Gable when she kisses-- (07:08) Pearl jokes about her brothers mental health and her friend's fifteen children -- (08:50) Unidentified fiddle riff ([Unidentified]) -- (08:54) Unidentified fiddle riff ([Unidentified]) -- (09:00) Pearl jokes about the difference from country and city girls; additionally, Cowboy Copas gives Pearl advice -- (11:49) Pearl tells Copas about a Skunk farm -- (12:06) Unidentified fiddle riff ([Unidentified]) -- (12:15) Unidentified fiddle riff ([Unidentified]) -- (12:20) Pearl reflects on the good looking members of the crowd and cows in the outfield -- (14:16) Brasfield introduces the best player on his baseball team; additionally, the difficulties of finding an umpire is discussed -- (16:05) Pearl jokes about her first blind date [incomplete] -- (17:04) Unidentified fiddle riff ([Unidentified]) -- (17:08) Pearl discusses how she is going to give up and how she got stuck in a revolving door -- (19:33) Pearl and Brasfield joke about Brasfield being slow and his misfortune on the Grand Ole Opry -- (21:35) Brasfield jokes about his girlfriend's work -- (21:54) Unidentified fiddle riff ([Unidentified]) -- (22:02) Pearl discusses how she had her feelings hurt -- (22:49) Pearl calls on Red Foley to read letters to her -- (24:04) Pearl recalls a patient with a swollen leg; additionally, Pearl discusses her basket weaving uncle and brother -- (25:50) Foley recalls seeing two people at Pearl's home -- (26:19) Unidentified fiddle riff ([Unidentified]) -- (26:25) Unidentified fiddle riff ([Unidentified]) -- (26:30) Pearl reflects on how people were saying that she was "not all there" -- (27:31) Foley introduces Pearl's question and answer section -- (29:48) Pearl reflects on her Aunt Rosy and a clock -- (30:19) Unidentified fiddle riff ([Unidentified])</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>15 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-0215_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-0215</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-08-28</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Pearl, Minnie; Price, Ray, 1926-2013; Brasfield, Rod; Brasfield, Rod, 1910-1958; Young, Faron; Copas, Cowboy; Foley, Red, 1910-1968;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9432</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>