<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Eddie Rabbitt Interview - Biff Collie</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of an interview with Eddie Rabbitt (performer) conducted by Biff Collie. </dc:description>
<dc:date>0028-09</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Eddie Rabbitt; Biff Collie</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Eddie Rabbitt declares that the production on his album Jersey Boy is a pride of his, and Rabbitt thanks Richard Landis for his production -- (00:25) Rabbitt radio spot for Biff Collie and the Music City Album Review -- (00:34) Rabbitt says ""Move over Biff, I'm your cohost this week"" -- (00:39)  Rabbitt messes up radio spot for the Music City Album Review -- (00:46) Collie laughs during Rabbitt radio spot for the Music City Album Review -- (00:53) Rabbitt radio spot for the Music City Album Review -- (01:00) Rabbitt radio spot for Biff Collie and the Music City Album Review -- (01:07) Collie and Rabbitt discuss the upcoming review for Jersey Boy, released by Capitol Records -- (01:17) Rabbitt and Collie joke about Rabbitt's pair of t-shirts, and Rabbitt reveals how he had wanted a Jersey Boy t-shirt for a promotion with Dean Markley Strings -- (2:00) Rabbitt reveals how he wrote, Ronnie Milsap's first number one record, ""Pure Love"" -- (02:13) Rabbitt reveals his pride in writing, Elvis Presley's fiftieth gold record, ""Kentucky Rain"" -- (02:21) Rabbitt tells that the first song he had recorded in Nashville was Roy Drusky's ""Working My Way Up to the Bottom"" -- (02:36) Collie and Rabbitt discuss how ""Jersey Boy"" became the title track and Rabbitt reflects on how a number of his songs he writes he does not release -- (03:37) Rabbitt tells of how he got his first exposure to country music from his scout leader; as well as, from his father's fiddle playing -- (04:31) Rabbitt and Collie discuss Rabbitt's Irish heritage and his families extensive musical background -- (05:36) Collie introduces the format of the album review and Rabbitt reflects on his country music roots and country music's connection to Ireland -- (06:49) Rabbitt calls ""Tennessee Born and Bred"" the epidemy of bluegrass 'All American' music -- (07:18) Collie says he will play  ""Tennessee Born and Bred"" for Rabbitt -- (07:27) Rabbitt discusses how he stayed at Reed Nielsen's apartment while recording ""Tennessee Born and Bred"" with a number of bluegrass legends -- (08:22) Rabbitt says 'Welcome to the music business' -- (08:28) Rabbitt discusses his unease when it comes to complacency, Collie likes the terminology Rabbitt uses, and Rabbitt asserts his normality -- (09:40) Rabbitt discusses his desire to write a song similar Ray Price and being asked to write a song while on the tour bus -- (10:39) Rabbitt tells of how he recorded his music video to be a replica of a 1950s barn yard party -- (11:21) Collie brings up ""The Wanderer's"" music video and Rabbitt gives praise to Jack Cole -- (11:38) Rabbitt tells how ""Suspicions"" had been written in five minutes -- (12:05) Rabbitt describes ""They're Tearin' My Little Town Down"" to be a song about small towns turning into 'ghost towns' -- (12:51) Collie has Rabbitt recall how Rabbitt wrote ""American Boy"" while riding on a moped in Bermuda -- (14:26) Rabbitt talks about the obsessive repetition he had when he was trying to memorize ""American Boy"" -- (15:27) Collie recaps the show to that point and Rabbitt jokingly thanks Collie for coming on his show -- (15:54) Collie recalls and has Rabbitt tell about the time he made an ashtray, for his father, in the side of his father's chair -- (17:35) ""Hold on to Me (The Rain Song)"" is discussed by Rabbitt to be a song build off a melody that Nielsen was playing one day at the studio, and Rabbitt reveals his three-year-old son's immediate love for the song -- (19:14) Rabbitt continues to tell of his son's enjoyment of ""Hold on to Me (The Rain Song)"" including his son's love of the thunder sound effects -- (19:27) ""Feel Like a Stranger"" is discussed to be a 'Louisiana mud swamp' type song about someone who feels like a stranger in their own home -- (20:25) Collie has Rabbitt recall attempting to sell country songs in New York and Rabbitt tells about how he brought a fifty pound recorder with him everywhere -- (22:28) Rabbitt recalls having an interview with Shapiro, Bernstein &amp; Co. and how he was offered $25 a week -- (24:34) Rabbitt says ""It's Lonely Out Tonite"" is a country-rock song and Rabbitt says it invites people to come across the room to meet each other -- (25:12) Collie has Rabbitt discuss his plan of attack when it comes to recording an album and Rabbitt discusses how he can start with over thirty songs -- (27:05) ""Suspicions"" is revealed to be an add-on to an already complete album -- (28:25) Rabbitt reveals how he didn't believe that ""Sweet Janine"" was going to be a recorded track -- (29:20)  ""Jersey Boy"" is revealed to be an autobiography for Rabbitt -- (30:23) Rabbitt says ""I just like it, it's a real nice song about what happened to me"" -- (30:29) Rabbitt recalls a time he was touring through Montana and he and Nielsen were in the right mood to write ""Only One Love in My Life"" -- (31:07) Collie praises Rabbitt's efforts and Collie has Rabbitt discuss his children's names, and Rabbitt tells how his daughter Demelza got her name officially authenticated from English writer Winston Graham -- (33:22) Collie speaks praise and Rabbitt speaks of his idea on having children with a single woman -- (33:58) Collie recaps the subject of the show and Rabbitt expresses his interest in being on the show again</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1193_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1193</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-01-28</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Rabbitt, Eddie; Rabbitt, Eddie, 1941-1998; Collie, Biff;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8446</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>