<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Restless Heart Interview - Biff Collie</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of an interview with Restless Heart (performance group) conducted by Biff Collie. </dc:description>
<dc:date>1989-03-06</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Restless Heart; Biff Collie</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) "Big Dreams in a Small Town" is described by John Dittrich as a universal statement of people wanting more -- (00:39) Biff Collie introduces Dittrich and Larry Stewart of Restless Heart in a Music City Album Review radio spot -- (00:50) Dittrich tells of how the studio dictates when an album is to be released, and Stewart, Dittrich, and Collie discuss the pre-production behind Restless Heart's fourth studio album -- (02:45) "Say What's in Your Heart" is described by Stewart as an aggressive song with difficulties during recording -- (03:39) Dittrich describes how Stewart won the lead vocalist spot and Stewart describes Dittrich and Paul Gregg's vocal solos -- (04:42) Stewart remembers the moment, when driving, Restless Heart discovered "A Tender Life" and Dittrich describes the collective understanding, by the group, that "A Tender Life" would be their 'country standard' -- (05:55) Collie recalls a story of what causes a song to become great -- (06:07) Dittrich and Collie discuss the longevity of a 'standard' -- (06:56) Dittrich addresses every owner of a baseball team; Dittrich states that teams that have Restless Hearts perform have their team move on to the World Series -- (07:45) Dittrich describes the learning process of a musician -- (08:23) Collie questions the next steps after discovering a song, and Stewart addresses the desire to rehearse before performing it -- (09:11) Dittrich, Stewart, and Collie discuss the arrangement process when creating a song structure -- (10:16) Dittrich describes the advice given to him by Larry Londin -- (11:13) Dittrich jokes about the divorce behind "Jenny Come Back" -- (11:41) "No Way Out" is discussed by Dittrich, he describes it as the best vocal performance Restless Heart has performed -- (12:27) Dittrich and Stewart describe the gifts received from baseball teams and reflect on their ability to perform being directly correlated to the touring schedule -- (13:18) Collie infers about Restless Heart's huge popularity -- (13:32) "I'll Still be Loving You" is described by Dittrich as Restless Heart's career song -- (14:02) Collie questions the difficulty of working with others and Stewart and Dittrich describes the different bond of Restless Heart from other bands -- (15:46) "Why Does it Have to be Wrong or Right?" is discussed by Dittrich and Stewart as a rare cross-over from country music -- (16:22) "Big Dreams in a Small Town" is reflected on by Stewart as an extremely personal song for most of the members of Restless Heart -- (17:05) "Tender Lie" is said to be a 'staple' and 'classic' by Dittrich -- (17:24) Dittrich and Stewart describe the unknown possibilities of "No Way Out" -- (18:11) "Jenny Come Back" is described as an up-tempo 'fun' song by Dittrich -- (18:21) "Wheels" is reflected on as the song that had changed the career of the Restless Heart band; Collie, Stewart, and Dittrich reflect on the inspirational impact of "Wheels" -- (20:02) "That Rock Won't Roll" is described by Dittrich and Stewart as the song that 'got the ball rolling' -- (20:20) "The Bluest Eyes in Texas" is said to be a 'magical song' by Stewart -- (20:47) "Let the Heartache Ride," Restless Heart's first single, surprises Stewart and Dittrich for its continued popularity -- (21:53) Collie describes how Randy Travis released a track twice -- (22:08) Collie and Dittrich discuss the decision for naming the band -- (22:42) Dittrich describes the situation behind discovering "Calm Before the Song" while Dittrich was at Warner Brothers Studios</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1174_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1174</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-01-18</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Restless Heart (Musical group); Collie, Biff;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8401</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>