<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Jim Glaser Interviewed by Bob Battle in 1978 </dc:title>
<dc:description>The recording is of Bob Battle interviewing Jim Glaser on the telephone. The recording takes place on 01-04-78.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1978-01-04</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Jim Glaser</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Side One - (0:02) -- Phone Interview - Bob Battle from the Nashville Banner calls Jim Glaser. (0:46) -- Bob Battle asks about Jim Glaser's career and his plans for the future artistically. (1:14) -- Bob Battle asks about the productivity of Jim Glaser's publishing, songwriting, and singing. (1:54) -- Bob Battle asks about Jim Glaser's newest album. (2:44) -- Bob Battle asks Jim Glaser about working with Owen Bradley. (2:54) -- Bob Battle questions Jim Glaser about young talent he's been mentoring as of late. (3:28) -- Bob Battle questions Jim Glaser about his music publishing endeavors. (4:30) -- Bob Battle asks Jim Glaser the year he first came to Nashville. Jim Glaser has lived in Nashville since 1958. (4:50) -- Bob Battle asks Jim Glaser about "the greatest thing that's ever happened to you." (5:28) -- Bob Battle asks Jim Glaser about the first time he decided to become a solo recording and performing artist. Jim Glaser responds that it was a gradual process. (6:42) -- Bob Battle asks about Jim Glaser's strategies and goals when attempting to write a hit record. Owen Bradley told Jim Glaser that an artist needs three hit records to establish themselves in the music business. (7:49) -- Jim Glaser describes being dropped by Victor RCA. (8:46) -- Bob Battle asks about Jim Glaser's age and living situation. (8:57) -- Bob Battle asks Jim Glaser about the future of country music. (10:28) -- Bob Battle asks Jim Glaser about his future touring plans. (12:15) -- Bob Battle describes his "Country Cooking" column, asks Jim Glaser to send his personal recipes.  </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>audio cassette, compact;</dc:format>
<dc:format>1.75 ips;</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>CAS4665_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>CAS4665</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-08-28</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Glaser, Jim;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#169; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/9427</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>