<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Southern Pacific Interview - Biff Collie</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording of an interview with Southern Pacific (performance group) conducted by Biff Collie. </dc:description>
<dc:date>1990-04-03</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Southern Pacific; Biff Collie</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Southern Pacific member's John McFee and Keith Knudsen tell of how they named their albums County Line and Zuma based on places they surf -- (01:16) "Any Way the Wind Blows" is discussed by McFee, Knudsen and Biff Collie as a track used in the Pink Cadillac movie soundtrack by Clint Eastwood -- (02:13) "Any Way the Wind Blows" is defined as a career song by Knudsen and McFee tells of writing with Bernadette Peters and Nicolette Larson -- (03:55) Collie begins to tell a story of seeing Southern Pacific [incomplete] -- (04:07) McFee and Knudsen talk about their arrangement of the "Star Spangled Banner" -- (04:51) "I Can't Complain" is described by Knudsen as a normal feeling -- (05:21) Knudsen, McFee, and Collie joke about how Southern Pacific came together and tell of how they were originally members of the Doobie Brothers -- (06:33) Kurt Howell tells how he was a session artist and Knudsen touches on Stu Cook's time as a member of Creedence Clearwater Revival -- (07:46) McFee reminisces on his time as a guitar player and country artists pioneering electric guitar -- (08:20) Collie tells of Jimmy Rogers using a wide range of music to revolutionize country -- (09:15) Collie reflects on Bob Wills having a large orchestra backing him up to allow the band to join a union -- (10:00) "Beyond Love" writer Knudsen is discussed and Howell reflects on the idea of a romantic partner -- (11:08) Howell and Knudsen tells of Southern Pacific's fandom of surfing -- (12:02) McFee tells of "Times Up" being a song that developed into including Carlene Carter -- (13:53) "Memphis Queen" is discussed by Knudsen as a romantic song of riverboats -- (14:51) McFee discusses the stylist discussions that make them different -- (15:17) Collie and Howell talk about "G.T.O" originally being perceived as a Beach Boys song; the Southern Pacific group worked with the Beach Boys to complete the song -- (16:53) Knudsen tells of how their album format was perceived as only country and how that changed with "Side Saddle" -- (18:07) Knudsen jokes about writing another song [unidentified] -- (18:17) Knudsen tells of "Restless Heart" as a song with a certain type of feeling -- (19:04) Knudsen and Collie talk about the rodeo show circuit that they have been playing -- (19:59) McFee addresses Justin Boots and a rodeo relief fund they donate to -- (21:00) Collie and Southern Pacific discuss the decision to release their album and the royalty rate of the album -- (22:08) Southern Pacific joke about "The One that Got Away" being a fishing song; but, it is actually a love song -- (23:27) Knudsen tells of how the magic of a song can be changed drastically -- (24:15) "Mary Lou" is told by McFee as being discovered by Jim Ed Norman and addresses the number of songs they tried -- (25:25) "Help Wanted" is told by Knudsen as a story wrote by Knudsen by an experience in California and McFee jokes about the "Star Spangled Banner" -- (26:25) Collie addresses "I Go to Pieces" and Southern Pacific tells of how they recorded the acapella for the song; additionally, the decision was made while touring -- (29:10) Knudsen tells about the inability to test songs on tour except when they are performing live shows -- (30:18) Collie addresses his gratefulness and Southern Pacific joke about Collie's name relation to a dog</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1169_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1169</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-01-15</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Southern Pacific; Southern Pacific (Musical group);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8383</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>