<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Johnny Cash Show promo radio spots</dc:title>
<dc:description>Various radio spots for the Johnny Cash Show, featuring Little Jimmy Dickens (performer), Stonewall Jackson (performer), Nat Stuckey (performer), Charlie Walker (performer), Jay Lee Webb (performer), Tom T. Hall (performer), Jimmy Payne (performer), George Hamilton IV (performer), the Compton Brothers (performers), Bill Anderson (performer), Jan Howard (performer), and Stu Phillips (performer).</dc:description>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Johnny Cash Show promo radio spot (Little Jimmy Dickens) -- (01:00) Johnny Cash Show promo radio spot (Stonewall Jackson) -- (01:42) Johnny Cash Show promo radio spot (Nat Stuckey) -- (02:25) Johnny Cash Show promo radio spot (Charlie Walker) -- (03:05) Johnny Cash Show promo radio spot (Jay Lee Webb) -- (03:47) Johnny Cash Show promo radio spot (Tom T. Hall) -- (04:32) Johnny Cash Show promo radio spot (Jimmy Payne) -- (05:15) Johnny Cash Show promo radio spot (George Hamilton IV) -- (05:58) Johnny Cash Show promo radio spot (Compton Brothers) -- (06:38) Johnny Cash Show promo radio spot (Bill Anderson) -- (07:23) Johnny Cash Show promo radio spot (Jan Howard) -- (08:02) Johnny Cash Show promo radio spot (Stu Phillips)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- full track</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-7-01124_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-7-01124</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-01-25</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Johnny Cash Show (Television series); Dickens, Little Jimmy, 1920-2015; Jackson, Stonewall; Stuckey, Nat; Walker, Charlie, 1926-2008; Webb, Jay Lee; Hall, Tom T.; Payne, Jimmy (Vocalist); Hamilton, George, IV, 1937-; Compton Brothers; Anderson, Bill, 1937-; Howard, Jan (Vocalist); Phillips, Stu;</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8427</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>