<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Opryland Music Demo Recordings - Y-97</dc:title>
<dc:description>Recording is of a group of demo recordings from Opryland Music. Recordings are from an unknown date and recorded by a number of unknown bands. Tape is labeled Y-97. </dc:description>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) All Mine to Love (Chris Harris) -- (02:02) Am I That Easy to Forget (C. Belew and W. S. Stevenson) -- (04:35) At My Side (M. and A. Goldman, K. Adelman) -- (05:57) Am I To Blame (Geo. Whitten) -- (08:37) As Always (B. Flournoy) -- (10:06) At Christmas This Year (B. Flournoy) -- (11:22) Ain't Gonna Love Just One (E. Miller) -- (12:13) Arms (That Won't Hold Me) (E. Miller and J. Lynch) -- (13:38) All the Time (Bobby Lile) -- (16:04) Angel (S. Masters) -- (18:24) All My Love (F. Wilson and R. Baker) -- (20:00) All I Want For Christmas is You (S. Rhodes and B. George) -- (22:25) An Old Fashioned Picture (M. Bias and V. Bias) -- (24:58) After the Sun Goes Down (Jimmy Walton) -- (26:59) Adios Mi Amore Adios (B. Flournoy) -- (28:25) The Ace of Spades (Smokey Reason) -- (30:29) All of My Dreams (L. Tholen, B. Klein, and C. Carpenter) -- (32:17) An Unanswered Prayer (L. Newman and Joe Hobson) -- (34:20) Are You Ready (Cecil Gant and W. S. Stevenson) -- (36:48) As the Sun was Sinking Low [Unconfirmed] ([Unidentified]) -- (40:08) As Long As I Live (S. Felfels and M. Burton) -- (41:27) Always You [Scratchy] (L. Barney, E. Potter, and W. S. Stevenson) -- (44:40) Annabelle (Otis Pierce) -- (47:21) Albuquerque (J. Miller, I. C. Lemly, and D. L. Smith) -- (49:08) Baby Shoes ([Unidentified]) -- (51:39) A Rain of Love ([Unidentified]) -- (54:34) Ever After ([Unidentified]) -- (57:55) Before You ([Unidentified]) -- (1:00:32) A Child Shall Lead ([Unidentified]) -- (1:03:33) I'm Flexable ([Unidentified])</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>1/4 inch -- 2 half tracks</dc:format>
<dc:format>7.5 ips</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>RT-10-1293_1</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isPartOf>RT-10-1293</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:created>2019-03-11</dcterms:created>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8615</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>