<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Grand Ole Opry - Prince Albert - 1959-04-25 - Part 1</dc:title>
<dc:description>Part 1 of Prince Albert tobacco sponsored Grand Ole Opry segment from April 25, 1959. Featuring Grant Turner (announcer), Porter Wagoner (host/performer), guest performer Skeeter Davis (although Elton Britt was advertised as the guest for this week on the previous show), and regular performers the Jordanaires, Tommy Jackson, Hank Garland, Archie Campbell, and Grandpa Jones. Held at Ryman Auditorium, Nashville, TN. It is announced that this is the 1020th broadcast.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1959-04-25</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Porter Wagoner; Jordanaires; Skeeter Davis; Tommy Jackson; Hank Garland</dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>Grant Turner introduces Porter Wagoner -- Tell Her Lies And Feed Her Candy (Porter Wagoner) -- Opening statement (Grant Turner, Porter Wagoner) -- Porter Wagoner introduces the Jordanaires -- Dip Your Fingers In Some Water (Jordanaires) -- Porter Wagoner introduces Skeeter Davis -- I Forgot More Than You'll Ever Know (Skeeter Davis) -- Prince Albert commercial (Grant Turner, Porter Wagoner) -- Porter Wagoner introduces Tommy Jackson -- Tennessee Wagoner (Tommy Jackson fiddle) -- Porter Wagoner and Grant Turner talk -- What Would You Do (If Jesus Came To Your House) (Porter Wagoner) -- Porter Wagoner introduces Hank Garland -- Fireball Mail (Hank Garland)</dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>16 inch metal-based acetate disc</dc:format>
<dc:format>33 1/3 rpm</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>TR000461</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2006-05-05</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>WSM (Radio station : Nashville, Tenn.); National Broadcasting Company; Grand ole opry (Radio program); Ryman Auditorium (Nashville, Tenn.); United States. Armed Forces Radio Service; Turner, Grant; Garland, Hank, 1930-2004; Jones, Grandpa, 1913-1998; Jackson, Tommy; Jordanaires (Musical group); Campbell, Archie; Sloan, Ralph; Tennessee Travelers; Wagoner, Porter; Davis, Skeeter</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/1402</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>