<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Discussion - Beyond Music Row; Tompall Glaser and his renegade studio, Hillbilly Central aka Glaser Sound Studio - 2018-06-02</dc:title>
<dc:description>Panel discussion on Tompall Glaser, his studio and it's importance to the Outlaw movement from the Ford Theater at the Country Music Hall of Fame and Museum on June 2, 2018.  Includes excerpted audio from video and recorded sound excerpts.  Participants include Kinky Friedman, Marshall Chapman and Kyle Lehning.  Moderated by Peter Cooper.  Presented in support of the exhibit Outlaws &amp; Armadillos: Country&#8217;s Roaring &#700;70s.  </dc:description>
<dc:date>2018-06-02</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Marshall Chapman; Kinky Friedman; Kyle Lehning; Peter Cooper; </dc:creator>
<dcterms:tableOfContents>(00:00) Walk-in Music / (01:34) Opening comments by Peter Cooper and introduction of the panel participants / (05:01) Kyle and Peter talk about Tompall and the Glaser Brothers path to Nashville / (06:25) Plays audio from video / (07:31) Talks about the writer of the previous song Cowboy Jack Clement / (08:04) Talk about Tompall and the Glaser Brothers publishing company hitting it big with the song Gentle On My Mind / (08:39)  Plays recorded audio excerpt of Glen Campbell's Gentle On My Mind / (09:33) Kinky talks about his impression of Tompall and the Glasers / (11:07) Marshall talks about hearing the song Gentle On My Mind the first time / (11:36) Peter Cooper talks about Gentle On My Mind and the money created from it for the Glasers / (12:35) Talk about the John Hartford album Aereo-Plane / (13:35) Kyle Lehning talks about the recording of that album, audio engineer Claude Hill and being impressed by the musicians he heard / (15:44) Plays recorded audio excerpt of Back In The Goodle Days / (16:54) Kinky talks about how the Glasers found him, Glen Campbell and Willie Nelson / (23:09) Kinky talks about how he came to record at Hillbilly Central and Willie Nelson / (25:22) Marshall tells story about Willie Nelson playing golf with a record company executive / (26:36) Kyle talks about engineering at Glaser Studio / (29:34) Marshall talks about the open door policy at Glaser Studio / (30:23) Marshall talks about what attracted her to the scene in Nashville / (31:27) Kyle talks about the working hours at Glaser Studio and his early days working there / (33:03) Kyle and Kinky talk about the recording Honky Tonk Heroes, Billy Joe Shaver and Captain Midnight / (35:20) Kyle talks about Roger Schutt aka Captain Midnight / (38:03) Kinky talks about Captain Midnight / (39:40) Kinky talks about Captain Midnight's input on the scene and his observations about Willie Nelson / (41:07) Kyle talks about Waylon recording This Time at Glaser Studios with Willie Nelson producing / (41:56) Peter talks about Captain Midnight throwing knives and Marshall talks about their knife throwing contests / (42:53) Peter tells story about Captain Midnight and his leather satchel / (45:04) Talk about Waylon Jennings and Tompall Glaser playing pinball machines at JJ's Market / (46:19) Reads quote from Dave Hickey article on Tompall / (46:48) Talk about Waylon and Tompall's friendship and adding Cowboy Jack Clement to the production of Waylon's album Dreaming My Dreams / (47:27) Marshall talks about being at the studio during the recording of the album Dreaming My Dreams / (48:25) Kinky talks about Tompall introducing Kinky Friedman and the Texas Jewboys on the Grand Ole Opry and tells Jimmie Snow and Dobie Gray story / (51:51) Kyle talks about the Dreaming My Dreams song being the best thing he's been involved in and tells story about Jesse Colter sister Sharon meeting Cowboy Jack Clement / (54:24) Plays recorded excerpt from the album Dreaming My Dreams / (55:40) Kyle tells stories about mixing the album / (58:09) Kinky tells story about making the album They Ain't Making Jews Like Jesus Anymore / (59:21) Marshall tells story about working at the Jolly Ox restaurant and how Jack Clement came to produce the Dreaming My Dreams album / (01:01:59) Plays videotape recording of Tompall's appearance on the Bobby Bare and Friends television show / (01:05:19) Kinky talks about Hazel Smith / (01:07:38) Kyle and others talk about Hazel Smith / (01:09:21) Peter reads excerpts of an article written by Hazel Smith / (01:10:21) Marshall talks about her song Rode Hard And Put Up Wet and the circumstances around writing it / (01:!3:25) Performs Rode Hard And Put Up Wet (Marshall Chapman) / (01:17:34) Talk about the demise of Hillbilly Central and the estrangement of the Glaser Brothers and Tompall and Waylon falling out / (01:18:23) Kyle talks about leaving Glaser Sound studio and the pressures on Tompall / (01:20:15) Peter and Kyle talk Tompall and the Glaser Sound building / (01:20:47) Marshall and Peter talk about Tompall's album Tompall And His Outlaw Band and some of Tompall's other albums / (01:21:58) Peter talks about what the building is now / (01:22:36) Kinky talks about Tompall's loneliness, writing a song about it and tells story about his necklace / (01:27:12) Performs The Loneliest May I Ever Met (Kinky Friedman) / (01:30:00) Closing comments / (01:30:24) Walk-out Music / (01:31:27) FILE END                                                        </dcterms:tableOfContents>
<dc:format>Born digital;</dc:format>
<dc:format>original source recorded as an mp3 file at 44.1</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>DEN0124</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:created>2019-02-23</dcterms:created>
<dc:subject>Glaser, Tompall; Chapman, Marshall; Friedman, Kinky; Lehning, Kyle; Cooper, Peter; Country Music Hall of Fame &amp; Museum (Nashville, Tenn.);</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dcterms:accessRights>This audio file is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and may be protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The file may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. End users must obtain all required permissions or consents from the owners of such rights. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this, contact audio@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite audio file information in email. </dcterms:accessRights>
<dcterms:rightsHolder>The Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum is the exclusive owner of this content, including, without limitation, all copyrights. End users must obtain any other required permissions or consents, e.g., rights of privacy and rights of publicity, from the owners of such rights.</dcterms:rightsHolder>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/musicaudio/id/8642</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>