<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:identifier>shades_eths_0002.tif</dc:identifier>
<dc:title>Drawings of Confederate Soldiers</dc:title>
<dc:title>Bleak House Tower Drawings</dc:title>
<dc:date>ca. 1863</dc:date>
<dc:description>Portrait sketches of two bearded men and one youth.</dc:description>
<dc:description>This drawing, found on the interior plaster wall of the tower of Bleak House--Confederate Memorial Hall on Kingston Pike in Knoxville, Tennessee, is purported to represent three Confederate sharpshooters who killed Union General William P. Sanders on the afternoon of November 17, 1863 as he accompanied soldiers marching up Kingston Pike. The central figure has been identified as Corporal William Raines, 9th Georgia unit. During the siege of Knoxville, Bleak House was being used as Confederate General James Longstreet's headquarters. The home's residents, Louisa Franklin Armstrong and  her daughters, remained in second floor quarters, emerging for meals during periods when hostilities allowed.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Military personnel--Confederate</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Visualizing the War; The Persistence of Memory</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Sanders, William P.; Longstreet, James; Armstrong, Louisa Franklin</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States--Tennessee-Knoxville</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>1860-69</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact the East Tennessee Historical Society.</dc:rights>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jp2</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>East Tennessee Historical Society</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/108</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>