<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Hunt Phelan Used as Western Sanitary Hospital, 1863</dc:title>
<dc:title>Soldiers Home, Memphis Tennessee, Established by the Western Sanitary Commission, February 8, 1863</dc:title>
<dc:date>1863</dc:date>
<dc:description>Oval photograph of white-columned house with substantial outbuildings and grounds, with a number of men and a horse and carriage in foreground. Two small round photographic portraits of a woman and a man below the larger image and an inscription give their names with the titles matron and superintendent.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The home of William Hunt, just outside of downtown Memphis, was occupied by both Confederate and Federal officers during the war. The inscription on this photograph indicates that it was taken over by the Western Sanitary Commission on 8 February 1863 for use as a "soldier's home," under the jurisdiction of the matron and superintendent pictured here. The imposing brick mansion is also thought to have been a Freedmen's School for several years before it was returned to the Hunt family.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Architecture, domestic; Hospitals; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Medical Aspects; Women</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Capturing the Flag; Making Music</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States--Tennessee--Memphis</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact the Tennessee State Museum.</dc:rights>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpg</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Tennessee State Museum</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/217</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>