<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:identifier>shades_loc_0009.tif</dc:identifier>
<dc:creator>Barnard, George N.</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Nashville, Tenn., March 1864 From Fort Negley Looking North East</dc:title>
<dc:title>Fort Negley</dc:title>
<dc:date>1864-03</dc:date>
<dc:description>This panoramic photograph taken from an upper level of the fort shows log construction, earth walls reinforced with stone, and bunker-like structures, as well as uniformed Union soldiers, tents, cannons, and a look out tower. In the distance are low tree-covered hills and a few scattered houses across a relatively flat landscape.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Barnard was a photographer in the Topographical Branch of the Department of Engineers, Army of the Cumberland, United States Army. He traveled to Nashville, Knoxville, and Chattanooga in 1864. Fort Negley, a star-shaped fortification, was designed by Army of the Ohio chief engineer James St. Clair Morton and constructed largely by African Americans, both freedmen and conscripted labor. The fort overlooked the junction of the Nashville and Chattanooga Railroad and the Tennessee and Allatoona Railroad. Barnard later made single views of Fort Negely and the capitol.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Military facilities; Fort Negley (Tenn.); Forts and fortifications</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Visualizing the War; Building a Future Through Opportunity</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact the Library of Congress.</dc:rights>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jp2</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Library of Congress</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/60</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>