<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:identifier>shades_adah_0003.tif</dc:identifier>
<dc:creator>Gutherz, Frederick G.</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Stephens Bluff on the Black Warrior River, taken from the Steamer Lily, May 14, 1864</dc:title>
<dc:title>Gutherz drawing</dc:title>
<dc:date>1864-05-14</dc:date>
<dc:description>A grouping of buildings is situated on top of a bluff.  Vegetation is sparse with a few trees and shrubs.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Carl Gutherz's older brother Fred joined the 154th Senior Tennessee Volunteer Regiment as an army engineer for the CSA. Fred later served with the Confederate forces fighting Sherman in North Georgia in 1864. The Steamer Lily was a side-wheel  steamboat that transported troops through Alabama during the Civil War. Here it transports Fred and other Confederate soldiers down the Black Warrior River, which runs from a forested area of high bluffs at the extreme southern end of the Appalachian Mountains to the suburbs of Birmingham, Alabama.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Transportation; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Art and the war</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Buildings; Rivers</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Visualizing the War</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States--Alabama</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact the Alabama Dept. of Archives and History.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>Q26186</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jp2</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Alabama Dept. of Archives and History</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/28</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>