<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:identifier>shades_loc_0001.tif</dc:identifier>
<dc:creator>Barnard, George N.</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Knoxville, Tennessee, View from Cupola of East Tennessee University,  March 19, 1864</dc:title>
<dc:title>View from Cupola of East Tennessee University</dc:title>
<dc:date>1864-03-19</dc:date>
<dc:description>Panoramic view from the cupola of East Tennessee University looking East toward the Holston (Tennessee) River with notes on the locations of Forts Stanley, Higley, Dickinson; Battery Noble; and Second Creek.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Barnard was a photographer in the Topographical Branch of the Department of Engineers, Army of the Cumberland, United States Army. He traveled to Nashville, Knoxville, and Chattanooga in 1864. This 360 degree photograph was taken on March 19, 1864 by Barnard with the help of Captain Orlando M. Poe. The unusual exposure required the use of seven photographic plates and probably took the two much of the day to complete. Note how few clouds are visible. Because the exposure required to document the landscape usually overexposed the sky, few clouds are visible in most wet plate negatives. In 1866, Barnard would return to Tennessee to document Sherman's earlier campaign for a book. At that time, he took multiple images of the scenes to allow for more detailed views of the sky.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Military facilities; Forts &amp; fortifications</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Visualizing the War</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States--Tennessee--Knoxville</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact the Library of Congress.</dc:rights>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jp2</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Library of Congress</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/61</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>