<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:creator>Schrader, Theodore</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Nashville and the camp of the Sixteenth Regiment of Ills. Vols. Inft. At Edgefield, Tennessee, circa 1863-1865</dc:title>
<dc:date>ca. 1863-1865</dc:date>
<dc:description>A pictorial representation in lithographic form of Nashville during the Civil War, with the camp of the Illinois 16th Volunteer Regiment at Edgefield in the foreground. The Cumberland River is seen in the background with gunboats and riverboats depicted. The state capitol building can be seen in the background overlooking the city of Nashville. Structures featured within the camp are the guard house, the headquarters, the hospital, the sutler, and the housing for the band. </dc:description>
<dc:description>Most of the lithograph depicts camp activities as might be seen during the Civil War. The lithograph was created by Theodore Schrader of St. Louis, Missouri. The 16th Regiment Illinois Infantry was organized at Quincy, Illinois, and mustered in May 24, 1861. They marched from Tuscumbia, Alabama to Nashville from August 25 through September 15, 1862. They saw action at Columbia on September 10, 1862. They participated in the Siege of Nashville from September 15 through November 6 of 1862. </dc:description>
<dc:subject>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; United States. Army. Illinois Infantry Regiment, 16th</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Visualizing the War</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Nashville</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact the Tennessee State Library and Archives or email to photoorders.tsla@tn.gov.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>33068</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:publisher>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/283</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>