<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:identifier>shades_mca_0001.jpg</dc:identifier>
<dc:title>Abel Streight Brigade Banner</dc:title>
<dc:title>United States Brigade Flag</dc:title>
<dc:description>The flag appears to have been trimmed, particularly in the blue field and the border areas, with possible portions taken as souvenirs. The fabric is faded, particularly the red and white stripes. It has a blue field with gold stars and a fringe border.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Antoinette Polk, daughter of Andrew Jackson Polk of Ashwood Hall, was sixteen years old and visiting her cousins in Columbia when she heard that Union Gen. John T. Wilder&#8217;s &#8220;Lightning Brigade&#8221; was approaching. Knowing that there were Confederate soldiers recuperating at her home, she jumped on her horse and raced home in time to warn the soldiers. When Colonel Nathan Bedford Forrest heard of Antoinette&#8217;s bravery, he gave her this banner captured from Union Gen. Abel Streight&#8217;s Brigade in May 1864.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865; Flags</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Capturing the Flag; The Persistence of Memory</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States--Tennessee--Columbia</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact the Maury County Archives.</dc:rights>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jp2</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Maury County Archives</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/49</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>