<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:identifier>shades_tsla_0032.tif</dc:identifier>
<dc:title>Designs for Gate and Stone Fence</dc:title>
<dc:title>Chattanooga National Cemetery, Design for Gates and Stone Fence</dc:title>
<dc:date>ca. 1863</dc:date>
<dc:description>Three separate drawings on one sheet done in a scale of 1/2 inch to 1 foot. The drawings show a stone wall, with a wooden gate, and stone or concrete gate posts mounted into a wood and rubble below-ground structure, which is shown in a detail.</dc:description>
<dc:description>This engineering drawing, which was found in the papers of William Alonzo Wainright, United States Assistant Quartermaster, 1861-1870, shows a design apparently intended for the Chattanooga National Cemetery, where re-burial of Union casualties began, under the command of General George H. Thomas, on 25 November 1863.  Drawn in ink on paper with fancy block lettering, three separate views  illustrate  a stone wall supported by an embankment, a wide wooden gate with a smaller gate door, and either stone or concrete gateposts to be buried below grade in a wooden structure made from timbers arranged as crossed rectangles. During Wainright's tenure, the Quartermaster Department of the U.S. Army oversaw the creation of national cemeteries, which entailed retrieving and identifying bodies and reinterring them on newly landscaped burial grounds  at Knoxville, Murfreesboro, Atlanta, and Chattanooga.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Cemeteries--Union</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>The Persistence of Memory</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Wainright, William Alonzo; Thomas, George H.</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States--Tennessee--Chattanooga</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact the Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives.</dc:rights>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jp2</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/151</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>