<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:identifier>shades_loc_0041.tif</dc:identifier>
<dc:creator>Mathews, Alfred Edward, 1831-1874</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Charge of the first brigade, commanded by Col. M.B. Walker, on the Friday evening of the battle of Stone River &#8230;</dc:title>
<dc:title>Stones River, Battle of</dc:title>
<dc:source>Cin[cinnati], O[hio] : Middleton, Strobridge &amp; Co. Lith.,</dc:source>
<dc:date>[186?]</dc:date>
<dc:format>50.1 x 66.7 cm.</dc:format>
<dc:description>A winter scene with leafless trees and cedars in which two lines of Union soldiers advance toward a line of men positioned on the left at the edge of the forest.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The Battle of Stones River near Murfreesboro, Tennessee, took place around dawn on December 31, 1862 and on and off through January 2, 1863. Much of it centered in the Round Forest area, which would become the site for Hazen&#8217;s Monument, one of the earliest Civil War memorials to be built on a battlefield. While considered by many to be a draw, General Bragg&#8217;s withdrawal allowed General Rosecrans to claim victory for the North. The timing was critical for the Union victory, as northern morale was low in the days following a disastrous loss at Fredericksburg, Virginia.  This important Confederate defeat also reinforced the promise and raised hopes for President Lincoln's Emancipation Proclamation issued on 1 January 1863.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Stones River, Battle of, Murfreesboro, Tenn., 1862-1863; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Campaigns &amp; battles</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Making Music; The Persistence of Memory</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Murfreesboro</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jp2</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Library of Congress Prints and Photographs Division Washington, D.C. 20540 USA</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/16</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>