<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:identifier>shades_cpl_0002.tif</dc:identifier>
<dc:title>Adolph Ochs</dc:title>
<dc:description>Head and shoulders photographic portrait in black and white of Ochs at about age 65.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Adolph Ochs, who purchased a floundering Chattanooga newspaper in 1877, and parlayed his business success into the acquisition of the New York Times in 1896,  was one of many who seized opportunity during the post Civil War era in Chattanooga. Ochs, who was raised in Knoxville, had experienced life in that divided city during the war. Even though his father Julius had served in the Union army, his mother, Bertha Levy, who had grown up on a plantation in the Deep South, remained loyal to the Confederacy. In Chattanooga, Adolph Ochs became a prominent member of Chattanooga society, chairing one of the South's earliest Blue-Gray reunions and supporting the formation of the Chickamauga-Chattanooga National Battlefield Park as well as taking a leadership role by purchasing land to preserve Point Park. A Civil War museum bearing his name stands in the park today. </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Ochs, Adolph S. -- (Adolph Simon), -- 1858-1935 </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>The Persistence of Memory; Building a Future through Opportunity</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States--Tennessee--Chattanooga; United States--Tennessee--Lookout Mountain</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>1880-1889</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact the Chattanooga Hamilton County Bicentennial Library.</dc:rights>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jp2</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Chattanooga Hamilton County Bicentennial Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/138</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>