<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:identifier>lc_3b12651u.tif</dc:identifier>
<dc:title>James Walker and Theodore Davis, Civil War artists, full-length portrait, seated on camp stools, facing each other</dc:title>
<dc:title>Special Artists James Walker and Theodore Davis</dc:title>
<dc:date>[ca. 1864]</dc:date>
<dc:description>Two men seated on camp stools face each other in a tent-like area, smoking. Both men wear coats, light-colored trousers, and knee-high leather boots.  At upper right is a series of holes, possibly bullet holes. Card is signed on reverse: "Very Truly Yours, James Walker."</dc:description>
<dc:description>James Walker (1819-1889) and Theodore R. Davis (1840-1894) were "Special Artists" for news magazines such as Harper's Weekly and Frank Leslie's Illustrated Weekly, illustrating activities at the front. This carte-de-visite is thought to have been made in Chattanooga. While their images were published contemporaneously with the events they depicted, both men are also known to have created later works of art based on their war-time experiences.  </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Walker, James, 1819-1889; Davis, Theodore R., 1840-1894; Artists; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Communications; Group portraits; Portrait photographs</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>The Persistence of Memory; Visualizing the War</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact the Library of Congress.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>LC-USZ62-65086 (b&amp;w film copy neg.)</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>Still Image</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jp2</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Library of Congress</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/20</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>