<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:creator>O'Sullivan, Timothy (1840-1882)</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Gettysburg, Pa. Alfred R. Waud, artist of Harper's Weekly, sketching on battlefield</dc:title>
<dc:title>Waud, Alfred R. (1828-1891) sketching on battlefield at  Gettysburg</dc:title>
<dc:date>1863</dc:date>
<dc:description>This is the left side of a stereograph. It shows a bearded man in dark jacket and light-colored trousers and boots. He is wearing a flat-topped hat with a wide brim, seated on a rock and balancing a sketchpad on his upraised right thigh and knee.</dc:description>
<dc:description>This photograph of British-born artist Alfred Rudolph Waud (1828-1891), a special artist for Harper's Weekly, was taken by Timothy H. O'Sullivan (1840-1882) at Gettysburg. He studied at the Government School of Design in London, then emigrated to the US in 1850. Waud executed action sketches for the New York Illustrated News in 1860 and for Harper's Weekly from 1861 to 1865, covering a great deal of action in the eastern theater as he followed the Union Army of the Potomac. Since photographic reproduction was not yet possible for newspapers, battles were often covered by such sketches, which were quickly converted into wood engravings for publication. Waud continued to produce editorial artwork for Harper's and Century Magazine in the post-war decades.  The Library of Congress owns an extensive collection of Waud drawings and sketches.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Artists; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Pictorial works; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Portraits; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Battlefields</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Building a Future</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States--Pennsylvania--Gettysburg</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:identifier>http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.pnp/cwpb.00074</dc:identifier>
<dc:publisher>Library of Congress</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/246</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>