<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:creator>Ladies of Philadelphia</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Sewanee Flag</dc:title>
<dc:title>Flag Used during Founding and Dedication of the University of the South</dc:title>
<dc:date>1851</dc:date>
<dc:description>United States flag with thirteen red and white alternating bars, blue field with 13 stars surrounded by a circle of 18, and a gold fringe border. The flag is faded and several sections of fringe are missing.</dc:description>
<dc:description>This presentation flag, which bears the 31 stars of the United States after admission of California in 1851, was carried in the University of the South's initial founding ceremony, which included a patriotic procession on Lookout Mountain on July 4, 1857. It was also used at the dedication marking the University's permanent location on October 10, 1860. Although founded three years earlier by Bishops Leonidas Polk and James Hervey Otey, a permanent location was not obtained until just before the Civil War. The war and its aftermath delayed the start of classes at the University until 1867.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Flags; University of the South</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Capturing the Flag</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States--Tennessee--Sewanee</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>1850-1859</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact the University of the South, Jessie Ball duPont Library.</dc:rights>
<dc:type>Digital image</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpg</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>University of the South</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/215</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>