<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:creator>Davis, Theodore (1840-1894)</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Chattanooga from the Artists Camp</dc:title>
<dc:title>Working at Easel</dc:title>
<dc:date>1864</dc:date>
<dc:description>Black and white scene of a man standing at an easel on a wooded hillside in the  lower right section of image. The  landscape he is sketching has a river bend and a low hill.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Theodore Davis and James Walker were two of the most prolific "Special Artists" working in the Chattanooga and Lookout Mountain area for Harpers Weekly and other publications during the Civil War. Here, Davis depicts a fellow artist, possibly Walker, painting a bend in the Tennessee River with the city of Chattanooga featured behind a low hill. After the Confederate defeats of Lookout Mountain and Missionary Ridge in November 1863, the path to Atlanta was opened for Union forces, who would have been on the move in 1864. Wagons move across a pontoon bridge toward Chattanooga. </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Chattanooga (Tenn.), Battle of; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Art and the war</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Visualizing the War</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States--Tennessee--Chattanooga; United States--Tennessee--Lookout Mountain</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. Any reproduction, even for student use, should be labeled with the accompanying credit line as well as the name of the lending institution. Research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images must be sent directly to the institution that holds the item (i.e., "contributing institution").</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>1991.044.003</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jp2</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Chattanooga History Center</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/210</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>