<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:identifier>shades_harp_0004</dc:identifier>
<dc:creator>Wood, Thomas Waterman (1823-1903)</dc:creator>
<dc:title>The Contraband, the Recruit, and the Veteran</dc:title>
<dc:date>1867</dc:date>
<dc:description>The paintings depicted in these engravings were painted in 1866. The caption indicates that they were photographed for the magazine by "Rockwood." (?).</dc:description>
<dc:description>Based on the titles, these three images of an African American man portray him as a contraband in ragged clothes, as a recruit with a new uniform and gun over his shoulder, and as a wounded veteran.</dc:description>
<dc:description>This page from Harper's Weekly May 4, 1867, describes three paintings that Wood had on display at the National Academy of Design in New York. According to the text, they were "made from studies in Tennessee during the late war." Wood was elected an Associate of the National Academy of Design, perhaps on the basis of these works, and moved to New York. He became a full member of the Academy in 1871. In later years he served as President of the National Academy as well as the American Watercolor Society.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--African Americans; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Pictorial works</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Building a Future Through Opportunity; Walking A Fine Line</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Nashville</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>1860-69</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact HarpWeek.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:source>Harper's Weekly</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/280</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>