<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:identifier>shades_mccl_0006.jpg</dc:identifier>
<dc:creator>Shaver, Samuel M. (1816-1878)</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Susan Penniman Dickinson</dc:title>
<dc:date>ca. 1855</dc:date>
<dc:description>The portrait shows a seated woman with a red drape at left and a house at right. She appears to be in young middle age and wears a cameo and lace collar and cuffs.</dc:description>
<dc:description>This painting portrays Susan Penniman Dickinson, a native of Massachusetts, was married Perez Dickinson in Suffolk County, Massachusetts in 1845. The house in downtown Knoxville where they most likely lived with Dickinson's  brother-in-law James Estabrook and his family appears to be shown in the background. This may be a posthumous portrait. Susan Penniman Dickinson died in 1846. Dickinson purchased the house from Estabrook in 1851. The portraitist, Flavius Fisher, who had grown up in East Tennessee, is known to have studied in Philadelphia until about 1850 and was working in Richmond by 1855.  His crayon drawing of Annie White, Dickinson's niece, is thought to have been made about 1857.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Dickinson, Susan Penniman -- Portraits; Women</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Taking Care of Business</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States--Tennessee--Knoxville</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library.</dc:rights>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jp2</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/50</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>