<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:identifier>shades_tsm_0021.tif</dc:identifier>
<dc:creator>Chambers, George W.</dc:creator>
<dc:title>In the Tennessee Mountains, 1887</dc:title>
<dc:date>1887</dc:date>
<dc:description>It depicts a late summer scene in which an elderly woman standing in a garden leaning on a hoe. In the garden are cabbages and tomatoes, a shock of corn stalks is visible at the edge of the garden where there are also flowers blooming. There are two cabins in the background, one of which appears to be in deteriorating condition.</dc:description>
<dc:description>George W. Chambers (b. 1857) taught in Nashville at the Watkins Institute beginning in 1885 and at the Nashville School of Art in the 1890s. A native of St. Louis, Missouri, Chambers had studied under Carl Gutherz  (1844-1907) at the St. Louis School of Fine Arts and under Jean Leon Gerome in Paris in 1880.
He may have known Gilbert Gaul (1855-1917) who was living in Van Buren County in the 1880s on an inherited farm with outbuildings of a similar design to those in this painting. Cabbages were an important crop for 19th century farmers and were a particular staple of Americans of German descent, who used the vegetable in cooking and pickling. Flowers around the perimeter of the garden were planted to attract useful bees. In the background a pumpkin is visible, set against the fence to support its massive vines.  The time of year is probably mid to late fall based on the size of the pumpkin.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Gardens; Older people; Women</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Holding Fast to Beauty; The Persistence of Memory</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States--Tennessee</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>1880-1889</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact Tennessee State Museum.</dc:rights>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jp2</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Tennessee State Museum</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/52</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>