<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:identifier>shades_tsm_0006.tif</dc:identifier>
<dc:creator>Shaver, Samuel (1816-1878)</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Portrait of Joseph Alexander Mabry, Jr.</dc:title>
<dc:title>Mabry, Joseph Alexander, portrait</dc:title>
<dc:date>circa 1862</dc:date>
<dc:description>Portrait of a middle aged man with reddish brown hair and side whiskers dressed in formal clothing, seated in a red chair, and posed against a column base to his left.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Joseph Alexander Mabry, Jr. (1826-1882), a wealthy Knoxvillian who outfitted a Confederate regiment at the start of the Civil War, swore an oath of loyalty to the Union after federal troops occupied the city. Founder of the Knoxville and Kentucky Railroad, Mabry was first and foremost a businessman. He had substantial landholdings in and around Knoxville. His fashionable country house on the outskirts of the city's east side proved a strategic location. Mabry's Hill was fortified during the war and used by both sides. Artist Samuel Shaver moved to Knoxville in 1859. He is known to have painted portraits of a number of distinguished East Tennessee individuals. Here he portrays Mabry has a man of means in an iconic pose with the trappings of wealth.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Portraits; Businessmen</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Taking Care of Business; Visualizing the War; Walking a Fine Line</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Railroads</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States--Tennessee--Knoxville</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact the Tennessee State Museum.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>81.246.1 (Confed)</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jp2</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Tennessee State Museum</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/125</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>