<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:identifier>shades_mccl_0005</dc:identifier>
<dc:creator>Knaffl &amp; Bro</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Battle of Fort Saunders [sic]</dc:title>
<dc:title>Souvenir Card, Knoxville, 1890</dc:title>
<dc:source>S.B. Newman</dc:source>
<dc:date>1890</dc:date>
<dc:description>Card printed with text in blue ink on gray paper. Card image is a photograph of a painting that is referred to in text on verso as: "painting 8 x 20 feet, on view at 242 Gay Street" and inscribed "Photo by Knaffl &amp; Bro From Painting" in lower right corner.</dc:description>
<dc:description>This souvenir card was apparently created for a reunion of the Battle of Fort Sanders (name is mis-spelled Saunders) in Knoxville on 7, 8, &amp; 9 October 1890. It features a photograph, signed by local photographers Knaffl &amp; Bro., of a panoramic painting (perhaps by Lloyd Branson). Branson is known to have painted at least one painting showing the battle, which is shown here as if seen from a Confederate fortification on the opposite side of the river.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Reunions; Panoramic Photographs; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Pictorial Works; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Battlefields; Fort Sanders (Knoxville, Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>The Persistence of Memory</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States--Tennessee--Knoxville</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>1890-1899</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images , contact the Frank H. Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images , contact the McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/272</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>