<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:identifier>shades_tsm_0001.tif</dc:identifier>
<dc:creator>Cooper, William Browning (1811-1900)</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Portrait of James H. Otey</dc:title>
<dc:date>ca. 1855</dc:date>
<dc:description>Portrait of a dark-haired, stern-faced man of middle age, wearing clerical clothing consisting of a white smock with billowing sleeves and a black neck sash draped over the shoulders.</dc:description>
<dc:description>James Hervey Otey was the first Episcopal Bishop of Tennessee. While living in Columbia, Tennessee, he helped organize  the Ashwood Episcopal Church and the Columbia Female Institute with his close friend Leonidas Polk. Polk and his several brothers,  cousins of President James K. Polk, were prominent and wealthy plantation owners in the Ashwood district outside of Columbia.  Leonidas Polk enlisted Otey in founding the University of the South in 1857. Polk, who was serving as Bishop of the Southwest Territory and living in Louisiana when the Civil War broke out, joined the Confederate Army. Neither he nor Otey lived to see the opening of the University where they had hoped to provide a classical education for young southern gentlemen.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Otey, James Hervey, 1800-1863 -- Portraits; Episcopal Church -- Tennessee -- Bishops</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Holding Fast to Beauty; Capturing the Flag </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Episcopal Church; University of the South (Sewanee); Columbia Female Institute; Polk, Leonidas</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States--Tennessee--Columbia</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>1850-1859</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact the Tennessee State Museum.</dc:rights>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jp2</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Tennessee State Museum</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/155</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>