<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:identifier>shades_tsm_0025.jpg</dc:identifier>
<dc:creator>Calvert, Peter Ross</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Miniature Portrait of Gen. G.P. Thruston</dc:title>
<dc:date>circa 1875</dc:date>
<dc:description>Oval miniature painting of a man in young middle age, shown in bust view, facing to his left, with light brown hair and mustache, wearing a light-colored jacket, white shirt with  pointed standing collar, and silk cravat.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Artist Peter Ross Calvert (1855-1931), an Englishman, studied art in London before arriving in Nashville in the 1870s. He specialized in portrait miniatures and photography. This painting shows Brigadier General Gates P. Thruston, a Union veteran of Stones River and Chickamauga who settled in Nashville and began a law practice after the Civil War. Thruston, a collector of art, antiquities, and geological specimens, became a leader in the cultural community. He was active in founding the Nashville Art Association and a leading member of the Tennessee Historical Society.  He took a leading role in the historical exhibitions at the Tennessee Centennial Exposition and was an honored speaker at Civil War reunions of the 1890s.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Thruston, Gates Phillips, 1835-1912 -- Portraits; Portrait miniatures, American</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Building a Future Through Opportunity</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Artists; Tennessee Historical Society; Nashville Art Association</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>1870-79</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact the Tennessee State Museum.</dc:rights>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpg</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Tennessee State Museum</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/148</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>