<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:identifier>shades_polk_0005.jpg</dc:identifier>
<dc:title>Polk Place Interior</dc:title>
<dc:title>Hallway or Corridor in Polk Place</dc:title>
<dc:description>This photograph shows what appears to be a hallway or corridor leading into the large room depicted in the other photograph taken at the same time. It appears cluttered and possibly underkept, indicating it may have been taken in the later years of her life.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Polk Place, on Capitol Hill, was remodeled by President and Mrs. James K. Polk to serve as a retirement residence after he left Washington when his term concluded in 1848. Polk died 15 June 1849. His portrait is visible in this photograph at right. Sarah Childress Polk resided at Polk Place during the Civil War and continued to live in the home until her death on 14 August 1891. She remained publicly neutral during the war and was known for her hospitality. The layout of the painting on the left wall suggests that this might be the reception room in Polk Place, as shown in the 1880 Frank Leslie's newspaper image shown in this section.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Polk, Sarah Childress, -- 1803-1891 -- Homes and haunts; Polk, James K. -- (James Knox), -- 1795-1849 -- Homes and Haunts</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Interiors; Furniture</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Holding Fast to Beauty</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact James K. Polk Ancestral Home.</dc:rights>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jp2</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>James K. Polk Ancestral Home</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/86</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>