<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:identifier>shades_obln_0001.jpg</dc:identifier>
<dc:creator>Lewis, Edmonia (1845-1907)</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Bust of James Peck Thomas</dc:title>
<dc:title>Thomas, James Peck, portrait</dc:title>
<dc:date>1874</dc:date>
<dc:description>This carved white marble bust-length portrait of a middle-aged man with mustache wearing a suit coat, vest, collarless shirt, and tie is mounted on a pedestal.</dc:description>
<dc:description>James Peck Thomas (b. 1827)  was the son of Sally Thomas, a slave born in Virginia (1787-1850), and John C. Catron, a Nashville attorney. Sally Thomas and her two older sons came to Nashville to  live on lands owned by the Thomas family around 1817. Although still a slave, Sally Thomas was able rent a house in the city and take in laundry for pay. She guaranteed the future of her oldest son by sending him to work for a barge captain who acted as intermediary to purchase his freedom.  And she persuaded prominent Nashville attorney Ephraim Hubbard Foster to "purchase" her younger son James with her money, thus ensuring that he could remain in Nashville after an 1834 ruling that all free blacks had to leave the state. In 1851, Foster posted bond for James in order to guarantee his good behavior.  James, who had worked as a barber in Nashville, ultimately made his fortune in real estate in St. Louis. In 1873, he visited Edmonia Lewis at her studio in Rome and commissioned this portrait bus</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Thomas, James Peck, 1827-1913 -- Portraits; African Americans</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Building A Future Through Opportunity</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>African American women artists; African American women sculptors</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>1870-1879</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact the Allen Memorial Art Museum, Oberlin College.</dc:rights>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpg</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/305</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>