<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:creator>Cooper, W(ashington) B(ogart), 1802-1888</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Portrait of Carrie McGavock</dc:title>
<dc:date>1848</dc:date>
<dc:description>Portrait of a young dark-haired woman in an off the shoulder dress with lace sleeves seated in front of a red curtain and next to a round marble-topped table.</dc:description>
<dc:description>It is possible that this portrait was done to commemorate the marriage of Carrie Elizabeth Winder (1829-1905) to John McGavock in 1848. Their plantation home, Carnton, on the outskirts of Franklin, Tennessee, was used as a hospital after the Battle of Franklin on 30 November 1864. Carrie McGavock not only oversaw the care of the wounded in and around her house, she was responsible for making sure that nearly 1500 Confederates were reinterred in a cemetery on the McGavock property. She has been immortalized in a fictional portrayal, The Widow of the South, by author Robert Hicks.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Portraits; Women</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>women; cemeteries</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Capturing the Flag; The Persistence of Memory</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States--Tennessee--Franklin</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>1840-1849</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact Carnton / Battle of Franklin Trust</dc:rights>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpg</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Carnton / Battle of Franklin Trust</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/220</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>