<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:identifier>shades_mccl_0012.tif</dc:identifier>
<dc:title>Island Home, Dickinson Residence</dc:title>
<dc:title>Perez Dickinson Home and Gardens</dc:title>
<dc:date>ca. 1887</dc:date>
<dc:description>Two-story mansion with well-dressed men, women, and children strolling in gardens and pathways. There are two horse and buggies parked out front.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Island Home was the country residence of prominent Knoxville businessman Perez Dickinson (1813-1901).  The Massachusetts-born Dickinson, who remained loyal to the Union, left Knoxville during the early years of the Civil War, returning to resume his partnership in the mercantile establishment of Cowan, McClung &amp; Company after the war. He also purchased Williams Island and 164 acres near the confluence of the Holston and French Broad rivers, constructing the house he called Island Home around 1870. </dc:description>
<dc:subject>Dickinson, Perez -- Homes and haunts; Architecture, Domestic; Gardens</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Children; Gardens; Houses; Women</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Taking Care of Business</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States--Tennessee--Knoxville; United States--Tennessee--Island Home</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>1880-1889</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact the McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library.</dc:rights>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jp2</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/54</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>