<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:identifier>shades_winc_0001</dc:identifier>
<dc:title>Rosella and Sylvester Winchester</dc:title>
<dc:title>Portrait of Sylvester Winchester and his wife, Rosella </dc:title>
<dc:date>1861?</dc:date>
<dc:description>Formal portrait of a seated middle-aged couple. The woman has her dark hair pulled back away from her face, hands clasped in front, and is wearing a dark pattered dress with round white collar. The gentleman has curly hair, wears a suit with vest and watch chain, and is seated under a patterned drape with his left hand resting upon several books on a table. </dc:description>
<dc:description>Sylvester Winchester enlisted in the federal army for a three-year period at the age of 52. He entered into infantry service as a musician on 4 October 1861, leaving his wife, Rosella, and seven children at home in Ohio.This formal studio portrait, which shows the Winchesters as a prosperous pair, may have been taken to mark his departure. Unfortunately, Winchester did not return from war, for he died on 21 December 1862, on the first day of fighting at the Battle of Stones River. </dc:description>
<dc:subject>United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865; Musicians; Women</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Making Music</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States--Tennessee--Murfreesboro</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. This image may be subject to copyright.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Private collection</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/309</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>