<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:creator>Quintard, Charles Todd (1824-1898)</dc:creator>
<dc:title>"Balm for the Weary and the Wounded"</dc:title>
<dc:title>Quintard Prayer Book "Balm for the Weary and Wounded"</dc:title>
<dc:source>Columbia, S.C.: Evans &amp; Cogswell</dc:source>
<dc:date>1864</dc:date>
<dc:description>Interior cover bears dedication "with warmest regards" to Mrs. A. O. Harris from C.T. Quintard.</dc:description>
<dc:description>After the death of Bishop James H. Otey in 1863, Doctor C.T. Quintard became the second Episcopal Bishop of Tennessee. During the Civil War, he served as a chaplain with an elite group of Confederate soldiers, the Rock City Guards, which was organized from Nashville and the surrounding area. This book was printed in Columbia, South Carolina, apparently to be issued to Confederate soldiers. According to tradition, a copy was found in the jacket of Leonidas Polk after his death at Pine Mountain, Georgia, on June 4, 1864. After the war, Quintard was appointed Vice-Chancellor of the University of the South, Sewanee, Tennessee.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Devotional literature; Prayer books; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Religious aspects; University of the South (Sewanee)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>The Persistence of Memory</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Episcopal Church; University of the South (Sewanee); Columbia Female Institute; Polk, Leonidas</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States--Tennessee--Sewanee</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact the University of the South, Jessie Ball duPont Library.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>University of the South</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/213</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>