<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:identifier>shades_loc_0048.tif</dc:identifier>
<dc:title>Senator Isham G. Harris from Tenn.</dc:title>
<dc:title>Harris, Isham G., Senator</dc:title>
<dc:date>[between 1865 and 1880]</dc:date>
<dc:description>This glass negative is part of the Brady-Handy collection, which contains images taken in the studio of Mathew Brady in Washington, D.C.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Half-length portrait of a balding man seated facing the camera.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Isham Green Harris, from Paris, Tennessee, was Governor of Tennessee at the outbreak of the Civil War. In many respects, he was responsible for constructing a legislative process by which the state government moved to secede from the Union, even though citizens of the state were almost evenly divided on the issue. Harris organized a state militia that he turned over to the Confederate Army and served as an advisor to the Army, seeing action at Shiloh and other conflicts. He returned to Tennessee politics in 1877 and was elected to the United States Senate, in which he served until 1895.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Harris, Isham G. -- (Isham Green), 1818-1897; Portrait photographs</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact the Library of Congress.</dc:rights>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jp2</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Library of Congress</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/167</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>