<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:identifier>shades_ccnp_0003.jpg</dc:identifier>
<dc:creator>Walker, James</dc:creator>
<dc:title>The Battle Above the Clouds</dc:title>
<dc:title>Battle of Lookout Mountain</dc:title>
<dc:date>1874</dc:date>
<dc:format>13 x 30 feet</dc:format>
<dc:description>This painting shows troops in the foreground massed on a plain below a mountain with some cloud cover. At the base of the mountain, troops can be seen charging forward and clouds of smoke from gun and cannon fire can be seen across the horizon.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Englishman James Walker, 1819-1889, was living in Mexico City during the U.S. - Mexican War and later did a series of panoramic paintings depicting it. He created works during and after the Civil War, including several versions of the Battle of Lookout Mountain. A smaller version, done in 1864, was commissioned by Gen. Joseph Hooker, U.S.A., who is depicted on the white horse at left. Artists like Walker created and often travelled large show piece works like this one to satisfy public audiences in the decades following the war.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Campaigns &amp; battles</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>The Persistence of Memory</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States--Tennessee--Lookout Mountain; United States--Tennessee--Chattanooga</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>1870-1879</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact www.nps.gov or Chickamauga and Chattanooga National Military Park.</dc:rights>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpg</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Chickamauga and Chattanooga National Military Park, Fort Oglethorpe, Georgia</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/85</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>