<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:identifier>shades_chc_0001b.jpg</dc:identifier>
<dc:creator>Dorr, F.W.</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Chattanooga and Its Approaches</dc:title>
<dc:title>Map of Chattanooga, Tennessee, and Its Appro(a)ches Showing the Union and Rebel Works before and during the Battles of 23rd, 24th, and 25th November, 1863</dc:title>
<dc:description>Map showing the city of Chattanooga and a section of the Tennessee River,as well as some of the topography, including Lookout Mountain and Missionary Ridge.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Inscription under the title notes: Surveyed under the direction of Brig. Gen. Wm. F. Smith, Chief Engineer of the Military Division of the Mississippi, during parts of November and December 1863 by F.W. Dorr, U.S. Coast Survey. The map, which was apparently completed after the Battle of Lookout Mountain, is both informative and artistically rendered and labeled with names of fortifications. It includes railroad lines and the downtown Chattanooga street grid.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Maps; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Transportation; Railroads</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Visualizing the War</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States--Tennessee-Chattanooga</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>1860-69</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact the Chattanooga History Center.</dc:rights>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jp2</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Chattanooga History Center</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/122</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>