<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:identifier>shades_chee_0006.tif</dc:identifier>
<dc:title>Polk Place</dc:title>
<dc:title>Polk Place with Tomb of President James K. Polk</dc:title>
<dc:description>This photograph was published in History of Homes and Gardens of Tennessee in 1936. It shows the facade of Polk Place with the tomb in the front yard on the right side.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Polk Place, on Capitol Hill, was remodeled by President and Mrs. James K. Polk to serve as a retirement residence after he left Washington when his term concluded in 1848. Polk died 15 June 1849. The state of Tennessee paid for the erection of a tomb on the grounds of Polk Place. Sarah Childress Polk resided at Polk Place during the Civil War and continued to live in the home until her death on 14 August 1891. After which, the home was sold and the tomb was moved to the grounds of the Tennessee State Capitol.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Polk, James K.--(James Knox),--1795-1849--Tomb; Polk, James K.--(James Knox),--1795-1849 -- Homes and haunts; Polk, Sarah Childress, -- 1803-1891 -- Homes and haunts; Tombs &amp; sepulchral monuments; Architecture, domestic</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Holding Fast to Beauty</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact Cheekwood Botanical Garden &amp; Museum of Art.</dc:rights>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jp2</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Cheekwood Botanical Garden &amp; Museum of Art</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/66</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>