<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:identifier>shades_berr_0001.jpg</dc:identifier>
<dc:creator>Weeden, Maria Howard</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Uncle Man</dc:title>
<dc:title>Wessyngton Plantation, former slave, Emmanuel Washington</dc:title>
<dc:date>ca. 1890</dc:date>
<dc:description>Depicts an elderly African American man with short white beard and wearing a cloth cap and plain buttoned shirt with pointed collar. This accomplished portrait was done in soft tones of gray and brown with dark shading of facial features.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Maria Howard Weeden, 1846-1905, was born in Huntsville, Alabama. She developed her natural artistic abilities while attending Tuskegee Female Methodist College just after the Civil War. Weeden, best known for her sympathetic images of former slaves, also spent time in Tennessee. This portrait is of Emmanuel Washington, who remained at Wessyngton in Cedar Hill, Tennessee after the Civil War where he was employed as a cook for the Washington family.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>African Americans; Older people; Portraits</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Building a Future Through Opportunity</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Women artists</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States--Tennessee--Cedar Hill</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>1890-1899</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact John F. Baker, Jr, author, The Washingtons of Wessyngton Plantation. (New York: Simon &amp; Schuster, 2008), http://www.wessyngton.com/.</dc:rights>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jpg</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Private Collection, courtesy of John F. Baker, Jr.</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/65</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>