<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:identifier>shades_mccl_0011.tif</dc:identifier>
<dc:creator>Burnand, Auguste (ca. 1835-1860)</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Maison Dickenson, Knoxville, 1856</dc:title>
<dc:title>Swiss American Sketchbook, August Burnand 008</dc:title>
<dc:date>1856</dc:date>
<dc:description>Italianate villa in landscape setting.</dc:description>
<dc:description>This drawing, whose title mis-spells Dickinson's name, is part of the "Swiss American Sketchbook" of Auguste Burnand. Burnand lived in the Swiss American community near Knoxville, Tennessee, from 1853-1860. The house depicted in the drawing once  belonged to Perez Dickinson. Dickinson, who grew up in Amherst, Massachusetts, followed his brother-in-law, Joseph Estabrook, principal of the Knoxville Female Academy, to Knoxville around 1830.  Dickinson lived in this Knoxville residence with Estabrook and his wife Nancy Dickinson, along with his sister and his mother, apparently purchasing it in 1851. Dickinson left Knoxville during the Civil War, but returned afterwards to resume his interest in the mercantile partnership of Cowan McClung, which included his brother-in-law, James H. Cowan,  and former confederates Frank H. and Charles J. McClung.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Dickinson, Perez --Homes and haunts; Architecture, Domestic</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Taking Care of Business</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Knoxville</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>1850-1859</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact the McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library.</dc:rights>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jp2</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/166</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>