<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:identifier>shades_bma_0005b</dc:identifier>
<dc:creator>Wyon, Leonard C(harles), (1826-1891)</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Prize Medal for Cotton from the Crystal Palace Exhibition, London, (awarded to Dr. Samuel Bond), 1851</dc:title>
<dc:title>Medal for Cotton, Great Exhibition of the Industry of All Nations, London, 1851</dc:title>
<dc:date>1851</dc:date>
<dc:description>This is the reverse side of the medal. It shows what appears to be a toga-clad Roman emperor placing a wreath on the head of a kneeling young woman, while four other women (perhaps representing virtues) stand behind her. The inscription: DISSOCIATA LOCIS CONCORDI PACE LIGAVIT  appears around the top edge of the medal. Type along the bottom edge includes the name of the artist who designed the medal: Leonard C. Wyon.  The name S.Bond is engraved on the edge of the medal.</dc:description>
<dc:description>This medal was awarded to Dr. Samuel Bond, a Memphis cotton producer, who, along with nine other Americans, including fellow Memphian John Pope, won prize medals in the category of "Vegetable and Animal Substances Chiefly Used in Manufactures" at the 1851 world's industrial fair held at the Crystal Palace in London. A commentary in the official catalogue of the exposition noted that all of the cotton on display came from countries other than Great Britain, and that the English writer hoped that soon "encouragement given to the growth of cotton in our Indian and colonial possessions  shall enable us to dispense with the slave-grown cotton of America." Reference: The Illustrated Exhibitor, A Tribute to the World's Industrial Jubilee (London: John Cassell, 1851), p. 485.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>cotton; slavery</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Taking Care of Business</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States--Tennessee--Memphis</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>1850-1859</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact Memphis Brooks Museum of Art</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>87.8</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:publisher>Memphis Brooks Museum of Art</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/291</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>