<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:identifier>shades_mccl_0001b.tif</dc:identifier>
<dc:creator>Schleier, T.M.</dc:creator>
<dc:title>View of Knoxville, TN, 1865. Part 2 of 4.</dc:title>
<dc:title>Knoxville, Tennessee, panoramic photograph, part 2.</dc:title>
<dc:date>1865</dc:date>
<dc:description>Slight overlap on scans.</dc:description>
<dc:description>This is the center left portion of the four-part photograph. It was taken from across a river and shows what appear to be farm fields extending down to the river, with some industrial outbuildings near the river. These fields are bounded on their upper edge by a road.  A substantial white house with multi-leveled rooftops sits on the opposite side of the road at upper right.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Theodore M. Schleier (1832-1908), a photographer born in Prussia, is known to have worked in Nashville during the period from 1859-1869 and in Knoxville during the 1870s and 1880s. In 1862, he married Caroline Knaffl, whose brothers ran a photography studio in Knoxville. Schleier's studio imprint, which indicated studio locations in Nashville, Knoxville, and Chattanooga, can be found on cartes-de-visite produced during the Civil War, including  portrait photographs of officers in the 1st United States Colored Troops Heavy Artillery, which was organized in Knoxville in 1864. This portion of Schleier's Knoxville panorama, taken from the south side of the Holston (Tennessee) River  shows a section of farmlands and riverside buildings between East Tennessee University and downtown Knoxville.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Cityscapes; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>The Persistence of Memory; Taking Care of Business; Walking a Fine Line;</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States--Tennessee--Knoxville</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact the McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library.</dc:rights>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jp2</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>McClung Historical Collection, Knox County Public Library</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/126</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>