<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:identifier>shades_tsm_0024.tif</dc:identifier>
<dc:title>Woodpecker Gorget</dc:title>
<dc:title>Shell ornament, incised designs of woodpeckers</dc:title>
<dc:description>Incised circular gorget cut from conch shell.  Has two drilled holes along edge through which the hanging cord was strung.  Also has four smaller drilled holes in the center encircled by three concentric circles and sun rays. The center sun emblem is then bordered by a square made up of 3 incised lines on each side.  At the corners, the lines curl around and under.  To the outside of the square are four woodpecker heads, one to each side of the square.  
 
Woodpecker gorget found by D. G. Charles in a stone box burial on the Buffalo River, near Ashland, Wayne County, Tennessee.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The pileated woodpecker symbolized war, while the looped-corner square represented the four cardinal directions and the rayed sun was associated with one of the principal deities of the Southeastern Ceremonial Complex. This gorget, which was published by General Gates P. Thruston on page 327 of his ANTIQUITIES OF TENNESSEE (1890), was included in the extensive collection of artifacts that he donated to Vanderbilt University.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Indian shell engraving -- Southern States</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Building a Future Through Opportunity</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States--Tennessee--Middle Tennessee</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images , contact the Tennessee State Museum.</dc:rights>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jp2</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Tennessee State Museum</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/181</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>