<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:identifier>shades_tsm_0008.tif</dc:identifier>
<dc:creator>Giers, Carl</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Photograph of Andrew Johnson in Masonic Regalia, 1869</dc:title>
<dc:date>1869</dc:date>
<dc:description>Formal portrait photograph with some hand-coloring showing Andrew Johnson dressed in a dark frock coat, with white sash across his chest from right shoulder to left hip, his left hand behind his back at waist, and his right hand on an ornate ceremonial dagger. A cap with ornamental braid sits on a stand at his right.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Taken in Nashville, in the final year of Johnson's term of office, this portrait of Andrew Johnson by photographer Carl C. Giers (1828-1877) may have been intended to bolster the President's stature after he survived impeachment by just one vote. Vice-President Johnson, who had assumed office after Lincoln's assassination in 1865, was resented by too quickly "reconstructing" the South--allowing former Confederates who took an oath of allegiance to the United States to regain property and position. And he seemed to look the other way as "black codes" that greatly restricted the activities of those who had been granted full citizenship by the passage of the Civil Rights Act of 1866 were put in place in many southern states.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Johnson, Andrew, 1808-1875 -- Portraits; Freemasonry</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Walking a Fine Line</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact the Tennessee State Museum.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier># 86.100.9</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jp2</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Tennessee State Museum</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/147</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>