<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:identifier>shades_tsm_0012.JPG</dc:identifier>
<dc:creator>Wood, Thomas Waterman (1823-1903)</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Portrait of Genevieve Morgan Williams</dc:title>
<dc:date>1861</dc:date>
<dc:description>Small child in a blue dress, seated on what appears to be a marble step, with a variety of cut flowers in her lap, holding up a sprig containing three red blossoms. A landscape with city is visible in the distance at far right.</dc:description>
<dc:description>This portrait depicts the granddaughter of Samuel Dold Morgan (1798-1880) a powerful Nashville industrialist who supplied percussion caps for the war effort and whose sons served in the Confederacy. Genevieve (1859-1915), who appears to be about two or three years of age, holds what appear to be Bleeding Heart blossoms in her left hand. At far right is a  distant view of the newly-completed Tennessee State Capitol, for which her grandfather served on the Building Commission. Genevieve's father, Robert N. Williams, was a physician who owned plantation lands in Arkansas. Like two of his wife's brothers, he served in the Confederate army. Unlike his Morgan brothers-in-law, Williams survived the war. Genevieve later married a Kentuckian and lived in Lexington, KY. This painting stayed in the family until 1985 when it was sold at auction;  soon afterwards it was purchased by the Tennessee State Museum. From 1859 until 1862, when he left the city for neutral Kentucky, artist Thomas Waterman Wood, a New Englander who had moved to the growing cosmopolitan city of Nashville to make a living as a portrait artist and genre painter, enjoyed the patronage of wealthy Nashvillians.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Williams, Genevieve Morgan, 1859-1915 -- Portraits; Girls</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Taking Care of Business; Walking a Fine Line</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Artists</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact the Tennessee State Museum.</dc:rights>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jp2</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Tennessee State Museum</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/140</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>