<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:identifier>shades_chc_0012.tif</dc:identifier>
<dc:title>Chattanooga Cordially Invites You to a Barbeque at Crawfish Springs, Walker County, Georgia September 20, 1889</dc:title>
<dc:title>Invitation to Barbeque Dedication of Chickamauga National Battlefield Park</dc:title>
<dc:date>1889</dc:date>
<dc:description>Several vignettes showing a uniformed Union and Confederate veteran preparing for a barbeque by selecting a pig and building a fire. Crossed pipes with the letters "CV" and "A of C" frame a scene with a train crossing an elevated track over a river with a waterwheel. The stars and stripes appears at left.  Two crawfish appear above text at bottom.</dc:description>
<dc:description>This barbeque, held at Crawfish Springs, Georgia, near Chattanooga, Tennessee, was the first joint Blue-Gray reunion organized in Tennessee. Veterans of the Army of the Cumberland, led during the war by Confederate General Rosecrans, reunited with Union soldiers near the site of the Battle of Chickamauga in September 1889. In 1890, Chickamauga was appropriated $325,000 as the first American battlefield to be preserved by Congress. The development of the area, including rail infrastructure, made the location, then called Crawfish Springs, an accessible and pleasant vacation spot.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Reunions; Railroads</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>The Persistence of Memory</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States--Tennessee--Chattanooga; United States--Georgia--Chickamauga</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>1880-1889</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jp2</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Chattanooga History Center</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/30</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>