<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:identifier>shades_haun_0002</dc:identifier>
<dc:creator>Richardson and Cox, engravers </dc:creator>
<dc:title>Hanging of Fry and Hensie near the Railroad, by Colonel Leadbetter</dc:title>
<dc:source>George W. Childs, Applegate &amp; Co., Philadelphia </dc:source>
<dc:date>1862</dc:date>
<dc:description>William G. Brownlow, Sketches of the Rise, Progress, and Decline of Secession; with a Narrative of Personal Adventures Among the Rebels (Philadelphia: George W. Childs, Applegate &amp; Co., 1862), p. 311 </dc:description>
<dc:description>Two men clad in shirts and trousers hang by ropes from tree branches. They are taunted by a man with a cane standing on a train platform next to a rail car while people watch from the  platform and peer out of the rail car windows.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Henry Fry and Jacob M. Hensie (Hinshaw) were among a group of five Union loyalists in East Tennessee who attempted to disrupt Confederate troop movements by destroying bridges along the East Tennessee &amp; Virginia and East Tennessee &amp; Georgia railroad lines on the night of November 8-9, 1861.  The "bridge burners," who believed they had the support of the Lincoln administration and that the United States Army was about to sweep into in East Tennessee and liberate it from Confederate authorities,  were executed for their actions. Master potter 
Christopher A. Haun, who was also among their number, was hanged in Knoxville on 10 December 1861.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>nited States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Destruction and Pillage--Union </dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Walking a Fine Line </dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States--Tennessee--Greeneville; United States--Tennessee--Knoxville </dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869</dc:coverage>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/278</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>