<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:identifier>shades_tsla_0023.tif</dc:identifier>
<dc:title>Samuel Dold Morgan</dc:title>
<dc:date>circa 1860</dc:date>
<dc:description>This photograph appears to show a large portrait of an elderly gentleman in a three-piece suit, posed in front of a large fluted column base and leaning against a stone pedestal with one hand in his pocket, the other holding a pair of glasses. His walking stick is hooked on the pedestal and there is a landscape scene of a rock bluff and trees in the background.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Samuel Dold Morgan (1798-1880) was a prominent Nashville industrialist who served on the Building Commission for the Tennessee State Capitol. During the Civil War, he served as Tennessee's Chairman of the Central Bureau of Military Supplies and also manufactured percussion caps for the Confederate army. He lost two of his sons in the war: Samuel Morgan Jr., and St. Clair McIntosh Morgan, a former West Point cadet married Ida Percy Pope, daughter of John Pope of Memphis.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Morgan, Samuel Dold, 1798-1880</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Taking Care of Business; Walking a Fine Line</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Tennessee State Capitol</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States--Tennessee--Nashville</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact the Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives.</dc:rights>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jp2</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/139</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>