<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:identifier>shades_rpw_0002.jpg</dc:identifier>
<dc:creator>Palmer, Samuel Bell</dc:creator>
<dc:title>Gay Street, Knoxville, Tenn. 1861</dc:title>
<dc:title>Simultaneous Recruiting for Confederate and Union Armies on Gay Street, 1861</dc:title>
<dc:date>ca. 1863</dc:date>
<dc:description>This drawing depicts a crowd gathered on Gay Street in Knoxville, Tennessee for the purposes of recruiting Union and Confederate soldiers.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The personal art of soldiers reveals not only their skills at carving or drawing but also what they felt most important to communicate. This drawing, which Palmer completed in 1863 while imprisoned at Camp Douglas, near Chicago, gives a vivid sense of how evenly split loyalties were in the city of Knoxville right after the secession vote, June 8, 1861, when a majority of Tennesseans voted to join the Confederacy.  A Confederate training camp was set up across from Old Gray cemetery and 400 soldiers were housed in Knoxville. Although young men in rural sections of East Tennessee were more likely to be Union loyalists, Palmer and others like him in the cities joined many sons of wealthy and prominent families, such as the McClung and Ramsey families in Knoxville, in signing up for the Confederacy. Many Confederate soldiers set down images of their war experiences, sent home illustrated letters, and kept journals. So also did Union troops, many of whom had never before ventured south.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Prisoners and prisons -- Pictorial works; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Recruiting &amp; enlistment</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Visualizing the War</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States -- Tennessee -- Knoxville</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869</dc:coverage>
<dc:language>eng</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact the East Tennessee Historical Society.</dc:rights>
<dc:publisher>Private Collection</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/40</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>