<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:identifier>shadesharv_0002a.jpg; shades_harv_0002b.jpg</dc:identifier>
<dc:creator>Vizetelly, Frank (1830-1883)</dc:creator>
<dc:title>General Pope's Division at the Levee, Cairo, Junction of the Mississippi &amp; Ohio rivers on its way from New Madrid to Reinforce General Halleck, near Corinth.</dc:title>
<dc:date>1862</dc:date>
<dc:description>Published as wood engraving in Illustrated London News, 31 May 1862</dc:description>
<dc:description>Steamer ships at dock at mid-distance, river and other shore in far distance. Soldiers and rail car on dock in foreground. Boats are the new Uncle Sam, Yankee, and Aleck Scott. Verso also includes sketches of: a "Western soldier", "Labourer on levee", and a "loafer", with the note, "These to fill up with."</dc:description>
<dc:description>Frank Vizetelly was a British artist and war reporter for the Illustrated London News. This drawing, which was done on or about April 20, 1862, comes from a collection in Harvard University's Houghton Library (MS Am 1585) that includes 29 Civil War drawings. This image of steamboats at Cairo, Illinois, on the Mississippi River, depicts Kentucky Brigadier General John Pope's Union army troops provisioning before heading south to Mississippi. It was published on May 31, 1862 (p. 554, volume 40, no. 1147) in the Illustrated London News.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Military personnel; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Art and the war</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Visualizing the War</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States--Illinois--Cairo</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>1860-1869</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact the Houghton Library, Harvard University.</dc:rights>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jp2</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Houghton Library, Harvard University</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/115</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>