<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:identifier>shades_chm_0002b.tif</dc:identifier>
<dc:creator>Philippoteaux, Paul</dc:creator>
<dc:title>General Grant Looking Over the Battlefield at Fort Donelson</dc:title>
<dc:title>General Grant at the Battle of Fort Donelson</dc:title>
<dc:date>ca. 1880</dc:date>
<dc:description>This painting shows a snowy landscape with Gen. U. S. Grant on horseback at center overlooking a sloping battlefield with cannon fire in the near distance and wooded hills and a river in the far distance. In the foreground is a broken tree, a dead and bleeding horse, a dead soldier in a pool of blood, and a wounded soldier being carried off by African Americans. Signed "P. (?) Philippoteaux" at lower right.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Paul Philippoteaux was a Frenchman who came to the United States in 1879 and painted historical images of the Civil War for American audiences. His first was the 27 foot high, 359 foot long Battle of Gettysburg Cyclorama first shown in Chicago in 1883. It now belongs to the National Park Service, Gettysburg National Military Park.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Fort Donelson (Tenn.) -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Campaigns &amp; battles; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Art and the war; Grant, Ulysses S. -- (Ulysses Simpson), -- 1822-1885</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>The Persistence of Memory</dc:subject>
<dc:coverage>United States--Tennessee--Fort Donelson; United States--Tennessee--Dover</dc:coverage>
<dc:coverage>1880-1889</dc:coverage>
<dc:rights>Images reproduced on this website are intended for individual, educational use only. For research inquiries about specific objects or requests for high resolution images, contact Chicago History Museum, http://www.chicagohs.org/.</dc:rights>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>image/jp2</dc:format>
<dc:publisher>Chicago History Museum</dc:publisher>
<dc:publisher>Digital Initiatives, James E. Walker Library, Middle Tennessee State University</dc:publisher>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15838.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/shades/id/134</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>