<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Suffragette, oh suffragette</dc:title>
<dc:description>The lyrics of this song lament the changes wrought by women's suffrage. The suffragette is portrayed as being "trapped in the politician's net" for Carrie Catt and Alice Paul. Her pure thoughts and poise had been replaced by course talk, and thorns left where roses grew."The proud South hangs her head in shame...Oh suffragette, you've tolled the bell, now wear the pants and work like hell."</dc:description>
<dc:description>The 19th Amendment to the U. S. Constitution granted women the right to vote. When the Tennessee General Assembly passed the ratification resolution on August 18, 1920, it gave the amendment the 36th and final state necessary for ratification. Suffragists and anti-suffragists lobbied furiously to secure votes during that intense summer in Nashville. The ratification resolution passed easily in the Tennessee State Senate on August 13, but the House of Representatives was deadlocked. When young Harry T. Burn of Niota changed his vote to support ratification of the 19th Amendment, he broke a tie in the House of Representatives and made history.</dc:description>
<dc:source>Library Broadside Collection, 1814-2010</dc:source>
<dcterms:references>http://sos.tn.gov/products/tsla/library-broadside-collection-1814-2010 </dcterms:references>
<dcterms:isPartOf>2007-035</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:instructionalMethod>5.46; US.18; Women's Suffrage and the 19th Amendment; Progressive Era</dcterms:instructionalMethod>
<dc:subject>Women -- Suffrage -- Tennessee; Constitutional amendments -- United States -- Ratification; Sex role -- United States -- 20th century; Catt, Carrie Chapman, 1859-1947; Paul, Alice, 1885-1977; Idealism, American; Southern states -- Intellectual life; Femininity</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Political organizations; Songs; Women's rights; Women's suffrage</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>33913</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>XLI-D-4, Box 5, Folder 5</dc:source>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Women's Suffrage in Tennessee</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dcterms:medium>Documents</dcterms:medium>
<dc:rights>Copyright not evaluated: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll27/id/73</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>