<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Letter from Catherine T. Kenny to Carrie Chapman Catt</dc:title>
<dc:description>Kenny, one of the 6th Congressional District chairpersons of the Tennessee Woman Suffrage Association, wrote to Carrie Chapman Catt about a meeting with Governor Albert H. Roberts about various suffrage issues. In 1919, Tennessee had passed legislation to allow women to vote in municipal and presidential elections, but it had not clarified whether or not women could vote in primary elections. At the time, Governor Roberts had been adamant that Tennessee law did not allow a special session for the ratification of the 19th Amendment. [He would later reconsider after substantial national pressure from Democratic leaders, including President Wilson.] Kenny believed that national Republicans had chosen Tennessee as their focus to "break the Solid South," and saw women's suffrage as a chance to "get the Negro women lined up." She informed Catt that this situation could hurt the women's suffrage movement in the south. Kenny went on to describe how African American women had worked with the white women, though they had a separate organization. In a recent election, they had "helped very decisively," noting that it was instead "illiterate white women in the cotton factory district" who were exploited. She praised the "intelligent and dignified demeanor" of the African American women, who - unlike their men - had stood against bribery and threats. Kenny wanted Catt to know "how we handled the negro women" and that they planned to "send a negro woman into every district" under the direction of the white organization. She wrote also of her pride in the victory for women's suffrage that Tennessee had won in earning presidential suffrage, accomplishing what their better organized and better funded sister states could not do.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The 19th Amendment to the U. S. Constitution granted women the right to vote. When the Tennessee General Assembly passed the ratification resolution on August 18, 1920, it gave the amendment the 36th and final state necessary for ratification. Suffragists and anti-suffragists lobbied furiously to secure votes during that intense summer in Nashville. The ratification resolution passed easily in the Tennessee State Senate on August 13, but the House of Representatives was deadlocked. When young Harry T. Burn of Niota changed his vote to support ratification of the 19th Amendment, he broke a tie in the House of Representatives and made history. Carrie Chapman Catt (1859-1947) was president of the National American Woman Suffrage Association (NAWSA). She came to Nashville during the summer of 1920 to support the efforts of Tennessee suffragists. Her leadership was a key factor in Tennessee becoming the "Perfect 36," the state that put the 19th Amendment over the top.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1920 January 27</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Kenny, Catherine Talty</dc:creator>
<dc:source>Carrie Chapman Catt Papers, 1916-1921</dc:source>
<dcterms:references>http://sos.tn.gov/products/tsla/catt-carrie-chapman-papers-1916-1921</dcterms:references>
<dcterms:isPartOf>72-119</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:instructionalMethod>5.46; US.18; Women's Suffrage and the 19th Amendment; Progressive Era</dcterms:instructionalMethod>
<dc:subject>Women -- Suffrage -- Tennessee; Constitutional amendments -- United States -- Ratification; Catt, Carrie Chapman, 1859-1948; Women -- Political activity -- United States; African Americans -- Suffrage -- United States</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Activists; Correspondence; Women's rights; Women's suffrage</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>42429</dc:identifier>
<dcterms:isFormatOf>1077</dcterms:isFormatOf>
<dc:source>I-J-2, Box 1, Folder 13</dc:source>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Women's Suffrage in Tennessee</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dcterms:medium>Correspondence</dcterms:medium>
<dc:rights>No copyright - United States: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll27/id/1042</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>