<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>League of Women Voters Convention Delegate Card and "Carry on!"</dc:title>
<dc:description>A card or ticket identifying Mrs. K. P. Wright as a delegate at the League of Women Voters convention. The convention took place May 18-19, 1920 in Nashville. Mrs. Wright was a member and secretary of the Belmont Civic Federation as well as Chairman of Publicity for the Tennessee Women's Democratic Headquarters. This page also contains a notice reminding women of their political commitments following passage of the 19th Amendment. One of the statements reads: "We owe it to Governor Roberts to secure his triumphal re-election. We remember that it was he who gave, not alone the women of Tennessee, but the women of the entire nation, the sacred privilege of the vote." Governor Albert H. Roberts called a special session of the Tennessee General Assembly to consider ratification of the 19th Amendment. Roberts lost his re-election campaign in 1920.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The 19th Amendment to the U. S. Constitution granted women the right to vote. When the Tennessee General Assembly passed the ratification resolution on August 18, 1920, it gave the amendment the 36th and final state necessary for ratification. Suffragists and anti-suffragists lobbied furiously to secure votes during that intense summer in Nashville. The ratification resolution passed easily in the Tennessee State Senate on August 13, but the House of Representatives was deadlocked. When young Harry T. Burn of Niota changed his vote to support ratification of the 19th Amendment, he broke a tie in the House of Representatives and made history.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1920</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>Nashville (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>Belmont Civic Federation Scrapbook</dc:source>
<dcterms:isPartOf>1480</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:instructionalMethod>5.46; US.18; Women's Suffrage and the 19th Amendment</dcterms:instructionalMethod>
<dc:subject>Congresses and conventions; League of Women Voters of Tennessee; Tennessee -- Politics and government -- 1865-1950; Women -- Political activity -- Tennessee; Women -- Societies and clubs; Women -- Suffrage -- Tennessee; Constitutional amendments -- United States -- Ratification</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Ephemera; Women's rights; Women's suffrage</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>45496</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>VII-E-3, Box 1</dc:source>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Women's Suffrage in Tennessee</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dcterms:medium>Ephemera; Scrapbooks</dcterms:medium>
<dc:rights>No copyright - United States: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll27/id/770</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>