<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>"Diagram of Official New York Vote"</dc:title>
<dc:description>Full title: "Diagram of Official New York Vote, Proving Woman Suffrage Carried by N.Y. City Converts to Socialism and that Majority of Democrats and Republicans, in City &amp; State, Voted Against Suffrage." This diagram was distributed by the National Association Opposed to Woman Suffrage to illustrate the ties between suffrage and socialism. The First Red Scare reached its height in 1919 and 1920 over the concern that radical politics would aid the spread of communism.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The 19th Amendment to the U. S. Constitution granted women the right to vote. When the Tennessee General Assembly passed the ratification resolution on August 18, 1920, it gave the amendment the 36th and final state necessary for ratification. Suffragists and anti-suffragists lobbied furiously to secure votes during that intense summer in Nashville. The ratification resolution passed easily in the Tennessee State Senate on August 13, but the House of Representatives was deadlocked. When young Harry T. Burn of Niota changed his vote to support ratification of the 19th Amendment, he broke a tie in the House of Representatives and made history.</dc:description>
<dc:date>undated</dc:date>
<dc:publisher>National Association Opposed to Woman Suffrage</dc:publisher>
<dc:coverage>New York (N.Y.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>Josephine A. Pearson Papers, 1860-1943</dc:source>
<dcterms:references>https://sos.tn.gov/products/tsla/pearson-josephine-papers-1860-1943</dcterms:references>
<dcterms:isPartOf>74-099</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:instructionalMethod>5.46; US. 18; Women's Suffrage and the 19th Amendment</dcterms:instructionalMethod>
<dc:subject>Campaign literature; Socialism -- United States; Elections -- New York (state); Women -- Suffrage -- Tennessee; Constitutional amendments -- United States -- Ratification</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Political strategies; Women's rights; Women's suffrage</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>44360</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>VIII-E-4-6, Box 1, Folder 5</dc:source>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Women's Suffrage in Tennessee</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dc:rights>No copyright - United States: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll27/id/367</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>