<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Anne Dallas Dudley</dc:title>
<dc:description>Anne Dallas Dudley was a national and state leader in the fight for women's suffrage who worked tirelessly to secure the ratification of the 19th Amendment in Tennessee. She was from a prominent Nashville family, and married to one of the founders of the Life and Casualty Insurance Company. This picture of Dudley reading with her children Trevania and Guilford, Jr. was used in women's suffrage publicity materials to counter the stereotypes of suffragists as mannish, childless radicals intent on destroying the American family. The historical marker erected by the Tennessee Historical Commission at Centennial Park in Nashville states that "Anne Dudley played a significant role in the ratification of the 19th Amendment by the State of Tennessee. A native of Nashville, she served as president of the Nashville Equal Suffrage League, 1911-15; president of the Tennessee Equal Suffrage Association, Incorporated, 1915-17; and as vice president of the National American Woman Suffrage Association, 1917. May 1, 1916, Anne Dudley walked from downtown Nashville to Centennial Park to demonstrate her support for the right of women to vote."</dc:description>
<dc:description>The 19th Amendment to the U. S. Constitution granted women the right to vote. When the Tennessee General Assembly passed the ratification resolution on August 18, 1920, it gave the amendment the 36th and final state necessary for ratification. Suffragists and anti-suffragists lobbied furiously to secure votes during that intense summer in Nashville. The ratification resolution passed easily in the Tennessee State Senate on August 13, but the House of Representatives was deadlocked. When young Harry T. Burn of Niota changed his vote to support ratification of the 19th Amendment, he broke a tie in the House of Representatives and made history.</dc:description>
<dc:date>undated</dc:date>
<dc:source>Library Photograph Collection</dc:source>
<dcterms:instructionalMethod>5.46; US.18; Women's Suffrage and the 19th Amendment; Progressive Era</dcterms:instructionalMethod>
<dc:subject>Women -- Suffrage -- Tennessee; Suffragists -- Photographs; Motherhood; Sex role -- United States -- 20th century</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Activists; Photographs; Women; Mothers and children; Women's rights; Women's suffrage</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>1286</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Drawer 7, Folder 7</dc:source>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Women's Suffrage in Tennessee</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:type>Still image</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dcterms:medium>Photographs</dcterms:medium>
<dc:rights>Copyright not evaluated: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll27/id/69</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>