<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Letter from Walter C. Childs to Governor Albert H. Roberts</dc:title>
<dc:description>Writing on behalf of the Man Suffrage Association from New York, Walter Childs expressed his hope that Governor Roberts would stand against the pressure of suffragists and cowardly politicians to sway him from his duty. According to Childs, representative government was at stake. In order to "protect the basic rights of the people of many States, whose votes would be nullified by the passage of the 19th Amendment," he wanted the governor to stand firm against women's suffrage. He included a broadside entitled "The People versus Woman Suffrage" produced by the Man Suffrage Association that listed electoral defeats of women's suffrage efforts in various states as proof that "suffrage is not coming by the will of the people."</dc:description>
<dc:description>The 19th Amendment to the U. S. Constitution granted women the right to vote. When the Tennessee General Assembly passed the ratification resolution on August 18, 1920, it gave the amendment the 36th and final state necessary for ratification. Suffragists and anti-suffragists lobbied furiously to secure votes during that intense summer in Nashville. The ratification resolution passed easily in the Tennessee State Senate on August 13, but the House of Representatives was deadlocked. When young Harry T. Burn of Niota changed his vote to support ratification of the 19th Amendment, he broke a tie in the House of Representatives and made history. Albert H. Roberts (1868-1946), served as a single term governor of Tennessee from 1919-1921. Roberts hesitated to call a special session of the General Assembly to consider the ratification of the 19th Amendment, in part because many legislators maintained that voting on the resolution in special session would violate their oath to the Tennessee constitution. Rulings from the Attorney General, and pressure from the national Democratic Party, particularly from President Woodrow Wilson, persuaded Roberts to support the special session and the ratification of the 19th Amendment. Though Roberts won national acclaim for his support of women's suffrage, many conservative Tennesseans were outraged. His support for women's suffrage was one reason for his defeat in the 1920 gubernatorial election by Republican Alfred Taylor.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1920 June 22</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Childs, Walter C.</dc:creator>
<dc:coverage>New York (N.Y.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>GP 38: Governor Albert H. Roberts Papers, 1919-1921</dc:source>
<dcterms:references>http://sos.tn.gov/products/tsla/governor-albert-h-roberts-papers-1918-1921</dcterms:references>
<dcterms:isPartOf>GP 38</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:instructionalMethod>5.46; US.18; Women's Suffrage and the 19th Amendment; Progressive Era</dcterms:instructionalMethod>
<dc:subject>Women -- Suffrage -- Tennessee; Constitutional amendments -- United States -- Ratification; Roberts, Albert Houston, 1868-1946; States' rights (American politics); Man-Suffrage Association Opposed to Extension of Political Suffrage for Women</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Activists; Correspondence; Political organizations; Politicians; Women's rights; Women's suffrage</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>42517</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>GP 38, Box 27, Folder 3</dc:source>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Women's Suffrage in Tennessee</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dcterms:medium>Correspondence</dcterms:medium>
<dc:rights>No copyright - United States: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll27/id/951</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>