<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Tennessee Women's Democratic Headquarters, Letter to the Editor</dc:title>
<dc:description>A letter from the Tennessee Women's Democratic Headquarters to the editor of an unidentified publication. The letter, written by Chairman of Publicity Katherine P. Wright, lists the many positive ways women would use the vote.</dc:description>
<dc:description>The 19th Amendment to the U. S. Constitution granted women the right to vote. When the Tennessee General Assembly passed the ratification resolution on August 18, 1920, it gave the amendment the 36th and final state necessary for ratification. Suffragists and anti-suffragists lobbied furiously to secure votes during that intense summer in Nashville. The ratification resolution passed easily in the Tennessee State Senate on August 13, but the House of Representatives was deadlocked. When young Harry T. Burn of Niota changed his vote to support ratification of the 19th Amendment, he broke a tie in the House of Representatives and made history.</dc:description>
<dc:creator>Wright, Katherine P.</dc:creator>
<dc:source>Belmont Civic Federation Scrapbook</dc:source>
<dcterms:isPartOf>1480</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dcterms:instructionalMethod>5.46; US.18; Women's Suffrage and the 19th Amendment</dcterms:instructionalMethod>
<dc:subject>Democratic Party (Tenn.); Letters to the editor; Tennessee -- Politics and government -- 1865-1950; Women -- Political activity -- Tennessee; Women -- Suffrage -- Tennessee; Constitutional amendments -- United States -- Ratification</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Correspondence; Political organizations; Women's rights; Women's suffrage</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>45495</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>VII-E-3, Box 1</dc:source>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Women's Suffrage in Tennessee</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dcterms:medium>Correspondence</dcterms:medium>
<dc:rights>No copyright - United States: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll27/id/778</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>