<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Descriptive Records.  Department of Tennessee. Grand Army of the Republic (G.A.R.) Volume II Posts 45-102</dc:title>
<dc:description>The Grand Army of the Republic (G.A.R.) first established posts in Tennessee in 1867. By 1872 posts in the South and West were generally demoralized, many Tennessee members being given a choice of leaving the state or disavowing membership in the organization. The Department of Tennessee and Georgia, like other southern departments, remained more disposed to accept as members those who deserted from the Confederate Army to join the Union forces. Hostility to the G.A.R. grew from rival societies in the 1890s, and membership began to dwindle.  -------  There are two volumes of "Descriptive Records. Department of Tennessee G.A.R." The first volume includes posts 1 through 44, and volume two contains posts 45 through 102. Entries for individuals list name; age; birth place; residence; occupation; entry into service; final discharge; related service information; when and where died; where buried; and remarks.  The Table of Contents (volume 1) lists page number, post number, post name, and location of post.  All non-Tennessee posts are identified with a state abbreviation. Occasionally there are duplicate post numbers. Usually this represents posts both in Tennessee and another state. To be certain of locating the correct post, the researcher should scan the entire table of contents. Changes of post names and continuations on non-consecutive pages are noted as original entries in the volumes. ------  Blank pages have been removed from this item although appearing the original microfilm.   ------  The names are searchable.  Many names have standard abbreviations for the time: Wm for William, Jno for John, Geo for George, etc.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Fraternal organizations; Veterans;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>1890s</dc:date>
<dc:type>book</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF; 400 dpi </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>MSC 0250 Volume 2</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>McClung Historical Collection</dc:source>
<dc:rights>To use photographs or to order reproductions, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. Please refer to Image Number and provide a brief description of the photograph. </dc:rights>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15136coll4/id/8009</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>