<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>"To The Stock-Raisers of East Tennessee.", 1860</dc:title>
<dc:description>"To The Stock-Raisers of East Tennessee."  Re:  race horses.  Jos. A. Mabry, Knoxville, Tenn.  Broadside.  1 pc.  1860.  Beckett, Haws &amp; Co., Prs., Knoxville.   Charles G. Nenney Papers.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Horses; Broadsides; Ephemera;</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Jos. A. Mabry</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1860</dc:date>
<dc:type>ephemera</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF; 400 dpi</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Charles G. Nenney Papers, 1860</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Charles G. Nenney Papers</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>To The Stock-Raisers of East Tennessee.
"SOVEREIGN, Jr."
This thorough and popular-bred Racehorse and Stallion will Stand this season.
(1860) at my farm, adjoining the Knoxville
Fair Grounds.
"SOVEREIGN, Jr.," is a dark bay, 16 hands high :
8 years old this spring; has great strength of bone and
musscle, fine action and good disposition. His fine color,
hard, clean limbs, expressive countenance, large intelligent eves, magnificent high carriage, and the beautiful
symmetry of his proportions, combine to give him a
most remarkable and commanding appearance. "Sovereign, Jr.," breeds large and fine colts, and is of as
fine blood as any horse in the Union. His distance is
from 1 to 4 miles.
PEDIGREE.    " SOVEREIGN, Jr." by imported Sovereign ; dam
by imported Autocrat; grand-dam by Virginian; he by
Sir Archy; great grand-dam by imported Diomede,
Synames Wildair, Mark Anthony, imported Jolly Roger,
imported Shark, imported Sober John, imported Primrose, &amp;c. (See American Turf Register, Vol. 11, page
656.)
$300  PREMIUM
will be given to the fastest colt, 1 mile and repeat, at 2
years old. Speed to be tested at the Knoxville Fair
Grounds during the fair in October after the colts are
two years old.
Every care will be taken of mares from a distance,
but no liability for accidents or escapes.
Mares pastured at $1.00 per week.
TERMS:&#8212;$30.00 for the Season, with privilege of com-
peting for the Premium; $10.00 without the privilege.
 Payment required before the Mares are removed.
In all cases of failure to become with foal, no charge will
be made for the succeeding season.
PREMIUM JACKS. 
"BLACK PRINCE, Jr."
and
"ANDREW JACKSON,"
will Stand the present season, at the Knoxville Fair
Grounds, two miles East of Knoxville. Mares at $10.00
and Jennets at $25.00 the season.
Fifty Dollars and the Season will be paid for Colts
from all Mares over 15 1/2 hands high&#8212;making Sixty
Dollars for Colts.
 Persons trading the Colts will be required to
take good care of the Mares.
In all cases of failure to become with foal, no charge
will be made for the succeeding season.
$100.00 PREMIUM WILL  BE   GIVEN
FOR  THE BEST   COLT.
 Ample arrangements have been made for Pasturing
Mares and Jennets, for which a charge of 75 cents per week
will be made.    Notes will be taken during the season.
PEDIGREES.
"BLACK PRINCE, Jr." is 15 hands and 3 inches high ; 4
years old last September. He was sired by imported Black
Prince, and dam by Old Wonder. I would rather have him
than any Jack in Tennessee. T. BARRY.
Gallatin Tenn., Nov. 14, 1859.
"ANDREW JACKSON" is black, with white muzzle and
belly; 15 hands and 2 inches high. 8 years old the 3rd of June;
by Commodore Rodgers"; dam by Sancho; grand dam by Big
Partnership; great grand dam imported. Commodore Rodgers
was sired by an imported Jack from Malta, out of an imported
Jennet from Malta. The Commodore has been the winner of
19 Premiums. Sancho was sired by imported Maltese Jack;
dam by Big Partnership; grand-dam by Sampson : great grand-
dam by Mississippi. Sancho was the winner of Premium at
Nashville Fair in 1850. Andrew Jackson was winner of Premium in 1854, at Nashville. I consider his Stock equal to the
Stock of any Jack in the world. J. SHELBY.
Fatherland, Nov. 3rd, 1856.
"Andrew Jackson" took the Premium at the Fair in 1856.
1858, and 1859, at Knoxville, and at Cleveland in 1858.
 Those who may wish to see and examine the Jacks,
can apply at the Fair Ground to Mr. A. J. Andrews.
JOS. A. MABRY,
KNOXVILLE,   TENN.
BECKETT,   HAWS   &amp;   CO.,   PRS.,   KNOXVILLE
</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15136coll4/id/529</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>