<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>First Regiment of Tennessee Cavalry, by WilliamThurman</dc:title>
<dc:creator>William Thurman</dc:creator>
<dc:description>History of the First Regiment of Tennessee Cavalry.  By William Thurman.  Louisville, KY.  Hart &amp; Mapother, Printers. 1865.
</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Military leadership; History; Cavalry; Civil wars; Military personnel; Battlefields;</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Hart &amp; Mapother, Printers</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1865</dc:date>
<dc:type>book</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF; 400 dpi</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Thurman C973.7468</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Cataloged book, McClung Historical Collection</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814.</dc:rights>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:description>
HISTORY of the
First Regiment of Tennessee Cavalry. 
BY  WILLIAM  THURMAN.
Containing a correct account of the sufferings of the men of whom this Regiment 
was formed while they were effecting their escape from  Rebels and   Rebel 
tyranny in the beginning of the war, and fighting, and forcing their way across 
Cumberland  Mountain in order to reach the  Federal Camps; also giving sat- 
isfactory information relative to all the extensive marches, important skirm-
ishes and battles, casualties, diseases and deaths which occurred during the 
organization of the Regiment.    The reader will  not fail to be pleased with 
narratives of the particular prowess of private soldiers and eulogizing sketches 
of the military character and conduct of the Commissioned Officers belonging 
to the Regiment. 
LOUISVILLE, KY.
HART   &amp;   MAPOTHER, Printers
Corner of Third and Market Streets.
1865.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15136coll4/id/2773</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>