<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Johnson.  Funeral Service of Ex-President Andrew johnson.</dc:title>
<dc:creator>H.H. Ingersoll</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Funeral Service of EX-PRESIDENT ANDREW JOHNSON.  Broadside with details of the funeral service of former President Andrew Johnson, Greeneville, TN.  [August 1875].</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Presidents; Funeral rites &amp; ceremonies; Funeral processions; Ephemera;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>[August 1875]</dc:date>
<dc:type>ephemera</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF; 400 dpi</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Ephemera 2014.001</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Ephemera Collection</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814.</dc:rights>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:description>Funeral Service of EX-PRESIDENT ANDREW JOHNSON.
The body of the illustrious dead now lies in state under Masonic guard,
at the Court House, where it may be visited by all until
11 o'clock, A.M., when the Masonic horse service will be performed-
in the Court House.
During this service, the procession&#8212;other than the Masonic
portion&#8212;will be formed on Main Street under charge of H. H.
Ingersoll, Chief Marshal.
After the service the body will be taken from the Court-House,
attending down Main Street and up Ridge Street, one half mile
South West to the place of burial chosen by the Ex-President
and known as "Johnson's Hill," where the Masonic Funeral service will be performed.
ORDER OF PROCESSION  File of Assistant Marshals.
Andy Johnson Guards
Patrons of Husbandry.
O'Conner's  Zouavaes.
Odd Fellows.
Other Civic Organizations.
German Band.
Dickinson Light Guard.
Masonic Bodies.      
Hearse Bearing Body.
Family of Deceased.
Governor, Staff and Other Public Officers.
All Other Citizens.
Persons desiring dinner can obtain it at any   time after 12 p.m.
at the following places:
Reeve House at Depot; Mason's Hotel, diagonally across from
Court House; Lane House two doors North of Mason's; Willhoit
House, three doors South of Court House , Godfrey House, in
Johnson Block.
Greeneville Lodge, No. 119. will be open at 9:30 A. m., and all
regular Master Masons not with their own Lodges desiring to
join the procession are requested to present themselves at the
Lodge Room before the hour of service.
Special trains will remain till the services are concluded.
All citizens desiring to pay respect to the memory of the, dis-
tinguished dead are cordially invited to join in the procession.
H.H. INGERSOLL,
Chief Marshal</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15136coll4/id/3259</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>