<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Broyles. Jessie Broyles officer appointment, 1865.</dc:title>
<dc:description>By the Commanding Officer of the First Regiment of the U.S. Colored Arty. "Heavy."  To all who shall see these presents, Greeting:  Know Ye That reposing special trust and confidence in the patriotism, valor, fidelity and abilities of Jessie Broyles I do hereby appoint him 7th Corporal in Company "M" of the First Regiment of U.S.C. Arty. (Artillery) (Hvy.) in the service of the United States to rank and as such from the 20th day of November one thousand eight hundred and 64 .....  Given under my hand at the Head Quarters of the Regiment at Greenville, Tennessee this twenty-third day of May in the Year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and 65.  Signed by J.E. McGowan (?), Lieutenant Colonel, Commanding the Regiment.  Signed by J. Whitset(?), Lieutenant.  Jesse Hinton enlisted in the 1st U.S. Colored Heavy Artillery In Knoxville, Tennessee, on October 8, 1864.  He enlisted under the name of Jessie (Jesse) Broyles, the surname of his last owner.  This document is glued onto the front</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Civil wars; Military officers; African Americans;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>May 23, 1865</dc:date>
<dc:type>document</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF; 400 dpi</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Charles Ducloux Scrapbook</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Glued in the front cover of the Charles Ducloux Scrapbook.</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814.</dc:rights>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:description>Jesse Broyles (Jessie) (Jesse Hinton) (ca. 1835-May 16, 1886)
Susan Wallace Hinton (ca. 1838-Dec. 1904)
Jesse Hinton enlisted in the 1st U. S. Colored Heavy Artillery in Knoxville on October
8,1864 under the surname "Broyles," the name of his last owner. According to the
pension application of his widow Susan Wallace Hinton, Jesse Hinton was born in Pea
Ridge below Columbia, South Carolina. He was brought to York, South Carolina as a
small boy, where he lived as a slave of Col Joel Rawlinson about four miles east of Rock
Hill. Jesse and Susan were married "some years before the war" by "Wyatt Harp, a
colored Baptist Preacher" at the plantation of Susan's owner, Mrs. Emily Wallace. The
couple were recognized as man and wife during the years before the Civil War. Their
eldest child was ten years old by the end of the war.
In 1862 Jesse ran away from his master, presumably to try to get behind Union lines.
James B. Gaulden. Jesse's former overseer, gave testimony that "they put the
bloodhounds after him and ran him down." He was captured and sold to Adam Broyles of
Washington County in East Tennessee. Susan did not hear from him until the end of the
war, when he returned home to his family with a "free discharge with him and dressed in
Yankee uniform." Jesse and a fellow Broyles slave, Alfred Broyles, both enlisted in the
army in the 1st U.S.C.H.A.  Alf Broyles was reported to be living in Liberia in 1886.
Jesse spoke of participating in a number of battles under generals Tilson and McGowan
and fighting near Richmond, Virginia. The married couple stayed in South Carolina for
some time on the plantation of Jesse's former owner and then moved to Mecklenburg
County, North Carolina where they lived for about twenty years before Jesse's death in
1886. Susan reported that a number of people from Rock Hill who could have provided
testimony for her case "scattered to such an extent when the Ku Klux got after them that I
am unable to tell you where they may be found." At the time of Jesse's death the couple
were living on the farm of Thomas Shaw in North Carolina. In her pension application,
Susan described Jesse as being "of medium build, about five feet six inches high, rather
dark ... with brownish hair and brownish gray eyes." Susan had no photograph of him.
Jesse left six children under the age of 16 when he died in 1886.
Steve Cotham
Calvin M. McClung Historical Collection
Knox County Public Library System</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15136coll4/id/3077</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>