<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Scientific American March 17, 1894 Aerial Cable Railway (tinted)</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Scientific American</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Scientific American, New York, March 17, 1894.  Vol. LXX, No. 11. Page [161].  "The Aerial Cable Railway."  Article and illustrations.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Cable railroads; Aerial tramways;</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>Munn &amp; Co.</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>March 17, 1894</dc:date>
<dc:type>article</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF; 400 dpi</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Ephemera 1987.002</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Ephemera Collection</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814.</dc:rights>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:description>SCIENTIFIC AMERICAN    [Entered at the Post Office of New York, N. Y., as Second Class matter.   Copyrighted, 1894, by Munn &amp; Co.]
A WEEKLY JOURNAL OF PRACTICAL INFORMATION, ART, SCIENCE, MECHANICS, CHEMISTRY, AND MANUFACTURES.
NEW YORK, MARCH 17, 1894.
THE   AERIAL   CABLE   RAILWAY.
A wire rope tramway for passenger car service over the
Tennessee River, at Knoxville, and which is suspended
at a height of 350 feet above the water as it reaches
the south side of the river, as shown in our illustration, has been in practical use for some time past, passengers being conveyed thereby to a pleasure resort back of the bluff on the other side of the river from
the city of Knoxville. The starting point of this suspended railway is only about five minutes' ride by
street cars from the center of the city, and here is a
power house where are two twenty horse power engines which operate the hauling cable. The tramway
cables are each 1 3/8 inches in diameter, and the length
of the span is 1,060 feet. These cables on the Knoxville
side are anchored to 12x12 inch oak timbers, 14 feet
long, placed behind plank bulkheads. The connecting
bars are 12 feet long and 134 inches thick, and provision
is made for taking up the slack by means of the long
threaded screws, as shown in the plan and side view
of the anchor. The anchor at the high end, on the
opposite side of the river, consists of iron plates fixed
in the rock. The supporting cables each have a breaking strain of 60 tons. The cable conveying the motive
power is 1/2 inch in diameter and permanently fastened
to the car. The car, empty, weighs 1,200 pounds. It
has a 14 foot body and 3 foot platforms, and is 6 feet
wide by 6 1/2 feet high. The seating capacity is 16 passengers. The car is provided with automatic brakes,
which stop the car in case the propelling cable breaks
or slips on the drum. The up trip takes about three
and a half minutes. The descent is made in a half
minute by gravity.
An accident occurred on this aerial ferry on Sunday, February 18, by which one passenger was killed
and two others slightly injured. The hauling cable
broke just as the car reached the top of the incline, and
struck the car with such force as to damage it somewhat, the earthen starting rapidly down the grade until
it was stopped by the automatic brakes. When the
car was brought to a standstill it was at a point about
200 feet above the water, and the eight passengers it
contained were rescued by being let down by ropes
into a boat on the river.
PLAN   AND   SIDE   VIEW   OF   ANCHOR.                   THE   AERIAL   CABLE   RAILWAY,  KNOXVILLE,  TENN.,  350   FEET   HIGH.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15136coll4/id/3396</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>