<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Proclamation</dc:title>
<dc:description>Proclamation issued by  Major General E. Kirby Smith, Commanding Dept. of  East Tenn., April 18, 1862, and W.M. Churchwell, Colonel and Provost Marshal, Knoxville, Tenn., April 23, 1862.  Re: clemency and amnesty for citizens.  Confederate document.  Printed.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Broadsides; Proclamations;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>April 1862</dc:date>
<dc:type>Broadside</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF; 400 dpi </dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Ephemera 2006-011</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Ephemera Collection</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814. </dc:rights>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:description>PROCLAMATION.
The Major General Commanding this Department, charged with the enforcement of Martial Law,
believing that many of its citizens have been misled into the commission of treasonable acts through ignorance of their duties and obligations to their State, and that many have actually fled across the mountains and joined our enemies under the persuasion and misguidance of supposed friends&#8212;but designing
enemies&#8212;hereby proclaims :
1st. That no person so misled, who comes forward, declares his error, and takes the oath to support
the Constitution of the State and of the Confederate States, shall be molested or punished on account of
past acts or words.
2d. That no person so persuaded and misguided, as to leave his home and join the enemy, who shall
return within thirty days of the date of this Proclamation, acknowledge his error, and take an oath to
support the Constitution of the State and of the Confederate States, shall be molested or punished on account of past acts or words.
After thus announcing his disposition to treat with the utmost, clemency those who have been led
away from the true path of patriotic duty, the Major General Commanding furthermore declares his determination henceforth to employ all the elements at his disposal for the protection of the lives and property of the citizens of East Tennessee&#8212;whether from the incursions of the enemy or the irregularities of
his own troops&#8212;and for the suppression of all treasonable practices.
He assures all citizens engaged in cultivating their farms, that he will protect them in their rights,
and that he will suspend the Militia draft under the State laws, that they may raise crops for consumption in the coming year. 
He invokes the zealous co-operation of the authorities, and of all good people, to aid him in his endeavors.
The Courts of Criminal Jurisdiction will continue to exercise their functions, save the issuing of writs
of habeas corpus. Their writs will be served and their decrees executed by the aid of the Military, when
necessary.
When the Courts fail to preserve the peace or punish offenders against the laws, those objects will be
attained through the action of Military tribunals, and the exercise of the force of his command.
E. KIRBY SMITH,
Major Gen. Commanding Dept. of East Tenn.
Head-Quarters,  Knoxville, April. 18, 1862. 
TO THE DISAFFECTED PEOPLE OF EAST TENNESSEE.
HEAD-QUARTERS, DEPARTMENT EAST TENN.,
Office Provost Marshal, April 23d, 1862.
The undersigned, in executing Martial Law in this Department, assures those interested, who have
fled to the enemy's lines, and who are actually in their army, that he will welcome their return to their
homes and their families:&#8212;they are offered amnesty and protection, if they come to lay down their arms
and act as loyal citizens within the thirty days given them by Maj. Gen. E. Kirby Smith to do so.
At the end of that time, those failing to return to their homes, and accept the amnesty thus offered,
and provide for and protect their wives and children in East Tennessee, will have them sent to their care
in Kentucky, or beyond the Confederate States lines, at their own expense.
All that leave after this date, with a knowledge of the above acts, their families will be sent immediately after them. 
The women and children must be taken care of by husbands and fathers, either in East Tennessee or
in the Lincoln Gownment.
W. M. CHURCHWELL,
Colonel and Provost Marshal.
Knoxville, Tenn., April 23, 1862.

</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15136coll4/id/7243</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>