<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Republicans Urge Tennessee to Ratify Suffrage</dc:title>
<dc:creator>National Woman's Party</dc:creator>
<dc:description>Republicans Urge Tennessee to Ratify Suffrage [1920].  Ephemera.  Mentions resolution passed in Ohio and planks in Republican platforms in Chicago and Tennessee.  National Woman's Party.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Women's suffrage; Politics &amp; government; Political parties; Political participation; Ephemera;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>[1920]</dc:date>
<dc:type>ephemera</dc:type>
<dc:format>400 dpi, TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Ephemera 2011.006</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Ephemera Collection</dc:source>
<dc:rights>For information on license and use fees and acquiring high-resolution image files, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814.</dc:rights>
<dc:description>
Republicans Urge Tennessee
to Ratify Suffrage
Resolution Passed Unanimously by Executive Committee of the Republican National
Committee at Columbus, Ohio, July 21, 1920
"Resolved:&#8212;That it is the sense of the Executive Committee of the Republican National Committee that the REPUBLICAN MEMBERS OF THE TENNESSEE LEGISLATURE should be and
hereby ARE MOST EARNESTLY URGED and requested by this resolution TO VOTE UNANIMOUSLY FOR RATIFICATION OF THE WOMAN SUFFRAGE AMENDMENT in the special session of the Tennessee legislature which is to be called; and the chairman of the Republi-
can National Committee is hereby authorized to communicate this resolution to each Republican
member of said legislature."
* *  *
Plank in Republican National  Platform, Adopted at Chicago  Convention, June, 1920
"We welcome women into full participation in the affairs of government and the activities of
the Republican party.    
"We earnestly hope that Republican legislatures in states which have not yet acted upon the
suffrage amendment WILL RATIFY the amendment to the end THAT ALL THE WOMEN OF
THE NATION OF VOTING AGE MAY PARTICIPATE IN THE ELECTION OF 1920, which is
so important to the welfare of the country."
* *  *
Plank in Tennessee Republican Platform, Adopted April 14, 1920,
Chattanooga, Tennessee
"We rejoice that the women of our state have at last the opportunity to express their choice
for those who shall conduct the affairs of the national government, on an equal footing with men,
and we express the hope that the Nineteenth Amendment to the Constitution of the United States
shall be adopted at such time that universal suffrage shall prevail at the next general election."
NATIONAL   WOMAN'S   PARTY
LAFAYETTE   SQUARE
WASHINGTON,   D.   C.</dc:description>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15136coll4/id/477</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>