<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Manly  Barber Family Collection  HPCP 2018-001 Journal</dc:title>
<dc:creator>Manly D. Barber</dc:creator>
<dc:description>HPCP 2018.001.001    Journal kept by Manly DeWitt Barber   It includes the August 1906 account of his trip with other members of the family in three row boats from Knoxville to Chattanooga. (Pages 1-47).  This boating adventure was mentioned  as a memorable event in Charles I. Barber's obituary in the 14 June 1962 Knoxville News-Sentinel.  &#8216;Camp Hemlock, An Outing in the Great Smokies, August 1909,&#8217; is on pages 51- 81, with a list of the nicknames used to describe the participants on page 59.  &#8220;The Song of the Mountain Streams&#8221; by Ruth Parmalee is on pages 85-86; &#8220;Who Are We?&#8221; by Marion and Katherine is on pages 87-88; and &#8220;The Mountains&#8221; by Mrs. Alice Barber Whitmore is on pages 89-91. The entries conclude with &#8220;Hurrah for Camp Hemlock&#8221; by Dad [Manly D. Barber], pages 92-94.  The remaining pages of the journal are blank.  Several loose papers from the volume were scanned following page 94.  The family retains the literary rights to the journal; it may not be published without permission.  Manly DeWitt Barber (1852-1928) was the older brother of architect George Barber.  He was married to Sarah Love (1854-1932) in DeKalb County, Illinois on March 14, 1877.  The couple had four children born in Illinois: Alice, Guy Love, David West, and Lora. After moving to Knoxville in 1903, Manly worked with George in the architectural firm of Barber &amp; Kluttz, and he also worked as a contractor and builder. Manly was well known as a collector of shells and fossils and he discovered a number of new specimens which he sent to the Smithsonian Institute in Washington D.C.  The name Manly appears both with and without an &#8216;e&#8217; (Manly, Manley) in various places in the material; the family says Manly is correct.</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Diaries; Families; Rivers; Rowboats; Great Smoky Mountains; Camping;</dc:subject>
<dc:date>1906-1909</dc:date>
<dc:type>manuscript journal</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF; 400 dpi</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>Manly  Barber Family Collection  HPCP 2018-001-001 Journal</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>Historic Photographs Copy Project 2018-001</dc:source>
<dc:rights>	For information about reproducing this material, contact DigitalCollections@knoxlib.org or phone 865 215-8814.</dc:rights>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16311.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15136coll4/id/7124</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>