<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:identifier>31905</dc:identifier>
<dc:title>Ferry at Chattanooga</dc:title>
<dc:subject>Ferries; Marine terminals; Boats; Flatboats; Barges; Rivers; Mountains; Cattle; Farms</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Agriculture; Chattanooga (Tenn.); Hamilton County (Tenn.); Tennessee River.</dc:subject>
<dc:description>Ferry in Chattanooga, Tennessee. The etching shows the operation of an active ferry. In the drawing are cattle being ferried across the river. There are some small boats and trees in the foreground. There are also hills and a farm in the background.</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Chattanooga (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:date>undated</dc:date>
<dc:source>Library Photograph Collection</dc:source>
<dc:description>Due to lack of road building, the need for reliable river crossings became evident. Ferry boats operated by individuals soon appeared at major river crossings.  Some 700 to 1,000 ferries operated in Tennessee in the 19th century.  The Tennessee River landing and ferry operation of John and Lewis Ross becames Ross's Landing, the forerunner of Chattanooga.</dc:description>
<dc:relation>S434</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</dc:source>
<dc:format>IMAGE</dc:format>
<dc:format>TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:rights>While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law.  Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/agricult/id/22</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>