<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:identifier>33758</dc:identifier>
<dc:title>Forest Nursery Company Catalog Cover</dc:title>
<dc:subject>Nurseries (Horticulture); Trees; Horticulture; Forests</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Agriculture; Commercial catalogs; Nurseries (Horticulture); Ornamental plant industry; Trees; Gardening; Landscape gardening</dc:subject>
<dc:description>The cover of this nursery catalog highlights color images of the American elm and the Lombardy poplar trees.  These images appear on top of a black and white background image of a forest.</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>McMinnville (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:date>Approximately 1929</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Forest Nursery Co.</dc:creator>
<dc:source>Library Special Collections</dc:source>
<dc:description>The Forest Nursery Company was founded by J. H. H. Boyd in 1887. He located his wholesale nursery business in McMinnville in 1904 and specialized in forest and shade trees, evergreens, and ornamental shrubs. His sons James R. and Fernando C. Boyd assisted him and continued the business after his death in 1924. It is still vital today. J. H. H. Boyd is often referred to as the father of the nursery industry in Warren County, and Warren County is referred to as "The Nursery Capital of the World."</dc:description>
<dc:publisher>A.B. Morse Co.</dc:publisher>
<dc:coverage>St. Joseph (Mich.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</dc:source>
<dc:format>TEXT</dc:format>
<dc:format>TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:rights>While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law.  Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/agricult/id/26</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>