<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:identifier>24155</dc:identifier>
<dc:title>Isolated Mountain Farm in East Tennessee</dc:title>
<dc:subject>Log cabins; Log buildings; Aerial views; Country life; Mountains; Farms; Agriculture; Outbuildings; Smokehouses</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Agriculture</dc:subject>
<dc:description>Aerial view of an isolated mountain farm in east Tennessee.  The photograph shows a large log house along with several outbuildings. A fence separates the fields. A mountain road is seen as well.</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>East Tennessee</dc:coverage>
<dc:date>undated</dc:date>
<dc:source>Tennessee Department of Conservation Photograph Collection</dc:source>
<dc:source>Tennessee Valley Authority</dc:source>
<dc:description>The log cabin is a familiar symbol of Tennessee's pioneer period. Although its use as shelter is well known, its quaint image has tended to obscure its importance as a bridge between civilization and the wilderness. The most important and enduring use of log construction occurred in the dwellings, barns, and related outbuildings of the thousands of independent farmsteads. Logs were used for the construction of smokehouses, tobacco barns, stock barns, and corn cribs.</dc:description>
<dc:relation>RG 82</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</dc:source>
<dc:format>IMAGE</dc:format>
<dc:format>TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:rights>While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law.  Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/agricult/id/16</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>