<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:identifier>19596</dc:identifier>
<dc:title>Joseph Buckner Killebrew</dc:title>
<dc:subject>People associated with agriculture; Plantation owners; Farmers' groups; Iron industry; Monuments &amp; memorials; Journalists; Emigration &amp; immigration; Bas-reliefs</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Agriculture; Killebrew, J. B. (James Buckner), 1831-1906; Montgomery County (Tenn.)</dc:subject>
<dc:description>Tennessee Agriculture Hall of Fame memorial honoring Joseph Buckner Killebrew. There is included an bas-relief image of Killebrew, and brief details of his life.</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Nashville (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:date>undated</dc:date>
<dc:source>Tennessee Department of Conservation Photograph Collection</dc:source>
<dc:source>Historic Sites</dc:source>
<dc:description>Joseph Buckner Killebrew (1831-1906) was a New South advocate and Tennessee's first Commissioner of Agriculture. In his writings and speeches, he advocated the improvement and extension of public education, encouraged immigration to the South, the development of natural resources for industrialization, and improvement of agriculture, including the break up of large landholdings, the diversification of crops, enrichment of soil, and a program to attract European immigration to farm unoccupied land.</dc:description>
<dc:relation>CV17153</dc:relation>
<dc:relation>RG 82</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</dc:source>
<dc:format>IMAGE</dc:format>
<dc:format>TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:rights>While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law.  Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/agricult/id/15</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>