<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Shindig In The Country (version 2) (16562)</dc:title>
<dc:subject>festivals; Music festivals; Wiseman, Mac; Walker, Charlie, 1926-2008; Tubb, Ernest, 1914-1984; Cooper, Stoney, 1918-1977; Cooper, Wilma Lee, 1921-2011; Lonzo and Oscar; Martin, Jimmy; Harrell, Bill; Louvin, Charlie, 1927-2011;</dc:subject>
<dc:description>Two color half sheet (red and black on white) announcing a Shindig in the Country with Mac Wiseman, Charlie Walker, Ernest Tubb, Wilma Lee and Stoney Cooper, Lonzo and Oscar, Jimmy Martin, the Sunny Mountain Boys, Don Reno, Bill Harrell, Tennessee Cutups, Charlie Louvin, Leon Morris, Peggy Sue and Sonny Wright and others at Aunt Minnie's Farm and Country Roads Park on July 4-6. Poster features metal photoplates of Mac Wiseman, Charlie Walker, Ernest Tubb, Wilma Lee and Stoney Cooper, Lonzo and Oscar, Jimmy Martin, Don Reno, Bill Harrell, and Charlie Louvin. Poster was ordered by Dave Austin (purchase order 16562). For additional information about this poster see https://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/digital/collection/hatch3/id/32014.</dc:description>
<dc:publisher>Hatch Show Print</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>1975</dc:date>
<dc:date>2018-06-08</dc:date>
<dcterms:extent>55.5 cm x 71 cm</dcterms:extent>
<dc:type>Still Image</dc:type>
<dcterms:medium>half-sheet posters; posters;</dcterms:medium>
<dc:identifier>PrintMaterials_Hatch_JobFolder_16562_ShindigInTheCountry_version 2_fullsheet_19750704_Poster</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>HSP_General_Oversize_1975_001_07</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>General Collection</dc:source>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dcterms:accessRights>This digital image is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and is protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The image may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this file, contact print@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite image information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dc:contributor>Digitized by Stephanie Chapman.</dc:contributor>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/hatch3/id/32013</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>