<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Starwood Amphitheater list of performers (2006)</dc:title>
<dc:subject>Steely Dan (Musical group); Poison (Musical group); Def Leppard (Musical group); Journey (Musical group); Fogerty, John; Nelson, Willie, 1933-; Korn (Musical group); Lynyrd Skynyrd (Musical group); Dave Matthews Band; Counting Crows (Musical group); Goo Goo Dolls (Musical group); Williams, Hank, Jr., 1949-; Crow, Sheryl; Motley Crue (Musical group); </dc:subject>
<dc:description>Two color window card (red and blue on white) announcing Starwood Amphitheater's 2006 list of performers including Warped Tour, Sammy Hagar, Black Crowes, Hootie and the Blowfish, Steely Dan and Michael McDonald, Poison and Cinderella, John Pogerty and Willie Nelson, Korn, Lynyrd Skynyrd, Dave Matthews Band, Counting Crows and Goo Goo Dolls, Buzzfest, Hank Williams Jr., John Mayer and Sheryl Crow, and Aerosmith and the Motley Crew. </dc:description>
<dc:creator>Brad Vetter</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Hatch Show Print</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2006</dc:date>
<dc:date>2018-04-19</dc:date>
<dcterms:extent>34 cm x 60 cm </dcterms:extent>
<dc:type>Still Image</dc:type>
<dcterms:medium>posters; window cards;</dcterms:medium>
<dc:identifier>PrintMaterials_Hatch_General_StarwoodAmphitheaterWarpedTour_2006_Poster</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>HSP_General_2006_006_16</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>General Collection</dc:source>
<dc:source>Country Music Foundation</dc:source>
<dc:language>English</dc:language>
<dcterms:accessRights>This digital image is the property of the Country Music Hall of Fame&#174; and Museum and is protected by U.S. and international copyright laws. The image may not be downloaded, reproduced, or distributed without permission. To inquire about use permissions and obtain a high-quality version of this file, contact print@countrymusichalloffame.org. Please cite image information in email.</dcterms:accessRights>
<dc:contributor>Digitized by Stephanie Chapman.</dc:contributor>
<dc:identifier>http://digi.countrymusichalloffame.org/cdm/ref/collection/hatch3/id/30462</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>