<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>The Junior Collegian, V. 1, N. 1 (1940)</dc:title>
<dc:subject>Newspapers; Newsletters; Students</dc:subject>
<dc:description>The first issue of the first student paper, the Junior Collegian, appeared in December 1940. It was typeset by the students and printed on a portable press owned by a student named Preston Englert.

It aspired to "be a paper for the students, by the students, and of the students . . . We are anxious to have the full cooperation of the student body in furnishing news and helping to write it. If therre are occasional errors, well, let's work together to eliminate them in the future."  This first issue included notes on recent sporting events, as well as very mildly naughty jokes and gossip regarding several of the students.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1940-12-13</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text;</dc:type>
<dc:format>Printed matter</dc:format>
<dc:source>Brother I. Leo O'Donnell Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>CS17114_dec40</dc:identifier>
<dc:publisher>Christian Brothers University</dc:publisher>
<dc:coverage>East Parkway, Memphis, TN</dc:coverage>
<dc:contributor>Preston Englert (student), printer</dc:contributor>
<dc:rights>http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:rights>While CBU may house an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use. Any image from the library's collection must cite as the source: Brother I. Leo O'Donnell Archives, Plough Library, Christian Brothers University. For all requests, please contact the Archives at archives@cbu.edu.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15916.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15916coll1/id/805</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>
