<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Order to send supplies from Nashville to Tullahoma, Estill Springs, Elk River Bridge, Manchester, and Murfreesboro</dc:title>
<dc:rights>While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law.  Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:subject>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865;  Tennessee -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Military orders; United States -- Army -- Supplies and Stores; United States -- Army -- Quartermaster Corps</dc:subject>
<dc:relation>Assistant Quartermaster&#8217;s Office
Nashville, Tenn. July 14th 1863
Capt S Perkins Jr. A Qrm.
Captain,
	Transport to Tullahoma 100 lbs Soap 10 lb Calomel. Fifty Feed boxes &amp; 50 End Gates.
To Estille Springs Tenn, Fifty Feed boxes and Fifty End Gates,  500 Axes and handles, 200 Spades, 100 Shovels, 100 Picks &amp; handles, 25 Paulins, 100 kegs of horse shoes, 100 kegs of mule shoes &amp; nails.
To Elk River Bridge, 2 bundles inch round iron and 2 bundles 5/8th inch, lg bridge bolts.
To Manchester. 10 Wagon saddles, 10 Riding saddles, 200 pounds 10 penny nails, 500 lbs horse shoes, 500 lbs of mule shoes, 100 lbs mule shoe nails, 300 Axes, 100 pick axes, 100 spades, 3000 Bootees, Stockings, &amp; Infantry Trousers, 5000 Blouses, 4000 Gray Flannel Shirts, 1000 Boots, 2000 Denim &amp; 3000 Hats.
To Murfreesboro. 600 Pack saddle Blankets.
					Respectfully
					Henry C Hodges
						Capt &amp; A Qrm</dc:relation>
<dc:description>Order from the Federal Quartermaster at Nashville sending soap, axes, spades, shovels, picks, horseshoes, nails, bridge bolts, saddles, boots, infantry trousers, stockings, blouses, grey flannel shirts, and saddle blankets to Tullahoma, Estill Springs, Elk River Bridge, Manchester, and Murfreesboro.</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Nashville (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:date>1863 July 14</dc:date>
<dc:creator>United States -- War Dept -- Adjutant-General's Office</dc:creator>
<dc:source>Tennessee Historical Society Civil War Collection, 1860-1982</dc:source>
<dc:description>The Quartermaster of the Army provides logistical support to the combat troops in the form of ammunition, clothing, food, and pay.</dc:description>
<dc:relation>THS 389</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Tennessee Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>35086</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>TEXT</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll9/id/184</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>