<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Board of Trade affudavit and memorandum for R. G. Page</dc:title>
<dc:rights>While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law.  Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:subject>Tennessee -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Economic aspects; Affidavits; Permits; Loyalty oaths; Dry-goods; Merchants; East, Edward H., 1830-1904</dc:subject>
<dc:description>One-page printed and handwritten Board of Trade affidavit represents the oath of R. G. Page that the dry goods supplies that he requires for his retail business in Nashville will be used for approved purposes and that he is a loyal citizen. The attached handwritten memorandum from Page states that the requested supplies will be shipped from Cincinnati and that their value is $9,000.00. President of the Board of Trade Edward H. East signed the affidavit.</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Nashville (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:date>1863 June 8</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Board of Trade (Nashville, Tenn.)</dc:creator>
<dc:source>Record Group 21, Adjutant General's Office Records, 1796-1900</dc:source>
<dc:description>Nashville's Board of Trade was established by Miltary Governor Andrew Johnson, in conjunction with the U. S. Treasury Department, following Federal occupation of the city during the Civil War.  The Board was Johnson's effort to regulate commerce with the manufacturers and merchants.  Both the offices of the Federal Quartermaster and Tennessee's Adjutant General were involved in this endeavor, as this was actually a military board of trade.</dc:description>
<dc:relation>RG 21</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>35215</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>TEXT</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:relation>RG 21</dc:relation>
<dc:relation>http://www.tn.gov/tsla/history/state/recordgroups/findingaids/rg21.pdf</dc:relation>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll9/id/320</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>