<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Military pass for William Ferguson and John Branham</dc:title>
<dc:rights>While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law.  Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:subject>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865;  Tennessee -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Military Passes; Military Orders</dc:subject>
<dc:relation>Camp Walker
Sept. 10th 1861
Privates Wm Ferguson &amp; John Branham of Co. K. Walker Legion have permission to pass through the country between [Q r ci ities] &amp; Chappawamsie &#8211; Keeping out of sight of the river for the purpose of preparing a map of certain designated localities to be used by me.
Wm B Bate
Col Comig
&#8220;Walker Legion&#8221;
Tenn Vols.</dc:relation>
<dc:description>Orders signed by Colonel William B. Bate permitting William Ferguson and John Branham of the Walker Legion (2nd Tennessee Infantry) to pass through the country, keeping out of sight of the river, for the purpose of preparing a map of certain designated localities to be used by Colonel Bate.</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Sumner County (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:date>1861 September 10</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Confederate States of Ameirca -- War Dept</dc:creator>
<dc:source>Fergusson Family Papers, 1784-1927</dc:source>
<dc:description>Orders such as these were typically issued to prevent friendly units from confusing engineers, cartographers, and scouts with Federal spies.  These orders were issued by Colonel William B. Bate of the 2nd Tennessee Infantry, later a major general, who fought at First Manassas, Shiloh, Tullahoma, Chickamauga, Chattanooga, Atlanta, and the Carolinas.  Bate was elected Governor of Tennessee in 1882.</dc:description>
<dc:relation>478</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>35104</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>TEXT</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:relation>1260</dc:relation>
<dc:relation>http://www.tn.gov/tsla/history/manuscripts/findingaids/478.pdf</dc:relation>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll9/id/22</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>