<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Volunteer descriptive list and account of pay and clothing of Claiborne M. George, Company D, 6th East Tennessee Volunteer Infantry</dc:title>
<dc:rights>While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law.  Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use.</dc:rights>
<dc:subject>George, Claiborne M., 1835 -  ; United States -- Army -- Tennessee Infantry Regiment, 6th; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; Tennessee -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865</dc:subject>
<dc:description>Lists name, rank, description, birthplace, occupation, date enrolled and mustered in, last pay date, bounty, and remarks. Claiborne M. George was a private, 27 years old, with black eyes and hair and dark complexion, and he was five feet, six inches tall. He was born in Blount County and was a waggonmaker. The form is stamped received at DeCamp U. S. A. General Hospital, May 3, 1865, Davids Island, New York Harbor.</dc:description>
<dc:coverage>Davids Island (N.Y.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:date>1865 April 27</dc:date>
<dc:source>Record Group 21, Adjutant General's Office Records, 1796-1900</dc:source>
<dc:description>The Army established De Camp General Hospital on Davids Island during the Civil War. After the hospital closed in 1866, the Army continued to use the island. From the late 1860s to the mid-1890s, the Army simply called the post Davids Island.  In July 1896 the Army formally named the post Fort Slocum, after Major General Henry Warner Slocum (1827-1894) of Civil War fame. Fort Slocum closed in November 1965.</dc:description>
<dc:relation>RG 21</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library &amp; Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>35168</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>TEXT</dc:type>
<dc:format>TIFF</dc:format>
<dc:relation>RG21</dc:relation>
<dc:relation>http://tennessee.gov/tsla/history/state/recordgroups/findingaids/rg21.pdf</dc:relation>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll9/id/280</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>