<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>King George III's Proclamation of 1763</dc:title>
<dc:description>The first in a bound collection of colonial documents is a complete copy of the Proclamation of 1763 promulgated at the end of the French and Indian War by King George III of Great Britain. The item is hand-written in ink on paper, copied by John Milton, Georgia Secretary of State. A short introduction to this document is available here: http://tsla.tnsosfiles.com/digital/teva/intros/33639.pdf .</dc:description>
<dc:description>This 1795 copy of King George III&#8217;s proclamation at the close of the French &amp; Indian War (aka Seven Year&#8217;s War) is one of the earliest and most significant documents for the history of Tennessee. The copy was produced by Georgia&#8217;s first Secretary of state, John Milton, and was found among the papers of John Sevier (Tennessee&#8217;s first governor and one of the chief violators of the edict). Promulgated after the 1763 Treaty of Paris, the proclamation lays out the British Crown&#8217;s regulations for the governance of its new territories in North America. Specifically, the king introduces the bounty land warrant system as a method of paying soldiers of the war, a method of public land disposal that was adopted by the colonies (later states) of North Carolina and Virginia and greatly impacted the distribution of Tennessee land. George III also proclaims a desire to protect the native inhabitants of America by prohibiting his American subjects from migrating and settling across the crest of the Appalachian mountains. The prohibition had little effect in stemming the tide of American westward movement.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1795</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Milton, John, 1740-1804</dc:creator>
<dc:coverage>Savannah (Ga.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>Milton, John, Manuscript Copybook of Early Georgia Documents, 1795</dc:source>
<dc:source>THS 024</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Tennessee -- History -- To 1865</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Documents; Law &amp; legal affairs</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>33639</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Documents</dc:format>
<dc:rights>No copyright - United States: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/tfd/id/488</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>