<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>An Ordinance for Circumscribing the Counties of Greene and Hawkins and Laying out Two New Counties</dc:title>
<dc:description>"An Ordinance for Circumscribing the Counties of Greene and Hawkins and Laying Out Two New Counties" is the first resolution appearing in the bound collection of acts passed by the Southwest Territory. The act is written in script and is four pages long. The act gives specific boundary lines of the two new counties. The resolution was passed at Knoxville on June 11, 1792. It is signed by Governor William Blount and the territorial secretary, Daniel Smith. On May 26, 1790, President George Washington signed into law an act of Congress passed earlier in the month that established the Territory of the United States South of the River Ohio (Southwest Territory). Embracing the western lands ceded by the state of North Carolina on December 22, 1789, the new territory was to be governed under the terms of the Ordinance of 1787, which created its predecessor, the Northwest Territory.
	The extent of the new territory was well defined. Containing about 43,000 square miles of land, it was restricted to North Carolina&#8217;s western district bounded on the north by the boundary of North Carolina and Virginia; on the west by a line in the middle of the Mississippi River, on the south by the parallel 35 degrees north and on the east by a jagged line running from the northeast to southwest connecting some dominant mountain peaks. It was this territory that in 1796 would become the state of Tennessee.
An introduction to this document is available here: http://tsla.tnsosfiles.com/digital/teva/intros/33665.pdf .</dc:description>
<dc:description>On May 26, 1790, President George Washington signed into law an act of Congress passed earlier in the month that established the Territory of the United States South of the River Ohio (Southwest Territory). Embracing the western lands ceded by the state of North Carolina on December 22, 1789, the new territory was to be governed under the terms of the Ordinance of 1787, which created its predecessor, the Northwest Territory. The acts passed by the elected General Assembly were varied, reflecting the interests of the territorial lawmakers. It was felt by the Governor and his representatives that statehood would become more likely with the creation of counties and towns. The act creating the counties of Greene and Hawkins County was approved on November 20, 1792.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1792 June 11</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Territory of the United States, South of the River Ohio. General Assembly</dc:creator>
<dc:coverage>Knoxville (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>Tennessee. General Assembly. Acts, Public and Private, 1790-[ongoing]</dc:source>
<dc:source>RG 260</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Blount, William, 1749-1800; Greene County (Tenn.); Hawkins County (Tenn.); Nolichucky River (N.C. and Tenn.); Holston River, South Fork (N.C. and Tenn.); Tennessee River; Jefferson County (Tenn.); Smith, Daniel, 1748-1818</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Boundaries; Physical geographic features; Politics &amp; government; Treaties; Legislative bodies; Resolutions</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>33665</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>RG 260</dc:relation>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Documents</dc:format>
<dc:rights>No copyright - United States: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/tfd/id/528</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>