<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Cumberland Compact</dc:title>
<dc:description>Original manuscript of the Cumberland Compact of Government, or Articles of Agreement, entered into by settlers on the Cumberland River, May 1, 1780, at what is now Nashville, and signed May 13, 1780 by 255 inhabitants of five stations on the river. First page missing; some following pages damaged, some quite significantly. Handwritten in ink on paper. </dc:description>
<dc:description>The Cumberland Compact was drawn up in May of 1780 by Richard Henderson, a land speculator and representative for North Carolina on the western Virginia/North Carolina survey team. The contract was signed in &#8220;Nashborough,&#8221; Tennessee, by 250 men of the new Cumberland settlement and established early government institutions (the infrastructure of courts, governance, and taxation) for the first settlers of the Tennessee territory. The Compact called for the creation of a civil government, and represented the settlers&#8217; desire for self-governance and independence from North Carolina. Yet only a small part of the document was devoted to governance; it was in large measure a contract dictating a legal framework for land transfers. For instance, it dictated the legal grounds by which title to Native American land would be transferred to the new settlers, some of whom were land speculators. A complete transcription of the Cumberland Compact is available in A. W. Putnam's book, History of Middle Tennesseee; or, Life and Times of General James Robertson (Nashville, Tennessee, 1859). Included in this transcription is a complete list of all signatories. A short introduction to this document is available here: http://tsla.tnsosfiles.com/digital/teva/intros/33634.pdf .</dc:description>
<dc:date>1780 May 1</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Henderson, Richard, 1735-1785</dc:creator>
<dc:coverage>Nashville (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>THS 155</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Tennessee -- History -- To 1865</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Documents; Law &amp; legal affairs</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>33634</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Documents</dc:format>
<dc:rights>No copyright - United States: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/tfd/id/460</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>