<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Watauga Purchase (Old Book A)</dc:title>
<dc:description>This volume comprises the first land grant book created for the area which became Tennessee. Located at the front is the contract or treaty formalizing the land purchase between the Watauga Association and the Cherokee chiefs. It is followed by the entry of the Watauga grants (generally individual tracts of 200-400 acres). The remainder contains recorded Washington County grants issued by the State of North Carolina. In the years prior to the American Revolution, settlers primarily from Virginia filtered down the Holston Valley to inhabit the fertile areas along the Watauga and Holston Rivers. As Wataugans went about the business of settling their families, developing their lands, and co-existing with the Cherokees, they sowed the initial seeds of democracy and self-governance in the West and, specifically, the land that was to be Tennessee.

The Watauga settlers who gained a foothold in the area around 1769 occupied a tenuous position. King George&#8217;s Proclamation of 1763 forbade settlement west of the Appalachian divide, and though it could be argued that two later treaties with the Cherokee nullified this order, the Wataugans&#8217; status might still be considered that of squatter. In addition, the Watauga inhabitants feared their settlement would become a haven for debtors and criminals. Moses Fisk, a nineteenth-century historian, described them &#8220;as little protected, controlled, or recollected by any government whatever, as their co-tenants the bears.&#8221; The order, justice, and security that a form of government would provide proved enticing.

Their rationale in place, and with John Carter as their chairman, the Wataugans formed the Watauga Association in May of 1772. Though their actions may have been considered a temporary emergency resolution, with this endeavor and with their written Articles of Association, the settlers of Watauga drafted the inaugural constitution of civil government west of the Alleghanies, and formed what some have called the &#8220;first free and independent government in American.&#8221;

The text of the Articles of Association did not survive, but other documents, such as the Association&#8217;s later petition for annexation by North Carolina in 1776, provide insight into the operation of this self-government. A magistrate&#8217;s court was formed with the consent of the people and was manned by five judges. This body executed, by majority, judicial and legislative functions and carried out public business and land affairs. They adopted the laws of Virginia as the basis for their rulings. A short introduction to this document is available here: http://tsla.tnsosfiles.com/digital/teva/intros/33636.pdf .</dc:description>
<dc:description>With the Watauga Purchase on March 19, 1775, the Watauga Association arranged with the Cherokee chiefs to secure the land along the Watauga, Holston, and Great Conaway Rivers. This negotiation solidified the hold the settlers had on the area and further legitimized their burgeoning experiment in democracy and self-government. This volume containing the treaty and recording the Watauga Purchase grants provides the earliest record of the Watauga settlement and proves to be the first land grant book created for the area which became Tennessee. The original ledger book kept by Trustee Charles Robertson was used to record the grants. James Smith served as Clerk for the Land Office opening in Watauga on April 1, 1775; the office was probably located at the residence of John Carter. This volume was transferred to Jonesborough with the formation of Washington County and used to record Washington County grants issued by the State of North Carolina. The presence of a &#8220;copied by&#8221; notation in TSLA&#8217;s volume and its designation as &#8220;Old Book A&#8221; indicate that this book is most likely a copy of the original and that the original resides in the old land office papers held at the Archives in Raleigh, North Carolina.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1775-1782</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Watauga Association</dc:creator>
<dc:coverage>Elizabethton (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>RG 50: Early Tennessee Land Records</dc:source>
<dc:source>RG 50</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Watauga Association; Indians of North America; Cherokee Indians; Land grants -- Tennessee</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Treaties</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>33636</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Land Grants, Reel 24</dc:relation>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Documents; Land records</dc:format>
<dc:rights>No copyright - United States: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/tfd/id/466</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>