<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Tennessee Constitution, 1870</dc:title>
<dc:description>Document of 26 pages.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Tennessee&#8217;s Constitution of 1870 was ratified in the wake of the Civil War and codified basic changes from that defining event in American history. The constitution remained essentially unchanged until 1953 and became in due course &#8220;the nation&#8217;s oldest unamended state constitution.&#8221; It is still the fundamental charter for the State of Tennessee. The most profound change in the 1870 Constitution was the permanent abolition of slavery in Tennessee. The real purpose of the Constitution&#8217;s framers, however, was to undo the electoral laws and other measures passed by Reconstruction governor William G. Brownlow. Conservative Democrats&#8212;many of them ex-Confederates&#8212;dominated the constitutional convention, and they were determined to prevent any future heavy-handed governorship such as Brownlow&#8217;s Radical regime. Delegates were driven by fear of an arbitrary executive and sought a Constitution that would guard against such abuses and excesses of state government from recurring. Many delegates had been disenfranchised by Brownlow and some imprisoned, and they were committed to restoring universal male suffrage. There was a good deal of argument over black men voting. With the passage of the 15th Amendment to the US Constitution (even though Tennessee voted NOT to ratify), convention delegates knew they could not repeal suffrage for African Americans. A Radical US Congress was watching for just such a misstep by former Confederate states. Instead, the convention authorized a poll tax in the Constitution as a tool for controlling who voted. To prevent the evils of Brownlowism from returning to the state, the convention enshrined in the Constitution certain restrictions on the governor&#8217;s power, namely, that he: 1. Could not suspend habeas corpus 2. Could not call out the militia without consent of the legislature 3. Could not appoint local judges and county officials 4. Had only limited veto power, which could be overridden by a simple majority of the General Assembly The 1870 Constitution also put limits on the legislature&#8217;s ability to meet in marathon sessions, to enact omnibus bills, and to saddle the state with large debts. In a constitutional addendum, all of Brownlow&#8217;s judicial and county office appointments were vacated, effectively clearing out many Union loyalists appointed during Reconstruction. Such measures proved popular in a state devastated by war and weary of the turmoil of Radical Reconstruction. The new Constitution was approved in a statewide referendum by a vote of 98,128 to 33,872.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1870</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Tennessee. General Assembly</dc:creator>
<dc:coverage>Nashville (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:subject>Constitutions; Reconstruction (U.S. history, 1865-1877)</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Constitutions; Documents</dc:subject>
<dc:identifier>39417</dc:identifier>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Documents</dc:format>
<dc:rights>No copyright - United States: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/tfd/id/584</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>