<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>1818 Letter from Cherokee chiefs to Gov. McMinn</dc:title>
<dc:description>Seven handwritten pages, in ink, of a letter from various Cherokee leaders to Tennessee Governor Joseph McMinn discussing the removal of Cherokees west of the Mississippi. Notation at top: "For the Raleigh Register." At end of letter: "A True Copy attest; John Ross member of the Nation'l Committee." A short introduction to this document is available here: http://tsla.tnsosfiles.com/digital/teva/intros/33637.pdf .</dc:description>
<dc:description>This letter, written and signed by over forty chiefs and warriors of the Cherokee National Council, is addressed to Tennessee Governor Joseph McMinn and dated November 21, 1818. McMinn, under pressure from the United States government and land-hungry speculators, found himself in the position of trying to coerce the Cherokees to relinquish their lands and remove to lands west of the Mississippi. Specifically, the letter is a reaction to the stipulations of the Treaty of 1817 which presented the eastern Cherokee with two options: removal or citizenship. Those Cherokees who decided to move to Arkansas would be provided with tracts of land similar to what they left behind; while those who decided to stay would have to become American citizens and be confined within reservations of 640 acres per each head of household. </dc:description>
<dc:date>1818</dc:date>
<dc:source>Tennessee Historical Society Miscellaneous Files, 1688-1951</dc:source>
<dc:source>THS 191</dc:source>
<dc:subject>Cherokee Indians -- Relocation; Cherokee Indians -- Treaties; McMinn, Joseph, 1758-1824</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Correspondence; Contracts; Treaties</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee Historical Society</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>33637</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>678</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Box C-1, No. C-54</dc:source>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Application/pdf</dc:format>
<dc:format>Correspondence; Documents</dc:format>
<dc:rights>No copyright - United States: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/tfd/id/616</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>