<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Chucalissa Museum Park</dc:title>
<dc:description>Native Americans at Chucalissa Museum/Park, making handicrafts, color image.</dc:description>
<dc:description>&#8220;Family Handicrafts - Chucalissa Pre-Historic Indian Town -- This famous Archeological Ruin &#8211; now a State Park &#8211; is under development by an archeologist, and is open to public the year &#8216;round. (Closed on Mondays). It is though that this ancient town was once occupied by Indians very much like the Chickasaw and Choctaw as they were first known to Europeans. The town itself was an important ceremonial center. Located west of U. S. Highway 61, just south of Memphis, Tennessee. For additional information, write: Division Of State Parks, Cordell Hull Bldg., Nashville 3, Tennessee&#8221;</dc:description>
<dc:subject>Chucalissa Museum; Native Americans; museums; parks; Fuller State Park;</dc:subject>
<dc:publisher>W. M. Cline Co., Chattanooga, Tennessee</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Natural Color Photo Frank Shannon; Collection processed by Angela Price</dc:contributor>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Postcard, 3.5 x 5.5 inches</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>203; Drawer 2, Folder 18</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>post405, post406</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Postcards from Memphis</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Bluff City Collection</dc:source>
<dc:source>Memphis &amp; Shelby County Room, MPLIC</dc:source>
<dc:rights>Digital Image &#169;2011, Memphis Public Library &amp; Information Center.  All rights reserved.  While the Memphis Public Library &amp; Information Center may house an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use. Any image from the library's collection published in any form must cite as the source: Memphis and Shelby County Room, Memphis Public Library &amp; Information Center .  For all requests, please contact the History Department at 901.415.2742 or hisref@memphistn.gov.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16108.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15342coll3/id/608</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>