<oai_dc:dc xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc.xsd">
<dc:title>Elks National Convention and Worlds Fair</dc:title>
<dc:description>"Elks National Convention and Worlds Fair New York City 1939 -- The Booker T. Washington High School Drum and Bugle Corps, Composed of Junior Elks of Memphis, Tennessee -- Left: J.E. Kelly Grand Secy, B.T. Hung Regional Director of Education, Right: G.W. Lee Exalted Ruler of Bluff City Lodge No. 96, Rev. H.P. Gibson, Chairman Civil Liberties, Miss Lucy L. McClinton, Sponsor." Two-tone photo.</dc:description>
<dc:description>Handwritten: "Mr. E.H. Crump -- 1962 Peabody Ave. -- Memphis Tenn." -- "Girls of B.T.W. Hi Drum &amp; Bugle wish me to tell you they are on their way. A million thanks to you. by Blair T. Hunt."</dc:description>
<dc:date>1939-08-20</dc:date>
<dc:subject>Booker T. Washington High School; schools; music; Elks; Lee, George W.; Hunt, Blair T.; Kelly, J. E.; Gibson, H. P.; McClinton, Lucy; Crump, E. H.;</dc:subject>
<dc:creator>Hunt, Blair T.</dc:creator>
<dc:publisher>Bluff City Lodge No. 96</dc:publisher>
<dc:contributor>Collection processed by Angela Price; digitized by S. Frierson;</dc:contributor>
<dc:date>1939</dc:date>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>postcard, 5.5 x 3.5 in.</dc:format>
<dc:identifier>267; Drawer 2, Folder 19</dc:identifier>
<dc:identifier>SFPost061, SFPost062</dc:identifier>
<dc:relation>Postcards from Memphis</dc:relation>
<dc:source>Bluff City Collection</dc:source>
<dc:source>Memphis &amp; Shelby County Room, MPLIC</dc:source>
<dc:rights>Digital Image &#169;2012, Memphis Public Library &amp; Information Center.  All rights reserved.  While the Memphis Public Library &amp; Information Center may house an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use. Any image from the library's collection published in any form must cite as the source: Memphis and Shelby County Room, Memphis Public Library &amp; Information Center.  For all requests, please contact the History Department at 901.415.2742 or hisref@memphistn.gov.</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm16108.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15342coll3/id/821</dc:identifier></oai_dc:dc>