<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:dltn="https://github.com/digitallibraryoftennessee" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Supply route road leading up to the Kumhwa front</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <accessCondition type="local rights statement">While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees, that may be necessary for the intended use.</accessCondition>
  <location>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll32/id/117</url>
    <url access="preview">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p15138coll32/id/117</url>
    <url note="iiif-manifest">https://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/iiif/info/p15138coll32/117/manifest.json</url>
  </location>
  <name>
    <namePart>Brock, David Franklin, 1931 -</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cre">Creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <abstract>This is a road in Korea in the Kumhwa area. There is a hill leading up to the front. The road leading to the front is used as a supply route. The edge of a bunker and a vehicle behind it are barely visible.</abstract>
  <abstract>The main line of resistance (MLR) is defined as the line or zone of contact with the enemy; it is also referred to as the front or front lines. In the Korean War, the area known as no man's land separated the fronts of the two sides. It was heavily mined and contained trip flares to alert military forces to enemy penetration. The front lines largely stabilized north of Seoul in 1951, and the final two years of the Korean War (1952/1953) represented a static ground phase characterized by battles for hills and outposts along the MLR. A combat engineer seeks to advance his dual mission of keeping armies moving to attack, and impeding the enemy. In the Korean War, combat engineer units rotated toward the front, often attached to combat infantry regiments to provide support. Brock's Company D of the 2nd Infantry Division's 2nd Engineer Combat Battalion, though attached to the 72nd Tank Battalion, possessed more mobility than other companies of the 2nd Engineers. Squads from Company D made up of ten to twelve men were generally sent out from base camp on location to tackle necessary construction, repair, and demolition assignments. When near the front, however, the company, like the rest of the 2nd Engineers, remained on call twenty-four hours a day. During this time, these soldiers often labored all day on engineer projects and at night were called to the front lines when the enemy tried to break through. Brock experienced the fiercest fighting as a combat infantryman and in conjunction with his engineer work in the Hook sector of the MLR near the Samichon River. This would have been the time of the bloody last battle of the Hook in July of 1953.</abstract>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated>Spring/Summer 1953</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Tennessee State Library and Archives</recordContentSource>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
  </recordInfo>
  <subject>
    <topic>Korean War, 1950 - 1953</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Korean War, 1950 - 1953 -- United States</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Korean War, 1950 - 1953 -- Battlefields</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Bunkers (Fortification)</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Trench warfare</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Military vehicles</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Supplies, Military</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Roads</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Dirt roads</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>War damage</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Photographs</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Roads</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Battlefields</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Bunkers</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Military vehicles</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Roads</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Dirt Roads</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Fences</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>War damage</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <geographic>Korea</geographic>
  </subject>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>David Franklin Brock Korean War Photograph Collection</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Tennessee State Library and Archives</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <physicalDescription>
    <form>Photographs</form>
  </physicalDescription>
  <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
</mods>
