<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:dltn="https://github.com/digitallibraryoftennessee" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Brock catching up on correspondence during Tokyo R&amp;R</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <accessCondition type="local rights statement">While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees that may be necessary for the intended use.</accessCondition>
  <location>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll32/id/326</url>
    <url access="preview">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p15138coll32/id/326</url>
    <url note="iiif-manifest">https://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/iiif/info/p15138coll32/326/manifest.json</url>
  </location>
  <name>
    <namePart>Brock, David Franklin, 1931 -</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cre">Creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <abstract>Brock is writing a letter while on leave in his hotel room at the Civil Service Hotel in Tokyo. He is dressed in his OD's (olive drab uniform), minus the jacket and cap. Brock had only this one-week leave during his tour of duty in Korea. He was close to being due another, when it was time for him to go home, but he didn't want to take it; the plane trouble during this leave made safety a consideration. Also, he wanted to get home more quickly. Brock's girlfriend, whom he would later marry, Laura Mae Phillips, has written across the photograph "Writing Laura."</abstract>
  <abstract>Born in 1933 into a family of Tennessee sharecroppers at the height of the Great Depression, Laura Mae Phillips experienced sacrifice and hardship early in life. Phillips captured the attention of David Franklin Brock when they were teenagers, and he was immediately smitten. The two were sweethearts throughout the course of his service in the Korean War. Phillips's combined fear of commitment and delight in playing hard to get, however, led to her absenting herself several times when Brock came home on leave from training at Fort Leonard Wood and to her heading north for work in a Detroit spark plug factory while Brock was overseas. When Brock returned stateside in 1953, he renewed his courtship of Phillips, and they married in 1954.</abstract>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated>Spring 1953</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Tennessee State Library and Archives</recordContentSource>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
  </recordInfo>
  <subject>
    <topic>Korean War, 1950 - 1953</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Korean War, 1950 - 1953 -- United States</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Tokyo (Japan)</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Hotels -- Japan -- Tokyo</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Military leave and furloughs</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Letter writing</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Photographs</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Soldiers</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Military Personnel</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Hotels</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Letter writing</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Correspondence</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <geographic>Tokyo (Japan)</geographic>
  </subject>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>David Franklin Brock Korean War Photograph Collection</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Tennessee State Library and Archives</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <physicalDescription>
    <form>Photographs</form>
  </physicalDescription>
  <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
</mods>
