<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:dltn="https://github.com/digitallibraryoftennessee" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" version="3.5" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
  <titleInfo>
    <title>Brock stands in front of Chorwon Valley mess hall</title>
  </titleInfo>
  <accessCondition type="local rights statement">While TSLA houses an item, it does not necessarily hold the copyright on the item, nor may it be able to determine if the item is still protected under current copyright law. Users are solely responsible for determining the existence of such instances and for obtaining any other permissions and paying associated fees, that may be necessary for the intended use.</accessCondition>
  <location>
    <url usage="primary" access="object in context">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll32/id/36</url>
    <url access="preview">http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/utils/getthumbnail/collection/p15138coll32/id/36</url>
    <url note="iiif-manifest">https://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/iiif/info/p15138coll32/36/manifest.json</url>
  </location>
  <name>
    <namePart>Brock, David Franklin, 1931 -</namePart>
    <role>
      <roleTerm authority="marcrelator" authorityURI="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators/cre">Creator</roleTerm>
    </role>
  </name>
  <abstract>Brock pictured in front of the mess hall at his first base camp in the Chorwon Valley. Logs anchored in the ground serve to keep soil from washing away with the rains, and they can be used as seating for eating or watching movies outside. Brock's company got to this base camp just in time for monsoon season. A week or two after they arrived, the rains washed out the roads and a bridge for the air strip. Brock kept his cigarettes and wallet under his helmet as the only dry spot. Brock recounts that the soldiers were served good food in the mess hall; the commander of the 2nd Engineers and General James C. Fry made sure the supply outfit behaved.</abstract>
  <abstract>Brock's service in the Korean War occurred in the vicinity of the Iron Triangle and near the 38th parallel. During this time (from July of 1952 to the end of the war), the 2nd Engineer Combat Battalion was stationed at the Chorwon Valley, then in the Kumhwa region, and finally at the Hook. The 2nd Engineers set up base camps at these three stations and remained at each for approximately six months. The soldiers were a part of the rotation points system instituted in March of 1951 for all United Nations personnel. Service within different sectors garnered an assigned number of points per month, with more dangerous locations carrying a higher number of points. Assignments from the base camp would rotate closer toward the front and then back away. Thus, there were a certain number of days per month for which a soldier would receive extra combat pay. After extended periods of service near the front, the unit would be rotated to the rear, perhaps twenty-five miles from the lines, and placed in reserve for rest and additional training. Once a soldier had accumulated a certain number of points, he was eligible to return home; his position would be taken by a replacement. During 1952, the 2nd Division received an average of 1,800 replacements per month. The highest monthly total for the year of 3,000 replacements occurred in July of 1952--when Brock arrived in Korea as a replacement combat engineer. Though the rotation points system had the potential to heighten morale, it also could erode comradery and undermine unit allegiance with its notion of limited service. In Brock's case, it took fourteen months to obtain the necessary thirty-six points to leave Korea. When moving to a new station to set up a base camp, and thus, replace another unit, the 2nd Engineers might camp half a dozen times for a two-week period before reaching their final destination. With each stop, their supply of explosives, anti-personnel mines, and anti-tank mines had to be unloaded from trucks by the combat engineers and located a safe distance away from the main camp. Then, at the end of the two-week interval, these dangerous stores would be reloaded onto trucks, so the battalion could move out. When the 2nd Engineers arrived at the new station, the combat engineers could then deposit the explosives and mines at an adjacent site a safe distance away (usually on the side of a hill) for a period of months.</abstract>
  <originInfo>
    <dateCreated>1952 July</dateCreated>
  </originInfo>
  <recordInfo>
    <recordContentSource>Tennessee State Library and Archives</recordContentSource>
    <languageOfCataloging>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
    </languageOfCataloging>
  </recordInfo>
  <subject>
    <topic>Korean War, 1950 - 1953</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Korean War, 1950 - 1953 -- United States</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Military Camp</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Mess halls</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Korean War, 1950 - 1953 -- Military personnel</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Photographs</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Military life</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Military camps</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Soldiers</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Military personnel</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Mess halls</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <topic>Logs</topic>
  </subject>
  <subject>
    <geographic>Korea</geographic>
  </subject>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>David Franklin Brock Korean War Photograph Collection</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <relatedItem type="host">
    <titleInfo>
      <title>Tennessee State Library and Archives</title>
    </titleInfo>
  </relatedItem>
  <physicalDescription>
    <form>Photographs</form>
  </physicalDescription>
  <typeOfResource>still image</typeOfResource>
</mods>
