<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Cuban and American flags over Morro Castle</dc:title>
<dc:description>Black and white photograph showing the flags of Cuba and the United States flying over Morro Castle. Handwritten in the border of the image: "Morro Castle at Havana Cuba flying Cuban Flag for the first. (Realization of Cuban Hopes)." </dc:description>
<dc:description>From 1898 to 1902, in the aftermath of the Spanish-American War, the United States Military occupied Cuba. The period is known as the First Occupation of Cuba. The 1901 Constitution of the Republic of Cuba was adopted with the Platt Amendment, which stipulated eight conditions for the withdrawal of U.S. troops and the protection of Cuba's independence from foreign intervention. On December 31, 1901, Tom&#225;s Estrada Palma (1835-1908) was elected as the first President of the Republic of Cuba. Palma resigned on September 28, 1906, leaving Cuba without a leader and opening the door for the Second Occupation of Cuba (Cuban Pacification), which lasted until 1909. A third occupation, the Sugar Intervention, lasted from 1917 to 1922. </dc:description>
<dc:date>1902</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>Havana (Cuba)</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>Grassmere Collection, 1786-1985</dc:source>
<dc:source>1989-046</dc:source>
<dcterms:references>https://sos.tn.gov/products/tsla/grassmere-collection-1786-1985</dcterms:references>
<dc:subject>Castillo del Morro (Havana, Cuba); Fortification--Cuba; Bays--Cuba; Cuba--Politics and government; Cuba--History; Cuba History American occupation, 1906-1909</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Black and white photographs; Castles &amp; palaces</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>44105</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>XX-H-1, Box 40, Folder 5</dc:source>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Grassmere Collection, 1786-1985</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:type>Still Image</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dcterms:medium>Photographs</dcterms:medium>
<dc:rights>No copyright - United States: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/NoC-US/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll31/id/552</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>