<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>General Concrete Construction Company of Cuba advertisement</dc:title>
<dc:description>This poster advertises two companies managed by Bradford Dallas in Cuba. William Croft owned the General Concrete Construction Company until his death in 1938. The advertisement includes locations of both companies and an illustration of a brick building and concrete chimney in the foreground, with a factory in the background.</dc:description>
<dc:description>William Croft moved to Cuba in 1900 and started the General Concrete Construction Company of Cuba in Havana. The company specialized in the construction of concrete chimneys for the sugar industry on the island. After Mr. Croft&#8217;s death in 1938, his daughters Elise and Margaret became sole owners of the company&#8217;s stocks and relied on income from the company for their livelihood. Elise visited Cuba at least once a year on business through the 1950s and kept up a regular correspondence with company manager Bradford Dallas. On December 6, 1961, all of the Crofts&#8217; property in Cuba, including the company, was confiscated pursuant to Law 989 - the abandoned property law issued by Fidel Castro (1926-2016). The Croft sisters filed a claim with the United States Government in the late 1960s, but never received compensation for their losses. Their claims against the Cuban government are still outstanding.</dc:description>
<dc:date>approximately 1955</dc:date>
<dc:coverage>Havana (Cuba)</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>Grassmere Collection, 1786-1985</dc:source>
<dc:source>1989-046</dc:source>
<dcterms:references>https://sos.tn.gov/products/tsla/grassmere-collection-1786-1985</dcterms:references>
<dc:subject>Construction industry--Cuba</dc:subject>
<dc:subject>Posters; Advertisements</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>43809</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>XX-G-6, Box 35, Folder 1</dc:source>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Grassmere Collection, 1786-1985</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:type>Still Image</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dcterms:medium>Advertisements</dcterms:medium>
<dc:rights>Copyright not evaluated: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll31/id/382</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>