<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Letter from Bradford B. Dallas to Elise Croft</dc:title>
<dc:description>Two page typed letter from Bradford B. Dallas to Elise Croft. Dallas writes from Saigon, Vietnam, to let Elise know she and Margaret must file a claim for their Cuban property, which was confiscated by the Cuban government. Dallas includes instructions and tips on how to file the property claim.</dc:description>
<dc:description>William Croft moved to Cuba in 1900 and started the General Concrete Construction Company of Cuba in Havana. The company specialized in the construction of concrete chimneys for the sugar industry on the island. After Mr. Croft&#8217;s death in 1938, his daughters Elise and Margaret became sole owners of the company&#8217;s stocks and relied on income from the company for their livelihood. Elise visited Cuba at least once a year on business through the 1950s and kept up a regular correspondence with company manager Bradford Dallas. On December 6, 1961, all of the Crofts&#8217; property in Cuba, including the company, was confiscated pursuant to Law 989 - the abandoned property law issued by Fidel Castro (1926-2016). The Croft sisters filed a claim with the United States Government in the late 1960s, but never received compensation for their losses. Their claims against the Cuban government are still outstanding.</dc:description>
<dc:date>1967 April 23</dc:date>
<dc:creator>Dallas, Bradford B.</dc:creator>
<dc:coverage>Saigon (Vietnam)</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>Grassmere Collection, 1786-1985</dc:source>
<dc:source>1989-046</dc:source>
<dcterms:references>https://sos.tn.gov/products/tsla/grassmere-collection-1786-1985</dcterms:references>
<dc:subject>Construction industry--Cuba; Americans--Cuba--History; United States.--Claims vs Cuba; Eminent domain--Cuba</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>43877</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>XX-H-3, Box 47, Folder 25</dc:source>
<dcterms:isPartOf>Grassmere Collection, 1786-1985</dcterms:isPartOf>
<dc:type>Text</dc:type>
<dc:format>Image/jpeg</dc:format>
<dcterms:medium>Correspondence</dcterms:medium>
<dc:rights>Copyright not evaluated: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll31/id/298</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>