<oai_qdc:qualifieddc xmlns:oai_qdc="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xsi:schemaLocation="http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc-1.0/ http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/qdc/1.0/qdc-1.0.xsd http://purl.org/net/oclcterms http://worldcat.org/xmlschemas/oclcterms/1.4/oclcterms-1.4.xsd">
<dc:title>Elise and Margaret Croft discuss donation of Grassmere</dc:title>
<dc:description>Elise and Margaret Croft express why they wanted to donate their land and what it means for the future. They share that they are "very contented" to live at Grassmere, and they hope it will be enjoyed by all Tennesseans, not just people from Nashville. Also heard on the tape are Joe Thompson, Jr., and Mary Hamilton Thompson Orr.</dc:description>
<dc:description>In 1964, Margaret and Elise Croft donated the Grassmere property to the Children's Museum of Nashville to be used as a "nature study center." As part of the agreement, the sisters would live on the property until their deaths and the Museum would pay taxes and maintain the property. Margaret passed away in 1974. After Elise's death in 1985, the Museum developed Grassmere Wildlife Park on the property, which opened in 1990 and closed in 1995. In 1996, the Nashville Zoo moved from Joelton to Grassmere where it remains to this day. Joe Thompson, Jr. (1919-2012) and Mary Hamilton Thompson Orr (1909-1976) were friends of the Croft sisters and descendants of Thomas Thompson (1759-1837), an early settler of Nashville and a signer of the Cumberland Compact. The Thompson family's ancestral home, Glen Leven, was situated on present-day Franklin Road, within miles of the Grassmere property. For more information about the Thompson and allied families, see the Orr, Mary Hamilton Thompson, Papers, 1791-1896, and Addition, 1779-1955. </dc:description>
<dc:date>1964 October 22</dc:date>
<dc:contributor>Croft, Margaret, 1889-1974; Croft, Elise, 1894-1985</dc:contributor>
<dc:coverage>Nashville (Tenn.)</dc:coverage>
<dc:source>Grassmere Collection, 1786-1985</dc:source>
<dc:source>1989-046</dc:source>
<dcterms:references>https://sos.tn.gov/products/tsla/grassmere-collection-1786-1985</dcterms:references>
<dc:subject>Family farms--Tennessee--History</dc:subject>
<dc:source>Tennessee State Library and Archives</dc:source>
<dc:identifier>44276</dc:identifier>
<dc:source>V-A-4v</dc:source>
<dc:type>Sound</dc:type>
<dc:format>Audio/mp3</dc:format>
<dcterms:medium>Audio; Oral histories</dcterms:medium>
<dc:rights>Copyright not evaluated: http://rightsstatements.org/vocab/CNE/1.0/</dc:rights>
<dc:identifier>http://cdm15138.contentdm.oclc.org/cdm/ref/collection/p15138coll31/id/619</dc:identifier></oai_qdc:qualifieddc>